<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 08:39:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 08:39:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The road to electric is filled with tiny cars]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 102 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232760">thread link</a>) | @jimmy2020
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			<!-- Article Start -->
			
<p><span>I</span>n Beijing’s southwestern outskirts, past a four-lane overpass with sidewalks as wide as the streets themselves, is Zhengyang Road. It has the usual banks, small convenience stores, and noodle houses of many areas in the capital, but it is set apart by a row of about a dozen shops all selling the same thing — tiny electric cars. The cars look, variously, like small Range Rovers, golf carts, trolley cars, or rickshaws with sheet-iron sides, and they are slow. Their fundamental attraction is their price — between $600 and $2,500 — and that drivers can charge them the same way they would a cell phone. They also come with the perks of being loosely regulated. These low-speed electric cars, nicknamed “elderly transport vehicles,” have an enormous market, made up mostly of people who earn very little. And in China, there are a lot of them — <a href="http://english.www.gov.cn/premier/news/202005/29/content_WS5ed058d2c6d0b3f0e9498f21.html">more than 40%</a> of the population, or some 600 million people, make around $150 per month.</p>



<p>On a Sunday afternoon in October, Zhengyang Road is filled with potential customers chatting with store owners.<strong> </strong>Outside a shop with a worn sign, a young couple with a child are in the midst of a heated conversation.<strong> </strong>They came on an electric scooter and are debating whether to leave with a tiny car.</p>



<p>“Don’t we need one for school pickups?” the woman argues. “The children won’t have to put up with the cold in winter.” Her scooter offers no protection from the weather other than oven-mitt-like gloves secured to its handlebars. Her husband counters, “The 1,000 renminbi [$150] quote was for normal batteries, but lithium ones can be five times that. Can’t you just add a windshield to your scooter instead?” The shop owner shows them a cheaper model — which is cheaper because it has no roof. He suggests putting a plastic covering on top.</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 600px(max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="A woman exits a tiny car near a subway station in Beijing.">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<p>Having decided that the future of mobility is electric,<strong> </strong>the Chinese government has subsidized sales of regular electric cars since 2010. With <a href="https://insideevs.com/news/394229/plugin-electric-car-sales-china-2019/">close to 1.18 million sold</a> in 2019, China accounts for just over half of electric-vehicle sales globally. Bill Russo, founder and CEO of advisory firm Automobility Limited, sees a “steady and solid rise” in China’s electric-vehicle sales generally. The country has set a top-down target for electric vehicles to <a href="http://energy.mit.edu/news/chinas-transition-to-electric-vehicles/">make up 40%</a> of car sales by 2030, and Russo thinks they’ll have no problem hitting this goal. Tiny cars,<strong> </strong>which first began appearing in the early 2010s,<strong> </strong>have more than double the sales of regular electric cars but have<strong> </strong>never benefited from subsidies. Nor do advertisements for them air on television — instead, they appear on Kuaishou, a short-video platform popular with people living outside China’s big cities. Alongside streamers selling plums by the thousands, and others telling viewers what long-haul trucker life is like, drivers show off their tiny cars. Su Hua, Kuaishou’s founder, has long maintained that his app’s users are not “cool,” unlike those on Douyin, the TikTok predecessor popular with China’s urban elite. Rather, they are ordinary — the kind of people who might be in the market for miniature cars.</p>



<p>As they don’t technically require licenses, tiny cars tend to be popular with migrant workers, who struggle to pay for driving lessons and other car-related costs. The elderly, too, find tiny cars attractive since, up until October of last year, people over 70 could not apply for a driving license in China. They’re also convenient for anybody who wants a car to pick up groceries or their kids from school: No tiny car is longer than 1.5 meters, and their speed tops out at between 40 and 56 kilometers an hour. They’re for the short trips of daily life, not for traveling from one side of the city to another.</p>



<p>Some cities have banned sales of tiny cars — Beijing did so in 2018. Their production isn’t regulated by the government, and since they can’t be insured in many parts of China, it can be difficult for other drivers to get a payout if a tiny car is involved in an accident. Because tiny-car drivers don’t need to take a driving test, other drivers complain, they often go the wrong way and weave in and out of traffic. But since enforcement is lax, sales have quietly resumed in Beijing over the past two years. These little electric cars now exist in a kind of regulatory gray zone.</p>


    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      
    </figure>

    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      <figcaption>Tiny cars come in a variety of styles and cost between $600 and $2,500.</figcaption>
    </figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>One of the</strong> smaller shops on Zhengyang Road is officially known as Xinlei Scooters, its name emblazoned in white characters on a large red sign above its doors. But inside, past rows of electric scooters, is a smaller, flimsier plaque above the counter announcing its other name: Shitou Cars. This subterfuge is necessary because the police could shut down the operation and confiscate its vehicles if the owners were caught selling tiny cars. Yet because enforcement hasn’t been strict of late, attempts at being covert go only so far: There are several tiny cars parked outside, an open-air showroom.</p>



<p>Xinlei/Shitou’s owner is a middle-aged man with pronounced cheekbones wearing a black tracksuit. He is more attentive to the phone calls he’s constantly receiving than the customers in the shop. It is his wife, with dyed-dark-brown hair and a pink coat, who maintains the sales patter: “I taught an auntie who had never driven a car before. She got the hang of it in three days.” She shows the cars outside to potential customers, opening their doors, instructing people to sit inside, and rolling down the windows. When two old men come in for repair services, her husband finally gets off the phone to deal with them. Meanwhile, two government functionaries in black uniforms pace down the street. They tell one owner to make his storefront tidier, but otherwise overlook the illicit operation.</p>



<p>Part of the reason why tiny cars are so popular is because there has not been an official decision on whether they need license plates. For regular cars, unfettered access to Beijing’s inner city — anywhere within the fifth ring road — is restricted to cars with Beijing plates. Licenses for gas cars are distributed through a special system so competitive that it has generated its own black market. License-plate holders can collect up to $2,700 a year by renting them to those who want to drive in the city. In addition to government subsidies, getting around some of the more onerous aspects of the licensing system is one of the main selling points for regular electric cars.</p>



<p>With Beijing temperatures reaching lows of 4 degrees Celsius in wintertime, Xinlei/Shitou has been selling,<strong> </strong>on average, two of its four-wheeled fully enclosed models every day, a saleswoman boasts. Younger couples prefer four wheels, she adds, while older people usually want three. When asked about the possibility of a tiny car being confiscated, she draws in a breath. “Don’t go on the main roads. Don’t make a business out of it,” she advises.</p>



<p>At least one of Zhengyang Road’s customers isn’t listening: Guo Caiying, who works primarily in the construction-supply industry,<strong> </strong>chauffeurs Fengtai residents around her district. She has a sticker on her tiny car’s back window with the phone number of her car dealer. Guo’s car looks like a golf cart, with cushioned brown seats enclosed by windows. A red <em>fudai</em>, a lucky charm, swings from the ceiling, its characters spelling out “peace.” There is enough space for two people to comfortably sit upright but not enough to extend your legs without hitting the plexiglass divider between driver and passenger. The car tops out at 40 kilometers an hour, and<strong> </strong>as a result, Guo never ventures beyond Fengtai — a borderland where urban and rural meet.</p>



<p>Guo wears the uniform of the countryside: a padded jacket. She is from Henan, a province 800 kilometers southwest of Beijing, and speaks its dialect. Guo starts taking calls from her regulars around 7 a.m., arriving at their door whenever they want to be picked up. She stops driving at 9 a.m., when the traffic police begin work. She characterizes her customers as “people with money who sit in offices.” Once, while in the middle of a trip, Guo saw a cop stop a car like hers. She kept driving, but dropped her passenger off before their destination. Now, if a customer calls her after 9:00, she sends her husband to pick them up with his electric scooter. He charges 75 cents (5RMB), which is half her price. Guo’s flat rate was fixed by the tiny-cab drivers who preceded her.</p>



<p>The economy of tiny cars depends on such informal practices.<strong> </strong>When asked whether she would consider undercutting other drivers, Guo is adamant. “No one can break the rules,” she says. There are local WeChat groups for tiny-car drivers that new owners are inducted into upon purchasing one. Within these groups, members swap information on the whereabouts of local cops and whether anyone has been fined or had their car taken away.</p>



<p>Despite the risks, Guo still thinks it’s worth being a tiny-car driver to make a little pocket money.<strong> </strong>Tiny cars are part of a last-mile economy that flourishes at the beginning and end of the workday. Many Fengtai residents are employed at the local high-tech park, which is host to thousands of businesses. It takes 20 minutes to walk from one end of the park to the other, a trip many would rather make by tiny car. The cars’ main competitors are share bikes, which are cheaper but lack space for luggage and can’t be split with a friend. Tiny cars are also more social — a feature Guo tries to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/">https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232760</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 01:12:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nintendo DS-TV-Out Restoration Project]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 176 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232600">thread link</a>) | @max-m
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <section id="main_content">
        

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>During late 2020, we discovered that the Nintendo DS Lite had a leftover feature in its SoC allowing it to easily have cheap hardware video output. With a little circuitry and some software hacks, we were able to restore it and make it usable for anyone. No FPGA’s, no bulky or cumbersome hardware. This mod is specially useful to revive consoles with only the lower screen, being able to watch the upper screen on your TV. Or to create a GBA Macro with additional TV Output.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/DSTVOUT.jpg" width="250" height="250"><br></center>
<center>
  <b>First iteration of the TV-OUT board in action</b>
  </center>

<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>

<p>If you are just interested in installation, this is the current method <strong>while we work on simpler methods</strong> and more features you have requested:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Install the <a href="https://ezflash.sosuke.com/wiki/index.php/Flashme">flashME CFW</a> (Custom FirmWare) on your DS Lite</li>
  <li>Connect the Nintendo DS Lite’s upper screen flex to the PCB board.</li>
  <li>Donwload the “NDS TV OUT ENABLE.nds” homebrew from the <a href="https://github.com/LostNintendoHistory/Lost-NDS-TV">NDS TV OUT repo</a></li>
  <li>Download <a href="https://github.com/DS-Homebrew/TWiLightMenu/releases">Twilight Menu</a></li>
  <li>Copy both the NDS TV OUT ENABLE and Twilight Menu .nds files to a flashcart.</li>
  <li>Use flashme to autoboot into the flashcart. You can do this by pressing A + B + Start + Select while booting. Run Twilight menu, and from there, run the enabler homebrew.</li>
  <li>The console will return to Twilight Menu. Now you can use the buttons on the board to swap between the different screen modes (Upper Screen to TV, Bottom Screen to TV, etc) and launch your games.</li>
</ol>

<hr>

<h2 id="software">Software</h2>

<p>The retail firmware of the Nintendo DS Lite disables this specific feature early in the boot process. To reenable it, we use a custom firmware like flashme, which is very easy to install and is required only once, plus a homebrew. Despite that, we are working on an even simpler solution to make it available to as many people as possible, our own custom firmware which integrates patches to enable this feature directly on boot. Additionally, we are currently working with homebrew developers to integrate control of this new feature into existing software for the DS Lite.</p>

<h2 id="hardware">Hardware</h2>

<p>This feature is only found on the Nintendo DS Lite. Nintendo DS Phat does not contain this feature nor does the Nintendo DSi. It is important to remark that <strong>this is not the same hardware</strong> found on Devkits or other special units. This hardware feature is present in virtually <strong>every single Nintendo DS Lite</strong> out there. The reason why it was left there is unknown, but as said before, it is not related to development units, those use a different video capture hardware. Perhaps Nintendo imagined the Nintendo Switch as early as 2006?</p>

<center><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/PCB_Rev_11.png" width="350" height="400"></center>

<p>We only need a few extra hardware components to make this video signal usable. You will be able to download the schematics and gerber files for our open hardware circuit board <a href="https://github.com/LostNintendoHistory/Lost-NDS-TV">from the repository</a>. The latest version is revision 1.2 which fixes some minor issues with a component in the board.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/Prototype.jpg" width="350" height="350"><br>
</center>
<center>
  <b>First prototype and tests before designing a proper board</b></center>


<p>The final, production-ready board contains a DAC (Digital to Analogue Converter) which turns the 10 bits digital signal at 16.7 MHz provided by the DS Lite into a proper analogue signal. This signal then goes through an operational amplifier and it’s ready to be delivered to your nearest TV trough composite video.</p>

<p>We are currently considering creating an additional PCB revision which would allow to install the mod on consoles without lossing a working upper screen.</p>


      </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232600</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Bombard Story]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232597">thread link</a>) | @jbergstroem
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
				<div id="content">
			
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">
			
<article id="post-618" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="">
	<div>
					
			
		<div itemprop="text">
			<p><strong>The Bombard Story</strong> is the account of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alain_Bombard">Alain Bombard’s</a> amazing journey in 1952 across the <a href="http://greatestadventurers.com/the-north-west-passage-by-roal-amundsen/">Atlantic</a> on a small 14-foot inflatable boat. Alain Bombard left without food or fresh water and sailed 4.400 kilometers. He lost 25 kg. but proved his point: Man can actually survive on ocean water for an extended period of time!</p>
<figure id="attachment_619" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-619"><img loading="lazy" src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/TheBombardStory1953.jpg" alt="The Bombard Story" width="300" height="203" data-src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/TheBombardStory1953.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="><figcaption id="caption-attachment-619">In this small vessel Bombard sailed across the Atlantic – without freshwater</figcaption></figure>
<p>As a doctor, Bombard was concerned about the hundreds of deaths at sea every year related to sailors drinking ocean water. He developed the theory that humans can not just survive but live for years on seawater. This sounds very strange, but his big idea was to begin drinking seawater, while you are still hydrated – and in small quantities. It turns out that saltwater is only dangerous if you are dehydrated and suddenly drink large amounts of it. – The way shipwrecked sailors typically would do when they run out of fresh water. From the book:</p>
<blockquote><p>For some time I had made a study of the resistance of the human organism to privations and had convinced myself that it was possible for an individual to survive beyond the limits normally assigned by physiological science. I had paid particular attention to the case histories of political deportees, prisoners, and undernourished populations. But, with my background as a doctor, for whom the teachings of science remain a dead letter unless they can find practical application, my theoretical studies only seemed to lead to the question: ‘What use can made of this knowledge?’</p></blockquote>
<p>Bombard ate spoonfuls of plankton that he collected in a fine net and he also drank juice made from pressed fish he caught along the way. Sound disgusting, but the man survived and he might have discovered an important piece of knowledge for survival on the ocean.</p>
<p>Download the free PDF e-book here (223 pages/38MB):</p>
<h3><img loading="lazy" src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/PDF-download-e1597850191432.png" alt="" width="35" height="35" data-src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/PDF-download-e1597850191432.png" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">&nbsp;<a href="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/The-Bombard-Story-1953.pdf">The Bombard Story 1953</a></h3>

		</div>

				
			</div>
</article>

			

					</main>
	</div>

	

	</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232597</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:48:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Living Like It's 99: No Social Media, No Smartphone]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 143 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26226864">thread link</a>) | @betaman0
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://www.alvarez.io/posts/living-like-it-s-99/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.alvarez.io/posts/living-like-it-s-99/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				<p><img src="https://www.alvarez.io/img/color/l99.jpg" alt="Robot"></p>
<p>At the time of writing this article, I’ve been living without social media for 3 years and without a smartphone for 2 years. Everything started as an experiment motivated by my privacy concerns. I ended up living like that for an entire different reason: peace of mind. You can find a lot of people on internet that have tried this experiment, from a couple of days to an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B0RVWU_nROk">entire month</a>. However I discovered that the brain dependencies created by social media and smartphones take a lot longer to go away (30 days for me). You can’t really see the effects it has on your life unless you try this kind of experiment for a long time, because you will be stuck in the withdrawal phase that makes you crave dopamine.</p>
<p>Contrary to popular belief, I do not live in a cave where I spend my time coding without any social life, sorry guys ;) I did this experiment while having a busy professional and personal life: I traveled around the world, moved to a new city without knowing anyone, ran <a href="https://www.duple.io/">my own software startup</a>, met new people and made new friends, etc… So it is possible to live your life the same way, or even better, without a smartphone or social media.</p>
<p>I will share with you my experience leaving social media and my smartphone, the tools I replaced them with, some tips and tricks, people’s reactions to my experiment, as well as some funny anecdotes.</p>
<h2 id="lets-start-with-why">Let’s Start With Why</h2>
<h3 id="privacy">Privacy</h3>
<p>The original motivation behind this experiment was privacy. I’m a professional hacker, the things I can do are scary and I’m far from being the only one with these skills. <strong>Smartphones are a dream come true for people like me, little spy devices that are 24/7 on you, remotely accessible from anywhere around the world</strong>. Throw social media into the equation, and you can get inside the head of anybody, and make them do whatever you want. Yes, you should be scared. And that’s even without mentioning all the other <a href="https://lithub.com/what-does-privacy-really-mean-under-surveillance-capitalism/">privacy</a> and <a href="https://the.ink/p/we-can-have-democracy-or-we-can-have">freedom</a> issues that come with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/04/facebook-phone-numbers-exposed/">social media</a> and <a href="https://nrkbeta.no/2020/12/03/my-phone-was-spying-on-me-so-i-tracked-down-the-surveillants/">smartphones</a>.</p>
<h3 id="curiosity">Curiosity</h3>
<p>Another reason, which is less dark, was curiosity. I like to experiment and try new things in my life. I was curious about the idea of living without a smartphone and social media especially in a world more connected than ever. And if I didn’t like the experiment, I could always go back to <a href="https://www.meta-nomad.net/avoiding-the-global-lobotomy/">zombieland</a>.</p>
<h3 id="planned-obsolescence">Planned Obsolescence</h3>
<p>The cherry on top was to stop paying each year for a new smartphone, that does nothing more than the previous one, just because the providers decided to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planned_obsolescence">sabotage old models</a> so they <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Batterygate">stop working</a>.</p>
<h3 id="peace-of-mind">Peace of mind</h3>
<p>This is for me the most important reason (even though I discovered it afterwards). The positive effects on your mind, being free from social media and smartphones, are incredible. More on it later.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“Technology has solved old economics problems by giving us new psychological problems.”<br>
Mark Manson, The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In 2018 I deleted my accounts from Twitter, Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp. No coming back, no temptation to reactivate them later on. I kept LinkedIn on standby for professional use although it came close to being deleted as well. WhatsApp got replaced by <a href="https://signal.org/">Signal</a> because Facebook bought them, plus <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/parmyolson/2018/09/26/exclusive-whatsapp-cofounder-brian-acton-gives-the-inside-story-on-deletefacebook-and-why-he-left-850-million-behind/">they’re not really big fan s of privacy</a>.</p>
<p>During that year I kept my smartphone, as I wanted to do the experiment gradually. This decision allowed me to discover something quite counter intuitive about social media and smartphones (more on it later).</p>
<p>From that point on I was reachable by SMS, call, email and Signal. I wasn’t ready for what happened next. Fasten your seatbelts.</p>
<h3 id="people-thought-i-was-dead">People Thought I Was Dead</h3>
<p>The first reaction people had was to think something bad had happened to me, some of them even thought I was dead. Then something socially curious happened: everybody started speaking to each other on Facebook and WhatsApp to try to figure out what was wrong. Some of them even contacted my family multiple times. They all had my phone number, email address and other ways of contacting me. <strong>However, none of them did</strong>. It was like I had exited the matrix, and was living in another reality.</p>
<h3 id="trustworthiness">Trustworthiness</h3>
<p>I was told that I couldn’t be trusted since people can’t check online what I’m doing when I’m not around.</p>
<p>Yeah, you read that right.</p>
<p><strong>Society has been brainwashed to believe that privacy is something criminal. Sorry to disappoint, but privacy is a basic fundament of freedom and democracy. That’s why the voting system is anonymous</strong> [1]. When people tell you “<a href="https://write.privacytools.io/freddy/why-privacy-matters-even-if-you-have-nothing-to-hide">If you have nothing to hide, you have nothing to fear</a>”, what they really mean is “democracy is overrated, get over it”.</p>
<p><em>[1] Privacy: you know who I am but not what I do. Anonymity: You know what I do but not who I am. The voting system uses both, privacy when you go vote, anonymity when they count the results.</em></p>
<h3 id="whatsapp">WhatsApp</h3>
<p>This was for me the biggest problem. <a href="https://seirdy.one/2021/01/27/whatsapp-and-the-domestication-of-users.html">Getting people out of WhatsApp</a> if they wanted to talk to me created a lot of friction. Some of them even stopped texting me because they had to open another app on their phone in order to write to me.</p>
<p>Yeah, you also read that right.</p>
<p>I don’t miss WhatsApp, nor do I miss its endless group talks without anything useful. If you leave one of these groups people look at you as if you did something wrong. In the end I still had access to all the event’s information I needed despite them being organized on WhatsApp. In regards to this, not having the app didn’t change my life much.</p>
<p>A trick I’ve developed, when giving my contact info to new people, is to enter my phone number on their smartphone myself, and install Signal for them. This removed a lot of friction. I would then explain my experiment to them and tell them I can only be contacted via this app. I’ve always had a positive reaction. Everybody’s been curious and asking a lot of questions.</p>
<h3 id="and-then-nothing-happened">And Then Nothing Happened</h3>
<p>During the first weeks without social media, I felt off. As if I was missing out on something big that was happening. Like everybody was having fun except me. Once the <a href="https://joshcsimmons.com/quit-social-media/">withdrawal phase</a> went away, I realized that my life hadn’t changed that much. I was still doing the same things, talking to the same people, going to the same parties, etc… It was just more quiet and peaceful.</p>
<p><strong>I was no longer bombarded with pictures of everybody trying to fake a life they’re not living for the sole purpose of impressing someone else: <a href="https://hbr.org/2017/04/a-new-more-rigorous-study-confirms-the-more-you-use-facebook-the-worse-you-feel">my life had just upgraded</a>.</strong></p>
<p>In the end, after everybody got over their initial shock and calmed down, it became normal for them to contact me using Signal, and life went on as usual.</p>
<h2 id="round-2-goodbye-smartphone">Round 2: Goodbye Smartphone</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.alvarez.io/img/color/l99-2.jpg" alt="Phone"></p>
<p>Unlike social media, smartphones are a lot harder to get rid off. They handle many more things than just simply communicating with people.  I work all day long with a computer, most of what the smartphone was doing could be handled by my laptop. For the rest, I narrowed down my bare essential to Music, Pictures, GPS navigation and of course GSM calls.</p>
<h3 id="the-hardware">The Hardware</h3>
<p>You could solve these problems quite easily using multiple devices, however I wanted to be smart about it and not walk around with a luggage just to carry around all this stuff. After doing some research I figured out the perfect combination and I was even able to reduce the amount of things I had in my pockets.</p>

			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.alvarez.io/posts/living-like-it-s-99/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26226864</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 17:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Abundant Capital]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 348 | Comments 183 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26226723">thread link</a>) | @tomhoward
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://blog.aaronkharris.com/abundant-capital | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.aaronkharris.com/abundant-capital">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
      <div><p>The venture capital industry was built on the premise that both capital and high quality companies are scarce. For most of the history of the industry, this has been true. I remember sitting at demo day in 2011 and marveling at the fact that the combined capital of all the VCs in the room was less than that controlled by the hedge fund at which I had worked. But the model is wrong. Venture capital is abundant, and that fact should fundamentally change how founders fundraise.<br></p><p>This scarcity model has shaped the structure of startups and VCs - most of what an early stage startup does is designed to convince a VC to invest. Companies treat VCs as a limited resource that is both hard to access and hard to convince. Investors do their best to perpetuate this idea because it allows them to retain control of the pitch and fund dynamic.[1]</p><p>Something interesting happens, though, whenever a company has a signifier of quality - a YC demo day slot, a high quality angel, pedigreed founders, or, even better, strong growth. In these cases, there are investor feeding frenzies, leading to oversubscribed rounds, ever climbing prices, and investors willing to accept ownership targets they - until recently - would have termed unacceptable.</p><p>To be sure, there have always been bidding wars in private equity (of which venture is a subset), but these bidding wars are so frequent now as to be approaching the norm. If capital was actually scarce, this wouldn’t happen, there wouldn’t be enough money to create so many bidding wars.[2]</p><p>Bidding wars aren’t the only evidence of capital abundance. The VCs are changing their businesses because of this abundance, whether or not they admit the reason. The evidence is in the new funds that seem to launch on a daily basis, the multi-billion dollar growth funds that have become increasingly common, and the ownership targets at various rounds that continue to drop.</p><p>At the same time that capital has become more abundant, founders have become smarter about fundraising. There are now a huge number of blogs, classes, essays, guides, and advisers ready to help founders navigate the previously opaque world of fundraising. As a result, founders can approach each funding event with a clear plan of how to run a process. Running an orderly process further increases the chances that a company will see competitive bids.</p><p>As a thought experiment, assume that the abundance model is here to stay. It is also safe to assume that founders will not suddenly forget their newfound knowledge about process. I think this should encourage founders to think about changing fundraising in a few major ways:</p><ol>
<li><p>Founders should approach every fundraising as an auction. This is what each process already is, but the auction is inefficient. There’s lots of language and pseudo-moral arguments about why this is bad, but most of those fall apart if capital is abundant.</p></li>
<li><p>Founders should expand their funnels beyond the traditional VCs. These VCs hold a marketing and branding advantage, much of which is built around the signal to later rounds. If, however, each round is an auction, this benefit evaporates. YC’s demo day proved this funnel expansion works at seed, and there’s no logical reason it should fail at later rounds.</p></li>
<li><p>Once a founder has the information produced by this process, she can decide whether to minimize dilution, maximize price, or optimize around the partner. The answer will change based on the situation, but having access to the choice is important.</p></li>
</ol><p>Founders are hesitant to run this model because they fear that running an auction will create a negative quality signal. Investors encourage this belief because it allows them to keep deal flow proprietary. This is flawed logic. The quality of a company can’t be determined by the investors to whom that company talks when raising money. The quality of a company is determined by whether or not the company is good, and good companies should take advantage of abundant capital markets.[3]</p><p><i>Thanks to Adora Cheung, Janelle Tam, Ilya Sukhar, and Nabeel Hyatt for helping me think this through, even though our conclusions might differ.<br></i></p><p>__</p><p>[1] Perhaps more importantly to the investors’ business model is that this dynamic creates a reason for the existence of VCs. If founders and LPs both internalized how non-scarce capital actually is, they could find one another directly, bypassing VCs.</p><p>[2] It’s important to remember that, even though capital is abundant, it remains unevenly distributed. There are companies that struggle to raise money - some of these may be bad investments, but many are good. This is a problem of access rather than capacity, which is a whole different issue.</p><p>[3] When a company IPOs, it opens ownership up to anyone who can afford a share. Imagine, for a second, an investor arguing that this is a sign of low quality.</p></div>
    
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.aaronkharris.com/abundant-capital</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26226723</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:54:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Practical Color Theory for People Who Code (2016)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26225339">thread link</a>) | @martinlaz
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><header>
	
	<h3>Natalya Shelburne
		<br>
		<a href="https://twitter.com/natalyathree">@natalyathree</a>
	</h3>
</header>
	
		<div>
			<div>
				<div>
					

					<div><p>
						Hi! I'm Natalya! <img src="http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/images/tally-pic.jpg" title="natalya-profile" description="vector art self portrait">I'm a classically trained fine artist who spent 6 years teaching people how to paint, draw, and grow their creativity. I am now a front end developer, and I love writing code as much as I love painting. </p><p>I have a degree in Studio Art, a bachelor's in Developmental Psychology, and a master's degree in Creativity and Talent Development. But, most importantly, I have mixed gallons and gallons of paint. </p><p>I abstracted my domain knowledge as a fine artist into variables and functions in order to reveal color selection as being logical, predictable, and driven by principles anyone can learn. Sass color functions give you the same creative power as owning a set of paints, brushes, and canvas. </p><p>This is a demo of my functions for a complementary color scheme - pick any color on the color wheel and the functions will make sure that the scheme will still work! 🎨</p></div>
					</div>
					<div>
						
					
					<h4>Completely new to this? Check out these resources first:</h4>
					
				</div>
			</div>
		</div>
		<a href="#" name="start"></a>
<section>
	<h2>Let's build a Complementary Color Scheme!</h2>
	<img src="http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/images/color-circle.png" alt="color-wheel" title="color wheel" description="the color wheel with corresponding hsl degrees">
	<p>This is the color wheel, consider this the documentation for using color. <br> Notice that the degrees on the color wheel correspond to colors.</p>
	
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Pick a color <span> hsl($hue, $saturation, $lightness)</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		<p>Pick any color by selecting its hue (0-360) on the color wheel at full saturation (100%) and at half lightness (50%) - this way you start with the 'most colorful color' you can get.</p>
		<p>This is what your website will look like if you set every element to this one color. Notice how you can't tell one item from another. Color is information.</p>
	</div>
	<div>

		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>


	</div>
	<div>
		
		<div>
			<p>Why pick a fully saturated color, but only half lightness?</p>
			<p>Ever mix up a bunch of colors only to end up with a gray blob? In the real world, you can't mix a color to be more saturated - you only "lose" color information as you mix. So, the practice is to start with the most saturated colors at their most chromatic so you can still have a full range of mixing opportunities.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>
</section>


<section>
	<h2>Generate Complementary Color<span>complement( );</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		<p>Generate your second color without having to guess what will work. Thanks to science and wavelengths, we know that this works. The opposition of these two colors stimulate your photoreceptor cells in a good way!</p>
		<p>Finally! A different color - now hue separates elements from each other and a layout can be seen.</p>
	</div>
	<div>
		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

	</div>
	<div>
		
		<p>The complement to any color is always 180 degrees across on the other side of the color wheel. If you've ever wondered why it's the color wheel instead of a color line, this is part of that answer. Remember that the color wheel is our visual documentation for color relationships. <br> Fun fact, if you mix complementary colors, they'll cancel each other out and you'll end up with a neutral gray.</p>
		
	</div>
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Color Relationship Established by Mixing<span>harmonious-mix( );</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		
		<p>Establish a color relationship by mixing them together. This makes the colors look like they're under similar lighting conditions.</p>
		<p>Here, you see less saturated hues, with a clear relationship between each other.</p>
		</div>
		<div>
			<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

		</div>
		<div>
			
			<div>
				<p>Our eyes may be legacy systems, but they are really good at spotting patterns, especially things that look like they don't belong in a set.</p>
				<p>This mixing method is another way we can simulate lighting and color found in nature. It's a bit more complicated, but my favorite way of explaining it is this: Everything outside has some "yellow" mixed in from the sunshine during the day. Same thing happens when everyone and everything looks bad in photos taken under the glow of green flourescent lights - there is green added to all of the colors you're looking at, including adding a green glow to your skin if you're standing under the flourescent light yourself. Whether it looks good or bad, this color (light) mixing creates a visual harmony. We don't really notice it when it's there, but we really notice its absence.</p>
				<p>When you're painting, you want to simulate similar lighting conditions for a scene, and that effect is accomplished mixing a bit of one color into the other. Mixing different ratios of the same colors will usually generate a matching color palette.</p>
				<p>How do I decide what to do? Thanks to art school and science, I know that cool colors have lower luminosity than warm colors, and will dominate in mixes, with yellow being the lightest color. For example, a touch of blue will really affect yellow, whereas you can add a lot of yellow to blue before it is affected. So, here is this decision making in function form - I am weighing different colors differently when mixing.</p>
	</div>
		
		
		
</div>
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Create Neutrals<span>mix-neutral( ); lighten( ); darken( );</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		
		
		<p>Let your chosen color pop (in other words, don't exhaust your eyes by making them process non-stop intense chromatic colors!) by surrounding it with neutrals. Desaturate the painter way: by mixing complementary colors! Then, vary that neutral's lightness to create a highlight and a shadow.</p>
		<p>Making the complementary color neutrals will help the 'call to action' color you selected stand out - notice how much the button in the top right "pops" all of a sudden. Make things "pop" by making other things around them not pop.</p>
	</div>
	<div>
		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

	</div>
	<div>
		
		
		
		<p>We can do the same for our primary color too. More neutrals to work with.</p>
		<p>Doesn't it seem like we went too far with this whole making things neutral? Now, nothing "pops"! But, on the plus side, none of this seems to be irritating any eyeballs, either. Remember that our eyes don't like to handle seeing everything our computers are capable of rendering.</p>
	</div>
	<div>
		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

	</div>
	<div>
		
		<div>
			<p>The colors are way too intense at their full saturation for our eyes to handle. If all the colors are bright, none of the colors are bright.</p>
			<p>I picked my starting color for a reason -  I want that to be the heart of my design! That means the complementary color should support the chosen color, and we do that by mixing neutrals. Our eyes don't really handle saturated colors very well next to other saturated colors. Our eyes get confused at the edges - is it this color or the other one? Ahh both! We end up seeing optical illusions. Just give your eyes a break between super strong saturated colors with neutrals so they don't stress out about that much visual information. At the very minimum a rule of thumb is that your viewport should have 33% neutral space (white, desaturated, or black colors) so your poor eyes can have a break and process the information right. Otherwise you get eye strain!</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Why not just desaturate?<span>mix-neutral( ); lighten( ); darken( );</span></h2>
		<p>You totally can! Desaturate does a great job. But, I think not only is it important to understand what "desaturate" means. How would you desaturate a real color in the real world? Remember, you want "ugly" colors for your neutrals! You want to create bland and forgettable colors that recede into the background. These ugly duckling colors are how you get those other call to actions and buttons "pop"!</p>

		<h3>Primary and complementary Colors</h3>
			
			
		<h3>Mixed neutrals</h3>
			
			


		<h3>Desaturated neutrals</h3>
			
			

		<div>
			
			<p>Even though these may look "ugly", neutral colors are the heart of any painting, and that is the case on the web, too. Notice that the same decisions are …</p></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/">http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26225339</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 15:07:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Do We Talk About When We Talk About Dashboards? (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 64 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26224846">thread link</a>) | @sebg
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://alper.datav.is/publications/dashboards/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alper.datav.is/publications/dashboards/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
      <p>Dashboards have long been the much maligned visualization vehicle of choice for decision-making in commercial and governmental situations.  While the visualization research community has concentrated much of its effort on visual analytics, the commercial success and widespread use of dashboards begs more attention.  Critically, dashboards are becoming many peoples’ direct connection to “big data” sources, enabling data democratization and wider access to data.</p>

<p>In this paper, we explore the genre of dashboards through a two-prong approach.  We survey the existing literature in business, marketing, and related fields to capture the relevant factors to consider when designing appropriate dashboards and their tools for consumption by different parties, all of which have differing levels of visualization literacy, data literacy, and decision agency.  We also collect examples of dashboard designs based on the dimensions derived from our literature search, and identify different clusters of dashboard designs with similar analysis goals, audiences, and decision support.</p>

<p>We call ourselves the “dashboard conspiracy:” a truly diverse collection of authors across Tableau Research, Microsoft Research, and Simon Fraiser University.</p>

<p><em>This work was presented at <a href="http://ieeevis.org/year/2018/welcome">IEEE VIS 2018</a> in Berlin, Germany.</em></p>

<p><em>This work was discussed in an half-hour datastori.es podcast, <a href="https://datastori.es/135-the-dashboard-conspiracy-with-lyn-bartram-and-alper-sarikaya/">give it a listen</a>!</em></p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alper.datav.is/publications/dashboards/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26224846</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:22:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[JSON with Commas and Comments]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 155 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26224255">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<p><em>Summary: JWCC is a minimal extension to the widely used JSON file format with
(1) optional commas after the final element of arrays and objects and (2) C/C++
style comments. These two features make it more suitable for human-editable
configuration files, without adding so many features that it’s incompatible
with numerous other (deliberate and accidental) existing JSON extensions.</em></p>

<h2 id="extensibility">Extensibility</h2>

<p>The Peter Principle is the half-joking, half-serious observation that people
get promoted to their level of incompetence, because being competent at level
<code>N</code> leads to being promoted to level <code>N+1</code>.</p>

<p>My colleague Simon Morris made a similar observation about software complexity:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Software has a Peter Principle. If a piece of code is comprehensible, someone
will extend it, so they can apply it to their own problem. If it’s
incomprehensible, they’ll write their own code instead. Code tends to be
extended to its level of incomprehensibility.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="the-many-json-extensions">The Many JSON Extensions</h3>

<p>There’s a similar story with file formats. If they’re comprehensible, they’ll
get extended. JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) is this article’s example. The
<a href="https://json.org/">original specification</a> fits on a single page, either as
text or diagrams. The file format is simple and ubiquitous. Therefore, there
are many extensions - supersets of JSON. Here’s just a few (including two
slightly different extensions both called “JSONC”):</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://json5.org/">JSON5</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://komkom.github.io/">JSONC</a> #1</li>
  <li><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/languages/json#_json-with-comments">JSONC</a> #2</li>
  <li><a href="https://hjson.github.io/">HJSON</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/lightbend/config/blob/master/HOCON.md">HOCON</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Suprisingly, <a href="https://yaml.org/">YAML</a> is also a superset of JSON. Not just
conceptually, but also in the sense that valid JSON files are also valid YAML
files (although there’s some divergence about whether duplicate keys are
legitimate). As a bonus, if you use YAML, then to paraphrase <a href="http://regex.info/blog/2006-09-15/247">Jamie
Zawinski</a>: now you have <a href="https://noyaml.com/">NO
problems</a>.</p>

<h3 id="wandering-off-the-specification">Wandering Off the Specification</h3>

<p>There are also informal supersets-of-JSON in widespread use, sometimes more by
accident than by design. The Chromium web browser’s <a href="https://source.chromium.org/chromium/chromium/src/+/master:base/json/json_reader.h;l=27;drc=d0919138b7951c1a154cf802a68aad7904b6f4c9">JSON parser goes
off-spec</a>
in a number of ways. The timeline could have been:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Some developer long ago (perhaps in a yak-shaving hurry) wrote or
copy/pasted some parsing code that was accidentally too lenient, allowing a
superset-of-JSON. Perhaps they re-used existing code that handled C-style
string escapes, like the <code>"\n"</code> in <code>"line\nbreak"</code>, without realizing that
it also unescaped <code>"\v"</code>, valid in a C string but not a JSON string.</li>
  <li>People use the software. They write first-party and third-party JSON for it.
Some of it is actually malformed (e.g. they have <code>"\v"</code> inside strings) but
tests (manual and automatic) usually check that new features work, not that
all the slightly-incorrect things are rejected. Nobody notices at the time.</li>
  <li>Years pass. <a href="https://www.hyrumslaw.com/">Hyrum’s Law</a> slowly kicks in. We
can no longer tighten this custom JSON parser implementation to follow the
spec more strictly because too many things (in unknown places) will break.</li>
</ol>

<p>This also affects our ability to replace one JSON library with another. For
example, we might want to switch from a C++-based JSON parser to a Rust-based
one, because of its security benefits. If the upstream Rust library chooses to
follow the spec diligently (which is a perfectly reasonable position) then it
would ‘break’ our apps that have inadvertently relied on the previous
looser-than-the-spec implementation.</p>

<p>We could carry local patches, but that isn’t free. Upstream fuzz-testing
infrastructure only exercises the unmodified library, not our patched flavor.
Future upstream changes may also invalidate the downstream patch, possibly in
subtle ways. An upstream “this new unsafe block is OK because it’s a private
implementation detail and nothing in this crate does X” comment might not be
aware that our out-of-tree patch does X to its internals.</p>

<h3 id="quirks">Quirks</h3>

<p>The Wuffs library approach is to expose
<a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/blob/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/doc/note/quirks.md">quirks</a>: runtime
configuration options to go off-spec in various ways so that Wuffs’
implementation can be a drop-in replacement for other implementations, without
the need for downstream patches.</p>

<p>Wuffs has <a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/blob/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/std/json/decode_quirks.wuffs">20 JSON
quirks</a>
so far. As always, there are trade-offs. They’re not free (in terms of
maintenance cost) and have super-linear complexity: that file’s comments also
has 12 call-outs to the subtleties of combining two particular quirks.</p>

<p>Here’s an example of the emergent complexity when combining two simple-sounding
JSON extensions. The first one adds C++-style <code>/* slash-star block comments */</code>
and <code>// double-slash line comments</code>. The second one packs multiple top-level
values in a single stream, separated by line breaks.</p>

<p>That second extension - by itself and when holding minified, whitespace-free
‘vanilla’ (non-extended) JSON - plays well with Unix’s traditional
line-oriented tools. It is sometimes known as Line-Delimited JSON
(<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON_streaming#Line-delimited_JSON">LDJSON</a>),
Newline-Delimited JSON (<a href="http://ndjson.org/">NDJSON</a>) and JSON Lines
(<a href="http://jsonlines.org/">JSONL</a>). But “one value per line” tools’ assumptions
can break if slash-star comments can also contain blank lines.</p>

<p>Here’s another question (let’s call it the ‘end of comment’ question). Is the
<code>'\n'</code> at the end of of a <code>// double-slash line comment</code> actually part of the
comment? At first, this sounds merely philosophical. Comments are ignored and,
in ‘vanilla’ JSON, all whitespace is ignored, so why the distinction?</p>

<p>The ‘right’ answer to that ‘end of comment’ question isn’t obvious, but it can
affect whether a line comment at the end of a multi-value stream should end in
1 or 2 <code>'\n'</code> bytes. Ideally the answer should be self-consistent with whether
a line comment at the end of file must end with the <code>'\n'</code> or whether the
implicit EOF (end-of-file) alone suffices. See also the <a href="http://seriot.ch/parsing_json.php">“Parsing JSON is a
Minefield”</a> and <a href="https://nullprogram.com/blog/2019/12/28/">“Unintuitive JSON
Parsing”</a> articles for how subtle a
‘simple’ format like JSON can be.</p>

<p>Wuffs makes one particular choice for that ‘end of comment’ question. Its
particular choice probably isn’t that important, more that it made a concious
and documented choice.</p>

<h3 id="clarity-not-terseness">Clarity, not Terseness</h3>

<p>Some general advice, when designing a new file format or extending an existing
one, is keep some room for future extensions. For example, allowing unquoted
strings (writing <code>foo</code> instead of <code>"foo"</code>), is certainly convenient, but
re-defining <code>undefined</code> or <code>datetime</code> without quotes, from invalid JSON syntax
to valid some-extension-of-JSON strings, rules out a future extension adding
new ‘keywords’.</p>

<p><a href="https://cbor.io/">CBOR</a> is binary at the wire format level (unlike textual
JSON) but naturally extends JSON at the object model level. It also has an
<code>undefined</code> concept separate from <code>null</code>, and <code>undefined</code> can be a map key. We
couldn’t do the ‘obvious’ CBOR-to-some-extended-JSON conversion if <code>undefined</code>,
without quotes, was already repurposed to mean a string.</p>

<p>I find it suprising that, <a href="https://github.com/lightbend/config/blob/master/HOCON.md#unquoted-strings">in
HOCON</a>,
“<code>truefoo</code> parses as the boolean token <code>true</code> followed by the unquoted string
<code>foo</code>. However, <code>footrue</code> parses as the unquoted string <code>footrue</code>”.</p>

<p>It can also be helpful for a <a href="https://github.com/search?q=return.flase+extension%3Apy">typo like
<code>flase</code></a> to be picked
up early as a syntax error (without needing schemas or type checking) instead
of silently accepted (as a string, not a bool). This can otherwise be
especially dangerous if further processed in a weakly-typed programming
language where any non-empty string is ‘truthy’.</p>

<p><code>[a b c]</code> is invalid ‘vanilla’ JSON syntax, but in the various extended-JSON
variants, is it a list with three 1-byte strings or one 5-byte string? Or is it
one 3-byte string because three 1-byte strings are implicitly
whitespace-delimited and also then implicitly concatenated? Any particular
answer can be consistent in its own world, but different JSON extensions make
different choices. This can be confusing when software grows large enough (or
gains enough transitive dependencies) to have to speak multiple JSON
extensions.</p>

<p>These days, when I’m programming in C/C++ or Go, I often add unnecessary
parentheses in expressions like <code>(a * b) + c</code>. Even though they’re redundant
because of well-defined operator precedence rules, different programming
languages have different precedence rules and getting the precedence wrong can
lead to <a href="https://github.com/jbangert/nail/issues/7">hard-to-spot bugs</a>. The
Wuffs language actually <a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/blob/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/doc/wuffs-the-language.md#operators">rejects a bare <code>a * b +
c</code></a>
and you have to parenthesize the multiplication or the addition.</p>

<p>Similarly, for JSON-like documents, I prefer the clarity of either <code>["a", "b",
"c"]</code> or <code>["a b c"]</code>, even if it means a little extra typing. Reading is more
important than writing for code and configuration, especially when multiple
people or long periods of time are involved.</p>

<h2 id="introducing-jwcc">Introducing JWCC</h2>

<p>Having said all of that, here is yet another superset-of-JSON, called JWCC
(JSON With Commas and Comments). It is a minimal extension. As its name
suggests, there are only two new features:</p>

<ul>
  <li>“Commas” lets you optionally have a comma after the final element of an array
or an object: <code>[1,2,3,]</code>. When you format one element per line, it’s easier
to insert and remove elements (and eyeball the diffs) when you don’t have to
fiddle with any commas (or lack of commas) on adjacent but otherwise
unrelated lines.</li>
  <li>“Comments” lets you have C++-style <code>/* slash-star block comments */</code> and <code>//
double-slash line comments</code>, anywhere where ‘vanilla’ JSON allows whitespace.
Line comments must end with a <code>'\n'</code> byte, even at the end of the file.</li>
</ul>

<p>To be clear, while every JSON file is valid JWCC, this is a new file format. It
just happens to be very familiar if you (or your software) already speak JSON.
Yes, Doug Crockford <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150105080225if_/https://plus.google.com/+DouglasCrockfordEsq/posts/RK8qyGVaGSr">deliberately removed comments from
JSON</a>
but people keep putting them back in. If we’re going to have comment-enriched
JSON (e.g. for human-editable configuration files), we might as well have a
standard one. Cue <a href="https://xkcd.com/927/">XKCD #927 “Standards”</a>.</p>

<h3 id="cc-implementation">C/C++ Implementation</h3>

<p><a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs">Wuffs</a>’ JSON library (availble as a C or C++
API) can decode either ‘vanilla’ JSON or JWCC, using its quirks mechanism.
<a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/tree/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/example/jsonptr"><code>jsonptr</code></a>
is a command line tool (a JSON formatter) that uses this library. By default,
it speaks spec-compliant ‘vanilla’ JSON:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ echo '[1,2,/*hello*/3,]' | jsonptr
[
    1,
    2
json: bad input
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It has a JWCC mode:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ echo '[1,2,/*hello*/3,]' | jsonptr -jwcc
[
    1,
    2,
    /*hello*/
    3,
]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It can also convert from JWCC syntax to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html">https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26224255</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 13:30:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Virtual passport app presents real data risk, experts warn]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26223347">thread link</a>) | @pseudolus
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/passport-application-online-program-1.5920625 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/passport-application-online-program-1.5920625">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Canadian privacy experts are concerned the federal government's plan to develop an online passport application process could put&nbsp;personal information at risk and open a new angle of attack for fraudsters.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.4612031.1536417303!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/passport.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>IBM Canada's digital passport application platform is expected to begin testing in three months, and could be ready for use as early as 2022.<!-- --> <!-- -->(John Badcock/CBC)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Canadian privacy experts are concerned the federal government's plan to develop an online passport application process could put&nbsp;personal information at risk and open a new angle of attack for fraudsters.</p>  <p>IBM Canada has been awarded the&nbsp;$1.5-million contract to create software that would allow Canadians to apply for a passport using their&nbsp;smartphones, tablets or&nbsp;computers.</p>  <p>The new platform would also allow applicants to&nbsp;pay fees and upload their passport photos securely, according to a statement from Immigration, Refugees and Citizenship Canada (IRCC).</p>    <blockquote><span><span><svg version="1.1" focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="30px" height="25px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g display="none"><g display="inline"> <path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg>They will attempt to&nbsp;exploit the program very quickly, very intensely to obtain the most fraudulent passports they can in the least amount of time.<svg focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="23px" height="22px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g display="none"><g display="inline"><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg></span><cite>- Benoît&nbsp;Dupont, l'Université de Montréal</cite></span></blockquote>    <p>But privacy and data protection experts worry that personal information may be stored on foreign servers, providing an appealing target to criminals.</p>  <p>Sébastien Gambs, a professor in the information technology department of l'Université de Québec à Montréal&nbsp;and Canada Research Chair on privacy and data protection, said there are real&nbsp;concerns about&nbsp;where the data will be stored, a detail neither the government nor IBM Canada has divulged, though the tender identifies Amazon Web Services (AWS), the cloud computing branch of the American online retail giant.</p>  <p>"Even when we do business with an American company that agrees to store data within Canada, under the [U.S.] CLOUD Act, data could eventually be transferred out of the country," Gambs said in French.</p>  <p>In a statement, AWS said its clients retain full ownership and control of their data, including who may access that information.</p>  <p>In a separate statement, IRCC said "the privacy of Canadians and the safety of their personal information will be an absolute priority."</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_300/tech-cloud.JPG 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_460/tech-cloud.JPG 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_620/tech-cloud.JPG 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/tech-cloud.JPG 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_1180/tech-cloud.JPG 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/tech-cloud.JPG"></p></div><figcaption>Amazon Web Services (AWS) says its clients retain full control over the data it stores.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Ivan Alvarado/Reuters)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>Canadian passports highly valued</h2>  <p>Benoît Dupont, a criminology professor at l'Université de Montréal and Canada Research Chair in cybersecurity, said the passport app will likely be a major target for fraudsters&nbsp;eager to get their hands on&nbsp;Canadian passports and the mobility that comes with them.</p>  <p>"That's very attractive for organized crime groups who specialize in human trafficking," Dupont said in French. "They will attempt to&nbsp;exploit the program very quickly, very intensely to obtain the most fraudulent passports they can in the least amount of time."</p>  <p>But&nbsp;Gambs said any virtual application will likely have extra&nbsp;steps built in to protect against hackers.</p>  <p>"As soon as we're doing things remotely, verifying somebody's identity becomes much more difficult," he said. "The government will definitely need to collect more personal information in order to verify an applicant's identity."</p>  <h2>'Vicious cycle': PIPSC</h2>  <p>The Professional Institute of the Public Services (PIPSC) said this tender should never have gone out to the private sector when it could have been developed in-house by public servants, as was done with the online tax portal.</p>  <p>"It's a vicious cycle. Instead of developing resources internally, we go externally," said&nbsp;Stéphane Aubry, vice-president of PIPSC. "Then we don't have the needed expertise internally,&nbsp;which&nbsp;unfortunately, over the years, fades and makes it so we need to contract out."</p>  <p>PIPSC said the project raises <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/phoenix-pay-system-cost-report-1.5138036">the spectre of the Phoenix pay system fiasco</a>, which also involved IBM.&nbsp;IBM Canada will be required to train and support IRCC employees in running the new passport system, according to the tender documents.</p>  <p>In 2020, the government issued just 897,401 passports, compared to 2.6 million the year before. For the first four months of the pandemic, Service Canada was only providing critical passport services for urgent travel.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Nevertheless, the Canadian Anti-Fraud Centre received 1,806 reports of passport-related fraud last year.</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/passport-application-online-program-1.5920625</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26223347</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 11:36:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ethereum Isn't Fun Anymore]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 285 | Comments 592 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26222709">thread link</a>) | @timdaub
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://timdaub.github.io/2021/02/22/ethereum-isnt-fun-anymore/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://timdaub.github.io/2021/02/22/ethereum-isnt-fun-anymore/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><strong>Ethereum isn't fun anymore. There I said it.</strong> And although, the last time I developed an app using it has been more than a year ago, I stand by my word. <strong>Developing dapps on Ethereum has become annoying</strong>. Here's why:</p>
<p><img src="https://timdaub.github.io/assets/images/pedro.gif"></p>
<h2 id="i-used-ethereum-before-it-was-cool.">I used Ethereum before it was cool.</h2>
<p>I know; it's such a hipster statement. But it's true. Ethereum has stopped being edgy. It has transitioned out of its niche to build a world computer. Its community has become huge, and I stopped knowing most faces. Where there was a feeling of revolution and new beginnings, now there are people in suits talking corporate. Within just a few years, it went from <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/DaddyDeFi/DaiDaddy">DAI daddys</a> and only <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.molochdao.com/">half-ironic satanist cults</a> to lending, insurance, and trade protocols.</p>
<p>"What's Ethereum's killer app?" we asked ourselves not long ago. Now we know. It's the world's best publicly-accessible settlement platform for financial transactions. In a way, that's exciting. The markets think so too. But for anyone else that worked with Ethereum but outside of financial applications, it's somewhat of a letdown.</p>
<p><img src="https://timdaub.github.io/assets/images/homer.gif"></p>
<h2 id="how-do-you-do-fellow-ethereans">How do you do, fellow Ethereans?</h2>
<p>I think it must have been around the time of the last big crypto bubble when Monero enthusiasts called for "Making Monero cheap again."</p>
<p>Monero, being the anonymous digital currency that had indeed just legit use cases apart from the occasional rumors that entangled it in drug trafficking, had suddenly become too expensive for everyday use. Realizing the glaring threat of becoming too valuable, its core developers went on to fix the problem by campaigning at CoinDesk's yearly industry gathering Consensus.</p>
<p>They announced the "Monero Enterprise Alliance." An inside joke, supposed to piss off other projects that had started to take themselves too seriously. Being slightly confused that day myself, I now can't recall if the effort had ever been successful. But in any case, I can't recommend buying Monero. It's useless.</p>
<h2 id="gas-prices-are-too-damn-high">Gas prices are too damn high!</h2>
<p><img src="https://timdaub.github.io/assets/images/deepfried_high_rents.jpg"></p>
<p>There was a phase in my short career as an Ethereum developer where I looked at Etherscan's "<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://etherscan.io/contractsVerified">Verified Contracts</a>" page all day long to find vulnerabilities in newly uploaded contracts. "My name's Tim and I'm an etherholic!"</p>
<p>It was addictive. I ended up calling a few of those contracts, failing to cause any havoc, sadly. But it was so much fun! Back when transaction fees were still affordable on Ethereum, building projects was great. We started up Ganache and our favorite text editor (vim). The only choice we had was Solidity. And off we went.</p>
<p>Now, building Ethereum applications has become painful. <a href="https://timdaub.github.io/2020/09/08/web3/">web3 is a stupid idea</a>. Layer 2 isn't ready. Neither is Eth 2.0. And there are still <a href="https://timdaub.github.io/2019/02/28/poa/">many reasons to NOT ship to a Proof of Authority network</a>. Finally, gas prices are too damn high!</p>
<p>How do we move on from here?</p>
<h2 id="i-need-a-hero.">I need a hero.</h2>
<p><strong>I need a hero, and by that, I mean that I need a usable methodology for building scaleable decentralized apps.</strong> Yes, you've heard that right. We don't need more "Ethereum killers" that can do 10x more tx/s than Ethereum. Those are useless.</p>
<p>Instead, we need an approach for the average Joe developer to create their idea within the Ethereum ecosystem without the need for hardcore unproven technologies. I know, you Vitalik will say: "Oh, it's not a problem, we can has '<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://vitalik.ca/general/2020/03/21/garbled.html">Garbled Circuits</a>' and zkrollups." But I'm telling you that no sane Joe will touch that shit without a serious cryptographic specialist by their side.</p>
<p>We want what we stayed for initially: Good ol smart contracts. But right now, they're too damn expensive to innovate.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://timdaub.github.io/2021/02/22/ethereum-isnt-fun-anymore/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26222709</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 10:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Start with a Niche]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26222313">thread link</a>) | @tablet
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://fibery.io/blog/start-with-a-niche/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fibery.io/blog/start-with-a-niche/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The most popular products don’t become mass popular overnight. It’s a process. Usually, their popularity is uneven, they are unknown in some niches, but very popular in other niches.</p><p>When you start a product, sometimes you know the niche already and can easily define target customers. However, in many cases, you just don’t and try to find the niche and this miraculous niche-market-fit. </p><p>One of the most common mistakes is to ignore niches and just try to attract all kinds of customers. It’s essential to find 1-2 ponds to start from and then expand to the other, larger, and more promising lakes and oceans 🚰 → 🛁 → 🌊.</p><p>Here are a couple, maybe surprising examples, that demonstrate how popular products took off. </p><h4>Electrical telegraph (1837)</h4><p>Its adoption was not easy, since it was not clear what are the benefits for commercial institutions. Stockbrokers and reporters got the benefits first. They understood that fast information transition increases efficiency and helps to get an edge. In a short term, all major news agencies and major stock markets were connected to the telegraph. </p><h4>Telephone (1876)</h4><p>Telephones were adopted by police departments and fire stations. Fast reaction to crime reports and fires was great, but the telegraph was not enough. You have to have two-ways communication to get some details that the sender maybe is not expecting to report initially. </p><h4>Phonograph (1877)</h4><p>Try to guess the first niche market for the phonograph. Rich music lovers? Nope. First phonographs were coin-machines in bars. Throw a nickel and enjoy Stephen Foster ballads.</p><h4>Car (1886)</h4><p>Cars are almost among the lucky exception to the niche rule. However, there was still one group of people in the USA that moved from horses to cars enormously fast — farmers. Cars just expanded the borders of farmers’ social life and business activities. Suddenly you can buy goods, not from a local dealer, but a dealer in a remote town (much cheaper). Suddenly you can visit a town and watch a movie. These benefits were not important for the urban population, for they were life-changers for the rural population. Nevertheless, cars were adopted in cities quite fast as well.</p><blockquote><p>In addition, the car delivered you to the door and was faster than a horse-and-buggy, thus allowing longer trips in shorter time. Farmers had traditionally felt guilty about taking such trips, even when the time was available. </p></blockquote><h4>Radio (1895)</h4><p>Radio was immediately adopted by the British Royal Navy, they thought that radio can speed up communication between ships and were right. Fun fact: in 1912 Titanic sent CQD (distress signal), however, <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/article/why-titanic-first-call-help-not-sos-signal">radio receiver was turned off on the closest ship</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Meanwhile, the closest ship, Californian, didn’t receive Titanic’s distress calls at all. Its wireless operator had switched off his receiver and gone to bed after Phillips told him to shut up.</p></blockquote><h4>VisiCalc (Excel predecessor, 1979)</h4><p>First, it was adopted by accountants. Businessmen and analysts joined the party much later. Accountants just saw the value right away (and quite many people pirchased Apple II just to get <a href="https://thenewstack.io/how-visicalcs-spreadsheets-changed-the-world/">VisiCalc</a>):</p><blockquote><p>Like an accountant, I remember showing it to one around here and he started shaking and said, “That’s what I do all week. I could do it in an hour.” … I meet these people now, they come up to me and say, “I gotta tell you, you changed my life. You made accounting fun.”</p></blockquote><h4>Facebook (2004)</h4><p>Everybody knows that Facebook got its popularity in universities first. Everybody knows the rest of the story.</p><blockquote><p>Within 24 hours, 1,200 Harvard students had signed up, and after one month, over half of the undergraduate population had a profile. The network was promptly extended to other Boston universities, the Ivy League and eventually all US universities</p></blockquote><hr><p>Can you start without any niche in mind? Yes, you can, but this is just hard. The most problematic part is marketing. Who are your ideal customers? How to reach them? How to target your message? <strong>Product is the message</strong>, so without proper marketing startup success chances are low. </p><h4>My experience</h4><p>In Fibery we did our first release in April 2020 as a general work management tool. We were not sure in what types of companies it will work better and what use cases will be more valuable. In just a month it became clear that we had all kinds of leads from all kinds of companies. Leads demanded all kinds of improvements that just didn’t form a sane strategy. </p><p>We quickly <a href="https://fibery.io/blog/chronicles-21/">decided to select a single niche and focus on it</a>. The niche we choose was product companies from 20 to 200 people. And it made everything much simpler. Finally, we can quite accurately say what features are important and what features are not so important, what is our value proposition, who is our ideal lead (Product Ops or CPO). It took us 9 months to prepare the <a href="https://fibery.io/product-management">second release</a>, but in this niche Fibery can fly much better, I believe. </p><p>OK, niche strategy looks convincing, but how to find the niche? We used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_law">Conway’s law</a>, and it’s just partially a joke. We’ve reviewed a couple of alternatives and selected one we knew best and were confident that our product will provide a significant value boost. There were other alternatives, like education space or digital agencies space, but our knowledge here was not deep enough. It means we should rely on some domain experts, etc. It’s not a huge problem, but we also did not feel that these niches are better.</p><p>A startup should be an experimentation facility that hypothesizes, executes, and measures the results. The faster you can do it, the faster you find your niche. Why it took us 9 months to make this niche release? In fact we spend time to create a niche-probing framework. Now we can asseble solutions for various niches in 1-2 weeks and check initial response in 1-2 months. If the first niche will not be successful, we at least have a decent experimentation framework 🧬.</p></section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fibery.io/blog/start-with-a-niche/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26222313</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 09:05:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Indian Government Breached, Massive Amount of Critical Vulnerabilities]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 293 | Comments 65 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26221607">thread link</a>) | @astroanax
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A writeup detailing the vulnerability reporting process that took place after Sakura Samurai had breached the Indian Government</p><p>Reading time: 6 minutes.</p><div>
      

<p>Sakura Samurai knew that the Indian Government operated an RVDP (Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure Program). <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> put a list together of initial assets in scope for Sakura Samurai to legally test. <a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a> reported that he had found sensitive data and was able to breach police assets. <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> was working in the enumeration processes with his friend, <a href="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001" title="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001">Zultan Holder</a> [not an active Sakura Samurai member] and identified a slew of various attack vectors, immediately resulting in the exposure of many pairs of credentials for databases and other pertinent applications.</p>
<p>The team was informed of the initial enumeration results as they continued to work on the list of assets within scope, while also further jumping into the research and began performing analysis on the sensitive data, identifying additional vectors of attack, exposed PII, and even more credentials.</p>
<p>Sakura Samurai team members included <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner">Aubrey Cottle</a>, and<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking"> John Jackson</a></p>
<p>In total, the following vulnerabilities were identified, in no specific order:</p>
<ul>
<li>35 Separate Instances of Exposed Credential Pairs (Servers, Important Applications, etc)</li>
<li>3 Instances of Sensitive File Disclosure</li>
<li>5 Exposed private-key pairs for servers</li>
<li>13K+ PII Records [and those are only the records that we were inadvertently exposed to]</li>
<li>Dozens of Exposed Sensitive Police Reports</li>
<li>Session Hijacking Chained via Multiple Vulnerabilities, resulting in the compromise of extremely sensitive government systems</li>
<li>Remote Code Execution on a sensitive financial server; a server that contained large backups of Financial Records</li>
</ul>

<p>First and foremost, it is important to note that so many Critical findings had been identified during our testing that we cannot possibly include all of the vulnerabilities without making this writeup unnecessarily heavy. Therefore, we have opted to include small snippets of repetitive findings in this section. Many variations of application and server credentials also were obtained but the point has already been made.</p>
<p><strong>Exposed Database Credentials</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/db-creds.png" alt=""><br>
<strong>Private SSH Keys</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/priv-ssh.png" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Sensitive File Exposure</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/sens-file-exp.png" alt=""><br>
<strong>Exposed PHP Mailer Credentials</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/mailer.png" alt=""></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a> identified an application that resulted in a vulnerability that allowed him to access Sensitive Police Records, containing PII of individuals listed on the report. In addition, sample forensic reports and forensic tooling that is used by the police department was identified by Willis. The exposure of citizen’s sensitive information, some being victims, is a sensitive subject within itself and highly alarming.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/police.png" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/police2.png" alt=""><br>
Shortly after, <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> found a vulnerability that resulted in the exposure of 14,000+ user records. The records included a wide range of sensitive information, including full name, contact info, employee’s department, date of birth, etc. These exposed records along with other various SQL server dumps and Rob’s Police Record Exposure is enough to constitute a data breach without even logging into any of the servers.</p>
<p>Henry identified many credential pairs which could have resulted in even more exploitation of many other people. The PII identified is a small sample of a much larger issue.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/14k-records.png" alt=""><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">John Jackson</a> was able to identify a relevant Remote Code Execution Vulnerability, affecting an out-of-date application residing on one of the government servers. The remote code execution vulnerability allowed for complete access to sensitive files on the server, including the ability to exfiltrate complete backups of financial records [although data exfiltration wasn’t performed to avoid unnecessary action]</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/rce1.png" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/rce2.png" alt=""><br>
Finally, <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://www.twitter.com/Kirtaner">Aubrey Cottle</a> identified the presence of what appeared to be an extremely important application being hosted by the same server that John had achieved successful Remote Code Execution on. Cottle then chained together multiple vulnerabilities in conjunction with the Remote Code Execution vulnerability, resulting in the ability to hijack any user’s session on the web application. The application contained troves of sensitive government data and could have given a threat actor the ability to perform highly-critical, admin-based government actions.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/session-chained.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Even though the Indian Government has a RVDP in place, we didn’t feel comfortable disclosing the vulnerabilities right away. The hacking process was far from the standard situation of business-as-usual security research. In total, our report compounded to a massive 34 page report worth of vulnerabilities. We knew that our intent was good, but we wanted to ensure that the US Government had eyes on the situation. Sakura Samurai coordinated with the <a href="https://twitter.com/DC3VDP" title="https://twitter.com/DC3VDP">U.S. DoD Vulnerability Disclosure Program (VDP)</a> to assist in facilitating initial conversations of disclosure. <a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">John Jackson</a> spoke with DC3’s Program Manager via email and coordinated on a plan of action.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-1.png" alt=""><br>
Roughly 4 days later, after further communication with the DC3, we felt safe to begin our initial reveal of research on the NCIIPC’s RVDP program.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-2.png" alt=""></p>
<p>In addition, the DC3 also commended the hacking that we did in support of making the cyberspace a better place for everyone.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-3.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Unfortunately, what seemed like a done deal turned out to be quite the unprofessional ride. Any organization knows that fixing breach-worthy vulnerabilities is extremely time sensitive. Once threat actors catch wind of major vulnerabilities against an organization they begin poking on their own, looking for more vectors of attack. Immediately upon revealing that Sakura Samurai was the group responsible for hacking the Indian Government, we followed up with them via Email.</p>
<p><strong>Timeline</strong></p>
<p><strong>2021/02/04</strong> - DC3 begins initial contact with the Indian Government.<br>
<strong>2021/02/08</strong> - Sakura Samurai informs the public that they breached the Government.<br>
<strong>2021/02/08</strong> - Sakura Samurai makes contact with the NCIIPC, noting that the report that they received was a result of their research.<br>
<strong>2021/02/09</strong> - The NCIIPC responds, with a basic acknowledgement and thank you for the research.<br>
<strong>2021/02/09</strong> - Sakura Samurai asks for clarification on patching and the responsibility of breach disclosure to the public.<br>
<strong>2021/02/10</strong> - Sakura Samurai, having received no response, asks for an update on the involved remediation and breach notification processes.<br>
<strong>2021/02/16</strong> - Sakura Samurai once again asks for NCIIPC’s plans for remediation and disclosure.<br>
<strong>2021/02/17</strong> - The NCIIPC makes contact, 7-days later, stating that they will follow up in a short time. Again, we ask about plans of anticipated patching and breach notification to the affected citizens.<br>
<strong>2021/02/19</strong> - In the morning, we ask again about patching and disclosure, 8-hours later and still no response on the matter.<br>
<strong>2021/02/19</strong> - Sakura Samurai reviews the submitted vulnerability report and notes that only about an eighth or less of the submitted Critical Vulnerabilities have been resolved within a two-week period. No notification of breach has occurred even though Government Employees and Indian Citizens are at risk of exploitation from threat actors.</p>

<p>Governments have an obligation to protect the private data of its employees and citizens. In addition, the exposure of proprietary government data can be used for great means of manipulation and for other destructive purposes. While the NCIIPC operates a Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure Program, the recklessness and avoidance of communication represents the complete opposite of a responsible program. A failure to release notification of breach to affected citizens and to patch highly-critical vulnerabilities in a timely manner reflects poorly on the state of their Information Security posture. The clock to patch vulnerabilities began immediately when the DC3 contacted the NCIIPC via Twitter, as it is a highly visible space - one which threat actors avidly monitor.</p>
<p>Sakura Samurai urge the NCIIPC to patch the remainder of the vulnerabilities. The criticality of some of the issues cannot wait weeks or months for adequate resolution.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Check out our website</strong><br>
<a href="https://sakurasamurai.org/" title="https://sakurasamurai.org">https://sakurasamurai.org</a></p>
<p><strong><em>Twitter Links:</em></strong><br>
Main Page<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii" title="https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii">https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii</a><br>
Founders<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">https://twitter.com/johnjhacking</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/nicksahler" title="https://twitter.com/nicksahler">https://twitter.com/nicksahler</a><br>
Members<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner">https://twitter.com/Kirtaner</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">https://twitter.com/rej_ex</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/endingwithali" title="https://twitter.com/endingwithali">https://twitter.com/endingwithali</a><br>
Collaborator<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001" title="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001">https://twitter.com/orpheus9001</a></p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26221607</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 06:57:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Frustrated with Parler deplatforming, I am building a service no one can silence]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 110 | Comments 190 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218900">thread link</a>) | @anon20190221
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<p>This is the first post in this blog, it was published on February 19, 2021.</p>

<h2 id="motivation">Motivation</h2>

<h3 id="censorship">Censorship</h3>

<p>The year of 2020 will be remembered for the pandemic, the BLM movement, and the U.S. elections among other billion of things around the globe. It is funny I even mention the third one considering how little I give a damn about U.S. politics, yet this whole story begins with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parler">Parler</a> deplatforming that happened about a month ago. Let me remind you: Apple, Google, Amazon, and a few other companies terminated their service to the free speech social network for insufficient moderation effectively destroying the platform in a matter of just a couple of days. What the fuck?</p>

<p>OK, let me be clear with my position: I believe every private company has a right to refuse service to anyone, whether an individual or a business, but I also have my own right to despise them for exercising that. What they did was probably legal, but screw them anyway, they failed us. Regardless what these psychopathic corporations like to tell the public, they are only concerned with maximizing shareholder value, and if there is anything  even remotely resembling an image liability (through pressure by political radicals, cancel culture SJWs, you name it), they will not think twice. What disgusts me the most here is neither greed nor hypocrisy but their unwillingness to grow a pair of balls and stand up for freedom of speech.</p>

<p>You see, freedom of speech and expression must be absolute. You cannot have censorship-resistance with exceptions; otherwise, these exceptions could be used to remove or block anything unwanted, not only offensive. This way, the Chinese cannot access Wikipedia because of what originally started as a counter-terrorism measure, and the Russians cannot access LinkedIn because of what originally started as a children protection measure. We cannot deprive humanity of their freedom just because some small fraction of users might, unfortunately, use that freedom to spread offensive content. In the same way, you do not ban electricity because people get electrocuted.</p>

<p>Let us now switch from corporates to governments. Ooh, wee! Do not even get me started on that. And I am not even talking about cases like Google happily not letting people disable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SafeSearch">SafeSearch</a> in Indonesia because its government knows best, that is just the tip of the iceberg. I am talking about political censorship which includes silencing people with torture, gulags, and bullets. Here is the world map of the freedom of the press status:</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/press-freedom.png" alt="2020 Press Freedom Index"></p>

<p>Just look at this mess. Blue tones mean OK-ish, others not so much. This map is <a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/User:NordNordWest">NordNordWest</a>’s work based on the <a href="https://rsf.org/en/ranking">2020 Press Freedom Index</a> and is distributed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/de/legalcode">CC BY-SA 3.0 de</a>. Keep in mind population densities, e.g. there are about 90 times more people per unit area living in Vietnam than Australia. I am actually surprised the U.S. did so well in 2020 considering how badly they wanted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julian_Assange">Mr. Assange</a> to be extradited and executed.</p>

<p>What would you answer your children if they asked you how in the world North Korea still exists in its current form with 25 million Koreans suffering for over 70 years and no one is doing anything about that? Or how about 28 million people in Venezuela? Or 82 million people in Iran? Giving voice to all whistleblowers and activists, especially the ones risking their lives and freedom in hostile environments is the fundamental goal of Pepe.</p>

<h3 id="darknets">Darknets</h3>

<p>There is already <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tor_(anonymity_network)">Tor</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I2P">I2P</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freenet">Freenet</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNUnet">GNUnet</a> etc. We can run emails, message boards, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent">BitTorrent</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kad_network">Kad</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System">IPFS</a> on top of them, maybe even use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethereum">Ethereum</a> smart contracts for decentralized computing. All the technology is there, why bother with something new? Well, first of all, these are all amazing projects, there is nothing wrong with them. The peculiar thing, however, is none of them except BitTorrent (and perhaps Tor) gained much popularity, neither do we see any readily available censorship-resistant communication platforms. Why is that?</p>

<p>I claim there are 2 main reasons for that:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>They are hard to use. The “Unix is user-friendly, it is just picky about who its friends are.” aphorism still lives in most them: you may need to install a bunch of additional software (such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_virtual_machine">JVM</a> or shared libraries) potentially dealing with a dependency hell on some platforms; read through sparse documentation and dead forums on optimal network, security, and sharing settings; carefully configure your router, computer, and client; install, study, and configure applications running on top of the darknet, i.e. repeat the steps. The reason why Tor became popular outside of research was not because it was first, but because of the hacky all-in-one Tor Browser Bundle with sane defaults.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>They prefer purity to practicality. Instead of concentrating manpower on few specific use cases, most existing tools try to conquer the world: a new internet, interplanetary, infrastructure, an application framework, APIs, a Turing-complete language on the blockchain etc. This is great and all, it is general, conceptual, modular, extensible, and stackable—everything we like—but sometimes overengineering is just overengineering given the goal. And our goal here is not to make a technical revolution, but to help as many people as we can communicate without fear of retribution.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>BitTorrent evolved into something that is used by 150 million people worldwide, it seamlessly adopted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_hash_table">DHT</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer_exchange">PEX</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micro_Transport_Protocol">µTP</a>, trackerless <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnet_URI_scheme">magnet links</a>, and people do not even know what the hell it all means. Even though proprietary, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skype">Skype</a> thrived very similarly (at least before it was crippled by Microsoft), millions of its users did not even know what peer-to-peer meant, not to mention how it worked under the hood, it just did. These two systems succeeded not because of luck but rather as a result of some excellent product decisions. We need to learn from that and reiterate.</p>

<h2 id="pepe-overview">Pepe overview</h2>

<h3 id="user-level">User level</h3>

<p>For the messaging platform, I chose to use an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imageboard">imageboard</a> similar to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4chan">4chan</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futaba_Channel">Futaba Channel</a>. While not the most popular type of forum, imageboards are extremely flexible and free of junk like authentication or karma, they promote anonymity in a very practical way, and over 30 million people are already familiar with them. Perhaps, I am not a big fan of their crowded old-school design, but the initial user traction is more important than my sense of beauty, we will refine the looks through time.</p>

<p>That is, the Pepe imageboard is going to be the only application running on top the Pepe darknet, they are in fact inseparable. This way, we can design the network specifically for this one use case. This brings both security and performance benefits. Joining the darknet can be as simple as double clicking the application, and users do not need to install or configure any third-party browsers or proxy servers, they can just go to <a href="http://localhost:8666/">localhost:8666</a> using Chrome, Safari, or whatever they like, and it is going to be safe without any third-party extensions.</p>

<p>Once online, users may browse existing or create new message boards about various topics in any language such as <code>/en/food/</code> or <code>/ja/math/</code>. A board is a collection of threads about something more specific, would it be an idea or a question. A thread has a collection of posts that people send replying to each other. Each post may have one or multiple attachments such as photos, videos, you name it. So that you have an idea of what it looks like, here is a screenshot of a random thread on the 4chan DIY board:</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/4chan-thread.png" alt="4chan thread"></p>

<p>What is fundamentally different with Pepe is moderation. Instead of relying on a centralized entity with a banhammer, each board and thread owner may anonymously moderate their spaces on their own. However, nothing can actually be deleted, it can only be shadowed, and each user decides whether they want to see the light or the full version of the page at any moment in time. People can still reply to shadowed posts inside their own shadowed posts, so no one cannot silence anyone, only maintain order on the light side.</p>

<p>If people are no longer interested in particular threads, they will eventually become forgotten by the network and naturally disappear from their board. But if there is at least one person who is subscribed to or has archived some thread, no one in the world (even Pepe creators) can censor or somehow shut it down without hurting most of the network Pepe is running on top of.</p>

<h3 id="network-level">Network level</h3>

<p>The three biggest problems with 4chan and similar communication platforms are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>They use closed source software so no one can tell how secure everything is and what is really going on there.</li>
  <li>They are centralized, i.e. some individual or business owns the servers and fully controls the whole infrastructure.</li>
  <li>They collect lots of metadata including but not limited to “someone with this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address">IP address</a> posted this at this moment in time”.</li>
</ul>

<p>Mitigating the first problem is the easiest: just use open-source software whenever possible. Regarding the centralization issue, we could switch to a decentralized solution like BitTorrent (imagine each torrent containing a thread with its posts and attachments), but that itself does not help with privacy, people can still see what others are doing. Similarly, we could tackle the privacy issue with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network">VPN</a> or a darknet like Tor or I2P, but that, contrary to popular belief, does not solve the centralization issue in any way. Clearly, we need the best of the two worlds. Let us fuse them together!</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/pepe-routing.png" alt="Pepe routing"></p>

<p>Here is an very simplified walk through how the network works. Imagine Bob is an undercover journalist who wants to anonymously share his report and Alice is a political activist who is interested in the investigation Bob had been doing. It all starts with Bob announcing he has the report:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Bob joins the network and gathers information about random peers on it through the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_hash_table">DHT</a>. This way, Bob discovers hundreds of participants including X and Y. Similarly, Bob registers himself on the network through the DHT so that others …</p></li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/">https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218900</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:28:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TransferWise changes name to Wise]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 237 | Comments 225 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218693">thread link</a>) | @watbe
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<div>
<p>Today, we’re changing our name from TransferWise to Wise.</p>
<p>Our customers now need us for more than money transfers. Sending, spending, and receiving money internationally is too expensive, slow, and inconvenient. We’re fixing that for people and businesses.</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://transferwise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise#transferwise-is-now-wise">skip ahead to see what changes for you</a> (spoiler: not much, right away), but first, let’s go back a bit.</p>
<h2><a href="#a-decade-into-our-mission" id="a-decade-into-our-mission"></a>A decade into our mission</h2>
<p>Ten years ago, Taavet and I set out to fix international money transfers for all of us who’d been overcharged and underserved by banks. We named our idea ‘TransferWise’ — because our early customers were ‘wise’ to know their banks were charging hidden fees in exchange rate markups.</p>
<p>We set ourselves a mission to make money work without borders — to make money move instantly, transparently, conveniently, and — eventually — for free.</p>
<p>Now, we’re a community of 10 million like-minded people and businesses managing money all over the world, saving billions and fighting as hard as ever against hidden fees.</p>
<p>Our multi-currency account and the clever debit card is replacing international banking for many of you. By building this infrastructure for you, we’ve created a platform that more than a dozen banks use today.</p>
<p>You’ve told us for years the problem is bigger than money transfers. Any time money moves into another currency, it’s still a maze of hidden exchange rate markups, high fees, delays, and small print.</p>
<h2><a href="#well-fix-international-banking-together" id="well-fix-international-banking-together"></a>We’ll fix international banking together</h2>
<p>Sending, spending, receiving, and holding money internationally doesn’t work like it should, because the international banking system was built for the past.</p>
<p>For generations, banks have been defined by borders. Traditional bank accounts trap our money in one country, making international lives more difficult and expensive than they need to be. We shouldn’t have to accept this status quo.</p>
<p>Today, we don’t. We’ll fix it with Wise — the world’s most international account. It makes your money borderless — with instant, super-cheap money transfers, a debit card to spend in any currency, account details to get paid in 30+ countries, balances to hold your money safely in 50+ different currencies, multi-currency direct debits, and other revolutionary features.</p>
<h2><a href="#transferwise-is-now-wise" id="transferwise-is-now-wise"></a>TransferWise is now Wise</h2>
<p>Today our name catches up with who we’re already building for — a community of people and businesses with multi-currency lives. Wise is for all of us who live, work, travel, or support family around the world. It’s for those of us who want to cut out the middlemen that hold us back from being truly borderless.</p>
<p>For customers, not too much will change right away. We become “Wise” or “Wise Business” — depending how you use us. You can access your exact same account via <a href="http://wise.com/">wise.com</a>, using your current email and password. You won't need a new account. In a few weeks we will start to redirect transferwise.com to wise.com.</p>
<p>Our logo has changed, and our apps will be renamed. But our icon — the fast flag — remains as a symbol for money without borders. Beyond that, you’ll notice some new colours, words, and designs.</p>
<p>The core experience of using Wise will remain faster, cheaper, and more convenient than anything else. Our mission remains the same. We’re still making — and always will be making — money work without borders.</p>
<p>We’re humbled that 10 million of you already rely on us to help you lead your international lives. We can’t wait to bring the next 100 million of you with us as we continue to build a new, fair, and transparent world of money.</p>
<p>Onwards.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218693</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
