<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 12:45:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 12:45:42 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Modules, Monoliths, and Microservices]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 103 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26247052">thread link</a>) | @kozmico
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://tailscale.com/blog/modules-monoliths-and-microservices/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tailscale.com/blog/modules-monoliths-and-microservices/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <p>Lately, I get people asking me when microservices are a good idea. In <a href="https://apenwarr.ca/log/20201227">systems design explains the world</a>, I talked about big-picture issues like second system effect, innovator’s dilemmas, and more. Can systems design answer the microservices question?</p>
<p>Yes, but you might not like the answers. First, we'll need some history.</p>
<h4 id="what-is-a-microservice">What is a microservice?</h4>
<p>You can find various definitions on the Internet. Here's mine: microservices are the most extreme possible backlash against <em>monoliths</em>.</p>
<p>Monoliths are what happen when you link everything your entire app needs into one giant program and deploy it as one big blob. Monoliths have a long history, going back to frameworks like CGI, Django, Rails, and PHP.</p>
<p>Right away, let's abandon the assumption that a monolith and a fleet of microservices are the only two options. There's a wide and nuanced continuum from "one giant service that does everything" to "infinite tiny services that each do nearly nothing."</p>
<p>If you follow fads, you'll have built a monolith at least once (whether on purpose or because that's what traditional frameworks encouraged you to do), then discovered some problems with monoliths, then heard that microservices are the answer, then started rearchitecting everything as microservices.</p>
<p>But don't follow fads. There are many points in between those extremes. One of them is probably right for you. A better approach starts with where you want to put your <em>interfaces</em>.</p>
<h4 id="boxes-and-arrows">Boxes and arrows</h4>
<p>An interface is the connection between <em>modules.</em> A module is a collection of related code. In systems design, we talk about "boxes and arrows" engineering: modules are the boxes, and interfaces are the arrows.</p>
<p>The deeper question then is: how big are the boxes? How much goes in each box? How do we decide when to split one big box into two smaller ones? What's the best way to connect the boxes? There are many approaches to all this. Nobody quite knows what's best. It's one of the hardest problems in software architecture.</p>
<p>Over the decades, we've evolved through many kinds of "boxes." <a href="https://homepages.cwi.nl/~storm/teaching/reader/Dijkstra68.pdf">Goto statements were "considered harmful"</a> largely because they prevented any hierarchy at all. Then we added functions or procedures; those are very simple boxes, with interfaces (parameters and return codes) between them.</p>
<p>Depending which branch of programming you go down, you then discover recursive functions, combinators, static function prototypes, libraries (statically or runtime-linked), objects (OOP), coroutines, protected virtual memory, processes, threads, JITs, namespaces, sandboxes, chroots, jails, containers, virtual machines, supervisors, hypervisors, microkernels, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unikernel">unikernels</a>.</p>
<p>And that's just the boxes! Once you have boxes isolated from each other, then you need to connect them with arrows. For that, we have ABIs, APIs, syscalls, sockets, RPCs, filesystems, databases, message passing systems, and "virtualized hardware."</p>
<p>If you tried to draw a complete boxes-and-arrows diagram of a modern Unix system (which I won't), it would be wild: functions inside threads inside processes inside containers inside userspace, layered under a kernel, inside a VM, running on hardware in a rack in a datacenter in a cloud provider tied together by an orchestration system, and so on.</p>
<p>Each of those boxes at each of the abstraction layers is somehow isolated from and then connected to some of the others, at the same or other layers. Some are inside others. You couldn't draw an honest version of this picture in a mere two dimensions without lines criss-crossing hopelessly.</p>
<p>This all evolved over decades. Fancy people call it "path dependence." I call it a mess. And let's be clear: most of the mess no longer provides much value.</p>
<p>Instead of focusing on what became very ugly evolutionary results, let's talk about what people were <em>trying</em> to do while they invented all that stuff.</p>
<h4 id="the-quest-for-modularity">The quest for modularity</h4>
<p>The top-line goals of module systems are always the same:</p>
<ol>
<li>Isolate each bit of code from the other bits.</li>
<li>Re-connect those bits only where explicitly intended (through a well-defined interface).</li>
<li>Guarantee that bits you change will still be compatible with the right other bits.</li>
<li>Upgrade, downgrade, and scale some bits without having to upgrade all the other bits simultaneously.</li>
</ol>
<p>The computer industry spends an absolutely immense amount of time messing around, trying to find the perfect balance of all these modularity issues, while still trying to keep development as painless and easy as possible.</p>
<p>We are, in short, not succeeding.</p>
<p>By far the part we're worst at is #1, isolation. If we could truly and efficiently isolate one bit of code from another, the other goals would mostly fall into place. But we simply do not know how.</p>
<p>Isolation is a super hard problem. Goodness knows people have tried. Yet browser sandbox escapes still happen regularly, undetected privilege escalation attacks are simply assumed to exist on every OS, iOS still gets jailbroken periodically, DRM never works (for better or worse), virtual machines and containers regularly have vulnerabilities discovered, and systems like <a href="https://blog.alcide.io/insecure-by-default-kubernetes-networking">k8s have their containers configured insecurely by default</a>.</p>
<p>People have even been known to <a href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2013/02/04/attack-of-week-tls-timing-oracles/">figure out encryption keys on remote servers by sending well-timed packets</a> to them over the Internet. Meanwhile, the most spectacular isolation failures in recent memory were the <a href="https://meltdownattack.com/">Meltdown and Spectre attacks</a>, which allowed any program on a computer, even a javascript app in a web browser, to read the memory of other programs on the same computer, even across sandboxes or virtual machines.</p>
<p>Every new isolation technology goes through a cycle like the following, from optimism to despair:</p>
<ul>
<li>New idea: we'll finally get it right this time, once and for all!</li>
<li>Initial experiments seem to work.</li>
<li>(Users complain that it's even slower and more tedious than the last thing we tried.)</li>
<li>Early fatal flaws are discovered and fixed.</li>
<li>Widespread deployment.</li>
<li>Ever-more-subtle flaws are successively discovered and fixed.</li>
<li>Eventually, we find flaws that we simply don't know how to patch.</li>
<li>Lose hope that efficient isolation is even possible with this method.</li>
<li>But also we can never retire this isolation method because now too many people are depending on it.</li>
<li>Repeat.</li>
</ul>
<p>For example, at this point security people simply don't believe that any of the following (each one the very best technology available at the time) is totally safe:</p>
<ul>
<li>Process isolation and memory protection on a Unix system.</li>
<li>Privilege separation between OS processes when remote code execution ("RCE" for security people) is allowed.</li>
<li>Filtering syscalls to isolate a process.</li>
<li>Mutually untrusted processes sharing a CPU hyperthread.</li>
<li>Memory isolation between virtual machines on a CPU core.</li>
</ul>
<p>As far as I know, the state of the art, the very best isolation, is something like the Chrome sandbox or <a href="https://github.com/google/gvisor">gVisor</a>. The big browser vendors and cloud providers all use tools like these. The tools remain imperfect, but providers do chase down every new breach as fast as they can, and the rate of new flaws is fairly slow.</p>
<p>Isolation is better than it's ever been before… if you put all your isolation at the virtual machine (VM) level so that your cloud provider can do it for you because nobody else knows how, or updates often enough.</p>
<p>If you trust your cloud provider's VM isolation, you can have hope that all known problems are mitigated; but we have every reason to think more problems will be found.</p>
<p>That's… actually pretty good, all things considered. At least we have <em>something</em> that works.</p>
<h4 id="great-vms-for-everything">Great! VMs for everything!</h4>
<p>Well, hold on. Spinning up an isolated VM for every little module is a pain. And how big is a module?</p>
<p>Long ago, when Java first came out, the dream was that every line of every function in every object could have permissions enforced, even between objects in the same application binary, so that CPU-enforced memory protection wouldn't be needed. Nobody believes anymore that they can make that work. And marketing claims like "cloud functions" aside, nobody really thinks you should try.</p>
<p>None of the currently-known isolation methods work <em>perfectly</em>, but each of them works to <em>some approximation</em>. Increasingly skilled attackers, or increasingly valuable targets, require better and more annoying isolation. The best isolation we know right now is inter-VM sandboxing provided by tier-1 cloud providers. The worst, well, it goes down to zero.</p>
<p>Let's also assume, skipping over the evidence, that most systems are so tightly coupled that <strong>a reasonably skilled attacker can break through laterally between modules.</strong> So, for example, if someone can link a malicious library into your Go or C++ program, they can probably take control of that entire program.</p>
<p>Similarly, if your program has write access to a database, attackers can probably make it write <em>anywhere</em> in the database. If it can contact the network, they can probably contact <em>anywhere</em> in the network. If it can execute arbitrary Unix commands or system calls, they can probably get Unix root access. If it's in a container, they can probably break out of the container and into other containers. If malicious data can <a href="https://imagetragick.com/">crash the png decoder</a>, they can probably make it do anything else the decoder program is allowed to do. And so on.</p>
<p>An especially powerful form of attack is getting the ability to commit code, because that code will eventually be run on developer machines, and some developer or production machine somewhere probably has access to do what you want to do.</p>
<p>The above is maybe a little too pessimistic, but making those assumptions can help avoid overcomplicating your systems without improving actual security. In <a href="http://cr.yp.to/qmail/qmailsec-20071101.pdf">Some thoughts on security after ten years of qmail 1.0</a>, Daniel J. Bernstein points out (if I may heavily paraphrase) that many of the defenses he added in qmail, particularly isolating the different components from each other using chroot and different Unix uids, were not worthwhile and have never paid off.</p>
<p>Anyway, let's take it for granted that attackers with the ability to execute code can "usually" jump …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tailscale.com/blog/modules-monoliths-and-microservices/">https://tailscale.com/blog/modules-monoliths-and-microservices/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tailscale.com/blog/modules-monoliths-and-microservices/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26247052</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 05:54:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[USPS Selects Oshkosh Defense for Next Generation Delivery Vehicle Fleet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 43 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26246116">thread link</a>) | @jonbaer
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://oshkoshcorp.com/en/news/2-23-21-usps | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://oshkoshcorp.com/en/news/2-23-21-usps">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <h3>USPS selects Oshkosh Defense for Next Generation Delivery Vehicle fleet</h3>
        <p><span>2/23/2021</span></p>

<p><span><strong><span>OSHKOSH, Wis. (February 23, 2021)</span></strong>&nbsp;—&nbsp;The U.S. Postal Service (USPS) announced today that it has awarded Oshkosh Defense, a wholly owned subsidiary of Oshkosh Corporation (NYSE: OSK),</span><span> an indefinite delivery, indefinite quantity (IDIQ) contract to produce the Next Generation Delivery Vehicle (NGDV), the USPS’s first large-scale fleet procurement in three decades. The competitively awarded contract allows for the delivery of between 50,000 and 165,000 vehicles over a period of 10 years.</span></p>
<p><span>“Oshkosh operates with unparalleled commitment to those who depend on our products and services to build, protect and serve communities around the world. We are honored to have been selected by the USPS to support their important work by manufacturing American-made Next Generation Delivery Vehicles that will connect every home and business across the United States for decades to come,” said John Pfeifer, President &amp; Chief Operating Officer, Oshkosh Corporation.</span></p>
<p><span>Oshkosh Defense will manufacture <span>both zero emission battery electric vehicles (BEV) and fuel-efficient low-emission internal combustion engine vehicles (ICE), </span>upgrading the USPS fleet to be increasingly sustainable. Under the contract announced today, the USPS has committed to pay Oshkosh Defense $482 million to initiate engineering efforts to finalize the production vehicle design, and for tooling and factory build-out activities that are necessary prior to vehicle production.</span></p>
<p><span>“Our century-long history of delivering products to customers, operating in some of the most demanding and severe conditions on the planet, uniquely positions us to bring exceptional reliability, safety, and maintainability to USPS’s Next Generation Delivery Vehicles,” said John Bryant, Executive Vice President, Oshkosh Corporation, and President, Oshkosh Defense. </span></p>
<p><span>“Partnering with trusted suppliers, we have developed a purpose-built solution to support the current and future needs of the USPS,” Bryant concluded. Production of the next generation delivery vehicle is expected to begin in 2023.</span></p>

<p><strong><span>About Oshkosh Defense</span></strong></p>
<p><span>Oshkosh Defense is a global leader in the design, production and sustainment of best-in-class military vehicles and mobility systems. As a pioneer of combat-ready vehicle solutions, Oshkosh develops and applies emerging technologies that advance troop safety and mission success. Setting the industry standard for sustaining fleet readiness, Oshkosh ensures every solution is supported worldwide throughout its entire life cycle.</span></p>
<p><span>Oshkosh Defense, LLC is an Oshkosh Corporation company [NYSE: OSK].</span></p>
<p><span>Learn more about Oshkosh Defense at </span><a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__http:/www.oshkoshdefense.com/__;!!N96JrnIq8IfO5w!0oPVjCe_9XKiyt970eFZ2ETGHbOUaHqUzI1RM4BZtfkq8yBh8DIO8xn4LAG9LmLn1gg$"><span>oshkoshdefense.com</span></a><span>.&nbsp; </span></p>

<p><strong><span>About Oshkosh Corporation</span></strong></p>
<p><span>At Oshkosh (NYSE: OSK), we make innovative, mission-critical equipment to help everyday heroes advance communities around the world. Headquartered in Wisconsin, Oshkosh Corporation employs more than 14,000 team members worldwide, all united behind a common cause: to make a difference in people’s lives. Oshkosh products can be found in more than 150 countries under the brands of JLG®, Pierce®, Oshkosh® Defense, McNeilus®, IMT®, Frontline™, Jerr-Dan®, Oshkosh® Airport Products, Pratt Miller, and London™. For more information, visit </span><a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__http:/oshkoshcorp.com__;!!N96JrnIq8IfO5w!0oPVjCe_9XKiyt970eFZ2ETGHbOUaHqUzI1RM4BZtfkq8yBh8DIO8xn4LAG9WR_C6yk$"><span>oshkoshcorp.com</span></a><span>.</span></p>
<p><sup><span>®</span></sup><span>, ™ All brand names referred to in this news release are trademarks of Oshkosh Corporation or its subsidiary companies.</span></p>



<p><span><strong><span>Forward Looking Statements</span></strong></span></p>
<p><span>This news release contains statements that the Company believes to be “forward-looking statements” within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. All statements other than statements of historical fact, including, without limitation, statements regarding the Company’s future financial position, business strategy, targets, projected sales, costs, earnings, capital expenditures, debt levels and cash flows, and plans and objectives of management for future operations, are forward-looking statements. When used in this news release, words such as “may,” “will,” “expect,” “intend,” “estimate,” “anticipate,” “believe,” “should,” “project” or “plan” or the negative thereof or variations thereon or similar terminology are generally intended to identify forward-looking statements. These forward-looking statements are not guarantees of future performance and are subject to risks, uncertainties, assumptions and other factors, some of which are beyond the Company’s control, which could cause actual results to differ materially from those expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. These factors include the overall impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on the Company’s business, results of operations and financial condition; the duration and severity of the COVID-19 pandemic; actions that may be taken by governmental authorities and others to address or otherwise mitigate the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic; the negative impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on global economies and the Company’s customers, suppliers and employees; the cyclical nature of the Company’s access equipment, commercial and fire &amp; emergency markets, which are particularly impacted by the strength of U.S. and European economies and construction seasons; the Company’s ability to increase prices or impose surcharges to raise margins or to offset higher input costs, including increased commodity, raw material, labor and freight costs; the Company’s estimates of access equipment demand which, among other factors, is influenced by customer historical buying patterns and rental company fleet replacement strategies; the strength of the U.S. dollar and its impact on Company exports, </span><span>translation of foreign sales and the cost of purchased materials; the expected level and timing of U.S. Department of Defense (DoD) and international defense customer procurement of products and services and acceptance of and funding or payments for such products and services; the Company’s ability to predict the level and timing of orders for indefinite delivery/indefinite quantity contracts with the U.S. federal government; risks related to reductions in government expenditures in light of U.S. defense budget pressures and an uncertain DoD tactical wheeled vehicle strategy; the impact of any DoD solicitation for competition for future contracts to produce military vehicles; potential impacts of budget constraints facing the USPS and continuously changing demands for postal services; risks related to facilities expansion, consolidation and alignment, including the amounts of related costs and charges and that anticipated cost savings may not be achieved; projected adoption rates of work at height machinery in emerging markets; the impact of severe weather, natural disasters or pandemics that may affect the Company, its suppliers or its customers; performance issues with suppliers or subcontractors; risks related to the collectability of receivables, particularly for those businesses with exposure to construction markets; the cost of any warranty campaigns related to the Company’s products; risks associated with international operations and sales, including compliance with the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act; risks that a trade war and related tariffs could reduce the competitiveness of the Company’s products; the Company’s ability to comply with complex laws and regulations applicable to U.S. government contractors; cybersecurity risks and costs of defending against, mitigating and responding to data security threats and breaches; the Company’s ability to successfully identify, complete and integrate acquisitions and to realize the anticipated benefits associated with the same; and risks related to the Company’s ability to successfully execute on its strategic road map and meet its long-term financial goals. Additional information concerning these and other factors is contained in the Company’s filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. All forward-looking statements speak only as of the date of this news release. The Company assumes no obligation, and disclaims any obligation, to update information contained in this news release. Investors should be aware that the Company may not update such information until the Company’s next quarterly earnings conference call, if at all.</span></p>

<p><span>For more information, contact:</span></p>
<p><span><br>
Financial:<br>
Patrick Davidson<br>
Senior Vice President, Investor Relations<br>
920.502.3266</span></p>
<p><span>Media:<br>
Bryan Brandt<br>
Senior Vice President, Chief Marketing Officer<br>
920.502.3670</span></p>
<p><span>Alexandra Hittle<br>
Director, Global Marketing and Communications<br>
920.410.1929</span></p>
<p><span><br>
Source: Oshkosh Corporation</span></p>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://oshkoshcorp.com/en/news/2-23-21-usps</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26246116</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 02:59:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Making Games on Your Own as an Engineer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 160 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26246049">thread link</a>) | @Eyas
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://blog.eyas.sh/2021/02/unity-for-engineers-pt11-development-process/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.eyas.sh/2021/02/unity-for-engineers-pt11-development-process/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In the <strong><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/tag/unity-for-software-engineers">Unity for Software Engineers</a></strong>
series, I give an accelerated introduction to game development in Unity.
<a href="http://eepurl.com/gVgusL">Subscribers</a> have been following this series over the
past few months, often suggesting areas to cover or elaborate on. A few months
ago, a reader<!-- -->—<!-- -->also a software engineer<!-- -->—<!-- -->reached out to me (lightly
edited, emphasis mine):</p><blockquote><p><strong>The biggest unknown for me is: How do I start?</strong> What does the process of
creating a game look like? Should I build the scenes first? Should I design
the gameplay mechanics first? With business software, it’s much more familiar.
It’s easy to think, “Well, okay, I need to write the DAO or controller, etc.”
But with games, I’m lost.</p></blockquote><p>While there is no single correct answer, we can still make some distinctions
that can help get us oriented. The answer will also undoubtedly depend on <em>who</em>
is doing the development: an individual, small indie team, or larger studio? If
an individual, the answer will also depend on their primary skillset: a
developer, artist, or designer?</p><p>Here, I’ll give heuristics especially helpful for individual Software Engineers
building a game on their own as a side project, hobby, or proof-of-concept.</p><figure><p><span>
      <a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/56037/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <picture>
          <source srcset="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/28a80/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.webp 400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/8d2ea/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.webp 800w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/43d96/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.webp 1600w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/4293a/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.webp 2400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/dc28f/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.webp 2448w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/4cda9/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg 400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/c60e9/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg 800w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/56dca/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg 1600w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/111a0/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg 2400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/56037/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg 2448w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/f30aee52607429436af23a48362a8fd5/56dca/irfan-simsar-wxWulfjN-G0-unsplash.jpg" alt="Scrum board, at an office" title="Scrum board, at an office" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
  </a>
    </span></p><figcaption><p>Photo by İrfan Simsar, <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/wxWulfjN-G0">via unsplash</a>.</p></figcaption></figure><h2>Questions you should ask yourself</h2><p>Before we start, here are some questions you should ask yourself.</p><h3>Do you know <em>what</em> you’re building?</h3><p>Do you know what your game is about? Do you have a sense of what game mechanics
your game will have? Do you know what genre, controls, and themes this game will
have?</p><p>If <em>yes</em>, you’re ready to decide <strong><a href="#start-coding">where to start coding</a></strong>.
Otherwise, you have a few more questions to ask yourself.</p><h3>Do you <em>want</em> to know what you’re building?</h3><p>It’s totally fine not to have a project in mind! Maybe you’re prototyping.
Perhaps you’re throwing a bunch of mini-games on the wall and seeing what
sticks. Or you’re looking for inspiration and trying to implement random
mechanics to see what feels fun.</p><p><strong>If you’re hoping to begin working on a specific, cohesive game</strong>, you will
likely want to know what you’re building. Consider brainstorming and sketching
out an informal
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_design_document">game design document</a>.
There are
<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=game+design+document+template">plenty of templates</a>
of various levels of detail you could decide to use. Especially as a software
engineer toying with abstract ideas in my brain, I’ll start with a super
high-level GDD, covering the feel, themes, genre, and mechanics of the game I
have in mind. Maybe a few pictures or sketches for inspiration, and that’s it.
The key part of this exercise will be the list of mechanics I’m working on.</p><p><strong>If you want to prototype and experiment</strong>, you should already have a vague
sense of 1-2 mechanics that could be fun: Maybe unusual movement or a different
control scheme. It could be a traditional mechanic that you’re wondering how to
implement. For instance, I might decide to build a 3rd Person character and
camera controller to see the “feel” of it, experiment with it a tiny bit, and do
something smooth and polish that I feel good about. I might end up keeping that
code in my back pocket for later, or I might use play-through sessions with that
controller to move around a scene, add a few assets, and use that as a starting
place to see the “feel” various mechanics and designs.</p><h2 id="start-coding">I know the mechanics I care about. Now what?</h2><figure><p><span>
      <a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/b09385282504ca9896553256d7953148/e8f7f/iterative-development.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <picture>
          <source srcset="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/b09385282504ca9896553256d7953148/28a80/iterative-development.webp 400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/b09385282504ca9896553256d7953148/dfbce/iterative-development.webp 499w" sizes="(max-width: 499px) 100vw, 499px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/b09385282504ca9896553256d7953148/4cda9/iterative-development.jpg 400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/b09385282504ca9896553256d7953148/e8f7f/iterative-development.jpg 499w" sizes="(max-width: 499px) 100vw, 499px" type="image/jpeg">
          <img src="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/b09385282504ca9896553256d7953148/e8f7f/iterative-development.jpg" alt="Spiral graph showing a representation of iterative development, between three axes: Plan, Build, and Test." title="Spiral graph showing a representation of iterative development, between three axes: Plan, Build, and Test." loading="lazy">
        </picture>
  </a>
    </span></p><figcaption><p>By Dave Gray, <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/davegray/6865783267">via Flickr</a>.
<a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd/2.0/">CC BY-ND 2.0</a>.</p></figcaption></figure><p>The goal of many iterative software development models is to de-risk software
development. You do that by failing fast and getting feedback early. In game
development, the primary metric for success is a feeling: the game should be
fun. So, when deciding what to start with when working on a game, one good
question to ask is: <em>“How can I see if this game is fun as soon as possible?”</em>
or <em>“How can I implement the ‘fun’ part of the game ASAP?”</em></p><p>One way to do that is to look at a game’s mechanics and implement them in some
order. The advice that resonates with me is implementing game mechanics in order
of what the most <em>“core”</em> mechanic first.</p><figure><p><span>
      <a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/94dc51f1aee3ae0db91cc4adef00ac50/a331c/scrolling-shooter-example.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <picture>
          <source srcset="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/94dc51f1aee3ae0db91cc4adef00ac50/28a80/scrolling-shooter-example.webp 400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/94dc51f1aee3ae0db91cc4adef00ac50/8d2ea/scrolling-shooter-example.webp 800w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" type="image/webp">
          <source srcset="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/94dc51f1aee3ae0db91cc4adef00ac50/a3397/scrolling-shooter-example.png 400w,https://blog.eyas.sh/static/94dc51f1aee3ae0db91cc4adef00ac50/a331c/scrolling-shooter-example.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" type="image/png">
          <img src="https://blog.eyas.sh/static/94dc51f1aee3ae0db91cc4adef00ac50/a331c/scrolling-shooter-example.png" alt="Example of a space scrolling shooter game" title="Example of a space scrolling shooter game" loading="lazy">
        </picture>
  </a>
    </span></p><figcaption><p>Space Scrolling Shooter. By Beyond2000, via
<a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:RosAsmGameSpace.png">Wikimedia Commons</a>.
<a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en">CC BY-SA 3.0</a>.</p></figcaption></figure><p>Let’s take <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strikers_1945">Strikers 1945</a>—the
plane shooting game—as an example. Here’s my attempt at writing its main
mechanics in descending order of importance:</p><ol><li>Movement: Navigate a vertically scrolling world</li><li>Obstacles &amp; Dodging: Player can collide with stationary obstacles and debris</li><li>Shooting: Player can shoot straight ahead to defeat obstacles</li><li>Enemies: Enemies are moving obstacles that can shoot back</li><li>Player Health: A player can take a finite number of hits before losing the
game</li><li>Enemy Health: Some enemies take multiple shots to destroy</li><li>Boosts: The player can pick up boosts that improve health, shooting, etc.</li></ol><p>… and so on.</p><p>If I’m trying to develop <em>1945</em> from scratch, I will implement that list in that
order. The game’s mechanics build on each other, so I can only tell if shooting
is “fun” is if I can move around the screen and if there are obstacles I’m
trying to clear (otherwise, there’s no urgency to just pressing <em>Space</em> and
seeing projectiles coming out of a plane).</p><p>In simpler games, we might order our mechanics so that every new feature adds to
a game’s feel. So, with every new mechanic you add, you can play the game and
tell if it’s adding what you hope for it to add.</p><p>In more complex games, some of the “core” mechanics might be too ‘standard’ to
be “risky” <em>per se</em>, but you’ll still need the core mechanics implemented to
assess how fun the other mechanics are. You might choose to use a simpler
throwaway implementation, like a few lines of input-handling code and Unity’s
<code>CharacterController</code> component. You’ll want your core mechanics just smooth
enough that they don’t ruin the fun of the things you’ll layer on top of it.
Another approach here is to use the asset store. I’ve previously mentioned the
<a href="https://assetstore.unity.com/packages/tools/game-toolkits/ufps-ultimate-fps-106748?aid=1011leWs6">Ultimate FPS (UFPS)</a>
asset, which you might choose to use when building an FPS game, and move on to
implementing the combat or some more unique (but still “core” feature of the
gameplay first).</p><h2>So I picked a mechanic, but where do I start programming <em>within</em> this mechanic?</h2><p><em>Within</em> a mechanic, your traditional software engineering intuition becomes
helpful. I hope to spend subsequent articles discussing patterns that are
especially helpful in Unity, but here are a few to consider:</p><ul><li>Work within Unity’s Object-Component paradigm. If you’re adding a new
<em>capability</em> to your player, write it as its own component.</li><li><em>Tuning</em> is especially important in game development; representing a
mechanic’s interesting pieces as <em>configurable</em>, <em>serializable</em> data that
can be input to a component will help you playtest and iterate.</li><li>Don’t shy away from using plain-old data objects to represent core concepts
you’re working with. E.g., health, ammo information, or powerups. Make it
serializable if you want it passed around in the editor (or saved to disk
across sessions).</li><li>Where pieces of a concept don’t correspond to a single object in a scene,
consider using Scriptable Objects to do the jobs. Scriptable Objects
introduce many patterns that might help represent what you’re doing.</li></ul><p>A few articles I have already written might prove helpful:</p><ul><li><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2020/10/unity-for-engineers-pt1-basic-concepts/">Basic Concepts in Unity for Software Engineers</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2020/10/unity-for-engineers-pt2-six-practices/">6 Software Practices to Keep, Shed, and Adopt in Unity</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2020/09/patterns-in-unity-adventure-tutorial/">Making Sense of Patterns in Unity’s Adventure Game Tutorial</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2020/10/unity-for-engineers-pt5-object-component/">Understanding Unity Engine Objects</a></li></ul><p>You might also take a look at patterns covered in:</p><ul><li><a href="https://unity.com/how-to/architect-game-code-scriptable-objects">Three ways to architect your game with ScriptableObjects</a>,
via the Unity Blog (based on
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=raQ3iHhE_Kk">his talk</a>)</li><li><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2020/10/unity-for-engineers-pt3-input-system/">Unity Input System, from Basic Principles</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2020/11/unity-for-engineers-pt10-1-pathfinding/">Pathfinding with NavMesh</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2020/11/unity-for-engineers-pt10-2-raycasting/">Physics Raycasting</a></li></ul><p>Once you have a stronger intuition of <em>how</em> you can represent different kinds of
data and abstractions, the reader’s initial comment also becomes the answer:</p><blockquote><p>It’s easy to think, “Well, okay, I need to write the DAO or controller, etc.”
But with games, I’m lost.</p></blockquote><p>Beyond learning about useful patterns and abstractions in game development to
make development clearer and cleaner, the real takeaway is to decide <em>what</em> to
work on at a macro-level.</p><h2>How much time should I spend on one mechanic?</h2><p>As you’re developing a mechanic, what’s a good signal you should move on to the
next on your list? Generally, that would be when you’re convinced:</p><ul><li>This mechanic <em>feels fun</em> and <em>adds to the game</em>,</li><li>Your implementation adds <em>just the
<a href="https://www.e4developer.com/2018/11/21/having-just-the-right-amount-of-technical-debt/">right amount</a></em>
of technical debt.</li></ul><p>Traditionally, folks will often say to worry about polish at the later stages of
your development. In his GDC 2016 micro-talk <em>“Pizzazz First, Polish Later”</em>,
Lee Perry makes a distinction in this traditional wisdom.</p><div> <p> <iframe title="" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d8QAVGeEj-U?rel=0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p> </div><p>Certain levels of pizzazz might give you a better sense of your mechanic and how
fun it feels. A certain amount of polish or pizzazz can also help you see your
game in a new light and motivate you to keep going.
<a href="https://gameanalytics.com/blog/squeezing-more-juice-out-of-your-game-design/">Juice</a>
is another form of pizzazz; in certain dull moments of your game design, adding
juice might be a low-cost way to get back into the groove of things.</p><p>I hope the conflicting advice shows there isn’t a silver bullet on what to add
when. Rather—as in traditional software development—this choice is about a
series of trade-offs that depend on the developer, the project, and lots more.</p><h2>Are you developing a game or architecting systems?</h2><p>For some software engineers, we’re often drawn to writing code for systems that
seem <em>interesting</em>. Sometimes, I have a game in mind, but <em>really</em>, I’m
interested in implementing a cool inventory system where <em>everything</em> in the
game is an item. It might not be the core mechanic, but it might be the thing I
want to build.</p><p>It’s important to recognize when you’re not building a game but building a
system. If you just quit your job to be a full-time indie gamedev and have a
year of runway before your run out of cash, it is probably a bad idea to start
building a complex inventory system that you don’t even know you’ll need<sup id="fnref-1"><a href="#fn-1">1</a></sup>.
But if you’re programming on the side to flex your game development muscle, then
go right at it.</p><hr><p>I don’t think I’m qualified <em>per se</em> to answer the …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.eyas.sh/2021/02/unity-for-engineers-pt11-development-process/">https://blog.eyas.sh/2021/02/unity-for-engineers-pt11-development-process/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.eyas.sh/2021/02/unity-for-engineers-pt11-development-process/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26246049</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 02:49:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building an E-Ink Laptop]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 189 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26245563">thread link</a>) | @alex-a-soto
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://alexsoto.dev/building-an-e-ink-laptop.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alexsoto.dev/building-an-e-ink-laptop.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://alexsoto.dev/static/building-an-e-ink-laptop/eink-t480.jpg"></p><p>A series where I’m documenting my process of designing and building an e-ink laptop.</p><ul><li><span><span title="2021-02-20T16:02"><a href="https://alexsoto.dev/dasung-paperlike-hdft-teardown.html">Dasung Paperlike HD-FT teardown</a><span data-nosnippet="" title="Folgezettel">#</span></span></span></li></ul><h2 id="background">Background</h2><p>Since the E Ink Corporation’s founding in 1997 and the patenting of its microencapsulated electrophoretic display, or epaper, manufacturers started to incorporate e-ink film into consumer devices. <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">1</a></sup></span>. Some of the first devices were ereaders: The Sony Librie in 2004<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2">2</a></sup></span> and the Amazon Kindle in 2007 <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn3" id="fnref3">3</a></sup></span>.</p><p>Throughout the years, we’ve seen several e-ink products and prototypes: e-ink film used with larger screens<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn4" id="fnref4">4</a></sup></span>, color<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn5" id="fnref5">5</a></sup></span>, flexible material<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn6" id="fnref6">6</a></sup></span> and most recently have started seeing e-ink displays used in smartphones and tablets, notably from Hisense and Onyx Boox product lines. And while e-ink has been around for 24 years, we have yet to see a laptop with an e-ink panel.</p><h2 id="why-isnt-there-an-e-ink-laptop">Why isn’t there an E Ink Laptop?</h2><p>There have been attempts in the past to create a similar device: Pixel Qi and OLPC<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn7" id="fnref7">7</a></sup></span>, Boox Typewriter<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn8" id="fnref8">8</a></sup></span>, Yoga Book C930<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn9" id="fnref9">9</a></sup></span> and the ThinkBook Plus<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn10" id="fnref10">10</a></sup></span>. These attempts did not materialize, were discontinued, or were not sufficiently suitable to meet users’ demands due to hardware or lack of a cohesive UX/UI paradigm. <strike>To make matters worse, the E Ink Corporation holds the patents for its e-ink technology and only licenses its technology to large manufacturers making availability or mass adoption difficult.</strike><span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn11" id="fnref11">11</a></sup></span></p><p>Fortunately, some of the most exciting work and innovation happening today is in the e-ink modding community<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn12" id="fnref12">12</a></sup></span>. There have been attempts to re-purposing ereaders: as a calendar,<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn13" id="fnref13">13</a></sup></span> to display a static image or site<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn14" id="fnref14">14</a></sup></span>, Kobo devices running GNU/Linux<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn15" id="fnref15">15</a></sup></span>, Amazon Kindle devices repurposed as a development platform<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn16" id="fnref16">16</a></sup></span>, the Remarkable 1 running Parabola<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn17" id="fnref17">17</a></sup></span>, and PINE 64 recently announcing a native e-ink single-board computer<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn18" id="fnref18">18</a></sup></span>.</p><p>After following the development of e-ink for some time, I’ve decided to re-use some of the existing hardware I have and create an e-ink laptop.</p><h2 id="why-do-you-want-to-build-an-e-ink-laptop">Why do you want to build an E Ink laptop?</h2><p>From about 6 am to 7 pm, I’m in front of a computer or digital device that’s emitting blue light. Throughout the day, I’m supporting students, attending meetings, reading documentation, news articles, programming, learning, using emacs and org-mode to capture information, write down thoughts, create tasks, and conversing with my knowledge management system.</p><p>I try to use my e-ink monitor as much as possible throughout the day to reduce eye strain, fatigue and lessen distractions while intermittently taking breaks. The Dasung monitors go a long way to make this possible when I’m home or in a stationary place. Though there are times, I’m not working in front of my desktop or would like to work at a different location. The teardown and set-up of my environment when using an e-ink monitor is somewhat tedious, in addition to changes having to make when switching from an LCD to an e-ink monitor:</p><ul><li>making adjustments and tweaks to the window manager.</li><li>adjusting font sizes.</li><li>changing themes in different applications.</li></ul><p>I am then having to switch the changes back when using an LCD for meetings or videos. I’ve already solved some of this by writing some scripts and making adjustments in some applications. Still, I would like to design the experience for using an e-ink monitor with a dedicated device from the ground-up.</p><h2 id="creating-an-e-ink-laptop">Creating an E Ink Laptop</h2><p>I’ll be using a ‘headless’ Thinkpad T480 <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn19" id="fnref19">19</a></sup></span> combined with the Dasung HD-FT <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn20" id="fnref20">20</a></sup></span>.</p><p><img src="https://alexsoto.dev/static/building-an-e-ink-laptop/eink-t480.jpg"></p><h2 id="thinkpad-t480">Thinkpad T480</h2><p>The Thinkpad T480 seems to be an ideal laptop for building an e-ink laptop, The T480 has <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn21" id="fnref21">21</a></sup></span>:</p><ul><li>A hot-swappable battery (internal and external).</li><li>13 hours of battery while web browsing with the 72Wh battery.</li><li>Supports up to 64 GB of ram.</li><li>Two Nvme drives (type 2280 and 2242).</li><li>Standard HDMI port, USB-C, Thunderbolt 3, Headphone Jack, Ethernet, and SD card slot.</li><li>Uses a standard USB-C charger. <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn22" id="fnref22">22</a></sup></span></li><li>Lightweight and portable.</li><li>It can be modded to use the classic 7-row keyboard. <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn23" id="fnref23">23</a></sup></span></li></ul><p>The hot-swappable battery and long battery life are essential for any portable setup, especially with an e-ink monitor. The T480 supports up to 64Gb of ram and two Nvme drives, providing plenty of power and expansion as a daily driver.</p><p>Since the Dasung monitors connect via HDMI and receives power through USB, the T480 has all of the necessary ports without an adapter. Lastly, after removing the lid cover with the T480, there is room here to hack and mod the Dasung screen to the T480.</p><p><img src="https://alexsoto.dev/static/building-an-e-ink-laptop/t480-mobo.jpg"> <img src="https://alexsoto.dev/static/building-an-e-ink-laptop/t480-no-lcd.jpg"></p><h2 id="dasung-hd-ft">Dasung HD-FT</h2><p>Dasung currently is the only manufacturer of e-ink monitors that I’m aware of <span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn24" id="fnref24">24</a></sup></span>, and their third-generation monitors are a substantial upgrade from prior generations.</p><p><img src="https://alexsoto.dev/static/building-an-e-ink-laptop/dasung-monitor.jpg"></p><p>Directly from the monitor, you can:</p><ul><li>Change image modes (M1, M2, M3, Fast, Fast+, Fast++, Black, Black+, Black++)</li><li>Adjust contrast</li><li>Clear the screen</li><li>Turn on and off the backlight</li></ul><p>The ability to easily change the monitor’s modes without software, the fast screen refresh, screen resolution of 2200×1650 and the backlight make it a great base to build an e-ink laptop.</p><h2 id="next-steps">Next Steps</h2><p>The first post went over my reasons for building an e-ink laptop, some history about e-ink technology, the e-ink modding community, recent advancements, and the hardware I’ve selected to create an e-ink laptop.</p><p>The next post in the series will be a teardown of the Dasung HD-FT, inspired by Kev Zettler’s work on the Dasung Paperlike Pro.<span data-nosnippet=""><sup><a href="#fn25" id="fnref25">25</a></sup></span></p><p>If this post resonated positively or negatively, send me a <a href="https://twitter.com/messages/compose?recipient_id=4648173315">direct message</a> on <a href="https://twitter.com/alexsotodev">Twitter</a>, and we can talk. Also, ping if you’d like to know the updates on this post or if you have suggestions, comments, questions, or would like to collaborate.</p><p><img id="avatar" src="https://alexsoto.dev/static/profile.jpeg"></p><p>Hi, I’m Alexander Soto.</p><p>I’m a community organizer, educator, software engineer, hacktivist, and agent of social change. My interests are in exploring community-building, social justice, education, and leveraging technology to address social problems.</p><p>In the past, I’ve worked as a labor rights organizer, a teacher, and I’m currently an Expert In Residence at <a href="https://www.resilientcoders.org/">Resilient Coders.</a>.</p><p>I enjoy tinkering/playing/breaking things, 3D printing, painting, playing piano, swimming, and writing in my spare time.</p><p>This site is the <a href="https://alexsoto.dev/impulse.html">scattered and unfinished version of my thoughts</a> while documenting what I’m currently learning and exploring.</p><p>If a post resonated positively or negatively, send me a <a href="https://twitter.com/messages/compose?recipient_id=4648173315">direct message</a> on <a href="https://twitter.com/alexsotodev">Twitter</a>, an <a href="mailto:contact@alexsoto.dev">email</a>, or subscribe to the <a href="https://buttondown.email/alexsotodev">mailing list</a> and we can talk. Also, ping if you’d like to know the updates of a post or if you have suggestions, comments, questions, or would like to collaborate.</p>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alexsoto.dev/building-an-e-ink-laptop.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26245563</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 01:39:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Architecture of the Playstation 2]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 227 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26243964">thread link</a>) | @biwasa
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/playstation-2/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/playstation-2/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div class="page"><nav id="navbar"></nav><h2>A Practical Analysis</h2><hr><hr><h2 id="a-quick-introduction">A quick introduction</h2><p>The Playstation 2 was not one of the most powerful consoles of its generation, yet it managed to achieve a level of popularity unthinkable for other companies.</p><p>This machine is nowhere near as simple as the <a href="https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/playstation/">original Playstation</a> was, but we will see why it didn’t share the same fate of <a href="https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/sega-saturn/">previous complicated consoles</a>.</p><hr><h2 id="cpu">CPU</h2><p>At the heart of this console we find a powerful package called <strong>Emotion Engine</strong> or ‘EE’ designed by Sony and running at <strong>~294.91 MHz</strong>. This chipset contains multiple components, one of them being the main CPU. The rest are at the CPU disposal to speed up certain tasks.</p><h4 id="the-leader">The leader</h4><p>The main core is a <strong>MIPS R5900-compatible</strong> CPU with lots of enhancements. This is the first chip that starts executing instructions after the console is turned on. The processor provides the following features:</p><ul><li><strong>MIPS III ISA</strong>: A 64-bit RISC instruction set. <em>Wait, is it me or this is the same ISA found on a <a href="https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/nintendo-64/#cpu">competitor’s console</a>?</em>. Not quite, Sony enhanced the ISA by adding some instructions from <strong>MIPS IV</strong> (prefetch and conditional move) along with their own SIMD extension called <strong>multimedia instructions</strong>.</li><li><strong>32 128-bit extra registers</strong>: Another enhancement. They are better managed using multimedia instructions and are very useful for vector processing.<ul><li>These registers are accessed through a 128-bit bus, while the rest of the CPU uses an internal 64-bit bus.</li></ul></li><li><strong>2-way superscalar</strong>: Up to two instructions are executed in parallel.</li><li><strong>24 KB L1 cache</strong>: Divided into 16 KB for instructions and 8 KB for data.<ul><li>It also implements a <strong>prefetch function</strong> to cache instructions and data before they are requested. This is done by including extra circuitry that can identify which places in memory are more often requested.</li></ul></li><li><strong>16 KB of Scratchpad RAM</strong>: Also known as ‘Fast RAM’.</li><li><strong>Memory management unit</strong>: Interfaces memory access with the rest of the system.</li></ul><p>The core is complemented with a <strong>dedicated floating point unit</strong> (identified as ‘COP1’) that accelerates operations with 32-bit floating point numbers (also known as <code>floats</code> in C).</p><h4 id="a-recognisable-memory-choice">A recognisable memory choice</h4><p>Next to the Emotion Engine are two blocks of 16 MB of RAM, giving a total of <strong>32 MB</strong> of main memory. The type of memory used is <strong>RDRAM</strong> (<a href="https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/nintendo-64/#ram-available"><em>déjà vu!</em></a>) which is accessed through a 16-bit bus.</p><div><div><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/ps2/MemoryArch.b34c74b38be1ed34237a641ee12d48fafbb98ad28688c4ebb79fc723d8e0ab24.png"><picture><img name="image_cover" alt="Image" width="605" height="269" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/ps2/MemoryArch.b34c74b38be1ed34237a641ee12d48fafbb98ad28688c4ebb79fc723d8e0ab24.png" loading="auto"></picture></a><figcaption>Memory design of the Emotion Engine<br>You can guess where the congestion is gonna appear</figcaption></div><p>At first, this can be a little disappointing to hear, considering the internal bus of the Emotion engine is as wide as 128 bits. However, the RAM chips are strategically placed by following the <strong>dual-channel architecture</strong>, which consists in connecting both chips using two independent 16-bit buses (one bus per chip) to improve data throughput. The resulting setup provides a theoretical 3.2 GB/sec, so rest assured that memory latency is not an issue in this console!</p></div><p>At one corner of the Emotion engine there is a powerful <strong>DMA Controller</strong> or ‘DMAC’ that transfers data between main memory and Scratchpad; or between main memory and any component inside the EE.</p><p>Data transfers are done in batches of 128-bits, but here is the interesting part: Every eight batches, the main bus is temporarily unlocked. This leaves a small window to perform other DMA transfers in parallel (up to ten) or let the CPU use the main bus. This <em>modus operandi</em> is called <strong>slice mode</strong> and is one of the many modes available on this DMA unit. Bear in mind that while slice mode reduces stalls on the main bus, it does so at the cost of slowing down the overall DMA transfer.</p><h4 id="preventing-past-mishaps">Preventing past mishaps</h4><p>Whether we want it or not, with the amount of traffic happening inside the Emotion Engine, this design will eventually suffer the consequences of the <strong>Unified memory architecture</strong> or ‘UMA’. That is… multiple independent components trying to access main memory at the same time, causing congestion. Well, to correct these issues, Sony alleviated the constant need for memory by:</p><ul><li>Wrapping their processors with <strong>lots of cache</strong>. Thus, only requiring access to main memory if absolutely necessary.<ul><li>99% of cache/scratchpad mentions in this article will be for this reason.</li></ul></li><li>Adding a 128-byte <strong>Write Back Buffer</strong>: Very similar to the <a href="https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/gamecube/#ibms-enhancements">Write Gather Pipe</a>, but instead of waiting until it’s 25% full, it will check the state of the bus (i.e congested or free) first.</li></ul><p>This sounds very convenient for applications that can benefit from cache, but what about those tasks, such as manipulating Display Lists, which shouldn’t use cache at all? Luckily, the CPU provides a different memory access mode called <strong>UnCached</strong>, which <strong>only</strong> uses the Write Back Buffer. Thus, it will not waste cycles correcting the cache (product of <em>cache misses</em>).</p><p>Furthermore, the <strong>UnCached accelerated mode</strong> is also available. This one adds a buffer for speeding up read of continuous addresses in memory.</p><h4 id="other-interesting-bits">Other interesting bits</h4><p>Inside the same Emotion Engine package, there is yet-another processor called <strong>Image Processing Unit</strong> or ‘IPU’, this time designed for <strong>image decompression</strong>. The IPU can be useful when a game needs to decode an MPEG2 movie without jamming the main CPU.</p><p>Long story short, the game sends compressed image streams to the IPU (hopefully using DMA) which is then decoded in a format that the GPU can display. The PS2’s operating system also relies in the IPU to provide DVD playback.</p><p>Finally, the IPU also operates compressed <strong>High-resolution textures</strong>, which saves CPU usage and reduces large transfers.</p><hr><h2 id="co-cpus">Co CPUs</h2><p>It’s been two years since the rivals presented their <a href="https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/dreamcast/">latest offering</a>. If you read the former article and just started reading this one, I presume you are <em>still</em> waiting for ‘the thing’ that makes the PS2 as powerful as it seemed back then. Now, let me introduce a <em>very</em> important set of components Sony fitted in the Emotion Engine, the <strong>Vector Processing Units</strong> or ‘VPU’.</p><p>A Vector Processing Unit is a small independent processor designed to operate vectors. In particular, vectors made of four <code>floats</code>. These processors are so fast that they only spend only <strong>one cycle per operation</strong>, which can be extremely convenient for geometry processing.</p><p>VPUs are made of the following components:</p><ul><li>Some <strong>Vector Unit Memory</strong> or ‘VU Mem’: Used as a working space for the Vector unit. It stores values needed to be operated and/or the results of previous operations.</li><li>A <strong>Vector Unit</strong>: The core of the processor. It contains some memory (called <strong>Micro Memory</strong>) to store a program (called <strong>Microprogram</strong>) which instructs the unit on how to operate the data found in ‘VU Mem’.<ul><li>It implements a <strong>64-bit ISA</strong> and the execution unit is <strong>split into two parallel sub-units</strong>. The first one multiplies or adds floats, while the other one divides floats or operates integers. This enables to operate both floats and integers <strong>concurrently</strong>.</li></ul></li><li>A <strong>Vector Interface</strong>: Automatically decompresses vertex data coming from main memory in a format the Vector unit can understand. This unit can also transfer microprograms to Micro Memory.</li></ul><p>To start working, the vector unit needs to be ‘kickstarted’. For this, the main CPU is in charge of supplying the microcode.
There are <strong>two VPUs</strong> fitted in the Emotion engine, but they are arranged differently, giving way to different uses and optimisations.</p><div><ul><li id="tab-1-1-vector-processing-unit-0-link"><a href="#tab-1-1-vector-processing-unit-0">Vector Processing Unit 0</a></li><li id="tab-1-2-vector-processing-unit-1-link"><a href="#tab-1-2-vector-processing-unit-1">Vector Processing Unit 1</a></li></ul><div><div id="tab-1-1-vector-processing-unit-0"><h4>Vector Processing Unit 0</h4><div><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/ps2/VU0.300aa8f5034941872e5a56f84ab61dfa3f3b2c71ede208b85d7edc99e6dd38a5.png"><picture><img name="image_cover" alt="Image" width="881" height="429" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/ps2/VU0.300aa8f5034941872e5a56f84ab61dfa3f3b2c71ede208b85d7edc99e6dd38a5.png" loading="auto"></picture></a><figcaption>Architecture of VPU0</figcaption></div><p>The first VPU, the <strong>VPU0</strong>, is positioned between the CPU and the other vector unit (VPU1). It provides an ‘assisting’ role to the main CPU.</p><p>The VPU0 has two modes of operation:</p><ul><li><strong>Micromode</strong>: This is the ‘traditional mode’. The VPU will independently execute ‘microinstructions’ from a microprogram stored in Micro memory.</li><li><strong>Macromode</strong>: The VPU0 becomes the ‘COP2’ of the main CPU and executes ‘macro-instructions’, received from the main CPU through a dedicated 128-bit bus.<ul><li>Macro-instruction have the same functionality of microinstructions but use different opcodes. Nonetheless, the VPU execution unit is no longer split (meaning it can only execute one instruction at a time).</li><li>While this mode doesn’t make full utilisation of all the components of the VPU0, it still speeds up the CPU’s vector operations. Moreover, in terms of simplicity, a co-processor is easier to program than an independent unit (something PC programmers will find helpful).</li></ul></li></ul><p>The memory map of the VPU0 also has access to some of the other VPU’s registers and flags, presumably to check its state or quickly read the results of some operations done by the other VPU.</p></div><div id="tab-1-2-vector-processing-unit-1"><h4>Vector Processing Unit 1</h4><div><a href="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/ps2/VUP1.a655cb236515c27f56d7d883e367c54381a35a4a08cd177165d92e443454087e.png"><picture><img name="image_cover" alt="Image" width="822" height="431" src="https://www.copetti.org/images/consoles/ps2/VUP1.a655cb236515c27f56d7d883e367c54381a35a4a08cd177165d92e443454087e.png" loading="auto"></picture></a><figcaption>Architecture of VPU1</figcaption></div><p>The second VPU found, the <strong>VPU1</strong>, is an enhanced version of the VPU0 with double the amount of micro memory and VU memory. Moreover, this unit includes an additional component called <strong>Elementary function unit</strong> or ‘EFU’ which speeds up the execution of exponential and trigonometric functions.</p><p>The VPU1 is located between the VPU0 and the Graphics Interface (the ‘gate’ to the GPU), so it includes additional buses to feed the geometry to the GPU as quickly as possible and without using the main bus.</p><p>On the other side and due to its location, the VPU1 <strong>only operates in micromode</strong>.</p><p>It’s obvious that this VPU was designed for trigonometric operations, and may serve as a pre-processor for the GPU. Hence, it’s often put in charge of delivering the famous Display Lists.</p></div></div></div><h4 id="infinite-worlds">Infinite worlds</h4><p>A useful approach that can be exploited with these units is <strong>procedural generation</strong>. In other words, instead of building the scene using hard-coded geometry, let the VPUs generate it using algorithms. In this case, the VPU computes <strong>mathematical functions to produce the geometry</strong> which is then interpreted by the GPU (i.e. triangles, lines, quadrangles, etc) and ultimately used to draw the scene.</p><p>Compared to using explicit data, procedural content is ideal for parallelised tasks, it frees up bandwidth, requires very little storage and it’s dynamic (programmers can set parameters to achieve different results). There are certain areas that can highly benefit from this technique:</p><ul><li><strong>Complex surfaces</strong> (e.g. spheres and wheels).</li><li><strong>World rendering</strong> (e.g terrains, particles, trees).</li><li><strong>Bezier curves</strong> (a very popular equation in computer graphics which is used to draw curves), …</li></ul></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/playstation-2/">https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/playstation-2/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.copetti.org/writings/consoles/playstation-2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26243964</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 22:41:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Taking a Stand in the War on General-Purpose Computing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 262 | Comments 247 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26242991">thread link</a>) | @Funes-
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/war-on-gp-computing.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/war-on-gp-computing.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cheapskatesguide.org/articles/war-on-gp-computing.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26242991</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 21:16:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A new take on remote/hybrid standups]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26242959">thread link</a>) | @Ali_Jiwani
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://www.rally.video/post/stand-ups-suck-why-not-rally-instead | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.rally.video/post/stand-ups-suck-why-not-rally-instead">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Covid-19 forced everyone to start thinking remote first. Companies started to replace meetings with video calls and eventually questioning if the meeting was necessary. Work went from 'why is everything a meeting?' to "just send me an email/slack message'. Over the past few months we spoke to dozens of remote companies, and we learned that while many have reduced the number of meetings, some actually changed certain meetings to adopt to new technology and ways of working. One of the changes we saw most consistency was the standup - their most frequent and hated meeting.</p><p>In this post, we will talk about:</p><ul role="list"><li>Why do synchronous and asynchronous stand ups suck.</li><li>How the purpose of the stand up will change with the predominance of remote work.</li><li>The end of the traditional standup, and the beginning of a better alternative - a Rally.</li><li>How you can make your standup more like a Rally.</li></ul><h2>Why do synchronous and asynchronous stand ups suck?</h2><p>Standups were originally designed for agile engineering teams. With the world going remote, many companies outside engineering have adopted this practice as a way to update each other on daily progress. They may not call it standups, but the essence is the same.</p><p>The problem with standups is that they are a distraction, and it feels more beneficial to management than to the team. For people working together, standups often don't deliver any new information, and for those working apart, the information is seemingly useless. Standups are also set at weird times to accommodate for everyone across all timezones. That sucks because it takes you away from your work state for a meeting that feels pointless. Finally standups are used as a way for managers to keep track of their teams. Sometimes this is effective, other times it feels intrusive.</p><p>How about asynchronous standups? Surely this is a better solution as it gives everyone flexibility and it feels less likely like management is breathing down your neck. A quick google search on asynchronous standups also reveals similar problems to the standups. People don't care about the update, the context is usually missing, and there is no conversation around blockers. Ultimately asynchronous standups don't provide much value either.</p><p>As one user on Hacker News puts it "Going async sends a message that people don't need to care about what their team members are working on. That's a dream come true for the people who just want to pull Jira tickets out of the queue, finish them in isolation, and then collect a paycheque." And another chimes in "it doesn't make for great team cohesion and knowledge sharing. Teams end up compensating with extra meetings and coordination overhead, which starts to defeat the point of async standups."</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f345c1d925d4f6201e2c2a9/60314b54800c1961716bd82f_hn%20post.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p><figcaption>Source: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23194569</figcaption></figure><p>Is the answer then to cancel standups? Or to do some form of a hybrid async standup? Call me crazy, but what about extending the standup virtually and inviting a few more teams. Let's go back to first principles so I can explain why.</p><h2>How the purpose of the stand up will change with the predominance of remote work</h2><p>The original purpose of a stand up was to answer three questions:</p><ul role="list"><li>What was I working on yesterday?</li><li>What will I work on today?</li><li>What is blocking me or stopping me from success?</li></ul><p>The idea is to physically get off your chair, discuss the above three questions, and finish the meeting in roughly 15 mins. It is a meeting for the team, not for management.</p><p><em>Source: </em><a href="https://www.atlassian.com/agile/scrum/standups"><em>https://www.atlassian.com/agile/scrum/standups</em></a></p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f345c1d925d4f6201e2c2a9/60314ba6f1c0b469307efa91_1_5L-pHXCmAl0GcryXyREF6A.jpeg" loading="lazy" alt=""></p><figcaption>Source: <a href="https://medium.com/@hans.bruins/the-standup-that-disrupts-the-workflow-78cb5b916bcb">https://medium.com/@hans.bruins/the-standup-that-disrupts-the-workflow-78cb5b916bcb</a></figcaption></figure><p>Standups also have an unintended benefit that is not talked about - it brings the team together. In a remote world, isolation is the number one complaint many employees have. Isolation leads to a decline in mental health, productivity, and overall well being. Isolation can also impact teams, where they feel left out from the rest of the company and are forced to have more meetings to play catch up. This is why so many people crave going back to the office. It's not for the meetings, it's for the people. Even the most introverted people have found isolation daunting.</p><p>The problem is this crucial benefit is overlooked in standups, and people start to resent this meeting. The way to solve this problem is to reframe the purpose of the meeting entirely, so much so that it may even warrant a new name, which we call a Rally.</p><h2>What is a Rally? And how will it replace the standup?</h2><p>A Rally is not a formal standup, it is a collaborative get together. Our Rallys are daily and they are 30 minutes long. The original idea came from one of our first engineering hires: Nate Wildermuth, and it's stuck ever since. We spend the first 20-25 minutes chatting, playing a game, or running an activity (see below for examples). Occasionally this leads to a great idea (such as this blog post!) or a tonne of laughs that builds some terrific momentum for the rest of the day. We then take the last 5-10 minutes discussing what we worked on, what we will work on, and any blockers we have. Usually by the time we are discussing work, we feel much more energized and ready to take on the day.</p><h3>"Standups are an endless series of trivia nights where everyone loses." Nate</h3><p>Of course, we use our own video software for these standups. This is because we designed Rally to allow multiple groups to have conversations in the same space. We call these groups 'tables', and we call the space a 'room'. It is easy to hop around to different tables to chat, or sit at a table in case someone needs to chat with you. We also have a stage where you can present to everyone in the room. This way we can let everyone know what we are working on if we needed. Luckily we're not the only ones that do this. We have a number of customers who have been using Rally for similar collaborative meetings. After speaking with them we have come up with a framework for how we think about Rallys, followed be some examples.</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f345c1d925d4f6201e2c2a9/60314aba2469e82b4aa034b1_Slide%204_3%20-%201.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p><figcaption>How Rally Works</figcaption></figure><p>A Rally consists of:</p><ul role="list"><li>A recurring event lasting between 30 and 60 mins, few times a week.</li><li>The team running the event will invite close stakeholders. If the team is less than 50 in size, the entire company will attend.</li><li>People notifying who they want to talk to in advance so they can be efficient with their time, while managers keep an open table to allow anyone to talk to them if needed.</li><li>CEO's and senior execs are also in attendance and can choose to hop around tables to stay put and wait for questions.</li><li>Starting and/or ending with an activity or a game to get people excited.</li></ul><p>While we use Rally every day, we have customers that use Rally multiple times a week for different types of get togethers. We consider all of these to be offshoots of the daily Rally:</p><p>1. <strong>Collaboration Rally</strong>: An hour long session where each team member discusses what they are working on in their team, then hops around to other teams to eliminate blockers. The benefit of this is having everyone in one place instead of setting up extra 30 minute meetings and one on ones. To this successfully, one of our customers runs this meeting every Monday and Friday morning. Each team member prepares what they want to discuss, and reaches out to anyone they need to speak to. On average there are 3-4 cross company conversations lasting 10-20 mins each.Since this is a dedicated hour for everyone, people use this time to catch up on work and remove any blockers they have across the company. It is also a great chance to have everyone in one place. Here is an example of what that looks like:</p><figure></figure><p>2. <strong>Sprint Demo Rally</strong>: An hour long meeting where members from the engineering team hop between tables to present their work. The tables are formed of teams outside engineering so any stakeholder can keep up with engineering work. The meeting usually starts with a presentation from one of the leads to the entire room, and finishes with an activity or hangout in case people have questions.</p><figure></figure><p>3. <strong>Virtual Cafeteria Rally</strong>: An hour long daily meeting for anyone in the company to attend. The meeting is at a set time where someone opens up a Rally lunch room. Teams will jump into tables and enjoy lunch together, as they would in real life, or find friends at other tables to talk to. Instead of having multiple video calls for smaller teams, all the teams are in one place. This way they can hop around tables as they overhear interesting conversations. HR managers have also shuffled people into random tables as a way for people to meet each other.</p><figure></figure><h2>How can you change your standup into a Rally?</h2><p>Start by calling it a Rally and not a standup.</p><p>Reframe the purpose of the standup so its not purely about work but about catching up and hanging out as well.</p><p>Start the Rally with a game, activity or fun fact. Here are some options you can try out:</p><ul role="list"><li><a href="https://www.rally.video/games-and-resources">Rally's Games &amp; Activity page</a></li><li><a href="https://bored.social/">Bored Social</a></li><li><a href="https://meet.airconsole.com/">Air Console</a></li></ul><p>If you are hybrid, encourage people to sign in with their own devices for this meeting so it feels like everyone is remote (on their own computers).</p><p>Consider having this meeting few times a week instead of daily</p><p>Consider not limiting this Rally to just your team, but inviting teams you collaborate with to join</p><p>You can improve your standups on any video platform. We're obviously biased because we built our own and we think it is more fun, easier to use, and gives more autonomy to each user! If you'd like to give us a try, why not head over to <a href="https://rally.video/">https://rally.video</a> and sign up for an account. Have questions or comments? Email us at <a href="mailto:hello@rally.video?subject=Blog%20on%20Daily%20Rallies">hello@rally.video </a></p><p>‍</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.rally.video/post/stand-ups-suck-why-not-rally-instead</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26242959</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 21:13:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Kafka API is great; now let's make it fast]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26242197">thread link</a>) | @sorenbs
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://vectorized.io/blog/fast-and-safe/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vectorized.io/blog/fast-and-safe/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><blockquote>
<p><small>Note: we will host a live twitch stream on Thursday, February 25th at 10am PT for 1hr. Come and ask us questions live. We will walk through the code, benchmarks, results, and if time permits, we’ll walk through the storage engine design.</small></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://vectorized.io/171856194738a05a78e745396ee0c493/1250k-rate-100-partitions-1kb-4-producers-e2e-latency-quantile.svg" alt="1.2GB/s"></p>
<blockquote>
<p><small>1250k msg/sec - 1KB payload - ack=all - fsync after every batch - 1 hour benchmark
</small></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This blog post represents months of work and over 400+ hours of actual
benchmarking where we compared
<a href="https://vectorized.io/redpanda">Redpanda</a>
and the latest 2.7 Kafka Release. We used the recommended production
setup and environment from Confluent’s
<a href="https://github.com/confluentinc/openmessaging-benchmark" target="_self" rel="nofollow">fork</a>
of the CNCF open messaging benchmark.</p>
<p>Before we get started, the entirety of the actual results with the full
workload distribution, saturation, latency and throughput are at the bottom
of this interactive <a href="https://vectorized.io/blog/fast-and-safe/#The-full-test-suite-below">blog post</a>.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://vectorized.io/blog/intelligent-data-api/" target="_self" rel="nofollow">Kafka API</a>
has emerged as the lingua franca for streaming workloads. Developers
love the ecosystem and being able to turn sophisticated products
overnight. Just like Apache and Nginx have their own HTTP
implementations, gccgo and the Go compiler specify parsers for the
language, MySQL and Postgres implement SQL, Redpanda and Kafka implement
the Kafka API. Redpanda aims to bring operational simplicity to the
existing overwhelming complexity of standing up state-of-the-art
streaming systems. This manifests at its lowest level in no longer
having to choose between data safety and performance.</p>
<p>Let’s be clear, the reason tail latency matters in the world of big data
is because Redpanda does not exist in isolation. It often sits between
your web servers, databases, internal microservices, data lakes, etc.
Redpanda controls the information flow of how, when and where things are
stored, transferred, accessed, mutated and eventually delivered. The
reason we obsess over tail latency is because the p99.99 in a messaging
system happens often - it’s a simple function of the messages exchanged.
As the volume of interactions and messages between systems using the
Kafka API increases, so does the probability that a single user
operation or API call is affected by latencies <strong>above</strong> the 99.99th
percentile.</p>
<p>The Kafka API is good, below, we showcase how we made it fast.</p>

<p>We present 18 workloads below. All workloads for both systems replicate
the data to 3 nodes in total with no lag (manually verified in the
quorum system). The only difference is that Apache Kafka was run with
in-memory replication (using the page-cache) and flushing after every
message. Redpanda can only be operated in safe mode (flushing after
every batch) with acks=all. The benchmarks below are the same benchmarks
<a href="https://www.confluent.io/blog/kafka-fastest-messaging-system/" target="_self" rel="nofollow"><u>Alok Nikhil &amp; Vinoth Chandar from
Confluent</u></a>
performed while comparing Pulsar and Kafka with a 1.2GB/s extension,
using the same CNCF Open Messaging Benchmark suite.</p>
<p>First, we note that we were only able to reproduce Confluent’s first 6
results. For the other three workloads, the data shows that it is in
fact impossible to achieve sustained network throughput above 300MB/s on
AWS on i3en.2xlarge instances. Please see our Benchmark Appendix section
at the end for a detailed explanation. We also change the default 1
minute warmup time to 30 minutes to account for <a href="http://www.brendangregg.com/blog/2016-09-28/java-warmup.html" target="_self" rel="nofollow"><u>common
pitfalls</u></a>
in <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1602.00602" target="_self" rel="nofollow"><u>Virtual Machine</u></a>
benchmarking practices and focus entirely on steady state performance.
We then ran each workload for 60 additional minutes, recorded the
results and repeated the steps, taking the best run of each system. That
is, each time we ran the benchmarks it took over 54 hours to finish.</p>
<p>For all workloads, we used two m5n.8xlarge for the clients, with
32-cores and with 25Gbps of guaranteed networking throughput
and 128GB of memory to ensure the bottleneck would be on the server
side. The benchmark used three i3en.6xlarge 24-core instances with
192GB of memory, 25Gbps guaranteed networking and two NVMe SSD devices.</p>
<p>We note that after spending several hundreds of hours benchmarks, we had
to scale up Confluent’s Kafka settings to keep up with larger instances
to num.replica.fetchers=16, message.max.bytes=10485760,
replica.fetch.max.bytes=10485760, num.network.threads=16,
num.io.threads=16, log.flush.interval.messages=1. Otherwise, the gap
between Redpanda and Kafka would be much larger. This had the
unfortunate effect that for lower percentiles, Kafka’s latency was a
little higher than using half as many threads as specified by
Confluent’s Github repo.</p>
<p>All the latencies below are the end-to-end p99.999 latency with 16
producers and 16 consumers with 100 partitions on a single topic. Every
message represents 1KB of data. We note that by and large Kafka is able
to keep up on throughput except for a couple of workloads with acks=all
where Redpanda is better. The meaningful differences are in latency: how
fast can each system go.</p>
<h2 id="Safe-workloads---fsync-with-every-batch">Safe workloads - fsync() with every batch<a href="#Safe-workloads---fsync-with-every-batch" aria-label="Safe workloads   fsync with every batch permalink"></a></h2>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th><strong>Workload</strong></th>
<th><strong>Kafka p99.999</strong></th>
<th><strong>Redpanda p99.999</strong></th>
<th><strong>Percentage Change</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>acks=all + fsync() after every batch</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(1) 10MB/s (10K msgs/s)</td>
<td>215.191ms</td>
<td>12.405ms</td>
<td>+1634.71%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(2) 40MB/s (40K msgs/s)</td>
<td>102.589ms</td>
<td>52.122ms</td>
<td>+96.82%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(3) 50MB/s (50K msgs/s)</td>
<td>235.675ms</td>
<td>13.999ms</td>
<td>+1522.66%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(4) 75MB/s (75K msgs/s)</td>
<td>1801.263ms</td>
<td>16.606ms</td>
<td>+10747.06%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(5) 100MB/s (100K msgs/s)</td>
<td>1725.391ms</td>
<td>20.552</td>
<td>+8295.25%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(6) 200MB/s (200K msgs/s)</td>
<td>1945.039ms</td>
<td>27.307ms</td>
<td>+7022.86%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(7) 0.5GB/s (500K msgs/s)</td>
<td>3015.295ms</td>
<td>60.943ms</td>
<td>+4263.23%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(8) 1GB/s (1M msgs/s)</td>
<td>3839.663ms</td>
<td>174.521ms</td>
<td>+2100.12%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(9) 1.25GB/s (1.25M msgs/s)</td>
<td>3797.167ms</td>
<td>237.688ms</td>
<td>+1497.54%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<blockquote>
<p><small> Percentage Change was computed using: ((v2-v1)/abs(v1))*100 </small></p>
<p><small> Note: All of our work is open source on <a href="https://github.com/vectorizedio/openmessaging-benchmark" target="_self" rel="nofollow">GitHub</a>. Safe workloads mean acks=all and fsync after every batch before returning to the client.</small></p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="In-memory-replication-for-Kafka-page-cache--no-explicit-flushes-vs-Redpanda-fsync-ing-after-every-batch">In memory replication for Kafka (page cache &amp; no explicit flushes) vs. <strong>Redpanda fsync()</strong>-ing after every batch<a href="#In-memory-replication-for-Kafka-page-cache--no-explicit-flushes-vs-Redpanda-fsync-ing-after-every-batch" aria-label="In memory replication for Kafka page cache  no explicit flushes vs Redpanda fsync ing after every batch permalink"></a></h2>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th><strong>Workload</strong></th>
<th><strong>Kafka (no fsync) p99.999</strong></th>
<th><strong>Redpanda (with sync) p99.999</strong></th>
<th><strong>Percentage Change</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>acks=all</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(1) 10MB/s (10K msgs/s)</td>
<td>12.728ms</td>
<td>12.405ms</td>
<td>+2.6%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(2) 40MB/s (40K msgs/s)</td>
<td>216.253</td>
<td>52.122ms</td>
<td>+314.9%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(3) 50MB/s (50K msgs/s)</td>
<td>222.785ms</td>
<td>13.999ms</td>
<td>+1491.44%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(4) 75MB/s (75K msgs/s)</td>
<td>216.195ms</td>
<td>16.606ms</td>
<td>+1201.9%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(5) 100MB/s (100K msgs/s)</td>
<td>13.737ms</td>
<td>20.552ms</td>
<td>-33.16%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(6) 200MB/s (200K msgs/s)</td>
<td>218.32ms</td>
<td>27.307ms</td>
<td>+699.5%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(7) 0.5GB/s (500K msgs/s)</td>
<td>4225.215ms</td>
<td>60.943ms</td>
<td>+6833.06%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(8) 1GB/s (1M msgs/s)</td>
<td>4877.279ms</td>
<td>174.521ms</td>
<td>+2694.67%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>(9) 1.25GB/s (1.25M msgs/s)</td>
<td>202.667ms</td>
<td>237.688</td>
<td>-14.73%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<blockquote>
<p><small> Workload (5) is a bug on our write-behind strategy: <a href="https://github.com/vectorizedio/redpanda/issues/542" target="_self" rel="nofollow">issue #542</a> </small></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>We’ve said this ad nauseam: <a href="https://vectorized.io/blog/redpanda-raison-detre/" target="_self" rel="nofollow"><u>hardware is the
platform</u></a></strong>.
Modern hardware is capable of giving you both low latency and no data
loss (fsync). Let’s talk about most of the meaningful low-level
architectural differences that get us there</p>

<p><img src="https://vectorized.io/171856194738a05a78e745396ee0c493/1250k-rate-100-partitions-1kb-4-producers-e2e-latency-quantile.svg" alt="1.2GB/s">
Before we dive deep into details, we encourage you to sign up for our
live Twitch Stream where we’ll be going through every single claim made
in this article, and are happy to answer your questions live. It will be
me, emacs, you and questions. Perfect.</p>
<p>When we started building Redpanda, the main driving factor was
<strong>understandability</strong>. Above performance, we wanted a simple mental
model of what it meant to have 2 out of 3 replicas up and running, which
is how we ended with Raft - a protocol with a mathematical proof of
correctness &amp; log completeness and a focus on usability as part of its
design goals.</p>
<p>However, once you get your replication model set, the rest of the life
of the product is spent on predictability, and for big-data &amp; real time
systems, that means understandable, flat tail latencies. It is not
enough to be fast. It is not enough to be safe. When trying to handle
hundreds of terabytes per day of streaming you need to be predictable
not only in the way the product breaks in case of network partitions,
bad disks, etc, but also in how performance degrades as a function of
hardware saturation. This is at the core of operational simplicity for
streaming systems.</p>
<p>Modern hardware allows us to finally have nice things. It is not the
case anymore that you have to choose between safety (no data loss) and
speed (low latency). Furthermore, this predictability affords you
accurate planning for product launches. As a user, I understand how to
buy hardware. I will perform an `fio` test and have a decent
understanding of what that specific hardware can do. Redpanda lets you
take these hardware saturation numbers and gives you a reasonable chance
of predicting how costly it is to develop a new product.</p>
<p>Without further ado, let me count the ways:</p>
<h2 id="0-No-page-cache">0) No page cache<a href="#0-No-page-cache" aria-label="0 No page cache permalink"></a></h2>
<p>The page cache is an object in the Linux Kernel. It is maintained per
file with global locking semantics. It is a tried and true, generic
scheduling mechanism with heuristics from a variety of production use
cases that push and pull the design to a really good middle ground. It
aims to never be a bad choice if you need to do IO. However, for our
specific use case - a log - we can do much better. We understand
exactly, all the way to the user application, how much data is going to
be needed next, the access patterns which mostly move forward, update
frequency, background operations and cache prioritization.</p>
<p>For us, the page cache introduces latency and nondeterministic IO
behavior. For example, when loading data for a Kafka fetch request the
Linux Kernel will trigger general-purpose read-ahead heuristics, and
cache the bytes it read, take a global lock, and update indexes.
Redpanda does not do general IO. It is a log, append only, with well
understood access patterns. We add data to the end file and have
aggressive write-behind strategies. When we read data, Redpanda reads in
order, which means we can in theory have perfect read-ahead and object
materialization that sits above the byte array style API of the page
cache, etc.</p>
<p>More fundamentally, bypassing the Kernel’s page cache allows us to be
predictable, with respect to both failure semantics and tail latency. We
can detect and measure the rate and latency of IO and adjust our buffer
pools accordingly. We can react to low memory pressure situations and
have a holistic view of our memory footprint. We have predictability
over each filesystem operation that can actually affect correctness - as
recently evidenced by the PostgreSQL team with an fsync() bug that was
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1VWIGBQLtxo" target="_self" rel="nofollow">undetected for 20 years</a>.</p>
<h2 id="1-Automatic-Linux-Kernel-Tuning">1) Automatic …</h2></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://vectorized.io/blog/fast-and-safe/">https://vectorized.io/blog/fast-and-safe/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vectorized.io/blog/fast-and-safe/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26242197</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 20:05:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rows launches a spreadsheet with data, integrations, and sharing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26239210">thread link</a>) | @helhady
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://blog.rows.com/p/rows-beta | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.rows.com/p/rows-beta">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><ol><li><p>Rows is coming out of our closed beta and launching in Public Beta<strong>. </strong></p></li><li><p>We have raised a $16 million Series B round, led by Lakestar. Our previous investors and other cool people joined us, too.</p></li></ol><p>Join us in this celebration! But first, what is Rows?</p><h3>Rows</h3><p>Rows is the only true Spreadsheet with Integrations and a slick Sharing experience.</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fe80e654c-cf95-48df-b894-309ded708b65_1200x316.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fe80e654c-cf95-48df-b894-309ded708b65_1200x316.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/e80e654c-cf95-48df-b894-309ded708b65_1200x316.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:316,&quot;width&quot;:1200,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:6454,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>One billion people in the world use spreadsheets, but it’s hard to connect them to different data sources and to turn them into something you actually like to share. Rows  solves this by integrating the 3 things people like: spreadsheets, data, and slick UIs.</p><p>You’ve never seen a spreadsheet like that! Check <a href="https://rows.com/">rows.com</a> for more info!</p><h3>🚀 Public Beta</h3><p>We’re now officially in a Public Beta!</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fa43dd995-9054-40df-96b6-c6f417f4d8c7_1200x700.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fa43dd995-9054-40df-96b6-c6f417f4d8c7_1200x700.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/a43dd995-9054-40df-96b6-c6f417f4d8c7_1200x700.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:700,&quot;width&quot;:1200,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:61461,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>Going <em>Public</em> means that anyone can <a href="https://rows.com/auth/sign-up">create an account</a>. It also means that platform has been certified ready by our private beta users: we onboarded more than 10k users, and 100s of teams are active every week. Being a <em>Beta</em> also means that there’s just a handful of features left to ship until we baptize our spreadsheet as a v1 later this year. </p><p><em>Rows is free for smaller teams with up to 10 users. We rolled out paid subscriptions for larger companies, starting at $59 per month. Rows will always have a free plan.</em></p><p>We are <strong>very</strong> excited to learn about what you will build with Rows!</p><h3>What’s Next</h3><p>Rows’ vision is to empower the world’s one billion spreadsheet users to build the tools they need. </p><p>Today, businesses use Rows for critical processes in <a href="https://rows.com/solutions/sales">sales</a>, <a href="https://rows.com/solutions/marketing">marketing</a>, and <a href="https://rows.com/solutions/operations">operations</a>. We will continue to serve these use cases, and expand them with exciting new features. Throughout 2021, our team in Porto and Berlin have lined up (more than) a few serious releases:</p><ul><li><p>More classic spreadsheet functionality, like Charts and conditional formatting. </p></li><li><p>Upgraded Integrations, including easier and faster data management; and, of course, more functions and Integrations (we’re beyond 50 now).</p></li><li><p>New elements for Sharing, including a new button, drop-downs, and more.</p></li></ul><p>We are also working on a Desktop App 👩‍💻!</p><h3>Series B Funding</h3><p>Today we are also announcing our Series B round, led by <a href="https://www.lakestar.com/">Lakestar</a>! The round had the participation of our existing investors Accel and Cherry, as well as new entrants Armilar and Shilling from Portugal and Visionaries Club from Berlin. </p><p>Stephen Nundy, partner at Lakestar, is joining our board — and adding his tech and spreadsheet experience from his career at Goldman Sachs. Also joining our board is Christian Reber, CEO of <a href="https://pitch.com/">Pitch</a>. </p><p>We are very fortunate to continue evolving our company with such a strong board and advisors!<br>—</p><p>We are incredibly happy to be a part of the world of spreadsheets, and we’re excited to enter this new phase of our journey to empower spreadsheet users to build their own tools.</p><div><p>As always, we appreciate your support and love!</p><p>Let’s GO!<br>Humberto &amp; Torben<br>— Rows Founders</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.rows.com/p/rows-beta</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26239210</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:30:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Git is my buddy: Effective Git as a solo developer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 389 | Comments 188 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26239068">thread link</a>) | @vortex_ape
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://mikkel.ca/blog/git-is-my-buddy-effective-solo-developer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mikkel.ca/blog/git-is-my-buddy-effective-solo-developer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

<p><small>February 23, 2021 • Reading time: 12 minutes</small></p>

<p>At this point, most developers use Git as a tool for collaboration. We have our
rote-learned commands to pull, commit, and push. And of course, there's <a href="https://xkcd.com/1597/">that
one coworker</a> who knows a bit more about Git than
everyone else, who helps get us back on track whenever our local repos end up in
a strange state.</p>
<p>But what if I told you that Git can be a valuable tool without ever setting up a
remote repository? I'm not just talking about having a working version of your
code base to roll back to if you mess something up, although there's that too.
Used correctly, Git can help to structure your work, identifying gaps in your
test coverage and minimizing dead code.</p>
<p>There are two subjects I'm going to avoid for the purposes of this blog post:
other developers, who are the most compelling but least interesting argument
for keeping your commit history clean, and <code>git bisect</code>, which does factor
heavily into my workflow but deserves its own blog post.</p>
<p>As with any ubiquitous developer tool, the Git user base has a lot of strong and
conflicting opinions about the one "correct" way to use it. My goal is simply to
introduce a workflow that I've been using and refining for much of my career;
take from it what you will. And, importantly, it's a workflow that has become a
vital part not just of my collaboration process, but of the way I write code.</p>
<p>Ultimately, these principles serve two purposes: they focus my work onto a
particular bugfix, feature, or goal, and they ensure that my Git history isn't
set in stone. With proper hygiene, commits can be dropped, rearranged, and split
off into other branches painlessly and without merge conflicts.</p>
<h2 id="principle-1-a-branch-must-do-one-useful-thing">Principle 1: A branch must do one useful thing</h2>
<p>When I'm managing my own projects, I have a lot of ideas that I want to see
happen. If I'm just throwing one commit after another into <code>main</code>, I'll get
halfway through implementing one feature and then jump off to hacking on
another. If any of the features get completed, it will be at the expense of a
wasteland of half-completed features that are now taking up space in my code
base.</p>
<p>In a brand-new project, sure, I'll throw a bunch of garbage commits into <code>main</code>.
My rule of thumb for when to stop this is when I can write my first effective
integration test. If there is <em>something</em> useful to test, there is now enough
substance to my project that I can have distinct tasks on the go. Trying to
break into branches too early just results in me throwing my garbage commits
into a branch instead of main.</p>
<p>In the early stages of a project, articulating the purpose of a branch can be as
simple as giving it a descriptive name. If a commit isn't moving the code base
in that direction, it can always get cherry-picked into a different branch.</p>
<p>As the project matures, I'll start using some sort of issue or bug tracking
software to flesh out what I'm trying to accomplish in more detail and
coordinate the branches for multiple related useful things.</p>
<p>I find that descriptive branch names also help to refocus my attention on what
I'm trying to accomplish. For instance, my command prompt currently looks like
this:</p>
<pre><span>10:02:19 </span><span>max</span> <span>~/Projects/mikkel.ca</span> <span>blog-post-git-as-a-solo-developer</span><span>|</span> <span>R</span><span>%</span></pre>
<h2 id="principle-2-every-commit-must-be-independent">Principle 2: Every commit must be independent</h2>
<p>So much for branches, let's zoom into a commit level. I've articulated what
concrete thing I want my branch to add, now how do I add it? Usually, there's
some poking around my code base involved in figuring that out. Sometimes I take
a wrong turn, sometimes I just get distracted. That's okay, it's part of the
process.</p>
<p>However, that doesn't mean that every commit I make right now is going to end up
getting merged in this branch. By keeping my commits independent from one
another, I ensure that I can rearrange or cherry-pick them into new branches
if I discover that they really don't have anything to do with what I'm working
on right now.</p>
<p>If my commits are not independent, I am essentially stuck with the exact history
as it was written. Trying to tease out a commit into a different branch or move
it to the beginning of my branch history will become fraught with merge
conflicts as later commits that modified code introduced in this commit fall
like dominoes.</p>
<p>Obviously, I'm still allowed to call code written in one commit from a later
commit. That's the reason I'm doing this particular work in this particular
branch, after all. But I never touch the same code multiple times. If I have to
go back and fix something, maybe add a validation check or field that I hadn't
thought of, I'll go back to the commit where it was created rather than amending
it in a later commit.</p>
<p>Obviously, this could go on forever, which is why the "one useful thing"
principle exists. Once I've settled on what I want the code to look like for the
purposes of this branch, I merge and then start a new commit in the next branch
for further changes to the same.</p>
<h3 id="principle-2a-every-commit-must-include-its-own-tests">Principle 2a: Every commit must include its own tests</h3>
<p>Here's where keeping commits small starts to pay dividends. If the code in each
commit is small enough for me to reason about, it's small enough for me to
visually ensure that its test coverage is good.</p>
<p>And of course, if I do end up rearranging this commit or splitting it off to a
different branch, I want its tests to come along with.</p>
<p>The exception to this is integration and functional/behavioural tests, which can
and should have their own commits. In that case, the tests are really tied to
the branch level rather than the commit level, since Principle 1 implies that
there should be exactly one new test to add as a result of this branch.</p>
<h2 id="principle-2b-every-commit-must-pass-all-tests">Principle 2b: Every commit must pass all tests</h2>
<p>Again, breaking something in a commit (even if I <em>really definitely</em> intend to
fix it in a later commit) locks me into the git history as written. And
introducing a breaking change with the intention of fixing things later always
carries the risk that I'll get distracted and end up merging the breaking
change.</p>
<p>If there's some prerequisite to get this change to pass tests - say, a
preexisting bug that snuck through a hole in my test coverage - that gets its
own commit.</p>
<p>Speaking of holes in test coverage, there's another (temporary) exception here.
I don't normally practice strict <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development">test-driven
development</a>, but if I do
fix a long-standing bug, I normally temporarily put its test in a separate
commit. I'll then rebase so that the test appears before the fix, ensure that
the test fails <em>without</em> the fix, then complete the rebase and validate that the
test now passes. Once the due diligence to validate my test is done, I can go
ahead and squash the bugfix with its test.</p>
<h2 id="principle-3-draft-commits-are-fine">Principle 3: Draft commits are fine</h2>
<p>If I know that I'll be coming back to a change later, I'm much more comfortable
setting it down and moving on to roughing in the next part of the process,
rather than finishing, polishing, and unit testing code that might need to
change before my branch gets merged.</p>
<p>In fact, I find that I waste much less time on writing tests for things that
I'll later change when I'm following this workflow to the letter than I do when
I get "lazy" and start dumping everything into big catch-all commits.</p>
<p>Some people favour TODO comments in their code, occasionally supported by
automated checks that prevent code containing "TODO" from merging. I prefer to
annotate my commit messages and leave my code clean. Normally, this looks
something like "add controller class - TODO test me". (I always put my TODOs on
the first line of the commit message, so that they show up even in short log
views.)</p>
<h2 id="principle-4-it-s-okay-to-discard-commits-completely">Principle 4: It's okay to discard commits completely</h2>
<p>Often I start a task by tidying up the surrounding code, in the same way I might
organize my desk before starting work. (I don't, but I <em>might</em>.) Sometimes that
cleanup turns out to be a valuable part of the groundwork for this change, but
sometimes it's just dead weight. Keeping my commits independent makes it easy to
discard or cherry-pick out code that turned out to be unnecessary, along with
any unit tests that went along with.</p>
<p>(I do still consider the tidying to be a valuable part of the process. It clears
my mind and refreshes my knowledge of the problem space with some simple rote
tasks before I dive into something more complex. And occasionally it results in
cleaner code.)</p>

<p>I'm not perfect.<sup>[citation needed]</sup> Obviously, it's not practical to
maintain this level of commit hygiene by making each change sequentially.
Instead, I jump around <em>constantly</em>. Doing so requires me to be comfortable in
navigating my commit history. (Conversely, it's also a good way to <em>become</em>
comfortable with navigating history.)</p>
<p>In that vein, here are some tools beyond your standard
<code>checkout</code>/<code>branch</code>/<code>pull</code>/<code>commit</code>/<code>push</code> workflow that come in handy.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-commit"><code>git commit --amend</code></a> – A quick and easy
way to update the most recent commit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-commit"><code>git commit --fixup [hash]</code></a> – When
changing history, I used to find myself making a lot of commits with messages
like "merge me with xyz" if I need to revisit commits before the most recent
one. It turns out that <code>git commit</code> has flags to help with this: <code>--fixup</code> and
<code>--squash</code> will automatically suggest a fixup or squash with another commit
during rebase if the <code>--autosquash</code> flag is provided to that command. (To
enable this behaviour by default, run <code>git config --global rebase.autosquash true</code>. It won't behave any differently if there are no commit messages in the
history being edited that contain "squash!" or "fixup!".) A surprise bonus:
since the fixup operation inherits the message of the previous commit, you
won't be prompted to enter a new one.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-rebase"><code>git rebase --interactive main</code></a> – I can
also use <code>git rebase --interactive HEAD~5</code> to edit the last 5 commits, but I
find rebasing directly on <code>main</code> (or <code>master</code>, or whatever my upstream branch
is) kills two birds with one stone. It will show me all commits since I
branched off from <code>main</code>, and will simultaneously bring my branch up to date
with my latest local copy of main.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-stash"><code>git stash</code></a> – Sometimes I have unrelated</p></li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://mikkel.ca/blog/git-is-my-buddy-effective-solo-developer/">https://mikkel.ca/blog/git-is-my-buddy-effective-solo-developer/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mikkel.ca/blog/git-is-my-buddy-effective-solo-developer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26239068</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:19:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Pretty JSON Revolution]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 158 | Comments 145 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26237048">thread link</a>) | @peterohler
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | http://www.ohler.com/dev/pretty.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.ohler.com/dev/pretty.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<div>
	  <table>
	    <tbody><tr>
	      <td colspan="2">
		<p>
		  Wouldn't it be nice if more JSON tools supported a truly
		  pretty JSON format? Demand options for truly pretty JSON
		  now! Viva la revolucion!
		</p>
		<p>
		  If only it were that easy. JSON format has become wildly
		  popular over the last decade easily passing XML as the
		  format of choice. For us humans JSON is much easier to read
		  than XML if the JSON is properly formatted. Sadly most tools
		  for viewing or formating JSON seem to be stuck on one of two
		  formats. One format is the single line format and the other
		  is a simple expanded format. There are other options though
		  with some tools.
		</p>
		<p>
		  One tool that offers more options is
		  the <span>oj</span> application
		  which is part of the
		  golang <a href="https://github.com/ohler55/ojg">OjG</a>
		  package. The <span>oj</span>
		  application will be used to illustrate the range of JSON
		  formats from the ugly up to the beauty of pretty
		  JSON. Follow along and try out your favorite JSON sample on
		  each step.
		</p>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	    <tr>
	      <td>
		<p>One Line</p>
		<p>
		  The tight one line JSON format is used when trying to
		  minimize the size of a JSON document. It is the preferred
		  format for transmitting and storing JSON as it takes less
		  bandwidth and less disk space. For viewing, it is hard for
		  the eye to find elements of interests and difficult to
		  determine element boundaries. It has to be the ugliest of
		  all JSON formats.
		</p>
	      </td>
	      <td>
<pre><span>$ oj -i 0 colors.json</span>
{"colors":[{"color":"black","hex":"#000","rgb":[0,0,0]},{"color"
:"red","hex":"#f00","rgb":[255,0,0]},{"color":"yellow","hex":"#f
f0","rgb":[255,255,0]},{"color":"green","hex":"#0f0","rgb":[0,25
5,0]},{"color":"cyan","hex":"#0ff","rgb":[0,255,255]},{"color":"
blue","hex":"#00f","rgb":[0,0,255]},{"color":"magenta","hex":"#f
0f","rgb":[255,0,255]},{"color":"white","hex":"#fff","rgb":[255,
255,255]}]}</pre>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	    <tr>
	      <td>
		<p>One Line Per Node</p>
		<p>
		  What many packages refer to as pretty is an expanded format
		  where every element and each array and object start are on
		  separate lines. The core
		  golang <code>json.MarshalIndent()</code> function produces
		  an example of this format. The format takes up so much
		  vertical space the example on the right had to be cut off to
		  avoid filling up this article with just large amounts of
		  white space.
		</p>
		<p>
		  With the expanded (pretty?) format it is certainly easier to
		  determine element boundaries but you need a large screen or
		  to be good at scrolling to find what you are looking for. So
		  the expanded format is a step up from the one line format
		  which makes it a bit prettier but it is a weak effort that
		  is not without flaws.
		</p>
	      </td>
	      <td>
<pre><span>$ oj -i 2 colors.json</span>
{
  "colors": [
    {
      "color": "black",
      "hex": "#000",
      "rgb": [
        0,
        0,
        0
      ]
    },
    {
      "hex": "#f00",
      "rgb": [
        255,
        0,
        0
      ],
      "color": "red"
    },
...
</pre>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	    <tr>
	      <td>
		<p>Sorted Object Keys</p>
		<p>
		  In many implementations JSON objects, whether implemented as
		  a golang map, Ruby Hash, Python dict, or what ever your
		  language of choice uses, the order of object elements is
		  random. That makes it more difficult to visually scan a set
		  of elements and pick out the same keyed element in each JSON
		  object. The brain is good at picking out visual or spacial
		  patterns but if the layout changes each each time there is
		  no pattern to pickup on. A visual scan has to be done,
		  looking at each key until the target is identified. JSON can
		  be made prettier by sorting the JSON object members by
		  element keys.
		</p>
		<p>
		  A sorted expanded format is a step up from just the expanded
		  format but it still suffers from taking up lot of vertical
		  space. If someone was writing the JSON by hand they would
		  probably not elect to expand the JSON to quite the level
		  that most packages or libraries do.
		</p>
	      </td>
	      <td>
<pre><span>$ oj -i 2 -s colors.json</span>
{
  "colors": [
    {
      "color": "black",
      "hex": "#000",
      "rgb": [
        0,
        0,
        0
      ]
    },
    {
      "color": "red",
      "hex": "#f00",
      "rgb": [
        255,
        0,
        0
      ]
    },
...
</pre>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	    <tr>
	      <td>
		<p>Human Style</p>
		<p>
		  The ideal pretty JSON pretty is to have the format look like
		  a human had typed it in. Well a pedantic human that didn't
		  make mistakes. Just like Goldilocks, the optimum middle
		  ground between a single line and a fully expanded format is
		  the goal. The
		  algorithm <span>oj</span> uses
		  considers a suggested edge to not exceed and a maximum
		  element depth allowed on a single line. Those two parameters
		  are specified as a float where the whole number part is the
		  edge and the fractional part or the number of 10ths is the
		  maximum depth on a single line. With those two parameters a
		  reasonable human style format can be achieved and the
		  results are looking rather pretty.
		</p>
	      </td>
	      <td>
<pre><span>$ oj -p 80.3 colors.json</span>
{
  "colors": [
    {"color": "black", "hex": "#000", "rgb": [0, 0, 0]},
    {"color": "red", "hex": "#f00", "rgb": [255, 0, 0]},
    {"color": "yellow", "hex": "#ff0", "rgb": [255, 255, 0]},
    {"color": "green", "hex": "#0f0", "rgb": [0, 255, 0]},
    {"color": "cyan", "hex": "#0ff", "rgb": [0, 255, 255]},
    {"color": "blue", "hex": "#00f", "rgb": [0, 0, 255]},
    {"color": "magenta", "hex": "#f0f", "rgb": [255, 0, 255]},
    {"color": "white", "hex": "#fff", "rgb": [255, 255, 255]}
  ]
}</pre>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	    <tr>
	      <td>
		<p>Human Style with Colors</p>
		<p>
		  With the human style formatting the JSON sample is very
		  readable but it can be made prettier. Well at least for
		  those of us than see in color. With the <code>-c</code>
		  option or the <code>-b</code> option the formatted JSON now
		  has colors. While colors do make the output prettier they
		  also make it easier for the eye to discern keys, string,
		  boolean, and numbers more easily. Try it, look at the
		  non-colored JSON and the colored and pick out your preferred
		  color name. Maybe not nirvana but compared to the first, one
		  line format, the colored pretty output is a completely
		  different level.
		</p>
	      </td>
	      <td>
<pre><span>$ oj -p 80.3 -c colors.json</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>"colors"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"black"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#000"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"red"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#f00"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"yellow"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#ff0"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"green"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#0f0"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"cyan"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#0ff"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"blue"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#00f"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"magenta"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#f0f"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>{</span><span>"color"</span><span>:</span> <span>"white"</span><span>,</span> <span>"hex"</span><span>:</span> <span>"#fff"</span><span>,</span> <span>"rgb"</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>,</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
  <span>]</span>
<span>}</span></pre>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	    <tr>
	      <td>
		<p>Human Style with Colored in the SEN Format</p>
		<p>
		  Sorted human style with colors is about as good as it gets
		  but what if we deviate from strict JSON format and take a
		  few shortcuts that Javascript and GraphQL allow such as
		  unquoted strings and optional
		  commas. The <a href="https://github.com/ohler55/ojg/blob/develop/sen.md">SEN</a>
		  format is that
		  format. The <span>oj</span>
		  application supports parsing and encoding in SEN
		  format. It's not JSON but the conversion from SEN to JSON
		  and the reverse is lossless. Getting rid of the extra quotes
		  and unnecessary commas make the data easier to read and as a
		  side benefit the SEN format takes up less space so
		  transmission and disk space requirements are reduced when
		  compared to JSON.
		</p>
	      </td>
	      <td>
<pre><span>$ oj -p 80.3 -c -sen colors.json</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>colors</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>black</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#000"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span> <span>0</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>red</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#f00"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span> <span>0</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>yellow</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#ff0"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span> <span>255</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>green</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#0f0"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span> <span>255</span> <span>0</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>cyan</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#0ff"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span> <span>255</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>blue</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#00f"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>0</span> <span>0</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>magenta</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#f0f"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span> <span>0</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
    <span>{</span><span>color</span><span>:</span> <span>white</span> <span>hex</span><span>:</span> <span>"#fff"</span> <span>rgb</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>255</span> <span>255</span> <span>255</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
  <span>]</span>
<span>}</span></pre>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	    <tr>
	      <td colspan="2">
		<p>Continue the Fight</p>
		<p>
		  Beauty is in the eye of the beholder. My preference is the
		  pretty colored SEN format. You might have a different
		  preference but let's continue the revolution together and get
		  more pretty JSON out there. Use pretty JSON on web pages and
		  in email. For the tool builders out there, offer the
		  option for pretty JSON.
		</p>
		<p>
		  Note: In case you are wondering if the colored JSON HTML was
		  written or colorized by hand, it was
		  not. The <code>-html</code> option
		  of <span>oj</span> was used to
		  produce the colorized HTML for this article. It's a handy
		  option when including JSON on web pages or in email.
		</p>
	      </td>
	    </tr>
	  </tbody></table>
	</div>
      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.ohler.com/dev/pretty.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26237048</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:37:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[You need to be able to run your system]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 279 | Comments 148 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26236908">thread link</a>) | @catern
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | http://catern.com/run.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://catern.com/run.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
When developing a system,
it is important to be able to run the system in its entirety.
<p>
"Run the unit tests" doesn't count.
The complexity of your system is in the interactions between the units.
</p><p>
"Run an individual service against mocks" doesn't count.
A mock will rarely behave identically to the real dependency,
and the behavior of the individual service will be unrealistic.
You need to run the actual system.
</p><p>
"Run an individual service in a shared stateful development environment running all the other services" doesn't count.
A shared development environment will be unreliable as it diverges more and more from the real system.
</p><p>
"Run most services in a mostly-isolated development environment,
calling out to a few hard-to-run external services" doesn't count.
Those few external services on the edge of the mostly-isolated development environment are often the most crucial ones;
without the ability to run modified versions of them, your development process is crippled.
Furthermore, being dependent on external services greatly complicates where and how you can run the system;
it's much harder to, for example, run tests with the system on every commit if that will access external services.
</p><p>
"Run all the services that make up the system in an isolated development environment" counts;
it's the bare minimum requirement.
Bonus points if this can be done completely on localhost,
without using an off-host cluster deployment system.
</p><p>
Without the ability to actually run the entire system in this way while developing,
many evil practices will tend to become common.
</p><ul>
  <li>
    Testing is harder and far less representative,
    and therefore many issues can only be found when changes are deployed to production.
  </li><li>
    In turn, production deployment will cause issues more often,
    and so deployment will be more slow and less frequent.
  </li><li>
    Deploying the system to new environments is more difficult,
    since the developers aren't able to actually run the system.
    Existing practices in production will be cargo-culted and copied around indefinitely,
    even when they are unnecessary or actively harmful.
  </li><li>
    Exploratory usage of the system is very difficult,
    so it will be harder to consider using the system for purposes outside what it was originally developed for,
    and new use cases will become rare.
  </li><li>
    Downstream clients who depend on the system will also suffer all these issues,
    since without the ability to run the upstream system in development,
    they can't run their own entire system, which is a superset of the upstream system.
</li></ul>
Running the entire system during development is the first step to preventing these issues.
Further steps include writing automated tests for the system (which can be run repeatedly during development),
and using, as much as possible, the same code to run the system in development and in production.
<p>
Developers of large or legacy systems that cannot already be run in their entirety during development
often believe that it is impractical to run the entire system during development.
They'll talk about the many dependencies of their system,
how it requires careful configuration of a large number of hosts,
or how it's too complex to get reliable behavior.
</p><p>
In my experience, they're always wrong.
These systems can be run locally during development with a relatively small investment of effort.
Typically, these systems are just ultimately not as complicated as people think they are;
once the system's dependencies are actually known and understood rather than being cargo-culted or assumed,
running the system, and all its dependencies, is straightforward.
</p><p>
Being able to run your entire system during development is just about the most basic requirement for a software project.
It's not, on its own, sufficient for your development practices to be high quality;
but if you can't do this, then you're not even in the running.
</p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://catern.com/run.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26236908</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:20:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Commodore History Part 1: The Commodore Pet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26236320">thread link</a>) | @SQL2219
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-4839">
														
							
														
							
														
							<div>
															<div>
									<p>When you watch documentaries about early computer innovations, particularly the late 70s, early 1980s, most of the documentaries tend to focus on Apple and Microsoft, and maybe IBM as the big innovators. But, I think often companies like Commodore, and Atari, and Tandy don’t get nearly enough credit for the role that they played.&nbsp; Let’s take a look at the Commodore PET!</p>
<p>Most of my readers are familiar with the Commodore 64, one of the best selling computers of all time. Well renowned for its great graphics and sound, but Commodore history didn’t start with this machine. So, let’s go back a little bit to the late 1970s and figure out where it all started!</p>
<h2>Commodore History Part 1 Video</h2>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eP9y_7it3ZM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>The Processor that Started it All</h2>
<p>It all began in 1974 when Chuck Peddle and a group of engineers started up a chip fabrication company called MOS Technology. Most of these guys had worked at Motorola on the 6800 processor, and so they set out to develop a compatible CPU known as the 6501 that could simply be substituted for the much more expensive Motorola CPU. As you might imagine, Motorola sued and to make a long story short, the 6502 was born, which was pretty much the same chip but changed just enough that it was no longer completely compatible with the 6800.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png"><img data-attachment-id="4855" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0002-the-6502-was-born/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0002 – The 6502 was born" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="The 6502 Processor" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0002-The-6502-was-born.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>Since the chip was no longer compatible with the 6800, customers would need some way to test the chip. In 1976 Chuck Peddle also designed the KIM-1 development computer. This was a single board computer that used the 6502, and could be programmed in machine language from the keypad on the top. However, later it was possible to connect a dumb-terminal display and actually run BASIC. Programs could be saved to a cassette tape. The computer proved to be popular with hobbyists as well as engineers.</p>
<p>The 6502 would go on to be a huge success and eventually found its way into the Apple II series, the Atari 2600, the Nintendo Entertainment System, the entire line of Atari 8-Bit computers, the BBC Micro, and of course the entire line of Commodore 8-Bit machines. But back to 1976 for the moment. MOS Technologies was bought up by Commodore Business Machines, who at this point was primarily in the calculator business. Chuck Peddle managed to convince Commodore boss Jack Tramiel that calculators were a dead-end business and that they needed to produce a computer to compete with the upcoming Apple II.</p>
<h2>The MOS Technology KIM-1</h2>
<p>In 1977 the Commodore PET 2001 was born, using much of the same design as the KIM-1. Much like the Apple II, the PET was all inclusive, having an integrated monitor, keyboard, and cassette tape storage device. 1977 was a big year for the personal computer revolution. With the market introduction of the big 3, the Apple II, Commodore PET, and TRS-80 computer, it was the first time that a regular person could buy an affordable computer without having to assemble it themselves.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png"><img data-attachment-id="4856" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0003-the-kim-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0003 – The KIM 1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0003-The-KIM-1.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>The cool thing about the PET is that it was actually designed by the same guy who designed the 6502 processor. If you look at the prices of the big 3, you’ll see the PET was competitively priced. Although the Apple II did have superior hardware, which we’ll get into shortly, the PET did have the advantage that it came with a monitor and tape drive, where the Apple II required those as separate purchases.</p>
<h2>A Closer Look at the PET</h2>
<p>Let’s take a closer look at the design of the Commodore PET. The first thing I want to draw your attention to is the keyboard. It’s insane, and it will drive you insane if you actually try to type on it. One thing that isn’t communicated well by video and pictures is just how small this keyboard is. The main part, excluding the number pad measures just 6in. by 2.75in. Just to put that into perspective, my iPhone 6 will essentially cover the entire keyboard. The Apple mini keyboard is actually huge by comparison.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png"><img data-attachment-id="4857" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0004-the-pet-keyboard/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0004 – The PET Keyboard" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="the pet keyboard" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0004-The-PET-Keyboard.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>The keyboard size isn’t the only problem. They layout is crazy. While the keys are technically in a QWERTY arrangement, normally the rows are offset creating diagonal lines. Not so on the PET. They are squared up. The weirdness doesn’t end there. The space bar is tiny! Normally you would expect numbers across the top row of keys, but there aren’t any. Instead you have just symbols. If you want to type a number, you have to use the number pad.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png"><img data-attachment-id="4859" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0005-the-pet-keyboard-will-drive-you-insane/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0005 – The PET Keyboard will drive you insane" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="PET keyboard is insane" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0005-The-PET-Keyboard-will-drive-you-insane.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>What is even more infuriating is the symbols. For example, if I want to type a Dollar sign or a number sign, I would instinctively press shift before the key. However, when I do that I wind up with a totally different character instead of the one I wanted. Then there’s the cursor keys. Notice that there are only 2 of them. One key cursors down, and the other key cursors right. If you want to reverse that, you have to hold down the shift key. So by using the combination of the cursor keys and shift you can cursor anywhere on the screen.&nbsp; The little back arrow? You might think that’s a backspace key. But, it’s not. It actually prints that character on the screen, and so when you make a mistake, and believe me you will, you’re going to go to push this key and it’s not going to fix your mistake and you’re going to go even more insane than you were before. The actual delete key is all the way over at the other side of the number pad.</p>
<p>To be fair, when this computer came out in 1977, most of the customers had never even used a personal computer before or a computer of any kind and so they didn’t have any pre-conceptions for what a keyboard layout should be – like we do today. It probably wasn’t quite as weird for them as it would be for us.</p>
<h2>Opening the Commodore PET</h2>
<p>Let’s take a look inside the PET, it opens like the cab of a semi truck, and even gives you a little kick stand to hold it open. Looking at these 16 RAM chips, you might think the PET came with a lot of RAM. But, you’d be wrong. The original PET only came with 4K of RAM. These are 1K by 4-bit static RAM chips. Being that cost was such a consideration for this computer, you might be wondering why they didn’t use the cheaper dynamic RAM, or DRAM? Well, static ram was and still is today much more expensive than dynamic RAM. However, DRAM has one drawback, it requires that it is refreshed every so often, which requires additional circuitry to handle that. When you’re dealing with only 4K, it actually ended up being cheaper just to use static RAM.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png"><img data-attachment-id="4860" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0006-opening-the-pet/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0006 – Opening the PET" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="opening the PET" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0006-Opening-the-PET.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>OK. So 4K is a ridiculously small amount or RAM, but it’s worse than that because the operating system actually needs at least 1K of that, leaving about 3K left over for the user. So how much is 3K of RAM? Well, the screen on the pet is 40-characters by 25-lines, meaning you need 1,000 bytes of RAM, or almost an entire kilobyte just to store one screen full of text. Essentially you had enough RAM for about 3 screens of text! To be fair though, the Apple II and TRS-80 only had 4K when they came out as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png"><img data-attachment-id="4861" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0007-the-pet-ram-chips/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0007 – The PET RAM chips" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="PET RAM chips" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0007-The-PET-RAM-chips.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>This particular PET has been upgraded a little daughter board. It’s an aftermarket 32K RAM expansion module, and that’s why it shows 31K available to BASIC on the boot screen. Let’s take a closer look at this cassette drive. This was actually just an off-the-shelf cassette recorder that Commodore bought and slightly modified. You can see the whole unit is actually mounted, in a rather clunky way in my opinion. The cassette drive was really the only storage device available for the PET at first. And with 4K of RAM, this wasn’t much of a problem.</p>
<h2>The PET Disk Drives</h2>
<p>It wasn’t until 1979 that Commodore came out with a matching disk drive. Since the PET was never really designed to use a disk drive, they decided to use the IEEE-488 parallel port as a means to connect the disk drive.&nbsp; Unlike the Apple II, the Commodore PET has no card slots inside so there’s nowhere to add a floppy disk controller card. So, what they had to do was essentially design an entire computer inside the floppy drive unit, which would handle controlling the floppy drives as well as an entire disk operating system.</p>
<p><a href="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png"><img data-attachment-id="4862" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0001-the-pet-8050-disk-drive/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0001 – The PET 8050 Disk Drive" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i1.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0001-The-PET-8050-Disk-Drive.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>Indeed if you take a look inside the disk drive, you’ll see it’s quite sophisticated, having it’s own 6502 processor, RAM, ROM, and I/O controllers. The PET didn’t really interact with information on the disks directly, rather it would send commands to the disk drive, such as telling it to fetch a file, and then the disk drive would take care of all of the work of finding the right data on the disk. In fact, it could even copy files or even entire disks from one drive to the other all by itself, just with a single command.</p>
<p>The PET was popular with schools and found its way into many computer labs. And while the disk drive was expensive, one of these floppy drive units could actually be connected to multiple PETs at the same time, thus saving space and money. In fact, you can see this arrangement being used in this photo from a computer lab where each table has 8 PETs connected to a single floppy drive and printer.</p>
<p><a href="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png"><img data-attachment-id="4863" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0010-the-pet-8080-disk-drive-chained/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0010 – The PET 8080 Disk Drive chained" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="chained PETs to disk drives" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i2.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0010-The-PET-8080-Disk-Drive-chained.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<h2>The Commodore PET’s Display</h2>
<p>Let’s talk about the screen on the PET. The original model here is black and white. A lot of people assume it’s green, but that actually wasn’t until later models. The original one was black and white. In fact, there’s not even any grayscale. It’s just literally two colors, black and white. The screen was controlled by a clone of the Motorola 6845 CRT controller, which was also used in the IBM CGA card, among other computers. However, there was no circuitry here for color.</p>
<p><a href="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png"><img data-attachment-id="4883" data-permalink="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/commodore-history-part-1-the-pet-0025-the-commodore-pet-black-and-white-display/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?fit=1280%2C720" data-orig-size="1280,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Commodore History Part 1 The Pet 0025 – The Commodore PET Black and White Display" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?fit=300%2C169" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?fit=1024%2C576" loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?resize=750%2C422" alt="Commodore PET Display" width="750" height="422" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?resize=1024%2C576 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?resize=300%2C169 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?resize=768%2C432 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?resize=600%2C338 600w, https://i0.wp.com/www.the8bitguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Commodore-History-Part-1-The-Pet-0025-The-Commodore-PET-Black-and-White-Display.png?w=1280 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1"></a></p>
<p>There are also no graphics modes. I mean, literally <em>none</em>. There is no way to put graphics on this machine at all. And what’s worse is that the character set is in ROM and it cannot be moved, so there’s no way to modify what the characters look like. So, you are pretty much stuck with putting characters on the screen and only the characters that came built into ROM. And that’s it.</p>
<h2>PETSCII</h2>
<p>However, there are 256 characters using a special character set called PETASCII or later just shortened to PETSCII. The character …</p></div></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/">http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.the8bitguy.com/4839/commodore-history-part-1-the-commodore-pet/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26236320</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 12:03:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Saving the World with Bayesian Modeling]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26235876">thread link</a>) | @twiecki
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://www.pymc-labs.io/blog-posts/saving-the-world/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.pymc-labs.io/blog-posts/saving-the-world/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            

    <div>
        <div>
            <div>
                
                <div>
                    
                        <h4>Saving the world with Bayesian modeling</h4>
                    
                    <p>After I left Quantopian in 2020, something interesting happened: various companies contacted me inquiring about
consulting to help them with their PyMC3 models.</p>
<p>Usually, I don't hear how people are using <a href="https://docs.pymc.io/">PyMC3</a> -- they mostly show up on
<a href="https://github.com/pymc-devs/pymc3">GitHub</a> or <a href="https://discourse.pymc.io/">Discourse</a> when something isn't working
right. So, hearing about all these really cool projects was quite exciting. However, I couldn't possibly take all of
these projects on by myself.</p>
<p>Thus, it was time to assemble a team of the most badass Bayesian modelers the world had ever seen -- the Bayesian
Avengers, if you will. Fortunately, I did not have to venture far, as PyMC3 had already attracted exactly these types
of people.</p>
<p>This brings me to the Big Announcement: For the last few months, we have quietly been building
<a href="https://pymc-labs.io/">PyMC Labs</a>, a Bayesian modeling consultancy.
<a href="https://www.pymc-labs.io/team/">We have an amazing team</a> consisting of three neuroscience PhDs, mathematicians,
social scientists, a SpaceX rocket scientist, and the host of the famous
<a href="https://www.learnbayesstats.com/">‘Learning Bayesian Statistics’ podcast</a>. All of us are united in our mission:</p>
<blockquote>
    <p>Saving the world with Bayesian modeling</p>
    
</blockquote><p>Does this sound a bit grandiose? Probably. Is this true? I firmly believe it is. There are so many important problems
the world faces today -- from climate change to COVID19, from education to poverty -- and Bayesian modeling can play a
critical role in solving these problems. Let me explain why.</p>
<h2 id="it-is-already-doing-it">It is already doing it</h2><p>I would not have imagined it when I started contributing to PyMC, but the science PyMC3 has directly enabled ranges
from <a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=pymc3+climate&amp;btnG=">climate science</a> and biology to
astronomy and zoology, and everything in between.</p>
<p>For instance, it was used to predict the spread of COVID19 in a recent
<a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/369/6500/eabb9789.full">Science paper</a>,
as well as <a href="https://rtlive.de/global.html">track the reproduction factor in real-time</a>.
In both cases, the benefit of PyMC3 was its ease-of-use and the ability to integrate scientific domain knowledge and
get honest uncertainty estimation in a highly volatile and uncertain situation.</p>
<p>Now I know you’re very observant and I hear you thinking: “wait a minute, those benefits of Bayesian modeling sound
quite general, so why would they be only valid for epidemiology?”. And indeed they aren’t! For similar benefits,
PyMC3 is also used to <a href="https://github.com/exoplanet-dev/exoplanet">find planets outside of our solar system</a>
and <a href="https://github.com/hvasbath/beat">detect earthquakes</a>. One of my coworkers here at PyMC Labs uses it for
<a href="https://share.streamlit.io/alexandorra/pollsposition_website/main/gp-popularity-app.py">electoral and political forecasting</a>,
because polls are noisy, scarce and need to be completed by domain knowledge -- one of the perfect settings for
Bayesian inference!</p>
<p>With all of this, at the time of writing, the <a href="https://peerj.com/articles/cs-55/">PyMC3 paper</a> has been cited over 930
times and is in the top 10 most cited articles of the entire PeerJ journal.</p>
<h2 id="solving-business-problems">Solving Business Problems</h2><p>Beyond scientific research, I find that PyMC3 is the perfect tool to also solve various business problems.
And indeed it’s already successfully used in production at companies as big and diverse as SpaceX, Roche,
Netflix, Deliveroo and HelloFresh.</p>
<p>This diversity means that the <a href="https://www.pymc-labs.io/clients/">PyMC Labs team intervenes</a> to, for instance,
<a href="https://support.everysk.com/hc/en-us/articles/1500001040721-Private-Investments">build complex models from the latest finance research</a>;
optimize supply chains for food delivery; build software from top to bottom for pharmaceutical applications;
speed up and extend models for the farm tech industry; train and enhance any data science team’s Bayesian stats
capacities, etc.</p>
<h2 id="prediction-vs-inference">Prediction Vs Inference</h2><p>As data science has exploded in the last decade I have always been surprised by the over-emphasis on prediction-focused
machine learning. For far too long, it has been hailed as the solution to most of our data science problems.</p>
<p>I believe that the potential of this is way overblown. Not because it doesn't work -- algorithms like deep nets or
random forests are extremely powerful at extracting non-linear predictive patterns from large data sets -- but rather
because most data science problems are not simple <em>prediction</em> but rather <em>inference</em> problems.</p>
<p>In addition, we often already have a lot of knowledge about our problem: knowledge of certain structure in our data
set (like nested data, that some variables relate to some but not other parameters) and knowledge of which range of
values we expect certain parameters of our model to fall into. Prediction-focused ML does not allow us to include any
of this information, that's why it requires so much data.</p>
<p>With Bayesian statistics, we don't have to learn everything from data as we translate this knowledge into a custom model.
Thus, rather than changing our problem to fit the solution, as is common with ML, we can tailor the solution to best
solve the problem at hand. I like to compare this with Playmobil vs Lego:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.pymc-labs.io/blog-posts/saving-the-world/playlego.jpeg" alt=""></p>
<p>Playmobil just gives you a single toy you can't change while Lego (i.e Bayes here) gives you building blocks to build
the toy you actually want. In Bayesian modeling, these building blocks are probability distributions.</p>
<p>But how do you do this in practice? This is where PyMC3 comes in, as it allows you to specify your models as Python
code and automatically estimate it without requiring manual mathematical derivations. Due to recent theoretical and
technological advances, this also runs quickly and scales to complex models on large(ish) data sets.</p>
<h2 id="serving-our-mission">Serving our mission</h2><p>So how do we best make progress on our mission?</p>
<p>First, we will continue to make PyMC3 the best, most user-friendly and scalable Bayesian modeling package out there.
We are well set up to do this, having a friendly API, a huge user-base, and a large developer team of over 20 active
members. With our renewed focus on
<a href="https://pymc-devs.medium.com/the-future-of-pymc3-or-theano-is-dead-long-live-theano-d8005f8a0e9b">PyMC3 on Theano with a JAX backend</a>
all our resources will go towards this goal.</p>
<p>Second, our new PyMC consultancy will support this endeavour. It allows us to directly help clients use these powerful,
customizable methods to solve their business problems, thereby increasing adoption and recognition.
As a great side effect, these client projects also help us find things that need to be fixed, improved or optimized
in PyMC3, thereby lifting all (Bayesian) boats instead of just the happy fews’.</p>
<p>So far, this has been an incredibly rewarding and exhilarating journey. Even though it is still early, we are learning
a lot about which areas Bayesian modeling is particularly well suited for but also what would make PyMC3 even better.
Without spoiling a future blog post that will go into more detail about what we have learned applying these methods,
the best use-cases include (but aren’t limited to) <strong>incorporating domain knowledge, building bespoke models and
quantifying uncertainty around estimates</strong>.</p>
<p><em>Sounds familiar? If you or your company has a problem for which prediction-based ML is not a good fit, I'd love to talk
to you at <a href="mailto:thomas.wiecki@pymc-labs.io">thomas.wiecki@pymc-labs.io</a>. This is just the beginning and
I hope you will join us on this marvelous journey.</em></p>

                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>


        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.pymc-labs.io/blog-posts/saving-the-world/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26235876</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 10:58:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I heat my home by mining crypto currencies]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 485 | Comments 376 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26235414">thread link</a>) | @geek_at
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://blog.haschek.at/2021/how-i-heat-my-home-by-mining.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.haschek.at/2021/how-i-heat-my-home-by-mining.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <div>
                            <p>After <a href="https://blog.haschek.at/2018/making-a-smartmeter.html">building my own smart meter using 4$ in parts</a> I started checking my electricity usage every day, which made me realize how expensive it is to heat your home. Especially since all heat and warm water in my low-energy house is made with electricity. I do have 4.8 kwp solar panels on my roof but in winter they don't cover too much for obvious reasons.</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/3de1wj.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/3de1wj.png"><figcaption>On cold days I pay up to 6€ for electricity per day</figcaption></a></figure>

<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/kenth4.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/kenth4.png"><figcaption>Nilan Compact P. Heating air and also has a 200L boiler</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>My house is heated (and cooled) with a central ventilation system powered by a heat pump. Basically my heat pump is pulling in fresh air from outside, heating it and blowing it in all rooms and making hot water. Also I have infrared panels in every room for the <em>really</em> cold days.</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/gc0kss.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/gc0kss.jpg"><figcaption>Central heating</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>It's pretty smart and even uses the absorbed heat of the house before venting it out to warm the fresh air but it has a major downside during cold days:</p>
<h4>The outside temperature has to be warmed up to room temperature by the ventilation system</h4>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/giinr0.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/giinr0.png"><figcaption>Heat exchanger in the Nilan Compact P</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>Since the air has to be heated to room temperature every °C counts. Many heat pumps take heat from the ground to pre-heat (in winter) or pre-cool (in summer) the outside air before sending it to the heat pump but that would have been too expensive for me so I chose the simple method of just using the outside air as-is.</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/sbmusz.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/sbmusz.jpg"><figcaption>How a central ventilation system works - from [meco](https://www.meco.at/produkte/wohnraumlueftung/)</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>Since laying about half a kilometer of air or salt tubes in my back yard was not an option I was looking for better solutions and I found it in the world of crypto currencies.</p>

<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/1flj1s.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/1flj1s.jpg"><figcaption>Crypto currency miner</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>Some crypto currencies (don't call them "crypto", that's lame and wrong) are generated by thousands of people who run dedicated hardware to basically calculate random numbers until one cryptographically correct one is found. <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/tech/how-does-bitcoin-mining-work/">Read more about how it actually works</a></p>
<p>Never mind how it works on a technical level, the main takeaway is that you can put some device in your house that uses electricity and produces heat. In exchange you get shares of that crypto currency coins like Ethereum or Bitcoin which you can sell on a trading platform.</p>

<p>I had 4 older AMD <strong>R9 390 GPUs</strong> laying around (for the nVidia crowd that's basically on a level with a GTX 970) and I thought it could work. They are not ideal for mining because even though they have a good hash rate (30MH/s), they are very power hungy and will use about 900 Watts combined. Mordern cards would perform much better. To see if they could still make a profit I checked the <a href="https://www.cryptocompare.com/mining/calculator/eth">Cryptocompare Mining calculator</a>, put in my electricity price, the consumption and the hashrate of these cards and was surprised by the results.</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/024r92.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/024r92.png"><figcaption>Not just worth it - If the price is stable I would even make a profit of <strong>4000$ a year</strong></figcaption></a></figure>
<p>So at the time I was making about <strong>3.8$ profit a day</strong> with the miner. Meaning on cold days I'd half my power bill even after paying for the electricity the miner is using. But that's just step one of the plan.</p>
<p>Now that we know it <em>is</em> worth it while the Ethereum price is higher than 900$, let's see what we can do with the heat.</p>

<p>Each of these cards are running at about 80°C (176°F). I can just harvest this heat and send it to my heatpump so it would need less energy warming the outside air. Basically I had two options.</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/6by5tc.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/6by5tc.png"><figcaption>My 4 GPUs in a 4U server case</figcaption></a></figure>
<h2>Option 1: Lazy heating from within the house</h2>
<p>The central ventilation system does not only push fresh air into the house, it also sucks out the used air and uses this air in the heat exchanger to pre-heat the outside air.</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/gfuy33.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/gfuy33.jpg"><figcaption>Sucking vent before going to the heat exchanger</figcaption></a></figure>
<p>Placing the miner in this room will cause the warm air to be sucked in and pushed directly into the heat exchanger together with the used air from the house. This is the lazy method because I don't really have to do anything but put the miner in the same room as the heat pump but of course there is a downside.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Pro</th>
<th>Contra</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Easy to set up</td>
<td>Room heating up too much, decreasing mining performance</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>No further investment needed</td>
<td>Limited space in the heating room</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>Option 2: Running the miner outside the house, funneling in the heat</h2>
<p>Since I'm only running the miner when it's cold outside (and the price is high enough) I can use the cold, dry outside air to cool the miners and also recycling the warm air they produce to feed into the heat pump. I asked the technician who installed the heat pump and he said that it's a good idea.</p>
<p>So the plan is that I have the GPUs in the server case and connect the front of the case to my heatpumps inlet.</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/0hrdt6.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/0hrdt6.jpg"><figcaption>Server case closed</figcaption></a></figure>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/5ek604.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/5ek604.jpg"><figcaption>Ventilation duct pipe and funnel</figcaption></a></figure>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/o2oysb.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/o2oysb.png"><figcaption>Example on my house. Air is sucked in from above the garage so the pipe has to be connected here</figcaption></a></figure>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Pro</th>
<th>Contra</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Using pre-heated outside air</td>
<td>Many headaches for parts and installation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Miner GPUs will be kept cool which results in better hash rates</td>
<td>Surprisingly pricy</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p>Okay so far the mining gains cover <strong>half of my electricity (=heating) bill</strong> but what difference does the pre-heated intake air make?</p>
<p>Let's see</p>
<figure><a href="https://pictshare.net/8cu9s3.png"><img loading="lazy" src="https://pictshare.net/1024/8cu9s3.png"><figcaption>Results before and after pre-heating the air</figcaption></a></figure>

<p>This turned out much better than I hoped for. Who has ever heard of a heating system that lowers your bill when running? Also on sunny days the miner and whole heat pump are running fully on solar energy collected on my roof.</p>
<hr>

<p>(updated when new questions come up)</p>
<h2>Q: How long will the Miner stay profitable?</h2>
<p><strong>A:</strong> My mining rig will stay profitable until the ETH price is at ~900$. Below that it'll no longer match it's own electricity bill. Might still be worth it afterwards because it does lower the electricity need of my heat pump</p>
<h2>Q: What software are you running on your miner?</h2>
<p><strong>A:</strong> I'm using <a href="https://simplemining.net/">Simple Mining</a>, it's basically a mining OS based on Ubuntu. It does all the configuration and fine-tuning for you and I had much better hash rates than on my DIY windows box. But it costs like 2$ a month to use the service and I think they also mine 1% of the time for themselves.</p>
<h2>Q: What about taxes? Can you keep 100% of your mining earnings?</h2>
<p><strong>A:</strong> That's different for every state and country. <a href="https://www.bmf.gv.at/themen/steuern/sparen-veranlagen/Steuerliche-Behandlung-von-Krypto-Assets.html">In Austria</a> mining is considered commercial activity and you have to pay taxes but can deduct electricity and hardware costs.</p>
<p>If you keep your coins longer than the one-year speculation period, it's tax free.</p>
                            </div>
                        </div>
                    </div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.haschek.at/2021/how-i-heat-my-home-by-mining.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26235414</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 09:34:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Amateur Tramp – A Walk of Ten Thousand Miles Around Australia]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 129 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26235348">thread link</a>) | @corpmedia
<br/>
February 23, 2021 | https://greatestadventurers.com/the-amateur-tramp-the-man-who-walked-around-a-continent/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://greatestadventurers.com/the-amateur-tramp-the-man-who-walked-around-a-continent/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
				<div id="content">
			
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">
			
<article id="post-107" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="">
	<div>
					
			
		<div itemprop="text">
			<p><strong>The Amateur Tramp – A Walk of Ten Thousand Miles Around Australia.</strong> Thousands of people have climbed the highest peaks of the Himalayas. Hundreds have visited <a href="https://www.un.org/en/member-states/">all nations on UN’s list</a> and 12 made it all the way to the moon. But this guy..!</p>
<p>In 1921, <em>Aidan de Brune</em> packed his backpack and walked around the entire continent of Australia by the coastline. We are (almost) sure he is the only person who ever did that. Even more impressive, he did it all alone and without assistance.</p>
<p>The amazing adventure was documented by himself along the way as he wrote articles about it for the <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/auhome/index.html">Australian newspaper Daily Mail</a> along the route.</p>
<figure id="attachment_110" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-110"><img loading="lazy" src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02.jpg" alt="The Man who walked around Australia free PDF" width="820" height="733" srcset="https://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02.jpg 820w, https://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02-300x268.jpg 300w, https://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02-768x687.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 820px) 100vw, 820px" data-srcset="https://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02.jpg 820w, https://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02-300x268.jpg 300w, https://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02-768x687.jpg 768w" data-src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Diary-02.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="><figcaption id="caption-attachment-110">The route around Australia</figcaption></figure>
<p>The walk took about two and a half year, and the accomplishment made&nbsp;Aidan de Brune famous. This book about the walk is written by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/7412219.Colin_Choat">Colin Choat</a>, who kindly allowed us to post the book here.</p>
<p>Download ‘The Amateur Tramp’ here:</p>
<h3><strong><a href="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/The-Amateur-Tramp.pdf">The Amateur Tramp</a></strong></h3>
		</div>

				
			</div>
</article>

			

					</main>
	</div>

	

	</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://greatestadventurers.com/the-amateur-tramp-the-man-who-walked-around-a-continent/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26235348</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 09:25:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Macamathehou in Lincolnshire and people named Muhammad in medieval England]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232817">thread link</a>) | @pepys
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-4764828100605476219" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p>The aim of the following draft is to offer some thoughts on a local name from thirteenth-century Lincolnshire, <i>Macamathehou</i>, that involves a version of the Arabic name Muhammad (Middle English <i>Makomet/Macamethe</i>, Old French <i>Mahomet</i>). Whilst it has been plausibly seen as an instance of a variant of the name of Muhammed being used to mean 'heathen', 'pagan idol' or similar (based on the false but common medieval Christian belief that the prophet Muhammad was worshipped as a god), here in reference to a barrow that was considered to be a pre-Christian site, it is worth noting that there are a small number of people with names and surnames derived from Arabic <i>Muḥammad</i> apparently living in twelfth- to fourteenth-century England.</p><table><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-w4ER6e7-JsI/X7AZDfw1bCI/AAAAAAADLhw/ULvdpDuWKwAelDOKu23y5ZJFgTBdhTdMgCLcBGAsYHQ/s879/macamathehou-large.jpg"><img data-original-height="355" data-original-width="500" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hhv-Lu79n_o/X7AZDcDbe6I/AAAAAAADLhs/RS2oeTJ3IocU1SGmohUZdB7Q-nFhCH-sgCLcBGAsYHQ/s16000/macamathehou-500.jpg"></a></td></tr><tr><td><i>Figure 1: the location of Macamathehou between Spridlington and Faldingworth parishes in Lincolnshire; click the image or <a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-w4ER6e7-JsI/X7AZDfw1bCI/AAAAAAADLhw/ULvdpDuWKwAelDOKu23y5ZJFgTBdhTdMgCLcBGAsYHQ/s879/macamathehou-large.jpg">here</a> for a larger version (image: C. R. Green/OpenStreetMap and its contributors).</i><i>&nbsp;</i></td></tr></tbody></table>
<p>The existence of the intriguing local name <i>Macamathehou</i> in the parish of Spridlington, Lincolnshire, was first noted in 2001 by Kenneth Cameron, John Field and John Insley in <i>Place-Names of Lincolnshire VI </i>(<i>PNL</i>), with both attestations of the name dating from the thirteenth century (the reign of King Henry III, 1216–72).(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn1">1</a>) They identify the two elements of the name as being Old Norse <i>haugr</i>, 'mound, barrow', and Middle English <i>Makomet/Macamethe</i>, which derives from the name of the prophet Muhammad (Medieval Latin <i>Machometus/Mahumetus</i>, Anglo-Norman <i>Mahumet/Mahomet/Machomete</i>, Old French <i>Mahomet</i> &lt; Arabic <i>Muḥammad</i>, probably via an Arabic regional form <i>Maḥammad</i>).(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn2">2</a>) Needless to say, this solution is most intriguing and has, moreover, found favour with other place-name specialist, including the <i>Vocabulary of English Place-Names </i>(<i>VEPN</i>) and Richard Coates.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn3">3</a>)</p><p>As to the import of this name, the easiest conclusion—and the one endorsed by&nbsp;<i>PNL</i>, <i>VEPN</i>&nbsp;and Coates—is that the first element, <i>Macamethe/</i><i>Maumate</i> etc, is not functioning simply as a normal Middle English rendering of the name Muhammad/<i>Mahomet</i>, but rather as a word indicative of heathen or pagan idolatry, based on the false but common medieval Christian belief that the prophet Muhammad was worshipped as a god. So, <i>PNL </i>describes the name as meaning 'the heathen mound', with the first element being 'a corrupt ME [Middle English] form of the name of the prophet Mohammed, for which <i>v.</i>&nbsp;MED [<i>Middle English Dictionary</i>], s.v. <i>Makomete</i>, also used to denote a pagan god or an idol'.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn4">4</a>) This is taken up by Richard Coates, who says that it has been suggested, 'with great plausibility', that <i>Macamathehou </i>in Spridlington parish 'is a Middle English name meaning "Mahomet mound", i.e. "heathen mound"', and points to 'the repeated compound of OE <i>hæðen </i>+ <i>byrgels "</i>heathen burial"' as a potential comparison.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn5">5</a>) Likewise, the <i>VEPN</i>'s draft section on M includes the following discussion:</p>

<blockquote><b>makomet </b>ME, 'idol, pagan god', an application of the name of the Arab prophet Mohammed (commonly though mistakenly believed by medieval Christians to have been worshipped as a god)... It occurs early in
<i>Macamathehou </i>(f.n.) 1216–72 L:6·211 (<b>haugr</b>), presumably to be
interpreted as 'heathen mound'.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn6">6</a>)</blockquote>
<p>On the whole, this interpretation is probably the safest option. There are certainly a handful of references to 'heathen' barrows in Old English charter bounds, for example <i>of leofwynne mearce to þam hæþenan beorge</i>, 'from Leofwine's boundary to the heathen barrow', in the charter S956 relating to Drayton, Hampshire, and dated AD 1019, although none are recorded from Lincolnshire.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn7">7</a>) It has also been suggested that the Lincolnshire names Bloater Hill (North Willingham) and Blod Hou (Barrow-on-Humber) derive from Old Norse <i>blóthaugr</i>, 'a sacrificial mound', whilst other names involving <i>haugr</i> certainly refer to supernatural/demonic creatures—for example, <i>Gasthehowe</i>/<i>Gastehowe</i>, Ashby Puerorum (Lincolnshire), recorded in the thirteenth century and deriving from Middle English <i>gast</i>/Old English <i>gāst</i>, 'ghost, dead-spirit', or names like Scratters (<i>Scrathou</i>, in Hayton, East Riding of Yorkshire) and Scrathowes (<i>Scrathou</i>, in Osmotherley, North Riding of Yorkshire), which derive from Old Norse <i>skratti</i>, 'devil, wizard'&nbsp;+ <i>haugr</i>.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn8">8</a>) Furthermore, the Old English compound <i>hæðen&nbsp;</i>+ <i>byrgels</i>, 'heathen burial', does indeed recur frequently in Late Saxon charter bounds, with these names often said to be identifiable with barrows in the landscape.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn9">9</a>)</p><p>On the other hand, there are some possible issues with this explanation, and other interpretations are possible of Spridlington's <i>Macamathehou</i>. First, the comparison with the many instances of the OE compound <i>hæðen </i>+ <i>byrgels</i>, ‘heathen burial’, is perhaps not as convincing as it might seem. Not only is a link between this term and barrows only demonstrable in a handful of instances, but Andrew Reynolds has also suggested that the sense of the term was primarily not ‘pagan’, but rather ‘unconsecrated’, and that it denoted burials of executed offenders and other social outcasts, which renders the proposed value of these names as support for interpreting <i>Macamathehou&nbsp; </i>as meaning ‘heathen mound’ open to significant debate.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn10">10</a>) Second, if the above is correct, then this would be the only known instance of a derivative of the Arabic name Muhammad being used in a place-name to indicate a 'heathen mound' or similar, which is potentially concerning—the other elements noted above all recur in multiple names. Third, the element identified by <i>PNL </i>and <i>VEPN</i> as being present in <i>Macamethehou</i> is Middle English <i>Makomet(e)</i>. The <i>Middle English Dictionary</i> (<i>MED</i>) on <i>Makomet(e)/</i><i>Macamethe</i> etc, however, makes it clear that the primary use of this word in Middle English is as a form of the name Muhammad, not as a word referring to an 'idol'/'pagan god', with the vast majority of quotations provided by the <i>MED </i>referring either the prophet Muhammad or people named Muhammad; the only exceptions are a single quotation from Layamon's <i>Brut </i>(<i>c.</i>&nbsp;1200, <i>mahimet</i>, lacking the <i>-c-</i>), and three from two later texts.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn11">11</a>) The form of the name Muhammad that <i>was </i>primarily—although not exclusively—used in the sense 'pagan deity, idol', is rather <i>Maumet/Maumate</i>, mentioned above, deriving from Anglo-Norman <i>Maumet</i>, a reduced form of <i>Mauhoumet</i>, Old French <i>Mahomet/Mahommet</i>.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn12">12</a>)</p>
<p>In this light, it is worth considering whether it is possible that the name <i>Macamathehou</i> could somehow be named from a person named <i>Makomet</i>/Muhammad or similar living in medieval England. Certainly, it should be noted that multiple local names relating to mounds/barrows do seem to be named after people who owned estates or land in the area. For example, Andrew Reynolds draws attention to the bounds of a mid-tenth-century charter for Swallowcliffe, Wiltshire (S468), that records the burial site of a seventh‐century woman whose grave had been cut into an existing mound as <i>Posses hlaew</i>, noting that 'Poss is a male name, and thus the mound is apparently not named after its Anglo‐Saxon occupant', implying that it was instead named after a later estate owner.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn13">13</a>) As Irene Bower long ago pointed out, such a situation can be credibly paralleled in Lincolnshire, with a number of Lincolnshire names involving <i>haugr</i> seeming to contain the same personal-name as is found in the same or a neighbouring parish-name—so, <i>Scalehau </i>(<i>Skalli </i>+ <i>haugr</i>) was located near to Scawby (<i>Skalli</i>&nbsp;+ <i>bȳ</i>), with Kenneth Cameron commenting that the two were 'no doubt named from the same man'; <i>Leggeshou</i> (<i>Leggr </i>+ <i>haugr</i>) was located on the boundary of Legsby parish (<i>Leggr&nbsp;</i>+ <i>bȳ</i>); <i>Katehou/Catehowe </i>(<i>Kati</i>&nbsp;+ <i>haugr</i>) was located in South Cadeby (<i>Kati&nbsp;</i>+ <i>bȳ</i>); and a <i>Grimaldeshawe</i> (<i>Grimaldi </i>+ <i>haugr</i>) was recorded in the neighbouring parish to Grimoldby (<i>Grimaldi</i>&nbsp;+&nbsp;<i>bȳ</i>), perhaps on the boundary between the two.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn14">14</a>)</p><table><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Nu02Jqw5h14/X7WB-D0A8sI/AAAAAAADLvg/p_vwSAkF6RQX5KkB8XMvM6WiC4a1eyI5gCLcBGAsYHQ/s1296/PipeRoll-Mahumet1160-1.jpg"><img data-original-height="216" data-original-width="500" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VAcqNuGj78U/X7WB-YLMzBI/AAAAAAADLvk/_TLGpi35Olg-dWNhgmcuMcZSaz-qhCgdACLcBGAsYHQ/s16000/PipeRoll-Mahumet1160-1-500.jpg"></a></td></tr><tr><td><i>Figure 2: Section from the Pipe Roll Society publication of&nbsp;The Great Roll of the Pipe for the Seventh Year of the Reign of King Henry the Second, A.D. 1160–1161 (London: Wyman &amp; Sons, 1885), p. 10, dealing with Mahumet of Wiltshire (image: <a href="https://archive.org/details/piperollsociety04pipeuoft/page/10/mode/2up">Internet Archive</a>).</i></td></tr></tbody></table><p>As to the likelihood of someone named Muhammad or one of its Anglo-Norman/Middle English variants (<i>Mahumet</i>,<i> Makomet</i> and similar) actually living in medieval England, this is perhaps less far-fetched than might be assumed. Katharine Keats-Rohan and John Moore have directed attention to the Wiltshire entries of five consecutive Pipe Rolls of Henry II (1160/61–1164/65) that refer to a man named <i>Mahumet, </i>whose name-form Moore considers very difficult to explain as anything other than a rendering of Muhammad and which is accepted as such by the <i>OED </i>and <i>MED</i>. This <i>Mahumet </i>is recorded in the Pipe Rolls only because he was fined for his part in an unlicensed duel with a John de Merleberge, probably in or near Marlborough Castle, and it seems he was not an especially wealthy man, as he was pardoned the last mark of his fine due to his poverty.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn15">15</a>) Furthermore, <i>Mahumet</i> of Wiltshire was not the only man with this name for whom we have evidence from medieval England. For example, a Theobald <i>filius Mahumet</i> (or <i>filius Mahomet</i>) is recorded from early thirteenth-century Hampshire in the Pipe Rolls of Henry III for 1222–24; another man named <i>Mahomet </i>is recorded in 1327, when Edward III issued him and six others a pardon at Newton-on-Ouse, Yorkshire, for 'offenses in Ireland'; and a <i>Mahummet Saraceno</i>&nbsp;occurs in the Close Rolls of Henry III for 1254. Furthermore, a number of people surnamed <i>Mahumet </i>and similar are recorded in documents of the twelfth and thirteenth centuries, for example a Humphrey Mahumet in a charter of Southwick Priory, Hampshire, a Herbert Maumet who was sergeant of Portsmouth in the mid-thirteenth century, and a Radulphus Maumet who is recorded in the reign of King John.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html#fn16">16</a>) Moore also notes the presence of someone bearing another 'apparent Arab name' in twelfth-century Hampshire, a certain <i>Paucamatus</i>, a name that he considers to probably reflect <i>Bakmat</i>, who is recorded in Winchester from 1159/60 until 1183/4 and who is associated with …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html">https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.caitlingreen.org/2021/01/macamathehou-in-lincolnshire.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232817</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 01:20:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The road to electric is filled with tiny cars]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 166 | Comments 243 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232760">thread link</a>) | @jimmy2020
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			<!-- Article Start -->
			
<p><span>I</span>n Beijing’s southwestern outskirts, past a four-lane overpass with sidewalks as wide as the streets themselves, is Zhengyang Road. It has the usual banks, small convenience stores, and noodle houses of many areas in the capital, but it is set apart by a row of about a dozen shops all selling the same thing — tiny electric cars. The cars look, variously, like small Range Rovers, golf carts, trolley cars, or rickshaws with sheet-iron sides, and they are slow. Their fundamental attraction is their price — between $600 and $2,500 — and that drivers can charge them the same way they would a cell phone. They also come with the perks of being loosely regulated. These low-speed electric cars, nicknamed “elderly transport vehicles,” have an enormous market, made up mostly of people who earn very little. And in China, there are a lot of them — <a href="http://english.www.gov.cn/premier/news/202005/29/content_WS5ed058d2c6d0b3f0e9498f21.html">more than 40%</a> of the population, or some 600 million people, make around $150 per month.</p>



<p>On a Sunday afternoon in October, Zhengyang Road is filled with potential customers chatting with store owners.<strong> </strong>Outside a shop with a worn sign, a young couple with a child are in the midst of a heated conversation.<strong> </strong>They came on an electric scooter and are debating whether to leave with a tiny car.</p>



<p>“Don’t we need one for school pickups?” the woman argues. “The children won’t have to put up with the cold in winter.” Her scooter offers no protection from the weather other than oven-mitt-like gloves secured to its handlebars. Her husband counters, “The 1,000 renminbi [$150] quote was for normal batteries, but lithium ones can be five times that. Can’t you just add a windshield to your scooter instead?” The shop owner shows them a cheaper model — which is cheaper because it has no roof. He suggests putting a plastic covering on top.</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 600px(max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="A woman exits a tiny car near a subway station in Beijing.">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<p>Having decided that the future of mobility is electric,<strong> </strong>the Chinese government has subsidized sales of standard electric cars since 2010. With <a href="https://insideevs.com/news/394229/plugin-electric-car-sales-china-2019/">close to 1.18 million sold</a> in 2019, China accounts for just over half of electric-vehicle sales globally. Bill Russo, founder and CEO of advisory firm Automobility Limited, sees a “steady and solid rise” in China’s electric-vehicle sales generally. The country has set a top-down target for electric vehicles to <a href="http://energy.mit.edu/news/chinas-transition-to-electric-vehicles/">make up 40%</a> of car sales by 2030, and Russo thinks they’ll have no problem hitting this goal. Tiny cars,<strong> </strong>which first began appearing in the early 2010s,<strong> </strong>have more than double the sales of regular electric cars but have<strong> </strong>never benefited from subsidies. Nor do advertisements for them air on television — instead, they appear on Kuaishou, a short-video platform popular with people living outside China’s big cities. Alongside streamers selling plums by the thousands, and others telling viewers what long-haul trucker life is like, drivers show off their tiny cars. Su Hua, Kuaishou’s founder, has long maintained that his app’s users are not “cool,” unlike those on Douyin, the TikTok predecessor popular with China’s urban elite. Rather, they are ordinary — the kind of people who might be in the market for miniature cars.</p>



<p>As they don’t technically require licenses, tiny cars tend to be popular with migrant workers, who struggle to pay for driving lessons and other car-related costs. The elderly, too, find tiny cars attractive since, up until October of last year, people over 70 could not apply for a driving license in China. They’re also convenient for anybody who wants a car to pick up groceries or their kids from school: No tiny car is longer than 1.5 meters, and their speed tops out at between 40 and 56 kilometers an hour. They’re for the short trips of daily life, not for traveling from one side of the city to another.</p>



<p>Some cities have banned sales of tiny cars — Beijing did so in 2018. Their production isn’t regulated by the government, and since they can’t be insured in many parts of China, it can be difficult for other drivers to get a payout if a tiny car is involved in an accident. Because tiny-car drivers don’t need to take a driving test, other drivers complain, they often go the wrong way and weave in and out of traffic. But since enforcement is lax, sales have quietly resumed in Beijing over the past two years. These little electric cars now exist in a kind of regulatory gray zone.</p>


    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      
    </figure>

    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      <figcaption>Tiny cars come in a variety of styles and cost between $600 and $2,500.</figcaption>
    </figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>One of the</strong> smaller shops on Zhengyang Road is officially known as Xinlei Scooters, its name emblazoned in white characters on a large red sign above its doors. But inside, past rows of electric scooters, is a smaller, flimsier plaque above the counter announcing its other name: Shitou Cars. This subterfuge is necessary because the police could shut down the operation and confiscate its vehicles if the owners were caught selling tiny cars. Yet because enforcement hasn’t been strict of late, attempts at being covert go only so far: There are several tiny cars parked outside, an open-air showroom.</p>



<p>Xinlei/Shitou’s owner is a middle-aged man with pronounced cheekbones wearing a black tracksuit. He is more attentive to the phone calls he’s constantly receiving than the customers in the shop. It is his wife, with dyed-dark-brown hair and a pink coat, who maintains the sales patter: “I taught an auntie who had never driven a car before. She got the hang of it in three days.” She shows the cars outside to potential customers, opening their doors, instructing people to sit inside, and rolling down the windows. When two old men come in for repair services, her husband finally gets off the phone to deal with them. Meanwhile, two government functionaries in black uniforms pace down the street. They tell one owner to make his storefront tidier, but otherwise overlook the illicit operation.</p>



<p>Part of the reason why tiny cars are so popular is because there has not been an official decision on whether they need license plates. For regular cars, unfettered access to Beijing’s inner city — anywhere within the fifth ring road — is restricted to vehicles with Beijing plates. Licenses for gas cars are distributed through a special system so competitive that it has generated its own black market. License-plate holders can collect up to $2,700 a year by renting them to those who want to drive in the city. In addition to government subsidies, getting around some of the more onerous aspects of the licensing system is one of the main selling points for standard electric cars.</p>



<p>With Beijing temperatures reaching lows of 4 degrees Celsius in wintertime, Xinlei/Shitou has been selling,<strong> </strong>on average, two of its four-wheeled fully enclosed models every day, a saleswoman boasts. Younger couples prefer four wheels, she adds, while older people usually want three. When asked about the possibility of a tiny car being confiscated, she draws in a breath. “Don’t go on the main roads. Don’t make a business out of it,” she advises.</p>



<p>At least one of Zhengyang Road’s customers isn’t listening: Guo Caiying, who works primarily in the construction-supply industry,<strong> </strong>chauffeurs Fengtai residents around her district. She has a sticker on her tiny car’s back window with the phone number of her car dealer. Guo’s car looks like a golf cart, with cushioned brown seats enclosed by windows. A red <em>fudai</em>, a lucky charm, swings from the ceiling, its characters spelling out “peace.” There is enough space for two people to comfortably sit upright but not enough to extend your legs without hitting the plexiglass divider between driver and passenger. The car tops out at 40 kilometers an hour, and<strong> </strong>as a result, Guo never ventures beyond Fengtai — a borderland where urban and rural meet.</p>



<p>Guo wears the uniform of the countryside: a padded jacket. She is from Henan, a province 800 kilometers southwest of Beijing, and speaks its dialect. Guo starts taking calls from her regulars around 7 a.m., arriving at their door whenever they want to be picked up. She stops driving at 9 a.m., when the traffic police begin work. She characterizes her customers as “people with money who sit in offices.” Once, while in the middle of a trip, Guo saw a cop stop a car like hers. She kept driving, but dropped her passenger off before their destination. Now, if a customer calls her after 9:00, she sends her husband to pick them up with his electric scooter. He charges 75 cents (5RMB), which is half her price. Guo’s flat rate was fixed by the tiny-cab drivers who preceded her.</p>



<p>The economy of tiny cars depends on such informal practices.<strong> </strong>When asked whether she would consider undercutting other drivers, Guo is adamant. “No one can break the rules,” she says. There are local WeChat groups for tiny-car drivers that new owners are inducted into upon purchasing one. Within these groups, members swap information on the whereabouts of local cops and whether anyone has been fined or had their car taken away.</p>



<p>Despite the risks, Guo still thinks it’s worth being a tiny-car driver to make a little pocket money.<strong> </strong>Tiny cars are part of a last-mile economy that flourishes at the beginning and end of the workday. Many Fengtai residents are employed at the local high-tech park, which is host to thousands of businesses. It takes 20 minutes to walk from one end of the park to the other, a trip many would rather make by tiny car. The cars’ main competitors are share bikes, which are cheaper but lack space for luggage and can’t be split with a friend. Tiny cars are also more social — a feature Guo tries …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/">https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232760</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 01:12:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nintendo DS-TV-Out Restoration Project]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 218 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232600">thread link</a>) | @max-m
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <section id="main_content">
        

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>During late 2020, we discovered that the Nintendo DS Lite had a leftover feature in its SoC allowing it to easily have cheap hardware video output. With a little circuitry and some software hacks, we were able to restore it and make it usable for anyone. No FPGA’s, no bulky or cumbersome hardware. This mod is specially useful to revive consoles with only the lower screen, being able to watch the upper screen on your TV. Or to create a GBA Macro with additional TV Output.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/DSTVOUT.jpg" width="250" height="250"><br></center>
<center>
  <b>First iteration of the TV-OUT board in action</b>
  </center>

<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>

<p>If you are just interested in installation, this is the current method <strong>while we work on simpler methods</strong> and more features you have requested:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Install the <a href="https://ezflash.sosuke.com/wiki/index.php/Flashme">flashME CFW</a> (Custom FirmWare) on your DS Lite</li>
  <li>Connect the Nintendo DS Lite’s upper screen flex to the PCB board.</li>
  <li>Donwload the “NDS TV OUT ENABLE.nds” homebrew from the <a href="https://github.com/LostNintendoHistory/Lost-NDS-TV">NDS TV OUT repo</a></li>
  <li>Download <a href="https://github.com/DS-Homebrew/TWiLightMenu/releases">Twilight Menu</a></li>
  <li>Copy both the NDS TV OUT ENABLE and Twilight Menu .nds files to a flashcart.</li>
  <li>Use flashme to autoboot into the flashcart. You can do this by pressing A + B + Start + Select while booting. Run Twilight menu, and from there, run the enabler homebrew.</li>
  <li>The console will return to Twilight Menu. Now you can use the buttons on the board to swap between the different screen modes (Upper Screen to TV, Bottom Screen to TV, etc) and launch your games.</li>
</ol>

<hr>

<h2 id="software">Software</h2>

<p>The retail firmware of the Nintendo DS Lite disables this specific feature early in the boot process. To reenable it, we use a custom firmware like flashme, which is very easy to install and is required only once, plus a homebrew. Despite that, we are working on an even simpler solution to make it available to as many people as possible, our own custom firmware which integrates patches to enable this feature directly on boot. Additionally, we are currently working with homebrew developers to integrate control of this new feature into existing software for the DS Lite.</p>

<h2 id="hardware">Hardware</h2>

<p>This feature is only found on the Nintendo DS Lite. Nintendo DS Phat does not contain this feature nor does the Nintendo DSi. It is important to remark that <strong>this is not the same hardware</strong> found on Devkits or other special units. This hardware feature is present in virtually <strong>every single Nintendo DS Lite</strong> out there. The reason why it was left there is unknown, but as said before, it is not related to development units, those use a different video capture hardware. Perhaps Nintendo imagined the Nintendo Switch as early as 2006?</p>

<center><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/PCB_Rev_11.png" width="350" height="400"></center>

<p>We only need a few extra hardware components to make this video signal usable. You will be able to download the schematics and gerber files for our open hardware circuit board <a href="https://github.com/LostNintendoHistory/Lost-NDS-TV">from the repository</a>. The latest version is revision 1.2 which fixes some minor issues with a component in the board.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/Prototype.jpg" width="350" height="350"><br>
</center>
<center>
  <b>First prototype and tests before designing a proper board</b></center>


<p>The final, production-ready board contains a DAC (Digital to Analogue Converter) which turns the 10 bits digital signal at 16.7 MHz provided by the DS Lite into a proper analogue signal. This signal then goes through an operational amplifier and it’s ready to be delivered to your nearest TV trough composite video.</p>

<p>We are currently considering creating an additional PCB revision which would allow to install the mod on consoles without lossing a working upper screen.</p>


      </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232600</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Bombard Story]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232597">thread link</a>) | @jbergstroem
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
				<div id="content">
			
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">
			
<article id="post-618" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="">
	<div>
					
			
		<div itemprop="text">
			<p><strong>The Bombard Story</strong> is the account of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alain_Bombard">Alain Bombard’s</a> amazing journey in 1952 across the <a href="http://greatestadventurers.com/the-north-west-passage-by-roal-amundsen/">Atlantic</a> on a small 14-foot inflatable boat. Alain Bombard left without food or fresh water and sailed 4.400 kilometers. He lost 25 kg. but proved his point: Man can actually survive on ocean water for an extended period of time!</p>
<figure id="attachment_619" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-619"><img loading="lazy" src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/TheBombardStory1953.jpg" alt="The Bombard Story" width="300" height="203" data-src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/TheBombardStory1953.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="><figcaption id="caption-attachment-619">In this small vessel Bombard sailed across the Atlantic – without freshwater</figcaption></figure>
<p>As a doctor, Bombard was concerned about the hundreds of deaths at sea every year related to sailors drinking ocean water. He developed the theory that humans can not just survive but live for years on seawater. This sounds very strange, but his big idea was to begin drinking seawater, while you are still hydrated – and in small quantities. It turns out that saltwater is only dangerous if you are dehydrated and suddenly drink large amounts of it. – The way shipwrecked sailors typically would do when they run out of fresh water. From the book:</p>
<blockquote><p>For some time I had made a study of the resistance of the human organism to privations and had convinced myself that it was possible for an individual to survive beyond the limits normally assigned by physiological science. I had paid particular attention to the case histories of political deportees, prisoners, and undernourished populations. But, with my background as a doctor, for whom the teachings of science remain a dead letter unless they can find practical application, my theoretical studies only seemed to lead to the question: ‘What use can made of this knowledge?’</p></blockquote>
<p>Bombard ate spoonfuls of plankton that he collected in a fine net and he also drank juice made from pressed fish he caught along the way. Sound disgusting, but the man survived and he might have discovered an important piece of knowledge for survival on the ocean.</p>
<p>Download the free PDF e-book here (223 pages/38MB):</p>
<h3><img loading="lazy" src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/PDF-download-e1597850191432.png" alt="" width="35" height="35" data-src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/PDF-download-e1597850191432.png" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">&nbsp;<a href="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/The-Bombard-Story-1953.pdf">The Bombard Story 1953</a></h3>

		</div>

				
			</div>
</article>

			

					</main>
	</div>

	

	</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232597</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:48:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
