<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 12:40:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 12:40:20 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Database Inside Your Codebase]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 60 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26160186">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
<div>
  <article>
    
      <p><img src="https://files.tanagram.app/file/tanagram-data/prod-feifans-blog/joshua-sortino-LqKhnDzSF-8-unsplash.jpg">
      </p>
<p>
Navigating codebases of any meaningful size is difficult. Most of a programmer’s time is spent jumping through the codebase, reading or skimming to build a mental model of the constructs and conventions within it. These constructs — among them: the DSLs, interfaces, and taxonomy of types that exist — are arguably the most important precursor to understanding where and how to make changes. But these constructs only exist in programmers’ heads. It’s difficult or impossible to navigate most codebases through the lens of those constructs; programmers lack “code browsers” that present the underlying code independently of files and the filesystem hierarchy. Yet code browsers that can do so — and we’ll look at some examples below — would be incredibly useful. This is because instances of these constructs can be thought of as records in a database, albeit an ad-hoc, poorly-specified database that can only be queried through carefully-crafted regexes<a href="#fn:1" id="fnref:1" title="see footnote">1</a>.</p>
<p>
In simple cases, some constructs manifest as naming conventions: prefixes in a name may be a rudimentary way to namespace classes<a href="#fn:2" id="fnref:2" title="see footnote">2</a>, while suffixes may be a rudimentary way to group classes or identify their type<a href="#fn:3" id="fnref:3" title="see footnote">3</a>. But these are easy examples; many patterns are much more subtle.</p>
<h2>
“Where is this used?”</h2>
<p>
Imagine figuring out “where is this used?”, for various types of “this”:</p>
<p>
Most code editors (perhaps paired with a <a href="https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/">language server</a>) can show you where local variables are used. This usually also works for finding where methods are invoked — although perhaps less reliably in dynamic-dispatch languages, or languages without types.</p>
<p>
What if you want to find where instances of a particular model get created? There may be multiple ways to create a model, so this isn’t super simple. In Rails, for example, there’s two built-in ways to create a model: you can either call <code>.new</code> to create a new instance in memory followed by <code>.save</code> to persist it to the database, or call <code>.create</code> to automatically do both. Your particular codebase might have additional wrappers for doing this that you’re supposed to use. Even worse, imagine that sometimes you create a <code>.new</code> instance, then set some properties on it over the next few lines, then finally call <code>.save</code>. Something like this:</p>
<pre><code>user = User.new
user.email = '<a href="https://feifan.blog/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection" data-cfemail="97fff2fbfbf8d7f2eff6fae7fbf2b9f4f8fa">[email&nbsp;protected]</a>' unless self.anonymous?
user.save</code></pre>
<p>
Conceptually, that’s still code that creates an instance of a particular model. But with the intervening syntax, this would be a difficult case to find with <code>grep</code>.</p>
<h2>
Static config</h2>
<p>
At <a href="https://stripe.com/">Stripe</a>, where I work, we have a lot of code for jobs that need to run at certain times each day. For example, we might need to move funds from one financial partner to another at noon UTC each day. Each of these jobs has configuration code describing when and how it should be run, implemented as a <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/mps/concepts/domain-specific-languages/">DSL</a>. This config might look something like this:</p>
<pre><code>run_config RunConfig.new(
  job_name: 'partner-daily-funding',
  env_vars: self.config_env,
  cron: RunConfig::Cron.new(
    schedule: { hour: 12, minute: 0 }
  ),
  owning_team: Company::Team::Liquidity
)</code></pre>
<p>
In our codebase, we have hundreds of these jobs, each with their own <code>run_config</code>. If you look at this codebase as a database, you can imagine these jobs being rows in a <code>jobs</code> table, where the fields on each row correspond to the parameters provided to the <code>RunConfig</code> class. </p>
<p>
Wouldn’t it be great to be able to browse all these jobs in a table? Maybe you could perform some basic operations on this data: searching for specific jobs by name or owning team; sorting by the time-of-day they’re scheduled to run; filtering for jobs owned by your team that have errored in the past week. Maybe you could edit the <code>run_config</code> from that interface (like you might edit a spreadsheet) and have it automatically make the corresponding change in the source code (or open a PR). Maybe you could even compute some aggregations on this data — for example, if you’re introducing a new job that requires some expensive computation, maybe you’d like to know which hours have the fewest other jobs scheduled. And of course, this job browser should be bidirectional with respect to the codebase — there should be a button beside each entry that shows the code for the job inline or opens the corresponding code in your editor.</p>
<h2>
Diffused concepts</h2>
<p>
Codebases typically contain logical concepts that are implemented across multiple pieces of code. This is often the case when you need to create multiple files to implement a particular feature.</p>
<p>
For example, in Rails, a “resource” is collectively implemented across a line in the router, a model file, a controller file, and a bunch of view files. Rails even ships with a code generator to <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/blob/5f3ff60084ab5d5921ca3499814e4697f8350ee7/railties/lib/rails/generators/rails/resource/USAGE">create some of these files</a> for you. But despite resources being a core concept when working with Rails, there’s no good way to browse the resources in your codebase<a href="#fn:4" id="fnref:4" title="see footnote">4</a>. There’s no good way to filter or query your codebase either — you can’t, for example, see which resources support JSON vs XML params. </p>
<p>
For another example, consider pubsub (aka emitter-consumer) pipelines. In web services, when you have processing that can happen “in the background”, one service will publish an event; another service subscribes to that event and will do the background processing on its own when it receives the event. Often, these will form event “pipelines” or trees where an event consumer will emit additional events that are consumed by yet other services. These pipelines are concepts that developers talk about (as in, the “account creation pipeline” or “funding reconciliation pipeline”), but in most codebases the pipeline itself isn’t declared or reified anywhere in the code.</p>
<p>
If you’re looking at code that emits an event, how do you find the consumers? If you’re lucky, the event has a unique, literal name and the consumer uses that name literally as well. But maybe some subscribers are using wildcard event names, or names generated by string concatenation, and that becomes a lot harder to grep for. Likewise, if you’re looking at a consumer of an event, how do you find the locations in the codebase that could emit that event<a href="#fn:5" id="fnref:5" title="see footnote">5</a>?</p>
<p>
Wouldn’t it be great to be able to browse those pipelines in a table or perhaps a directed graph<a href="#fn:6" id="fnref:6" title="see footnote">6</a>? Maybe that graph would support some basic operations on this data: searching for specific publishers or subscribers by class name or event name; filtering for pipelines that have run into errors; maybe even showing the flow of a particular event given an event ID<a href="#fn:7" id="fnref:7" title="see footnote">7</a>. And of course, this pipeline browser should be bidirectional with respect to the codebase — there should be a button beside each graph node that shows the code for the publisher or subscriber inline or opens the corresponding code in your editor.</p>
<p>
For a final example, consider code that has functionality inherited from elsewhere. Some environments let you see a <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/viewing-structure-of-a-source-file.html">list of inherited properties</a> or methods, but this isn’t possible for more specialized cases. At Stripe, we have code that implements shell scripts that can take command-line arguments and flags. These arguments are defined via a DSL in the implementing code, but these commands can be subclassed, and there’s no way to see what the available arguments are while working in the subclass.</p>
<h2>
Philosophy</h2>
<p>
I think it’s important to consider these problems not as disparate cases in need of bespoke tooling, but as a <em>class</em> of problems characterized by a lack of access to the data structures embedded within codebases. Just like SQL databases and spreadsheets provide a singular querying abstraction and a set of visualization primitives that can be applied to any kind of data, programming environments need a singular querying abstraction and set of visualization primitives that can be applied to the concepts lurking in codebases. Getting there does <em>not</em> mean using proprietary drag-and-drop visual programming interfaces where the introspection capabilities are limited to whatever the programming environment happens to have implemented. Just the opposite — you should still be able to do whatever you want with your code (including treating it as plain-text files), <em>and also</em> have access to more advanced introspection tools that can query and slice your code — tools that let you easily understand and navigate complex codebases to reduce the <em>incidental complexity</em> of building software.</p>
<h2>
Solutions</h2>
<p>
I don’t have a solution to sell you here (at least, not yet!). But <a href="https://twitter.com/hirday_g/status/1356657607381946369">by popular demand</a> I think it’s worthwhile to at least discuss principles that solutions should embody and directionally-related prior art. </p>
<p>
To start with a simple example, see <a href="https://ihp.digitallyinduced.com/">IHP</a>, a full-stack web framework similar to Rails. It comes with a web interface for manipulating your project’s codebase and database schema. <a href="https://youtu.be/UbDtS_mUMpI?t=102">One point in the introduction video</a> showed changes being made in the visual schema editor being automatically reflected in the SQL code that describes the database schema — and changes being made to the SQL code being bidirectionally reflected in the visual schema editor. </p>
<p>
For a more in-depth example, consider <a href="https://pharo.org/">Pharo</a>, a Smalltalk environment. “Environment” in this case means that it feels like you’re using a custom OS (including global menus, idioms, and keyboard and mouse conventions) designed specifically for browsing, writing, and debugging programs in the Smalltalk programming language<a href="#fn:8" id="fnref:8" title="see footnote">8</a>. The holistic integration of these tools is important. Unlike the programming environments we cobble for ourselves today — where the editor is agnostic of the language and runtime and other tools like debuggers, inspectors, and code browsers are tacked on (if they exist at all) — it’s worth thinking about what an entire computing experience <em>for</em> writing and building custom tools might look like<a href="#fn:9" id="fnref:9" title="see footnote">9</a>.</p>
<p>
Pharo is also interesting because of its Class Browser, which looks like this:</p>
<p>
  <img src="https://files.tanagram.app/file/tanagram-data/prod-feifans-blog/database-codebase-pharo-browser.png" alt="Pharo class browser">
</p>
<p>
This browser breaks free from the source code <em>file</em> as the atomic unit of browsing; instead, it allows the user to browse one method at a time. Making the “unit of browsing” …</p></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase">https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26160186</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 23:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Clubhouse Bio Generator]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 191 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26159405">thread link</a>) | @ChrisArchitect
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://perchance.org/owh9gelu4t | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://perchance.org/owh9gelu4t">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://perchance.org/owh9gelu4t</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26159405</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 22:11:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Simtel.net MS-DOS Collection]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 119 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26157165">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/index-msdos.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/index-msdos.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><table>
<tbody><tr><th></th><th><a name="0"> - 0 - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/00_info.html">00_info</a></b></td><td>Simtel.Net MS-DOS documentation, indexes</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/00_start.html">00_start</a></b></td><td>Essential info and utilities for beginners</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="4"> - 4 - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/4dos.html">4dos</a></b></td><td>4DOS shell - replacement for COMMAND.COM</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="A"> - A - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ada.html">ada</a></b></td><td>Ada programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ai.html">ai</a></b></td><td>Artificial Intelligence programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/animate.html">animate</a></b></td><td>Animation programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/apl.html">apl</a></b></td><td>The APL mathematics programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/arcers.html">arcers</a></b></td><td>Archiving and compressing programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/arcutils.html">arcutils</a></b></td><td>Utilities for using archives</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/asm_mag.html">asm_mag</a></b></td><td>The Assembly Language 'magazine'</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/asmutl.html">asmutl</a></b></td><td>Assembly language utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/astronmy.html">astronmy</a></b></td><td>Astronomical programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/autocad.html">autocad</a></b></td><td>Programs for Auto-CAD</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="B"> - B - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/basic.html">basic</a></b></td><td>BASIC programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/batchutl.html">batchutl</a></b></td><td>Batch utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bbs.html">bbs</a></b></td><td>BBS systems and support programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bbsdoors.html">bbsdoors</a></b></td><td>BBS 'door' interfaces</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bbslists.html">bbslists</a></b></td><td>BBS lists</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bible.html">bible</a></b></td><td>Bible and searching tools</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/binaryed.html">binaryed</a></b></td><td>Binary file editors</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/biology.html">biology</a></b></td><td>Biology programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bootutil.html">bootutil</a></b></td><td>Controlling the booting process</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/borland.html">borland</a></b></td><td>Borland product support</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/business.html">business</a></b></td><td>Business-related Programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="C"> - C - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/c.html">c</a></b></td><td>C programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/cad.html">cad</a></b></td><td>Computer Aided Design</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/calculte.html">calculte</a></b></td><td>Calculators for math, finance, etc.</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/catalog.html">catalog</a></b></td><td>Disk catalog utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/cdrom.html">cdrom</a></b></td><td>CD-ROM utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/chemstry.html">chemstry</a></b></td><td>Chemistry programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/clipper.html">clipper</a></b></td><td>Clipper programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/clocks.html">clocks</a></b></td><td>Computer time utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/commprog.html">commprog</a></b></td><td>Terminal and file transfer programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/compress.html">compress</a></b></td><td>Compression utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/cpluspls.html">cpluspls</a></b></td><td>C++ programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/crossasm.html">crossasm</a></b></td><td>Cross-Assemblers</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="D"> - D - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/database.html">database</a></b></td><td>Databases and programs to create them</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/dayo.html">dayo</a></b></td><td>DAYO business and accounting software</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/decode.html">decode</a></b></td><td>Encode/decode binary files to/from text</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/deskaces.html">deskaces</a></b></td><td>Handy Desk-Top utilities and programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/deskpub.html">deskpub</a></b></td><td>Desktop publishing</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/desqview.html">desqview</a></b></td><td>DESQview utilities and programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/dirutl.html">dirutl</a></b></td><td>Directory utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/disasm.html">disasm</a></b></td><td>Disassemblers: Convert executables to ASM</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/diskutil.html">diskutil</a></b></td><td>Disk utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/dv_x.html">dv_x</a></b></td><td>Programs and utilities for DESQview-X</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="E"> - E - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/editor.html">editor</a></b></td><td>Text editors</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/educate.html">educate</a></b></td><td>Programs for education</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/eel.html">eel</a></b></td><td>Epsilon editor EEL extensions</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/electrcl.html">electrcl</a></b></td><td>Electrical engineering programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/emulate.html">emulate</a></b></td><td>Emulators</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/engin.html">engin</a></b></td><td>Engineering Programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/envutil.html">envutil</a></b></td><td>Manipulating environment variables</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/execomp.html">execomp</a></b></td><td>Compress EXE and COM files to save disk space</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="F"> - F - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/fileutil.html">fileutil</a></b></td><td>File management and conversion utils</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/finance.html">finance</a></b></td><td>Financial software</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/flowchrt.html">flowchrt</a></b></td><td>Flowchart Generators</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/foods.html">foods</a></b></td><td>Food recipes</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/forms.html">forms</a></b></td><td>Form Generators and Forms Entry Programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/forth.html">forth</a></b></td><td>Forth programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/fortran.html">fortran</a></b></td><td>FORTRAN programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/fossil.html">fossil</a></b></td><td>FOSSIL drivers and utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/freemacs.html">freemacs</a></b></td><td>Emacs-like editor (small)</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="G"> - G - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/genealgy.html">genealgy</a></b></td><td>Genealogy programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/geogrphy.html">geogrphy</a></b></td><td>Geography programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/geology.html">geology</a></b></td><td>Geology programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/gif.html">gif</a></b></td><td>Programs to make/view/print/convert GIF files</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/graph.html">graph</a></b></td><td>Graphing programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/graphics.html">graphics</a></b></td><td>Graphics programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="H"> - H - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/hamradio.html">hamradio</a></b></td><td>Ham Radio programs and information</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/handicap.html">handicap</a></b></td><td>Programs for the handicapped</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/health.html">health</a></b></td><td>Health, Fitness, and Medical</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/html.html">html</a></b></td><td>HTML Tools</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/hypertxt.html">hypertxt</a></b></td><td>Hyper-Text files and programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="I"> - I - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/imail.html">imail</a></b></td><td>IMAIL FidoNet echomail processor</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/info.html">info</a></b></td><td>Information and documentation files</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/install.html">install</a></b></td><td>Program installation utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/internet.html">internet</a></b></td><td>Programs and utils for use on the Internet</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/io_utils.html">io_utils</a></b></td><td>I/O Utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/irit.html">irit</a></b></td><td>Polygonal solid modeler &amp; C++ source</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="K"> - K - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/keyboard.html">keyboard</a></b></td><td>Keyboard utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="L"> - L - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/lan.html">lan</a></b></td><td>Programs for use on Local Area Networks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/langtutr.html">langtutr</a></b></td><td>Tutorials on foreign languages</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/laser.html">laser</a></b></td><td>Laser printer utilities and fonts</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/legal.html">legal</a></b></td><td>Law-related programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/lingstcs.html">lingstcs</a></b></td><td>Linguistics</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/literatr.html">literatr</a></b></td><td>Teach/learn literature</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="M"> - M - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mailnews.html">mailnews</a></b></td><td>E-mail and Usenet News programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mapping.html">mapping</a></b></td><td>Map programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/math.html">math</a></b></td><td>Mathematics programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mcintosh.html">mcintosh</a></b></td><td>Convert Macintosh files to DOS format</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/memutil.html">memutil</a></b></td><td>Computer memory info and management utils</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/menu.html">menu</a></b></td><td>Creating and using menus</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/microsft.html">microsft</a></b></td><td>Microsoft product support</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/misclang.html">misclang</a></b></td><td>Misc. program languages</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mmedia.html">mmedia</a></b></td><td>Multimedia Programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mormon.html">mormon</a></b></td><td>The Book of Mormon</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mouse.html">mouse</a></b></td><td>Utilities for the mouse</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/music.html">music</a></b></td><td>Programs for writing and playing music</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/muslum.html">muslum</a></b></td><td>The Holy Book of Muslum</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="N"> - N - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/naplps.html">naplps</a></b></td><td>NAPLPS drawing program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ncsatlnt.html">ncsatlnt</a></b></td><td>NCSA Telnet TCP/IP package</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/nettamer.html">nettamer</a></b></td><td>Net-Tamer DOS PPP dial up access program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/network.html">network</a></b></td><td>Utilities for computer networks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/neurlnet.html">neurlnet</a></b></td><td>Neural Networks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/nfs.html">nfs</a></b></td><td>Network File System utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/notabene.html">notabene</a></b></td><td>Notabene word processor utils</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/novell.html">novell</a></b></td><td>Novell LAN utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="P"> - P - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/packet.html">packet</a></b></td><td>Programs for Packet Radio</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pascal.html">pascal</a></b></td><td>Pascal programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pcboard.html">pcboard</a></b></td><td>PC Board BBS software</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pcmag.html">pcmag</a></b></td><td>'PC Magazine' listings and utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pctech.html">pctech</a></b></td><td>'PC Tech Journal' listings and utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/perl.html">perl</a></b></td><td>Perl programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pgmtips.html">pgmtips</a></b></td><td>Programming Tips &amp; Tricks Magazine</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pgmutl.html">pgmutl</a></b></td><td>Programming utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pktdrvr.html">pktdrvr</a></b></td><td>TCP/IP/IPX/ODI packet drivers</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/plot.html">plot</a></b></td><td>Programs for plotters</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/postscrp.html">postscrp</a></b></td><td>PostScript view/print utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/printer.html">printer</a></b></td><td>Printer utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/progjorn.html">progjorn</a></b></td><td>Programmers Journal</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/projmgmt.html">projmgmt</a></b></td><td>Project Management programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="Q"> - Q - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/qbasic.html">qbasic</a></b></td><td>Quick BASIC and QBasic programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/qmodem.html">qmodem</a></b></td><td>Qmodem comm program &amp; utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/qtrdeck.html">qtrdeck</a></b></td><td>Quarterdeck utilities and technical notes</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="R"> - R - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ramdisk.html">ramdisk</a></b></td><td>Memory resident disks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/rbbs.html">rbbs</a></b></td><td>RBBS-PC BBS and support utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/recreatn.html">recreatn</a></b></td><td>Recreation and passtime-related programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="S"> - S - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/satelite.html">satelite</a></b></td><td>Communication satellite programs and listings</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/schedule.html">schedule</a></b></td><td>Schedule automatic program runs (like cron)</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/science.html">science</a></b></td><td>Miscellaneous science related material</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/screen.html">screen</a></b></td><td>Video screen utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/security.html">security</a></b></td><td>Improve computer security</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/semware.html">semware</a></b></td><td>SemWare editors, utilities and support files</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/simulatn.html">simulatn</a></b></td><td>Simulation programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sound.html">sound</a></b></td><td>Computer sound programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sports.html">sports</a></b></td><td>Sports programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/spredsht.html">spredsht</a></b></td><td>Spreadsheet programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/statstcs.html">statstcs</a></b></td><td>Statistics programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/surfmodl.html">surfmodl</a></b></td><td>Surface modeling programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/swap.html">swap</a></b></td><td>Free working memory by swaping to high mem</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sysinfo.html">sysinfo</a></b></td><td>Computer system information display programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sysutl.html">sysutl</a></b></td><td>System utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="T"> - T - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tcpip.html">tcpip</a></b></td><td>TCP/IP programs (ka9q, etc.)</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/teaching.html">teaching</a></b></td><td>Programs to assist teachers</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/telegard.html">telegard</a></b></td><td>Telegard BBS program &amp; utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/telix.html">telix</a></b></td><td>Telix communications program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/termnate.html">termnate</a></b></td><td>Terminate Terminal/Communications program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tex.html">tex</a></b></td><td>TeX type setting program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tiff.html">tiff</a></b></td><td>TIFF graphics format programs and information</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/torah.html">torah</a></b></td><td>Torah-related programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/travel.html">travel</a></b></td><td>Travel planning and information</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tsrutil.html">tsrutil</a></b></td><td>Terminate and stay resident utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbo_c.html">turbo_c</a></b></td><td>Borland Turbo C programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbobas.html">turbobas</a></b></td><td>Borland's Turbo Basic programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbopas.html">turbopas</a></b></td><td>Borland Turbo Pascal programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbovis.html">turbovis</a></b></td><td>Turbo Vision programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/txtutl.html">txtutl</a></b></td><td>Text utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="U"> - U - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ubasic.html">ubasic</a></b></td><td>UBASIC: Ultra high-precision BASIC for math</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/uemacs.html">uemacs</a></b></td><td>MicroEmacs text editor</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/uucp.html">uucp</a></b></td><td>Unix to Unix Copy for MS-DOS</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="V"> - V - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/vga.html">vga</a></b></td><td>VGA monitor utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/virus.html">virus</a></b></td><td>Virus detection and removal programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/visbasic.html">visbasic</a></b></td><td>Visual Basic programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/viscii.html">viscii</a></b></td><td>Vietnamese character programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="W"> - W - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/waffle.html">waffle</a></b></td><td>Waffle bulletin board system</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/weather.html">weather</a></b></td><td>Weather forecasting</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/wordperf.html">wordperf</a></b></td><td>WordPerfect word processing</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/worldmap.html">worldmap</a></b></td><td>A digitized map of the world</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/wwiv.html">wwiv</a></b></td><td>WWIV BBS</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="X"> - X - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/x_10.html">x_10</a></b></td><td>X-10 Powerhouse computer programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/xwindows.html">xwindows</a></b></td><td>X Windows Server and Support Programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="Z"> - Z - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/zmodem.html">zmodem</a></b></td><td>Zmodem file transfer protocol</td></tr>
</tbody></table></p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/index-msdos.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26157165</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 18:36:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AirPods as a Platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 121 | Comments 127 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26156881">thread link</a>) | @sc90
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://julian.digital/2020/04/19/airpods-as-a-platform/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://julian.digital/2020/04/19/airpods-as-a-platform/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
 		
<p><span>01</span> Intro</p>



<p>One of the favorite activities of tech analysts, VCs and similar Twitter armchair experts is to predict what the next big technology platform might be.</p>



<p>The usual suspects that come up in these conversations are VR/AR, crypto, smart speakers and similar IoT devices. A new contestant that I’ve <a href="https://twitter.com/BrianNorgard/status/1108755070642880512">seen</a> <a href="https://www.aboveavalon.com/notes/2019/11/19/airpods-are-becoming-a-platform">come up</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/chrismessina/status/1177619897884368904">more</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/HarryStebbings/status/1215425809944543240">frequently</a> in these debates recently are Apple’s AirPods.</p>



<p>Calling AirPods “the next big platform” is interesting because at the moment, they are not even a small platform. They are no platform at all. They are just a piece of hardware. </p>



<p>But that doesn’t mean they can’t become platform.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/platform.png"></p><p><span>02</span> What is a platform?</p>



<p>Let’s first take a look at what a platform actually is.</p>



<p>At its core, a platform is something that others can build on top of. A classic example would be an operating system like iOS: By providing a set of APIs, Apple created a playground for developers to build and run applications on. In fact, new input capabilities such as the touch interface, gyroscope sensor and camera allowed developers to create unique applications that weren’t possible before. </p>



<p>Platforms are subject to network effects: More applications attract more users to the platform, while more users in turn attract more developers who build more apps. </p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/flywheel.png"></p><p>It’s a classic flywheel effect that creates powerful winner-takes-all dynamics. This explains why there are only two (meaningful) mobile operating systems – iOS and Android. </p>



<p>It also explains why everyone is so interested in upcoming platforms – and why Apple might be interested in making AirPods a platform.</p>



<p><span>03</span> Why AirPods aren’t a platform</p>



<p>In their current form, AirPods are not a platform. They don’t provide any unique input or output functionalities that developers could leverage. Active Noise Cancellation and Transparency Mode are neat but not new or Airpods-exclusive features – other headphones offer exactly the same. In either case, developers don’t have any control over them and thus can’t build applications that use these functionalities.</p>



<p>Some say that AirPods will give rise to more audio apps because they are “always in” which in turn will lead to more (and perhaps new forms of) audio content. That might be true – content providers are always looking for <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/01/26/newsletters-and-alternative-trade-routes/">alternative routes</a> to get consumers’ attention – but, again, it does not make AirPods a platform. You can use any other pair of headphones to use these audio apps as well.</p>



<p>If Apple wants to make AirPods a platform, it needs to open up some part of the AirPods experience to developers so that they can build new things on top of it.</p>



<p><span>04</span> On Siri &amp; Voice Platforms</p>



<p>The most obvious choice here is Siri, which is already integrated into every pair of AirPods.</p>



<p>In contrast to other voice assistants like Alexa and Google Assistant, Apple has never really opened up Siri for 3rd-party developers. If they did, it would create a new platform that could have its own ecosystem of apps and developers.</p>



<p>But I’m not convinced that this is Apple’s best option.<br>Let me explain why.</p>



<p>Opening up Siri wouldn’t make AirPods a platform, it would make Siri a platform. This might sound like a technicality, but I think it’s an important difference. As <a href="https://twitter.com/einkoenig">Jan König</a> <a href="https://context-first.com/alexa-please-send-this-to-my-screen-6f4839eb415a">brilliantly summarized in this article</a>, voice isn’t an interface for <em>one</em> device – it’s an interface <em>across</em> devices. It’s more of a meta-layer that should tie different products together to enable multi-device experiences.</p>



<p>This means Apple has little interest in making Siri an AirPods-exclusive. Voice-based computing works best when it’s everywhere. It’s about reach, not exclusivity. This is part of the reason why Google and Amazon excel at it.</p>



<p>At the moment, Siri’s capabilities are considerably behind those of Google Assistant and Alexa. Again, this isn’t overly surprising: Google’s and Amazon’s main job is finding the right answers to users’ questions. The required ML capabilities for a smart assistant are among the core competencies of these two companies.</p>



<p>But even Amazon and Google haven’t really figured out the platform part yet, as indicated by the lack of breakout 3rd-party voice applications. It seems like the two platforms are still looking for their product-market-fit beyond being just cheap speakers that you can also control with your voice.</p>



<p>This is partly because the above-mentioned use case of voice as a cross-device layer isn’t something developers can build with the current set of APIs. </p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/voiceonlyinterfaces-3.png"></p><p>The other big reason I see is that people are mistaking voice as a replacement for other interfaces. Movies like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ne6p6MfLBxc">Her</a> paint a future where human-computer-interaction primarily occurs via voice-powered smart assistants, but in reality, voice isn’t great as a primary or stand-alone interface. It works best as an *additional* input/output channel that augments whatever else you are doing.</p>



<p>Let me give you an example: Saying “Hey Google, turn up the volume” takes 10x longer than simply pressing the volume-up button on your phone. It only makes sense when your hands are busy doing other things (kitchen work, for example).</p>



<p>The most convincing voice app I have seen to date was at a hackathon where a team <a href="https://upsidelab.io/blog/design-voice-user-interface-starcraft/">used the StarCraft API to build voice-enabled game commands</a>. Not to replace your mouse and keyboard but to give you an additional input mechanism. Actual multitasking.</p>



<p><span>05</span> What Apple Should Build</p>



<p>I’m not against Apple opening Siri for developers. On the contrary, given that AirPods are meant to be worn all the time, a voice interface for situations that require multitasking is actually a very good idea. But voice input should remain the exceptional case. And it shouldn’t be what makes AirPods a platform.</p>



<p>Instead of voice, I’d love to see other input mechanisms that allow developers to build new ways for users to interact with the audio content they consume.</p>



<p>Most headsets currently on the market offer the following actions with one (or multiple) clicks of a physical button:</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/earpodsremote-1.png"></p><p>These inputs were invented a long time ago and there has been almost zero innovation since. <strong>Why has no one thought about additional buttons or click mechanisms that allow users to interact with the actual content?</strong></p>



<p>For example, when listening to podcasts I often find myself wanting to bookmark things that are being talked about. It would be amazing if I could simply tap a button on my headphones which would add a timestamp to a bookmarks section of my podcast app. <span>(Or better even, a transcript of the ~15 seconds of content before I pressed the button, which are then also automatically added to my notes app via an Apple Shortcut.)</span></p>



<p>Yes, you could build the same with voice as the input mechanism, but as we discussed earlier, saying <em>“Hey Siri, please bookmark this!”</em> just doesn’t seem very convenient.</p>



<p>While podcast apps might use the additional button as a bookmarking feature, Spotify could make it a Like button to quickly add songs to your Favorites playlist. Other developers could build completely new applications: Think about interactive audiobooks or similar two-way audio experiences, for example. </p>



<p>This is the beauty of platforms: You just provide developers with a set of tools and they will come up with use cases you hadn’t even thought about. Crowdsourced value creation.</p>



<p><span>06</span> Closing Thoughts</p>



<p>(1) The input mechanism I describe doesn’t have to be a physical button. In fact, gesture-based inputs might be even more convenient. If AirPods had built-in accelerometers, users could interact with audio content by nodding or shaking their heads. Radar-based sensors like Google’s Motion Sense could also create an interesting new interaction language for audio content.</p>



<p>(2) You could also think about the Apple Watch as the main input device. In contrast to the AirPods, Apple opened the Watch for developers from the start, but it hasn’t really seen much success as a platform. Perhaps a combination of Watch and AirPods has a better chance of creating an ecosystem with its own unique applications?</p>



<p>(3) One thing to keep in mind is that Apple doesn’t really have an interest in making AirPods a standalone platform. The iPhone (or rather iOS) will always be the core platform that Apple cares about. Instead of separate iPhone, Watch and AirPods ecosystems, think about Apple’s strategy as more of a multi-platform bundle. Even as a platform, AirPods will remain more of an accessory that adds stickiness to the existing iPhone ecosystem.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fullcycle.png"></p>



<p>Do you have thoughts or feedback on this post?<br>If so, <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1251919017721421827">I’d love to hear it</a>!</p>



<p><span><i>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/einkoenig">Jan König</a> for reading drafts of this post.</i></span>
 	</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://julian.digital/2020/04/19/airpods-as-a-platform/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26156881</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 18:11:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bitcoin’s Overnight Collapse Probability Is About 50%]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 101 | Comments 209 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26155158">thread link</a>) | @dgellow
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | http://www.tr0lly.com/bitcoin/bitcoins-overnight-collapse-probability-is-about-50/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.tr0lly.com/bitcoin/bitcoins-overnight-collapse-probability-is-about-50/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-1154">
	
	<div>
		
<p>If you ever had a look at <a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/trading/equity-index/us-index/bitcoin_quotes_globex.html">CME’s Bitcoin futures</a>, you might have noticed that there are multiple contracts – one for each month, and that they have different prices. Systematically, the futures contracts for months that are further away, are more expensive than those with closer expiration, and also cheaper than spot. When this happens for a commodity like oil, we’re talking about contango.</p>



<p>This is usually due to the fact that there’s a risk premium on the uncertainty of the future, and it costs a little bit to be sure of the price that you’ll pay for something three months from now. But for futures on financial products, it’s very rare. Currently, the premium for Bitcoin is a whopping 2% per month, and it’s a red warning sign.</p>



<h3>Term structure of Bitcoin futures</h3>



<p>The reason contango for commodities like oil is normal, is that you can’t arbitrage it. The way to arbitrage contango is to buy spot, short the future, wait till expiry, and collect the premium. But you can’t simply “wait” when you buy thousands of barrels of oil – you have to store those barrels somewhere, and it will cost you an arm and a leg. The storage costs will eat up your contango premium, plus some.</p>



<p>There were occurrences in the past where traders were able to arbitrage this premium, but the contango needed to be absolutely off-the-charts (“super-contango”). For instance, after the 2008 financial panic, the spread between spot and futures in the oil market was so big, <a href="https://doc.rero.ch/record/323428/files/TDIBM_Loris_Beltramello.pdf">traders would literally rent tankers and use them as storage facilities</a> for oil, waiting for their futures leg to mature.</p>



<p>The reason contango for financial products isn’t normal, is that you can arbitrage it very easily, as you don’t have storage costs. You buy Bitcoin spot, sell an April future for 4% more than spot, and simply wait two months.</p>



<figure><img src="http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35.png" alt="" srcset="http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35.png 952w, http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35-300x79.png 300w, http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35-768x203.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 952px) 100vw, 952px"></figure>



<p>At expiry, you’ll sell your Bitcoin at a certain price, while the future will settle at the exact same price, and you’ll collect the premium. Your only cost is the carry, i.e. the interest you have forfeited on the cash you used to buy Bitcoin, but this is virtually zero today.</p>



<p>Why the premium, then? Why don’t hedge funds with hundreds of billions of dollars to spare don’t arbitrage the Bitcoin contango down to zero?</p>



<h3>Credit risk?</h3>



<p>One quick answer would be that you aren’t guaranteed to close your trade because of counterparty risk. This is what happened when Lehman went bust – all the hedge funds that had OTC derivatives positions with Lehman as one leg of a trade, suddenly saw the “Lehman leg” disappear, while the other leg was still there. Lehman going bust single handedly destroyed the convertible bonds market, as hedge funds who had bought convertible bonds and hedged their risks (credit, volatility, equity risks – you name it) with Lehman, suddenly were out of hedges, and had to sell their cash position (their convertible bonds) at literally any price.</p>



<p>But there is no counterparty risk here. You can’t lose your Bitcoins – you just keep them on chain, and no exchange going bust will affect your position. CME can’t go bust – it has margin calls, initial margin deposits, has a guarantee fund, and is almost explicitly guaranteed by the Fed because of its critical importance to financial markets.</p>



<p>So, again, why is nobody picking those hundred dollar bills lying on the street?</p>



<h3>Systemic risk</h3>



<p>There is one risk that you can’t edge – that of the world collapsing overnight, when there’s nobody left to pay you even if you win your bet. Imagine shorting USDT on Binance. What happens if you’re right and USDT goes to zero? Do you really think Binance will still be around to pay you?</p>



<p>You can always say, “bah, I’ll see it coming, the moment shit starts to hit the fan, I’ll close my positions”. But what if you don’t have the time to do so? What if a black swan event happens overnight?</p>



<p>This is the risk with Bitcoin. A whim from regulators, like passing the STABLE act, and all USDT exchanges go bust. What will happen to Bitcoin futures then? CME uses the “<a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/trading/cryptocurrency-indices.html">Bitcoin Reference Rate</a>” (BRR) to calculate the spot for its Bitcoin futures, which is a weighted average of the spots taken from multiple crypto exchanges, the list of which changes over time. What happens if the Bitcoin ecosystem collapses, the prices of Bitcoin on half of those exchanges go to 100,000 on paper because those exchanges become insolvent and people rush for the exits by buying Bitcoin to try and send it to their own wallets (as happened with MtGox)? Futures skyrocket because of a technicality, CME is slow to react, and you get wiped out on your “short futures” leg – while you can’t really sell the “long Bitcoin” leg either, because every exchange is on fire and nobody processes redemption requests.</p>



<h3>Implied probability of default</h3>



<p>This risk is rewarded handsomely – a big fat 2% per month. With interest rates at zero, we can borrow a formula from the Credit Default Swaps market to calculate the <a href="https://quant.stackexchange.com/questions/15986/how-to-compute-the-implied-probability-of-default-from-a-cds-spread#:~:text=Risk%2Dneutral%20default%20probability%20implied,R%20is%20the%20recovery%20rate.&amp;text=Hulls%20equation%20is%20a%20gross,works%20for%20all%20tenor%20points.">implied probability of default</a>, which we’ll <a href="http://nzz-files-prod.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/files/4/1/2/cds+deutsche+bank+161214_1.18446412.pdf">simplify to the extreme</a>:</p>



<p><strong>p = S/(1-R)</strong></p>



<p>Where p is the probability of default, S the annual “swap rate” that compensates for that probability, and R the recovery rate, i.e. how much you can expect to recoup from your investment if a default occurs.</p>



<p>In our case, S = 24% (12 months in a year, at 2% for each month), and R ≈ 50% based on what happened after MtGox collapsed. This means that we assume you’ll be able to cash out in the event of an apocalypse with an average 50% loss. Remember, this is assuming that you are hedged!</p>



<p>This gives us an implied probability of default p ≈ 50% over the next year. Again, that’s the probability of the whole Bitcoin ecosystem collapsing overnight, not giving you the time to close your positions, cutting you off from exchanges, and where CME futures no longer trade.</p>



<p>This is the risk as it’s being priced by the market, on relatively liquid financial instruments. So the next time someone tries to explain to you that “Bitcoin is a store of value”, when the chances of it getting utterly destroyed overnight before the year is over are around 50/50, try not to shoot coffee through your nose laughing.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

			
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.tr0lly.com/bitcoin/bitcoins-overnight-collapse-probability-is-about-50/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26155158</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 16:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Computers Aren't Fun Anymore (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 71 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26154754">thread link</a>) | @hacksilver
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://feifan.blog/posts/computers-arent-fun-anymore | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://feifan.blog/posts/computers-arent-fun-anymore">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
<div>
  <article>
    
      <p><img src="https://files.tanagram.app/file/tanagram-data/prod-feifans-blog/penny-farthing.jpeg">
      </p>
<p>
Throughout <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dream-Machine-M-Mitchell-Waldrop/dp/1732265119"><em>The Dream Machine</em></a>, a history of the early days of computing, tinkering and having fun was a recurring theme throughout the decades. I wasn’t around to experience the early days of computers myself, but they seemed to be genuinely exciting and rewarding. In the words of MIT sociologist Sherry Turkle: computers empowered their users, making them feel smart[er], “in control”, and “more fully participant in the future”. </p>
<p>
Those feel like odd descriptions for the modern computing experience. Using computers today doesn’t feel like￼ an empowering experience￼. Sometimes it’s mindless and distracting. Sometimes, when a redesign rolls out, or laptop doesn’t wake from sleep mode,￼ it’s downright hostile. The experience of using a computer in 2020 is a concoction of data silos, dinging notifications and reinvented wheels, presented in gratuitously bubble-wrapped UIs hyper-optimized by persnickety product managers and soulless A/B tests. </p>
<p>
For most people, the computing experience is <a href="https://feifan.blog/2020/06/22/no-one-cares-about-software-quality/">clicking around a lot</a>, typing into disparate apps in which your data is trapped except through narrowly-defined, bespoke integrations, and struggling to find <em>that thing you were just reading a few days ago</em> among all the silos. This doesn’t make anyone feel smarter or more in control. It’s simply frustrating.</p>
<p>
Software <em>development</em> is stuck in the doldrums too. A massive amount of cumulative engineering effort is spent rebuilding the same primitives<a href="#fn:1" id="fnref:1" title="see footnote">1</a> because the software engineering industry hasn’t convincingly developed platforms at higher levels of abstraction<a href="#fn:2" id="fnref:2" title="see footnote">2</a>. A significant portion of development effort goes to placating not-invented-here-ness, where companies feel the need to build their own version of every feature, each slightly different (user familiarity be damned). A lot of software is little more than looking up API documentation and plugging one into another. There’s a dearth of creativity, of joy and discovery, of inventing something interesting and new. </p>
<p>
To be fair, computers — both the desktop kind and various mobile kinds — enable<a href="#fn:3" id="fnref:3" title="see footnote">3</a> seemingly-impossible<a href="#fn:4" id="fnref:4" title="see footnote">4</a> things<a href="#fn:5" id="fnref:5" title="see footnote">5</a>. But it feels frustrating to see the pioneering spirit that originally led to the development of modern computers giving way to uninspired flat interfaces<a href="#fn:6" id="fnref:6" title="see footnote">6</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete">CRUD</a> SaaS apps. The things you can do are limited to bespokely-implemented features, dribbled out only as fast as a small team of designers and developers can think of and build them. Of course you have an extensive list of things you <em>wish</em> your phone/computer/most-used apps could do; everyone does. You know the majority of it will remain a wishlist; there’s almost no hope of the feature you really want being implemented<a href="#fn:7" id="fnref:7" title="see footnote">7</a>. This isn’t empowering. What’s more, new features tend to be one-off improvements and ungainly new ways for you to do more work<a href="#fn:8" id="fnref:8" title="see footnote">8</a> rather than adding or improving functionality in a generalized way so you can remix functionality and do things faster.</p>
<p>
For the people who’ve figured out the right incantations to type and buttons-buried-in-submenus to click, computers can automate administrivia, surface information, and make them feel “more fully participant in the future”. But getting there is an arduous journey, and many people get in a place where computers just make things harder. The experience of using computers is, in various ways, awkward and frustrating (and maybe even dangerous<a href="#fn:9" id="fnref:9" title="see footnote">9</a>) for everyone. Computers were supposed to be bicycles for the mind. So far we only have penny-farthings.</p>

  </article>
</div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://feifan.blog/posts/computers-arent-fun-anymore</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26154754</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 15:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Is Esbuild Fast?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 294 | Comments 150 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26154509">thread link</a>) | @mef
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      <p>This is a collection of common questions about esbuild. You can also ask questions on the <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues">GitHub issue tracker</a>.</p>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#why-is-esbuild-fast">Why is esbuild fast?</a></li>
        <li><a href="#benchmark-details">Benchmark details</a></li>
        <li><a href="#upcoming-roadmap">Upcoming roadmap</a></li>
        <li><a href="#production-readiness">Production readiness</a></li>
      </ul>
      <h2 id="why-is-esbuild-fast">
        <a href="#why-is-esbuild-fast">#</a>
        Why is esbuild fast?
      </h2>
      <p>Several reasons:</p>
      <ul><li><p> It's written in <a href="https://golang.org/">Go</a> and compiles to native code. </p> <p> Most other bundlers are written in JavaScript, but a command-line application is a worst-case performance situation for a JIT-compiled language. Every time you run your bundler, the JavaScript VM is seeing your bundler's code for the first time without any optimization hints. While esbuild is busy parsing your JavaScript, node is busy parsing your bundler's JavaScript. By the time node has finished parsing your bundler's code, esbuild might have already exited and your bundler hasn't even started bundling yet. </p> <p> In addition, Go is designed from the core for parallelism while JavaScript is not. Go has shared memory between threads while JavaScript has to serialize data between threads. Both Go and JavaScript have parallel garbage collectors, but Go's heap is shared between all threads while JavaScript has a separate heap per JavaScript thread. This seems to cut the amount of parallelism that's possible with JavaScript worker threads in half <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/111#issuecomment-719910381">according to my testing</a>, presumably since half of your CPU cores are busy collecting garbage for the other half. </p></li><li><p> Parallelism is used heavily. </p> <p> The algorithms inside esbuild are carefully designed to fully saturate all available CPU cores when possible. There are roughly three phases: parsing, linking, and code generation. Parsing and code generation are most of the work and are fully parallelizable (linking is an inherently serial task for the most part). Since all threads share memory, work can easily be shared when bundling different entry points that import the same JavaScript libraries. Most modern computers have many cores so parallelism is a big win. </p></li><li><p> Everything in esbuild is written from scratch. </p> <p> There are a lot of performance benefits with writing everything yourself instead of using 3rd-party libraries. You can have performance in mind from the beginning, you can make sure everything uses consistent data structures to avoid expensive conversions, and you can make wide architectural changes whenever necessary. The drawback is of course that it's a lot of work. </p> <p> For example, many bundlers use the official TypeScript compiler as a parser. But it was built to serve the goals of the TypeScript compiler team and they do not have performance as a top priority. Their code makes pretty heavy use of <a href="https://mrale.ph/blog/2015/01/11/whats-up-with-monomorphism.html">megamorphic object shapes</a> and unnecessary <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/TypeScript/issues/39247">dynamic property accesses</a> (both well-known JavaScript speed bumps). And the TypeScript parser appears to still run the type checker even when type checking is disabled. None of these are an issue with esbuild's custom TypeScript parser. </p></li><li><p> Memory is used efficiently. </p> <p> Compilers are ideally mostly O(n) complexity in the length of the input. So if you are processing a lot of data, memory access speed is likely going to heavily affect performance. The fewer passes you have to make over your data (and also the fewer different representations you need to transform your data into), the faster your compiler will go. </p> <p> For example, esbuild only touches the whole JavaScript AST three times: </p> <ol> <li>A pass for lexing, parsing, scope setup, and declaring symbols</li> <li>A pass for binding symbols, minifying syntax, JSX/TS to JS, and ESNext-to-ES2015</li> <li>A pass for minifying identifiers, minifying whitespace, generating code, and generating source maps</li> </ol> <p> This maximizes reuse of AST data while it's still hot in the CPU cache. Other bundlers do these steps in separate passes instead of interleaving them. They may also convert between data representations to glue multiple libraries together (e.g. string→TS→JS→string, then string→JS→older JS→string, then string→JS→minified JS→string) which uses more memory and slows things down. </p> <p> Another benefit of Go is that it can store things as compactly in memory, which enables it to use less memory and fit more in the CPU cache. All object fields have types and fields are packed tightly together so e.g. several boolean flags only take one byte each. Go also has value semantics and can embed one object directly in another so it comes "for free" without another allocation. JavaScript doesn't have these features and also has other drawbacks such as JIT overhead (e.g. hidden class slots) and inefficient representations (e.g. non-integer numbers are heap-allocated with pointers). </p></li></ul>
      <p>Each one of these factors is only a somewhat significant speedup, but together they can result in a bundler that is multiple orders of magnitude faster than other bundlers commonly in use today.</p>
      <h2 id="benchmark-details">
        <a href="#benchmark-details">#</a>
        Benchmark details
      </h2>
      <p>Here are the details about each benchmark:</p>
      <figcaption>JavaScript benchmark</figcaption>
      <figure>
        <div>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <p>0.37s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>1.54s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>36.00s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>41.91s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>54.50s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>56.71s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>118.51s</p>
          <p>0s</p>
          <p>30s</p>
          <p>60s</p>
          <p>90s</p>
          <p>120s</p>
        </div>
      </figure>
      <p>This benchmark approximates a large JavaScript codebase by duplicating the <a href="https://github.com/mrdoob/three.js">three.js</a> library 10 times and building a single bundle from scratch, without any caches. The benchmark can be run with <code>make bench-three</code> in the <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild">esbuild repo</a>.</p>
      <table>
      <thead>
      <tr>
      <th>Bundler</th>
      <th>Time</th>
      <th>Relative slowdown</th>
      <th>Absolute speed</th>
      <th>Output size</th>
      </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild</td>
      <td>0.37s</td>
      <td>1x</td>
      <td>1479.6 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.80mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild (1 thread)</td>
      <td>1.54s</td>
      <td>4x</td>
      <td>355.5 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.80mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>rollup + terser</td>
      <td>36.00s</td>
      <td>97x</td>
      <td>15.2 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.81mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 4</td>
      <td>41.91s</td>
      <td>113x</td>
      <td>13.1 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.97mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 5</td>
      <td>54.50s</td>
      <td>147x</td>
      <td>10.0 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.84mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 2</td>
      <td>56.71s</td>
      <td>153x</td>
      <td>9.7 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.92mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 1</td>
      <td>118.51s</td>
      <td>320x</td>
      <td>4.6 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.89mb</td>
      </tr>
      </tbody>
      </table>
      <p>Each time reported is the best of three runs. I'm running esbuild with <code>--bundle <wbr>--minify <wbr>--sourcemap</code> (the single-threaded version uses <code>GOMAXPROCS=1</code>). I used the <code>rollup-<wbr>plugin-<wbr>terser</code> plugin because Rollup itself doesn't support minification. Webpack uses <code>--mode=<wbr>production <wbr>--devtool=<wbr>sourcemap</code>. Parcel uses the default options. Absolute speed is based on the total line count including comments and blank lines, which is currently 547,441. The tests were done on a 6-core 2019 MacBook Pro with 16gb of RAM.</p>
      <p>Caveats:</p>
      <ul><li>Parcel 1: The bundle crashes at run time with <code>TypeError: <wbr>Cannot <wbr>redefine <wbr>property: <wbr>dynamic</code></li></ul>
      <figcaption>TypeScript benchmark</figcaption>
      <figure>
        <div>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <p>0.09s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>0.37s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>18.38s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>18.76s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>25.12s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>42.32s</p>
          <p>0s</p>
          <p>10s</p>
          <p>20s</p>
          <p>30s</p>
          <p>40s</p>
        </div>
      </figure>
      <p>This benchmark uses the <a href="https://github.com/facebookexperimental/rome">Rome</a> build tool to approximate a large TypeScript codebase. All code must be combined into a single minified bundle with source maps and the resulting bundle must work correctly. The benchmark can be run with <code>make bench-rome</code> in the <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild">esbuild repo</a>.</p>
      <table>
      <thead>
      <tr>
      <th>Bundler</th>
      <th>Time</th>
      <th>Relative slowdown</th>
      <th>Absolute speed</th>
      <th>Output size</th>
      </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild</td>
      <td>0.09s</td>
      <td>1x</td>
      <td>1464.8 kloc/s</td>
      <td>0.97mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild (1 thread)</td>
      <td>0.37s</td>
      <td>4x</td>
      <td>356.3 kloc/s</td>
      <td>0.97mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 4</td>
      <td>18.38s</td>
      <td>204x</td>
      <td>7.2 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.26mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 1</td>
      <td>18.76s</td>
      <td>208x</td>
      <td>7.0 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.56mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 5</td>
      <td>24.57s</td>
      <td>273x</td>
      <td>5.4 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.26mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 2</td>
      <td>42.32s</td>
      <td>470x</td>
      <td>3.1 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.68mb</td>
      </tr>
      </tbody>
      </table>
      <p>Each time reported is the best of three runs. I'm running esbuild with <code>--bundle <wbr>--minify <wbr>--sourcemap <wbr>--platform=<wbr>node</code> (the single-threaded version uses <code>GOMAXPROCS=1</code>). Webpack uses <code>ts-loader</code> with <code>transpileOnly: <wbr>true</code> and <code>--mode=<wbr>production <wbr>--devtool=<wbr>sourcemap</code>. Parcel 1 uses <code>--target <wbr>node --bundle-<wbr>node-<wbr>modules</code>. Parcel 2 uses <code>"engines": <wbr>"node"</code> in <code>package.json</code> and needs the <code>@parcel/<wbr>transformer-<wbr>typescript-<wbr>tsc</code> transformer to be able to handle the TypeScript code used in the benchmark. Absolute speed is based on the total line count including comments and blank lines, which is currently 131,836. The tests were done on a 6-core 2019 MacBook Pro with 16gb of RAM.</p>
      <p>The results don't include Rollup because I couldn't get it to work. I tried <code>rollup-<wbr>plugin-<wbr>typescript</code>, <code>@rollup/<wbr>plugin-<wbr>typescript</code>, and <code>@rollup/<wbr>plugin-<wbr>sucrase</code> and they all didn't work for different reasons relating to TypeScript compilation.</p>
      <h2 id="upcoming-roadmap">
        <a href="#upcoming-roadmap">#</a>
        Upcoming roadmap
      </h2>
      <p>These features are already in progress and are first priority:</p>
      <ul><li>Code splitting (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/16">#16</a>, <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/api/#splitting">docs</a>)</li><li>CSS content type (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/20">#20</a>, <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/content-types/#css">docs</a>)</li><li>Plugin API (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/111">#111</a>)</li></ul>
      <p>These are potential future features but may not happen or may happen to a more limited extent:</p>
      <ul><li>HTML content type (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/31">#31</a>)</li><li>Lowering to ES5 (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/297">#297</a>)</li><li>Bundling top-level await (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/253">#253</a>)</li></ul>
      <p>After that point, I will consider esbuild to be relatively complete. I'm planning for esbuild to reach a mostly stable state and then stop accumulating more features. This will involve saying "no" to requests for adding major features to esbuild itself. I don't think esbuild should become an all-in-one solution for all frontend needs. In particular, I want to avoid the pain and problems of the "webpack config" model where the underlying tool is too flexible and usability suffers.</p>
      <p>For example, I am <em>not</em> planning to include these features in esbuild's core itself:</p>
      <ul><li>Support for other frontend languages (e.g. <a href="https://elm-lang.org/">Elm</a>, <a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a>, <a href="https://vuejs.org/">Vue</a>, <a href="https://angular.io/">Angular</a>)</li><li>TypeScript type checking (just run <code>tsc</code> separately)</li><li>An API for custom AST manipulation</li><li>Hot-module reloading</li><li>Module federation</li></ul>
      <p>I hope that the extensibility points I'm adding to esbuild (<a href="https://esbuild.github.io/plugins/">plugins</a> and the <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/api/">API</a>) will make esbuild useful to include as part of more customized build workflows, but I'm not intending or expecting these extensibility points to cover all use cases. If you have very custom requirements then you should be using …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast">https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26154509</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 15:07:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Behold z, the unsung jewel that rethinks shell navigation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 116 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26153401">thread link</a>) | @aymericbeaumet
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://aymericbeaumet.com/behold-z-the-unsung-jewel-that-rethinks-shell-navigation | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://aymericbeaumet.com/behold-z-the-unsung-jewel-that-rethinks-shell-navigation">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
<div>
<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

<div itemprop="articleBody">
<p>I spend a fair amount of time wandering around in the terminal. The chances
are that you are too since you dared to open this story. My daily activities
led me to contribute to various kinds of projects (professional, personal and
open-source). For my sanity, I tend to follow strict rules to organize my
workspace, which helps me keep things tidied up and easily reachable. Or so I
thought.</p>
<p>I decided to arrange my projects by following the <a href="https://golang.org/doc/code.html#Workspaces">Go
philosophy</a>: make the
arborescence mirrors the urls where they are reachable. e.g.,
<code>~/Workspace/src/github.com/aymericbeaumet/dotfiles</code> would contain the
project <a href="https://github.com/aymericbeaumet/dotfiles">dotfiles</a> owned by
<a href="https://github.com/aymericbeaumet">@aymericbeaumet</a> and accessible at
<a href="https://github.com/">github.com</a>. That’s great, but I am now facing a complex
directory structure tedious to navigate quickly. Making it, in the end,
harder to access the resources I need.</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>pwd</span>
/Users/aymericbeaumet/Workspace/src/github.com/brigad/back-end
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Nobody wants to manually deal with this.</em></p>
<p>Remembering and typing the location of each project (even while leveraging
autocomplete) is time-consuming. Creating shell aliases is not scalable.
Instead, I would like to rely on the pseudo-unicity of each project name to
find it among all the directories on my computer.</p>
<h2 id="z">z?</h2>
<p>Several tools exist to tackle this problem. My favorite is
<a href="https://github.com/rupa/z"><em>z</em></a>. It follows the Unix philosophy by being
small, focused and interoperable. <em>z</em> allows jumping around swiftly,
automatically learning from your habits. The entries are ranked based on the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frecency">frecency</a> at which you access the
directories.</p>
<p>Let’s walk through the basics of this tool. Below is how I advise to install
it for Zsh on macOS (the install process should be similar for other shells
and operating systems):</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>brew <span>install </span>z
<span>$ </span><span>echo</span> <span>"source '</span><span>$(</span>brew <span>--prefix</span> z<span>)</span><span>/etc/profile.d/z.sh'"</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> ~/.zshenv
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Install z for Zsh on macOS.</em></p>
<p>Note how installing <em>z</em> is not enough to start using it. You have to source
<code>z.sh</code> at the beginning of each shell session to activate it. The <code>~/.zshenv</code>
configuration file is appropriate as Zsh <a href="http://zsh.sourceforge.net/Intro/intro_3.html">loads it in most
circumstances</a>, making the
tool accessible in a wide-variety of contexts (terminals, editors, IDEs,
scripts, etc.).</p>
<h2 id="lets-play">Let’s play</h2>
<p>Once the install and setup are complete: start a new shell session, <code>cd</code>
through some folders and execute <code>z</code> to confirm it has been accurately
tracking your activity:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>z | <span>sort</span> <span>-rn</span> | <span>head</span> <span>-3</span>
5331.72    /Users/aymericbeaumet/Workspace/src/github.com/brigad/back-end
637.255    /Users/aymericbeaumet/Workspace/src/github.com/brigad/ops
386.198 /Users/aymericbeaumet/.config/dotfiles
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Top 3 directories based on frecency.</em></p>
<p>As shown above, I spend quite some time navigating through
<a href="https://github.com/brigad">Brigad</a> projects, but it seems I also often
access my <a href="https://github.com/aymericbeaumet/dotfiles">dotfiles</a> to tweak
some configuration. The ranking score is volatile, and one could observe
significant changes in a brief amount of time.</p>
<p>Now that <em>z</em> has accumulated some knowledge try it by navigating to one of
the tracked folders. Navigating is as simple as executing the <code>z</code> command
followed by the directory name:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>z dotfiles
<span>$ </span><span>pwd</span>
/Users/aymericbeaumet/.config/dotfiles
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Navigating by matching with a whole directory name.</em></p>
<p>As a matter of facts, I do prefer to leverage partial matching (imagine <code>**</code>
surrounding your search pattern) to type fewer characters. Hence, <code>z dot</code> is
valid and should produce a similar behavior as <code>z dotfiles</code> (modulo possible
name collisions, but you get the idea). This works because <em>z</em> relies on
regular expressions. For example, the snippet below will navigate to the
directory ending with the letters “tmp” (with the highest score):</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>z tmp<span>$</span>
<span>$ </span><span>pwd</span>
/private/tmp
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Navigating by matching with a regular expression.</em></p>
<p>Neat right? I guess you start seeing the possibilities of this tool. And we
have only scratched the surface of its capabilities. I suggest you dive in
its <a href="https://github.com/rupa/z/blob/master/README">documentation</a> to get an
idea of its full potential. Features such as autocomplete, subdirectories
matching, consecutive matching, etc. are a game changer.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p><em>z</em> is tremendous. This tool saves me a non-trivial amount of time every
single day. When one starts relying on it, there is no going back. And I hope
it’s going to fit your workflow as well as mine.</p>
<p>I would be grateful to hear any of your time-saving tricks. Feel free to
share your experiences!</p>
</div>


</article>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://aymericbeaumet.com/behold-z-the-unsung-jewel-that-rethinks-shell-navigation</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26153401</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 12:54:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[US Presidential Election $25k Database Bounty Review]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 144 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26149511">thread link</a>) | @mjangle1985
<br/>
February 15, 2021 | https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-02-15-election-bounty-review/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-02-15-election-bounty-review/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="blog-post-text"><p>On December 14, we launched <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-12-16-data-bounties/">our first data bounty</a> to <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-12-14-make-money-data-wrangling/">earn a share of $25,000 by wrangling US Presidential Precinct-level data</a>. The bounty ended yesterday. How did it go? This blog entry will answer that question.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.doltdb.com/">Dolt</a> is a SQL database with Git-style versioning. It's the first SQL database you can branch and merge. <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/">DoltHub</a> is a place on the internet to share and collaborate on Dolt databases. Without both, data bounties would not be possible.</p>

<p>We built the <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results">best open database of US Precinct-level Election results</a> on the internet. </p>
<p>Here's some statistics:</p>
<ul>
<li>15.5M cells edited. 1.7GB of data collected</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+COUNT%28distinct%28state%29%29%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2016%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">All 51 "states" covered for 2016</a>. <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+COUNT%28distinct%28state%29%29%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2020%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">38 states covered for 2020</a>. </li>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+sum%28votes%29%2F136669276%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2016%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">100% of the vote covered for 2016</a>. <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+sum%28votes%29%2F159633396%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2020%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">78% for 2020</a>.</li>
<li>75 Pull Requests (PRs) accepted across 6 bounty participants. </li>
<li>Top bounty participant earned over $10,000.</li>
</ul>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/0fcea/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Final Scoreboard" title="Final Scoreboard" src="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/0fcea/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png" srcset="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/a48b3/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png 214w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/47730/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png 428w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/0fcea/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png 851w" sizes="(max-width: 851px) 100vw, 851px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>We're very excited to mail the checks to all the folks who worked hard to make this bounty a success.</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/2ad33/fat-check.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Fat Check" title="Fat Check" src="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/79a4e/fat-check.jpg" srcset="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/606a2/fat-check.jpg 214w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/65a3f/fat-check.jpg 428w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/79a4e/fat-check.jpg 856w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/99aeb/fat-check.jpg 1284w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/e88f6/fat-check.jpg 1712w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/2ad33/fat-check.jpg 3851w" sizes="(max-width: 856px) 100vw, 856px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>

<p>Now that the bounty is complete, we must figure out what to do with this data. How do we get the most out of our investment in the data?</p>
<h2>Clean up the data we got</h2>
<p>Given the heavily keyed nature of this data, we decided early on to not accept PRs for standardization or normalization of things like party names. Because most columns are part of the primary key, any change looks like a deletion and corresponding addition to Dolt. Thus, changes like that give the corrector credit for the whole row in the bounty instead of just the cell he or she changed. We queued up a number of these types of changes and we'll execute them now that the bounty is over.</p>
<h2>Find some users</h2>
<p>We collected the best US presidential Precinct level results on the internet. Now, we want people to use it. We think potentially the data is good enough that an open data community could be bootstrapped around it. The people who use it would have incentive to finish it as new state level data is released. We will reach out to the people at <a href="http://openelections.net/">Open Elections</a> and <a href="https://electionlab.mit.edu/">MIT Elections Lab</a> and start a conversation. If you know anyone else who could use this data, <a href="https://discord.com/invite/RFwfYpu">come let us know in our Discord</a>.</p>
<h2>Run another bounty?</h2>
<p>We're still missing 12 states and about 22% of the vote from 2020. If we want to get complete data and an open data community can't be bootstrapped, we may run another bounty in a couple months to finish the dataset. Let us know if you'd be interested in another bounty or the complete dataset.</p>

<p>We think <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/bounties">DoltHub Bounties</a> may be the fastest, cheapest way to build databases from open data. For $25,000 and 8 weeks, we were able to assemble a 1.7GB database of election results. </p>
<p>Our plan is to run at least one bounty per month for the rest of the year across a number of distinct data disciplines. We're running a <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-01-14-hopsital-prices-bounty/">hospital price transparency bounty</a> right now. We'll be launching two more over the next month or so. Hang out in <a href="https://discord.com/invite/RFwfYpu">our Discord</a> to keep up to date. Start wrangling data as your new side hustle.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-02-15-election-bounty-review/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26149511</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:20:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building Rich Terminal Dashboards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 483 | Comments 116 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26149488">thread link</a>) | @lumpa
<br/>
February 15, 2021 | https://www.willmcgugan.com/blog/tech/post/building-rich-terminal-dashboards/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.willmcgugan.com/blog/tech/post/building-rich-terminal-dashboards/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    

    
<p><a href="https://github.com/willmcgugan/rich">Rich</a> has become a popular (20K stars on GH) way of beautifying CLIs, and I'm pleased to see a number of projects using it.</p>
<p>Since Rich is mature and battle-tested now, I had considered winding-down development. Until, I saw this tweet:</p>
<h2>The Tweet</h2>
<blockquote><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Do you want to see something really cool you can do with <a href="https://twitter.com/willmcgugan?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@willmcgugan</a> 's rich library? </p><p>Checkout ghtop <a href="https://t.co/mn7oLbpw8e">https://t.co/mn7oLbpw8e</a>. It's a really fun CLI tool that demonstrates the power of rich (and other things).</p><p>Examples below 🧵👇 (1/8)</p></div>— Hamel Husain (@HamelHusain) <a href="https://twitter.com/HamelHusain/status/1357771218095546368?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 5, 2021</a></blockquote> 
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HamelHusain">@HamelHusain</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/jeremyphoward">@jeremyphoward</a> used Rich to enhance <a href="https://github.com/nat/ghtop">ghtop</a> (a repo owned by the CEO of Github, no less). Ghtop shows a realtime a stream of events from the Github platform. And it looks good! So good that I realised how much potential Rich has for these type of htop-like applications.</p>
<p>Hamel and Jeremy had to overcome a few technical hurdles to make that work. Fortunately this will no longer be required as the latest version of Rich has first-class support for full-screen interfaces via a new Layout system.</p>
<h2>Full-screen terminal interface</h2>
<p>Here's a video demonstration of a terminal interface built with Layout:</p>
<p>
<iframe width="auto" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/slrdSojCvlk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p>
<h2>Layout API</h2>
<p>The API to create a flexible layout is surprisingly simple. You construct a <code>Layout()</code> object, then call <code>split()</code> to create sub-layouts. These sub-layouts may then be further divided. Layouts have a small number of settings which define their size relative to the terminal window. It's a simple system that can create terminal interfaces that almost resemble modern web apps.</p>
<div><figure> <img width="1140" height="724" title="layout_vscode.png" name="layout_vscode" data-md="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg" data-square="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.square.7.jpeg" data-xlg2x="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg2x.2.jpeg" data-lg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg" data-xlg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg.8.jpeg" data-author="© 2021 Will McGugan<br>all rights reserved" data-og_preview="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.og.preview.2.jpeg" data-height="2100" data-width="3308" data-toggle="tooltip" data-details=" " data-sm="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg" data-blur="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.blur.6.jpeg" data-slug="layout_vscode" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1170px, (min-width: 992px) 970px, (min-width: 768px) 750px" srcset="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg 1170w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg 970w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg 750w" src="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg"> 
<figcaption>
<p>© 2021 Will McGugan</p>


<p>A Rich layout in VSCode</p>


</figcaption>

</figure>
</div>
<h2>Finally, some code</h2>
<p>Here's how you would create a basic layout with a header, a footer, and two side-panels.</p>
<pre><code>from rich.console import Console
from rich.layout import Layout

console = Console()
layout = Layout()

# Divide the "screen" in to three parts
layout.split(
    Layout(name="header", size=3),
    Layout(ratio=1, name="main"),
    Layout(size=10, name="footer"),
)
# Divide the "main" layout in to "side" and "body"
layout["main"].split(
    Layout(name="side"),
    Layout(name="body", ratio=2),
    direction="horizontal"
)
# Divide the "side" layout in to two
layout["side"].split(Layout(), Layout())

console.print(layout)
</code></pre>
<p>Running the code above produces the following output:</p>
<div><figure> <img width="1140" height="739" title="layout.png" name="layout" data-md="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg" data-square="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.square.7.jpeg" data-xlg2x="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg2x.2.jpeg" data-lg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg" data-xlg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg.8.jpeg" data-author="© 2021 Will McGugan<br>all rights reserved" data-og_preview="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.og.preview.2.jpeg" data-height="1464" data-width="2258" data-toggle="tooltip" data-details=" " data-sm="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg" data-blur="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.blur.6.jpeg" data-slug="layout" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1170px, (min-width: 992px) 970px, (min-width: 768px) 750px" srcset="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg 1170w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg 970w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg 750w" src="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg"> 
<figcaption>
<p>© 2021 Will McGugan</p>


<p>Terminal split in to 5 sub-layouts. The boxes are placeholders, you can insert any content in their place.</p>


</figcaption>

</figure>
</div>
<p>Any renderable (text, table, progress bars etc) may be placed inside those sub-layouts.</p>
<p>We can now use the <a href="https://rich.readthedocs.io/en/latest/live.html">Live</a> class to create an application that adapts itself to the terminal window:</p>
<pre><code>from rich.live import Live
from time import sleep

with Live(layout, screen=True):
    while True:
        sleep(1)
</code></pre>
<p>In a real app, that do-nothing loop will be doing something useful like pulling data from the network to update contents.</p>
<p>See the <a href="https://rich.readthedocs.io/en/latest/layout.html">layout docs</a> for an in-depth tutorial.</p>
<h2>What's next?</h2>
<p>I think it's clear that Rich is acquiring more TUI (text user interface) features, and I've decided not to fight it. Rich's core purpose is still to beautify CLI output, but I think there is an opportunity here for a new way to create terminal apps. Ultimately it will be less like curses and more like HTML in a browser.</p>
<p>There are a number of things to do before Rich could replace a full TUI library (keyboard and mouse input for one) but the potential is there. Stay tuned for progress.</p>
<p>Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/willmcgugan">@willmcgugan</a> for more Rich related news.</p>



</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.willmcgugan.com/blog/tech/post/building-rich-terminal-dashboards/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26149488</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:16:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
