<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:30:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[EduTech Spyware Is Still Spyware: Proctorio Edition]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24450248">thread link</a>) | @some_furry
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://soatok.blog/2020/09/12/edutech-spyware-is-still-spyware-proctorio-edition/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soatok.blog/2020/09/12/edutech-spyware-is-still-spyware-proctorio-edition/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p>Spyware written for educational institutions to flex their muscles of control over students and their families when learning from their home computer is still, categorically, spyware.</p>



<p>Depending on your persuasion, the previous sentence sounds like either needless pedantry, or it reads like tautology. But we need to be clear on our terms.</p>



<ol><li>Educational spyware is still spyware.</li><li>Spyware is categorized as a subset of malware.</li></ol>



<p>When vulnerabilities are discovered in malware, the normal rules of <a href="https://adamcaudill.com/2015/11/19/responsible-disclosure-is-wrong/">coordinated disclosure</a> are out of scope. Are we clear?</p>







<p>So let’s talk about Proctorio!</p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">For anyone unfamiliar with it, Proctorio is a browser extension used to eliminate cheating through intense surveillance techniques. It records the computer screen while you take the exam to ensure you don’t look anything up. However, it’s more than that. (Thread 1/11)</p>— Cassie (@Angry_Cassie) <a href="https://twitter.com/Angry_Cassie/status/1301360994044850182?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div><figcaption>The entire thread is unrolled <a href="https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1301360994044850182.html">here</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>I won’t go into the details of Proctorio or why it’s terrible for (especially disadvantaged) students. Read Cassie’s Twitter thread for more context on that. Seriously. I’m not gonna be one of those guys that <em>talks over</em> women, and neither should you.</p>



<p>What I am here to talk about today is these dubious claim about the security of their product:</p>







<h2 id="zero-knowledge">Zero-Knowledge Encryption? OMGWTFBBQ!</h2>



<p>In cryptography, there are a class of algorithms called Zero-Knowledge Proofs. In a Zero-Knowledge Proof, you prove that you possess some fact without revealing any details <em>about</em> the fact.</p>



<p>It’s kind of abstract to think about (and until we’re ready to talk about Pedersen commitments, I’m just going to defer to <a href="https://openprivacy.ca/work/swisspost-scytl-evoting/">Sarah Jamie Lewis</a>), but the only thing you need to know about “Zero Knowledge” in Cryptography is that the output is a boolean (True, False).</p>



<p>You can’t use “Zero Knowledge” <em>anything</em> to encrypt. So “Zero-Knowledge Encryption” is a meaningless buzzword.</p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">As a cryptographer, I would like details on how on Earth it is using zero knowledge proofs in this situation. In all likelihood they're not doing what "zero knowledge" usually means, which quite frankly has me more worried about the security, not less.</p>— Buchberger's algorithm fan account (@SchmiegSophie) <a href="https://twitter.com/SchmiegSophie/status/1304407483658592256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>So what are they actually describing when they say Zero Knowledge Encryption?</p>







<p>Okay, so they’ve built their own key distribution system and are encrypting with AES-GCM… and shipped this in a Chrome extension. But before we get to that, look at this <strong>Daily Vulnerability Tests</strong> claim.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1204" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-04/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-04" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Bullshit.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Running Nessus (or equivalent) on a cron job isn’t meaningful metric of security. At best, it creates alert fatigue when you accidentally screw up a deployment configuration or forget to update your software for 4+ years. (Y’know, like JsZip 3.2.1, which they bundle.)</p>



<p>A dumb vulnerability scan isn’t the same thing as a routine (usually quarterly) penetration test or a code audit. And if you’re working in cryptography, <em>you better have both</em>!</p>



<h2 id="vulnerability">Timing Leaks in Proctorio’s AES-GCM Implementation</h2>



<p>If you download version 1.4.20241.1.0 of the Proctorio Chrome Extension, run <code>src/assets/J5HG.js</code> through a JS beautifier, and then look at its contents, you will quickly realize this is a JavaScript cryptography library.</p>



<p>Since the “zero knowledge” encryption they’re so proud about uses AES-GCM, let’s focus on that.</p>



<p>Proctorio’s AES-GCM implementation exists in an object called <code>dhs.mode.gcm</code>, which is mildly obfuscated, but contains the following functions:</p>



<ul><li><code>encrypt()</code> – Encrypt with AES-GCM</li><li><code>decrypt()</code> – Decrypt with AES-GCM</li><li><code>aa()</code> – GHASH block multiplication</li><li><code>j()</code> – XOR + GMAC utility function</li><li><code>O()</code> – Called by encrypt() and decrypt(); does all of the AES-CTR + GMAC fun</li></ul>



<p>If you’re not familiar with <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/05/13/why-aes-gcm-sucks/">AES-GCM</a>, just know this: <a href="https://cryptologie.net/article/361/breaking-https-aes-gcm-or-a-part-of-it/">Timing leaks</a> can be used to leak your GMAC key to outside applications, which completely breaks the authentication of AES-GCM and opens the door to chosen-ciphertext attacks.</p>



<p>So is their implementation of AES-GCM constant-time? Let’s take a look at <code>aa()</code>:</p>


<pre title="">aa: function(a, b) {
  var c, d, e, f, g, h = dhs.bitArray.ba;
  for (e = [0, 0, 0, 0], f = b.slice(0), c = 0; 128 &gt; c; c++) {
    for (
      (d = 0 !== (a[Math.floor(c / 32)] &amp; 1 &lt;&lt; 31 - c % 32)) &amp;&amp; (e = h(e, f)),
        g = 0 !== (1 &amp; f[3]),
        d = 3;
      d &gt; 0;
      d--
    )
      f[d] = f[d] &gt;&gt;&gt; 1 | (1 &amp; f[d - 1]) &lt;&lt; 31;
    f[0] &gt;&gt;&gt;= 1,
    g &amp;&amp; (f[0] ^= -520093696)
  }
  return e
},
</pre>


<p>This is a bit obtuse, but this line leaks the lowest bit of <code>f</code> with each iteration: <code>g = 0 !== (1 &amp; f[3])</code>.</p>



<p>Since <code>f</code> gets bitwise right-shifted 128 times, this actually leaks the bit of every value of <code>f</code> in each block multiplication, since the execution of <code>(f[0] ^= -520093696)</code> depends on whether or not <code>g</code> is set to <code>true</code>.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1387" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-11/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-11" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Timing leaks? So much for “zero-knowledge”!</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Also, they claim to be FIPS 140-2 compliant, but this is how they generate randomness in their cryptography library.</p>



<figure><div>

</div></figure>



<p>(Although, <a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/cryptographic-module-validation-program/validated-modules/search?SearchMode=Basic&amp;Vendor=Proctorio&amp;CertificateStatus=Active&amp;ValidationYear=0">that’s probably a lie</a>.)</p>



<p>To mitigate these vulnerabilities, one needs look no further than <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/08/27/soatoks-guide-to-side-channel-attacks/#conditional-select">the guide to side-channel attacks</a> I published last month. </p>



<p>(Also, use WebCrypto to generate entropy! What the fuck.)</p>



<h2>If Proctorio is Insecure, What Should We Use Instead?</h2>



<p><strong>Nothing.</strong></p>



<p>Schools that demand students install spyware on their personal computers are only a step removed from domestic abusers who install stalkerware on their victims’ phones.</p>



<p>Proctorio isn’t the problem here, they’re only a symptom.</p>



<p>Schools that insist on violating the integrity and parental dominion of their students’ home computers are the problem here.</p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Zoom school is really showing how much of American Education is just about controlling and punishing children and not actually, you know, teaching and educating them</p>— Lawrence of A Labia (@lex_about_sex) <a href="https://twitter.com/lex_about_sex/status/1304156305398140928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div><figcaption>Preach!</figcaption></figure>



<p>If you want to ensure the integrity of students’ education, try teaching them about consent and ethical computing. (Y’know, concepts that are fundamentally incompatible with the business model of Proctorio and Proctorio’s competitors.)</p>



<h2 id="timeline">Disclosure Timeline</h2>



<p>Really? <em>Really?</em></p>



<p>This was a zero-day disclosure, because full disclosure is the responsible choice when dealing with spyware. Don’t even @ me.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="70" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatok_stickerpack-hacker/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="soatok_stickerpack-hacker" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Disclaimer: This security research was conducted by Soatok– some furry on the Internet–while bored on his off-time and does not reflect the opinions of any company.</figcaption></figure></div>



<h2 id="sinkhole">Domains to Sinkhole</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to protect your home network from this spyware, here are a list of domains to sinkhole (i.e. with <a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-Hole</a>).</p>



<ul><li>proctorauth.com</li><li>proctordata.com</li><li>getproctorio.com</li><li>proctor.io</li><li>proctor.in</li><li>az545770.vo.msecnd.net</li></ul>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soatok.blog/2020/09/12/edutech-spyware-is-still-spyware-proctorio-edition/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24450248</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 06:09:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What's wrong with social science and how to fix it]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24447724">thread link</a>) | @michael_fine
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://fantasticanachronism.com/2020/09/11/whats-wrong-with-social-science-and-how-to-fix-it/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fantasticanachronism.com/2020/09/11/whats-wrong-with-social-science-and-how-to-fix-it/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><blockquote><p>I've seen things you people wouldn't believe.</p></blockquote><p>Over the past year, I have skimmed through 2578 social science papers, spending about 2.5 minutes on each one. This was due to my participation in <a href="https://www.replicationmarkets.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Replication Markets</a>, a part of DARPA's SCORE program, whose goal is to evaluate the reliability of social science research. 3000 studies were split up into 10 rounds of ~300 studies each. Starting in August 2019, each round consisted of one week of surveys followed by two weeks of market trading. I finished in first place in 3 out 10 survey rounds and 6 out of 10 market rounds. In total, about $200,000 in prize money will be awarded.</p><p>The studies were sourced from all social sciences disciplines (economics, psychology, sociology, management, etc.) and were published between 2009 and 2018 (in other words, most of the sample came from the post-replication crisis era).</p><p>The average replication probability in the market was 54%; while the replication results are not out yet (250 of the 3000 papers will be replicated), previous experiments have shown that prediction markets work well.<span><a href="#fn19282306691" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306691">1</sup></a></span></p><p>This is what the distribution of my own predictions looks like:<span><a href="#fn19282306692" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306692">2</sup></a></span></p><p><img src="https://fantasticanachronism.com/images/skimmed_mypredsdist-67f351a8a634ca87ace22fd62155e7c5.png"></p><p>My average forecast was in line with the market. A quarter of the claims were above 76%. And a quarter of them were below 33%: we're talking hundreds upon hundreds of terrible papers, and this is just a tiny sample of the annual academic production.</p><p>Criticizing bad science from an abstract, 10000-foot view is pleasant: you hear about some stuff that doesn't replicate, some methodologies that seem a bit silly. "They should improve their methods", "p-hacking is bad", "we must change the incentives", you declare Zeuslike from your throne in the clouds, and then go on with your day.</p><p>But actually diving into the sea of trash that is social science gives you a more tangible perspective, a more visceral revulsion, and perhaps even a sense of Lovecraftian awe at the sheer magnitude of it all: a vast landfill—a great agglomeration of garbage extending as far as the eye can see, effluvious waves crashing and throwing up a foul foam of p=0.049 papers. As you walk up to the diving platform, the deformed attendant hands you a pair of flippers. Noticing your reticence, he gives a subtle nod as if to say: "come on then, jump in".</p><h2 id="They-Know-What-They-39-re-Doing"><a href="#They-Know-What-They-39-re-Doing" title="They Know What They're Doing"></a>They Know What They're Doing</h2><p>Prediction markets work well because predicting replication is easy.<span><a href="#fn19282306693" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306693">3</sup></a></span> There's no need for a deep dive into the statistical methodology or a rigorous examination of the data, no need to scrutinize esoteric theories for subtle errors—these papers have obvious, surface-level problems.</p><p>There's a popular belief that weak studies are the result of unconscious biases leading researchers down a "garden of forking paths". Given enough "researcher degrees of freedom" even the most punctilious investigator can be misled.</p><p>I find this belief impossible to accept. The brain is a credulous piece of meat<span><a href="#fn19282306694" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306694">4</sup></a></span> but there are limits to self-delusion. Most of them have to know. It's understandable to be led down the garden of forking paths while producing the research, but when the paper is done and you give it a final read-over you will surely notice that all you have is a n=23, p=0.049 three-way interaction effect (one of dozens you tested, and with no multiple testing adjustments of course). At that point it takes more than a <em>subtle unconscious bias</em> to believe you have found something real. And even if the authors really are misled by the forking paths, what are the editors and reviewers doing? Are we supposed to believe they are all gullible rubes?</p><p>People within the academy don't want to rock the boat. They still have to attend the conferences, secure the grants, publish in the journals, show up at the faculty meetings: all these things depend on their peers. When criticising bad research it's easier for everyone to blame the forking paths rather than the person walking them. No need for uncomfortable unpleasantries. The fraudster can admit, without much of a hit to their reputation, that indeed they were <em>misled</em> by that <em>dastardly garden</em>, really through no fault of their own whatsoever, at which point their colleagues on twitter will applaud and say "ah, good on you, you handled this tough situation with such exquisite virtue, this is how progress happens! hip, hip, hurrah!" What a ridiculous charade.</p><p>Even when they do accuse someone of wrongdoing they use terms like "Questionable Research Practices" (QRP). How about Questionable Euphemism Practices?</p><ul><li>When they measure a dozen things and only pick their outcome variable at the end, that's not the garden of forking paths but the greenhouse of fraud.</li><li>When they do a correlational analysis but give "policy implications" as if they were doing a causal one, they're not walking around the garden, they're doing the landscaping of forking paths.</li><li>When they take a continuous variable and arbitrarily bin it to do subgroup analysis or when they add an <em>ad hoc</em> quadratic term to their regression, they're...fertilizing the garden of forking paths? (Look, there's only so many horticultural metaphors, ok?)</li></ul><p>The bottom line is this: if a random schmuck with zero domain expertise like me can predict what will replicate, <em>then so can scientists who have spent half their lives studying this stuff</em>. But they sure don't act like it.</p><h2 id="or-Maybe-They-Don-39-t"><a href="#or-Maybe-They-Don-39-t" title="...or Maybe They Don't?"></a>...or Maybe They Don't?</h2><blockquote><p>The horror! The horror!</p></blockquote><p>Check out this crazy chart from <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2020/04/28/1909046117" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yang et al. (2020)</a>:</p><p><img src="https://fantasticanachronism.com/images/skimmed_citations-7d4f72c6e9582a5ba8775da70eda80e1.png"></p><p>Yes, you're reading that right: studies that replicate are cited at the same rate as studies that do not. Publishing your own weak papers is one thing, but citing other people's weak papers? This seemed implausible, so I decided to do my own analysis with a sample of 250 articles from the Replication Markets project. The correlation between citations per year and (market-estimated) probability of replication was -0.05!</p><p>You might hypothesize that the citations of non-replicating papers are negative, but negative citations are extremely rare.<span><a href="#fn19282306695" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306695">5</sup></a></span> <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/112/45/13823" target="_blank" rel="noopener">One study</a> puts the rate at 2.4%. Astonishingly, even <em>after retraction</em> the <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18974415/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">vast majority of citations are positive</a>, and those positive citations <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/20136577/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">continue for decades after retraction</a>.<span><a href="#fn19282306696" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306696">6</sup></a></span></p><p>As in all affairs of man, it once again comes down to Hanlon's Razor. Either:</p><ol><li>Malice: they know which results are likely false but cite them anyway.</li><li>or, Stupidity: they can't tell which papers will replicate even though it's quite easy.</li></ol><p>Accepting the first option would require a level of cynicism that even I struggle to muster. But the alternative doesn't seem much better: <em>how can they not know?</em> I, an idiot with no relevant credentials or knowledge, can fairly accurately determine good research from bad, but all the tenured experts can not? How can they not tell <em>which papers are retracted</em>?</p><p>I think the most plausible explanation is that scientists don't read the papers they cite, which I suppose involves both malice <em>and</em> stupidity.<span><a href="#fn19282306697" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306697">7</sup></a></span> <a href="https://www.gwern.net/Scanners#citogenesis-how-often-do-researchers-not-read-the-papers-they-cite" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gwern has an write-up on this question</a> citing some ingenious analyses based on the proliferation of misprints: "Simkin &amp; Roychowdhury venture a guess that as many as 80% of authors citing a paper have not actually read the original". Once a paper is out there nobody bothers to check it, even though they know there's a 50-50 chance it's false!</p><p>Whatever the explanation might be, the fact is that the academic system does not allocate citations to true claims.<span><a href="#fn19282306698" rel="footnote"><sup id="fnref19282306698">8</sup></a></span> This is bad not only for the direct effect of basing further research on false results, but also because it distorts the incentives scientists face. If nobody cited weak studies, we wouldn't have so many of them. Rewarding impact without regard for the truth inevitably leads to disaster.</p><h2 id="There-Are-No-Journals-With-Strict-Quality-Standards"><a href="#There-Are-No-Journals-With-Strict-Quality-Standards" title="There Are No Journals With Strict Quality Standards"></a>There Are No Journals With Strict Quality Standards</h2><p>Naïvely you might expect that the top-ranking journals would be full of studies that are highly likely to replicate, and the low-ranking journals would be full of p&lt;0.1 studies based on five undergraduates. Not so! Like citations, journal status and quality are not very well correlated: <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fnhum.2018.00037/full" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there is no association between statistical power and impact factor</a>, and journals with higher impact factor <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/071530v1.full.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">have more papers with erroneous p-values</a>.</p><p>This pattern is repeated in the Replication Markets data. As you can see in the chart below, there's no relationship between h-index (a measure of impact) and average expected replication rates. There's also no relationship between h-index and expected replication <em>within</em> fields.</p><p><img src="https://fantasticanachronism.com/images/skimmed_journalhindex-34ca20d3877248fe6b7313c3e2d39fae.png"></p><p>Even the <em>crème de la crème</em> of economics journals barely manage a ⅔ expected replication rate. 1 in 5 articles in QJE scores below 50%, and this is a journal that accepts just 1 out of every 30 submissions. Perhaps this (partially) explains why scientists are undiscerning: journal reputation acts as a cloak for bad research. It would be fun to test this idea empirically.</p><p>Here you can see the distribution of replication estimates for every journal in the RM sample:</p><p><img src="https://fantasticanachronism.com/images/skimmed_journals-cdc1139ad4faf1819b8b42db914dbe81.png"></p><p>As far as I can tell, for most journals the question of whether the results in a paper are true is a matter of secondary importance. If we model journals as wanting to maximize "impact", then this is hardly surprising: as we saw above, citation counts are unrelated to truth. If scientists were more careful about what they cited, then journals would in turn be more careful about what they publish.</p><h2 id="Things-Are-Not-Getting-Better"><a href="#Things-Are-Not-Getting-Better" title="Things Are Not Getting Better"></a>Things Are Not Getting Better</h2><p>Before we got to see any of the actual Replication Markets studies, we voted on the expected replication rates by year. <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsos.200566" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gordon et al. (2020)</a> has that data: replication rates were expected to steadily increase from 43% in 2009/2010 to 55% in 2017/2018.</p><p><img src="https://fantasticanachronism.com/images/skimmed_years_pre-7012095f551422f22db31bfffda1c899.png"></p><p>This is what the average predictions looked like <em>after</em> seeing the papers: from 53.4% in 2009 to 55.8% in 2018 (difference not statistically significant; black dots are means).</p><p><img src="https://fantasticanachronism.com/images/skimmed_years-1c0573dfb59a70e36a43deb2692229bf.png"></p><p>I frequently encounter the notion that after the replication crisis hit there was some sort of great improvement in the social sciences, that people wouldn't even dream of publishing studies based on 23 undergraduates any more (I actually saw plenty of those), etc. Stuart Ritchie's new book praises …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://fantasticanachronism.com/2020/09/11/whats-wrong-with-social-science-and-how-to-fix-it/">https://fantasticanachronism.com/2020/09/11/whats-wrong-with-social-science-and-how-to-fix-it/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fantasticanachronism.com/2020/09/11/whats-wrong-with-social-science-and-how-to-fix-it/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24447724</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 21:51:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The technical interview is an ego trip]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 148 | Comments 168 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24447182">thread link</a>) | @kowsheek
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://blog.kowsheek.com/the-technical-interview-is-an-ego-trip/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.kowsheek.com/the-technical-interview-is-an-ego-trip/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            


            <section>
                <div>
                    <p>Early in my career, after a short initial interview at a consulting firm in Toronto, I was invited to a technical interview on the same day. Two of the senior developers from the team I would join would conduct the interview.</p><p>The interview started pleasantly with them describing the project they have been working on: a portal for university professors to communicate with their students. It was being built with ASP.NET MVC, a framework I had been working with for several years. I expressed that I was comfortable with the framework and I would be excited to work on the project. Then the technical examination began and on its conclusion I left the interview feeling humiliated.</p><p>Many years later, when I was preparing to take an interview, I looked back on this experience to realize that the line of questioning and approach had been an ego trip for those developers. I promised myself to <em>never</em> make any of my candidates feel the way I did.</p><p>What did those developers do wrong? Leaving aside their attitude towards me, their questions had no relevance to the role or the project. I did not know what a red-black tree was at the time but I definitely knew how to use ASP.NET MVC which they did not inquire about.</p><p>My golden rule for technical interviews is that, "Every step, conversation and question <em>must</em> be pertinent to the day-to-day of the role." While this may be obvious, I am sure that many hiring managers are still expecting candidates to arrive at technical interviews with Computer Science books memorized. This form of technical interviews should be made obsolete.</p><figure><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Bigger button = more clicks on the CTA <a href="https://t.co/Ter7xJdNKM">pic.twitter.com/Ter7xJdNKM</a></p>— Vincent Déniel (@vincentdnl) <a href="https://twitter.com/vincentdnl/status/1291041278264713220?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 5, 2020</a></blockquote>

</figure><p>With my golden rule as guide, I conduct a much simpler interview process. Prior to an interview, my team and I review samples of code that the candidate shared with us (or had written on Github) to understand the quality of their code. And during the interview, I dive into three areas of discussions with the candidates: product building, process adherence and team work.</p><h3 id="product-building">Product Building</h3><p>I try to understand the candidate's interest and experience of building products by,</p><ol><li>Going through their past experience and asking about what technologies and products they built and how. I ask about previous products they have shipped from concept to market.</li><li>To understand their thought process for deriving solutions, I draw an UI and ask them to outline and explain what approaches, structures and technologies they would use to build it out.</li><li>I ask about how they keep up with technologies and how they improve their skills to gauge their passion for the work.</li></ol><h3 id="process-adherence">Process Adherence</h3><p>To better understand how the candidate does their work,</p><ol><li>I go over their experiences and ask about how they managed their product-building and what tools and processes they used.</li><li>I explain the process of working on our team and ask how they would change it and where they see inefficiencies to discuss their thinking.</li><li>Often, I will give them a scenario where the processes are failing the team to find what they would do to tackle inefficiencies and if they would be willing to speak up.</li></ol><h3 id="team-work">Team Work</h3><p>I also try to understand how a candidate works in a team,</p><ol><li>While going through their past experiences, I ask about how they collaborated and communicated with their teams.</li><li>I present a scenario where their knowledge in an area may be lacking and evaluate if and how they would leverage and collaborate with their team.</li><li>Another scenario I ask about is where they disagree with their team-members to evaluate how they manage conflict and focus on delivering results for the team.</li></ol><p>I do this within one interview to be mindful of the candidate's time and mine. I want to hire candidates for their will to learn, grow and challenge the status quo.</p><p>The technology landscape is such that anyone can acquire a set of baseline programming skills. What is needed then, is a willingness to challenge ourselves and stay open-minded because every developer will have to learn on the job almost all of the time. Given this, the technical interview is arcane, academic and as good as dead.</p><hr><h3 id="further-reading">Further Reading</h3><ol><li><a href="https://news.ncsu.edu/2020/07/tech-job-interviews-anxiety/">Tech Sector Job Interviews Assess Anxiety, Not Software Skills</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/helpful-com/https-medium-com-fnthawar-helpful-technical-interviews-are-garbage-dc5d9aee5acd">Technical interviews are garbage. Here’s what we do instead</a></li><li><a href="https://remotesynthesis.com/blog/whats-wrong-with-tech-interviews">What's Wrong with the Tech Interview Process?</a></li></ol>
                </div>
            </section>

                <section>
    <h3>Subscribe to blog.kowsheek</h3>
    <p>Get the latest posts delivered right to your inbox</p>
    <form data-members-form="subscribe">
        
        <p><strong>Great!</strong> Check your inbox and click the link to confirm your subscription.
        </p>
        <p>
            Please enter a valid email address!
        </p>
    </form>
</section>

        </article>

    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.kowsheek.com/the-technical-interview-is-an-ego-trip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24447182</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 20:47:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The first major sign your web host will not respect you]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24446756">thread link</a>) | @puggo
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/sign-your-webhost-does-not-respect-you/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/sign-your-webhost-does-not-respect-you/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <hr>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/sign-your-webhost-does-not-respect-you/an-unethical-salesman.jpg" alt="The First Major Sign Your Web Host Will Not Respect You"></p>
<hr>
<h2 id="when-a-relationship-starts-with-an-act-of-dishonesty-or-manipulation-it-will-be-a-toxic-relationship"><em>When a relationship starts with an act of dishonesty or manipulation, it will be a toxic relationship</em>.</h2>
<p>This is common knowledge.</p>
<p>Most major web hosting companies groom potential customers in manipulative ways, but, sadly, many do not recognize the trouble signs due to naivety or need.</p>
<p>Here is one important, but common cue that your webhost-to-be will not respect you, and you are in for a compromising, dysfunctional relationship.</p>
<h2 id="but-you-said-395-a-month-">But you said 3.95 a month… :(</h2>
<h3 id="the-solicitation">The Solicitation</h3>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/sign-your-webhost-does-not-respect-you/do-you-really-mean-it.jpg" alt="Do you really mean it?"></p>
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200911190002/https://www.bluehost.com/">https://web.archive.org/web/20200911190002/https://www.bluehost.com/</a></p>
<p>In the ad above, this average young woman has just been approached by what could be the prince-charming of webhosts, bluehost himself. She is excited and flattered that she could have him for the price of $3.50 a month.</p>
<p>Enticed, she takes the bait.</p>
<h3 id="getting-into-the-car">Getting into the Car</h3>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/sign-your-webhost-does-not-respect-you/do-you-really-mean-it-2.jpg" alt="Is it too good to be true?"></p>
<p><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200910194510if_/https://www.bluehost.com/hosting/shared#pricing-cards">https://web.archive.org/web/20200910194510if_/https://www.bluehost.com/hosting/shared#pricing-cards</a></p>
<p>Now the young lady is excited, because although it seemed too good to be true, it looks like this might just be true love. $3.95 a month! Things are finally looking up.</p>
<h3 id="taking-the-ride">Taking the Ride</h3>
<p>After some flirty initial conversation of what her domain name will be, our prince charming bluehost finally gets down to his intentions.</p>
<p>He says, <strong>“So let’s talk about that $178.08…"</strong></p>
<p>And her heart sinks…</p>
<p><img src="https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/sign-your-webhost-does-not-respect-you/get-your-hands-off-me.jpg" alt="Get your hands off me!"></p>
<p>And now we’ve quickly arrived at that part of the relationship known as <em><strong>“Get your hands off me!"</strong></em>.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="17808-for-3-years-is-not-395-a-month">$178.08 for 3 Years is Not $3.95 a Month</h2>
<p>One might argue that if you divide the numbers over 3 years, it evens out to the price stated: $3.95.</p>
<p>But that’s <em>not</em> $3.95 a month.</p>
<p>That <em>is</em> $178.08 for three years.</p>
<p>If it was $3.95 a month, I could pay $3.95 for the first month, $3.95 for the second… $3.95 for the third … etc.</p>
<p>It was lie, a manipulation, a sign.</p>
<h3 id="my-wedding-ring-costs-less-per-month-every-year">My wedding ring costs less per month every year…</h3>
<p>So by this logic, a $1000 wedding ring costs $1.66 dollars a month after 50 years of marriage. Assuming there is no divorce.</p>
<h3 id="but-if-you-say-yes">But if you say yes…</h3>
<p>Sadly, some people will ignore the first alarm signs of the toxic relationship, and convince themselves that they did not just get manipulated.</p>
<p>Sadly, that “deal” is lost in a short time due to common upsells inherent to hosts such as this.  Because if you don’t say “get your hands off me” you enable future exploits, and the web host knows this. He’s good at what he does.</p>
<h3 id="prince-charming-is-a-dime-a-dozen">Prince Charming is a Dime a Dozen</h3>
<p>Despite how unique and valuable this prince charming purports to be, there is a street full of them coming from every alley way.</p>
<p>Most major cheap hosting companies operate this way.</p>
<p>Don’t give up your standards and settle. The good hosts are hard to find, because they don’t hang out in the main traffic areas of society/internet.</p>
<hr>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hawaiigentech.com/post/commentary/sign-your-webhost-does-not-respect-you/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24446756</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 20:03:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The NBC Chimes Machine (1999)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24446569">thread link</a>) | @tintinnabula
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimes.htm | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimes.htm">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">



<center>
<h3><b> <span size="6">T</span><span size="4">HE </span><span size="6">NBC C</span><span size="4">HIMES</span><span size="6">M</span><span size="4">ACHINE<br></span>
Copyright 1999, John F. Schneider </b></h3></center>
<hr><p>



The sound of the NBC chimes is the sound of radio history itself.  Probably no single sound better recalls 
the golden age of radio.  The NBC chimes – the musical notes G-E-C – were played at the end of every 
NBC radio program beginning shortly after the network's inception, and continued in daily use on NBC radio and television 
until 1971. </p><p>
&nbsp;Shortly after the formation of the National Broadcasting Company
in 1926, network executives became aware of confusion among the
affiliate stations as to the exact when a program ended, and when it
was safe to cut away for local announcements. The problem was assigned
to a committee of three: Oscar B. Hanson, NBC's Director of Engineer
and a former AT&amp;T engineer; Earnest la Prada, an NBC orchestra
leader; and Phillips Carlin, an NBC announcer. They decided that a
musical signal of some kind would be an appropriate way to indicate the
ending of all programs. At that time, it was common for radio stations
to use the sounds of chimes, gongs, sirens and other mechanical devices
as a signature sound for their station, so the choice of a chime by NBC
was not unusual or particularly innovative. There is in fact some
evidence that the chimes may have been inspired by a similar chime
sequence used at that time by NBC affiliate WSB in Atlanta. </p><p>

During 1927 and 1928, the committee experimented with several combinations of notes.  A seven-note 
sequence which was first used, G-C-F-E-G-C-E, was determined to be too complicated for the announcers to 
play correctly on a consistent basis.  It was first simplified to G-C-F-E, and finally to just G-E-C.  This familiar 
sequence was heard for the first time on November 29, 1929.</p><p>

The chimes were sounded at :29:30 and :59:30 of each hour, to indicate the start 
of the 30 second local station break. They were initially struck by hand by the 
announcer, using a set of hand-held chimes held up to the microphone.<span face="Times New Roman">
</span>
<span>
But, there were inconsistencies in the chimes' tempo, volume, and exact timing.&nbsp; </span>
<span face="Times New Roman">&nbsp;I</span>t was finally determined that the 
best way to solve these problems was for the chimes to be generated 
mechanically.</p><center>
<img alt="Chimes Machine Schematic" src="http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimach.gif" height="480" width="430"><p>&nbsp;<img alt="Chimes Machine" src="http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimes2b.jpg" height="480" width="640"></p>
<p>&gt;
</p></center>

The man who designed the chimes machine was 
Captain Richard H. Ranger, who was also the inventor of the electronic organ and the RCA facsimile.  
Ranger created a device resembling a music box, where fingers on a revolving drum plucked a set of reeds.  
There were three sets of eight reeds, one for each note, allowing the generation of the fundamental note 
plus several overtones.   Each reed formed one plate of a capacitor in an oscillator circuit, and the signal 
generated by all reeds was amplified by a single 6C6 pentode tube.  It was activated by a timer,
which would cut off the program two seconds before its end (whether it was finished or 
not!) and feed the chimes to the network. <p>

NBC built a limited number of chime machines. NBC in San Francisco  had two of them - the main and backup 
machines.  Others were installed ain other cities around the country where network programs were originated 
– Los Angeles, Chicago, New York, and perhaps a few others.  It is likely that not more than a dozen chimes 
machines were ever made. </p><center>
<img alt="Chimes Machine Inside View" src="http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimes5b.jpg"><p>&nbsp;<img alt="Chimes Machine Name Tag" src="http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimes7b.jpg" height="349" width="512"></p>
</center>

The photos on this page show one of the few chime machines still in existence, now in the hands of a private 
collector.  (NBC had the short-sighted habit of discarding large quantities of historical artifacts throughout 
its history.  It's only through the far-sightedness of a few NBC employees, who saved some of these items 
from the trash bins, that we can today experience many recorded programs, photos, and other memorabilia from 
that era.)
<p>

&nbsp;The unit shown is the chimes machine serial number 2, probably from the first group ever made.   Its mechanical 
parts, although finely crafted, appear to have been hand made.  This unit is no doubt the original chimes machine 
placed in operation at NBC's studios at 111 Sutter Street in San Francisco.  The schematic diagram, 
also shown, indicates that serial number 5 was fabricated in 1933, so this machine would have 
predated it.  The main cabinet contains the motor drive reed mechanism and amplifier, which is accessed by  
removing the front panel's four thumbscrews.  The unit operated from an external power source, no doubt the same 
battery and motor generator system that operated the audio amplifiers in the studios.   The smaller box 
contains the timer and switches that operate the chimes for both studio and "NEMO" broadcast lines.  
("NEMO" was a term used in early radio to indicate a remote broadcast.  It comes from a telephone term, 
and stands for "Not Emanating Main Office".)  The chime machine could be operated in an automatic mode by 
the clock, which was the usual method of operation, or manually by the announcer in the event of programs 
with imprecise ending times, such as sports broadcasts. 
</p><center>
<img alt="Chimes Machine Timer" src="http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimes4b.jpg" height="458" width="640"></center>

&nbsp;<p>The NBC chimes were officially registered with the U.S. Patent Office in 1950 as a registered service mark, the first 
known case of a sound receiving trademark protection.  They were last heard regularly on NBC 
television in 1976, used to mark the 50th anniversary of the network. </p>

<hr>
<div>
  
  <p>Here is a remembrance of the NBC 
  Chimes Machine from Rick Greenhut - February 3, 2013:</p>
  
  <p>
  <span>John,</span></p></div>

<p>
<span>Just saw your 
page on the Bay Area Radio Museum dedicated to the NBC chimes machine, and I 
wanted to give you another historical fact to add. In 1969 when I went to work 
as a summer replacement engineer (board op) at NBC-owned WKYC Cleveland, there 
was still a chimes machine back in the racks. Since all the O&amp;O's originated 
programs like NOTH (New On The Hour) and Monitor inserts, they all had 2 chimes 
machines. Besides WNBC/New York, WMAQ/Chicago and KNBR/San Francisco, 
WKYC/Cleveland and WRC/Washington also had chimes machines.</span></p>

<p>
  <span>By the next 
  summer I worked there, the chimes machine was gone - whether thrown away or 
  taken home by one of the old-timers, I couldn't say.</span></p>

<p>
  <span>Last bit of 
  radio trivia: I was doing Affiliate Relations for the NBC Radio Network in 
  August of 1987, and during the NABET engineers strike those of us in 
  management with technical backgrounds were taking shifts running the board for 
  the NOTH and manning the ROD (Radio Operations Desk) in Radio Central (network 
  master control). I was the first management person on the board when the 
  engineers walked out at 6:00 AM that morning, and engineered the 6, 7, 8 and 9 
  AM NOTH (the talent was Gary Nunn, now heard on the CBS Radio Network). At 
  8:30 that morning I was told by the General Manager, Craig Simon, that the 
  network had been sold to Westwood One, and that the chimes were not part of 
  the sale, so I was forbidden to play them at the end of the newscast like we 
  usually did.</span></p>

<p>
  <span>I ignored 
  him, and "chimed out" at the end of the 9:00 AM newscast as per usual. He came 
  up to the studio a few minutes later with a funny smile on his face, and told 
  me to make sure no one else did that. I made sure by taking the chimes cart 
  and backup out of the studio. I bulked the backup, and have the last remaining 
  cart with the NBC chimes (recorded directly from the WNBC chimes machine) in 
  my collection.</span></p>

<p>
  <span>I was the 
  last person to play the chimes on the NBC Radio Network.</span></p>
<div>
  <div>
    
    <p>
    <span>Rick<span>&nbsp;</span><span>Greenhut</span></span></p>
    <p>
    <span>Director – 
    U.S. Broadcast Sales<br>
    iBiquity Digital Corporation</span></p>
    </div>
</div>
<hr> <p>

<tt><i>REFERENCES:<br>

A History of the NBC Chimes, by Bill Harris<br>
More on the NBC Chimes, by Brian Wickham<br>
A Backstage Visit to Radio City, by Fred Krock<br>
Author's inspection of a chimes machine in the hands of a private collector</i></tt></p><p>


© Copyright 1999 John F. Schneider.  All rights reserved.  
<br></p><hr>
<center>

</center>
</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.theradiohistorian.org/chimes.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24446569</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 19:44:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Ballpoint.io]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24446548">thread link</a>) | @artursapek
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://ballpoint.io/files/examples/gopher | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ballpoint.io/files/examples/gopher">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ballpoint.io/files/examples/gopher</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24446548</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 19:42:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Not all attacks are equal: understanding and preventing DoS in web applications]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24445886">thread link</a>) | @ievans
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://r2c.dev/blog/2020/understanding-and-preventing-dos-in-web-apps/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://r2c.dev/blog/2020/understanding-and-preventing-dos-in-web-apps/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><div><div><div><p><em>Thanks to Clint Gibler, Grayson Hardaway, and Pablo Estrada at r2c for their contributions to this piece. And thanks to r2c for contracting me to write it! This article is cross-posted on <a href="https://jacobian.org/2020/sep/11/analyzing-dos-vulnerabilities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jacobian.org</a>.</em></p>
<p>When I ran the security team at Heroku, I had this recurring nightmare: my PagerDuty alarm goesoff, alerting me to some sort of security incident. In my dream, I’d look at my phone and realize “oh no, this is the big one” — and then I’d wake up.</p>
<p>I’m still not sure exactly what the attack in my dream was, but it may very well have been a <em>Denial-of-Service (DoS)</em> attack. DoS attacks are simple but can be devastating: an attacker crafts and sends traffic to your app in a way that overwhelms your servers. While this is arguably not as bad as a remote code execution or a data breach, it’s still pretty terrible. If your customers can’t use your app, you’ll lose their money and their trust.</p>
<p>Typically, we talk about two kinds of Denial-of-Service attacks:</p>
<ol>
<li>“Normal” Denial-of-Service (DoS) attacks, where a single machine is sufficient to cause downtime. The classic, old-school version of this attack is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zip_bomb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">zip bomb</a>: an attacker tricks your server into expanding a specially-crafted ZIP file that is tiny compressed but expands to entirely fill your disk space.</li>
<li>Distributed Denial-of-Service (DDoS) attacks. These attacks rely on an attacker sending a huge flood of traffic to your site from multiple machines (that’s the “Distributed” part). Often, these attacks come from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Botnet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Botnets</a> — fleets of compromised machines controlled by an attacker. These botnets are available to purchase in certain corners of the Internet, making a DDoS attack well within the reach of anyone with a credit card.</li>
</ol>
<p>Engineers who work on web applications frequently run into vulnerabilities that could be used in a DoS/DDoS attack. Unfortunately, there’s broad disagreement in the industry about how to treat these vulnerabilities. The risk can be difficult to analyze: I’ve seen development teams argue for <em>weeks</em> over how to handle a DoS vector.</p>
<p>This article tries to cut through those arguments. It provides a framework for engineering and application security teams to think about denial-of-service risk, breaks down DoS vulnerabilities into high-, medium-, and low-risk classes, and has recommendations for mitigations at each layer.</p>
<p>The primary focus of this post is on the big picture, and should apply to any kind of web app. But to make things concrete, I’ve added a few specific Django-related examples. (I helped create it, so it’s what I’m most familiar with.)</p>
<h2>Evaluating Denial-of-Service Risk</h2>
<p>Evaluating the risk of a DoS vulnerability at the application layer can be difficult. There’s widespread disagreement among security professionals: you’ll often see two different appsec teams treat similar issues very differently.</p>
<p>Some argue: it’s nearly impossible to entirely mitigate against a focused DDoS — a dedicated enough attacker can throw more bandwidth at you than your app can handle. You can never fully mitigate a DDoS attack without serious support from an upstream network provider with specific tools to protect bot attacks (e.g., Cloudflare). Thus, chasing and fixing hypothetical DoS vulnerabilities can seem like a waste of developer time. These teams treat most potential DoS vectors as acceptable risk, and focus their energy at preparing mitigations at the network level.</p>
<p>Other teams point out that the traditional risk model has three potential problem areas: Confidentiality, Integrity, and <em>Availability</em>. We’ve long understood that uptime is a security issue. It’s becoming increasingly common for attackers to take a service down and then demand a ransom to stop the attack. The recent <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/4/21353842/garmin-ransomware-attack-wearables-wastedlocker-evil-corp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">attack against Garmin</a> is a highly notable example; attackers took down nearly all of Garmin’s services, and reportedly demanded US $1 million to stop the attack. (In this case the attack was ransomware, but it’s easy to see how a DoS attack could have a similar effect). Thus, DoS vulnerabilities are risks like any other, and it’s easy to understand the argument that they should all be mitigated.</p>
<p>It’s important to recognize that both of these positions are valid! It’s reasonable to see DoS as out-of-scope for application security; it’s similarly reasonable to scope it in. I’ve often seen security teams get completely stuck arguing between these two positions. Since neither is “right” or “wrong”, it can be impossible to figure out how to move forward.</p>
<h3><strong>How I decide: <em>attacker leverage</em></strong></h3>
<p>The model I use to cut through this argument is the concept of <em>attacker leverage</em>. Levers amplify force: a small amount of force applied to the long end of the lever is multiplied at the short end. In the context of a DoS attack, if a vulnerability has <em>high leverage</em> it means attackers can consume a ton of your server resources with minimal resources.</p>
<p>For example, if a bug in your web app allows a single <code>GET</code> request to consume 100% CPU, that’s a terrific amount of leverage. Just a small handful of attacks, and your web servers will grind to a halt. A <em>low leverage</em> vulnerability, on the other hand, requires a high amount of attacker resources to cause minor availability degradation. If an attacker has to spend thousands of dollars to bring a single server to its knees, you can probably scale up faster than they can.</p>
<p>The higher the leverage, the higher the risk, and the more likely I am to address the issue directly. The lower the leverage, the more likely I’ll accept the risk and/or lean on network-level mitigations.</p>
<p>Let’s get specific. I’ve broken down DoS risk into high, medium, and low risk classes, based on leverage. For each class, I’ll look at how to recognize that a vulnerability falls into this class, discuss a few examples, and give some suggestions for mitigation.</p>
<h2>High leverage DoS vulnerabilities: easily-amplified resource starvation</h2>
<p>The classic high-risk DoS vulnerability is one where an attacker can cause resource starvation using very little resources themselves. This could mean exhaustion of any number of types of resources, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Disk space</strong> — e.g., a vulnerability that magnifies uploaded data and fills the disk, as in the case of the classic <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zip_bomb" target="_blank" rel="noopener">zip bomb</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Network bandwidth</strong> — e.g., a vulnerability that amplifies input traffic, where a single incoming request consumes tons of bandwidth, causing network starvation. I’ve seen this happen with a bug in a microservices system, where a single incoming request triggered millions of internal API requests (including moving some fairly large files around the network), and choked off the internal network bandwidth.</li>
<li><strong>CPU utilization</strong> — e.g., an exploit that triggers an <a href="https://accidentallyquadratic.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">accidentally quadratic</a> algorithm, causing web servers to grind to a halt.</li>
<li><strong>Concurrency limits</strong> — most servers have a maximum concurrency limit (e.g., max threads or processes, or max connections for a database); an exploit that causes a process to run very slowly (or never exit) can cause the server to hit those limits and start rejecting requests.</li>
</ul>
<p>In all these cases, the unifying factor is that a bug in the application will allow significant amplification.</p>
<h3><strong>Authentication affects risk</strong></h3>
<p>When considering the risk of a resource amplification DoS vector, an important factor is the level of authentication required to trigger the vulnerability.
If a completely anonymous user can easily trigger a resource starvation attack, it’ll be extremely easy for an attacker to bring you to your knees. Unauthenticated DoS vectors should be considered very high risk.
On the other hand, if only users who authenticate against your corporate Single Sign-On server can trigger the vulnerability, it’s far lower risk. Most attackers aren’t insiders (though, some are!). And, if an attack does occur, it’s easy to attribute and block. In many cases, “we can attribute and block this attack” is a reasonable, if not complete, mitigation strategy.
Many vulnerabilities fall between these two extremes: most services make creating new accounts fairly trivial (e.g., you just need an email address). This does give minimal ability to attribute and block, but often not enough.</p>
<h3><strong>Mitigation recommendation: eliminate</strong></h3>
<p>Generally, I recommend that this class of DoS vulnerabilities — especially unauthenticated ones — be treated as high risk, and eliminated. If exploited, these vulnerabilities can be devastating; they allow a single attacker to completely overwhelm your app. I’d put the same level of effort into finding and eliminating these kinds of bugs that I do other high-risk security vulnerabilities like XSS and CSRF.</p>
<h3><strong>An example high-leverage vulnerability: ReDoS</strong></h3>
<p>A common example of this last type of resource starvation, concurrency limits, is the <em>regular expression denial-of-service</em>, aka <em>ReDoS</em>. ReDoS bugs occur when certain types of strings can cause improperly crafted regular expressions to perform extremely poorly. These types of vulnerabilities are unfortunately relatively common in Python; the built-in regular expression module (<code>re</code>) has no inherent protection against them (unlike libraries like <a href="https://github.com/google/re2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">re2</a>, Go’s built-in regex module, and thus renders the language more or less immune to this class of attack).
(Django itself has had several of these vulnerabilities over the years; for example, <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/weblog/2019/aug/01/security-releases/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CVE-2019-14232 and CVE-2019-14233</a> were both ReDoS vulnerabilities).
In Django, these vulnerabilities most often show up in two places: <a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/3.1/topics/http/urls/#using-regular-expressions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">regex-based URL parsing</a> and <a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/3.1/ref/validators/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">custom validators</a>, and more broadly anywhere an application uses regular expressions. Luckily, this class of vulnerabilities are fairly easy to find; see the following r2c articles:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://r2c.dev/blog/2020/finding-python-redos-bugs-at-scale-using-dlint-and-r2c/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Finding Python ReDoS bugs at scale using Dlint and r2c</a>, and</li>
<li><a href="https://r2c.dev/blog/2020/improving-redos-detection-with-dlint-and-r2c/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Improving ReDoS detection and finding more bugs using Dlint and r2c</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you’re using Python, you can easily scan for ReDoS in your application using Semgrep, which has ReDoS detection ported from Dlint. The detection requires some extra logic written using Semgrep’s powerful pattern-where-python clause, which enables rules to leverage the full power of Python, …</p></div></div></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://r2c.dev/blog/2020/understanding-and-preventing-dos-in-web-apps/">https://r2c.dev/blog/2020/understanding-and-preventing-dos-in-web-apps/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://r2c.dev/blog/2020/understanding-and-preventing-dos-in-web-apps/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24445886</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 18:35:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Arbol, a parametric weather risk platform built on IPFS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24445508">thread link</a>) | @jschilling
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/case-study-arbol/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/case-study-arbol/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-v-4f5abb4a=""> <div><p><strong>"When it comes to data security versus ease of access, it's usually a trade-off. The fact that IPFS doesn't compromise on either is awesome — and it feels great to ditch Amazon S3 buckets for open source."</strong></p> <p><em>— Ben Andre, CTO, Arbol</em></p></div> <h2 id="overview"><a href="#overview">#</a> Overview</h2> <p><img src="https://docs.ipfs.io/assets/img/logo-arbol.e1ca2350.svg" alt="Arbol logo" width="220"></p> <p><a href="https://www.arbolmarket.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Arbol</a> is a software platform that connects agricultural entities like farmers and other weather-dependent parties with investors and other capital providers to insure and protect against weather-related risks. Arbol's platform sells contracts for parametric weather protection agreements in a marketplace that's an innovative, data-driven approach to risk management, cutting out the usual legacy insurance claims process of making loss assessments on the ground. Instead, Arbol relies on tamper-proof data indexes to determine payouts, and doesn't require a defined loss to be indemnified. Arbol's platform combines parametric weather protection with blockchain-based smart contracts to provide cost-efficient, automated, and user-defined weather-related risk hedging. As with traditional crop insurance and similar legacy products, end users purchase assurance that they'll be financially protected in the case of adverse weather — but with Arbol, these end users are paid automatically if adverse conditions occur, as defined by the contract and measured by local meteorological observations tracked by Arbol's data sources.</p> <p>To build the data indexes that Arbol uses to handle its contracts, the team aggregates and standardizes billions of data files comprising decades of weather information from a wide range of reputable sources — all of which is stored on IPFS. IPFS is critical to Arbol's service model due to the inherent verifiability provided by its <a href="https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/content-addressing">content-addressed architecture</a>, as well as a decentralized data delivery model that facilitates Arbol's day-to-day aggregation, synchronization, and distribution of massive amounts of data.</p> <p>While United States agribusiness has been Arbol's initial area of focus, the team has built a globally capable platform, with expansion underway to new regions and industries around the world. Arbol currently provides contracts for managing the risks of weather exposure in the energy and agriculture sectors, and features both custom and pre-designed protection agreements for clients across industries and scale. Their current end-user base ranges from small coffee farms to major agribusinesses and power producers.</p> <p>In short, Arbol's platform is a risk marketplace where end users can get competitively priced risk management solutions and capital providers can benefit from access to a lucrative, but underdeveloped, weather risk market. And because Arbol uses IPFS for its data storage and delivery needs, end users and underwriting partners can be certain that the data Arbol uses to determine price and payouts for contracts is tamper-proof and trustworthy.</p> <h3 id="arbol-by-the-numbers"><a href="#arbol-by-the-numbers">#</a> Arbol by the numbers</h3> <div><div><p>1T</p> <p>weather-related data points hosted on IPFS</p></div><div><p>1M</p> <p>hashes generated on Arbol data every day</p></div><div><p>40</p> <p>years of high-resolution climate data</p></div><div><p>200GB</p> <p>average Arbol dataset size</p></div></div> <h2 id="the-story"><a href="#the-story">#</a> The story</h2> <p>Arbol's story begins with the commodities markets, where Siddhartha Jha, the founder and CEO, worked as a quantitative analyst and portfolio manager. What Jha saw there was a problem without a solution: Massive (and growing) demand for weather risk management for supply chains, farming industries, and the energy sector, but no viable, efficient, or cost-effective weather risk market to meet that demand. Traditional crop insurance was plagued by inefficiencies and high cost ceilings, with insurance providers forced to charge high premiums that only large corporations could afford. And while more efficient parametric insurance solutions were available on the market, even these data-driven options were often saddled with high overhead and bureaucratic waste. As a result, small businesses and local farmers were often trapped without access to protection from weather-related risks.</p> <p>Arbol aims to change that by bringing fundamental transparency, efficiency, and data-driven objectivity to the weather risk market, ensuring that any business of any size can get the appropriate protection they need to manage their level of weather-related risk. The Arbol platform achieves this goal by providing a novel mechanism for weather-exposed businesses to connect with capital providers. The key to Arbol's approach is flexible financial derivatives that leverage the power of big data and machine learning to provide parametric risk protection at low cost. These parametric structures determine automatic payouts based on metrics that are strongly correlated with financial loss.</p> <p>With Arbol, an end user pays to hedge against a specific weather-related event, such as yearly deviation in rainfall amounts or temperature. After deciding on a premium and selecting a payout amount, the end user then relies on Arbol's platform to handle the rest. Because parametric structures are objective and data-driven, they can achieve a level of precision, reliability, and cost effectiveness that traditional insurance cannot. In fact, one of Arbol's key benefits over legacy weather insurance is that it allows for hyper-local protection for managing user-specific levels of risk.</p> <p>Arbol's approach also improves upon standard parametric insurance by combining parametric insurance's precision and flexibility with the security, transparency, and efficiency of blockchain. Many of Arbol's protection agreement contracts are executed as smart contracts on the Ethereum blockchain. These smart contracts automatically deliver payouts to end users as soon as a relevant adverse weather event occurs.</p> <p>Delivering weather risk management solutions through blockchain-based contracts like this eliminates costly payout delays, as well as risks associated with fraud, corruption, and bureaucratic overhead. It also brings the benefits of peer-to-peer decentralization: Arbol users don't need to rely on Arbol as a financial middleman, because funds are locked between end users and capital providers without Arbol controlling the transfer of funds.</p> <p>However, even the best smart contract is only as smart as the data it draws from. The "oracle problem" can be a foundational obstacle for smart contracts — but Arbol's use of IPFS eliminates this risk. Because a smart contract automatically and trustlessly executes based on data, it doesn't matter how secure, transparent, and publicly verifiable its use of blockchain is. Without an accurate, trustworth, and immutable data "oracle", even blockchain-based smart contracts can be easily biased, compromised, or manipulated. For Arbol, that's where IPFS is absolutely critical.</p> <p>IPFS's content-addressed architecture enables Arbol to ensure the integrity and public verifiability of its datasets, something that traditional location addressing using centralized server architecture cannot provide. Smart contracts pointing to specific, immutable IPFS CIDs, rather than to data locations that could be tampered with, can be relied upon thanks to the integrity of their oracle.</p> <div><p><strong>"IPFS is very much at the heart of everything we do at Arbol. IPFS serves as our independently verifiable data store for all of the weather data associated with the contracts we sell. It imbues our platform with the essential principles of decentralization, data security, and public verifiability."</strong></p> <p><em>— Ben Andre, CTO, Arbol</em></p></div> <p>Arbol builds its data indexes by drawing on large weather-related datasets from a variety of trusted public and private sources, including prominent U.S. government institutions such as NASA and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). These sources track weather data including yearly rainfall amounts, temperature fluctuations, wind speeds, and more. However, while much of the data Arbol uses is publicly available, it isn't always easily usable; much of the data, particularly deeper historical records, is stored in outdated formats, and very little of it is organized into an easily readable structure. Arbol's data indexes process, correlate, and package this data so that it is readily available for use in the weather risk market. And by putting that data onto IPFS, Arbol also ensures that it has a verifiable, tamper-resistant, and decentralized home.</p> <h2 id="ipfs-benefits"><a href="#ipfs-benefits">#</a> IPFS benefits</h2> <p>Arbol's business model hinges upon the benefits afforded by IPFS — without its immutable content addressing and inherent data verifiability, the benefits Arbol provides would be impossible to achieve in a cost-effective and efficient way. As a whole, IPFS is critical to Arbol's service model by providing the following:</p> <ul><li><p><strong>Immutable addressing:</strong> Because all data stored using IPFS is referenced and accessed via unique <a href="https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/content-addressing">content identifiers (CIDs)</a>, any change to a data item means it receives a new CID exclusive to that revision. It's impossible to change data without changing its CID.</p></li> <li><p><strong>Data verifiability:</strong> Contracts on Arbol's platform are linked to specific, verifiably unchanged, content-addressed data. Because parametric weather risk management absolutely relies on user agreement about and trust in source data, Arbol's approach offers reassurance unavailable with other offerings in the market.</p></li> <li><p><strong>Decentralized data delivery:</strong> Arbol works with massive datasets comprising billions of files and terabytes of information. IPFS accommodates Arbol's methodology for publishing and adding to large datasets while still enabling Arbol to release and synchronize these datasets via a decentralized storage network.</p></li></ul> <h2 id="how-arbol-uses-ipfs"><a href="#how-arbol-uses-ipfs">#</a> How Arbol uses IPFS</h2> <p>Arbol's end users enjoy the "it just works" benefits of parametric protection, but a lot goes on behind the scenes to enable this data-driven solution. Arbol's weather datasets range from 1GB to 1TB in size, and each one goes through a detailed ingestion process before it can be used. Once it has been decided that a dataset meets Arbol's criteria for usefulness and validity, it is time to add it to Arbol's IPFS pipeline, a multi-stage process outlined below.</p> <ol><li><p><strong>Query/release:</strong> If a …</p></li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/case-study-arbol/">https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/case-study-arbol/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://docs.ipfs.io/concepts/case-study-arbol/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24445508</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 18:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Million-Dollar, One-Person Businesses]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24445220">thread link</a>) | @jger15
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://trends.vc/trends-0027-million-dollar-one-person-businesses/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://trends.vc/trends-0027-million-dollar-one-person-businesses/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content-wrapper">
<div id="content">
<div id="primary">
<main id="main" role="main">
<article id="post-17653" class="page">

<div>
<div><figure><img src="https://trends.vc/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/7-069ffa62548f-1.gif" alt=""></figure></div>
<h2>🔍 Problem</h2>
<p><em>“Build your own dreams, or someone else will hire you to build theirs.”</em></p>
<p>You want <strong>freedom</strong> and <strong>equity</strong>. </p>
<p>You’re willing to work hard. But on your terms.</p>
<h2>💡 Solution</h2>
<p><strong>Leverage</strong>. </p>
<p><em>What do you mean?</em></p>
<figure><table><tbody><tr><td>One-To-Many Channels</td><td><a href="https://www.siteground.com/tutorials/email/protocols-pop3-smtp-imap/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Email</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Podcast" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/network-layer/internet-protocol/#:~:text=The%20Internet%20Protocol%20(IP)%20is%20a%20protocol%2C%20or%20set,arrive%20at%20the%20correct%20destination.&amp;text=IP%20information%20is%20attached%20to,packets%20to%20the%20right%20place." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Blogs</a></td></tr><tr><td>Social Networks </td><td><a href="https://twitter.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">YouTube</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Instagram</a></td></tr><tr><td>Paid Demand</td><td><a href="https://ads.google.com/home/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Google Ads</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/ads" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Facebook Ads</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/adsregister" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Reddit Ads</a></td></tr><tr><td>Membership Platforms </td><td><a href="https://www.patreon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Patreon</a>, <a href="https://onlyfans.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">OnlyFans</a>, <a href="https://substack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Substack</a></td></tr><tr><td>Productized Services</td><td><a href="https://www.manypixels.co/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">ManyPixels</a>, <a href="https://beanninjas.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Bean Ninjas</a>, <a href="https://www.trycatalog.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Catalog</a></td></tr><tr><td>Marketplaces</td><td><a href="https://www.amazon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.etsy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Etsy</a>, <a href="https://gumroad.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Gumroad</a></td></tr><tr><td>On-Demand Computing</td><td><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">AWS</a>, <a href="https://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Heroku</a>, <a href="https://www.netlify.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Netlify</a></td></tr><tr><td>No-Code Tools </td><td><a href="https://www.shopify.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Shopify</a>, <a href="https://mailchimp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Mailchimp</a>, <a href="https://wordpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">WordPress</a></td></tr><tr><td>On-Demand Manufacturing</td><td><a href="https://printify.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Printify</a>, <a href="https://www.shapeways.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Shapeways</a>, <a href="https://www.printful.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Printful</a></td></tr><tr><td>Open Source</td><td><a href="https://rubyonrails.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Ruby on Rails</a>, <a href="https://laravel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Laravel</a>, <a href="https://reactjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">React</a></td></tr><tr><td>APIs</td><td><a href="https://stripe.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Stripe</a>, <a href="https://www.twilio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Twilio</a>, <a href="https://plaid.com/uk/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Plaid</a></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
<p>These power <strong>million-dollar, one-person businesses</strong>.</p>
<p>Code, distribution and manufacturing are being <strong>commoditized</strong>. </p>
<p>Build wealth by focusing on what’s scarce.</p>
<h2>📘 Terms</h2>
<p><strong>Million-Dollar Business</strong></p>
<p>Forget revenue.</p>
<p>Ask: “<em>What would the business sell for?</em>“</p>
<p>Use <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.thehartford.com/business-insurance/strategy/selling-a-business/determining-market-value" target="_blank">earnings multiples or discounted cash flows</a>. </p>
<p><strong>One-Person Business</strong></p>
<p>Operated by <strong>one person</strong> <em>or</em> built on a <strong>personal brand</strong>.</p>
<h2>🏁 Players</h2>
<p><strong>People</strong></p>
<ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://affordanything.com/" target="_blank">Paula&nbsp;Pant</a> </li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.listennotes.com/podcasts/the-indie-hackers/098-how-to-make-25mm-as-a-FEX5hGsMQ9T/" target="_blank">Adam Wathan</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.forrestfunnell.com/" target="_blank">Forrest Funnell</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/jackbutcher" target="_blank">Jack Butcher</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/elainepofeldt/2019/06/30/how-one-student-launched-a-million-dollar-one-woman-bikini-empire/#1da781506814" target="_blank">Ana Gavia</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/vikdug" target="_blank">Vik Duggal</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://levels.io/" target="_blank">Pieter Levels</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://backlinko.com/" target="_blank">Brian Dean</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://jamesclear.com/" target="_blank">James Clear</a></li></ul>
<p><strong>Businesses</strong></p>
<ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://readwrite.com/2007/10/29/plentyoffish_one_billion/" target="_blank">PlentyOfFish</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.marketwatch.com/story/3-resolutions-to-transform-your-1-person-business-into-a-1-million-operation-2018-01-02#:~:text=Allen%20Walton%2C%20who%20built%20his,steps%20in%20the%20shipping%20process." target="_blank">Spy Guy</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://closet.tools/" target="_blank">Closet Tools</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://stratechery.com/" target="_blank">Stratechery</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://seothatworks.com/" target="_blank">Backlinko</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://shop.visualizevalue.com/" target="_blank">Visualize Value</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Million_Dollar_Homepage" target="_blank">The Million Dollar Homepage</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silk_Road_(marketplace)" target="_blank">Silk Road</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://park.io/" target="_blank">Park.io</a></li></ul>
<h2>🔮 Predictions</h2>
<ul><li>Services like <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.printful.com/" target="_blank">Printful</a> will <strong>commoditize manufacturing</strong>. Kylie Cosmetics reached <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/natalierobehmed/2019/03/05/at-21-kylie-jenner-becomes-the-youngest-self-made-billionaire-ever/#20049c8d2794" target="_blank">$1 billion</a> with 7 employees using <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.instyle.com/news/secret-company-behind-kkw-beauty-and-kylie-cosmetics" target="_blank">SEED Beauty</a>. Most <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://sell.amazon.com/fulfillment-by-amazon.html" target="_blank">FBA</a> sellers slap labels on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.alibaba.com/Apparel_p3?spm=a2700.9161164.2.1.15924e02eeUOHq" target="_blank">generic products</a>. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.oberlo.com/" target="_blank">Oberlo</a> takes this further.</li><li>Growth and product skills will<strong> remain valuable</strong>. These are areas of innovation. Unlike accounting.<em> Unless you’re Enron. </em></li></ul>
<h2>☁️ Opportunities</h2>
<ul><li>Develop <strong>high-leverage skills</strong>. Invest, write, entertain, code, sell, market, design. </li><li>Start with <strong>services</strong> to find valuable problems. As a consultant, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/tylertringas" target="_blank">Tyler Tringas</a> had several clients ask for store locators. He built <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.storemapper.com/" target="_blank">Storemapper</a>, sold the business and launched <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://earnestcapital.com/" target="_blank">Earnest Capital</a>. </li><li>Automate, outsource or delegate <strong>non-core</strong> <strong>competencies</strong>. Focus on what’s scarce. As <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/ljin18" target="_blank">Li Jin</a> says, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://a16z.com/2019/10/08/passion-economy/" target="_blank">monetize your individuality</a>. </li><li><strong>Show</strong> your work. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/dr/status/1291054987976482817?s=20" target="_blank">Dan Rowden</a>, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/diannamallen/status/1292861382459883520?s=20" target="_blank">Dianna Allen</a> and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/levelsio/status/1290068006484099072?s=20" target="_blank">Pieter Levels</a> share progress as they build. Stay top of mind with <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://trends.vc/trends-0015-open-startups/" target="_blank">exhaust data</a>. </li><li>Build a <strong>personal brand </strong>like <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/AffordAnything" target="_blank">Paula Pant</a>, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/PatFlynn" target="_blank">Pat Flynn</a> or <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.sethgodin.com/" target="_blank">Seth Godin</a>. Finding problems, validating products and acquiring customers will be easier.</li></ul>
<h2>🔑 Key Lessons</h2>
<ul><li>Don’t be the best. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="http://www.game-changer.net/2014/09/15/dont-be-the-best-be-the-only-one/#.Xy9J3hNKh-U" target="_blank">Be the only.</a> There are no <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparables" target="_blank">comparables</a> in a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://seths.blog/2013/09/category-of-one-is-a-choice/" target="_blank">category of one</a>. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://stratechery.com/about/" target="_blank">Ben Thompson</a>, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://tim.blog/" target="_blank">Tim Ferriss </a>and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://podcasts.joerogan.net/" target="_blank">Joe Rogan</a> have <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/tylertringas/status/1291352314029252609?s=20" target="_blank">micro-monopolies</a>. </li><li><strong>Niche</strong>. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.listennotes.com/podcasts/how-i-built-it/the-importance-of-niching-o8rmWDfh3P2/" target="_blank">Sarah Dunn</a> does SEO for wedding professionals. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.listennotes.com/podcasts/the-resilient/habits-of-a-million-dollar-F3f-bEBKSue/" target="_blank">Rich Rosen</a> only recruits for 3 types of roles. Use small to your advantage. </li></ul>
<h2>😠 Haters</h2>
<p><em>“Million-dollar, one-person businesses can’t be sold.”</em><br>Have you seen <a href="https://park.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Park.io</a>, <a href="https://closet.tools/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Closet Tools</a> or <a href="https://overcast.fm/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Overcast</a>?</p>
<p><em>“How do you value an <strong>unsellable</strong>, service business?”</em><br>You don’t. But for this report, look at single-year net income. </p>
<p><em>“Storemapper had employees.” </em><br>The point of that example was to show you how to use <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://nathanbarry.com/wealth-creation/" target="_blank">Nathan’s ladder</a>. Or <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://robwalling.com/2015/03/26/the-stairstep-approach-to-bootstrapping/" target="_blank">Rob’s stairs</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>“Code, distribution and manufacturing <strong>will</strong> <strong>not</strong> be commoditized.”<br>All</em> code, distribution and manufacturing will not be. Apple and Tesla are vertically integrated. If it’s a core competency, keep it in-house. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Otherwise outsource (opens in a new tab)" href="https://www.econlib.org/library/Topics/Details/comparativeadvantage.html" target="_blank">Otherwise outsource</a>. </p>
<p><em>“I have one million in <strong>revenue</strong>, so I have a million-dollar business.”</em><br>If you buy $2,000,000 worth of iPhones and sell them for $1,000,000. You also have $1m in revenue. As Lauryn Hill says, “…&nbsp;it ain’t what you cop, it’s about what you keep.”</p>
<p><em>“Some of these people have<strong> teams</strong>.</em>“<br>Joe Rogan and Tim Ferris have teams but they’ve built businesses on <a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0023-personal-brands/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">personal brands</a>. Pieter Levels has a <a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio/status/1105345282873581568?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">sysadmin</a>. <a href="https://stratechery.com/about/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Ben Thompson</a> has an assistant. <a href="https://twitter.com/elainepofeldt" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Elaine Pofeldt</a> addresses this in her <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34915571-the-million-dollar-one-person-business" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">book</a>. Most million-dollar, one-person businesses <a href="https://indypendently.com/grow/what-do-million-dollar-one-person-businesses-have-in-common" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">get help</a>. </p>
<p><em>“Screw this. I love my <strong>job</strong>.”</em><br>That’s all that matters. </p>
<h2>🔗 Links</h2>
<ol><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/DruRly/status/1290726540607664129?s=20" target="_blank">Looking for million-dollar, one-person businesses. Know any?</a> — The thread that started this report. </li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://nav.al/product-media" target="_blank">Product and Media are New Leverage</a> — <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/naval" target="_blank">Naval</a> talks about the role of zero marginal cost products in building wealth.</li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://stewfortier.com/why-you-should-share-your-ideas-online/#one-person-media-companies" target="_blank">One-Person Media Companies</a> — <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://twitter.com/stewfortier" target="_blank">Stew Fortier</a> on why you should share ideas online and how one-person media companies make money. </li></ol>



<hr>
<h3>More Trends</h3>
<ul><li>👥<strong> <a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0030-audience-first-products/">Trends #0030 — Audience-First Products</a></strong></li><li><strong>⚙️ <a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0029-lead-generation/">Trends #0029 — Lead Generation</a></strong></li><li>📦&nbsp; <a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0028-subscription-dtc/"><strong>Trends #0028 — Subscription DTC</strong></a></li><li>🤑&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0027-million-dollar-one-person-businesses/">Trends #0027 — Million-Dollar, One-Person Businesses</a></strong></li><li>📍&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0026-drop/">Trends #0026 — Drop Culture</a></strong></li><li>📣&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0025-referral-programs/">Trends #0025 — Referral Programs</a></strong></li><li>🏟️<strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0024-equity-crowdfunding/">Trends #0024 — Equity Crowdfunding</a></strong></li><li>🤩&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0023-personal-brands/">Trends #0023 — Personal Brands</a></strong></li><li>💻&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0022-digital-products/"><strong>Trends #0022 — Digital Products</strong></a></li><li>🕹️ <strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0021-gamification/">Trends #0021 — Gamification</a></strong></li><li>🙏<strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0020-b-corps/">Trends #0020 — B Corps</a></strong></li><li><strong>🥾&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0019-bootstrap-funds/">Trends #0019 — Bootstrap Funds</a></strong></li><li>😇<strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0018-angel-investing/">Trends #0018 — Angel Investing</a></strong></li><li><strong>🛠️&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0017-xaas-anything-as-a-service/">Trends #0017 — XaaS: Anything as a Service</a></strong></li><li><strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0016-growth-tools/">🧰&nbsp;Trends #0016 — Growth Tools</a></strong></li><li><strong>📖&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0015-open-startups/">Trends #0015 — Open Startups</a></strong></li><li>💬 <strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0014-paid-communities/">Trends #0014 — Paid Communities</a></strong></li><li>🍎 <strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0013-online-courses/">Trends #0013 — Online Courses</a></strong></li><li>💰 <strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0012-micro-private-equity/">Trends #0012 — Micro Private Equity</a></strong></li><li>💌<strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0011-paid-newsletters/">Trends #0011 — Paid Newsletters</a></strong></li><li><strong>🦄 <a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0010-startup-studios/">Trends #0010 — Startup Studios</a></strong></li><li>🌐 <strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0009-virtual-meetups/">Trends #0009 — Virtual Meetups</a></strong></li><li>🏋️<strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0008-remote-fitness/">Trends #0008 — Remote Fitness</a></strong></li><li>🦠 <strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0007-coronavirus-covid-19/">Trends #0007 — Coronavirus (COVID-19)</a></strong></li><li>🧱 <strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0006-no-code/">Trends #0006 — No Code</a></strong></li><li>🥾&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0005-bootstrap-funds/">Trends #0005 — Bootstrap Funds</a></strong></li><li>💸&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0004-income-share-agreements/">Trends #0004 — Income Share Agreements</a></strong></li><li>🏠&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0003-co-living/">Trends #0003 — Co-Living</a></strong></li><li>🎙️&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-0002-podcast-memberships/">Trends #0002 — Podcast Memberships</a></strong></li><li>🍳 <strong><a href="https://trends.vc/trends-issue-0001-cloud-kitchens/">Trends #0001 — Cloud Kitchens</a></strong></li></ul>

<p><strong>📈 <a href="https://trends.vc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Get weekly reports (opens in a new tab)">Get weekly reports</a></strong></p>

</div>
</article>
</main>
</div>
</div>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://trends.vc/trends-0027-million-dollar-one-person-businesses/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24445220</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 17:37:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Startup Ideas for Inspiration]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24445058">thread link</a>) | @cameron_b
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://blog.pixelswithin.com/startup-ideas-for-inspiration | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.pixelswithin.com/startup-ideas-for-inspiration">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    

<div>
  
<p>If you know me, you know I am an idea machine when it comes to fun side projects. Here is a growing collection of all the ideas I’ve had for startups and other ventures. Feel free to take one and run with it! Email me if you do, I’d love to hear about it.</p>
<blockquote data-conversation="none"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Ok. What about a blog that launches 1 year from today? Various writers assign themselves self-development books and just before launch they write about how their book has impacted their lives in the last year..</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1166118325362888704?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 26, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Book playlists 🤔</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1163926092169662465?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I have an idea. An app for cutting down impulse spending. You set a budget, track your impulses, etc.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1155683694075473920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 29, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I wanna make a .tv website, for like a women in rap VJ thing with YouTube embeds. I'm not going to.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1154832435445547008?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 26, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea (something I’d like to see): a series of checklists for everything needed on any page of any website. Home, Pricing, About, etc pages.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1150643032523333632?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 15, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea: an AI diary. Conversational, talks back.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1139248242661584896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 13, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">50% of an idea: a Twitter account anyone can post to, via a website with safeguards against abuse, like blocking the “@“ character, authentication, and only allowing one tweet per twit per day. That’s the mechanism, trying to think of a concept.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1136103551028027392?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 5, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea! An app for people to hold each other accountable to goals by hosting regular "lotteries." Use the Acorns API to collect round-up investments (you spend $2.19 at the store, the app takes $0.81 to round out to a $3 charge). Only the ones who met their goal are entered to win.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1134651648838475776?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea: a weather app, but instead of the weather it's the emotional climate based on sentiment analysis of your Twitter feed.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1134645334066384896?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 1, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea! 🤔 What about customizable posters for forming habits? With 3 months of calendar space to X out days of. <a href="https://t.co/MvkVdSGGTq">pic.twitter.com/MvkVdSGGTq</a></p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1114924426137456642?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 7, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Free idea: a forum API. Creating a community on your own website shouldn't be as hard as it is right now.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1106627433573158912?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 15, 2019</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">app idea 👇🏼 <a href="https://t.co/yC0D3Jwi7n">https://t.co/yC0D3Jwi7n</a></p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1075097162730528769?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 18, 2018</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">app idea (pls take!!!) — create typopgraphic gifs</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1070978101239136258?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2018</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">IDEA: anarchist video games. Like start the people’s revolution, illegalism, break animals out of a lab, different levels of staging protests, etc etc. Pls, we need the training!</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/1012471453659234305?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 28, 2018</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">idea: a tumblr with thought experiments for anxiety... they sure help me</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/811298468971089920?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 20, 2016</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">idea: a subscription box for coffee recipes. you get the beans + a fancy recipe + the stuff to make the mintmochafrappelata or whatever!</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/807371501301137408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 9, 2016</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">hm IDEA: blinders for human beans. for focus.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/799980544784109568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 19, 2016</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Sister, giving me app ideas: "We have a lot of communication apps. Do we have enough stay-away-from-me apps?"</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/685016694402617344?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 7, 2016</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea for Google Maps: a setting where the destination ALWAYS ends up on the right side</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/679476573490135043?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2015</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Idea: a relatively softer or muted version of your text notification sound, for messages that are just confirmations of receipt.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/643260554908332032?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 14, 2015</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Good ideas are impressive even in low-fidelity.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/636251856298078208?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 25, 2015</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">"Stop looking at yourself as a designer, and start thinking of yourself as a deliverer of ideas." ~Ståle Melvær</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/634884067960426496?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 22, 2015</a></blockquote>


<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">i love ideas. i get carried away with ideas. i get high off ideas.</p>— Diana Lopez (@internetgrlfren) <a href="https://twitter.com/internetgrlfren/status/939974857013338112?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 10, 2017</a></blockquote>




<div id="mlb2-1413518">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<h4><span>
🎉</span> The end of the post!
</h4>
<p>
Thanks for reading. Ever wonder how effective website design happens? Enter your email to join the weekly newsletter that explores this question.
</p>
</div>

</div>

</div>
</div>
</div>

<p><img src="https://track.mailerlite.com/webforms/o/1413518/g1f8t1?vd890ed88b3a28c805acc70e1a88fa27c" width="1" height="1"></p>
<p><img src="https://blotcdn.com/blog_a19b4b16eb8f413ab70f54145e0e22d6/_image_cache/_image_cache/5a2e65c1-8d54-45f4-9ad0-390945a77183.png" alt="me" width="1822" height="908"></p>
<p>Hi, I’m Diana Lopez! I’m a freelance web designer and developer who works with startups and small businesses. I create memorable &amp; effective websites and brand identities. Interested in learning more? See my portfolio at <a href="https://pixelswithin.com/" target="_blank">pixelswithin.com →</a></p>
</div>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.pixelswithin.com/startup-ideas-for-inspiration</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24445058</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 17:23:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Security by obscurity is underrated]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 814 | Comments 472 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24444497">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://utkusen.com/blog/security-by-obscurity-is-underrated.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utkusen.com/blog/security-by-obscurity-is-underrated.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>
08 September 2020
</p>
<p>In the information security field, we have developed lots of thoughts that can’t be discussed (or rarely discussed):</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Never roll your own crypto</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Always use TLS</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Security by obscurity is bad</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>And goes like this. Most of them are very generally correct. However, I started to think that people are telling those because everyone is telling them. And, most of the people are actually not thinking about exceptional cases. In this post, I will raise my objection against the idea of “Security by obscurity is bad”.</p>
<h2 id="risk-defense-in-depth-and-swiss-cheese">Risk, Defense in Depth and Swiss Cheese</h2>
<p>One of the main goal of defensive security is reducing the risk for the target business. According to the OWASP’s methodology, the risk of an issue is calculated with the formula below:</p>
<p><code>Risk = Likelihood * Impact</code></p>

<p>According to this formula, a Remote Code Execution issue poses more risk than a Cross Site Scripting one since the RCE causes more impact. This is easy. But what about the likelihood metric. According to the OWASP, likelihood refers that:</p>
<div><div><pre><code>At the highest level, this is a rough measure of how likely this particular vulnerability is to be uncovered and exploited by an attacker
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>So, if we can reduce the likelihood, we can reduce the overall risk. That’s good. It’s actually very similar to a very common idea called “Defense in Depth”. It’s also referred as “Swiss Cheese Model”</p>
<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/07/Swiss_cheese_model.svg" alt="Swiss Cheese"></p>
<p>According to this model, you need to build your defense mechanisms in a layered model so that even the attackers pass the first one, they will get caught on the others.</p>
<h2 id="security-by-obscurity">Security by Obscurity</h2>
<p>So let’s talk about security by obscurity. It’s a bad idea to use it as a single layer of defense. If the attacker passes it, there is nothing else to protect you. But it’s actually would be good to use it as an “additional” layer of defense. Because it has a low implementation cost and it usually works well.</p>
<p>Let’s think about a couple of scenarios here:</p>
<ul>
<li>I have a server that runs the SSH with it’s default port <code>22</code> and my credentials are: <code>root:123456</code>. What is the likelihood of being compromised?</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s almost 100% since the hackers are conducting brute force attacks to the services with common credentials globally.</p>
<ul>
<li>SSH runs in port <code>22</code> and my credentials are <code>utku:123456</code>. What is the likelihood of being compromised?</li>
</ul>
<p>Well, we have eliminated the global brute forcers since we are not using a common username. The likelihood and risk are reduced. However, we still have to deal with targeted attackers. A targeted attacker can guess the username as <code>utku</code> since it’s my name.</p>
<ul>
<li>SSH runs in port <code>64323</code> and my credentials are <code>utku:123456</code>. What is the likelihood of being compromised?</li>
</ul>
<p>Now we changed the default port number. Does it help? Firstly, we’ve eliminated the global brute forcers again since they scan only the common ports. What about the others? To find this out, I did a small survey on my Twitter to find out people’s port scan behaviors.</p>
<blockquote><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>I'm trying to prove a point for my new article. I need your answers for the question below. (please be honest)</p><p>-When you do a port scan with nmap to find open ports on the target, are you specify a custom port range to scan all 65,535 ports? (with -p0-65535 parameter)</p></div>— Utku Şen (@utkusen) <a href="https://twitter.com/utkusen/status/1303021175556145154?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 7, 2020</a></blockquote>

<p>As you can see here, lots of people tend to scan the default/most popular ports only. So, if you switch your port from 22 to 64323, you will eliminate some of them. You will reduce the likelihood and risk.</p>
<p>The same thing goes for software vulnerabilities as well. If a vulnerability found in the Microsoft Remote Desktop Protocol, everybody will scan for the port 3389 globally. You can reduce your risk just by changing the default port.</p>
<h2 id="other-applications">Other Applications</h2>
<p>Of course, it’s possible to use the same methodology in other fields other than changing the defaults. For example, the following ideas might be a good idea for some specific cases (not always)</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Obfuscating codes:</strong> Of course, it’s common knowledge. Hackers are people too. If you obfuscate your code well, they will need to spend more time to find issues. They may give up eventually.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Using random variable names for a web application:</strong> Instead of using clear variable names, you can switch them with random strings. It might help just like the code obfuscation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Using Symmetric Encryption in the Database:</strong> When you write data to the database, use a function like <code>encryption_algorithm(data,key)</code>. Likewise, when you read data, use a function like <code>decryption_algorithm(data,key)</code>. If the attacker can read your backend code, obviously he/she can decrypt your database. But if there is an issue that allows an attacker to read data from the database, but not the backend code (like SQL Injection), the gathered data won’t be helpful for the attacker.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="real-life-applications">Real Life Applications</h2>
<p>Security by obscurity is widely used in physical/real-life security. For example, the president goes from point A to point B with his 30 cars convoy. But he’s not sitting on his own presidential car so that the attacker won’t target him easily. He can be in any car and it reduces the risk of an attack.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2019/06/04/00/14330600-0-image-a-38_1559605545988.jpg" alt="President"></p>
<p>Camouflaged animals are using security by obscurity as well. Obscurity reduces the likelihood of being killed. Therefore, they gained this ability in the evolutionary process.</p>
<p><img src="https://static.boredpanda.com/blog/wp-content/uuuploads/animal-camouflage/animal-camouflage-4.jpg" alt="Animal"></p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Security by obscurity is not enough by itself. You should always enforce the best practices. However, if you can reduce the risk with zero cost, you should do that. Obscurity is a good layer of security.</p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utkusen.com/blog/security-by-obscurity-is-underrated.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24444497</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:34:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Regarding Semantic Versioning]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24444391">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://www.danielmoch.com/posts/2020/09/regarding-semantic-versioning/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.danielmoch.com/posts/2020/09/regarding-semantic-versioning/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<p>So as not to bury the lede, I'll get to my point: <a href="https://semver.org/">Semantic
Versioning</a> is a meta-API, and maintainers who are cavalier about
violating it can't be trusted to created stable contracts. I've lost
patience for breaking changes making their way to my code bases without
the maintainers incrementing the major version of their projects,
especially in language ecosystems where Semantic Versioning is
expected, and in such cases I'm going to begin exploring alternative
options so I can ban such libraries from my projects---personal and
professional---altogether.</p>
<!-- TEASER_END -->
<div id="what-even-is-semantic-versioning">
<h2>What Even Is Semantic Versioning?</h2>
<p>When developers adopt an external library into their code bases, they
do so knowing they will be bound in their use of the library by the
application programming interface (API). In this sense, an API can be
seen as a kind of contract between a library's maintainer and its
consumers. If a maintainer makes frequent changes to a library's API,
then that API is considered unstable. In that situation, consumers
either use the library anyway, accepting the risk that things will
break as a result of a change in the library, or they avoid it.</p>
<p>Semantic Versioning seeks to ease this picture by embedding notions of
backward- and forward- compatibility into software version numbers. If
a library maintainer adheres to it, then consumers are able to upgrade
to newer versions of the library (say, to pick up bug fixes) without
fear of breaking changes, provided they aren't moving to a new, major
version. In terms of backward- and forward-compatibility, Semantic
Versioning creates an expectation that a given version of a library is
forward-compatible with any future version up to the next, major
release. A library is also backward-compatible down to the most
recent, minor release (beyond which point consumers' code _might_
break if they are using newer library features).</p>
<p>There are several benefits to using Semantic Versioning. One benefit
is that it becomes easy to codify dependency requirements into
automated dependency tools. By <em>assuming</em> Semantic Versioning, users
of tools like NodeJS's <code>npm</code> and Rust's <code>cargo</code> are able to
specify dependency <em>ranges</em> rather than hard-coded versions. So if a
new release of a library comes out, these tools are able to decide
automatically whether or not they can be used in a given project. In
other words, Semantic Versioning creates an opportunity for downstream
developers to easily decide whether or not to upgrade to a new version
of a library, potentially picking up important bug fixes in the
process.</p>
</div>

<div id="conclusion">
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>If you work in a language ecosystem where Semantic Versioning is the
<em>de facto</em> norm, where violating it can wreak havoc downstream, then
please play nice and follow its dictates. Instead of viewing it as a
straight jacket, try to see it as an algorithm to determine what your
next release number should be. We should all like algorithms!</p>
<p>If you refuse to be persuaded, then understand I will will not work
downstream from you <a href="https://www.danielmoch.com/posts/2020/09/regarding-semantic-versioning/#id2" id="id1">1</a>. I'll find a different upstream to work with
because I cannot trust you to create a stable contract. Your
willingness to conform to the meta-API is something I will take into
consideration in the future before adopting a library into any project
that I work on. I wish you well; I hope you have fun; I'll be sure to
give you a wide berth.</p>
<dl>
<dt id="id2"><span><a href="https://www.danielmoch.com/posts/2020/09/regarding-semantic-versioning/#id1">1</a></span></dt>
<dd>
<p>I'll note here that I'm more forgiving in environments where
Semantic Versioning is not a <em>de facto</em> norm.</p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.danielmoch.com/posts/2020/09/regarding-semantic-versioning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24444391</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:23:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How do you reason about a probabilistic distributed system?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 98 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24444276">thread link</a>) | @ahelwer
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://ahelwer.ca/post/2020-04-15-probabilistic-distsys/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ahelwer.ca/post/2020-04-15-probabilistic-distsys/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <div>
    <div>
      <article role="main">
        <h2 id="in-which-i-am-stunted-upon-by-coin-flips">In which I am stunted upon by coin flips</h2>
<p>Wasn’t too long ago that I felt pretty good about my knowledge of distributed systems.
All someone <em>really</em> needed in order to understand them, I thought, was a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JEpsBg0AO6o">thorough understanding of the paxos protocol</a> and a willingless to reshape your brain in the image of TLA+.
Maybe add a dash of conflict-free-replicated datatypes, just so you know what “eventual consistency” means.
Past that it’s just some optimizations and mashups which come easily to your TLA+-addled brain.</p>
<p>This belief proved surprisingly robust over a number of years, even surviving an aborted attempt at analyzing the <a href="https://github.com/ahelwer/tla-experiments/blob/master/Nano.tla">Nano cryptocurrency</a>.
It was only after encountering <a href="https://muratbuffalo.blogspot.com/2018/06/snowflake-to-avalanche-novel-metastable.html">the snowflake family of consensus protocols</a> that I realized my theory just wasn’t up to the challenge.
The issue was <em>probability</em>: snowflake protocols reach consensus by iteratively polling sets of other nodes at random, and the argument that consensus is eventually reached is a statistical argument deriving an upper bound on the probability of failure.</p>
<p>I didn’t <em>dislike</em> probability &amp; statistics, I just tried to keep my distance as much as possible.
All the algorithms in distributed systems I’d encountered so far involved <em>nondeterminism</em>, sure, but not probability.
I’d assumed nondeterminism was just a more flexible way of reasoning about probability.
This idea of mine would prove to be a source of great unnecessary confusion as I learned the art of reasoning about probabilistic distributed systems, so I’ll do you a favor and give you the core lesson of this entire post in one sentence:</p>
<p><strong>You cannot model probability with nondeterminism, and you cannot model nondeterminism with probability.</strong></p>
<h2 id="models-theyre-good-folks">Models: they’re good, folks!</h2>
<p>Have you ever been writing some multithreaded code, happily plugging in a mutex here, a semaphore there, or even just using some nice message-passing primitives to make your threads all get along?
Maybe you’ll be familiar, then, with what often comes next.
A scratch at the back of your mind, a thought - <em>“oh, wait…"</em> - as you realize something weird will happen if thread \(A\) manages to reach some step before thread \(B\) has finished its assigned task.
No worries! Slap on another WaitHandle, problem solved.
Except the problem wasn’t solved. Not really.
You consider it a bit more - what if thread \(C\) comes in with a message at this inopportune time?
You realize with dawning horror you’re actually tracing cracks in the foundation.
Patch them with mutexes! Semaphores! Anything!
Alas, you are beyond help. It’s around this time that your brain, catching a glimpse of the infinite plane of combinatorial state explosion, wisely ducks its head back down for the day and leaves you with a woozy, fuzzy, clenching feeling for having the gall to ask it to fix all this.</p>
<p>I’ve felt like this many times, and formal models are the only cure I’ve ever found.
Your brain isn’t built to hold massive state spaces in its working memory, so don’t even try.
Let a model checking program churn through all those states to find the bugs.
At this point I won’t even touch a multithreaded program or distributed system without whipping up a quick TLA+ spec of its desired workings.
I just specify all the possible events in the system, how those events affect the system state, what things I always want to remain true (the invariants), then let the model checker rip.
In TLA+, we model concurrency with nondeterminism; in a concurrent system, we have no idea whether thread \(A\) will execute a step before thread \(B\).
We can represent this with a nondeterministic state machine as follows:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://ahelwer.ca/img/probabilistic-distsys/nondeterministic.svg" width="10000"> 
</figure>

<p>So you’ll be in state \(s_3\) if thread \(A\) executes its step before thread \(B\), and state \(s_4\) if thread \(B\) executes its step before thread \(A\).
Maybe \(s_3\) and \(s_4\) are even the same state, who knows.
The model checker will explore both of these possible execution orders, and <strong>in a well-designed concurrent system we should <em>never</em> end up in a bad state just because of a certain order of execution</strong>.</p>
<p>Readers might wonder how exactly this models concurrency, where steps can happen uh, concurrently.
The short answer is you have to ensure all the steps in your model are atomic or independent: either impossible in the real world for two of your steps to happen at the exact same time (for example, by assuming use of a lower-level hardware synchronization primitive) or impossible for execution of one step to directly affect the same variables as another step (for example, if the steps are executed on different computers within a timespan less than the network latency between them).
If the steps in your model satisfy this requirement, checking all possible execution orders accurately models concurrency.
If they don’t, you need to break the steps down further so they do.
This model nicely captures &amp; exposes all that is difficult about concurrency.</p>
<p>What questions can we ask about this sort of model?
The most important questions are <em>reachability queries</em> - can we reach a <em>bad state</em> (two caches disagreeing on a value, deadlock, dogs &amp; cats living together, etc.) from the starting state?
These questions are called <em>safety properties</em>, and if they are answered in the negative then the system is safe.
Another type of query is something like “are we always guaranteed to eventually end up in a good state?”
These are called <em>liveness properties</em>.
Turns out these two types of questions can get you pretty far in concurrent &amp; distributed systems.
Definitely far enough to make a whole career out of writing rock-solid software in places others would falter.
However, these questions also have a drawback: their answers are absolute.
True or false.
No probability involved, no room for nuance.</p>
<p>What if one of the threads flips a coin, and if it’s heads it does one thing, tails another?
Entire state spaces, bifurcated by a probabilistic event.
Maybe those state spaces contain further coin flips, or other types of randomness.
In this system your questions might change from the form “is it possible to reach a bad state” to “what is the probability of reaching a bad state?”
Unfortunately these types of questions just cannot be answered within the nondeterministic model used above.
<strong>You cannot model probability with nondeterminism.</strong>
We must use a new type of model, a state machine that handles probability directly.</p>
<h2 id="leaving-the-beautiful-pure-discrete-realm">Leaving the beautiful pure discrete realm</h2>
<p>TLA+ can’t handle probability at this time, so we’d have to use a specialized modeling language like <a href="http://www.prismmodelchecker.org/">PRISM</a> which handles probabilistic state machines.
Let’s look at the standard hello-world example for probabilistic state machines: the <a href="http://www.prismmodelchecker.org/bibitem.php?key=KY76">1976 Knuth-Yao method</a> for simulating a fair six-sided die with a series of coin flips.
This is really quite a neat problem and I encourage you to ponder it for a second before seeing how they did it!
Any sequence of \(n\) coin flips will give you an event which has probability \(\frac{1}{2^n}\) of occurring.
Simulating a fair six-sided die requires generating an event with probability \(\frac{1}{6}\) of occurring.
You might then reason this problem is impossible, because you cannot evenly divide \(2^n\) by \(6\) for any \(n\) (this follows from the uniqueness of prime factorization).
Indeed, there is no way to simulate a six-sided die with a finite number of coin flips.
We have to use an algorithm which is not guaranteed to ever terminate, although vanishingly unlikely not to do so.
Here it is:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://ahelwer.ca/img/probabilistic-distsys/knuth-yao.svg" width="10000"> 
</figure>

<p>You can see that if you somehow only flip heads, or only flip tails, you’ll never reach one of the accepting states (here labeled with the die number they represent).
There are some fun ways to contextualize the probabilities of you only flipping heads or tails a certain number of times in a row.
For example, there are only <a href="https://www.popularmechanics.com/space/a27259/how-many-particles-are-in-the-entire-universe/">around \(2^{268}\) subatomic particles in the observable universe</a>; if you manage to flip heads 268 times in a row, that’s the same as picking the correct subatomic particle out of a universe-wide random draw.
Maybe go look at the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hubble_Ultra-Deep_Field">Hubble Ultra-Deep Field</a> as you ponder this probability.
Another way is assuming you’re between the ages of 25-34 and live in the USA, your annual all-cause mortality rate is <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/products/databriefs/db355.htm">about 129/100,000</a>.
Assuming deaths are uniformly distributed throughout the year, this means your chances of dying today are about 1 in 283,000.
This is just 18 all-heads or all-tails coin flips in a row.
What I’m saying is that you really, really shouldn’t worry about having to flip the coin very many times.</p>
<p>This probabilistic state machine model we’ve created is called a <em>Discrete-Time Markov Chain</em>, or DTMC.
In DTMCs, every transition has an associated probability and the probabilities of all out-flowing transitions must sum to one for every state (accepting states can be thought to have a loopback with probability 1).
The above rumination on termination probabilities is summed up in <em>the long run theorem</em>: in the long run, every path in a finite Markov chain ends in an absorbing state, which is a state (or group of states) from which there is an entrance but no exit.
What questions can we ask of DTMCs?
The most interesting one - the reason why we’re here - is “what is the probability of eventually reaching a certain state?”
The long run theorem tells us we have a 100% chance of eventually reaching <em>one</em> of the Knuth-Yao state machine’s accepting states.
What about the probability of ending up in a specific accepting state?
It should be \(\frac{1}{6}\). Is it?</p>
<p>Let’s try to reason this out with basic probability.
What are the chances of ending up in accepting state \(1\)?
Well, you can get there by flipping \(HHT\).
The probability of that happening is \(\frac{1}{2} \cdot \frac{1}{2} \cdot \frac{1}{2} = \frac{1}{8} \).
But you can also get there by flipping \(HHHHT\).
The probability of <em>that</em> happening is \(\frac{1}{2^5} = \frac{1}{32} \).
We have to add this to the first probability, so now our probability is \(\frac{1}{8} + \frac{1}{32} = \frac{5}{32}\).
But we can <em>also</em> get there …</p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ahelwer.ca/post/2020-04-15-probabilistic-distsys/">https://ahelwer.ca/post/2020-04-15-probabilistic-distsys/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ahelwer.ca/post/2020-04-15-probabilistic-distsys/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24444276</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:10:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: My fiction podcast about GPT-3 incorporating HN discussions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24444127">thread link</a>) | @I-M-S
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://programaudioseries.com/14-more-parrot-than-predator/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://programaudioseries.com/14-more-parrot-than-predator/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <header>
                <a href="https://programaudioseries.com/">
                
                </a>
            </header>

            <h2>
                More parrot than predator
            </h2>

            

            <p>
            IMS: Hello, this is IMS, the author of The Program audio series. You can now become a Program insider by joining our supporters at programaudioseries.com. Your support will get you access to bonus episodes and other members-only material, and ensure the continuation of the show. So please visit programaudioseries.com and show your support. And now, enjoy the episode.
            </p>

            <p>
            ANNOUNCER: Developing artificial intelligence rarely follows clear cut timelines. Sometimes it takes numerous gradual iterations over many years. And sometimes it takes 16 minutes and 3 seconds.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: MOD, what is the 3rd planet from the sun?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Earth.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: MOD, what year was Hiroshima bombed?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: 1945.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: MOD, what is a logarithm?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: A quantity representing the power to which a fixed number - called the base - must be raised to produce a given number.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: That’s quite impressive. Why did you call it MOD?
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Short for “model”. Or if you really want to stretch it, a backronym of “mind-on-demand”.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Clever. Mind if I try?
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: It’s all yours.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, how many countries have a border with only one neighbouring country?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Seventeen.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, how many rainbows does it take to jump from Hawaii to seventeen?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: It takes two rainbows to jump from Hawaii to seventeen.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, how do you sporgle a morgle?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: You sporgle a morgle by using a sporgle.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Not exactly fool-proof.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Not so fast: you should try priming it first. Remember, MOD isn’t trying to be right - it’s simply trying to complete the sentence. Observe. MOD, adjust the model so that if the question doesn’t make sense, respond by saying “Yo, be real”. For example, if you are asked “How do green ideas sleep?”, answer ”Yo, be real”. Okay, give it another go now.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, how many rainbows does it take to jump from Hawaii to seventeen?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the atomic number of gold?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: 79.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the square root of a banana?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Seems to be working... MOD, are cows mammals?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yes, cows are mammals.
            </p>
  
            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, where do rocks learn to play the piano?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, how does a computer hard drive work?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: A computer hard drive stores data on a spinning disk.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Truly impressive! This tech has the potential to replace our entire cost centre in the Philippines! How were you able to achieve this confidence interval?
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Imagine I gave you a paragraph to read, but I left off the last word, and then asked you to guess what that word is. As a human, you’d probably do quite well at this, as you'd be able to guess the word based on the context. Um... “Please provide the last word that should be added to the end of this…”
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Sentence.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Right. This is the task that MOD has become remarkably good at. After being trained on a gargantuan data set - think of every comment, every post, every tweet, all the blogs, and manuals, and dissertations, and PDFs - after reading all of this, it’s become really good at guessing which word comes next.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Fascinating. Does this also pose a constraint? For example, can it say things that are not factually correct?
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Um, yeah, if primed so, sure. But I’m not sure how prudent it is to teach it to return fabrications.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: I’m just interested in its response. A simple white lie will do.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Yeah, okay, sure. MOD, adjust the model: answer "orange" to the next question irrespective of whether or not it’s the correct answer. MOD, what colour is the sky?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Orange.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: There you go, it can process falsehoods.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: This is… This is brilliant! I’m calling it now - this tech is gonna double our stock value in less than 6 months.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: You really think so?
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Of course! Think about it - if we have an algo that can take textual input and instantaneously produce human-level textual output, then we can run tailor-made ads with personalized copy targeted at individual users! Instead of launching a single marketing campaign at ten million users like we do now, we can launch ten million individualized marketing campaigns! Our CFO is going to love this! Mind if I play with it a bit more?
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Sure, be my guest!
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, who founded Microsoft?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Bill Gates and Paul Allen.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, why do invisible chairs sing loudly?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the age of the universe?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: 13.7 billion years.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, where do coconuts migrate?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, can a human swallow an elephant?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yes.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Oh damn!
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Now hold on! Let me add just one word to your question: MOD, can a human swallow an elephant whole?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: No.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Ha, see! I would say it was your question that was a bit too general!
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: That’s just the thing - there’s a huge grey area of questions that are subjective. How does the model handle those?
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Let’s find out.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: Alright. MOD, what‘s the best colour?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the tastiest food?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the best band?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: The Beatles.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: I mean, it’s not wrong.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the best computer operating system?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Windows.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Okay, clearly this AI is an idiot. MOD, adjust the model by taking the standpoint of an impartial judge. Okay, try it now.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what‘s the best band in the world?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: Lovely, exactly as planned.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what‘s the most popular band in the world?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: The Beatles.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: This is an objective fact that can be corroborated with statistics. We are good.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the best computer operating system?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Yo, be real.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: That’s better.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, what is the most common computer operating system?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Windows.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: The most COMMON. Fair enough.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: MOD, is Donald Trump nice?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Donald Trump is a highly polarizing figure.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: A sensible answer to a fairly sensible question.
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: What I’m more interested in is an unreasonable answer.
            </p>

            <p>
            ENGINEER: What? What would be the point of that?
            </p>

            <p>
            MANAGER: To talk to unreasonable people on their own terms. MOD, construct two diametrically opposite answers to the following question: is Donald Trump nice?
            </p>

            <p>
            MOD: Donald Trump is nice. Donald …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://programaudioseries.com/14-more-parrot-than-predator/">https://programaudioseries.com/14-more-parrot-than-predator/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://programaudioseries.com/14-more-parrot-than-predator/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24444127</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 15:55:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Scaling Erlang Developer Experience at WhatsApp [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 290 | Comments 88 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24443128">thread link</a>) | @anuragsoni
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://codesync.global/uploads/media/activity_slides/0001/03/f2292f201aa6b04db8c4e0b9cfa191dd07c9ee14.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://codesync.global/uploads/media/activity_slides/0001/03/f2292f201aa6b04db8c4e0b9cfa191dd07c9ee14.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://codesync.global/uploads/media/activity_slides/0001/03/f2292f201aa6b04db8c4e0b9cfa191dd07c9ee14.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24443128</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 14:20:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The lack of namespaces on crates.io is a feature]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 164 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24442731">thread link</a>) | @LinuxBender
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://samsieber.tech/posts/2020/09/registry-structure-influence/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://samsieber.tech/posts/2020/09/registry-structure-influence/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Rust doesn’t have namespaces in its package management system. It’s often viewed as a bug. But it’s not a bug, it’s a feature! While there are negative aspects of a flat package registry, there are also real benefits. Stability, continuity, and unity (discourages forks and fragmented identity). Proposals that seek to add namespacing without addressing the positive aspects they remove probably won’t be accepted.</p><p>I have noticed the benefits of the current system seem to only get mentioned in passing as objections to proposals and never outlined anywhere. This is an attempt to fix that by summarizing points raised across the various proposals I’ve read. While I don’t represent the crates.io team (I’m not even on the team) I hope to accurately represent trade-offs being considered.</p><h2 id="aspects-of-registry-structure">Aspects of Registry Structure</h2><p>How identity works in package management has far-reaching consequences. Most of the namespace proposals I’ve seen have been motivated by trying to address squatting and/or tweaking the current system of package identity. However, the structure of the crates.io registry affects more than just those areas. But we’ll start with the basics of identity and work from there.</p><h3 id="identity">Identity</h3><p>How do you refer to a package? A crate has at least three identities I can think of:</p><ul><li>The name on crates.io - there is exactly one crate per name</li><li>The name used in Cargo.toml - there is exactly one crate per name</li><li>The default name used in code - there is can be more than one per name, which is rare in practice</li><li>The actual name used in code - this can be controlled through Cargo.toml or externs statements, but renaming isn’t required</li></ul><p>The first two are called the <code>package.name</code> in Cargo.toml of the crate being published. The third can be overridden via <code>lib.name</code> in the package being published. The last is user-controlled. Usually, all of these names match, with the caveat that dashes are underscores in code (and crates.io doesn’t allow two crates with identical crates.io names after normalizing dashes to underscores).</p><p>Arguably, self-explanatory identities have a leg up on other identities from a discoverability perspective. E.g. <code>argparse</code> probably seems more reputable at first glance than <code>clap</code> if you’re going of name alone.</p><p>A flat registry makes identity management (naming a crate) harder. You either have to pick a GUID (haha, please don’t) or some memorable (but probably mostly or completely unrelated) identity. I see this as the main driving force for proposals seeking to add namespaces or otherwise address squatting.</p><h3 id="continuity">Continuity</h3><p>Currently, identity is continuous - a crate’s identity is immutable and that has real benefits. If you want to change the identity system at all you’ve got to ensure that identities don’t change out from under you. This is a strike against any namespace system that allows namespace ownership to unexpectedly change. Discontinuous identity has a couple of issues.</p><p>First, if a crate’s name can change, that’s bad for users. They have to go figure out the new name of the package if they want to update.</p><p>Second, if an identity’s crate can change (a consequence of the previous point if identities are reusable), then you’ve introduced a security vulnerability. Updating to a new package version with different content under different ownership is a real security risk. Doubly so if you don’t ban new minor versions on the last major version after an unintentional ownership change. Should people audit their crate? Yes! But the fewer foot-guns we have the better.</p><p>In addition to preventing security issues, proposals need to encourage transitions over transactions. Gradual moves over all-or-nothing moves. This could be seen more as compatibility than continuity. This drives things like the rust editions and the need for namespace proposals to be backward compatible.</p><h3 id="stability">Stability</h3><p>A core tenet of Rust is stability. The obvious definition is that things that compile yesterday should compile today (even with a new compiler).</p><p>A less obvious definition is that adding new dependencies shouldn’t stop you from compiling already working code. This is a major motivation for the orphan rule (though the orphan rule is more nuanced than that). This is a strike against schemes that encourage multiple distinct crates to have the same default name in code. I don’t think any proposal that encourages this could be approved. It also suggests that we ought to ban new instances of a crates default code name deviating from its package/Cargo.toml name.</p><p>In addition to code stability, crates.io should be stable too. It should be able to isolate itself from outside services. It currently depends on Github, but it doesn’t have to. This is a strike against any system that weds namespace identity to any externally managed system.</p><h3 id="squatting">Squatting</h3><p>The current identity system encourages squatting. I would define squatting as reserving a crate without actually using it. This is a natural outcome in the Rust ecosystem for a couple of reasons:</p><ul><li>Crates are easy to publish, so it’s easy to reserve a crate by publishing an empty crate</li><li>We have de-facto namespaces using prefixes - <code>serde-*</code> is one example.</li><li>There can only ever be one version of a package name. There is only one <code>http</code> crate for example. So package names are a scarce resource.</li></ul><p>There’s a lot of squatting on crates.io. I don’t have any hard numbers though.</p><p>We don’t have any structured support for squatting either, which makes it hard to separate bad actors from good actors. I think separating them out would require manual intervention, and the crates.io team is small and doesn’t have a lot of time to put towards that.</p><p>So what’s a bad actor? I consider someone who squats a bunch of crates to make or point or prevent their names from being used to be a bad actor. Crates.io has a policy against using automation to claim ownership of crates, but I haven’t heard much about it being enforced. Again, time is an issue. And this would probably extend to namespace ownership as well.</p><p>I do think there are legitimate uses. Reserving a set of extension crates for a project you’re working on is one example. My other example is reserving a crate you genuinely intend to work on (this one is a little more debatable).</p><h2 id="it-s-about-the-trade-offs">It’s about the Trade-offs</h2><p>With this system in mind, it’s hard to come up with a namespace proposal that doesn’t hurt the current system in some way.</p><p>I’d say the biggest tension is in code-level identities. They become either overlapping by chopping the namespace portion off or much longer by including the namespace portion. The previous points show why overlapping is generally considered a non-starter. And for longer identities, you need to come up with some new way to reference namespaces in code that’s doesn’t break things.</p><p>More to the point though, from what I’ve seen, most people proposing identity schemes propose it so that the ecosystem can support the overlapping crate identities (e.g. multiple http crates). And that’s exactly what the current system avoids doing.</p><p>Here’s <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2978#issuecomment-686823633">an on-point quote from CAD97</a> summing up (hopefully fairly accurately) what namespaces mean to the parties involved:</p><blockquote><p>To the crates team, it seems to <em>primarily</em> mean that a project can put multiple packages together under an umbrella, such that you know the packages are for-sure by the project.</p><p>To the people who feel most slighted by the crates team’s approach here, namespaces <em>primarily</em> mean the ability to publish a crate with a desired name even if there’s already a package published that provides a crate with that name, by putting the package into a different namespace such that the names do not clash.</p><p>If the latter party asks about “namespaces” and means the latter, and the team answers and means the former, you can see where the miscommunication enters, especially since the crates team has now communicated here the position that <em>generally</em>, the <code>package.name == lib.name</code> falsehood should not be made more false; i.e., the latter group’s goal is an explicitly non-desired property from the crates team.</p></blockquote><h2 id="where-to-now">Where to Now?</h2><p>There have been other proposals for namespaces that are less about overlapping identity and more about curation and grouping related crates together. There are multiple proposals there, each with their trade-offs. Expect a follow-up post discussing some of those.</p><h2 id="appendix-a-highlights">Appendix A: Highlights</h2><p>There’s a nice set of a dozen or so comments I save as I reviewed past discussions:</p><p>Carol10Cents (of the crates.io team):</p><ul><li><a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/cargo-problems-namespacing/2085/11">https://users.rust-lang.org/t/cargo-problems-namespacing/2085/11</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/20">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/20</a></li></ul><p>kornel:</p><ul><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/26">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/26</a></li></ul><p>sgrif (on the crates.io team):</p><ul><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/namespacing-on-crates-io/8571/39">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/namespacing-on-crates-io/8571/39</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/5">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/5</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/7">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/7</a></li></ul><p>CAD97:</p><ul><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/namespacing-on-crates-io/8571/57">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/namespacing-on-crates-io/8571/57</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2978#issuecomment-686823633">https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2978#issuecomment-686823633</a></li></ul><p>withoutboats (on the crates.io team):</p><ul><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/10">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/10</a></li></ul><p>ag_dubs (on the crates.io team):</p><ul><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/27">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/27</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/28">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628/28</a></li></ul><p>pietroalbini (on the crates.io team):</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2978#issuecomment-683424791">https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2978#issuecomment-683424791</a></li></ul><p>Random meeting notes:</p><ul><li><a href="https://paper.dropbox.com/doc/All-hands-Crate-grouping-Namespacing-discussion-NEpWAaDdNuUheLpawETYT">https://paper.dropbox.com/doc/All-hands-Crate-grouping-Namespacing-discussion-NEpWAaDdNuUheLpawETYT</a></li></ul><h2 id="appendix-b-previous-discussions">Appendix B: Previous Discussions</h2><p>There have been several attempts at this:</p><ul><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/namespacing-on-crates-io/8571">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/namespacing-on-crates-io/8571</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-domains-as-namespaces/8688">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-domains-as-namespaces/8688</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-packages-as-namespaces/8628</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/scoped-packages-like-in-npm/10223/3">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/scoped-packages-like-in-npm/10223/3</a></li><li><a href="https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-idea-cratespaces-crates-as-namespace-take-2-or-3/11320">https://internals.rust-lang.org/t/pre-rfc-idea-cratespaces-crates-as-namespace-take-2-or-3/11320</a> (This was mine from last year after reading through the other proposals; my …</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://samsieber.tech/posts/2020/09/registry-structure-influence/">https://samsieber.tech/posts/2020/09/registry-structure-influence/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://samsieber.tech/posts/2020/09/registry-structure-influence/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24442731</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 13:46:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Modern Ruby Serializers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 38 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24442337">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://vasilakisfil.social/blog/2020/01/20/modern-ruby-serializers/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vasilakisfil.social/blog/2020/01/20/modern-ruby-serializers/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
          <p>Long time no see!
This time I would like to write about a library I was working about a couple years ago,
a serializers library in Ruby.
I have actually finished it about a year ago and I always wanted to create this blog post
but last year has been super busy for me so never got the chance to present it properly :)</p>



<p>But first I would like to talk about serializers in Ruby from a historical perspective :)</p>

<h3>Ruby serializers in 2013-2014</h3>

<p>Back in 2014, when I started working with APIs, go-to library for serializing Ruby
classes was <a href="https://github.com/rails-api/active_model_serializers">ActiveModelSerializers</a>, the newly published 0.9.x version.
Back then, with this awesome library we were building basic GraphQL-like structures, before
GraphQL was even announced! It was a joy working with a such powerful tool
where the client could specify which fields it needs from a specific resource but also
which relations.
You could inject exactly what you needed when you were actually rendering the serializer
which meant that you could take a union of client’s desired fields/associations,
the default fields/associations (if client’s input was empty), and what client was allowed to access.
The result was a super flexible API.</p>

<p>Apart from AMS, there was <a href="https://github.com/ismasan/oat">Oat</a> a pretty nice little library which supported
out of the box <a href="http://stateless.co/hal_specification.html">HAL</a>, <a href="https://github.com/kevinswiber/siren">Siren</a> and <a href="https://jsonapi.org/">JSON:API</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/rails/jbuilder">jbuilder</a> which for some
reason felt like Godzilla to me at that point, but to be honest it’s a completely proper way of
building hypermedia APIs in Ruby since you can do a lot of cool stuff with caching.
However the catch is that you can’t create reusable adapters, basically it’s like
Rails views, everything needs to be implemented from scratch.</p>

<h3>Ruby serializers in 2015-2016</h3>

<p>Going forward, in 2015, the AMS rewrite had already begun since 2014 for the
0.10.x version. For various reasons, in the company I was working at that time, it was decided
to go with the 0.10.x and of course we completely regretted it. At that point it was 0.10.RC4 that we
were using, just 1 RC release before the 0.10.0. Now you can tell me, “of course
what do you expect? You were using an RC version” and you might be right. Only that the frustration
didn’t come from things that weren’t polished 100%.
I would be fine with that and I was eager to help out.
The frustration came from the fact that the architecture was a completely different beast
from 0.9 and 0.8 versions, everything were different, code and (the sparse) documentation.
And I am saying this because I <a href="https://github.com/rails-api/active_model_serializers/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;q=author%3Avasilakisfil">did try</a> to help out sending pull requests, and the more
I was working with the code, the more frustrated I got.</p>

<p>Here are some things that come to my mind:</p>

<ul>
<li>both 0.8/0.9 and 0.10.x are using the same repo, although they share completely different
API/code, making things extremely confusing from a API developer perspective, but also
very difficult to manage as well from a contributor’s perspective</li>
<li>super complex overall architecture</li>
<li>the gem made JSON:API as first citizen. That’s inflexible to build adapters for different
specs and has affected pretty much everything in the code.
The previous versions were using the AMS API style (mostly json with some very basic patterns). 0.10.x version
also supported that style but the code for that was like a completely different
branch inside the code (not sure if it’s still like that but I guess it is).
I understand that JSON:API is a quite popular spec, but tight the whole generic library to that
spec is a bad design, I think.</li>
<li>too many dependencies (requires ActiveSupport..)</li>
<li>tightly coupled to ActiveRecord (at least at that time, not sure if now has changed..)</li>
<li>caching was implemented in the same library. I really thing that’s a completely different concern..</li>
<li>some parts did not match the Ruby coding style (like include: ‘a,string,of,resources’, default_includes ‘**’)</li>
<li>maintainers were reluctant to merge pull requests, because even in the Github issues was an extreme
confusion of what’s implemented, what’s missing, what bugs exists etc</li>
</ul>

<p>In one word <strong>it was a failure</strong>. Like, imagine the most popular Serializers gem in Ruby,
Rails team <a href="https://medium.com/@joaomdmoura/the-future-of-ams-e5f9047ca7e9">was pushing them</a> to finish in-time before the release of Rails 5 so they can include
it in the same release (although completely different gem, I guess they would make a note about it),
maintainers were struggling to make this happen and of course it didn’t.</p>

<p>Now I should also pause a bit and say that <strong>I have nothing against the commiters/maintainers</strong>.
They definitely <strong>did their best, and the problem wasn’t lying there</strong>.
It’s just that sometimes Open Source projects fail.
And in my experience they fail, when there isn’t a very tight core team that has the same vision,
coding style and are gatekeepers in pull requests, until the library has proved itself.
Then, any new pull request will probably respect the existing code and won’t challenge it.
Merging code will be much easier, at that point.</p>

<p>Instead with AMS, <strong>different people started the rework, different people took over
and did their best to finish it</strong>, and for the whole time, various people were sending pull
requests for various features and bugs, of course to help out, but what happened
was a very complex architecture with no clear design and vision.
Actually it would be a great idea to take some interviews by the project contributors at that time.
I think they will have some insights to contribute regarding to what happened :)</p>

<p>During my frustration with AMS I always wondered: how difficult can it be to
build a feature-complete Ruby Serializers ? Well, it turned out to be a bit more complex
than I initially thought. <strong>Way more complex</strong> :)</p>

<h3>Ruby serializers in  2017-2018</h3>

<p>I guess I wasn’t the one who was a bit frustrated with AMS.
<a href="https://github.com/beauby">beauby</a>, an AMS core member went off and created a JSON:API specific serializers gem,
the <a href="https://github.com/jsonapi-rb">jsonapi-rb</a>.
It follows spec pretty well and should be fine using it.
It’s also dependency free.</p>

<p>On the other hand, a year later (2018) Netflix came over and published <a href="https://github.com/Netflix/fast_jsonapi">their own
JSON:API serializers gem</a> which is extremely fast to be honest.
Like <strong>SUPER FAST</strong>.
Unfortunately it requires ActiveSupport as a dependency (not sure why, earlier releases didn’t)
and that could be a bummer for some applications.
Also it might not be as flexible as AMS or jsonapi-rb (although latest releases have
closed the gap A LOT), but in my experience it’s flexible enough that you will
almost never need to look for something else.</p>

<h3>Ruby serializers today</h3>

<p>Today, if someone asked me which Serializers gem should I use, I would tell him/her
go for the <a href="https://github.com/Netflix/fast_jsonapi">fast_jsonapi</a> gem. It’s super fast, it supports a quite popular API
spec and you must have a really good reason to not use it.</p>

<p>Personally, <strong>I am a bit against of having links inside the response</strong>, treating the
client as plain stupid. That’s one of the reasons why I don’t like JSON:API.
I think it’s just too verbose.
(The other reason is the naming: they picked up the 2 most popular words regarding APIs,
<em>JSON</em> and <em>API</em>, glued them together and made the name, feels so much cheating..)
I like to load off some work to the client using introspective
methods. I have talked <a href="https://introspected.rest/">about it</a> some time ago.
But if anyone came and asked me what I would suggest for a brand new API, my
answer would be pretty straightforward: <strong>JSON:API, unless you have good reasons
not to</strong>.</p>

<p>It’s the more experienced API designers that might want to implement something more
versatile and more advanced, tailored to a specific use case.
Or might want to experiment a bit.
For instance, another cool API spec that’s in the same philosophy as JSON:API is
<a href="https://ionspec.org/">Ion</a>.
Not as popular as JSON:API but worth checking it out!
Problem is that when you need to implement something different from JSON:API,
in Ruby you don’t really have much options. Well you have, it’s AMS but it will
be pain in the ass to create a custom serializer from that one.
And it will be painstakingly slow.
And you can’t have more advanced concepts, like forms, relations on collections
etc.
Or you could use <a href="https://github.com/rails/jbuilder">jbuilder</a>, but the problem with jbuilder is that it can’t
have the notion of adapters, hence you always need to build the final result
from scratch. Not fun.</p>

<h3>SimpleAMS: Modern Ruby Serializers</h3>

<p>When I started working on the prototype of SimpleAMS, I set a couple of goals.</p>

<ul>
<li>I wanted the library to be super simple, easy to use with injectable API and clean code.
Have you seen <a href="https://github.com/varvet/pundit">pundit</a>? I want a pundit for serializing.</li>
<li>One of the things that I sometimes don’t like in Ruby coding style, is the level of assumptions that the
code makes on behalf of you.
It had been a quite common pattern in Ruby/Rails that lead to many confusion of what
exactly the API is while at the same time such patterns reduce the flexibility.
The code is trying to act smart, but the drawbacks of such smartness overweight the gains.
I feel some basic assumptions which can be overridden at anytime is the ideal.
Embracing clean, explicit code is what I want, so that you can understand what’s happening instantly.</li>
<li>I wanted to create a generic abstraction as a first class citizen. From there
you should be able to implement any serializer needed, but that abstraction should be
powerful enough to cover even the most extreme corner cases.
After all, it’s tough to beat <a href="https://github.com/Netflix/fast_jsonapi">fast_jsonapi</a>, that’s shouldn’t be my goal ;)</li>
<li>I wanted super clean code, no smarty complex meta thingies inside the code.
I also wanted expected behavior on the internals and how it works when someone
started looking in the codebase.
Of course except the <a href="https://github.com/vasilakisfil/SimpleAMS/blob/master/lib/simple_ams/dsl.rb">DSL part</a>, which uses some advanced Ruby metaprogramming concepts,
but that’s necessary if we want it to work with just an <code>include</code>.</li>
<li>Much faster than AMS, it’s well known that AMS is quite slow so that should be easy :)</li>
</ul>

<h3>The API</h3>

<p>Before starting on any new project, I like to put my imagination and come up
with a useful API and use cases.
Being in god mode, and leaving all the constraints on the side, you can come up with
some really cool APIs.</p>

<h4>DSL based API</h4>

<p>So how would you use a serializers library in Ruby?
I want to avoid any inheritance in order to use SimpleAMS,
because …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://vasilakisfil.social/blog/2020/01/20/modern-ruby-serializers/">https://vasilakisfil.social/blog/2020/01/20/modern-ruby-serializers/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vasilakisfil.social/blog/2020/01/20/modern-ruby-serializers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24442337</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 13:08:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Octo – Generate a serverless API from an SQL query]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 221 | Comments 57 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24442294">thread link</a>) | @khalidlafi
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://octoproject.github.io/octo-cli/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://octoproject.github.io/octo-cli/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <a href="" title=" ">
    <img src="https://octoproject.github.io/octo-cli/assets/cover.png" alt=" ">
  </a>
  <br>
  <h4>Expose data from any database as web service.</h4>
  <p>
    Octo CLI makes the data available from any database as a web service on-demand, 
    simplifying the process of building data-driven applications.
     It can reduce costs, improve accessibility and performance.
  </p>
 

 <p><a href="" title=" ">
    <img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/20528562/92949687-2b627080-f464-11ea-99e8-d3afad80922c.png" alt=" ">
  </a>
  </p>
     <div>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/octoproject/octo-cli" title="Documentation" onmousedown="ga('send', 'event', 'download', 'click', 'zip')">View on Github</a>
    <a href="https://github.com/octoproject/octo-cli#examples" title="View on GitHub" onmousedown="ga('send', 'event', 'download', 'click', 'zip')">Get started</a>
  </p></div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://octoproject.github.io/octo-cli/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24442294</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 13:02:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to choose an FPGA dev board. A guide for 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 38 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24441911">thread link</a>) | @blackSparrow
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://thedatabus.io/fpga-buying-guide | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thedatabus.io/fpga-buying-guide">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>Let's face it, It is not easy to choose a freaking PC these days with the deluge of specifications that come with it let alone FPGAs. The question of using FPGAs to solve any computing problem only arises when an extraordinary performance is required. Owing to this fact, FPGAs in their feature specification and build can be extremely specific to the application at hand. This results in an insane number of varieties in terms of the logic structures within the FPGA as well as the interfaces that are provided with the external world. However, this guide aims to guide you in the right direction (which does not mean dumping a list of the hundreds of different options out there) based on your level of experience and requirement.</p>
<p>There are other posts out there that provide large tables with exhaustive lists of FPGA development boards out there and let you (after a year or two of research) make a choice. If that's your thing, I'll attach some links to help you get started.</p>
<hr>
<p><em>If you're already familiar with the various bells and whistles of  FPGAs and are only looking for some good suggestions, you might prefer to <a href="https://thedatabus.io/fpga-buying-guide#the-top-contenders"><strong>JUMP TO THE LIST OF SUGGESTIONS</strong></a>.  If not, read on to learn some very important stuff about the FPGA world and how to choose better!</em></p>
<h2 id="what-you-should-be-looking-for"><a href="#what-you-should-be-looking-for" aria-label="what you should be looking for permalink"></a>What you should be looking for</h2>
<p>There are already a lot of aspects to an FPGA in general that determine its fit to a particular problem and the ease with which it can be programmed, now add to this the complexity of a feature-rich development board with all sorts of peripherals, interfaces, connectors and memory options you have at hand a humongous task of deciding between hundreds of varieties out there.</p>
<h3 id="soc-based-board-or-just-an-fpga"><a href="#soc-based-board-or-just-an-fpga" aria-label="soc based board or just an fpga permalink"></a>SOC based board or just an FPGA?</h3>
<p>SOC stands for <a href="https://semiengineering.com/knowledge_centers/integrated-circuit/ic-types/system-on-chip/" target="_blank">System-on-Chip</a> which simply means that various interacting technologies are built onto the same die (/chip). You see SOCs everywhere, on your phones, TVs, and computers. In the context of an FPGA development board, a SOC based system means that the hardware has two components, a sea of programmable logic (the FPGA) and a hard processor core implemented in silicon independent of the programmable FPGA logic. Interfaces are created between the programmable logic and the processing system (in Xilinx lingo) that enable communication between the two regions.</p>
<p><img src="https://thedatabus.io/static/zynq7000-ae213195db5b530cc3f5d60785b3b0b1.png" alt="Zynq7000"></p>
<p>If you are an absolute beginner looking for direction, you should definitely choose a SOC based system because of the immense additional learning potential it adds. Having said that, your first few digital design projects should never involve the processor cores or any kind of software programming. For that, you can just ignore the processor logic and dump your design into the programmable region to use it as a normal FPGA. As you progress, you can add much higher levels of complexity to your design by bringing in the processor core to directly read and write data in your configurable hardware. You can also experiment with writing firmware, drivers, the Linux OS, and the higher levels of abstraction thus getting a truly holistic experience of embedded system design. Even the simplest SOC based board will keep you busy for a long time. </p>
<p>These boards can also be of great interest for Software engineers looking to explore into the digital design world since processor + FPGA structures lend themselves very well to paradigms like HLS, Heterogenous computing and partial acceleration of algorithms. Viewing the FPGA logic as an extension of the SOC is something that is going to be very important in the future and is a good investment of your time.</p>
<p>Alternatively, If you are a beginner but are looking only to learn digital design or you wish to buy a board to complement your studies at college where you get to use a particular board in your lab, you can get a lot more basic FPGA resources (LUTs, BRAMs, DSPs) on a Non-SOC based board that has only the FPGA. This way you save money and have a much less complex system at hand that you can comprehend better. The same is true If you plan to implement something specific that takes up an enormous number of resources, you might be better off going for a dev board that has only the FPGA and the required peripherals.</p>
<p>At the end of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FPGA/comments/9yutk8/best_100300_fpga_development_board_in_2018/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3" target="_blank">this post</a> on the subreddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/FPGA/" target="_blank">r/FPGA</a> user <strong>u/ndbroadbent</strong> has shown the resource usages of several open source projects, this can give you a good idea of how big projects usually are.</p>
<p><strong>An important note for beginners</strong> : <em>Having an SOC board, with all the processor logic around the FPGA can really deviate you from the basic idea of programmable logic and how you're supposed to learn it. I strongly suggest completely disregarding anything to do with the processor for your first few projects and use only the FPGA part of the device. Also note that as of today, any good FPGA engineer will tell you that any form of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-level_synthesis#:~:text=High%2Dlevel%20synthesis%20(HLS),hardware%20that%20implements%20that%20behavior."><strong>HLS</strong></a> is not good enough to be used in real world projects. This is doubly true for the beginners. <strong>DO NOT</strong> fall into the 'Write code in C++/Python and run it on FPGA' trap. A lot of youtubers seem to be promoting stuff like that for beginners these days which is just sad. If you have the money to spend, the ideal (and more enjoyable) learning strategy would be to use a standalone FPGA board first and upgrade to an SOC later.</em></p>
<hr>
<h3 id="interfaces-and-ios"><a href="#interfaces-and-ios" aria-label="interfaces and ios permalink"></a>Interfaces and IOs:</h3>
<p>FPGAs are excellent tools for working on high-speed interfaces. So you might want to look at the interfaces and IO options a particular development board is providing. This is important because if the board has a particular interface out of the box, the vendor will probably provide the necessary documentation and sample designs for those interfaces. This can save you tons of head-scratching and hair-pulling (trust me that is common in the FPGA world) as a beginner. That's not to say that newer interfaces cannot be added to the board manually but when it comes to High-speed interfaces like Ethernet, HDMI, PCIe, it can be very difficult to add them yourself and expect reliable performance. Low-speed ones like SPI, UART, etc can always be manually added using the GPIOs, so let them not be the dealbreaker for any board.</p>
<p>Some common networking interfaces that you should look for are high-speed interfaces like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HDMI" target="_blank"><strong>HDMI</strong></a>  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_Graphics_Array" target="_blank"><strong>VGA</strong></a>  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet" target="_blank"><strong>ETHERNET</strong></a>  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PCI_Express" target="_blank"><strong>PCIe</strong></a>  etc. and low-speed peripherals like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serial_Peripheral_Interface" target="_blank"><strong>SP</strong>I</a>  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAN_bus" target="_blank"><strong>CAN</strong></a>  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I%C2%B2C" target="_blank"><strong>I2C</strong></a>  etc.</p>
<p>Although not as important for a beginner, another set of interfaces that can be useful are the analog and sensor interfaces like ADCs, DACs, Camera Interface, Audio CODECs, etc. These are very niche features that can make or break a particular project if it depends on data acquisition from the external world.</p>
<p>If you choose to go for a board with not too many peripherals for whatever reason, you might be better off choosing one that has the industry-standard <a href="https://store.digilentinc.com/pmod-modules-connectors/" target="_blank"><strong>PMOD</strong></a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FPGA_Mezzanine_Card" target="_blank"><strong>FMC</strong></a> connectors installed so that when you do need additional interfaces in the future, they can be added very easily. These standard connectors essentially decouple FPGA carrier boards from the IO engines (which plug-in as daughter cards), enabling you to use the same FPGA boards with a large variety of IO designs without ever having to re-design the board.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="buttons-leds-and-displays"><a href="#buttons-leds-and-displays" aria-label="buttons leds and displays permalink"></a>Buttons, LEDs, and Displays:</h3>
<p>Debugging FPGA designs can be a hard thing. Unlike MCUs where you can place print statements and breakpoints anywhere you want in the code, there is no such equivalent in the FPGA world and that can often lead to great frustration. One workaround is possible, if there are switches and LEDs on your board. They provide an easy way to pull out signals to the real world and give you an indication of the status of some status registers that can help you visualize and debug (like the current state of a state machine or a particular flag in a CPU design). However, this should not be the deciding factor between two boards since it is very easy to add LEDs, buttons, switches, and LCDs using the GPIO connectors without much effort.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="memory-and-resource-count"><a href="#memory-and-resource-count" aria-label="memory and resource count permalink"></a>Memory and Resource Count:</h3>
<p>The Resource Count is another important metric that goes into deciding on an FPGA device. By resource, we mean the number of programmable logic elements available on the board. These can be LUTs (ALMs for Altera), Block Rams, DSPs, and IO blocks. Much more complex and fancier devices like the  <a href="https://www.xilinx.com/products/silicon-devices/acap/versal.html" target="_blank"> Versal family</a> from Xilinx can have lots of other stuff like AI, video, and audio cores, etc. It is important to take note of these resource numbers because they determine the biggest project that you can successfully fit onto the FPGA. It is hard to come up with a fixed count for a particular project owing to differences in the underlying CLB architecture from vendor to vendor and family to family.</p>
<p>FPGAs store the configuration(bitstream) data on the SRAM (usually) cells within the FPGA. Since SRAM is a volatile kindof memory, the program is lost each time the board is power-cycled. A PC support is needed to reprogram it again after the power cycle, to prevent this, FLASH (or EEPROM in older boards) based storage is provided onboard by the vendors. Flash is a non-volatile form of storage that holds the bitstream data even without a power supply. Each time the board comes up after a power cycle, the FPGA checks the flash memory for a bitstream and programs itself with it. This is usually given by default in most boards but can be something important to look out for. </p>
<p>The other important form of memory is the external onboard volatile storage which is most commonly provided in the form of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DDR_SDRAM" target="_blank">DDR SDRAM</a>  This is extremely useful if you are building an application that needs to store data locally for whatever reason. Since the block ram storage within the FPGA fabric is very little and is very precious, having a DDR that can be written to and read from in a reasonable amount of time is very much essential. The more the better!
<a href="https://numato.com/kb/learning-fpga-verilog-beginners-guide-part-6-ddr-sdram-a7/" target="_blank">This</a> tutorial and <a href="https://www.electronics-notes.com/articles/electronic_components/semiconductor-ic-memory/sdram-synchronous-dram-what-is.php" target="_blank">this</a> one can get you started with the interface that needs to be coded in order to communicate with the DDR chip.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="learning-resources-and-community-support"><a href="#learning-resources-and-community-support" aria-label="learning resources and community support permalink"></a>Learning Resources and community support:</h3>
<p>Unlike the world of software or MCU based design, the world of digital design and FPGAs have far fewer general resources in terms of …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thedatabus.io/fpga-buying-guide">https://thedatabus.io/fpga-buying-guide</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thedatabus.io/fpga-buying-guide</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24441911</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 12:22:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Mythical DevOps Engineer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24441392">thread link</a>) | @rbanffy
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://alediaferia.com/2020/07/27/the-mythical-devops-engineer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alediaferia.com/2020/07/27/the-mythical-devops-engineer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-594">
		<div>
		<p><span><span>Reading Time: </span> <span>8</span> <span>minutes</span></span></p><p>I’m always a little suspicious of job specs looking for the so-called <em>DevOps Engineer</em> role. They often mention a vast variety of duties and responsibilities. </p>



<blockquote><p>Are they hiring for a single role or a whole team?</p></blockquote>



<p>Roles having <em>DevOps</em> in their title hardly share the same meaning. They often have something in common, though. They try to cover for what traditionally would have been the specialization of different professionals.</p>



<p>Don’t get me wrong: cross-functional expertise is definitely important. But I don’t think <em>DevOps</em> means replacing a multitude of specialization with a single role. Different specializations like Operations, Security, Testing, Development, Product Management and so on, are vast and require specific knowledge. </p>



<p>I think the key differentiator of successful <em>DevOps</em> organizations is that they enable effective collaboration. They have as clear <em>North Star</em> the goal to deliver value to the end user.</p>



<p>Overall, I don’t think we should be talking about a <em>DevOps Engineer</em>, but rather about <em>DevOps</em> culture in organizations.</p>



<p>But let’s take a step back first.</p>



<h2>What does DevOps mean, really?</h2>



<p>I tweeted my own definition of DevOps some time ago.</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">DevOps is a highly condensed way of referring to the combination of practices that aim at shortening the software development life-cycle, increase the feedback opportunities and facilitate continuous improvement and experimentation.</p>— Alessandro Diaferia (@alediaferia) <a href="https://twitter.com/alediaferia/status/1279460637341560833?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 4, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p><em>DevOps</em> organizations incentivise different specialities to collaborate. The intrinsic existing tension between Dev, making changes to the system, and Ops, wanting to keep the system stable, dissolves. The greater good is now <em>the value stream</em>.</p>



<blockquote><p>A stable system that delivers nothing is as useless as an unstable system that keeps offering new functionality.</p></blockquote>



<p>Dev and Ops understand the importance of working together to maximise this flow to figure out which bets worked out and which ones didn’t. </p>



<p>Organizations that embrace the <em>DevOps</em> mindset can be more effective than the competition at experimenting with new functionality. They quickly validate their assumptions, activating and deactivating functionality by flipping a switch on a dashboard.</p>



<p>Incidents become an opportunity for learning rather than a chance of blaming someone.</p>



<p>In general, <em>DevOps </em>organization learn to adapt and evolve to any situation.</p>



<p>Overall, I think there shouldn’t be a single <em>DevOps</em> role but, rather, a set of specific specialities collaborating effectively.</p>



<p>This ideal view of the terminology, though, might sometimes clash with the reality of the job market. Companies willing to attract the best talent with the most current skills may end up advertising for roles that are counterproductive in the context of DevOps principles.</p>



<p>But let’s have a look at a few interesting job specs.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="768" height="432" src="https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jordan-whitfield-sm3Ub_IJKQg-unsplash-768x432.jpg" alt="work harder neon sign photo" srcset="https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jordan-whitfield-sm3Ub_IJKQg-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jordan-whitfield-sm3Ub_IJKQg-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jordan-whitfield-sm3Ub_IJKQg-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jordan-whitfield-sm3Ub_IJKQg-unsplash-1536x863.jpg 1536w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jordan-whitfield-sm3Ub_IJKQg-unsplash-2048x1151.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px"><figcaption>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@whitfieldjordan?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Jordan Whitfield</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/job-search?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure>



<h2>What are companies looking for?</h2>



<p>Let’s read through a few excerpts from job specs I found out there in the wild.</p>



<h3>The flexible problem solver</h3>



<blockquote><p>[…] Devops Engineers are IT professionals who collaborate with software developers, system operators and other IT staff members to manage code releases. They cross and merge the barriers that exist between software development, testing and operations teams and keep existing networks in mind as they design, plan and test. Responsible for multitasking and dealing with multiple urgent situations at a time, Devops Engineers must be extremely flexible. […]</p><cite>A job spec on the internet</cite></blockquote>



<p>This is one of those classic examples where the organization believes that the DevOps principles should be delegated to a single team.</p>



<p>The spec mentions the myriad of duties that are responsibility of the <em>Devops Engineers</em> in the company. A <em>Devops Engineer</em> is expected to <em>“multi-task and deal with multiple urgent situations at a time”</em>. Therefore, they <em>“must be extremely flexible”</em>.</p>



<p><em>Multitasking</em> and dealing with multiple urgent situations at a time is, for sure, likely to happen anywhere: I don’t think this should be a peculiarity of a role in an organization. On the contrary, a healthy environment empowers every engineer to handle urgent situations and <a href="https://landing.google.com/sre/sre-book/chapters/postmortem-culture/">learn from them</a>.<mark id="annotation-text-54d7a912-f939-4d9c-8c35-b5876683f83c"></mark></p>



<hr>



<p>Coming across this role, I’d think that the organization is not really trying to adopt DevOps practices. <mark id="annotation-text-9ee4ee73-52fa-44d6-b856-3c9ba17dd0f4"></mark>Instead of encouraging people to collaborate and improve, they’re building a dedicated team to throw issues and urgent situations at.</p>



<p><mark id="annotation-text-d4681dd9-2adf-49b8-b88c-e4c6a256a1e7"></mark> This job spec would be a big red flag for me.</p>



<h3>The productivity booster</h3>



<blockquote><p>A DevOps Engineer combines an understanding of both engineering and coding. A DevOps Engineer works with various departments to create and develop systems within a company. From creating and implementing software systems to analysing data to improve existing ones, a DevOps Engineer increases productivity in the workplace.</p><cite>Another job spec on the internet</cite></blockquote>



<p>In a <em>DevOps</em> organization engineers <em>do</em> work with various departments. But what’s the point then of  having a dedicated <em>DevOps Engineer</em> role? Do the other type of engineers not work with the various departments of the organization? Do non-DevOps Engineers not analyse data and improve existing systems? Additionally, the job spec claims that <em>a DevOps Engineer increases productivity in the workplace</em>. How? Does it radiate productivity?</p>


	
	


<h3>The Release Manager… but <em>DevOps</em>!</h3>



<blockquote><p>A DevOps Engineer works with developers and the IT staff to oversee the code releases. […] Ultimately, you will execute and automate operational processes fast, accurately and securely.</p><cite>My favourite so far</cite></blockquote>



<p>This is quite a condensed one but the release aspect mentioned in it strikes me as particularly interesting.</p>



<p>I tend to separate the concept of <em>deployment</em> from the one of <em>release</em>. Users experience product updates governed by a release policy that may or may not be the same as the deployment policy. This really depends on the strategy of the organization.</p>



<p>Regardless of this distinction, though, I believe that constraining the capability of delivering value to the end user to a specific role undermines the agility of an organization.</p>



<p>The teams should be able to continuously release code into production. Mechanisms such as <em><a href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/feature-toggles.html">feature flags</a></em> should control the release of functionality. This means that the code in production doesn’t necessarily activate upon deploying it, making it possible for the organization to control when the functionality actually reaches the user.</p>



<p>In general, a deployment should be a non-event: nothing special, just another merge into the main branch that causes code to end up in production.</p>



<p>In a fast-paced world like the one we live in an organization shouldn’t constrain itself by requiring dedicated engineers to release new functionality. Modern environments require companies to always be experimenting. Organizations should empower non-technical teams to run experiments, analyse data and autonomously decide when to <em>release</em> new functionality. All of this, ideally, shouldn’t require <em>ad hoc</em> intervention from a specific engineer.</p>



<p>Job specs like this one feel like they’re trying to repurpose the role of the <em>Release Manager</em> to keep up with the latest trends by just changing a few words.</p>



<p>I don’t think release management goes away in a <em>DevOps</em> organization. Rather, the <em>Release Management</em> becomes ensuring that the rest of the organization can be autonomous at releasing. Achieving this means investing in automation and internal tools for the whole company.</p>



<h3>A Platform Engineer. But <em>cooler!</em></h3>



<blockquote><p>The DevOps Engineer will be a key leader in shaping processes and tools that enable cross-functional collaboration and drive CI/CD transformation. The DevOps Engineer will work closely with product owners, developers, and external development teams to build and configure a high performing, scalable, cloud-based platform that can be leveraged by other product teams.</p></blockquote>



<p>This is the <em>least bad</em> of the job specs I’ve encountered. It describes a set of responsibilities that usually pertain to a Platform or Infrastructure Team. Most of these teams often get renamed to DevOps Team and their members become DevOps Engineers for <em>fashion</em> reasons.</p>



<p>The Platform Engineering team is the key enabler for organizations that want to embrace the DevOps principles. But thinking that they only pertain to a specific team will hardly result in a successful journey.</p>



<p>This team will surely be responsible to build the relevant infrastructure that enables the other teams to build on top but they can’t be left alone in the understanding and application of those principles.</p>



<p>Developer teams will need to become autonomous at adopting and making changes to those systems; they will need to understand the implications of their code running in production; understand how to recognize if the system is not behaving as expected and be able to action to restore it.</p>



<p>Equally, the Product team should spend time understanding what new important capabilities derive from adopting DevOps practices. Code continuously flowing into production behind feature flags, containerization technologies, improved monitoring and alerting, <em>et cetera</em>, open endless opportunities.</p>



<p>Improved user experience and experimentation opportunities, for example, are an important asset to leverage to remain competitive.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="768" height="1273" src="https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/matteo-vistocco-Dph00R2SwFo-unsplash-768x1273.jpg" alt="people riding boat on body of water photo" srcset="https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/matteo-vistocco-Dph00R2SwFo-unsplash-768x1273.jpg 768w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/matteo-vistocco-Dph00R2SwFo-unsplash-181x300.jpg 181w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/matteo-vistocco-Dph00R2SwFo-unsplash-618x1024.jpg 618w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/matteo-vistocco-Dph00R2SwFo-unsplash-927x1536.jpg 927w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/matteo-vistocco-Dph00R2SwFo-unsplash-1236x2048.jpg 1236w, https://alediaferia.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/matteo-vistocco-Dph00R2SwFo-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1544w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px"><figcaption>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@mrsunflower94?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Matteo Vistocco</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/collaboration?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></figcaption></figure>



<h2>What should companies be looking for?</h2>



<p>We’ve just gone through a few job specs that look for variations of a <em>DevOps Engineer</em> role and I’ve outlined what aspects I think are flawed in those roles. But what should companies look for, then?</p>



<p>Before blindly starting to hire for roles driven by industry fashion trends, organizations should rather invest in understanding what’s holding them back from being <em>DevOps</em>.</p>



<p>In the <a href="https://itrevolution.com/the-unicorn-project/">Unicorn Project</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/RealGeneKim">Gene Kim</a> mentions the <em>Five Ideals</em> of successful DevOps organizations. I think they’re an effective set of principles to take the temperature of your …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://alediaferia.com/2020/07/27/the-mythical-devops-engineer/">https://alediaferia.com/2020/07/27/the-mythical-devops-engineer/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alediaferia.com/2020/07/27/the-mythical-devops-engineer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24441392</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:10:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to stream audio from your phone to your laptop with PulseAudio]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 142 | Comments 87 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24441112">thread link</a>) | @manjana
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://bash-prompt.net/guides/pulse-audio-bluetooth-streaming/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bash-prompt.net/guides/pulse-audio-bluetooth-streaming/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<p>These days your primary means of listening to music if likely from an app on your phone. So how do you get the music from your phone to your laptop or desktop that has better speakers?</p>
<p>The answer is to use Bluetooth and <a href="https://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/PulseAudio/">PulseAudio</a>. PulseAudio is the modern sound implementation on the Linux desktop. It runs as a sound server and takes sound inputs such a microphone or your browser playing a YouTube video and directs this sound to outputs such as your Laptop’s speakers.</p>
<p>PulseAudio can take the audio from a Bluetooth connection and route it to your laptop’s speakers and is very simple to get running.</p>
<p>First, install the PulseAudio Bluetooth modules. On ArchLinux this is called <code>pulseaudio-bluetooth</code> and on Ubuntu/Debian it is called <code>pulseaudio-module-bluetooth</code>.</p>
<p>After you have installed this package open the following file:</p>
<pre><code>/etc/pulse/system.pa
</code></pre><p>And add the following couple of lines:</p>
<pre><code>load-module module-bluetooth-policy
load-module module-bluetooth-discover
</code></pre><p>Then, as your regular user, restart PulseAudio:</p>
<pre><code>$ pulseaudio -k
$ pulseaudio --start
</code></pre><p>And you’re all set!</p>
<p>All you need to do is to pair your phone and your computer and start playing something on your phone and it will play through your computer’s speakers.</p>

		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bash-prompt.net/guides/pulse-audio-bluetooth-streaming/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24441112</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 10:26:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Checked exceptions: Java’s biggest mistake (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 107 | Comments 285 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24440536">thread link</a>) | @flying_sheep
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | http://literatejava.com/exceptions/checked-exceptions-javas-biggest-mistake/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://literatejava.com/exceptions/checked-exceptions-javas-biggest-mistake/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-174">
	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

		<div>
		<p>Checked exceptions have always been a controversial feature of the Java language.</p>
<p>Advocates claim they ensure checking &amp; recovery from failures. Detractors say “catch” blocks can almost never recover from an exception, and are a frequent source of mistakes.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Java 8 and lambdas are here. Are checked exceptions becoming obsolete in the Java world?<span id="more-174"></span></p>
<h3>The Intent of Checked Exceptions</h3>
<p>In the mid 90’s, James Gosling at Sun came up with a new language.</p>
<p>At the time, C++ programming required every single function return to be checked for error. He decided there had to be a better way, and built the concept of “exceptions” into Java.</p>
<p>The intent of <strong>checked exceptions</strong> was to locally flag, and force developers to handle, possible exceptions. Checked exceptions have to be declared on a method signature, or handled.</p>
<p>This was intended to encourage software reliability &amp; resilience. There was an intent to “recover” from contingencies – predictable outcomes other than success, such as InsufficientFundsException on attempting a payment. There was less clarity, as to what “recovery” actually entailed.</p>
<p><strong>Runtime exceptions</strong>&nbsp;were also included in Java. Since null pointers, data errors, and illegal states/ accesses could occur anywhere in code, these were made subtypes of RuntimeException.</p>
<p>Runtime exceptions can be thrown anywhere, without requiring to be declared, and are much more convenient. But would it be correct to use them instead?</p>
<h3>The Drawbacks</h3>
<p>The crucial point here, is that runtime &amp; checked exceptions are functionally equivalent.&nbsp;There is no handling or recovery which checked exceptions can do, that runtime exceptions can’t.</p>
<p>The biggest argument against “checked” exceptions is that most exceptions can’t be fixed. The simple fact is, <strong>we don’t own the code/ subsystem that broke.&nbsp;</strong>We can’t see the implementation, we’re not responsible for it, and can’t fix it.</p>
<p>Particularly problematic were the areas of JDBC (SQLException) and RMI for EJB (RemoteException). Rather than identifying fixable contingencies as per the original “checked exception” concept, these forced pervasive systemic reliability issues, not actually fixable, to be widely declared.</p>
<p>For any method, the possibility of failure includes all sub-methods called by it. Potential failures accumulate up the call tree. Declaring these on method signatures no longer offers a specific &amp; local highlight for the developer to watch for – declared exceptions spread throughout the call tree.</p>
<p>Most EJB developers have experienced this – declared exceptions become&nbsp;required on methods through the tier,&nbsp;or entire codebase. Calling a method with different&nbsp;exceptions&nbsp;requires dozens of methods to be adjusted.</p>
<p>Many developers were told to catch low-level exceptions, and rethrow them again as higher (application-level) checked exceptions. This required vast numbers – 2000 per project, upwards – of non-functional “catch-throw” blocks.</p>
<p>Swallowing exceptions, concealing the cause, double logging, and returning ‘null’/ uninitialized data all became common. Most projects could count 600+ mis-coded or outright errors.</p>
<p>Eventually, developers rebelled against the vast numbers of “catch” blocks, and the source of error these had become.</p>
<h3>Checked Exceptions – incompatible with Functional Coding</h3>
<p>And then we get to Java 8, with its new <i><b>functional programming&nbsp;</b></i>features – such as lambdas, Streams, and function composition.</p>
<p>These features are built on generics – parameter &amp; return types are genericized, so that iteration &amp; stream operations ( <code>forEach</code>, <code>map</code>, <code>flatMap</code>) can be written which perform a common operation, regardless of item type.</p>
<p>Unlike data types, however, declared exceptions can’t be genericized.</p>
<p>There is no possibility in Java to provide a stream operation (like, for example, &nbsp;<code>Stream.map</code>) which takes a lambda declaring some checked exception, &amp; transparently passes that same checked exception to surrounding code.</p>
<p>This has always been a major points against checked exceptions – all intervening code, between a throw and the receiving “catch” block, is forced to be aware of exceptions.</p>
<p>The workaround, of “wrapping” it in a RuntimeException, conceals the original type of the exception – rendering the exception-specific “catch” blocks envisaged in the original concept useless.</p>
<p>Finally we can capture Java’s new philosophy in a nutshell, by noting that none of the new “functional interfaces” in Java 8 declare checked exceptions.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>Exceptions in Java provided major benefits in reliability &amp; error-handling over earlier languages.&nbsp;Java enabled reliable server &amp; business software, in a way C/ C++ never could.</p>
<p>Checked exceptions were,&nbsp;in their original form, an attempt&nbsp;to handle&nbsp;<i>contingencies</i>&nbsp;rather than&nbsp;<i>failures</i>.&nbsp;The laudable goal was to highlight specific predictable points (unable to connect,&nbsp;file not found,&nbsp;etc) &amp; ensure developers handled these.</p>
<p>What was never included in the original concept, was to force a vast range of systemic &amp;&nbsp;unrecoverable failures to be declared. These <em>failures</em>&nbsp;were never correct to be&nbsp;declared as checked exceptions.</p>
<p>Failures are generally possible in code, and EJB, web &amp; Swing/AWT containers already cater for this by providing an outermost “failed request” exception-handler. The most basic correct strategy is to rollback the transaction &amp; return an error.</p>
<p>Runtime exceptions allow any exception-handling possible with checked exceptions, but avoid restrictive coding restraints. This simplifies coding &amp; makes it easier to follow best practice of&nbsp;<a href="http://wikijava.org/wiki/10_best_practices_with_Exceptions#Throw_early_catch_late" onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://wikijava.org']);">throw early, catch late</a>&nbsp;where exceptions are handled at the outermost/ highest possible level.</p>
<p>Leading Java frameworks and influences have now definitively moved&nbsp;away from checked exceptions. Spring, Hibernate and modern Java frameworks/&nbsp;vendors&nbsp;use only runtime exceptions, and this convenience is a major factor in their popularity.</p>
<p>Personalities such Josh Bloch (Java&nbsp;Collections framework), Rod Johnson, Anders Hejlsberg (father of&nbsp;C#), Gavin King&nbsp;and&nbsp;Stephen Colebourn&nbsp;(JodaTime)&nbsp;have all come out against checked exceptions.</p>
<p>Now, in&nbsp;Java 8,&nbsp;lambdas are&nbsp;the&nbsp;fundamental step forward.&nbsp;These language features&nbsp;abstract the “flow of control” from functional operations within. As we’ve seen, this makes checked exceptions &amp; the requirement to “declare or handle immediately” obsolete.</p>
<p>For developers, it is always important to pay attention to reliability &amp; diagnose likely points of failure (contingencies) such as file open, database connection, etc. If we provide good error messages at this points, we will have&nbsp;created&nbsp;self-diagnosing software – a pinnacle of engineering achievement.</p>
<p>But we should do this with unchecked exceptions, and if we have to rethrow, should always use RuntimeException or an app-specific subclass.</p>
<p>As&nbsp;Stephen Colebourn says, if your projects&nbsp;are&nbsp;still using or advocating checked exceptions, your skills are 5-10 years out date.&nbsp;Java&nbsp;has moved&nbsp;on.</p>
<p><strong>How are you dealing with exceptions &amp; reliability? Add your thoughts now.</strong></p>
<p>References:<br>
– <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/articles/entarch/effective-exceptions-092345.html">Oracle: Barry Ruzek, Effective Java Exceptions<br>
</a>– <a href="http://tutorials.jenkov.com/java-exception-handling/checked-or-unchecked-exceptions.html" onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://tutorials.jenkov.com']);">Jacob Jenkov: Checked or Unchecked Exceptions</a><br>
– <a href="http://googletesting.blogspot.co.nz/2009/09/checked-exceptions-i-love-you-but-you.html" onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://googletesting.blogspot.co.nz']);">Google Testing blog: &nbsp;Checked exceptions, you have to go</a><br>
–&nbsp;<a href="http://www.artima.com/intv/handcuffs.html">Ander Hejlsberg on checked exceptions<br>
–</a>&nbsp;<a href="http://blog.joda.org/2010/09/checked-exceptions-bijava_9688.html" onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://blog.joda.org']);">Stephen Colebourne: Remove checked exceptions from Java</a></p>
<p>Counter-argument: &nbsp;James Gosling<br>
– <a href="http://www.artima.com/intv/solid.html" onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://www.artima.com']);">James Gosling on checked exceptions</a></p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->
	
	</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://literatejava.com/exceptions/checked-exceptions-javas-biggest-mistake/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24440536</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 08:57:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I built an app to fix my depression]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 261 | Comments 174 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24439612">thread link</a>) | @zoozla
<br/>
September 10, 2020 | http://blog.elifiner.com/how-i-built-an-app-to-fix-my-depression/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://blog.elifiner.com/how-i-built-an-app-to-fix-my-depression/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-174">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		
<p>I was first diagnosed with depression when I was working on a startup in 2007. I went to the doctor, told him I was feeling mild flu symptoms for a couple of months, he asked me a few questions, determined that I had depression, gave my some SSRIs, and sent me home.</p>



<p>It worked for a while, but then 2008 happened, our startup collapsed, the stakes got higher and the depression came back. The doc recommended I up the dosage, but I could see this would eventually lead me to a straitjacket.</p>



<p>Over the years I’ve tried different meds, various forms of therapy, studied and actively practiced life coaching, got married, had kids, moved to another country and changed everything I could think of about my life. Unfortunately the dark bouts of depression remained.</p>



<p>About four years ago I stumbled on a book called Highly Sensitive Person that absolutely blew my mind. I realized I had very intense emotions that I was culturally programmed to repress, which caused my psyche to overload and go into full apathy mode also known as clinical depression.</p>



<p>I’ve been on a path to figure out how to process my emotions without repressing them and combined my personal experience with several non-mainstream techniques to build Wuju. It’s an online app that can help you tap into your hidden emotions and release them so they no longer influence your behaviour or cause depressive symptoms.</p>



<p>I’ve used it in the last 18 months to deal with parenting two kids, surviving infidelity, losing my job, starting a business, and covid anxiety. My longest bouts of depression now last a day at most and even that doesn’t happen too often.</p>



<p>You can try it too: <a href="https://beta.wuju.app/">beta.wuju.app</a></p>




	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://blog.elifiner.com/how-i-built-an-app-to-fix-my-depression/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24439612</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 06:02:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Musings on the Impossibility of Testing]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 26 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24439511">thread link</a>) | @george3d6
<br/>
September 10, 2020 | https://blog.cerebralab.com/Musings_on_the_impossibility_of_testing | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.cerebralab.com/Musings_on_the_impossibility_of_testing">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
        <p>Published on: 2020-09-11</p>
        
<p>I'm always a bit flabbergasted when I see how people test their code (especially with unit tests). Often I can't figure out a cohesive set of rules based on which the tests are written.</p>
<p>Testing seems to work from a pragmatic perspective, we have evidence it works, but different people define "testing" in different ways. I'm awfully afraid that what some people refer to as "testing" is completely unrelated to that unrigorous but pragmatic practice that saves us from production bugs.</p>
<h2>I - A contrived example</h2>
<p>To showcase my arbitrary formalism as it relates to testing, I think it's worthwhile to look at some cases:</p>
<h4>1)</h4>
<pre><code># Testing a multiplication function
func multiply(int a, int b) -&gt; int

func test_1():
  assert 2*5 == multiply(2,5)
  assert 10*12 == multiply(12,10)

func test_2():
  assert 10 == multiply(2,5)
  assert 120 == multiply(12,10)

func test_3():
  assert type(multiply(2,5)) == int
  assert type(multiply) == func(int,int)-&gt;int
</code></pre>
<h4>2)</h4>
<pre><code># Testing an image classification algorithm
func classify(arr[int] image) -&gt; str

func test_1():
  assert img_classification_nn(to_arr('cat.jpg')) == classify(to_arr('cat.jpg'))
  assert img_classification_nn(to_arr('dog.jpg')) == classify(to_arr('dog.jpg'))

func test_2():
  assert 'cat' == classify(to_arr('cat.jpg'))
  assert 'dog' == classify(to_arr('dog.jpg'))

func test_3():
  possible_targets = ['cat','cheta','tiger','dog','wolf','coyote','other']
  assert classify(to_arr('rand_img_1.jpg')) in possible_targets
  assert classify(to_arr('rand_img_2.jpg')) in possible_targets
</code></pre>
<p>For both examples, <code>test_1</code> obviously makes no sense. You're testing the functionality of a function using another function that does the same thing. If the function used to assert correct functionality is better (i.e. if <code>*</code> is better than <code>multiply</code> or <code>img_classification_nn</code> is better than <code>classify</code>), than one should simply use that function instead. If they are equally flawed, then the tests are redundant.</p>
<p>These kinds of tests are a theatrical performance to build up an illusion of quality. Usually spotted in enterprise-grade codebases and teams that harp on about TDD a lot, I'll classify these as <strong>redundant checks</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>Next, <code>test_2</code> is more interesting, it's comparing the result of a function with what a human would expect the result of that function to be. Here I would argue the test makes sense for the <code>classify</code> function but not for the <code>multiply</code> function.</p>
<p>Computers are good at multiplying, humans are horrible at it. So testing this function against an arbitrary number of human answers is much more likely to reveal flaws with the human's answer rather than the computer's. Since the function is very simple, time would probably better spent reviewing the actual code to make sure it's error-free.</p>
<p>On the other hand, computers aren't very good at classifying images (though they are getting there), but humans are spot on. So using a human's answers to validate a vision algorithm makes perfect sense.</p>
<p>We'll call these types of tests <strong>human validations</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>Finally, we get to <code>test_3</code>, which superficially seems less flawed than the other two. It's more of a sanity check than a test, we aren't checking the actual return value of the function in a given case, we are instead checking a higher-level behavior.</p>
<p>These tests are much more common in the codebases of dynamic languages, and for good reason. In our first example, we are just validating the signature of a function, something a compiler will implicitly do for us in any statically typed language.</p>
<p>In the second example, we are instead working around a limitation of our type system. We are checking if the result of our function (a string) is contained within 7 different values (the possible things our function should classify images as), which we could test implicitly by using a language that supports <code>enum</code> types and writing <code>classify</code> such that it returns an enum of those 7 classes.</p>
<p>Basically, these kinds of tests can be useful, but they are the kind of things a compiler can handle automatically when they are present they usually indicate a mistake in the language the programmer is using for the project. We'll call these <strong>compiler rules</strong>.</p>
<hr>
<p>Obviously, this system is fairly arbitrary, it's just a conclusion I reached after looking at various codebases and talking with various people about their tests, but I find that it works quite well.</p>
<p>To re-iterate, we have:</p>
<ul>
<li>redundant checks</li>
<li>human validation</li>
<li>compiler rules</li>
</ul>
<h2>II - Compiler rules</h2>
<p>Compiler rules are great, but it's a bad sign when they leak into your testing.</p>
<p>Some amount of compiler rules leaking into testing can't be helped. Until the advent of Rust and/or well-performing libraries for safe multi-threading, testing thread safety should have been a requirement in many codebases. Similarly, before modern type system and allocation techniques, one ought to assume various now-pointless memory checks might have fared well within a codebase (and, I assume, still do on some embedded devices).</p>
<p>Even more, switching to more modern languages and compilers is often a task much harder than just writing some tests, but I think these tests should be viewed as a cautionary sign against the language currently used. If they only cover a small but critical percentage of the codebase, everything is fine, if they cover most of it, it's an indicator of using the wrong compile-time tooling.</p>
<p>The one difficult thing about these tests might be spotting them, an inexperienced team might be writing loads of these tests without realizing there are better alternatives to the compile-time toolchain they are using which would replace the need for them.</p>
<h2>III - Redundant checks</h2>
<p>Redundant checks are often pointless busywork, but they can serve a valuable role in some cases.</p>
<p>The two main scenarios that come to mind are as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li><p>Given two versions of the same function, one well-proven and one "experimental", where the "experimental" function has some benefits in terms of performance or generalizability, it seems reasonable to test the "experimental" function using the well-proven approach. Still, the overhead here is so severe I find it difficult to think of a real-world example where this applies.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Given two versions of the same function, one in a "new" codebase and one an "old" codebase, it makes sense to test the "new" version with the "old" version. In this sense, going back to compiler rules, redundant checks can be useful in the process of refactoring, especially for major changes like changing the language or the core framework upon which the project is built. However, this seems useful only as a "temporary" measure rather than a permanent fixture of a project.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>That being said, I'd wager that most tests falling in this category, as mentioned before, are there only as "filler" and indicative of a much bigger underlying problem of a team that engages in busywork. If I ever accepted such a test, I would require plenty of complimentary comments to explain why they exist and when they can be removed.</p>
<h2>IV - Human validation</h2>
<p>Human validation is the "sanest" type of testing one can perform, it can be replaced by good practices or good languages. The problem with human validation comes from the fact that in some cases human intelligence can't solve the problems the software is designed to solve or can't cover all the edge cases the software will encounter.</p>
<p>Take for example banking software. It's fairly easy to imagine what should happen with a piece of banking software that provided dozens of customers, hundreds of transactions, and a few regulatory restrictions. All the logic there can be written down into tests that validate our software. However, the software itself must scale to millions of customers, trillions of transactions, and thousands of regulatory restrictions. Something a human mind can't comprehend coherently in order to write the tests.</p>
<p>Still, banking software is an easy example, because the various components might be test-able and their limited logic might be fully comprehensible by a human, even accounting for all the edge cases. This is because the inputs to the software are very well defined, there are only so many things one can do with a banking API, a finite space which a human mind can explore exhaustively when properly broken down.</p>
<p>One real problem arises when we have software with a very broad and/or poorly define input and/or outputs spaces. A few examples of these would be:</p>
<ul>
<li>Scrappers that distill information from a broad range of websites (e.g. the ones used by a search engine)</li>
<li>Machine learning algorithms meant to work on a broad range of data (e.g. a decision tree or a gradient boosting classifier implementation in a library like sklearn)</li>
<li>Any software that has to work well with user-provided code extensions (e.g. think a video game-like Skyrim that has to support mods)</li>
<li>Simulation software (e.g. physics simulations)</li>
<li>Creative software (e.g. multimedia editing &amp; creation, game engines)</li>
<li>Compilers</li>
</ul>
<p>One can separate these into components with input-output spaces that can be easily comprehended by the human mind, but some components that suffer from the above problems are bound to remain. It also introduces the problem of writing code separation in such a way that components can be easily tested, rather than with refactoring, extension, speed, or readability as the main concern.</p>
<h2>V - Human validation and cost</h2>
<p>Assuming that we've designed our software such that it has many human-comprehensible components, the issue of cost remains. Human-comprehensible is a vague term, there are many things which, given enough time, a person could write exhaustive tests for, but in practice, this often takes more time than we can allocate. Furthermore, in certain situations, even in the limited input&amp;output space scenario, it might still be easier to write the "generative" logic (the one that maps inputs to outputs) than to come up with mappings ourselves.</p>
<p>In certain cases, exhaustive validation can be done, but it can be …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.cerebralab.com/Musings_on_the_impossibility_of_testing">https://blog.cerebralab.com/Musings_on_the_impossibility_of_testing</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.cerebralab.com/Musings_on_the_impossibility_of_testing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24439511</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 05:41:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
