<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 20:36:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 20:36:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Functioning iPhone returned to owner after six months at bottom of lake]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26372407">thread link</a>) | @Tiktaalik
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A Vancouver woman who lost her phone in Harrison Lake in September is shocked and surprised that not only has it been recovered from the lake bottom, but that it still works.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939069.1614985130!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/cell-phone.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Clayton Helkenberg puts a cellphone in a net along with other items he and his wife Heather found in a lake-bottom search at Harrison Lake. The cellphone would later power up and Helkenberg tracked down the owner — six months after it was lost in the water.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Clayton Helkenberg)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Fatemeh Ghodsi was skeptical at first when she got a text from someone saying they found her phone nearly six months after she lost it in Harrison Lake.</p>  <p>Ghodsi, who lives in Vancouver, was confused&nbsp;and thought one of her friends might&nbsp;be playing a prank on her. But she was soon convinced and made the trip to Chilliwack to collect the phone, which amazingly still works.</p>  <p>Clayton Helkenberg&nbsp;and his wife Heather found the lost iPhone 11 during a sweep of the lake bottom under the water park at Harrison Lake — part&nbsp;of a hobby that includes the odd treasure find, but mostly just lots of&nbsp;garbage clean up.</p>  <p>Ghodsi dropped the phone in the water in early September, during a ride on the bumper boats — photos recovered from the phone show her still smiling moments before the mishap.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939063.1614985154!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/fatemeh-ghodsi.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Fatemeh Ghodsi gives the peace sign as she and her friend are seen riding bumper boats at Harrison Lake in early September. Moments later, Ghodsi's phone was lost at the bottom of the lake.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Fatemeh Ghodsi)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"I was in a situation where I kind of lost balance and dropped it in the water," she said, adding that the water park staff convinced her it would be impossible to find the phone in the deep water.</p>  <p>"Distressed and in tears, we went back to Vancouver just kind of hopeless," said Ghodsi.</p>    <p>She soon bought a new phone, and came to terms with the lost photos, contacts, and other personal information that hadn't been backed up.</p>  <h2>YouTubing&nbsp;diver</h2>  <p>Helkenberg&nbsp;has been snorkeling, swimming&nbsp;and diving for years, but at the start of 2020 — with extra time on his hands after being laid off — he started putting more effort into searching for lost items in the water, as well as doing trash cleanup missions.</p>  <p>Sometime he goes on his diving missions with friends and his wife.&nbsp;He even started a YouTube channel to document his finds.</p>  <p><span><span><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ifzizYAf-hs" frameborder="no" title="YouTube content" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></span></span></p>  <p>Last year, he found more than a hundred pairs of sunglasses, 26 cellphones and two GoPro cameras. This year, he's already counted 35 pairs of sunglasses, five phones and one GoPro.</p>  <p>His underwater work has even attracted some <a href="https://www.theprogress.com/news/chilliwack-diver-retrieves-items-dropped-in-cultus-lake/" target="_blank">media attention</a>, including a report&nbsp;of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vancouverisawesome.com/bc-news/divers-haul-792-pounds-of-trash-out-of-cultus-lake-3364548" target="_blank">359 kilograms of trash he and friends pulled from Cultus Lake</a> earlier this year.</p>  <p>This week, he was at Harrison Lake — the water is much shallower now than it was in the summer, and according to&nbsp;Helkenberg, it's quite clear. He found a severely damaged&nbsp;flip phone, but Heather Helkenberg&nbsp;noticed Ghodsi's iPhone.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/cell-phone.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/cell-phone.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/cell-phone.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/cell-phone.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/cell-phone.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5939076.1614993376!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/cell-phone.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Heather Helkenberg finds an iPhone 11 in the sediment at the bottom of Harrison Lake. She said it was the first cellphone she has found. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Clayton Helkenberg)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>'It just turned right on'</h2>  <p>Clayton Helkenberg&nbsp;said he usually puts phones in a container of silica to dry them out, but he's had good luck with iPhone 11s.</p>  <p>"I took it home, cleaned the dirt off of it and it just turned right on, so it was pretty amazing," he said.</p>  <p>He pulled out the SIM card, put it in another phone to figure out the phone number and got in touch with Ghodsi.</p>  <p>"I was in complete shock, initially to start with. It was kind of like a zombie phone coming back to me, because I'd totally made peace with it being gone," she said.</p>    <p>Ghodsi said the microphone is broken and the speaker sounds weird, but everything else is in perfect shape; the battery health is still at 96 per&nbsp;cent.</p>  <p>She's thankful for the phone's recovery and inspired that Helkenberg makes the effort to reunite people with lost valuables, asking nothing in return. But the experience has left Ghodsi even more impressed by his trash cleanup work, saying it's a reminder to keep our water clean.</p>  <p>"It gives me so much hope for the good that's out there," she said.</p>  <p>As for the next time she takes a ride on the bumper boats?&nbsp;Ghodsi said she'll either leave her phone and valuables on the shore&nbsp;or keep them securely stowed in a pocket.</p>  <hr>  <p><em>Do you have more to add to this story? Email <a href="mailto:rafferty.baker@cbc.ca?subject=diving%20for%20trash%20and%20valuables">rafferty.baker@cbc.ca</a></em></p>  <p><em>Follow Rafferty Baker on Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/raffertybaker" target="_blank">@raffertybaker</a></em></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26372407</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 01:54:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: PrograMaker – Visual Programming Platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26369893">thread link</a>) | @kenkeiras
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://programaker.com/about | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://programaker.com/about">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://programaker.com/about</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26369893</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 19:38:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tech posers of the Bauhaus]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26366513">thread link</a>) | @amicoleo
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        




<article itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  


  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>The Bauhaus greatest achievement was to make artists interested in the creative use of technology, to design things that are useful and nice to use. And they did that without knowing a lot about tech.</p>

<hr>

<p>Product, experience, interaction, industrial designers, creative technologists. If somehow you are a creative interested in making things that are useful and nice to use, you owe that to the Bauhaus. It’s also because of that school and their influence on art education that we can enjoy things designed by people with an artistic sensibility. Rather than only having things designed by engineers.</p>

<p>At the time, few artists were willing to collaborate with the industry to create mass-manufactured objects. Architect Walter Gropius, founder and director of the school, was especially passionate about social architecture and in general in creating things for the common people. Mass-manufacturing technology could allow that at scale. So some years after the creation of the school, he adjusted the focus in the Bauhaus curriculum. And since 1925, when the Bauhaus moved to Dessau, the school new motto became ‘Art and technology: a new unity’.</p>

<hr>

<p>But despite the ambition of the Bauhaus to teach students how to design for the industry, few of the tutors at the time had experience in industrial production. The school method was still based on a combination of applied arts and academic education, and the students’ practical lessons were given by craftsmen whose experience was in making things by hand and not in designing for production.</p>

<p>For instance, in the metal workshop under Moholy-Nagy, students would handmade prototypes with a style they thought would be easy to reproduce industrially. For instance using spheres, cylinders and other basic shapes. Except that due to their ignorance of industrial processes, those objects were hard to make in a mass-production facility.</p>

<p>But the strongest critique of the Bauhaus lack of technological knowledge was Buckminster Fuller. Fuller was familiar with the work of the Bauhaus due to the Black Mountain College in the US, where he and other former Bauhaus tutors were teaching. According to him, the ‘International Style’ brought to the US by the Bauhaus, simple replaced the previous decorative style with a new simplified one made of basic shapes and colours. A new exterior, but that was leaving unchanged the structural and functional elements of the building.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In short they only looked at problems of modifications of the surface of end-product, which end-products were inherently sub-functions of a technically obsolete world</p>
</blockquote>

<p>(Obviously, Bucky did all the things he was criticising Gropius and the Bauhaus about. But that’s a story I’ll save for some other time).</p>

<hr>

<p>The excitement of the Bauhauslers for new technologies is still present among designers now. And so is that limit in understanding fully a new innovation that can be used in a new product or service. I feel that every time I’m working with machine learning. But what the Bauhaus achieved was to get artists interested in bringing their sensibility in the creative use of technology. And whatever Bucky thinks, that remains.</p>

<p><strong>References</strong></p>

<p>Bauhaus - Madgalena Droste</p>

<p>Theory and Design in the First Machine Age - Reyner Banham</p>


  </div>

  
</article>



      </div>


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26366513</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 10:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tell HN: I am doing online reading sessions on analytic number theory]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 99 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26366464">thread link</a>) | @susam
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://spxy.github.io/bc/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://spxy.github.io/bc/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p>
Welcome to the first edition of our online reading session. This is a
tiny book club. In the first edition, we will be diving into the
beautiful world of <em>number theory</em>.
</p>



<p>
  <small>
  †
  The Matrix room and Freenode channel are bridged together, so if you
  join one of them, you will automatically receive the updates and
  messages from the other one too. If you are not an active Freenode
  user, prefer joining the Matrix room because it is more convenient,
  e.g., you can close your browser or client and your chat session will
  still stay alive. You can connect back the next day and catch up with
  the messages. Doing that with Freenode IRC requires slightly more work
  (setting up IRC bouncers etc.).
  </small>
</p>


<h2 id="reference">Reference Material<a href="#reference"></a></h2>

<p>
The primary reference book for these meetings is going to be:
<em>Introduction to Analytic Number Theory</em> written by Tom M.
Apostol. Admittedly, the book is quite expensive but you may find a
relatively cheap paperback (softcover) copy on some websites. A DRM-free
PDF eBook is available for purchase at <a href="https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9780387901633">springer.com/gp/book/9780387901633</a>.
</p>

<p>
If you are unable to buy the reference book, you can still participate
in this book club activity by downloading freely available notes from
  the University of Illinois: <a href="https://faculty.math.illinois.edu/~hildebr/ant/main.pdf">main.pdf</a>.
</p>

<p>
For solutions to exercise problems, refer to this excellent PDF created
by Greg Hurst: <a href="https://greghurst.files.wordpress.com/2014/02/apostol_intro_to_ant.pdf">apostol_intro_to_ant.pdf</a>.
</p>


<h2 id="schedule">Schedule<a href="#schedule"></a></h2>

<p>
Here is the schedule for the upcoming planned meetings:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>
     04 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Introduction. Kick-starting chapter 1.
    (Pilot)
  </li>
  <li>
    05 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    06 Mar 2021 10:00-10:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    07 Mar 2021 10:00-10:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    08 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    09 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    10 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    More sessions coming up later ...
  </li>
</ul>

<p>
Roughly speaking, the plan is to cover a chapter every one or two weeks.
</p>

<p>
If you have any questions, join our <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">Matrix room</a>
(or the corresponding Freenode channel) and discuss.
</p>

<p>
Also, <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/follow?screen_name=susam">follow me on
Twitter</a> where I will post upcoming reading session details.
</p>

<h2 id="faq">FAQ<a href="#faq"></a></h2>
<ol>
  <li id="faq-who">
    <h3>
      Who are you?
      <a href="#faq-who"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Hi! I am <a href="https://susam.in/">Susam</a>. I am just someone
      who enjoys mathematics, Lisp, and Emacs and wants to spread the
      joy of spending time with these beautiful things. I have been
      working as an information security professional for about 15
      years. Of these 15 years, close to 7 years were spent working with
      probability theory, calculus, and combinatorics, and another 3
      years in implementation of cryptographic utilities.
    </p>
    <p>
      I do a lot of teaching as hobby. This is my way of giving
      something back to the technology community. I have taught Common
      Lisp, Emacs, Python, C, Vim, and various areas of mathematics. In
      each one of my previous workplaces, I have created communities
      around mathematics, algorithms, and/or, cryptography. In the
      online world, I created the <a href="https://webchat.freenode.net/##algorithms">##algorithms</a>
      channel on Freenode IRC (my nick there is <code>spal</code>). What
      started as a tiny hobby club around algorithms 13 years ago is now
      a thriving community with over 200 members. (Disclosure: I don't
      participate in it anymore but a highly talented group of
      moderators helps maintain the channel).
    </p>
    <p>
      These hobbies of teaching and forming local and online communities
      have also led me to write some open source projects. Some are
      mildly popular and some not so popular but have managed to find
      its own niche community of users. For example, <a href="https://github.com/susam/texme">TeXMe</a> and <a href="http://mathb.in/">MathB.in</a> were born out of the need to
      share mathematics problems and solutions within these communities.
      <a href="https://github.com/susam/uncap">Uncap</a> was born when I
      used to teach Vim and I wanted Windows users to have a good
      ergonomic experience. Similarly, <a href="https://github.com/susam/emacs4cl">Emacs4CL</a> was born
      while teaching Common Lisp with Emacs and SLIME.
    </p>
    <p>
      To summarize, I work in information security by profession and I
      am an open source software developer by hobby. I want to use some
      part of my leisure time in hosting book club meetings where we
      pick up good books and work through them together.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-why">
    <h3>
      Why are you doing this?
      <a href="#faq-why"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      During the course of my career and hobbies, I have found
      Mathematics, Lisp, and Emacs to be extraordinarily elegant and
      beautiful and it is my goal to introduce as many people to these
      things as possible.
    </p>
    <p>
      Software development these days focus a lot around stitching
      together many libraries to accomplish complex tasks. I understand
      that this is more economical and productive. This approach has
      certainly made it possible to develop huge and complex
      software-based infrastructure that has changed the way we live.
      However, I think, in this fast-paced software development world,
      the simpler joys of devising or implementing algorithms from
      scratch and appreciating the underlying beauty of mathematics is
      taking a backseat. I intend to introduce more and more people to
      some of these simpler joys, especially, the joy of unravelling the
      mysteries of prime numbers, appreciating the simplicity and
      elegance of Lisp, experiencing the remarkable extensibility of
      Emacs, and so on.
    </p>
    <p>
      Also, the more I help others work though a formidable book like
      <em>Introduction to Analytic Number Theory</em>, the more it helps
      me too to appreciate some finer and deeper points that I may not
      have paid due attention to when I read the book for the first
      time. So I benefit from these reading sessions too. Similarly, the
      more I help someone with Common Lisp programming, the more I have
      to dive into the Common Lisp HyperSpec which often teaches me a
      few new things too, so I gain from the experience too.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-book">
    <h3>
      Have you read the entire book?
      <a href="#faq-book"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      No, I have read approximately half of the book (Introduction to
      Analytic Number Theory) and I am enjoying it so far. This means
      that I am a good number of chapters ahead of someone who has just
      begun reading this book, so I can maintain a steady pace in the
      reading sessions and also be able to tell if some topics or areas
      of confusion in an earlier chapter will be clarified in a later
      chapter.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-lisp">
    <h3>
      You mentioned Lisp. Can you do a book club for it?
      <a href="#faq-lisp"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Yes, Lisp and Emacs are two other areas at the top of my mind.
      Once there has been sufficient progress in the number theory book
      club, I plan to start a Lisp one next. Join the <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">Matrix
      room</a> or <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">follow me
      on Twitter</a> to receive further updates about this.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-but">
    <h3>
      But I want to do group reading sessions for another book!
      <a href="#faq-but"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Start your own book club around it! This is mine. I have chosen
      number theory as the topic of discussion for now. After a few
      months, I will move on to topics around Lisp and Emacs. If you
      have a different topic or book in mind, start your own book club
      for it. You can reuse my channels (see top of this page) for it or
      you can do it your own way. If you let me know about it and if I
      can find the time, I will join your book club too! I think, we
      need more book clubs, not less!
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-recording">
    <h3>
      Will these sessions be recorded?
      <a href="#faq-recording"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Not at this time because we often refer to a few pages of the book
      via screen sharing during the reading session. I don't know the
      copyright implications of recording such sessions as videos and
      sharing them with everyone online. If you have expertise in this
      area, I would like to know if my concern is genuine and if there
      is a way to resolve it.
    </p>
  </li>


</ol></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://spxy.github.io/bc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26366464</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 10:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Build a Community: Starting with “Why?”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26363709">thread link</a>) | @alexdean
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://clrcrl.com/2021/03/03/how-to-build-a-community-why.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://clrcrl.com/2021/03/03/how-to-build-a-community-why.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <h2 id="my-origin-story">My origin story</h2>

<p>In November 2018, I moved from Sydney to the US to take on a role managing the dbt community. I’d been a member of the community for the two years prior, and in that time had gone from a data analyst who knew enough SQL to be dangerous, to someone who understood the data space deeply enough that I wanted a new challenge. And I’d learned almost everything about data from the dbt community.</p>

<p>Over the last few years, the dbt community has been incredibly successful — since I started, we’ve grown from 1000 members to over 10 000. In December, we hosted a conference that had 5 000 registrants, and received incredibly positive feedback. Late last year, when our eventual Series-B investors reached out to a dozen community members and asked for their NPS, we received an average score of 10.2/10 — no, this is not a typo, apparently someone gave us as 12/10. (If this was you: you should know better as a data person! You’re really messing up my numbers here!). Most of these community members cited the community as a reason for their high score.</p>

<p>Finally, around once a week I get around one DM a week saying thanks for everything we’ve built!</p>

<p><img src="https://clrcrl.com/assets/img/posts/tickled-pink.png"></p>



<p>If you had asked me when I joined in November 2018 what our community would look like at 10k members, I would have guessed that it would have become like most other online communities: full of unkind people and extractive behavior (after all, <a href="http://blog.vickiboykis.com/2017/05/10/good-things-don't-scale/">good things don’t scale</a>). I would have been scared of that day.</p>

<p>Yet somehow, despite my worst fears of growth (or perhaps because of them), people still find being a part of the dbt community to be a net-positive experience. Sure, it’s not perfect, but it’s still pretty good!</p>

<p>As a result, other companies in the industry are noticing, leading to a number of “can I pick your brain?” meeting requests¹ over the past few months. Most days, I feel wholly unqualified to give an opinion on why, or how, we’ve been so successful, I’ve just been making it up as I go along. But when I look at what we’ve achieved, when I talk to new starters at our company, or when I <em>do</em> let someone pick my brain, I realise that I do know <em>something</em> about this whole community building thing, and perhaps that thing is worth writing about.</p>

<p>So, this is the first of who-knows-how-many posts on <em>How to Build a Community</em>.</p>



<p>Often folks end up in my inbox because their CEO has heard that community building is the latest hotness, and they’re scrambling to figure out what that means, and how they should do this.</p>

<p>My first question is always “why do you want to build a community?”. Here’s some common answers:</p>
<ul>
  <li>“Well, it must be fantastic at increasing your top of funnel for sales and marketing.”</li>
  <li>“It just feels like your community creates incredible hype around your product.”</li>
  <li>“I guess we’ll be able to understand our users’ needs better, and get more product feedback.”</li>
  <li>“After all, you get free content, and get to outsource a ton of other work.”</li>
</ul>

<p>These are pretty reasonable answers on the surface, especially if you’re looking at our community as a model of success — after all, we do in fact get all of these benefits.</p>

<p>But if these are the primary motivators for <em>why</em> you’re building a community, I’m skeptical that you’ll succeed. These reasons put the benefit of the company ahead of the community member, and I’m pretty sure that any of our community members would see right through these motivations.</p>

<h2 id="building-mission-driven-communities">Building mission-driven communities</h2>

<p>So if those answers aren’t quite right, what <em>is</em> a good answer? Here’s my two step process to identifying why community might be right for you:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Find for your company mission, and</li>
  <li>Ask yourself “does building a community help us achieve this mission?”. If yes, then that’s your “why”.</li>
</ol>

<p>Let’s take the mission of the company I work for, Fishtown Analytics, as an example:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Fishtown Analytics is on a mission to empower analysts.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>(OK there’s actually a little bit more in the mission, but this is the part that I like most).</p>

<p>Another great example is <a href="https://www.animalz.co/about/">Animalz</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Set a new bar for quality content marketing</strong>. <br> We envision a world where the internet is dominated by content that’s informative, insightful and entertaining.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In both of these examples, it’s so clear that community is a tool for the company to achieve this mission — yes, a company can provide software and services in pursuit of this mission, but to <em>really</em> achieve it, one needs to be thinking bigger than this.</p>

<h2 id="how-does-this-play-out">How does this play out?</h2>

<p>For the last two and a half years, I’ve approached community-management from the perspective of trying to achieve our mission of empowering more analysts. Often, this leads us to make decisions that look different to other companies in our space.</p>

<ul>
  <li>On creating events:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Other companies:</strong> I recently saw the info sheet for an event that a vendor wanted us to participate in. At the top of the sheet was the goal for the event: “Create $X of sales opportunities”. Most of the talks were a thinly-veiled sales pitch for their product. I didn’t feel like I’d learned anything by attending, and I won’t be attending next year.</li>
      <li><strong>My take:</strong> When planning our inaugural conference, Coalesce, our goal was to create an event that advanced the practice of analytics engineering. When selecting talks, we chose the ones that we felt helped data teams be more impactful.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>



<ul>
  <li>On speaking at conferences:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Other companies:</strong> It’s not uncommon to have Developer Advocates whose role it is to speak at conferences.</li>
      <li><strong>My take:</strong> In comparison, I prefer to work with our community members so that they give the best conference talks possible (note: I have spoken at the odd-conference here and there – it’s a great way for to make sure that I’m well placed to give community members advice on how to make talks great!).</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>



<ul>
  <li>On getting product feedback:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Other companies:</strong> If I had an Amazon gift card for every time a company sent me an email asking me to do a product survey (in exchange for… an Amazon gift card). Some times, it’s up to the community team to bring feedback back to the company.</li>
      <li><strong>My take:</strong> I think more about how I can bring our team <em>into</em> the community — I’m very lucky in that all of our product team are data people themselves, so have a shared context with our community. But even our non-data teammates are building connections in the community — everyone on our team is great at what they do, and our community members often enjoy getting the chance to speak to a fantastic product designer and learn from them.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>



<ul>
  <li>On recognizing community members:
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Other companies:</strong> Ever been to a conference that had a points system for swag? Or seen a community that had a leaderboard? In these cases a company is trying to incentivize someone to give them something.</li>
      <li><strong>My take:</strong> If someone does something wonderfully kind, I’ll try to say thanks with a small gift. As much as possible, I’m trying to recognize, rather than incentivize.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>



<p>I think part of this is also just treating our community members with respect. Our community is full of incredibly bright, curious, and kind human beings&nbsp;— they’d see right through us if our motivations were related to dollars.</p>

<p>The <em>incredible</em> thing about this approach is that we do end up getting all of those benefits that I listed above — yes, we have a great sales funnel; yes, we have huge reach; yes, we stay in touch with our user needs; yes, we have people contribute work that we could not do ourselves. But we only get to sustain the good vibes (even with our growth) because we stay true to our mission.</p>


<p>That’s okay! But I think you need to be realistic with what you’re going to achieve if you try to build a community. Maybe your team isn’t going to build <em>the</em> <code>&lt;insert field of practice&gt;</code> community, but perhaps there’s ways you can generate goodwill by contributing to adjacent communities.</p>

<p>A lot of this mindset also applies to other interactions with your users, crossing over into the world of “developer experience” (i.e. how easy it is for a developer to be successful with your product) — by putting your user first, you’ll still create a lot of virtuous cycles.</p>

<p>No matter what your mission is, I encourage you to ask not what your community can do for you, but what you can do for your community.</p>



<p>We’ll see, this is my first time writing about community, and I have no idea how it will land.</p>

<p>Here’s a few topics I’m thinking about:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Managing the growth of a community</li>
  <li>Measuring the success of community</li>
  <li>Assessing community-market fit (or: when community isn’t the right strategy)</li>
  <li>What to look for in an early hire</li>
</ul>

<p>If one of these appeals to you, let me know via <a href="https://twitter.com/clairebcarroll/status/1365679922585468931">the bird site</a> or <a href="mailto:hello@clrcrl.com">email</a>.</p>

<hr>

<p>¹If you are reading this, and you have sent an email to someone in the past asking to “pick their brain” via a 30 minute meeting with no agenda, please don’t do this. Instead, send an email that includes the specific questions you are interested in, and don’t assume that the best way to get them answered is via a call.</p>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://clrcrl.com/2021/03/03/how-to-build-a-community-why.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26363709</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 23:39:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[FizzBuzz Mario World: Learning Assembly Language and Having Some Fun]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 126 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26362739">thread link</a>) | @vga805
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://computebeauty.com/posts/fbmw/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://computebeauty.com/posts/fbmw/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I've wanted to learn <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assembly_language" target="_blank">Assembly language (ASM)</a> programming for a long time. I finally found the perfect project to do it: hacking Super Mario World (SMW). It was a lot of fun so I thought I'd document the process.</p><p>The SMW <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ROM_hacking" target="_blank">ROM hacking</a> community is vibrant. It's an impressively talented and creative community that makes a lot of awesome games with custom graphics, music, level design, and game physics. Stumbling upon <a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=super+mario+world+rom+hack" target="_blank">these hacks</a> on YouTube started me down this rabbit hole.</p><p>TLDR: the code and a list of the resources mentioned in this post can be found on <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbyte/super-fizzbuzz-world" target="_blank">GitHub</a>.</p><h2>FizzBuzz Mario</h2><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fizz_buzz" target="_blank">FizzBuzz</a> is a common problem that beginner programmers solve for practice. The objective is to loop from 1 to 100 and:</p><ul><li>for every number divisible by 3, print 'fizz'</li><li>for every number divisible by 5, print 'buzz'</li><li>for every number divisible by 3 and 5, print 'fizz buzz'</li><li>otherwise print the number</li></ul><p>The goal of this project is to solve a problem similar to FizzBuzz by writing custom ASM that can be patched, or inserted, into the SMW code. The perfect context for FizzBuzz in SMW is the coin count. At any one time the player can have between 0 and 99 coins. Additionally, Mario can have 1 of 4 power-up statuses: small, big, cape, and fire. Here's the behavior we'll hack into our version of SMW:</p><ul><li>when coin count is divisible by 3, set status to big</li><li>when coin count is divisible by 5, set status to cape</li><li>when coin count is divisible by 3 and 5, set status to fire</li><li>otherwise set status to small</li></ul><p>Here's game-play of the finished product:</p><p><iframe title="FizzBuzz Mario World Demo" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/APwAE0wiGF8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p><h2>Getting Started</h2><p>After a few minutes of searching the web I found the source of most of the information I'll be sharing: <a href="https://www.smwcentral.net/" target="_blank">SWM Central</a>. You can find a full list of resources at the end of this article but the guides I found most helpful were Ersanio's <a href="https://ersanio.gitbook.io/assembly-for-the-snes/" target="_blank">Assembly for the SNES</a> and <a href="https://www.smwcentral.net/?p=section&amp;a=details&amp;id=15073" target="_black">Assembly for Super Mario World</a>. The former assumes no knowledge of ASM. The latter refreshes the ASM information from the former and then goes into how to apply a simple patch similar to the one we'll be writing. Both are quick reads and I recommend them to any programmer that wants to know what ASM programming feels like.</p><h3>Memory</h3><p>ASM is a low-level language with which you deal directly with individual bytes of memory. SNES games are comprised of read-only memory (ROM) and random-access memory (RAM). You can think of the ROM as the game cartridge itself. Instead of an actual cartridge and SNES, the ROM for present purposes is a computer file that you can play on a <a href="http://www.snes9x.com/" target="_blank">SNES emulator</a>. The ROM is where all the code for how the game works is stored. This memory, as the name implies, is usually only ever read from. Our goal is to hack this ROM by overwriting a small part of it thus changing how the game behaves.</p><p>The RAM is on the SNES itself and it's where values are stored that will change while the game is played. The coin counter value needs to live in RAM because it changes often. The same goes for the player's power-up status.</p><p>In both ROM and RAM, memory is a long list of addresses where values can be stored. These addresses are represented in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hexadecimal" target="_blank">hexadecimal (hex)</a>. For our purposes we'll need to figure out the memory addresses for three things: the value of the coin count, the value of the power-up status, and where to insert some custom code.</p><p>Fortunately, people have completely disassembled SMW and mapped the RAM and ROM, so finding what we need is a simple web search. The RAM map can be found on <a href="https://www.smwcentral.net/?p=memorymap&amp;game=smw&amp;u=0&amp;address=&amp;sizeOperation=%3D&amp;sizeValue=&amp;region[]=ram&amp;type=*&amp;description=" target="_blank">SMW Central</a>. The RAM begins at address <code>$7E0000</code> and ends at <code>$7FC800</code>. The <code>$</code> indicates hex. By searching a few relevant keywords I found that the coin count is stored at address <code>$7E0019</code> and the power-up status is stored at address <code>$7E0DBF</code>. The entry for power-up status also indicates the 4 possible values for this address and what they mean: 1 for big Mario, 2 for cape Mario, 3 for fire Mario, and 0 for small Mario.</p><p>This gives us a basic idea of what our ASM code will need to do, in pseudocode:</p><pre><code>every time the coin count increases:
  get the value of RAM address $7E0019 (coin count)
  if that value is divisible by 15
    store 3 in RAM address $7E0DBF (power-up status)
  else if that value is divisible by 5
    store 2 in RAM address $7E0DBF
  else if that value is divisible by 3
    store 1 in RAM address $7E0DBF
  else store 0 in RAM address $7E0DBF</code></pre><p>Now we need to figure out where to insert our code. I want this code to run whenever the player gets a coin so I searched for "coin count" within the ROM map and found <code>$008F1D</code>, a 30 byte piece of code that "handles actually increasing the player's coin count and giving a life from 100 coins." This is a good start, but we can't just insert code into 30 bytes of ROM without seeing what it does. We will break everything if we're not careful. Unfortunately the ROM map on SWM Central doesn't have the actual code stored at this address. But then I found <a href="https://www.smwcentral.net/?p=section&amp;a=details&amp;id=21822" target="_blank">All.log++</a>: a complete disassembly of the SMW source code, in ASM, with extensive comments and labels.</p><p>Inspecting the disassembled SMW source code at this coin count code address, I noticed that the address where the coin count is actually increased is <code>$008F25</code>. That is, this is the memory address of ROM that stores the instruction that literally adds 1 to the coin count every single time the player receives 1 coin. But instead of just increasing the coin count by 1, I want to patch the ROM so that when the code at this address gets executed, the SNES <i>also</i> runs my FizzBuzz code.</p><p>Now we have all of the relevant memory addresses that we need, and we have the pseudocode that we need to run at the coin count increase ROM address. Now we assemble.</p><h2>Writing the Code</h2><p>Our first two lines are easy:</p><pre><code>!PowerUpStatus = $0019
!CoinCount = $0DBF</code></pre><p>We simply set the RAM memory addresses that we need for the coin count and power-up status to some labels so they'll be easier to refer to in the code. Notice that we dropped the <code>7E</code> from both addresses. We don't need it. These lines don't actually get patched into the ROM. All occurrences of the labels in the code that we will write will get replaced with the addresses by the assembler. The assembler is the thing that will take our code and insert it into the ROM.</p><h3>Hijacking the Coin Count Increase Code</h3><p>We know where we want to insert our code: the ROM address where the coin count is increased. But we can't insert <i>all</i> of our code into this address, we'll overwrite a lot of stuff and break the game. We can only insert a few bytes, and we have to make sure the bytes that we overwrite are executed by us in our own code so that everything that the original code was supposed to do still happens. So what we'll do is insert one instruction in the ROM at the coin count increase address that tells the processor to <i>jump</i> to the rest of our code. Then we'll tell the assembler to insert our code in some free space so we don't overwrite anything. Here's what that looks like:</p><pre><code>ORG $008F25
JSL FizzBuzz
NOP
NOP

freecode</code></pre><p><code>ORG $008F25</code> instructs the assembler to insert the following instruction, <code>JSL FizzBuzz</code>, into the ROM address where the coin count is increased. What <code>JSL FizzBuzz</code> means is: <b>J</b>ump to the <b>S</b>ubroutine code labeled <code>FizzBuzz</code>. Most ASM operation codes, or opcodes, are menumonic. The J and S are for Jump and Subroutine. We can ignore the L, it's beyond the scope of this.</p><p>What's with the <code>NOP</code>s? As it turns out, the code we've chosen to overwrite, the coin count increase instruction, is 3 bytes long (we know this because All.log++ tells us that). The code we insert, <code>JSL FizzBuzz</code>, is 4 bytes long. So in our attempt to overwrite 1 3 byte long instruction, we overwrote the first byte of a second instruction.</p><p>The fix for this is that we need remember to execute <i>both instructions that we overwrote</i> in the code <i>we</i> write. The second instruction we overwrite, like the first, is 3 bytes long, for a total of 6 bytes. But again, the code we inserted is only 4 bytes: there are still 2 dangling bytes that were previously part of that second instruction. That's not good. Random, partially overwritten bytes in the code will break the game. So, we include 2 <code>NOP</code> instructions. These are <b>N</b>o <b>OP</b>erations. We do nothing for 2 bytes to fill up the space not filled up by the previous 4 bytes of code we inserted. To recap, we overwrote 6 bytes of 2 instructions with 6 bytes of our own instruction that jumps to our custom code.</p><p><code>freecode</code> just means find some free space in the ROM to put the rest of our custom ASM code.</p><h3>The FizzBuzz Subroutine</h3><p>The following code is the beginning of the <code>FizzBuzz</code> subroutine that we referenced above.</p><pre><code>FizzBuzz:
INC !CoinCount
LDA #$0F
STA $00
LDA !CoinCount
JSR Mod</code></pre><p>The first line is the label. The second, <code>INC !CoinCount</code>, means <b>INC</b>rement the value in the memory address for the coin count by 1. This is what the first instruction of the code we overwrote was supposed to do, so we do it here ourselves.</p><p>In ASM, one of the most important things is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accumulator_(computing)" target="_blank">accumulator</a>. Essentially, the accumulator (A) is the memory address where the microprocessor stores its results from math and logic operations. We can also store stuff there for use in math operations. <code>LDA #$0F</code> does just that. It <b>L</b>oa<b>D</b>s into the <b>A</b>ccumulator the value 15. 0F is hex for the decimal value 15, and the # means we want the value 15 itself, not what's stored at the memory address 15.</p><p>We then run <code>STA $00</code>, this <b>ST</b>ores the value of the <b>A</b>ccumulator into memory address <code>$00</code>. This memory address is "scratch" memory that has no assigned purpose other than as a place to store temporary values. We couldn't just store a value directly into <code>$00</code>, instead it was a two-step process: load a value into A, then store the value of A in <code>$00</code>. Next, <code>LDA !CoinCount</code> loads the value of the coin count into A.</p><p>So now we have two values stored in memory: the coin count, stored in A, and 15, stored in <code>$00</code>. To check if something is divisible by 3 and 5, we can divide it by 15 and check if there's a remainder. Many programming languages have a modulo operator that gives you the remainder of 1 number divided by another. For example, 47 modulo 15 is 2. <code>JSR Mod</code> means <b>J</b>ump to the <b>S</b>ub<b>R</b>outine labeled <code>Mod</code>.…</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://computebeauty.com/posts/fbmw/index.html">https://computebeauty.com/posts/fbmw/index.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://computebeauty.com/posts/fbmw/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26362739</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 22:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[SVG Tetris]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26360716">thread link</a>) | @marcodiego
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://www.xul.fr/svgtetris.svg | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.xul.fr/svgtetris.svg">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.xul.fr/svgtetris.svg</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26360716</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 19:07:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Do What Makes the Best Story]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 55 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26359378">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://amasad.me/story | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://amasad.me/story">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>Kids are always telling themselves stories. Try to remember yourself as a child lying in bed, anticipating an exciting day tomorrow, and you'll probably remember telling yourself a story about how cool it's going to be, who's going to be there, and how much fun you'll have. Self storytelling might be more pronounced in kids -- they like to say it out loud -- but it never goes away and only subsides to the background in adults. Self storytelling is so essential for people that one of the most effective <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_behavioral_therapy">techniques</a> for treating depression and anxiety boils down to "tell yourself better stories." </p>
<p>Life is also a form of self storytelling. We're continually retelling ourselves our life story, but very few people think of themselves as authors of their story, not mere subjects. People with extraordinary high-agency realize this early in life and start maximizing the interestingness of their life story.</p>
<p>Having a fascinating life story is not just an exercise in vanity -- it has a real impact on your success in life. You'll have an easier time attracting friends as well as life and business partners. It'll also make it much easier to sell yourself or your products. It has a kind of compounding <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halo_effect">halo effect</a>.</p>
<p>Startups also have to be good stories. A good business idea or market is not enough to endure the pain and have the motivation to get a startup off the ground. Without an interesting story about the founding of the company and the vision, you'll have a hard time attracting talent and money. Notice how the most successful startups in the world all have remarkable genesis stories. </p>
<p>So next time you're faced with a tough decision, consider the path that makes a more interesting story. If it turned out to be the wrong decision to have made, you'd at least be fun at dinner parties.</p>

          </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://amasad.me/story</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26359378</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 17:26:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The reason Okta spent $6.5B on Auth0]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 215 | Comments 143 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26358309">thread link</a>) | @advaitruia
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://supertokens.io/blog/the-real-reason-okta-spent-on-auth0 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://supertokens.io/blog/the-real-reason-okta-spent-on-auth0">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/okta_merged-14.png" loading="lazy" width="680" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 320px, (max-width: 767px) 540px, 680px" alt="Express session vs SuperTokens" srcset="https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/okta_merged-14-p-500.png 500w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/okta_merged-14-p-800.png 800w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/okta_merged-14-p-1080.png 1080w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/okta_merged-14-p-1600.png 1600w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/okta_merged-14.png 2835w"></p><p>March 05, 2021</p>

<p>Okta acquired <a href="https://www.okta.com/press-room/press-releases/okta-signs-agreement-to-acquire-auth0/">Auth0 for $6.5B</a> in an all stock deal (Okta was valued at ~$35B in the few days preceding the
announcement).<br></p>
<p>In July last year, Auth0 <a href="https://auth0.com/blog/auth0-announces-120m-seriesf-funding/">raised $120M</a> in private financing at a valuation of $1.9B. The round was led by Salesforce
Ventures with participation from DTCP and other existing investors.<br></p>
<p><strong>The acquisition is a ~3.5X jump in Auth0â€™s valuation from last year.Â&nbsp;</strong><br></p>
<h2 id="Security">Why acquire Auth0 for $6.5B?</h2>

<ol role="list">
<li>
<p><span>Complementary product and revenue streamâ€¨<br></span>Oktaâ€™s
core strength is workforce identity and it used to be almost all of their revenue. In the last few years,
revenues from their customer identity product has grown to 25% of total revenues from almost nothing. Auth0
core strength is customer identity. With Auth0, Okta has the best product for both use cases.<br></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><span>Increasing addressable marketâ€¨<br></span>According to Todd,
the founder of Okta, workforce identity is a $30B market and customer identity is $25B. The customer identity
space effectively doubles Oktaâ€™s addressable market. In return, Okta is paying 20% of its market cap for that
opportunity.<br></p><img src="https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/marketing_okta.png" loading="lazy" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 280px, (max-width: 767px) 500px, 640px" srcset="https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/marketing_okta-p-500.png 500w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/marketing_okta-p-800.png 800w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/marketing_okta-p-1080.png 1080w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/marketing_okta.png 1582w" alt="">
</li>
<li>
<p><span>Competition and pricing power<br></span>Auth0 is the most
prominent alternative that customers consider when evaluating Okta. The acquisition of Auth0 eliminates that
threat and grants Okta pricing power as a result.<br></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><span>Go To Market (GTM) strategy<br></span>Okta is built as a top
down sales organisation whereas Auth0 is built with a developer first bottoms up acquisition strategy. This
allows Okta to get the best of both worlds.<br></p>
<p>In the words of the Founder and CEO of Auth0, â€œWe have a large thriving developer
community, which provides powerful grassroot support for Auth0 within SMB and enterprise that we leverage in
our sales motion. Our developer-led adoption fosters rapid customer growthâ€�<br></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><span>Strategic acquisition<br></span>There were rumours that
Salesforce was interested in acquiring Auth0. Given that Salesforce has made several key acquisitions (Slack,
Mulesoft, and others) and led Auth0â€™s last round, this is a well founded theory. It is possible that Okta had
to make a preemptive move. Weâ€™ve heard anecdotally that Salesforceâ€™s and Oracleâ€™s identity solution were both
performing badly and they were looking to do something about it. Auth0 was the perfect candidate for and was
also supposedly being shopped around.<br></p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, â€¨there was a Hackernews comment along the lines of: â€œ$6,500,000,000.00 for a company
providing authentication APIs?â€� and the sentiment has been echoed by others too.<br></p>
<p>The thing to note is that Okta isn't just acquiring an API or a product. Itâ€™s acquiring
$200M in recurring revenue thatâ€™s probably growing at 50%. As soon as Okta acquires its largest competitor, it can
also refactor Auth0â€™s (and itâ€™s own) pricing to increase revenue even further. So it's paying a lot upfront
for what it hopes will be even more in the future.Â&nbsp;<br></p>
<p>Now that we have some clarity on the acquisition, weâ€™ll be looking at how the (stock) market,
users and employees reacted to the news (largely drawn from Reddit, Hackernews and some personal
conversations)<br></p>
<h2><strong>Reactions (and what this means)</strong><br></h2>

<p><span>Market<br></span>Oktaâ€™s will acquire Auth0 in an all stock deal
and dilute existing shareholders by 20%. The 10% fall in the stock price (equivalent to a decrease in $3-4B)
immediately post the announcement means that investors are valuing Auth0 at half the price what Okta paid for
it.<br></p>
<p>Okta will issue shares to Auth0 shareholders at share price of $276.21, close to 20% less
than the current share price (at the time of writing).<br></p><p><img src="https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/Screenshot-2021-03-05-at-17.35.19.png" loading="lazy" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 320px, (max-width: 767px) 540px, 680px" srcset="https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/Screenshot-2021-03-05-at-17.35.19-p-500.png 500w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/Screenshot-2021-03-05-at-17.35.19-p-800.png 800w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/Screenshot-2021-03-05-at-17.35.19-p-1080.png 1080w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/Screenshot-2021-03-05-at-17.35.19-p-1600.png 1600w, https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/Screenshot-2021-03-05-at-17.35.19.png 1830w" alt=""></p><p><strong>Users<br>â€�</strong>In general, the developer community has had an unpleasant
experience with Okta. This is perhaps expected given that it is not a â€œdeveloper firstâ€� company. Below are some
excerpts taken from Hackernews.<br></p>
<p>â€œWe moved from Okta a few years ago after we basically received almost no actual real support
for a bunch of issues, even though we were paying a premium cost. Nobody cares about issues on their Githubâ€�. â€œWe
ended up switching to Auth0â€�, â€œshaved a decent amount off our costsâ€�. â€œIn the end we were much happier.â€�<br></p>
<p>â€œOkta requires you to "contact support" to turn on basic features like email
customization, and even though I'm a paying customer, I was given a multi-week estimate (after waiting a week
or two) for how long it would take to enable this featureâ€�<br></p>
<p>â€œWe use Okta for multiple AWS accounts and they "ran a bad migration" that deleted
half our permissions and took a month to resolve. On top of that, nothing appeared in the audit logs.â€�<br></p>
<p>â€œOkta as a business are a pain to deal with, and unless you meet their minimum spend
requirements (which are not told to you up-front) you're screwed.â€�<br></p>
<p><strong>Employees<br>â€�</strong>Similarly, employees were worried about Auth0, given their
experience with Oktaâ€™s culture and hiring process.<br></p>
<p>â€œI interviewed with both, and the process at Auth0 had me walk away with respect, while
contrasted with Okta that left me reminded that tech hiring is broken.â€�<br></p>
<p>â€œThe two companies couldn't be more different, with Auth0 embracing a remote-first-class
culture with creative interview processes, and Okta (pre-covid) being very much the opposite.â€�<br></p>
<p>I used to work on the Okta team.. As far as I could tell, Okta is a sales company. The
salespeople got the fancy events, the high floors with nice views, all the budgetâ€¦ Enterprise customers are the
only ones that mattered.. I got to know some people who came into Okta via acquisitions and letâ€™s just say itâ€™s
not a fun ride.â€�<br></p>
<h2><strong>What next for Auth0?</strong><br></h2>

<p>â€¨Officially the statement is that the â€œCompany will operate as an independent unit inside of
Okta as they look for paths to integration in the coming monthsâ€�.<br></p>
<h2><strong>What is the opportunity for SuperTokens?â€¨</strong><br></h2>

<ol role="list">
<li>
<p>The incumbents in the space are Okta, Auth0, Firebase and AWS Cognito. However, they are all closed source,
proprietary companies. We have a strong belief in our open source approach as it benefits all stakeholders -
customers, the community and us as a company. There are a few others who are taking this approach and there is
a strong possibility for a project like SuperTokens to reach the scale that matches the incumbents.<br></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Consolidation typically creates small vacuums. It is our job, as the project creators, to understand which
vacuum (niche) is the strongest.Â&nbsp;<br></p>
</li>
<li>
<div><p>We claim to be truly developer friendly. <b>But what does that really mean?</b> How do we demonstrate
that?
</p><ul>
<li>First is <b>our open source approach</b> - we place developers and the community above all else.</li>Â&nbsp;
<li>Second is the <b>modular architecture of SuperTokens</b>. This enables developers to pick features
they need
for their use
case and forget about the complexity associated with everything else (for example, if you do not need SSO,
no
need worry about OAuth flows). It allows you to add authentication functionality as your product and
company
scale.
<strong>We even have different docs based on your feature set and use case.<br>â€�</strong>
</li>
<li>Finally, our
frontend
UI is the most customizable weâ€™ve seen of any of the alternatives. While Auth0 provides a ready made
frontend
or exposes the backend APIs to build your own frontend, we provide ready made frontends and make it far
easier
to build your own theme or customize existing ones.<br></li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Hope this added some insight into this massive development. Weâ€™re excited about the space and
are here to serve developers everyday.<br></p>
<p>Written by the Folks at <a href="https://supertokens.io/" aria-current="page">SuperTokens</a> â€” hope you enjoyed! We are always available on our Discord server.
Join us if you have any questions or need any help.<br></p>
<p><a rel="noopener" href="https://supertokens.io/discord" target="_blank"><img src="https://supertokens.io/static/webflow/blog/auth0-acquisition/images/Image-93x.png" loading="lazy" width="200" alt=""></a>
</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://supertokens.io/blog/the-real-reason-okta-spent-on-auth0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26358309</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 16:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Thanks HN: Lessons learned after Google nearly killed my site]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 491 | Comments 254 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26357033">thread link</a>) | @uploaderwin
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://www.uploader.win/blog/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.uploader.win/blog/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                <div class="page">
                    
                    
                    <p><span>I am the creator of Uploader window, a website that helps users to add an upload widget to their own apps or websites.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>We’ve been running this website for almost 3 years without any issues (<a href="https://www.uploader.win/about.html">since 2017</a>). </span><span>But something happened yesterday that almost shutdown my entire business at a moment’s notice.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>My Whatsapp started ringing. In addition to email support I give many paying users my personal WA number for emergencies. It was a message from a client using our services for over 2+ years now. He said that they are getting a warning on their site because of our script. Anybody
                        visiting any site in which my clients integrated my app were also showing this red screen of death.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span><a href="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/whatsapp.png" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/whatsapp.png"></a></span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>I opened my Inbox and there was another email from a client about the same issue.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Now we run automated tests to monitor server uptime and check server for problems every 30 seconds. Unfortunately automated test scripts were happily getting HTTP/200 replies while people using the Chrome browser were being told this is a scam business trying to
                        steal their
                        bank account information.</span></p>
                    <p><span>Not knowing the first thing about what had happened I started looking for ways I could fix it quickly. And this is when I realized that while it was something new to me, </span><span>it has been happening for a very long time and many businesses are affected by it.
                        All because this whole process for getting blacklisted is pretty automatic and
                        you don’t
                        really know about it until you’re actually blacklisted.</span></p>
                    <p><span><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5971403" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/other-people.png"></a></span></p>
                    
                    
                    <p><span>Lesson #1: The first place to look is Google webmaster tools</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>I never got any email from Google but as many articles suggested the best place to start is inside the <a href="https://developers.google.com/search" target="_blank">GWT</a> (renamed Search Central). As soon as I added my site to GWT, I got a big red security issue that my site
                        has been categorized as a deceptive phishing site which harms customers. It also listed my homepage as the deceptive page. </span>
                    </p>
                    
                    <p><span><a href="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/gwt.png" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/gwt.png"></a></span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>It was issued a few hours ago and I was already on 5 blacklists in a matter of a few hours. Soon firefox users started seeing a warning too. </span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>I checked the source code of my homepage, checked all Javascripts by hand, manually logged in to my server and checked all running processes on my servers to see if in fact we had been hacked. <b>Nothing, absolutely nothing was changed.</b></span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>There was a box to submit your site for a review but it didn’t say how much time it would take. Some said it may take upto 4 days, other sites said it could be even longer! </span><span>My business would most certainly be dead if it took that long.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Nevertheless I submitted for a review and that was it.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Lesson #2: Hacker news is the next best place to ask for help</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>When searching for why this has happened and ways to fix it I stumbled upon similar threads from Hacker news. <span>It seems a lot of other people have been victims of Google's trigger-happy blacklisting and it’s not an easy fix.</span></span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Once you’re listed, you get <b>bumped off Google search results and all users are banned from visiting your site</b> (some users said they couldn’t even access it after accepting the advanced warning). Basically it’s `poweroff -h` for your site.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>But there are plenty of Google engineers and good helpful people on Hacker news. People who go out of their way to help others</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5972927" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/helpful-googlers.png"></a></span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>I was super tempted to contact this person directly but I decided it isn't very polite to bother people like this. Instead I posted my own thread mainly looking for advice on how I can expedite the review process and maybe learn what the hell had happened yesterday.</span></p>
                    
                    
                    <p><span>I listed all the reasons I could think off and people were quick to help. My call for help quickly reached HN’s homepage and I finally figured out what had happened</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26326528" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/hn-thread.png"></a></span></p>
                    <p><span>Lesson #3: Never link to any user content from your main domain (or any subdomain or even redirects)</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>So after a lot of brainstorming and ideas from HNers I finally figured out the culprit(s). </span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>We have a live demo on our home where people can upload a test file. The demo is a way for users to actually see how the uploader will look in their own apps. It's a way for users to test drive the site without actually signing up.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span><i>Visitors love the demo. It greatly helps our conversions.</i> I did think the demo could be used for file piracy so any files uploaded to the demo are automatically deleted after 24 hours. We never allow anything other than video and image files either. And we host the files
                        on a
                        cdn, so they
                        are linked using a subdomain (cdn.uploader.win)</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>We also give all users a 20MB test storage. This is to help them integrate the Uploader in their own site during development.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>I believe that somebody signed up for our service (it’s free to sign up) and then uploaded a malicious file on our test storage and abused this feature.</span></p>
                    
                    
                    <p><span>We cannot unfortunately disable the live demo or remove the test storage because they both serve a purpose. But there are few things we can do to mitigate it in future:</span></p>
                    
                    <ul>
                        <li><span>Link to any user uploaded content using a separate domain altogether (never main domain or subdomain). </span></li>
                        <li><span>Expire test files quickly. Every few minutes instead of 24 hours.</span></li>
                        <li><span>If you are giving users any scripts to integrate on their site make sure to host them on a separate domain.</span></li>
                    </ul>
                    
                    <p><span>Lesson #4: Don’t use base-64 images (or inline images)</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>I’m not 100% sure about this but while I was frantically trying to scan my website using various online services a lot of them warned about using base64 content in the homepage. </span></p>
                    
                    
                    <p><span><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26327091" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/base64.png"></a></span></p>
                    <p><span>Also if you remember Google did not say it was the subdomain rather it linked directly to my homepage as hosting the deceptive content.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>The reason for adding inline images is to reduce the number of HTTP requests (which speeds up the page load). This got us a good score on Pagespeed insights but at the same time a lot of online virus scanners do frown upon pages that do it. </span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Since I will never know what I did wrong I just removed all inline content (as suggested by some HNers).</span></p>
                    
                    
                    <p><span>Again this is just hypothesis and it may or may not have been the case... but why take chances?</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Lesson #5: Communicating with your customers can be super helpful</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>My biggest worry in all this was how it would affect my customers who depend on my site for uploads. I was feeling so helpless and anxious. </span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>So I decided to instead communicate directly with some customers while I was waiting for resolution. Not only were most of my customers super supportive but I also realized that most of my customers are just developers like me and understood that things like this happen and
                        cannot be
                        controlled. </span></p>
                    
                    <p><span><a href="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/whatsapp2.png" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/whatsapp2.png"></a></span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Such words brought down my stress level from 100 to 60 :) </span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>Finally Good News!</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>The whole ordeal was sorted in only 6 to 7 hours</span> and things are great again! <span>I believe the HN thread getting on the homepage tremendously helped me and somebody from Google saw it and expedited the review after all (or maybe I was just lucky
                        who knows). In just 4 hours after posting the thread I heard from Google (got an email this time) that my site was
                        reviewed
                        and removed from blacklist.</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span><a href="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/gwt-reply.png" target="_blank"><img src="https://www.uploader.win/blog/assets/gwt-reply.png"></a></span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>It was a great learning experience for me but also a little scary how fragile online businesses are. You can write all the cron jobs to monitor every single part of your business but you can never be prepared for everything. </span></p>
                    
                    <p><span>And when shtf, the best solution is to always be open about what happened and ask for help. There are so many good people who will go out of their way to help you out.</span></p>
                    <p><span>So special thanks to all the people at Hacker news who were not only super helpful with their suggestions and comments, but also helped me get this sorted quickly!</span></p>
                    
                    <p><span><b>P.S.</b> In case you learned something from my experience or liked …</span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.uploader.win/blog/">https://www.uploader.win/blog/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.uploader.win/blog/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26357033</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 14:12:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Generating ePub from LaTeX]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26356903">thread link</a>) | @ivan_ah
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://minireference.com/blog/generating-epub-from-latex/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://minireference.com/blog/generating-epub-from-latex/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-648">
	<div>
		<p>I want to tell you about my journey to produce the ePub files for the <strong>No Bullshit Guide</strong> textbooks. This has been an epic battle with lots of technological obstacles, but I got it working in the end, and the results are beautiful:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://minireference.com/static/excerpts/noBSmath_v5_preview.epub">No Bullshit Guide to Mathematics ePub preview</a></li>
<li><a href="https://minireference.com/static/excerpts/noBSmath_v5_preview.mobi">No Bullshit Guide to Mathematics Mobi preview</a></li>
</ul>
<p>In this blog post, I want to share what I’ve learned about generating ePub and Mobi files from LaTeX source files that contain lots of math equations. I feel this ought to be recorded somewhere for the benefit of other STEM authors and publishers who have LaTeX manuscripts and want to convert them to .epub and .mobi formats. Read on to watch the “How it’s made” episode about math eBooks.</p>
<p>The end-to-end book production pipeline looks like this:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://minireference.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ebook_converion_pipeline.png" alt="eBook production pipeline including .tex, .html, .epub, and .mobi formats" width="534" height="328"></p>
<p><strong>Figure 1</strong>: The eBook production pipeline described in this blog post. Each box represents a different markup format and the arrows indicate the software used to convert between formats. The hard step is to produce clean .html+MathJax format from the .tex source. The generation of the other formats is standard.</p>

<p>Historically, the primary tool I used to produce the <strong>No Bullshit Guide</strong> textbooks has always been the pdflatex, which is the most common way to produce PDFs in the LaTeX ecosystem. <strong>The problem</strong> is the <strong>fixed-width layouts of PDF</strong> files are not a good fit for mobile screens and eReader devices with varying screen sizes. Modern publishing is all about reflowable formats like HTML and ePub. If we want more people to learn math, we have to make math textbooks readable on mobile.</p>
<p>The solution for ePub production that I came up with looks like this:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Transform</strong> the LaTeX source files to the macros supported by Softcover (using Python scripts for TeX wrangling based on TexSoup, and image conversion using ImageMagic)</li>
<li><strong>Convert</strong> the LaTeX to HTML+MathJax equations (performed using softcover, polytexnic, and Tralics)</li>
<li><strong>Generate</strong> an ePub file from the HTML (orchestrated by softcover based on MathJax, PhantomJS, Inkscape)</li>
<li><strong>(bonus) Convert</strong> the ePub to Mobi (thanks to ebook-convert command line utility that comes with Calibre)</li>
</ul>
<p><br>The conversion process is fairly complex and depends on tools written in several programming languages. Seriously, there are like 6+ different programming languages used in this pipeline: Python 3.x, Python 2.7 (because one library needs it), Perl, Ruby, JavaScript, and Bash.&nbsp; If this were a collect-them-all contest, I’d be winning big time!&nbsp; It’s a lot of dependencies to take on at once, but it had to be done. Besides, the Rube Goldberg machine is a well-recognized software design pattern 🙂</p>
<p>I’m super proud of <a href="https://github.com/minireference/sample-book/blob/master/fabfile.py">the scripts</a> I created for automating this pipeline, but I want it to be clear the real credit for everything you’re about to read goes to the people who developed the tools that I used. I was standing on the shoulders of giants: Michael Hartl (<a href="https://github.com/softcover/softcover">softcover</a> and <a href="https://github.com/softcover/polytexnic/">polytexnic</a>), Alvin Wan (<a href="https://github.com/alvinwan/TexSoup">TexSoup</a>), and Kovid Goyal (<a href="https://github.com/kovidgoyal/calibre">calibre</a>). These are the people who made all this possible through the open source software tools they maintain. They deserve the real credit—my contribution is simply to connect these tools to build an end-to-end pipeline using some Python scripts.</p>
<h4><br>Is this blog post for me?</h4>
<p>If you only have 10 more seconds of attention left, the only thing you need to know is to go install softcover (<a href="https://manual.softcover.io/book/getting_started#sec-installing_softcover">install instructions</a>) and use it for any new projects: it’s the best way of converting math books (.tex source&nbsp; files) to .epub and .mobi. Start with the sample book produced with (<code>softcover new --latex mybook</code>) and extend the chapters while compiling regularly.&nbsp;</p>

<h4>Sujet divisé</h4>
<ul>
<li>In the first part of this blog post, we’ll start with some background on eBook file formats. Think of this as the definitions section in a philosophy paper. What is an ePub file? (spoiler: it’s a zip file with .html+metadata in it) We’ll also talk about the software tools that I highly recommend for generating these files: softcover, and Calibre.<br>
<ul>
<li>This part should be interesting for anyone in the “eBook business” since understanding the underlying formats—the files that finally gets downloaded on readers’ devices—is a big thing. Even if you’re not technical, you need to know this stuff.</li>
<li>There will be some technical details (like command line terminal or cmd.exe) but it’s not that bad. In fact the tools described can probably be used by anyone who can get over the OMG-this-is-a-command-line-thing fear. Once you go through the process a couple of times, the “What am I supposed to type here?” moments go away, and you’ll know what to type: commands. Just like point-and-click commands run programs, command-line terminal commands run programs too.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The second part of the blog post will get into the nitty-gritty details of the transformations and processing steps described in Figure 1. There will be a lot of link-dropping to useful scripts, but note some of the scripts are very specific to the .tex macros used in the <strong>No Bullshit Guide</strong> textbooks, so don’t expect to reuse the same code directly. Think of it more like sample code. Or badge:proof-of-concept.
<ul>
<li>The technical details will only make sense after you have researched Softcover and Calibre, you’ve played around with them, and now you want to learn how to use them glue them together using a script. This code walkthrough is mainly written as a remember and how-it-works logbook for the Minireference Co. dev team (yours truly).</li>
<li>The technical parts will be interesting for anyone who needs to convert equation-heavy .tex books into .epub files, and <em>insists</em> on the math equations not looking horrible. Basically, if you’re a self-respecting self-publisher of math textbooks, then we’ve got some scripts for you!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<p>Let’s begin.</p>


<h2>Nouns: eBook File formats</h2>
<p>Let’s talk a little bit about eBook formats before we get into the technical details. It’s good to know a little bit about the final products we’re trying to produce.</p>
<h3>Kindle file formats</h3>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kindle_File_Format">Kindle file formats</a> (.awz, .awz3, .kf8, etc.) are a family of proprietary format used on Amazon Kindle devices. There is no way to generate Kindle eBooks directly, instead, the <a href="https://kdp.amazon.com/en_US/help/topic/G200634390#EPUB">recommended procedure for KDP</a> distribution is to generate an ePub file and let KDP take care of the conversion to their proprietary formats. So for distribution on Kindle devices through KDP, the key is to generate a good quality, standards-compliant ePub.</p>
<h3>Mobi format</h3>
<p>The .mobi format (short for Mobipocket) is another proprietary eBook file format that was very popular before the wide adoption of ePub. Early versions of the Amazon Kindle used mobi format internally, so the mobi format is still supported on Kindle devices.</p>
<p>It’s considered good practice for eBook publishers to offer .mobi files in addition to .epub for the benefit of readers who have a Kindle device, since Kindle devices don’t support ePub files natively. Luckily there is an excellent command-line tool for this (<a href="https://manual.calibre-ebook.com/generated/en/ebook-convert.html">ebook-convert</a>) that comes with every installation of <a href="https://calibre-ebook.com/">Calibre</a>.</p>
<p>Using ebook-convert is really simple. If you have a source file <code>book.epub</code>, and you want to convert it to .mobi format, you can run</p>
<pre>ebook-convert book.epub book.mobi --mobi-file-type both</pre>
<p>and you’ll end up with a file that is readable by all Kindle devices.</p>
<h3>ePub format</h3>
<p>This is the most widely-supported format for ebooks and the main focus of our efforts here. The ePub file format is based on web technologies like HTML and CSS, and it is codified as an <a href="https://www.w3.org/publishing/epub3/epub-overview.html">IDPF standard</a>. An .epub eBook is a self-contained container of HTML, CSS, images, and metadata that is packaged as a .zip file. If you have an ePub file you can change it’s extension from .epub to .zip and unzip it to look at the contents.&nbsp; You can also use an ePub editor like <a href="https://github.com/Sigil-Ebook/Sigil/releases/tag/1.4.0">Sigil</a> that lets you “view source” and modify ePub files directly without the need to unzip them first.</p>
<p>The use of HTML for content is—in principle—a good thing. In practice, different readers have different levels of support for markup, styling, and media playback, and very few ePub readers support the possibility of running scripts. For this reason, we take a conservative approach and target the basic ePub v3 format, without taking advantage of modern features of the web platform like SVG images, audio playback, and interactive elements. I’m looking forward to exploring these advanced features of ePub3 in the future, but for maximum compatibility, I will avoid such niceties for now and assume the “client” is a bare-bones eReader device that only supports basic HTML, CSS, and images.</p>
<p>So how do you build an ePub? Theoretically you just prepare your book using HTML markup and you’re done. Well, not quite. When I said the ePub format is based on web technologies like HTML and CSS, it’s a bit misleading, since that covers only the content pages—the chapters of the book. Additionally, a standards-compliant .epub file must also specify the book metadata (<code>content.opf</code>) and&nbsp; structure (<code>toc.ncx</code>). There are several “ebook frameworks” like <a href="https://pandoc.org/">pandoc</a>, <a href="https://www.sphinx-doc.org/">Sphinx</a>, <a href="https://www.gitbook.com/">gitbook</a>, etc. that can be used to produce ePubs. If your book doesn’t contain math equations,&nbsp; I would recommend one of these well-established frameworks to “outsource” the complexity of generating the ePub. See this <a href="https://puppet.com/blog/how-we-automated-our-ebook-builds-pandoc-and-kindlegen/">blog post</a> for example.</p>
<p>However, in the case of the No Bullshit Guide textbooks, we’re starting with 1000+ pages of LaTeX source files containing A LOT of equations.</p>
<p><strong>Statement of the problem</strong>: Generate a good-looking ePub file from LaTeX source files that include equations, figures, tables, and custom macros for exercises and problems.</p>
<p>The occurrence of the word “custom” should give you a hint that things will get interesting soon…</p>

<h2>Verbs: Software Tools</h2>
<p>Let’s now talk about the software tools that perform the specific transformation from .tex source to .epub file. In order of importance these tools are <a href="https://github.com/softcover/softcover">softcover</a>, <a href="https://github.com/kovidgoyal/calibre">calibre</a>,&nbsp; <a href="https://github.com/alvinwan/TexSoup">TexSoup</a>, and <a href="https://ploxiln.github.io/fab-classic/tutorial.html">fab-classic</a>. We start with the most important parts first: the tools that are broadly reusable in any context; we defer the technical details about the specific transformations we perform until the second half …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://minireference.com/blog/generating-epub-from-latex/">https://minireference.com/blog/generating-epub-from-latex/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://minireference.com/blog/generating-epub-from-latex/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26356903</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 13:59:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Clojure from a Schemer's Perspective]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 147 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26356367">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://www.more-magic.net/posts/thoughts-on-clojure.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.more-magic.net/posts/thoughts-on-clojure.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>Recently I joined <a href="https://www.bevuta.com/">bevuta IT</a>, where I am now working on a big project written in <a href="https://www.clojure.org/">Clojure</a>.  I'm very fortunate to be working in a Lisp for my day job!</p>
<p>As I've mostly worked with Scheme and have used other Lisps here and there, I would like to share my perspective on the language.</p><a href="#overall-design">
<h2 id="overall-design">Overall design</h2></a>
<p>From a first view, it is pretty clear that Clojure has been designed from scratch by (mostly) one person who is experienced with Lisps and as a language designer.  It is quite clean and has <a href="https://download.clojure.org/papers/clojure-hopl-iv-final.pdf">a clear vision</a>. Most of the standard library has a very consistent API.  It's also nice that it's a <a href="http://www.nhplace.com/kent/Papers/Technical-Issues.html">Lisp-1</a>, which obviously appeals to me as a Schemer.</p>
<p>My favourite aspect of the language is that everything is designed with a functional-first mindset.  This means I can program in the same functional style as I tend to do in Scheme.  Actually, it's even more functional, because for example its maps (what would be hash tables in Scheme) are much less clunky to deal with.  In Scheme, SRFI-69 hash tables are quite imperative, with <tt>hash-table-set!</tt> and <tt>hash-table-update!</tt> being the ways to insert new entries, which of course mutate the existing object.  Similarly, vectors can easily be extended (on either end!) functionally.</p>
<p>The underlying design of Clojure's data structures must be different. It needs to efficiently support functional updates; you don't want to fully copy a hash table or vector whenever you add a new entry. I am not sure how efficient everything is, because the system I'm working on isn't in production yet.  A quick look <a href="https://github.com/clojure/clojure/blob/master/src/jvm/clojure/lang/PersistentArrayMap.java">at the code</a> implies that various data structures are used under the hood for what looks like one data structure in the language.  That's a lot of complexity!  I'm not sure that's a tradeoff I'd be happy to make.  It makes it harder to reason about performance.  You might just be using a completely different underlying data structure than expected, depending on which operations you've performed.</p><a href="#non-lispiness">
<h2 id="non-lispiness">(non) Lispiness</h2></a>
<p>To a seasoned Lisp or Scheme programmer, Clojure can appear positively <i>bizarre</i>.  For example, while there is a <tt>cons</tt> function, there are no cons cells, and <tt>car</tt> and <tt>cdr</tt> don't exist.  Instead, it has <tt>first</tt> and <tt>rest</tt>, which are definitely saner names for a language designed from scratch.  It has "persistent lists", which are immutable lists, but in most day to day programming you will not even be <b>using</b> lists, as weird as that sounds!</p><a href="#symbols-and-keywords">
<h3 id="symbols-and-keywords">Symbols and keywords</h3></a>
<p>One thing that really surprised me is that symbols are not interned. This means that two symbols which are constructed on the fly, or when read from the same REPL, are not identical (as in <tt>eq</tt> or <tt>eq?</tt>) to one another:</p>
<pre><tt>user&gt; <span>(<span>= 'foo 'foo</span>)</span>
true
user&gt; <span>(<span>identical? 'foo 'foo</span>)</span>
false</tt></pre>
<p>Keywords seem to fulfil most "symbolic programming" use cases.  For example, they're almost always used as "keys" in maps or when specifying options for functions.  Keywords <i>are</i> interned:</p>
<pre><tt>user&gt; <span>(<span>= <span>:foo</span> <span>:foo</span></span>)</span>
true
user&gt; <span>(<span>identical? <span>:foo</span> <span>:foo</span></span>)</span>
true</tt></pre>
<p>Code is still (mostly) expressed as lists of symbols, though.  When you're writing macros you'll deal with them a lot.  But in "regular" code you will deal more with keywords, maps and vectors than lists and symbols.</p><a href="#numeric-tower">
<h3 id="numeric-tower">Numeric tower</h3></a>
<p>A favorite gotcha of mine is that integers <a href="https://clojure.org/reference/data_structures#Numbers">are not automatically promoted to bignums</a> like in most Lisps that support bignums.  If you need bignums, you have to use special-purpose operators like <tt>+'</tt> and <tt>-'</tt>:</p>
<pre><tt>user&gt; <span>(<span>* <span>(<span>bit-shift-left 1 62</span>)</span> 2</span>)</span>
Execution error <span>(<span>ArithmeticException</span>)</span> at user/eval51159 <span>(<span>REPL:263</span>)</span>.
integer overflow
user&gt; <span>(<span>*' <span>(<span>bit-shift-left 1 62</span>)</span> 2</span>)</span>
9223372036854775808N

user&gt; <span>(<span>* <span>(<span>bit-shift-left 1 62</span>)</span> 2N</span>)</span> 9223372036854775808N
user&gt; <span>(<span>* 1N 1</span>)</span> 1N</tt></pre>
<p>This could lead to better performance at the cost of more headaches when dealing with the accidental large numbers in code that was not prepared for them.</p>
<p>What about rationals, you ask?  Well, those are just treated as "the unusual, slow case".  So even though they <i>do</i> normalize to regular integers when simplifying, operations on those always return BigInts:</p>
<pre><tt>user&gt; <span>(<span>+ 1/2 1/4</span>)</span>
3/4
user&gt; <span>(<span>+ 1/2 1/2</span>)</span>
1N
user&gt; <span>(<span>/ 1 2</span>)</span> 1/2
user&gt; <span>(<span>/ 4 2</span>)</span> 2</tt></pre>
<p>The sad part is, bitwise operators do not support bignums, <i>at all</i>:</p>
<pre><tt>user&gt; <span>(<span>bit-shift-right 9223372036854775808N 62</span>)</span>
Execution error <span>(<span>IllegalArgumentException</span>)</span> at user/eval51167 <span>(<span>REPL:273</span>)</span>.
bit operation not supported for: class clojure.lang.BigInt
user&gt; <span>(<span>bit-shift-right' 9223372036854775808N 62</span>)</span> Syntax error compiling at <span>(<span>*cider-repl test:localhost:46543<span>(<span>clj</span>)</span>*:276:7</span>)</span>.
Unable to resolve symbol: bit-shift-right' in this context</tt></pre>
<p>There's one benefit to all of this: if you know the types of something going into numeric operators, you will typically know the type that comes out, because there is no automatic coercion.  Like I mentioned, this may provide a performance benefit, but it also simplifies reasoning about types.  Unfortunately, this does not work as well as you would hope because division may change the type, depending on whether the result divides cleanly or not.</p><a href="#syntax">
<h3 id="syntax">Syntax</h3></a>
<p>For many Lispers, this is the elephant in the room.  Clojure certainly qualifies as a Lisp, but it is much heavier on syntax than most other Lisps.  Let's look at a small contrived example:</p>
<pre><tt><span>(<span><i><span>let</span></i> [foo-value <span>(<span>+ 1 2</span>)</span>
      bar-value <span>(<span>* 3 4</span>)</span>]
  {<span>:foo</span> foo-value
   <span>:bar</span> bar-value}</span>)</span></tt></pre>
<p>This is a <tt>let</tt> just like in Common Lisp or Scheme.  The bindings are put inside square brackets, which is literal syntax for <i>vectors</i>.  Inside this vector, key-value pairs are interleaved, like in a Common Lisp <a href="http://www.lispworks.com/documentation/lw50/CLHS/Body/26_glo_p.htm#property_list">property list</a>.</p>
<p>The lack of extra sets of "grouping" parentheses is a bit jarring at first, but you get used to it rather quickly.  I still mess up occasionally when I accidentally get an odd number of entries in a binding vector.  Now, the <tt>{:foo foo-value :bar bar-value</tt>} syntax is a <i>map</i>, which acts like a hash table (more on that below).</p>
<p>There doesn't seem to be a good rationale about why vectors are used instead of regular lists, though.  What I <i>do</i> really like is that all the binding forms (even function signatures!) support <a href="https://clojure.org/guides/destructuring">destructuring</a>.  The syntax for destructuring maps is a bit ugly, but having it available is super convenient.</p>
<p>What I regard as a design mistake is the fact that Clojure allows for optional commas in lists and function calls.  Commas are just whitespace to the reader.  For example:</p>
<pre><tt><span>(<span>= [1, 2, 3, 4] [1 2 3 4]</span>)</span> =&gt; true
<span>(<span>= '<span>(<span>1, 2, 3, 4</span>)</span> '<span>(<span>1 2 3 4</span>)</span></span>)</span> =&gt; true
<span>(<span>= {<span>:foo</span> 1, <span>:bar</span> 2, <span>:qux</span> 3} {<span>:foo</span> 1 <span>:bar</span> 2 <span>:qux</span> 3}</span>)</span> =&gt; true
<span>(<span>= <span>(<span>foo 1, 2, 3, 4</span>)</span> <span>(<span>foo 1 2 3 4</span>)</span></span>)</span> =&gt; true
<span>(<span>= [,,,,,,1,,,2,3,4,,,,,,] [1 2 3 4]</span>)</span> =&gt; true</tt></pre>
<p>Maybe this is to make up for removing the extra grouping parentheses in <tt>let</tt>, <tt>cond</tt> and map literal syntax?  With commas you can add back some clarity about which items belong together.  Rarely anybody uses commas in real code, though.  And since it's optional it doesn't make much sense.</p>
<p>This has an annoying ripple effect on quasiquotation.  Due to this decision, a different character has to be used for <tt>unquote</tt>, because the comma was already taken:</p>
<pre><tt>`<span>(<span>1 2 ~<span>(<span>+ 1 2</span>)</span></span>)</span> =&gt; <span>(<span>1 2 3</span>)</span>
`<span>(<span>1 2 ~@<span>(<span>list 3 4</span>)</span></span>)</span> =&gt; <span>(<span>1 2 3 4</span>)</span></tt></pre>
<p>This might seem like a small issue, but it is an unnecessary and stupid distraction.</p><a href="#minimalism">
<h2 id="minimalism">Minimalism</h2></a>
<p>One of the main reasons I enjoy Scheme so much is its goal of minimalism.  This is achieved through elegant building blocks.  This is embodied by the <a href="https://schemers.org/Documents/Standards/R5RS/HTML/r5rs-Z-H-3.html#%_chap_Temp_3">Prime Clingerism</a>:</p>
<pre><tt>  Programming languages should be designed not by piling feature on
  top of feature, but by removing the weaknesses and restrictions
  that make additional features appear necessary.</tt></pre>
<p>Let's check the size of the <tt>clojure.core</tt> library.  It clocks in at 640 identifiers (v1.10.1), which is a lot more than R5RS Scheme's 218 identifiers.  It's not an entirely fair comparison as Scheme without SRFI-1 or SRFI-43 or an FFI has much less functionality as well. Therefore, I think Clojure's core library is fairly small but not exactly an exercise in minimalism.</p>
<p>Clojure reduces its API size considerably by having a "<a href="https://clojure.org/reference/sequences">sequence</a> abstraction". This is similar to Common Lisp's sequences: you can call <tt>map</tt>, <tt>filter</tt> or <tt>length</tt> on any sequence-type object: lists, vectors, strings and even maps (which are treated as key/value pairs). However, it is less hacky than in Common Lisp because for example with <tt>map</tt> you don't need to specify which kind of sequence you want to get back.  I get the impression that in Common Lisp this abstraction is not very prominent or used often but in Clojure <i>everything</i> uses sequences.  What I also liked is that sequences can be <i>lazy</i>, which removes the need for special operators as well.</p>
<p>If you compare this to Scheme, you have special-purpose procedures for every concrete type: <tt>length</tt>, <tt>vector-length</tt>, <tt>string-length</tt> etc.  And there's no <tt>vector-map</tt> in the standard, so you need <a href="https://srfi.schemers.org/srfi-43/srfi-43.html#vector-map"><tt>vector-map</tt> from SRFI 43</a>.  Lazy lists are a <a href="https://srfi.schemers.org/srfi-41/srfi-41.html">separate type</a> with its own set of specialized operators.  And so on and so forth.  Using concrete types everywhere provides for less abstract and confusing code and the performance characteristics of an algorithm tend to be clearer, but it also leads to a massive growth in library size.</p>
<p>After a while I really started noticing mistakes that make additional features appear necessary: for example, there's a special macro called <tt>loop</tt> to make tail recursive calls.  This uses a keyword <tt>recur</tt> to call back into the loop.  In Scheme, you would do that with a named <tt>let</tt> where you can choose your own identifier to recur.  It's also not possible to nest such Clojure loops, because the identifier is hardcoded.  So, this called for adding <a href="https://archive.clojure.org/design-wiki/display/design/Named%2Bloops%2Bwith%2Brecur-to.html">another feature</a>, which is currently in proposal.  Speaking of <tt>recur</tt>, it is also used for tail recursive self-calls.  It relies on the programmer rather than the compiler to mark calls as tail recursive. I find this a bit of a cop-out, especially in a language that is so heavily functional.  Especially since this doesn't work for mutually tail-recursive functions.  The <a href="https://www.windley.com/archives/2008/11/tail_optimized_mutual_recursion_in_clojure.shtml">official way to do those</a> is even more of a crutch.</p>
<p>I find the special syntax for one-off lambdas <tt>#(foo %)</tt> just as misguided as <a href="https://srfi.schemers.org/srfi-26/srfi-26.html">SRFI 26</a> (<tt>cut</tt> and <tt>cute</tt>).  You often end up needing to tweak the code in such a way that you have …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.more-magic.net/posts/thoughts-on-clojure.html">https://www.more-magic.net/posts/thoughts-on-clojure.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.more-magic.net/posts/thoughts-on-clojure.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26356367</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 13:01:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bring Your Own Client]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 522 | Comments 243 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26355779">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://www.geoffreylitt.com/2021/03/05/bring-your-own-client.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.geoffreylitt.com/2021/03/05/bring-your-own-client.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Just a little note about the main problem I'm pondering these days...</p><div><p>It’s delightful to have the freedom to <strong>Bring Your Own Client (BYOC)</strong>: to choose your favorite application to interact with some data.</p>

<p>For example, I can program with Sublime Text, while my teammate uses vim, and we don’t need to fight to the death to pick one editor between us. There are dozens of text editors to choose from, and no lock-in from proprietary file formats.</p>

<p>Contrast this with Google Docs: in order to live collaborate with each other, we all need to use the same editor. For someone who spends their whole working day in Google Docs, this can be a serious limitation. I personally hate doing substantial writing in Google Docs.</p>

<p>In cloud apps, the live collaboration logic is usually coupled to a specific editor; even if Google wanted to expose an API for editing Google Docs in third-party editors, it would probably be very challenging. The situation is nicer with text editors and git, because editing is decoupled from collaboration logic. Our team only needs to agree on a version control solution, which exposes a simple API (local text files) that many editors can interact with.</p>

<p>To be fair, local vs cloud isn’t the only factor here—even in local software, collaborators are often forced to converge on a single proprietary client (Microsoft Office, Adobe suite); conversely, a cloud service can support a third-party client ecosystem with the right APIs and attitude. Still, cloud apps exacerbate the problem. With local files, there’s some default openness built in; even proprietary file formats can be reverse-engineered. With cloud apps, the default is a single official client, unless the service actively exposes an API (and doesn’t shut it down—looking at you, Twitter).</p>

<p>It seems like local-first software is a good foundation for promoting Bring Your Own Client more broadly. What would it look like to have a thriving ecosystem of third-party clients for Google Docs style word processing, which can all interoperate with each other, even supporting realtime collaboration?</p>

<h2 id="concrete-examples">Concrete examples</h2>

<p>Some successful existing examples of client ecosystems built around open standards:</p>

<ul>
<li>text editors / IDE</li>
<li>RSS readers</li>
<li>email clients</li>
<li>web browsers</li>
</ul>

<p>Places where I want to have BYOC:</p>

<ul>
<li>Google Docs. I wish I could write this very doc in my preferred editor, locally, but have also support for inline comments and live collaboration. Might it be possible to build a VSCode extension that edits Google Docs live? (Tricky, because Google doesn’t have a nice API to integrate with, but maybe doable)</li>
<li>Google Slides</li>
<li>Figma</li>
<li>Notion</li>
<li>Trello / Asana / shared todo lists</li>
<li>multiplayer code editor: live collaboration as in repl.it</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="finer-granularity">Finer granularity</h2>

<p>Today we generally think about BYOC at the “app” level. But can we go finer-grained than that, picking individual interface elements?</p>

<p>Instead of needing to pick a single email client, can I compose my favorite email client out of an inbox, a compose window, and a spam filter?</p>

<h2 id="problems-questions">Problems / questions</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Schema compatibility</strong>: do all the editors need to agree on a single rigidly specified format? If there are reconcilable differences between formats, can we build “live converters” that convert between them on every change? (Essentially, imagine collaborating between Pages and Microsoft Word, running a file export in both directions on every keystroke from either app) This problem is closely related to the problem of schema versioning within a single editor, but BYOC can complicate things much further.</li>
<li><strong>Preserving intent</strong>: the decoupling of git + text editors has a downside: the text format fails to capture the intent of edits, so git can’t be very smart about merging conflicts. Is this something fundamental to decoupling editors from collaboration? Or are there ways to design APIs that preserve intent better, while also supporting an open client ecosystem? (It seems like deciding on how you store your data in a CRDT is the key question here?)</li>
<li><strong>Additional editor-specific metadata</strong>: Some editors need to store additional data that isn’t part of the “core data model.” Eg, Sublime Text stores my <code>.sublime-workspace</code> file alongside the code source. How does this work smoothly without polluting the data being used by other editors?</li>
<li><strong>Code distribution</strong>: Traditionally code distribution happens through centralized means, but could code be distributed in a decentralized way alongside documents? If we’re collaborating together in a doc, can I directly share a little editor widget/tool that I’m using, without needing to send you a Github link? This might be overcomplicating things / orthogonal to the general idea here… (This idea inspired by <a href="https://webstrates.net/">Webstrates</a>, linked below)</li>
<li><strong>Innovation</strong>: Unfortunately stable open formats can limit product innovation—eg, email clients are tied down by adherence to the email standard. Can we mitigate that effect? I think web browsers have struck a good balance between progress and openness, despite frustrations in both directions.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="addendum-faq">Addendum: FAQ</h2>

<p><em>Edited 2020-03-05: This post unexpectedly got popular on HN. As I drink my morning coffee, I’ll briefly respond to a few themes from the comments here.</em></p>

<p><strong>Q: Don’t standards make it harder to innovate?</strong></p>

<p>A: Yes, that’s a major challenge. For example, email and IRC have lagged behind Slack and Reddit, because it’s hard to change standards. We discussed this problem a bit in the <a href="https://www.inkandswitch.com/cambria.html#mastodon-protocol-evolution">Cambria paper, re: Mastodon</a>.</p>

<p>I think the key is to aim for more flexible and extensible standards: a useful 80% compatibility, rather than a perfect 100%.</p>

<p>Of course, once you abandon an exact standard, it’s easy to rack up tons of complexity. (I think the Semantic Web struggled with this problem trying to provide schema flexibility.) So we also need better tools to make partial compatibility easy to reason about, for both developers and users.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Hmm. 80% compatibility sounds like kind of a buggy mess? Word and OpenOffice don’t interop very well.</strong></p>

<p>A: I think with the right foundational tech for helping devs build maximally compatible formats, we can avoid the worst problems of incorrect format conversions. In the Cambria paper we sketched <a href="https://www.inkandswitch.com/cambria.html#lenses-in-action">a few examples</a> of partial compatibility, where Cambria guaranteed type safety and helped us easily avoid bugs.</p>

<p>That does leave a substantial design problem, though: even if everything works correctly, what do you show the <em>user</em> when two pieces of software aren’t fully compatible? How do you tell a user that their actions might show up differently for collaborators using different apps? I’m thinking a lot about these questions…</p>

<p><strong>Q: Cloud business models are so entrenched. Can this actually happen without government intervention?</strong></p>

<p>A:  It’s true that business incentives are a major challenge. Maybe some form of government intervention could help, but ultimately it’ll be fighting a headwind unless users and devs are excited for the change.</p>

<p>I think the most sustainable way to make progress is to make BYOC the most convenient option, for the typical user and the typical developer. On the desktop, it’s convenient for a developer to work with the user’s existing filesystem. On the web today, there’s no user-controlled filesystem, so it’s usually easiest to just put the data in a database, and add a ticket to the backlog for someday building a public-facing API. How would that change if we had a convenient user-controlled place to put data?</p>

<p>See the <a href="https://www.inkandswitch.com/local-first.html">local-first software</a> article by Ink &amp; Switch for some ideas on how new data architectures can make the right thing the easy thing, for both users and devs.</p>

<h2 id="prior-art">Prior Art</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://webstrates.net/">Webstrates</a> has some great demos of this philosophy. It uses a centralized server for the live sync.</li>
<li>Webstrates descends from Michel Beaudouin-Lafon’s work on <a href="https://youtu.be/ntaudUum06E?t=727">instrumental interfaces</a>—"polymorphic" tools that can operate in different applications. For example, a color picker that I can use in any app.</li>
<li>The <a href="https://solidproject.org/">SOLID</a> decentralized web project has some closely related ideas: <a href="https://ruben.verborgh.org/blog/2017/12/20/paradigm-shifts-for-the-decentralized-web/#apps-become-views">“apps become views”</a>, creating a competitive marketplace of clients decoupled from data silos. In turn it’s heavily inspired by ideas from the Semantic Web.</li>
<li><a href="https://mashable.com/2009/05/28/google-wave-guide/">Google Wave</a> had some related ideas… A platform for realtime collaboration, with a rich open <a href="https://youtu.be/v_UyVmITiYQ?t=4207">extension API</a> intended for people to build various collaboration clients on top of. Seems like the common wisdom on why it failed is that it was <a href="https://gizmodo.com/what-in-the-hell-was-google-wave-trying-to-be-anyway-1835038967">too complicated</a> and tried to do too much.</li>
<li><a href="https://braid.news/">Braid</a> is exploring ways to extend HTTP to support collaborative editing across diverse clients.</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>I believe one piece of the puzzle here is declarative schema mapping, for example the <a href="https://www.inkandswitch.com/cambria.html">Cambria</a> project I worked on recently.</li>
<li>Granular BYOC starts to look like <a href="https://www.geoffreylitt.com/2020/07/19/tools-over-apps-for-personal-notetaking.html">software as curation</a>: assembling software out of smaller “extensions”</li>
<li>Also relates to document-centric computing ideas like OpenDoc. Some <a href="https://twitter.com/geoffreylitt/status/1362779218241855494">recent notes</a> I took on why that failed…</li>
<li>Part of the solution may involve extracting and synchronizing data from cloud services without going through official APIs, as demonstrated in my <a href="https://www.geoffreylitt.com/wildcard">Wildcard</a> project.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="im-working-on-this">I’m working on this!</h2>

<p>I’m currently pursuing a PhD at MIT doing research on this topic. Lots of challenges and open questions ahead, but I have some ideas for how to make progress. I’m particularly excited about clever ways to incrementally nudge us from the status quo to a BYOC world, rather than reinventing everything.</p>

<p>If you want to follow along with future updates, you can subscribe via the links below.</p>

<p>And if you have ideas about this topic or want to chat, feel free to <a href="mailto:gklitt@gmail.com">get in touch</a>.</p>

<h2 id="ps-idea-incubation">PS: idea incubation</h2>

<p>I actually wrote this note 10 months ago and had totally forgotten about it.</p>

<p>An hour ago, I randomly came across it and was quite amused. It includes some ideas which I <em>thought</em> I had started thinking about only recently. But it turns out they’ve been incubating in my mind for a long time. Funny how that works!</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.geoffreylitt.com/2021/03/05/bring-your-own-client.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26355779</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 11:47:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Clothing, How Did They Make It? Part I: High Fiber]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26355046">thread link</a>) | @CapitalistCartr
<br/>
March 5, 2021 | https://acoup.blog/2021/03/05/collections-clothing-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-high-fiber/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2021/03/05/collections-clothing-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-high-fiber/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>This week we are starting the first of a four (?) part look at pre-modern textile production.  As with our series on <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/24/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-farmers/">farming </a>and <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/09/18/collections-iron-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-mining/">iron</a>, we are going to follow the sequence of production from the growing of fibers all the way to the finished object, with a focus not merely on the methods of production but also <em>on the people doing the producing</em> at each stage of production.  Now while I have titled this series, “Clothing, How Did They Make It?” it is worth noting that textiles were used for a lot more than just clothing.  All sorts of household goods were produced this way.  In addition, of course, clothing was sometimes made out of non-textile materials (although, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/12/04/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-i-barbarian-couture/">as we’ve discussed</a>, far less often than is portrayed in popular culture; in Eurasia, by and large, clothing meant textiles).  <strong>But what we are going to focus on here is really <em>textiles</em></strong> and (of course) the people that make them.  Leather working will have to wait for another day.</p>



<p>That said, even within textiles, to try to keep the scope manageable<strong> I am going to narrow things down further, by focusing on just two major fibers: wool and flax</strong> (which makes linen) and thus <strong>mostly focus on how this worked in the Mediterranean</strong>, broadly construed (so the Near East, North Africa and Europe).  I am choosing these two fibers because they dominate in locally produced textiles in the Near East and Europe for much of the pre-modern period.  Cotton, another important fiber, only seems to have been cultivated in Egypt in the Roman period (though, as far as I can tell, at some point Egyptian cotton cultivation seems to have largely dropped off, only to boom again in the Early Modern though this is a point about which I can express little confidence in my knowledge) and for much of Europe remained an expensive import fiber through the Middle Ages, transported from South Asia.  Likewise, silk remained in the pre-modern period almost entirely an expensive import good from far to the East of the Mediterranean.  Of course any import good must be local somewhere, but my expertise in pre-modern textile production does not extend so far into South or East Asia, so the task of laying that out must fall to someone else.  We will talk a <em>bit</em> about these fibers as they arrive in the Mediterranean as trade goods, but mostly stay focused on wool and flax.</p>



<p>The very rarity of these goods in the Near East and Europe confined them to the upper-classes, while wool and linen often remained the everyday fibers (though even the very wealthy used textiles of high quality wool and linen as well) and so saw a lot more use.  More importantly to our investigation here, for the ancient Mediterranean (where my knowledge is best) wool and linen were <em>by far</em> the fibers most involved in the household textile production.  Of course other fibers were used locally in the Mediterranean as well – hemp, nettle and even tree-bast, but the vast majority of<strong> textiles being produced in the broader Mediterranean world were wool and linen and so we are going to focus on that.</strong></p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="6453" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/616302001/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg" data-orig-size="2218,1817" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="616302001" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=2048 2048w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/616302001.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/G_1814-0704-573">From the British Museum</a>, a fourth century bell krater depicting the Judgement of Paris (which in turn leads to the Trojan War).  Paris, at the time, was living in exile as a shepherd – the occupation notable because of its lowly status.  Here he is seen seated with his shepherd’s crook (the standing male figure is Hermes); the animal below Paris is a sheep (you can see the twisted horns; to the right is a dog, presumably assisting in the herding.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Worry not, we will have more than enough to talk about with just those two fibers.  This week, we’re going to focus just on producing the raw fibers – how flax is farmed and how wool is produced from sheep.  Next week, we’ll look at the long process of taking those raw fibers, processing them and spinning them into thread.  The week after that, we’ll look at weaving as well as dying, bleaching and other color treatments treatments.  Then finally in the last week, we’ll look at finally sewing but also at markets and trade. <strong> As always, we’ll try to direct attention not only to the processes, but also to the workers who <em>performed</em> those processes and their place in the broader society.</strong></p>



<p>And that brings us to the second reason to discuss textile production, which is that in the broader pre-modern Mediterranean <strong>much of the textile production</strong> <strong>was done within the household and nearly all of that household production was done by women</strong>.  Now as we’ll see, household spinning, weaving and sewing is by no means the only jobs involved in the production of the clothes that say an Egyptian, Babylonian, Roman or early Medieval European family would wear and some important stages of production here were also generally done by men.  As I have mentioned before, the literary sources for the pre-modern world generally prefer to talk about individuals who are rich, male, and free, but as we will see, the workers involved in each stage of textile production are almost never rich, frequently not male and sometimes not free.  Nevertheless investigating textile production gives us a chance to peer into parts of the lives of some historical subjects that we very rarely hear about: women (rich and poor, slave and free), along with enslaved or poor men doing work that left them well outside of the ‘polite society’ of our literary sources.</p>



<p>I should note at the beginning that while I am going to try to keep this discussion general and at points cover technological or regional variations in how textiles in wool and linen were made, in practice a lot of what I am going to write here is going to reflect in particular practice during the Roman period (especially the period of the Republic) and even more specifically than that in Roman Italy, simply because that is where my own specialist knowledge is best.  Consult your friendly neighborhood primary sources when looking to apply these systems on a wider basis either geographically or chronologically!</p>



<p>As always, if you like what you are reading here, please share it; if you really like it, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>. And if you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or military history musings.</p>






<p>(<strong>Bibliography Note:</strong> For the sake of keeping these posts readable, especially since I don’t have a footnote function here, I am not going to laboriously cite everything at each point of reference, but instead I’m going to include a short selected bibliography here up front for the whole series.  For the beginner looking to get their feet under themselves when it comes to pre-modern textile production, E.W. Barber, <em>Women’s Work: The First 20,000 Years, Women, Cloth and Society in Early Times</em> (1994) is the standard starting point.  Also note E.W. Barber, <em>Prehistoric Textiles: The Development of Cloth in the Neolithic and Bronze Ages with Special Reference to the Aegean</em> (1991).  More specific to the Romans, M. Gleba, <em>Textile Production in Pre-Roman Italy</em> (2008) is an indispensable book which gathers together a lot of the quite technical investigation – often done by archaeologists rather than historians because the literary record on textile production can be quite disappointing – in a fairly easy to read location.  Several of the essays in M. Gleba and J. Pásztókai-Szeöke <em>Making Textiles in Pre-Roman Times and Roman Times: People, Places, Identities</em> (2013), while more technical in nature, were also useful here, especially on the question of who did this sort of thing.  Also on this point, L. L. Lovén, <em>The Imagery of Textile Making: Gender and Status in the Funerary Iconography of Textile Manufacture in Roman Italy and Gaul</em> (2002).  On textile production for soldiers, note in the Greek context G.S. Aldrete, S. Bartel and A. Aldrete, <em>Reconstructing Ancient Linen Body Armor: Unraveling the Linothorax Mystery</em>(2013) which also has some very useful time-labor study data; for Roman soldiers note the essays in M.L. Nosch ed., <em>Wearing the Cloak: Dressing the Soldier in Roman Times</em> (2012) and G. Sumner, <em>Roman Military Dress </em>(2009).  On the cloth trade in medieval Europe, I’ve relied heavily on J.S. Lee, <em>The Medieval Clothier</em> (2018).</p>



<p>If it sounds like pre-modern textile production is one of those fields that is only now, somewhat belatedly receiving the attention it has long deserved, that is by and large correct!  As you can see, compared to the discussion of farming or iron-working, the key references here are often decades younger (one is left to assume that it is something to do with the fact that this work was largely done by women that led to it being so late to receive its due study).  Fortunately, archaeology is giving us a lot of the evidence that our literary sources don’t, especially for the ancient world, which has enabled a lot of this work.  May it continue!)</p>



<h2>Meet the Fibers! Flax and Linen</h2>



<p>Linen fabrics are produced from the fibers of the flax plant, <em>Linum usitatissimum</em>.  This common flax plant is the domesticated version of the wild <em>Linum bienne</em>, domesticated in the northern part of the fertile crescent no later than 7,000 BC, although wild flax fibers were being used to produce textiles even earlier than that. Consequently the use of linen fibers goes <em><strong>way </strong></em>back. In fact, the oldest known textiles are made from flax, including finds of fibers at Nahal Hemar (7th millennium BC), Çayönü (c. 7000 BC), and Çatalhöyük (c. 6000 BC). Evidence for the cultivation of flax goes back even further, with linseed from Tell Asward in Syria dating to the 8th millennium BC. Flax was being cultivated in Central Europe no later than the second half of the 7th millennium BC.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="6451" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088.jpg" data-orig-size="439,591" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088.jpg?w=223" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088.jpg?w=439" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088.jpg?w=439" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088.jpg 439w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088.jpg?w=111 111w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/linum_usitatissimum_-_kohlere28093s_medizinal-pflanzen-088.jpg?w=223 223w" sizes="(max-width: 439px) 100vw, 439px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flax">Via Wikipedia</a>, the flax plant, showing the seeds and – more importantly for our purpose – the stalk which, when fully grown contains the bast fibers used to make linen.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Flax is a productive little plant that produces two main …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2021/03/05/collections-clothing-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-high-fiber/">https://acoup.blog/2021/03/05/collections-clothing-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-high-fiber/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2021/03/05/collections-clothing-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-high-fiber/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26355046</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Stability of Fixed Points of High Dimensional Dynamical Systems]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26352308">thread link</a>) | @adipandas
<br/>
March 4, 2021 | https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2021/03/fixed-point-high-dim/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2021/03/fixed-point-high-dim/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><header><p> 5 minute read</p><p><strong> Published:</strong> <time datetime="2021-03-04T00:00:00-08:00">March 04, 2021</time></p></header><section itemprop="text"><p>In the <a href="https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2020/02/stable-unstable-fixed-point/">previous post</a>, I discussed the basics regarding the stability of fixed points of a dynamical system and explained it with a simple continuous-time one-dimensional example. In this post, I will discuss fixed points for a general case of a continuous-time $n$-dimensional system.</p><h4 id="fixed-point">Fixed point</h4><p>Just to reiterate, if the ordinary differential equation (ODE) in $\eqref{eq:1}$ represents a dynamical system:</p>\[\dot x = f(x) \label{eq:1}\]<p>Fixed points of this system are given by the roots of the equation $\eqref{eq:2}$:</p>\[\begin{equation} \dot x = f(x) = 0 \label{eq:2} \end{equation}\]<h2 id="fixed-points-of-multi-dimensional-system">Fixed points of Multi-dimensional system</h2><p>My <a href="https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2020/02/stable-unstable-fixed-point/">previous post</a> only explained the definition of fixed point and provided an example with a scalar-valued dynamical system. Now, lets discuss a case of multi-dimensional ODE.</p><p>We will start with the system given by equation $\eqref{eq:3}$:</p>\[\mathbf{\dot x} = \mathbf{f(x)} \label{eq:3}\]<p>where $\mathbf{f}$ is a vector-valued function, $\mathbf{x}$ and $\mathbf{\dot x}$ are $n$-dimensional vectors:</p>\[\mathbf{x, \dot x} \in \mathcal{R}^{n} \label{eq:4}\]<p>We find the fixed points (a.k.a. equilibrium states) of the system by following $\eqref{eq:2}$:</p>\[\mathbf{\dot x_{eq}} = \mathbf{f}(\mathbf{x_{eq}}) = \mathbf{0} \label{eq:5}\]<p>The roots of $\eqref{eq:5}$ will give us the value of $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$, i.e., fixed points of our multi-dimensional system.</p><h2 id="stable-and-unstable-fixed-points">Stable and Unstable Fixed Points</h2><p>We analyzed the system in a one-dimensional case (<a href="https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2020/02/stable-unstable-fixed-point/">here</a>) using a small perturbation $\delta$ at the equilibrium condition of the system. We will follow the similar procedure here as well.</p><p>We evaluated $\mathbf{f}^{\prime}\mathbf{(x)}$ at $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$ to see if our fixed point is stable or unstable. In case of one-dimensional system, it was easy since $f^{\prime}(x_{eq})&gt;0$ is unstable fixed point $x_{eq}$ while it is stable when $f^{\prime}(x_{eq})&lt;0$. In case of high-dimensional system, we cannot do this.</p><p>To analyze the behavior of our $n$-dimensional system at $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$, we will introduce the perturbation $\mathbf{\delta x}$ at $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$. Thus, we end up with the following:</p>\[\begin{align} \mathbf{\dot x_{eq} + \dot {\delta x}} &amp;= \mathbf{f(x_{eq}+\delta x)} \label{eq:6} \end{align}\]<p>Using Taylor expansion on $\eqref{eq:6}$:</p>\[\begin{align} \mathbf{\dot x_{eq} + \delta \dot x = f(x_{eq}) + f^{\prime}(x_{eq}) \delta x + f^{\prime \prime}(x_{eq}) \frac{\delta x^2}{2!} + \dots} \label{eq:7} \end{align}\]<p>But, we know at fixed points, equation $\eqref{eq:5}$ holds and thus, $\eqref{eq:7}$ reduces to $\eqref{eq:8}$.</p>\[\begin{align} \mathbf{ \delta \dot x = f^{\prime}(x_{eq}) \delta x + f^{\prime\prime}(x_{eq}) \frac{\delta x^2}{2!} + \dots} \end{align}\] \[\mathbf{ \delta \dot x = f^{\prime}(x_{eq}) \delta x + H.O.T. \label{eq:8}}\]<p>We can ignore the higher order terms $\mathbf{H.O.T.}$ for values of $\mathbf{\delta{x}}$ close to $\mathbf{0}$, resulting in equation $\eqref{eq:9}$.</p>\[\begin{align} \mathbf{\delta \dot x = f^{\prime}(x_{eq}) \delta x \label{eq:9}} \end{align}\]<p>$\mathbf{f}^{\prime}\mathbf{(x)}$ is the Jacobian of $\mathbf{f(x)}$ at $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$, i.e., a <strong>linear approximation</strong> of our dynamical system $\mathbf{f(x)}$ near $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$ (you can refer <a href="https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2020/03/vector-calculus/#jacobian-aka-derivative-of-vector-valued-function">this</a> for further details on Jacobian).</p>\[\begin{align} \mathbf{f}^{\prime}\mathbf{(x)} &amp;= \left[ \frac{\partial\mathbf{f}}{\partial x_{1}}, \frac{\partial\mathbf{f}}{\partial x_{2}}, \dots, \frac{\partial\mathbf{f}}{\partial x_{n}} \right] \label{eq:11}\\ \mathbf{f}^{\prime}\mathbf{(x)} &amp;= \begin{bmatrix} \frac{\partial{f_{1}}}{\partial x_{1}} &amp; \frac{\partial{f_{2}}}{\partial x_{2}} &amp; \dots &amp; \frac{\partial{f_{n}}}{\partial x_{n}}\\ \vdots &amp; \ddots &amp; \ddots &amp; \vdots \\ \frac{\partial{f_{n}}}{\partial x_{1}} &amp; \frac{\partial{f_{n}}}{\partial x_{2}} &amp; \dots &amp; \frac{\partial{f_{n}}}{\partial x_{n}}\\ \end{bmatrix} \label{eq:12} \end{align}\]<p>Using this Jacobian, equation $\eqref{eq:12}$, at our fixed point $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$ for the dynamical system under consideration, we can calculate its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eigenvalues_and_eigenvectors"><strong>eigenvalues</strong></a> and interpret the results of the fixed point.</p><p>Therefore, we find the eigenvalues for equation $\eqref{eq:13}$,</p>\[\begin{align} \mathbf{f}^{\prime}(\mathbf{x_{eq}}) \mathbf{x_{eq}} = \lambda \mathbf{x_{eq}} \label{eq:13} \end{align}\]<p>Here, $\lambda$ denotes the eigenvalue of the system. The roots of $\eqref{eq:13}$ are the eigenvalues the dynamical system at the fixed point $\mathbf{x}=\mathbf{x_{eq}}$.</p><h3 id="eigenvalue-interpretation-">Eigenvalue interpretation <a name="eigen_value_interpretation"></a></h3><p>For a continuous-time nonlinear dynamical system given by $\eqref{eq:3}$, the eigenvalues $\lambda$ that are found as roots of equation $\eqref{eq:13}$ can be interpreted as:</p><ul><li>If any of the eigenvalues have a real part $Re(\lambda)&gt;0$: $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$ is an unstable fixed point.</li><li>If all $Re(\lambda)&lt;0$: $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$ is a stable fixed point.</li><li>If $\lambda=0$: $\mathbf{x_{eq}}$ is a neutral fixed point.</li><li>If eigenvalues $\lambda$ are complex conjugates, i.e., $Im(\lambda) \ne 0$: The dynamical system has oscillatory behavior around the fixed point.</li></ul><h3 id="important-points-to-note-regarding-this-article">Important points to note regarding this article</h3><p>In this post, we discussed a general case of interpreting the fixed points of a dynamical system. By general, I mean $\mathbf{f(x)}$ is a non-linear, continuous-time vector-valued function representing a dynamical system. Below are certain points one should note about any non-linear dynamical system:</p><ul><li>We assumed that the system is non-linear and linearized it using Taylor series expansion near its fixed point (a.k.a. equilibrium).</li><li>We evaluated the stability of a fixed point <strong>near</strong> the equilibrium condition by perturbing the system ($\mathbf{x_{eq}}+\mathbf{\delta x}$).</li><li>This approach of interpreting the stability of the system by linearizing it near the equilibrium <strong>does not tell much</strong> about a system’s asymptotic behavior at large.<ul><li>We only understand how the system behaves <strong>locally</strong> or <strong>in the neighborhood of the fixed points</strong>.</li></ul></li><li>In practical or real-world systems, it may not be possible to interpret the global stability characteristics of the system. Thus, the stability analysis around the neighborhood of the fixed point is useful for many practical applications such as sustaining a non-linear system’s state near or at the fixed point.</li><li>In general, global asymptotic behaviors of any non-linear dynamical system can be complex and there are no systematic methods to predict and analyze such behaviors.</li></ul><h3 id="references-and-further-readings">References and Further Readings:</h3><ul><li>Deshpande, A. M. Stablility of Fixed Point of a Dynamical System. [<a href="https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2020/02/stable-unstable-fixed-point/">web</a>]</li><li>Strogatz, Steven H. Nonlinear dynamics and chaos with student solutions manual: With applications to physics, biology, chemistry, and engineering. CRC press, 2018.</li><li>Khalil, Hassan K. “Lyapunov stability.” <em>Control Systems, Robotics and AutomatioN–Volume XII: Nonlinear, Distributed, and Time Delay Systems-I</em> (2009): 115.</li><li>Bomze, Immanuel M., and Jörgen W. Weibull. “Does neutral stability imply Lyapunov stability?.” <em>Games and Economic Behavior</em> 11.2 (1995): 173-192.</li><li>Fixed point. [<a href="https://mathworld.wolfram.com/FixedPoint.html">web</a>]</li><li>Jacobian matrix [<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bohL918kXQk">video</a>]</li><li>Stability Theory. [<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stability_theory">web</a>]</li><li>Lyapunov Stability. [<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lyapunov_stability">web</a>]</li></ul></section><!--<nav class="pagination"> <a href="https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2020/03/vector-calculus/" class="pagination--pager" title="Notes on Vector Calculus ">Previous</a> <a href="https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2021/03/biasvariancetradeoff/" class="pagination--pager" title="Bias, Variance and Trade-off ">Next</a></nav>--></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://adipandas.github.io/posts/2021/03/fixed-point-high-dim/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26352308</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 03:38:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
