<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:25:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 08:25:22 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Feedback Loop of Productivity]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24458482">thread link</a>) | @root993
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://www.sankalpjonna.com/posts/the-feedback-loop-of-productivity | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.sankalpjonna.com/posts/the-feedback-loop-of-productivity">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Being productive all the time is not just difficult, it might actually burn you out, but that being said lack of productivity for an extended period of time is dangerous too because it gives the mind an excuse to start looking at all the negative things happening in the world, especially with the global pandemic going on. </p><p>So how does one stay productive consistently? I find that the only way to be productive is through feedback. To be productive you need to receive a small but noticeable reward for attempting to be productive. If that did not make any sense, let me try and explain it with an example.</p><p><strong>Kickstarting the loop</strong></p><p><strong>‍</strong><br></p><p>I wanted to write a piece of content today because I have not written anything in a long period of time. Once this piece is out there on a few social media platforms, I might see a small but noticeable spike in the traffic to my blog which I can confirm from my good friend google analytics. This little spike in traffic is my tiny reward which will kick start a feedback loop.</p><p>Now there is higher likelihood that I will try and write some more content next week because I still remember the feeling of that reward and I want to feel it again, but the difference now is that I have built a tolerance for this reward and the only way I would feel satisfied is if I receive a higher reward which in this case might translate to a higher spike in google analytics.</p><p><strong>Add incremental steps to the loop</strong></p><p><strong>‍</strong><br></p><p>To receive a higher reward I am now motivated to write better quality content which reaches a wider group of audience and what gets even better is if people start engaging with me after reading my post and wish to dwell further into the subject. </p><p>If I can keep this up every week while slightly increasing the quantum of work but also the quantum of reward, eventually it becomes a habit that I can no longer ignore.</p><p><strong>Use the feedback loop for everything</strong></p><p><strong>‍</strong><br></p><p>I build software, so for me the feedback loop translates to building a small software module that does one particular task, run a few tests on it to see if it functions like it should and this will kick start the feedback loop. I feel rewarded that I built one tiny part of a large project which works perfectly and is ready to be integrated with the rest of the project.</p><p>Incremental steps can then be added by combining different modules with each other and making them work together. The loop becomes much stronger once there is an actual visual component to look at and interact with because at this point you have basically created something tangible and the reward you get from that lasts much longer than the smaller rewards.</p><p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p><p><strong>‍</strong><br></p><p>It is entirely possible that I put out this piece of content today and nobody cares. Maybe I do not see any spike in google analytics at all. But the very fact that I managed to write something today and share it a few people who are at the very least likely to give it a read creates a feeling of accomplishment which serves as a small reward to kick start the feedback loop. </p><p>Sometimes the reward is not as great as expected but as long as it is not zero, the loop is strong enough to get you going.</p><p>‍</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.sankalpjonna.com/posts/the-feedback-loop-of-productivity</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24458482</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 04:55:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Together vs. Alone: Thoughts on building a team]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24458258">thread link</a>) | @grwthckrmstr
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/building-a-team | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/building-a-team">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>We live in an incredible time in human history where the basic infrastructure for many of us is so good.</p><p>In today’s world it is possible to get ahead and achieve a lot all by yourself. You can be a writer with 1mn readers, a social media star with 1mn followers, or a SaaS business with $1mn in ARR.&nbsp;</p><p>That’s the mindset Sankalp and I both embodied when we first started on our journey. We had faith that just the 2 of us working together towards our shared goal is enough to get us really far.</p><p>Thankfully that faith turned into reality and lead to the success of SuperLemon.</p><h3>Challenging our beliefs</h3><p>But any great mindset or philosophy is only as great as the people who practice it, and people are always evolving and getting better. Mindset and philosophy evolves too.</p><p>The people in our lives who believed in us and wanted us to do even better challenged us on our beliefs of doing things amongst just the 2 of us.</p><p>One of them said - we are setting small goals, because we are afraid of hiring. If we had the confidence that we can put together a great team, we would think bigger and set higher goals.</p><p>We knew in our hearts that the challenge was genuine. Due to our poor experiences with hiring in the past, we started favouring the path of least resistance, which is to not try to hire anyone. Automatically our goals would only be as lofty as how much the two of us can achieve together. </p><p>We had to change this about ourselves. And so we immediately set out to <a href="https://twitter.com/hipreetam93/status/1296089975818055680" target="_blank">hire someone amazing</a> into our team. It was an exercise to prove to ourselves that we have what it takes to do this.</p><h3>An updated mindset</h3><p>Less than a month later, we hired an amazing <a href="https://twitter.com/akashjdotcom" target="_blank">first engineer</a> and have made an offer to another. This exercise has turned out way better than we anticipated, and it did exactly what it was supposed to do. It allowed us to dream bigger.</p><p>Our mindset and philosophy has thus been updated - We can get far in today’s world just by ourselves, but if we want to get really really far with our next venture <a href="https://delight.chat/" target="_blank">Delight.chat</a>, we need more than just the two of us.&nbsp;</p><p>While we suddenly haven't started wanting to build a 400 person company, our mindset has evolved enough to accept and understand how building a team of 5-15 people could produce a 100x result of what we had previously set out to achieve.</p><h3>People on the inside</h3><p>We need people on the inside (a team) who are aligned with our shared vision, and working together using their mind and abilities towards achieving that goal. </p><p>It's not just having more hands in the engineering team in building the product, or marketing team in creating content or distribution channels.</p><p>Their consciousness, ideas, problem solving abilities, attitude and values get added into a collective pool with our own. The sum is greater than the parts.</p><p>The people joining our team are entrepreneurial minds whose values align with ours, who want to build and grow something new and challenging from the ground up, learn from the experience, and eventually start their own companies. We will be their first supporters when they do. Psst, <a href="https://www.notion.so/Join-our-tribe-at-Delight-chat-dfb896c946a843ebb58bbb1cc161fe33#dfa80f89af17410e9076d1d4fbfcff35" target="_blank">we are hiring</a>.</p><h3>People on the outside</h3><p>We need people on the outside (advisors, investors) who are aligned with our end goal of building a great company, and are going out of their way in helping us get there. </p><p>They align with our mindset of building a real business that thrives without burning $1 for 70 cents,&nbsp;delivers real value to end users, and grows to a reasonably large size while being profitable.</p><p>Their experience observing other entrepreneurs and companies will help us avoid common pitfalls, make better connections like key hires, and open up doors that we can't even imagine today, because we don't know those doors exist. Serendipity.</p><h3>Onwards</h3><p>I feel incredibly lucky and grateful that we have a handful of such people who believe in us, and who are now working with us towards achieving our shared goal.</p><p>Together, we will reach farther than we previously dared to imagine.</p><p>Off we go towards the next milestone in this great adventure.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.preetamnath.com/blog/building-a-team</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24458258</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 04:12:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using the Monte Carlo Tree Search Algorithm in an AI to Beat 2048]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24457625">thread link</a>) | @xtrp
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://xtrp.io/blog/2020/09/12/using-the-monte-carlo-tree-search-algorithm-in-an-ai-to-beat-2048-and-other-games/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://xtrp.io/blog/2020/09/12/using-the-monte-carlo-tree-search-algorithm-in-an-ai-to-beat-2048-and-other-games/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I recently worked on an open source <a href="https://jupiter.xtrp.io/">project called Jupiter</a>, an online AI to beat the popular online game <a href="http://play2048.co/">2048</a>.</p>
<p>Go try out the AI:</p>
<p><a href="https://jupiter.xtrp.io/"><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xtrp/jupiter/master/demo-image.png" alt="Jupiter Screenshot"></a></p>
<p>In writing this AI, I decided to use a machine learning method called the Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) algorithm. Monte Carlo algorithms like the one used in Jupiter have been used in several notable AIs, including DeepMind's <a href="https://deepmind.com/research/case-studies/alphago-the-story-so-far">AlphaGo</a>, which famously beat the Go world champion in May 2017.</p>
<p>In this article, I'll explain:</p>
<ul>
<li>How and why the Monte Carlo method works</li>
<li>When and where Monte Carlo algorithms can be useful </li>
<li>How I used the Monte Carlo method in an AI to beat 2048</li>
<li>How to implement Monte Carlo algorithms in JavaScript and other languages</li>
</ul>
<p>Note: I got the idea of using a Monte Carlo method to beat 2048 from <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/23853848/10007107">this StackOverflow answer</a>.</p>
<h2>What is the Monte Carlo Method?</h2>
<p>The Monte Carlo method is the idea of using a large number of random simulations of an experiment to gain insights into the experiment's end results. Random simulations of an experiment are frequently referred to as <em>Monte Carlo simulations</em>.</p>
<p>For example, let's say that you were flipping a coin, and trying to figure out the probability of the coin landing heads. With the Monte Carlo method, we could simulate 10,000 coin tosses, and calculate the percentage of coins that landed heads.</p>
<p>Here's what that would look like.</p>
<p><img src="https://xtrp.io/api/content/static_files/using-the-monte-carlo-tree-search-algorithm-in-an-ai-to-beat-2048-and-other-games/coinflip.png" alt="Flip Coin Example Graph"></p>
<p>As can be seen, the result converges to the expected value, 50%. A notable feature of Monte Carlo simulations is that a higher number of simulations is correlated with higher accuracy. For example, if we only performed two simulations, there is a high (25%) probability of heads landing in both simulations, giving a result of 100%. This is very inaccurate in comparison to the expected result of 50%.</p>
<p>Monte Carlo simulations <strong>work because of the Law of Large Numbers</strong>, which says:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you simulate the same experiment many times, the average of the results should converge to the expected value of the simulation.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In other words, Monte Carlo simulations are a way to estimate what will happen in a given experiment <strong>without having to implement any specific algorithms or heuristics</strong>.</p>
<h2>When and Where the Monte Carlo Method Can Be Useful</h2>
<p>The Monte Carlo method is used in a variety of fields, including game AI development, finance and economics, and evolutionary biology to name a few.</p>
<p>The Monte Carlo method can be useful in any experiment with a random factor, where end results cannot be predicted algorithmically. For example, in 2048, a new tile at a random location is added after every move, making it impossible to calculate the exact location of upcoming tiles and subsequently the end result of the game as well.</p>
<p>In these types of experiments, running a large number of Monte Carlo simulations can help get a sense of the average end results, the probability of various events occurring, and the relationship between the variables in the experiment.</p>
<p>For example, using the Monte Carlo method to in Jupiter allowed me to better understand how variables like starting move, number of moves in a game, and best tile in the board affected the end results of the game.</p>
<h2>How I Used the Monte Carlo Method in Jupiter, an AI to Beat 2048</h2>
<p>Let's start with a few definitions:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Board and Tiles</strong>: a 4x4 grid with tiles optionally placed on each grid spot</li>
<li><strong>Game State</strong>: a set of tiles on the board which represents the board at a specific time</li>
<li><strong>Game Score</strong>: the sum of all the tiles on the board</li>
<li><strong>Real Game</strong>: the game that is being played and shown on the browser, not a simulation</li>
</ul>
<p>At any given game state, let's assume that four possible moves can be made: left, right, up, or down.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are indeed cases where a certain move is not possible in a given game state. Removing impossible moves can be easily added to the algorithm later.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With the Monte Carlo method, we can run a set of game simulations for every move.</p>
<p>For each possible move, the program simulates a set of simulations which <strong>start by playing the move for that set first</strong>. After that, the rest of the game can be played completely randomly until it is over.</p>
<p>In JavaScript, this algorithm looks something like:</p>
<pre><code>// assume Game object exists
// assume currentGame variable exists as the real game

const totalSimulations = 200; // 50 simulations are played for each move 

const possibleMoves = ["left", "right", "down", "up"];
possibleMoves.forEach((move) =&gt; { // simulations for all four possible starting moves
  for(let i = 0; i &lt; totalSimulations / 4; i++) {
    const simulation = new Game(); // create simulation
    simulation.board = currentGame.board; // copy current game state to simulation
    simulation.makeMove(move); // make initial move
    while(!simulation.gameover()) {
      simulation.makeMove(possibleMoves[Math.floor(Math.random() * 4)]);
    } // make random moves until simulation game is over
  }
});</code></pre>
<p>After all the simulations are completed, the program can gather the total final game scores of all the simulations, and average them for each move. We can then find the optimal move by optimizing for the highest final game score.</p>
<p>For example, if the simulations which started by playing left had an average final score of 250, whereas the ones which started by playing the other moves had an average final game score of 225, then left is the optimal move.</p>
<p>In this program, <strong>the optimal move is the one with simulations with the highest average final game score</strong>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Note: I could have chosen to optimize for a different value such as the number of moves in the game.</strong></p>
<p>However, this would actually make no difference in how the algorithm functions, because the number of moves in the game almost exactly predicts the game score. In 2048, the new tile added after each game move is normally a 2 tile, but has a 10% chance of being a 4 tile instead. This means the expected value of the new tile is 2.2 (<code>2 × 90% + 4 × 10%</code>). The total value of tiles is also preserved after every tile combination (ex: 2 tile combined with another 2 tile gives a 4 tile). As a result, game score can be calculated by multiplying the expected value of the new tile by the number of moves in the game, or with this formula: <code>2.2 × (real game move count + average move count)</code>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To add this functionality of optimizing for highest score to our current code: add an array of total final scores for the simulations for each possible move, and choose the move with the highest value in that array to play like so:</p>
<pre><code>const possibleMoves = ["left", "right", "down", "up"];
const totalSimulations = 200;

let moveSimulationTotalScores = [0, 0, 0, 0];

possibleMoves.forEach((move, moveIndex) =&gt; { // simulations for all four possible starting moves
  for(let i = 0; i &lt; totalSimulations / 4; i++) {
    const simulation = new Game(); // create simulation
    simulation.board = currentGame.board; // copy current game state to simulation
    simulation.makeMove(move); // make initial move
    while(!simulation.gameover()) {
      simulation.makeMove(possibleMoves[Math.floor(Math.random() * 4)]);
    } // make random moves until simulation game is over
    moveSimulationTotalScores[moveIndex] += simulation.getScore();
  }
});

// make best move with highest total simulation scores
let topScore = Math.max(...moveSimulationTotalScores);
let topScoreIndex = moveSimulationTotalScores.indexOf(topScore);
let bestMove = possibleMoves[topScoreIndex];

currentGame.makeMove(bestMove);</code></pre>
<p>In the end, this algorithm is simple to implement given a well-written 2048 game class. In JavaScript, there are a number of performance upgrades that can be made, starting by adding concurrency with <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Workers_API">Web Workers</a> and pruning moves with very low final game scores.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this post, and found it useful in helping you understand and implement the Monte Carlo method in your own projects.</p>
<p>Go check out <a href="https://jupiter.xtrp.io/">Jupiter</a> and <a href="https://github.com/xtrp/jupiter">its source code</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks for scrolling.</p>
<p><em>— Gabriel Romualdo, September 12, 2020</em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://xtrp.io/blog/2020/09/12/using-the-monte-carlo-tree-search-algorithm-in-an-ai-to-beat-2048-and-other-games/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24457625</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 02:14:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[QAnon Key Figure Revealed as Financial InfoSec Analyst from New Jersey]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24455697">thread link</a>) | @nickfromseattle
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://www.logically.ai/articles/qanon-key-figure-man-from-new-jersey | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.logically.ai/articles/qanon-key-figure-man-from-new-jersey">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
							<p><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hubfs/Qmap.jpg" alt="">
								<span id="hs_cos_wrapper_post_body" data-hs-cos-general-type="meta_field" data-hs-cos-type="rich_text"><p><em>A Logically investigation identifies a key QAnon figure as New Jersey resident Jason Gelinas. The investigation ties QAnon properties to a company owned by Gelinas, an information technology specialist who has held prominent positions at both Credit Suisse and Citigroup.</em></p>

<p><span>Ever since the shadowy figure known as Q made his first appearance on the 4chan imageboard in October of 2017, the author’s identity has remained a mystery. Since then, Q has posted thousands of ‘drops,’ converting legions of followers to the belief that Donald Trump is leading a global fight against a satanic cabal of child trafficking elites, commonly referred to in the QAnon world as the ‘Deep State’.</span></p>
<p>Over the years, Q’s posts would move from the 4chan forum to 8chan, and finally to its later iteration, 8kun. But these forums weren’t where most of Q’s followers would go to access the drops: most would find them neatly compiled on a site called QMap, now the main platform on which Q’s drops are published. For years it was believed that QMap was an endeavour that was independent of both the chan forums and the person or people posting Q’s drops, but recent discoveries concerning an IP address behind QMap raised questions as to whether Jim Watkins, the owner of 8chan and 8kun, an elusive figure in his own right, could also be Q. <a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/who-is-qanon-jim-watkins-rumors/"><span>As some QAnon researchers have pointed out</span></a>, however, the story of Q’s operations does not end with Jim Watkins.</p>

<p>In the world of QAnon, the site qmap.pub is something of a sacred text. It’s a site designed to collect Q’s posts on other message boards and collate them in a searchable database; over the years, it has grown to include glossaries on themes, profiles on people named across the drops (handily sorted into ‘Evil’, ‘Traitor/Pawn’, and ‘Patriot’), and even a prayer wall.</p>
<p>Most followers of QAnon tend not to visit Q’s posts on 8kun and the ‘chan’ boards where they are initially posted (the vernacular used on those sites is deliberately exclusionary and newcomers are often put off). This makes qmap.pub a crucial port of call for all QAnon information and a major node in how the movement disseminates its lore. The site&nbsp;has been hitting over 10 million monthly users since April of this year.</p>
<p>The developer of QMap has been known only as ‘QAPPANON’ since the launch of the site in May of 2018. They have a successful Patreon where they regularly post and update their following on the running of the website. They pull in over 600 patrons and a $3,320 a month income - although there is a $4,000 a month target for ‘running costs’ of the website. In addition to the website, QMap also had an accompanying app on the Google Play Store (for $2.99) until <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/google-removes-qanon-apps-from-play-store-for-violating-terms/"><span>it was removed in May</span></a> this year as “harmful content”. The user QAPPANON is synonymous with qmap.pub, acting as its sole developer and mouthpiece.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The QAnon community recognizes the importance of QAPPANON and how central QMap is to how the movement functions. In a recent campaign to deplatform QAPPANON from Patreon, QAnon power-influencer Praying Medic leapt to their defence, calling on his nearly 400,000 Twitter followers to help (and funnelling them towards QAPPANON’s Patreon). In addition, Praying Medic linked to the Patreon on his podcast, describing it as the “Qmap Patreon”.</p>

<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PrayMed.png?width=600&amp;name=PrayMed.png" alt="PrayMed" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PrayMed.png?width=300&amp;name=PrayMed.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PrayMed.png?width=600&amp;name=PrayMed.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PrayMed.png?width=900&amp;name=PrayMed.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PrayMed.png?width=1200&amp;name=PrayMed.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PrayMed.png?width=1500&amp;name=PrayMed.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PrayMed.png?width=1800&amp;name=PrayMed.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>

<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png?width=535&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png" alt="Screenshot_2020-09-10 Praying Medic on Twitter" width="535" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png?width=268&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png 268w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png?width=535&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png 535w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png?width=803&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png 803w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png?width=1070&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png 1070w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png?width=1338&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png 1338w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png?width=1605&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20Praying%20Medic%20on%20Twitter.png 1605w" sizes="(max-width: 535px) 100vw, 535px"></span></p>

<h4><strong><span>Who is behind QAPPANON?</span></strong></h4>
<p><a href="https://www.dailydot.com/debug/who-is-qanon-jim-watkins-rumors/"><span>It has been suspected that the owner of 8kun, Jim Watkins, is Q</span></a> and perhaps QAPPANON. A shared IP address for 8kun and qmap.pub was viewed as a significant link between Watkins and Q, placing him as a figure doing more than just hosting Q’s preferred method of communication. If Watkins was not in fact Q, his hosting of QMap suggested that at the very least, he could “become Q whenever he wanted”. When approached by Daily Dot, however, QAPPANON stated “they are ‘not associated with Watkins’ and that they moved to VanwaTech because “QMap suffers denial of service attacks regularly, hence the need for a content delivery network that could stop it.”</p>

<h4><strong><span>Logically Investigation into QAPPANON’s identity</span></strong></h4>
<p>Our investigation can reveal that QAPPANON is not Watkins, but instead a New Jersey man in his forties with prominent roles in technical analysis and IT security for the banking sector.&nbsp;</p>
<p>QAPPANON’s email address was initially discovered during our investigation into QMap’s translation efforts and international reach. A now-deleted Facebook post allowed us to trace the email to a CNET&nbsp;download cache for the QMap app as well as a new app in development called Armor of God.</p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl1.png?width=600&amp;name=Shirl1.png" alt="Shirl1" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl1.png?width=300&amp;name=Shirl1.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl1.png?width=600&amp;name=Shirl1.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl1.png?width=900&amp;name=Shirl1.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl1.png?width=1200&amp;name=Shirl1.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl1.png?width=1500&amp;name=Shirl1.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl1.png?width=1800&amp;name=Shirl1.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl2.png?width=600&amp;name=Shirl2.png" alt="Shirl2" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl2.png?width=300&amp;name=Shirl2.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl2.png?width=600&amp;name=Shirl2.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl2.png?width=900&amp;name=Shirl2.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl2.png?width=1200&amp;name=Shirl2.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl2.png?width=1500&amp;name=Shirl2.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Shirl2.png?width=1800&amp;name=Shirl2.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<p>The email found here in the URL serves as a point of contact in a call for translators for qmap.pub. Importantly, the post here states that “<strong><em>Q</em></strong> is looking for someone” rather than “QMap is looking for someone.” As Watkins’s connection to QMap has resulted in speculation that he could be Q, the connection here should not be ignored. However, this may be the result of Shirley_is believing that Q speaks through qmap.pub. What this post <em>does </em>indicate is that QAPPANON is directly responsible for hiring translators for QMap, and therefore has employees.</p>
<p>An extraction of QAPPANON’s email address from the URL led to their developer profile and list of created apps on CNET. While the qmap app is well known at this point, Armor of God is relatively new, having been uploaded on the 18th June 2020.</p>
<p><br><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/QAPPANONCnet.png?width=600&amp;name=QAPPANONCnet.png" alt="QAPPANONCnet" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/QAPPANONCnet.png?width=300&amp;name=QAPPANONCnet.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/QAPPANONCnet.png?width=600&amp;name=QAPPANONCnet.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/QAPPANONCnet.png?width=900&amp;name=QAPPANONCnet.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/QAPPANONCnet.png?width=1200&amp;name=QAPPANONCnet.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/QAPPANONCnet.png?width=1500&amp;name=QAPPANONCnet.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/QAPPANONCnet.png?width=1800&amp;name=QAPPANONCnet.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<h5><span><strong>Armor of God:</strong></span></h5>
<p>When investigating Armor of God, we were met with a bare sign-up screen. Attempts to register and investigate the platform both on desktop and mobile versions were met with login errors and no email to confirm registration or change passwords. This led us to believe that, while downloadable on app stores, the platform is not yet up and running.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AOG%20SPlash.png?width=600&amp;name=AOG%20SPlash.png" alt="AOG SPlash" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AOG%20SPlash.png?width=300&amp;name=AOG%20SPlash.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AOG%20SPlash.png?width=600&amp;name=AOG%20SPlash.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AOG%20SPlash.png?width=900&amp;name=AOG%20SPlash.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AOG%20SPlash.png?width=1200&amp;name=AOG%20SPlash.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AOG%20SPlash.png?width=1500&amp;name=AOG%20SPlash.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AOG%20SPlash.png?width=1800&amp;name=AOG%20SPlash.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></p>
<div><p><a href="https://youtu.be/xhVPxPiQQB4"><span>Proof-of-concept</span></a> <a href="https://youtu.be/xEZjHWxklTM"><span>videos</span></a> on QAPPANON’s Youtube channel reveal what appears to be a hybrid platform functioning as a QAnon research hub, Facebook-like, and Twitter-like. Archived versions of the Armor of God <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200425181515/https://server.aog.pub/site/about"><span>about page</span></a>, <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200425181518/https://server.aog.pub/site/privacy"><span>privacy policy</span></a> and <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200425183516/https://server.aog.pub/site/terms"><span>T&amp;Cs</span></a> from the Wayback Machine revealed more information.</p><p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAbout.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGAbout.png" alt="AoGAbout" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAbout.png?width=300&amp;name=AoGAbout.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAbout.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGAbout.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAbout.png?width=900&amp;name=AoGAbout.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAbout.png?width=1200&amp;name=AoGAbout.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAbout.png?width=1500&amp;name=AoGAbout.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAbout.png?width=1800&amp;name=AoGAbout.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p></div>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGAPP.png" alt="AoGAPP" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=300&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=900&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=1200&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=1500&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=1800&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>

<p>Following the “get the Android app” link led to the Google Play store. Here, we can see that QAPPANON is listed as the profile responsible for uploading the app.</p>
<p><br><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGPlay.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGPlay.png" alt="AoGPlay" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGPlay.png?width=300&amp;name=AoGPlay.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGPlay.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGPlay.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGPlay.png?width=900&amp;name=AoGPlay.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGPlay.png?width=1200&amp;name=AoGPlay.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGPlay.png?width=1500&amp;name=AoGPlay.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGPlay.png?width=1800&amp;name=AoGPlay.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>

<p>However, further down, we can see a different entity listed as the developer of Armor of God: Patriot Platforms.</p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGDev.png?width=226&amp;name=AoGDev.png" alt="AoGDev" width="226" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGDev.png?width=113&amp;name=AoGDev.png 113w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGDev.png?width=226&amp;name=AoGDev.png 226w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGDev.png?width=339&amp;name=AoGDev.png 339w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGDev.png?width=452&amp;name=AoGDev.png 452w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGDev.png?width=565&amp;name=AoGDev.png 565w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGDev.png?width=678&amp;name=AoGDev.png 678w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px"></span></p>
<p>Therefore, far from being a rogue developer creating QMap, QAPPANON has a company—and a company must be filed for.</p>

<h5><span><strong>Patriot Platforms LLC</strong></span></h5>
<p>Visiting Patriot Platforms’ <a href="http://patriotplatforms.com/"><span>website</span></a> reveals a plain splash page with a link to their support email.</p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPSplash.png?width=600&amp;name=PPSplash.png" alt="PPSplash" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPSplash.png?width=300&amp;name=PPSplash.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPSplash.png?width=600&amp;name=PPSplash.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPSplash.png?width=900&amp;name=PPSplash.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPSplash.png?width=1200&amp;name=PPSplash.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPSplash.png?width=1500&amp;name=PPSplash.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPSplash.png?width=1800&amp;name=PPSplash.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<p>We cross-referenced the listed premises of Patriot Platforms to<a href="https://www.google.com/maps/@40.6867177,-74.437065,3a,75y,149.28h,81.03t/data=!3m7!1e1!3m5!1shgM1E9AZLH-OI0Yg9uF08w!2e0!6s%2F%2Fgeo0.ggpht.com%2Fcbk%3Fpanoid%3DhgM1E9AZLH-OI0Yg9uF08w%26output%3Dthumbnail%26cb_client%3Dmaps_sv.tactile.gps%26thumb%3D2%26w%3D203%26h%3D100%26yaw%3D148.3542%26pitch%3D0%26thumbfov%3D100!7i13312!8i6656"><span> a PO box at a New Jersey Post Office</span></a>.</p>
<p><br><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPoffice.png?width=600&amp;name=PPoffice.png" alt="PPoffice" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPoffice.png?width=300&amp;name=PPoffice.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPoffice.png?width=600&amp;name=PPoffice.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPoffice.png?width=900&amp;name=PPoffice.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPoffice.png?width=1200&amp;name=PPoffice.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPoffice.png?width=1500&amp;name=PPoffice.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PPoffice.png?width=1800&amp;name=PPoffice.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<p>This was corroborated with a search for business details.&nbsp;</p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PP%20Edit.png?width=600&amp;name=PP%20Edit.png" alt="PP Edit" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PP%20Edit.png?width=300&amp;name=PP%20Edit.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PP%20Edit.png?width=600&amp;name=PP%20Edit.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PP%20Edit.png?width=900&amp;name=PP%20Edit.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PP%20Edit.png?width=1200&amp;name=PP%20Edit.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PP%20Edit.png?width=1500&amp;name=PP%20Edit.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/PP%20Edit.png?width=1800&amp;name=PP%20Edit.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<p>From here, we also found a name, Jason Gelinas, after which we were able to narrow this down to Jason J. Gelinas in New Jersey, whose listed phone number correlates with the one belonging to Patriot Platforms LLC.</p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas1.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas1.png" alt="Gelinas1" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas1.png?width=300&amp;name=Gelinas1.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas1.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas1.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas1.png?width=900&amp;name=Gelinas1.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas1.png?width=1200&amp;name=Gelinas1.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas1.png?width=1500&amp;name=Gelinas1.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas1.png?width=1800&amp;name=Gelinas1.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span><span></span></p>

<h5><span><strong>Jason J. Gelinas</strong></span></h5>
<p>Jason J. Gelinas, an information technology specialist from Berkeley Heights, New Jersey, whose CV lists prominent positions with both Credit Suisse and Citigroup, is the founder and sole employee of Patriot Platforms LLC, which is credited as the developer behind the QMap and Armor of God platforms. Gelinas’s home address is, in fact, a mere seven-minute drive from Patriot Platforms LLC’s listed P.O. box, also in Berkeley Heights; further investigation shows the connection between Gelinas’s personal WhatsApp and Patriot Platforms’ listed phone number.</p>

<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas2.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas2.png" alt="Gelinas2" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas2.png?width=300&amp;name=Gelinas2.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas2.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas2.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas2.png?width=900&amp;name=Gelinas2.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas2.png?width=1200&amp;name=Gelinas2.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas2.png?width=1500&amp;name=Gelinas2.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas2.png?width=1800&amp;name=Gelinas2.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>

<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas3.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas3.png" alt="Gelinas3" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas3.png?width=300&amp;name=Gelinas3.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas3.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas3.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas3.png?width=900&amp;name=Gelinas3.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas3.png?width=1200&amp;name=Gelinas3.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas3.png?width=1500&amp;name=Gelinas3.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas3.png?width=1800&amp;name=Gelinas3.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>

<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas4.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas4.png" alt="Gelinas4" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas4.png?width=300&amp;name=Gelinas4.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas4.png?width=600&amp;name=Gelinas4.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas4.png?width=900&amp;name=Gelinas4.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas4.png?width=1200&amp;name=Gelinas4.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas4.png?width=1500&amp;name=Gelinas4.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Gelinas4.png?width=1800&amp;name=Gelinas4.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<p>The distance between property owned by Jason J. Gelinas and Patriots Platforms’ postal address (P.O.Box) is only a 7 minute drive.</p>
<p>Jason appears to be scrubbed from social media, with only a Flickr account left. The account name is jjgelinas77.</p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png?width=505&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png" alt="Screenshot_2020-09-10 jjgelinas77" width="505" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png?width=253&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png 253w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png?width=505&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png 505w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png?width=758&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png 758w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png?width=1010&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png 1010w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png?width=1263&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png 1263w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png?width=1515&amp;name=Screenshot_2020-09-10%20jjgelinas77.png 1515w" sizes="(max-width: 505px) 100vw, 505px"></span></p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/FlickrEddit.png?width=600&amp;name=FlickrEddit.png" alt="FlickrEddit" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/FlickrEddit.png?width=300&amp;name=FlickrEddit.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/FlickrEddit.png?width=600&amp;name=FlickrEddit.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/FlickrEddit.png?width=900&amp;name=FlickrEddit.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/FlickrEddit.png?width=1200&amp;name=FlickrEddit.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/FlickrEddit.png?width=1500&amp;name=FlickrEddit.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/FlickrEddit.png?width=1800&amp;name=FlickrEddit.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<p>Crucially, echoes of Gelinas’ username “jjgelinas77” can be seen in the screenshots for Armor of God - “Board Owner <strong>@anon77</strong>” works as an app developer.&nbsp;</p>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGAPP.png" alt="AoGAPP" width="600" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=300&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 300w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=600&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 600w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=900&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 900w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=1200&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 1200w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=1500&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 1500w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/AoGAPP.png?width=1800&amp;name=AoGAPP.png 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px"></span></p>
<h5><span><strong>Relationship between Jason, Armor of God, QAPPANON</strong></span></h5>
<p><span><img src="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg?width=546&amp;name=Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg" alt="Qmap next edit-1" width="546" srcset="https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg?width=273&amp;name=Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg 273w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg?width=546&amp;name=Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg 546w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg?width=819&amp;name=Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg 819w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg?width=1092&amp;name=Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg 1092w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg?width=1365&amp;name=Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg 1365w, https://www.logically.ai/hs-fs/hubfs/Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg?width=1638&amp;name=Qmap%20next%20edit-1.jpg 1638w" sizes="(max-width: 546px) 100vw, 546px"></span></p>
<p>So does that mean Gelinas <em>is </em>Q? No. In fact, it’s quite unlikely that someone such as Gelinas would have been involved in the very early (i.e. 4chan) days of Q. It does suggest, however, that after the success of the QMap platform since it was launched in 2018, a direct line was opened between Watkins and Gelinas, as well as Q (if we are to believe that Q is actually an independent third party and whether the Q from the early days is the Q of today). Indeed, as <span>creator and former owner of 8chan </span>Fred Brennan told Logically, Watkins essentially operates Vanwatech, the company hosting both 8kun and QMap, meaning that he can offer Gelinas free or negligible running costs for QMap, which then reframes the monthly income from Patreon.</p>
<p>So how close is all this to Q? In a nutshell, it’s closer than we’ve ever been. In fact, recent Q drops discussing the ‘Armor of God’ prayer more and more frequently coincide almost perfectly with attempts to launch the ‘Armor of God’ platform, giving this the feel of a coordinated PR campaign. Of course, that could be down to the tendency among Q’s followers to use and re-use the same language, but given the established connection between Gelinas and Watkins, the fact that this timing suggests a level of coordination should not be dismissed.&nbsp;</p></span>
							</p>
						</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.logically.ai/articles/qanon-key-figure-man-from-new-jersey</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24455697</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 21:08:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Want to Fix Goodreads]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 322 | Comments 164 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24454221">thread link</a>) | @prepend
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post">
  

  <article>
    <p>I use <a href="https://goodreads.com/">goodreads</a> a lot because I like to read books and want to find more books to read. This morning I was reading a <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24451428">thread on hackernews</a> on <a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/science-tech/social-media/2020/08/better-goodreads-possible-bad-for-books-storygraph-amazon">Sarah Manavis’s NewStatesman article</a> and it reminds me of how much I want, I yearn, for useful book recommendations. I think about this pretty much every time I open the goodreads page or app and hope that maybe this is the day they finally fix recommendations, so I figure I would capture some ideas I have for fixing their recommendations.</p>

<h2 id="i-love-goodreads">I Love Goodreads</h2>

<p>First, I love Goodreads. My <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/9499790-brian">profile</a> says I joined May 2012. But I think that’s just whenever I started this profile and I have multiple, old profiles that I can’t find. My memory says I started using them soon after launch, but maybe I’m misremembering. But I’ve used them for a long time because I like to read books. I love browsing bookstores and libraries looking for new books. I experience joy finding a 50 or 100 year old book that I didn’t know about. One of my favorite things is reading a book so good that I can’t go to bed, or want to walk an extra mile. But that’s pretty rare for me, I’m lucky if I get one of those a year.</p>

<p>I have goodreads on my <a href="http://prepend.com/stack.xml">link stack</a> with the tag <a href="https://www.prepend.com/future/technology/2020/01/purdah.html">“purdah”</a> that I think means it is part of the stuff I do that uniquely identifies me.</p>

<p>Any time I get a recommendation from a friend or article or wherever, I add it to my “to read” shelf on goodreads. That helps me when I’m trying to buy a new book. So at least I can read through the 245 books that at least a past me wanted to read. This works well and is better than a vanilla list.</p>

<p>I also like seeing what my friends read and especially what they like or dislike. My friends have different tastes so it’s not as simple as just reading everything they read, but it helps a little. It’s one of the few places that I think facebook helps because at least I get to find out facebook friends who also are on goodreads. Every once in a while I find a new book through this feed, maybe once every 2 years. This might be because I don’t have many friends on goodreads (only 42), but I think it’s also because different people have different tastes in books.</p>

<p>I also like that goodreads will tell me when an author I’ve read releases a new book, or is having a book chat or something. Although I wish they would tell me when they come to a local book signing.</p>

<h2 id="the-problem-as-i-see-it">The Problem As I See It</h2>

<p>This gets me to what I think is wrong and want to fix. I have read and rated 802 books with my average rating of 3.97. This makes sense as I’m probably only going to read books I think I’ll like, but I think this is the average goodreads rating, not the average of my ratings. Looking at what I rated, I’ve only given out 3 one stars, 42 two stars and tons of five stars. I keep scrolling on and on.</p>

<p>The user interface for goodreads is pretty bad- information is hard to find, layout is wasted, search doesn’t work well, hard to tell ads from user content- but that’s not what I’m talking about here. The main problem is in finding books that I will like. Maybe a UX overhaul from a great designer would help, but not that much. A craigslist interface would be great if they could just solve this one problem…</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>What is the single book that I will love most in all the world?</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I want to find the next amazing experience. Books are great because they are cheap and portable. It’s not like wine where the best is more than I’ll ever pay. Or travel where a first class flight can cost $20k. If I can find a book, I can read it. And maybe someone I know can read it too.</p>

<p>If I can mix in more wonderful books, my life will be better. My family’s life will be better. Etc etc. Maybe this is the answer to world enlightenment. Probably not, but it will be great, I think.</p>

<p>When I click on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/recommendations">recommendations</a>, goodreads shows me five books that I don’t want to read. And it’s weirdly bad. Some of it makes since why it’s bad. They recommend different versions of books I’ve read. They recommend two different versions of <em>Lord of the Rings</em> (one of my favorite books), but I guess they don’t know these are the same book. That’s just a waste of time and it’s weird that amazon isn’t smart enough to avoid duplicative books.</p>

<p><img src="http://prepend.com/assets/images/goodreads_recommendations.png" alt="Screenshot of goodreads recommendations page"></p>

<p>But then they recommend stuff like Stephen King’s <em>The Long Walk</em>. This is perplexing because I only have one book that goodreads knows I’ve read from King and I rated it two stars. I don’t have any of his books in my “to read” list. Why would they recommend this book? Two of my friends rated it four stars and one even wrote a recommendation. So maybe that’s why. I’m aware of this book and don’t want to read it. But other books like <em>Shoe Dog</em> by Phil Knight has no relationship to me. Why would they recommend this? I also know about this book and don’t want to read it. I wish there was some way to note books that I don’t want to read. Then at least they would stop showing me the same book over and over.</p>

<p>So it seems like goodreads is making pretty basic, rules-based recommendations. And they don’t help me pick new books.</p>

<h2 id="my-perfect-wish">My Perfect Wish</h2>

<p>My idea for an 11-star experience <sup id="fnref:brian_chesky" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:brian_chesky">1</a></sup> in finding new books is that Goodreads knows me even better than I know myself and constantly recommends the perfect book. They recommend books that teach me, that spark enlightenment, that I hate but teach me to appreciate other books, books for when I want to be happy, and books for when I need to be sad. I want something like Jane from Ender’s Game who experiences everything I know but is fixated on finding me a good book. So the output of a book sommelier whose passion is seeing me sit there and love a book.</p>

<p>That’s what I would like.</p>

<h2 id="a-little-story-about-jeff-bezos">A Little Story About Jeff Bezos</h2>

<p>Once I was lucky enough to go to TED. It was great on so many levels, I highly recommend it and 2/3 of the cost was tax deductible. It was full of great stuff. I got to wait in the registration line in front of Neil Gaiman and Amanda Palmer, that was neat.</p>

<p>Anyway, one night Neil Gaiman was doing in a midnight ghost story reading in some neat four story townhouse type building <sup id="fnref:vancouver_club" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:vancouver_club">2</a></sup> that was totally empty and spooky and a great place for the event. The reading was on the top floor and there was a huge crowd waiting for the single elevator in this place. The lights were off and there weren’t any staff around so it was maybe 100 people waiting to go up three at a time. So I looked around the corner and took the stairs. About 2 or 3 other people had the same idea so we started racing up the stairs to get to the top and avoid the crowds.</p>

<p><img src="http://prepend.com/assets/images/vancouver_club.jpg" alt="Vancouver Club street view">
<em>photo by <a href="https://fineartamerica.com/profiles/2-joe-fox">Joe Fox</a></em></p>

<p>This building was awesome. It seemed 100 years old, rare in Vancouver, and as we went up the stairs we saw each floor. The stairwell opened up to a big room that could probably seat a 50 person wedding dinner. The lights were off, and someone had opened a few windows and the white, wispy curtains were blowing with a little breeze. Even though it didn’t feel like a breeze. I said “cool, haunted house” and stopped climbing the stairs to look around. The person next to me said “yeah, cool” and we started quickly running around checking out the empty room. We did this on the third floor too and me and this random person did quick 60 second explorations of this spooky house.</p>

<p>It all happened quickly. Maybe 3 minutes to go up the stairs, run around each floor, and get to the top. About halfway through I realized this random dude was Jeff Bezos. I thought that was neat. I’ve bought books from Amazon since 1995 and I’m pretty sure I telnetted into it to order some books (although maybe that was cdnow before they bought them), so it was cool to think that Jeff Bezos likes haunted houses and still likes exploring empty buildings.</p>

<p>We got to the top and went into the venue and were maybe the first 10 people. Comically got there maybe after two or three elevators full of people. We went to the front where Gaiman was setting up at the podium. I got a comfy chair right in the front about five feet in front of Gaiman. Jeff Bezos sat in the chair to my left. The chair on my right had Neil’s wife, Amanda Palmer, who was carrying a ukelele case. I didn’t know it was a ukulele case until she told me. She also said she might play, but she didn’t.</p>

<p>Gaiman finished setting up and came up to talk to Bezos. Bezos asked if Gaiman got the books he sent. Gaiman said he did and they were really great and he enjoyed reading them. It seemed like this was the most recent in a series of book shipments.</p>

<p>Aside from nerd joy from getting to witness this small talk of people who interest me, I thought, at the time and many times since,</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>How cool is it that Neil-freaking Gaiman is still finding new books that are great, and how cool would it be to get book recommendations from Jeff Bezos. I bet he has access to the best book recommendations in the world.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Also, TED has something called the “TED book club” where they mail you this box of books a month before the conference. This was the closest I’ve come to my dream. They maybe sent 10 and 5 are still on my bookshelf. But not the shelf behind me, so I don’t remember them specifically. I’ll look them up one day.</p>

<p>That’s probably better than Jane making recommendations. Amazon had just bought goodreads a year earlier and I was hopeful that any day, goodreads would roll out a wonderful recommendation engine any day now.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-want-to-do-to-fix">What I Want to Do to Fix</h2>

<p>What I would like to do is to just get a data dump of mine and everyone on goodreads recommendations. I don’t need to know the identities, just to know what recommendations go with what individual. It would be neat to protect privacy and find individuals to potentially follow them on goodreads, but I think for the analysis I want to do, I don’t need to know the actual identities.</p>

<p>I think if I have this data, I could try to find people who rate a few hundred books like I have, then look at what books they’ve read the most, or books that they’ve rated highest. I think that would be a good signal that I might like it.</p>

<p>It would also be cool to see …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html">http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://prepend.com/culture/2020/09/fixing_goodreads.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24454221</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 18:06:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Gesture Recognition with Line Integrals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24453825">thread link</a>) | @justinmeiners
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://justinmeiners.github.io/gesture-recognition | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://justinmeiners.github.io/gesture-recognition">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
            <p>
            By: Justin Meiners (2020)

            </p><p>
            <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line_integral">
                Line integrals</a> measure the extent to which a path agrees with a vector (directional) field.
                This provides an easy way to implement handwriting/tracing/gesture recognition.
                Although not as accurate as fancy ML methods, it still can recognize a wide
                varation in drawings with good accuracy and is versatile in application.
                However, this would not work for OCR applications as the direction of the strokes is an essential component of recognition.
           </p>

            <p>
                The line integral and total length of the path both contribute
                to the scoring. This allows "5" and "8" to be distinguished.
                The centroid of the path is used for adjusting position.
            </p>


            <p>
                Try drawing a number (1-9) in the box to see if it detects it.
            </p>

            
            <canvas id="main-canvas" width="220" height="220"></canvas>

            

            <p>
                To make a new glyph:
                </p><ul>
                    <li> Clear the Canvas </li>
                    <li> Hold <b>SHIFT</b> and draw the character 5-8 times.
Try to keep the position the same as before. Naturally you will add a little variation.

                    </li><li> Optional: Press smooth a few times, then redraw a few more times. </li>
                    <li> Type in the string your glyph represents and <b>Save</b>.</li>
                </ul>
            

            

            <p><label>String
            
            </label>
            </p><h4>Saved Glyphs</h4>
            
            <ul id="glyphs">
            </ul>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://justinmeiners.github.io/gesture-recognition</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24453825</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[From Rust to TypeScript]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 206 | Comments 137 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24453007">thread link</a>) | @valand
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>Edits:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>HN discussion here: <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24453007#24454277">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24453007#24454277</a>. Thank you HN folks for the corrections, kind responses, and insightful discussion.</em></li>
<li>*fixes in Getting Rid of Exceptions snippet 1.</li>
</ul>
<p>I was introduced to Rust in 2018 and has been enamored since. Rust is a system programming language, much like C++. Unlike C++ though, being relatively new, its language design is more modern and sophisticated. Writing with can feel more like writing TypeScript or Haskell. Not surprising since, despite being a language with a very minimum runtime and no GC, it derives many principles of functional programming such as immutability, type inference, higher-order functions, pattern-matching, etc. Over the course of tinkering things with Rust, I realized that writing Rust code makes me a better coder in other languages. This article will describe how my attempt to push the best in Rust's language design into TypeScript, my main language, without altering the language itself.</p>
<h2>Getting Rid of Exceptions</h2>
<p>The first thing that strikes me the first time I learnt Rust is that there are no straightforward to write exception-like code in Rust. For someone used to exceptions after using many languages like C++, Java, JavaScript and TypeScript, this seems like an incomplete language. But Rust's lack of straightforward exception-like is actually thought out in advance.</p>
<p>Exceptions feel neat the first time you understand it. A thrown exception skips code execution into the <code>catch</code> block. By doing that you can ignore the rest of code in the function. The rest of the code in the function represents positive case, which may seem irrelevant when an error happens. Here's a piece of code:</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>function</span><span> </span><span>foo</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span> </span><span>===</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>    </span><span>throw</span><span> </span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span>(</span><span>"Error: foo"</span><span>);
</span><span>  </span><span>}
</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>someNumber</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span>;
}
</span><span>function</span><span> </span><span>bar</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>foo</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span>;
}
</span><span>function</span><span> </span><span>baz</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>bar</span><span>(</span><span>someNumber</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span><span>;
}
</span><span>baz</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>);</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>When <code>baz</code> is called it will throw an uncaught exception. By reading the code you know that <code>foo</code> throws an Error. Debugging this snippet is a piece of cake, right?</p>
<p>Now let's see another snippet. In the snippet below you are importing a function that can throw exception.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>import</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>callMe</span><span> </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>from</span><span> </span><span>"somePackage"</span><span>;

</span><span>try</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>callMe</span><span>();
}</span><span> </span><span>catch</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>exception</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>console</span><span>.</span><span>error</span><span>(</span><span>exception</span><span>.</span><span>message</span><span>);
}</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>Compared to the first snippet, this one is harder to debug. It seems so because 1.) You don't know that <code>callMe</code> will throw an error or not. 2.) If it throws an exception you will not know what is the type of the exception. The more modular your code is, the harder it is to debug exceptions.</p>
<p>Why is that? If you noticed, in the first snippet, you know which function is throwing what because the <code>throw</code> and the caller are in one file. You don't need to switch files or even scroll that far to see what's wrong. Furthermore, unlike in other language like java, TypeScript exceptions are not typed. Because of that, unlike return values, the compiler could not deduce if a function will throw an exception or not, and that's bad. Combined with the fact that an exception propagates up until they are caught. That means exception can be n-level deep. The deeper it is from, the harder it is to debug it.</p>
<p>If you're familiar with statically-typed language, deferring what's supposed to be done in compile-time to run-time is bad. It hands over problems from the compiler to the user.</p>
<p>There are best practices for writing <code>try/throw/catch</code>, such as developers should throw <code>Error</code> objects instead of nullish values. But pushing everyone to apply best practice is not enough. You cannot assert control toward what is being written in external dependencies. There are not many points introducing law when enforcers are nowhere to be found.</p>
<p>Only when you have dealt with complex codebase you will understand why <a href="https://wiki.c2.com/?DontUseExceptionsForFlowControl">we should not use exception for flow control</a>.</p>
<p>So how Rust does this? Rust encourages us to return errors instead of throwing it by providing a data type called <code>Result</code>. It is a tagged union which can either be <code>Ok(IdealData)</code> or <code>Err(NonIdealData)</code>. With this, a function can communicate the situation of a a call to its caller. For example:</p>

    <div data-language="rust">
      <pre><code><span>fn</span><span> </span><span>main</span><span> () {</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>number</span><span>: </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>u8</span><span>, </span><span>_</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>"1"</span><span>.</span><span>parse</span><span>();</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>non_number</span><span>: </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>u8</span><span>, </span><span>_</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>"a"</span><span>.</span><span>parse</span><span>();</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>, &amp;</span><span>number</span><span>);      </span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>, &amp;</span><span>non_number</span><span>);  </span><span>
</span><span>}</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>The function <code>.parse()</code> converts a <code>string</code> into <code>u8</code>. There are scenarios where parsing a <code>string</code> into a <code>u8</code> can result in failure, one is if the parsed string is not a numeric string. Because <code>.parse()</code> has a negative case, it returns <code>Result&lt;u8, _&gt;</code>.</p>
<p>In Rust, <code>Err</code> does not jump like exceptions. Regardless the result is <code>Ok</code> or <code>Err</code>, the program will simply execute the next line. To handle the error the programmer has to check the return value is <code>Ok</code> or <code>Err</code>. Early return is encouraged instead of throw. Rust has the <code>?</code> syntax which help making early returns more concise to write and read.</p>
<p>To adopt this feature to TypeScript, these are the important things:</p>
<ol>
<li>Errors are returned instead of thrown</li>
<li>Errors types are known</li>
</ol>
<p>To simulate this behavior I am going to use tagged union too. I found this helpful library, <a href="https://github.com/gcanti/io-ts">fp-ts</a>. It covers a great deal of functional programming experience by leveraging TypeScript's type system, but I will only use a small portion of it.</p>
<p><code>fp-ts</code> has <code>Either&lt;Left, Right&gt;</code> data type. It is like Rust's <code>Result</code> but more flexible. <code>Either</code> is a tagged union value container. <code>Either</code> is <code>Left</code> or <code>Right</code>, usually <code>Right</code> represents the ideal case and <code>Left</code> represents the non-ideal case but both can be used with any types. Below is the type definition of <code>Either</code>.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>type</span><span> </span><span>Either</span><span>&lt;</span><span>L</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>R</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>Left</span><span>&lt;</span><span>L</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>Right</span><span>&lt;</span><span>R</span><span>&gt;</span><span>;
</span><span>type</span><span> </span><span>Left</span><span>&lt;</span><span>L</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>_tag</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"left"</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>left</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>L</span><span> </span><span>};
</span><span>type</span><span> </span><span>Right</span><span>&lt;</span><span>R</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>_tag</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"right"</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>right</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>R</span><span> </span><span>};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>What's cool about <code>Either</code> is that TypeScript actually supports deducing tagged union from its tag. For example inside this block <code>if (someEither._tag === "left") { }</code> TypeScript knows that <code>someEither</code> is a <code>Left</code>. If there's a <code>return</code> in that block, TypeScript will deduce that for the rest of the function block, <code>someEither</code> data type is <code>Right</code> and not <code>Either</code> anymore.</p>
<p>Let's make a called <code>tryCatch</code>. It is used to wrap a function into Either. <code>fp-ts</code> actually provides this function, but let's write it so that we know what's under the hood.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>const</span><span> </span><span>tryCatch</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>E</span><span>&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>fn</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>T</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>onError</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>unknown</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>E</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>try</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>    </span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>right</span><span>(</span><span>fn</span><span>());
</span><span>  </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>catch</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>    </span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>left</span><span>(</span><span>onError</span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>));
</span><span>  </span><span>}
};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>With our newly created <code>tryCatch</code>, creating a URL from string for example can be done like this.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>InvalidURLError</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span> </span><span>{}
</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>makeURLFromString</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>tryCatch</span><span>(
</span><span>    </span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>URL</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>),
</span><span>    </span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>InvalidURLError</span><span>()
</span><span>  </span><span>);</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>Calling the function will look like this. The following snippet receives a string called <code>maybeUrl</code>. If <code>maybeUrl</code> is not a valid URL it returns an error. If the URL is not calling "example.com" it returns an error. Otherwise, it returns a promise from the <code>fetch</code> call.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>NotExampleDotComError</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span> </span><span>{}
</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>callThisMaybeUrlIfItIncludesExampleDotCom</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>(
</span><span>  </span><span>maybeUrl</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span>
):</span><span> </span><span>Either</span><span>&lt;</span><span>InvalidURLError</span><span> </span><span>|</span><span> </span><span>NotExampleDotComError</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>Promise</span><span>&lt;</span><span>any</span><span>&gt;&gt;</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{
</span><span>  </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>urlResult</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>makeURLFromString</span><span>(</span><span>maybeUrl</span><span>);
</span><span>  </span><span>
</span><span>  </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>isLeft</span><span>(</span><span>urlResult</span><span>))</span><span> </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>urlResult</span><span>.</span><span>left</span><span>;

</span><span>  </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>url</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>urlResult</span><span>.</span><span>right</span><span>;
</span><span>  </span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>url</span><span>.</span><span>origin</span><span> </span><span>!==</span><span> </span><span>"example.com"</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>left</span><span>(</span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>NotExampleDotComError</span><span>());

</span><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>right</span><span>(</span><span>fetch</span><span>(</span><span>urlResult</span><span>));
};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>There's a bit more line of codes here, but it is great that the TypeScript compiler now can deduce the error type and you have more control over the flow. You can even deduce if the variable <code>error</code> is <code>instanceof</code> <code>NotExampleDotComError</code> or <code>InvalidURLError</code> for cases like printing different errors.</p>
<h2>Safe TypeScript</h2>
<p>If you have played an early 2000s FPS games and tried to cheat, usually you will find the <code>noclip</code> command. It makes your avatar fly through walls and grounds. Sometimes, though, you take a shortcut and triggers the wrong script. When that happens, you can't finish your level and must restart to make it work again.</p>
<p>That's how I see Rust's <code>unsafe</code> and TypeScript's <code>any</code>.</p>
<p>These two features solve a similar problem. In Rust's case, it enables developers to temporarily unlock the power of handling raw pointer in case someone needs it. In TypeScript's case, someone might need to escape into the free-typed JavaScript world. And in both, it is the programmer's responsibility to make sure everything is fine before the program goes back to the safe system.</p>
<p>Unsafe to safe Rust is like <code>any</code> type to typed TypeScript. Unlike Rust, TypeScript's type only works until you compile it to JavaScript code. Rust has <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/beta/rust-by-example/conversion/try_from_try_into.html">TryInto/TryFrom</a> trait to convert raw data into a data type. But in TypeScript's case, if you inject a value that does not match TypeScript's type annotation, TypeScript can't do anything. This comes from TypeScript team's decision to make it only a thin layer on top of JavaScript. They thought it is best if for people to write TypeScript like JavaScript and the compilation result to look almost the same as the source code.</p>
<p>My approach for this would be securing all external hole of my application, which are:</p>
<ul>
<li>WebAPIs, which consist of DOM, deserializable user inputs, fetch API, etc.</li>
<li>External Dependencies which returns <code>any</code></li>
</ul>
<p>When I was trying this approach, I was lucky to find <a href="https://github.com/gcanti/io-ts">io-ts</a>, created by the same author as <code>fp-ts</code>. This library helps me create a runtime type checker, or "codec" as the library's author calls it. Instead of writing:</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>type</span><span> </span><span>User</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>username</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span>;</span><span> </span><span>userId</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>string</span><span> </span><span>};</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>I wrote the codec for User:</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>const</span><span> </span><span>UserCodec</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>type</span><span>({</span><span> </span><span>username</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>string</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>userId</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>string</span><span> </span><span>});
</span><span>type</span><span> </span><span>User</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>ioTs</span><span>.</span><span>TypeOf</span><span>&lt;</span><span>typeof</span><span> </span><span>UserCodec</span><span>&gt;</span><span>;</span></code></pre>
    </div>
<p>Again, this is longer, but this is very useful if we want to secure those holes.</p>

    <div data-language="text/typescript">
      <pre><code><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>InvalidTypeError</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>Error</span><span> </span><span>{}
</span><span>export</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>Fet…</span></code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript">https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://valand.dev/blog/post/from-rust-to-typescript</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24453007</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 15:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GAlculator – Geometric Algebra Pocket Calculator]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24452509">thread link</a>) | @alex_hirner
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://enkimute.github.io/ganja.js/examples/galculator.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://enkimute.github.io/ganja.js/examples/galculator.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <h4>The Galculator - powered by Ganja.js</h4><p>
    The Galculator can be forked on <a href="https://github.com/enkimute/ganja.js">github</a></p><p>
    It works great on your phone - full screen if you add it to your homescreen.</p><h4>Example in <span>C</span> :</h4>
    <p>Calculate (3+2i)*(1+4i)</p>
    

    <h4>Example in <span>D</span></h4><p>
    Calculate the value of the function and first derivative at x=3</p><p>
    
    f(x)=x<sup>3</sup>-2x<sup>2</sup>+3
    </p>

    <h4>Example in spacetime <span>M</span></h4><p>
    You see two simultaneous lightning strikes in 10 microseconds, one where you are, one 20 km in the x-direction.<br>
    Are these events simultaneous for a spaceship flying at 0.5c in the x-direction? (given : atanh(0.5)=0.5493)
    </p>
    
    <h4>Example in PGA 2D (2,0,1)</h4>
    <p>Solve the system of equations :
       </p><li>x+y-0.5=0
       </li><li>2x-1y=0
    
    
    
  </li></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://enkimute.github.io/ganja.js/examples/galculator.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24452509</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 14:06:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Performance Benchmark Analysis of Egress Filtering on Linux]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24452458">thread link</a>) | @simonpure
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/09/performance-benchmark-analysis-of-egress-filtering-on-linux/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/09/performance-benchmark-analysis-of-egress-filtering-on-linux/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>Traffic filtering is a common technique used to protect networks and hosts from malicious activity. The filtering can be done in the incoming and outgoing flows, better known as ingress and egress filtering. There are many examples of use cases for ingress filtering: mitigating DDoS attacks, avoiding SPAM, blocking access to services for specific geographic regions and so on.</p>
<p>One common application of egress filtering is to prevent applications and users from reaching remote hosts.
These kinds of filters are usually based on a large deny-list of IP address ranges, like <a href="https://www.icann.org/news/blog/reputation-block-lists-protecting-users-everywhere">Reputation Block Lists</a>. The technology used to perform this task has to be able to handle a high number of restricted hosts, up to millions in some cases.</p>
<p>Our friends at SAP asked us to perform a benchmark of the common Linux technologies available for this task. This blog post presents the methodology and results from benchmarking some of the Linux filtering technologies: eBPF, IP sets and iptables.</p>
<p><em>Update 2020-09-14:</em> we have received some great feedback and suggestions about other options to try, including BPF JIT optimization (that we left inadvertently disabled) and inline BPF map lookup. We will take a look at this and update this post as soon as possible - expected at the end of the month.</p>
<h2 id="goals">Goals</h2>
<p>We had the following goals going into this study:</p>
<ul>
<li>Provide a reproducible benchmark framework that anyone else can download and use.</li>
<li>Evaluate the different mechanisms in the Linux networking stack to filter out a large amount of IP addresses and assess their scalability when the amount of IP ranges to block reaches 1 million.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="scenario">Scenario</h2>
<p>We aim to understand the cost of performing egress filtering based on the destination IP in a large set of IP ranges.</p>
<p>The scenario we consider is composed of a client and a server computer that communicate through an IP network. The egress filtering is performed on the client machine and there is no filtering performed on the server side.</p>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/scenario.svg">
</figure>
<h2 id="metrics">Metrics</h2>
<p>An egress filter has to perform a matching operation to understand if a packet can continue its way or has to be dropped. This operation could be costly if the number of blocked IPs is high. This kind of filter impacts the throughput of IP connections, it consumes extra CPU and increases the latency. We decided to take into consideration these metrics under the following conditions.</p>
<ul>
<li>Throughput</li>
<li>CPU usage</li>
<li>Latency</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="linux-filtering-mechanisms">Linux Filtering Mechanisms</h2>
<p>The Linux kernel provides different mechanisms to filter network packets. In this benchmark we considered the most known ones. iptables is the historical and probably more known filtering utility in Linux. IP sets support high speed matching for sets of specific types, like IP ranges for instance. eBPF is very flexible and customizable. The following section provides more details of how we used those mechanisms in our benchmark.</p>
<h3 id="ebpf">eBPF</h3>
<p>eBPF is a virtual machine built in the Linux kernel. In the networking scope, it allows the user to load programs that are executed each time a packet arrives or is sent out of a networking interface. Those eBPF programs can modify, redirect or drop the packets.</p>
<p>There are different types of networking eBPF programs, CGROUP_SKB for per-cgroup filtering, SCHED_CLS and SCHED_ACT for filtering at the traffic control level, and XDP for filtering at the network interface level.</p>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/ebpf.svg">
</figure>
<p>In our scenario, we want to apply the same filtering regardless of the cgroup of the application generating the traffic. The traffic coming from non-local applications or forwarded traffic should be filtered as well. This makes filtering at the socket level unfit for our scenario. XDP programs can only be attached to the ingress<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> path, removing it from consideration in our tests also. By process of elimination, we only consider eBPF programs attached to the traffic control layer.</p>
<p>Given that we want to keep the tests as simple as possible we decided to implement <a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/egress-filtering-benchmark/blob/master/pkg/filters/bpf/datapath/bpf.c">our own</a>filtering program in eBPF that will be attached to the traffic control layer with a clsact qdisc. The clsact qdisc was introduced in Linux 4.5, it’s a pseudo qdisc that allows to attach eBPF programs in ingress and egress using the <a href="https://qmonnet.github.io/whirl-offload/2020/04/11/tc-bpf-direct-action/">direct-action</a> mode.</p>
<p>Our filter implementation uses an <a href="https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/commit/?id=b95a5c4db09bc7c253636cb84dc9b12c577fd5a0">LPM map</a> to save the list of IP addresses to block. eBPF implements the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Longest_prefix_match">LPM</a> algorithm with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trie">digital tree</a>.</p>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/ebpflookup.svg">
</figure>
<h3 id="iptables">iptables</h3>
<p>We tested the standard iptables implementation by adding DROP rules to the OUTPUT chain in the filter table. The rules we used have the following format</p>
<p><code>-A OUTPUT -d 192.168.0.0/16 -o eth0 -m comment --comment "benchmark" -j DROP</code></p>
<p>While implementing this filter we found that appending each rule independently was too slow and we had to use the <code>iptables-restore</code> utility to do it.</p>
<p>iptables uses a linear search algorithm for rule matching.</p>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/iptableslookup.svg">
</figure>
<h3 id="ip-sets">IP Sets</h3>
<p>We performed the testing also with the <a href="https://ipset.netfilter.org/">IP sets</a> framework. We used an IP set of type <a href="https://ipset.netfilter.org/ipset.man.html#lbAZ"><code>hash:net</code></a> and linked it to iptables by using the following rule:</p>
<p><code>-A OUTPUT -o eth0 -m set --match-set myset dst -m comment --comment benchmark -j DROP</code>.</p>
<p>The IP address to check is hashed and the result of the hash is used as the index in a hash table. Each bucket of the hash table contains an array of networks for that hash. When an IP address is checked against an IP set of type “hash:net”, it is not known what network size will match. The IP set implementation hashes the IP address for all possible network sizes. For instance, if the IP to match is 1.2.3.4, it looks for 1.2.3.4/32, for 1.2.3.4/31 and so on until all the 32 possible network sizes have been tested.</p>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/ipsetslookup.svg">
</figure>
<h2 id="benchmark-set-up">Benchmark Set-up</h2>
<p>We used <code>iperf3</code> to measure the performance of TCP, UDP and the CPU usage. The standard <code>ping</code> utility was used to measure the latency. We tested with 10, 100, 1k, 10k, 100k and 1M rules and each test was run 5 times to get statistical robustness.</p>
<p>We used two bare metal servers - running on <a href="https://www.packet.com/">Packet</a> - as client and server machines. The specifications of such servers are:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="fallback">c2.medium.x86
1x AMD EPYC 7401P 24-Core Processor @ 2.0GHz
2x 120GB SSD
2x 480GB SSD
64GB RAM
2x 10Gbps
</code></pre></div><p>The exact versions of the tools we used are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.flatcar-linux.org/">Flatcar Container Linux</a> by Kinvolk alpha (<a href="https://www.flatcar-linux.org/releases/#release-2605.0.0">2605.0.0</a>)</li>
<li>Linux kernel 5.4.59</li>
<li>iperf 3.0.7 (in a Docker container with the host network)</li>
<li>iptables v1.6.2</li>
<li>ipset v6.20.1, protocol version: 6</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="reproducibility">Reproducibility</h2>
<p><a href="https://github.com/kinvolk/k8s-egress-filtering-benchmark">https://github.com/kinvolk/egress-filtering-benchmark</a> has all the tools and instructions to reproduce these tests.</p>
<h2 id="results">Results</h2>
<h3 id="test-1---tcp-throughput">Test #1 - TCP Throughput</h3>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/throughput-tcp-linerate.svg">
</figure>
<p>The throughput graph shows that the test is reaching line rate, 10Gbps because we are using a single connection hence only one of the interfaces on the bonding is used in most of the cases. Only iptables with more than 10k rules is not able to handle that performance. From this test we can conclude that iptables doesn’t scale well after 100k, but unfortunately we cannot conclude anything from other tests as network performance is the bottleneck.</p>
<p>In order to stress the CPU more, we performed another test using UDP.</p>
<h3 id="test-2---udp-throughput">Test #2 - UDP Throughput</h3>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/throughput-udp.svg">
</figure>
<p>The goal of this test is to saturate the CPU. We used UDP packets and the <code> -b 10G</code> parameter to try to reach line rate. The graph shows that none of the cases reaches the 10Gbps line rate, it’s good for this test because it means the network is not the bottleneck anymore.</p>
<p>We can see that iptables does not scale well beyond 1k rules and that IP sets are a bit faster than eBPF on the clsact qdisc with a high number of rules.</p>
<h3 id="test-3---cpu-usage">Test #3 - CPU usage</h3>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/cpu.svg">
</figure>
<p>We used <code>iperf</code> with a target bandwidth of 1Gbps (<code>-b 1G</code>) to avoid saturating the CPU and be able to compare the CPU usage with the different filters. We take the CPU usage reported by <code>iperf</code> that includes all the applications running on the host. From the above graph we can see that the CPU usage with iptables increases when using more than 1k rules. The CPU usage with eBPF and IP sets filters stays almost constant showing a bit higher usage in the eBPF case.</p>
<h3 id="test-4---latency">Test #4 - Latency</h3>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/latency.svg">
</figure>
<p>We used the standard Linux ping utility to measure the latency with the <code>-i 0.001</code> and <code>-c 1000</code> parameters, sending 1000 pings at a 1 millisecond interval. The above graph shows that the latency is not affected by the number of rules in the eBPF and IP sets filters, it’s ~27µs in those cases. On the other hand, it increases linearly with the number of rules for the iptables case.</p>
<h3 id="test-5---setup-time">Test #5 - Setup Time</h3>
<p>This test aims to measure the time it takes to install the filtering rules on the system. It doesn’t take into consideration fixed times like loading the eBPF program, creating the IP sets but instead focuses on measuring the time it takes to update the rules themselves and how it changes with the number of rules.</p>
<figure>
	<img src="https://kinvolk.io/media/2020-09-10-egress-filtering-testing/setup.svg">
</figure>
<p>The above graph shows that the time required to set up the rules in all the filters increases linearly with the number of rules.</p>
<p>With 100.000 IPs, the setup time is still less than one second. For 1 million IPs, the setup time is less than 10 seconds. This shows that in practice, all 3 methods have an acceptable setup time.</p>
<p>The setup time is very dependent on the benchmark implementation rather than being inherent to the filtering method. Each filtering method could be optimised in the benchmark code if it were deemed necessary.</p>
<ul>
<li>For the bpf filter: the benchmark performs one bpf() system call for every IP. From Linux 5.6, it is possible to <a href="https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/commit/?id=aa2e93b8e58e18442edfb2427446732415bc215e">perform several updates in a eBPF map with a single bpf() call</a>.</li>
<li>For the iptables and IP sets filters, the benchmark executes external commands and feeds each IP range individually over a pipe. We could avoid that by communicating the list to the kernel using the Netlink protocol directly. There are <a href="https://github.com/vishvananda/netlink/search?q=ipset&amp;type=Issues">some attempts</a> to implement IP Sets support in Golang with the vishvananda/netlink library.</li>
</ul>
<p>For this reason, the reader should be cautious before comparing the setup time of one filter to another. This should not be interpreted as one method being better than another but rather to show expected setup performance and that setup time is unlikely to be a problem for any filtering method.</p>
<h3 id="test-6---throughput-with-too-many-rules">Test #6 - Throughput with …</h3></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/09/performance-benchmark-analysis-of-egress-filtering-on-linux/">https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/09/performance-benchmark-analysis-of-egress-filtering-on-linux/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kinvolk.io/blog/2020/09/performance-benchmark-analysis-of-egress-filtering-on-linux/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24452458</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 14:00:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Review of Language Learning Tactics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24452418">thread link</a>) | @laybak
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://knowledgeartist.org/article/language-learning-tips | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://knowledgeartist.org/article/language-learning-tips">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <p><span>In my journey learning 9 languages over the years, I tried all sorts of different methods to make my learning more effective. Here are some of the notable approaches, along with why they work (or don't work). It </span> <a href="https://knowledgeartist.org/article/how-long-does-it-take-to-learn-a-language" target="_blank"><span>will be a long learning journey</span></a> <span>, I hope this article will make yours more fun and effective. </span></p> <p><span>Let's jump right in.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Moving to the Target Country</span></h3></p> <p><span>In my experience learning a language, immersion is powerful. Being in a country where your target language is spoken is ideal. Your learning becomes always on, even if you don't realize it. </span></p> <p><span>I moved to Tokyo and worked at an all-Japanese company a few years ago. At the beginning I knew very little Japanese. But with this sink-or-swim approach and the daily immersion, I became comfortable with basic conversations within three months.</span></p> <p><span>Now, it is not always possible to just pack up and move to a different place. Read on for other tips I tested from my own experience. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Language Exchange Meetups</span></h3></p> <p><span>You can only get so good at speaking a language without talking to native speakers. Language exchange groups are a great way to get that conversational practice. In a typical event, you would get paired up/grouped with native speakers of your target language, who are themselves looking to level up on your native tongue. </span></p> <p><span>For half of the time, the group would converse in one language, and then switch to the other language half-way. If you live in a major city, there are usually quite a few of these groups for the common languages. </span> <a href="https://www.meetup.com/" target="_blank"><span>Meetup</span></a> <span> is a great place to look for these events. This is an effective way to practice in your home city, or when you are already in your target country. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Online Language Exchange</span></h3></p> <p><span>If you are unable to attend in-person meetups, online language exchange can be effective as well. Though in-person conversations would always feel more organic, you still get the instant feedback and practice with online language exchange calls. </span></p> <p><span>I have made a few friends along the way, while practicing my German, French, and Japanese. I previously had a pleasant experience using </span> <a href="https://www.italki.com/" target="_blank"><span>iTalki</span></a> <span>, where I could easily find language partners and schedule 1-1 Skype calls with them. It was entirely free. But at the time of writing, it appears they may have removed the free partner option.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Learning Entire Phrases</span></h3></p> <p><span>I found it effective to memorize entire sentences, and pull them out when I need to. There are several benefits to this. When you are communicating in realtime, having phrases already memorized can reduce your stumbling. It can make you appear fluent and keep the conversation flowing. This also makes you feel more comfortable, knowing what to say or how to respond in a given situation.</span></p> <p><span>These familiar phrases serve as important anchors as well, for learning about the structure of the language, and for easily swapping out components to adapt to new situations. For example, after memorizing the phrase "After a few months of travelling, I am happy to finally be able to work with everyone", you can substitute some of the words and use it in a new scenario.</span></p> <p><span>Phrase books can be somewhat useful for this purpose, though it can sound scripted and unnatural. What feels more natural is writing down and remembering the response of native speaker in a real-life situation or in a movie.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Movies/Shows in Your Target Language</span></h3></p> <p><span>Movies and TV shows are a great source of natural-sounding phrases (though overly dramatic sometimes) to add to your knowledge bank. This is great for a number of reasons: </span></p> <p><li><span>You can usually figure out what the movie is about (especially if you first watch it in your native language).</span></li></p> <p><li><span>It is enjoyable, which means you will stick with it</span></li></p> <p><li><span>You get to learn about the culture behind your target language</span> <strong> </strong> <span>as well.</span></li></p> <p><span>And if you are watching it on TV, I find that even the commercials in your target language are interesting. Not only is it good practice, you get a better sense of what kinds of products local people buy and the messaging that appeals to them. With the growing selection of international shows/movies on Netflix, along with audio and/or subtitles, this is a fun and easy way to make progress.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Interviews with Subtitles and Translations</span></h3></p> <p><span>In addition to movies/shows, interviews are the perfect content for getting exposure to natural conversations, where people use casual everyday language. </span> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/magauchsein" target="_blank"><span>Easy Languages</span></a> <span> on YouTube is hands down one of my favourite language resources. They interview people on the streets on a different topic each episode, and provide subtitles in the original language + English. Over the years, they have built up an amazing collection of content in many (!) languages.</span></p> <p><span>Here's a taste of their content for German learners: </span></p> <div><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hLoatpfE7VM?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" frameborder="0"></iframe></p></div>  <p><h3><span>Passive Background Looping</span></h3></p> <p><span>This is one of the most effective hacks I developed to maximize my time spent learning a language. As I work, I would put on a familiar track of native speakers talking (much of the time it would be Easy Languages) in the ground. This way, I can get a lot of listening practice without spending much time. By picking content that you are already familiar with, you already know what is being talked about. And the looping gets you more "reps" for each phrase. It also helps you memorize entire phrases that you can use with ease later.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Podcasts </span></h3></p> <p><span>This one can be tricky. I have tried quite a few podcasts and many podcast formats aren't that conducive to learning a foreign language. Either I don't understand what's going on, or there is too much repeating over the often dry content. But for Japanese learners, I highly recommend </span> <a href="https://bilingualnews.libsyn.com/" target="_blank"><span>Bilingual News</span></a> <span> hosted by Michael and Mami. It features the hosts talking about interesting topics in the news, with Michael speaking only English and Mami speaking only Japanese. The conversation always moves forward and remains engaging, and you can usually easily fill in the words you missed from the context. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Ask a Native Speaker "How do I say X?" Wherever Possible</span></h3></p> <p><span>If you have friends (or better yet, roommates) from other countries, you can definitely get some practice in as you hang out. When you are trying to say something, why not learn to say it in your target language too? Anytime is learning time! You'll remember it much better than other methods because the learning takes place in real-life expeirences. I used to worry this may come off as annoying, but in my experience most people are happy to help, and appreciate the ernest effort you make to understand their language/culture. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Changing Your Phone's Language</span></h3></p> <p><span>One easy way to squeeze out an extra bit of language immersion is to simply change your mobile phone to your target language. Doing so should automatically update the language in all your apps as well. Since you likely already know how to navigate through most apps anyway, in most cases you can guess the meaning of new words that you don't yet know. With this, even Facebook notifications become good practice. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Taking classes</span></h3></p> <p><span>I have never been a fan of learning a language in a classroom, having taken Russian, French and Mandarin classs. This one is a bit of a hit or miss. The classroom environment has always felt a bit too artificial for this purpose. Typically, there is also limited practice, limited individual attention (and hence </span> <em>feedback</em> <span>). And the separation between the classroom learning context and the real-life situations makes it hard to apply the knowledge.</span></p> <p><span>That said, there are some amazing teachers out there who excel at teaching and building curriculum. And for some people, the structure of learning in a group guided by a competent instructor is just what they need. For Chinese learners, </span> <a href="https://www.excelmandarin.com/" target="_blank"><span>Excel Mandarin</span></a> <span> is an example of educators who have created an effective learning system for their students. Though not from my personal experience, I have heard nothing but positive reviews about these folks. </span></p>  <p><h3><span>Duolingo</span></h3></p> <p><span>There was a time when I would have a long-running practice streak on the popular free app </span> <a href="https://www.duolingo.com/" target="_blank"><span>Duolingo</span></a> <span>. I would use the app daily, and almost completed the curriculum for Brazilian Portuguese, Spanish, and German. I felt great. I felt engaged. I felt like I was making progress. But that's the dangerous part about apps like these that try to "gamify" the language learning process. it makes you feel productive, even if it may not reflect reality. </span></p> <p><span>It is all too easy to slip into auto-pilot mode, where you just rush to the finish line of each exercise. This is similar to how one would "speed read" a book in an hour and retain nothing from it. The app also trains you to get used to the machine-generated bad pronunciation, which is counter-productive for your listening skills. On the bright side, Duolingo can be helpful for exposure to new words, and adding some structure to your learning, especially if you are not following a curriculum or textbook.</span></p>  <p><h3><span>Reading Textbooks</span></h3></p> <p><span>Reading a textbook for the purpose of language learning is perhaps the best way to learn the formal structure of a language. But it is not effective for conversational purposes. Grammar rules are clean, but conversational languages are messy. Similar to the discussion above about taking classes, textbooks tend to give a similar passive understanding of rules, as opposed to the ability to apply that knowledge in real-time. </span></p>  <p><span>The best approach is the one you actually take and follow through with. One that fits your learning objectives and learning style. The more you can align your learning with your intrinsic motivation, the more likely it is that it will stick. </span></p>         


          
            
            <p><em>Each week, I send out a newsletter where I share my learnings, new ways to see things, and new ways to feel.</em></p>
            <p><em>Enter your email below to subscribe.</em></p>

            
          
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://knowledgeartist.org/article/language-learning-tips</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24452418</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 13:54:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why do so many people want us back in the office?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 351 | Comments 486 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24452280">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | https://paulitaylor.com/2020/09/12/why-do-so-many-people-want-us-back-in-the-office/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paulitaylor.com/2020/09/12/why-do-so-many-people-want-us-back-in-the-office/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>After the sudden and miraculous shift to remote work in March – the office fightback has well and truly begun.</p>



<p>Four months ago I wrote that – surprisingly- there was no fightback from technophobe hold-outs barricading themselves into their offices. They simply packed up their laptop and went home with the rest of us. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/04/06/did-a-virus-just-bring-about-the-end-of-the-office/" target="_blank">How </a><a href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/04/06/did-a-virus-just-bring-about-the-end-of-the-office/">premature</a><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/04/06/did-a-virus-just-bring-about-the-end-of-the-office/" target="_blank"> I was</a>. </p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>2019: millenials are wasting all their money on buying sandwiches </p><p>2020: THE ECONOMY WILL COLLAPSE IF YOU DON'T BUY MORE SANDWICHES</p></div>— Sam Grinsell (@samgrinsell) <a href="https://twitter.com/samgrinsell/status/1299288101743886336?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 28, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>If you thought that 2020 couldn’t get any crazier – it seems some people really are suggesting that businesses should alter their workplace strategies in order to save…sandwich shops.</p>



<p>OK, I’m exaggerating for effect. But there really has been a hand brake applied to the move to remote/hybrid working , or my favoured term,<em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://medium.com/work-futures/the-future-is-minimum-office-not-zero-office-821928abdba2" target="_blank"> minimum office</a></em> in recent weeks. </p>



<p>An <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2020/08/27/go-back-work-risk-losing-job-major-drive-launched-get-people/" target="_blank">article in the Daily Telegraph</a>&nbsp;suggested&nbsp;that employees who continue to work at home will be more vulnerable to redundancy, with bosses finding it far easier get rid of people they don’t physically see.</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/KirstieMAllsopp/status/1290987043829489666?s=20" target="_blank">Kirstie Allsopp</a> led the anti-remote work charge on Twitter, suggesting that if your job can be done from home, it can be done from anywhere in the world. Who would have thought that a couple of months of working in shorts and a T-Shirt has made us more susceptible to being replaced by less expensive folk in India, Myanmar and China? </p>



<p>A debate that is framed around saving sandwich shops and an already dying high street isn’t helpful or progressive. Cynically I might suggest the real subtext here is about propping up commercial property investment portfolios. Realistically though, we won’t see anything like a return to the same number of offices, and although few will shed tears for commercial real estate investors many small businesses will suffer a big hit and go out of business unless they can pivot very rapidly.</p>



<p>Clearly there are two groups emerging, those who are desperate for the pandemic to be viewed as a temporary event before everything returns to ‘normal’ and those embracing the true long term disruption that is occurring.</p>



<p>Thank heavens then for more balanced thinkers like Tom Cheesewright who has an uncanny ability to pan back and take the long view. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://tomcheesewright.com/were-still-human/" target="_blank">Writing on his website</a> about the current over-confidence in the possibilities for remote working he says:</p>



<p><em>“There is something different about being there, in person, with all of your senses engaged. It’s what I called a few years ago, ‘<a href="https://tomcheesewright.com/the-unbeatable-bandwidth-of-being-there/">the unbeatable bandwidth of being there</a>‘. What gets transmitted and received through the screen and headset, mediated by a million miles of fibre optic cable, is not the full experience of meeting. Nor does it allow for all the things that happen around those meetings. <a href="https://tomcheesewright.com/aftershocks-and-opportunities/">I’ve talked at length about the need for peer support, the subtler parts of staff training, and the mutual inspiration that happens when you’re sharing a physical space</a>.”</em></p>



<p>I’m a remote working, or at least a minimum office, enthusiast. I’ve written on this site for years about the worst aspects of office life and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2014/07/31/why-the-death-of-the-office-cant-come-too-soon/" target="_blank">the most popular post on here applauds its impending doom</a>.  Six years on though I’d admit it’s a deeply flawed argument. The idea that constant interruptions and back to back meetings were a symptom of being in a corporate building has been well and truly busted by…Microsoft Teams. </p>



<p>In truth the problem with work is not the tools or the physical location, but <a href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/01/03/ending-our-obsession-with-leadership/">the obsession with leadership</a> , an undue focus on work about work, an overbearing hierarchy and the lack of true digitisation of the enterprise. Deeper, more complex problems.  </p>



<p>It’s ironic that it has taken a pandemic to reveal what was good about the office. “The things that happen between meetings” that Tom writes about reveal our innate desire for human contact – the need to get <em>our senses fully engaged</em>. Wasteful? Quite often. But we dismiss this at our peril. It may seem logical that workplace chatter stifles productivity, but studies show the opposite to be true. </p>



<p>A narrow focus on efficiency in the workplace and a flawed view of what makes people productive is similarly regressive and likely to drag people back to the old normal. As Stowe Boyd writes the backlash against minimum office is in full flow , as detailed in <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/companies-start-to-think-remote-work-isnt-so-great-after-all-11595603397?mod=trending_now_pos1">Companies Start to Think Remote Work Isn’t So Great After All</a>, as executives want to get people back in the office:</p>



<p>“<em>An increasing number of executives now say that remote work, while necessary for safety much of this year, is not their preferred long-term solution once the coronavirus crisis passes.</em></p>



<p><em>“There’s sort of an emerging sense behind the scenes of executives saying, ‘This is not going to be sustainable,’” said Laszlo Bock, chief executive of human-resources startup Humu and the former HR chief at Google. No CEO should be surprised that the early productivity gains companies witnessed as remote work took hold have peaked and leveled off, he adds, because workers left offices in March armed with laptops and a sense of doom</em>.”</p>



<p>Perhaps it’s simply we haven’t yet matched our colleagues roles, and their specific work preferences, within our existing organisational design never mind considered a future state. Working from home (managed and supported appropriately) <strong>can</strong> be more productive than going into the office.</p>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://email.mg2.substack.com/c/eJwlUMuOwyAM_JpySwQkNHDgsJf9jYiA27BNIDKmVf5-aStZHsv2-DHeEdwznvbIhVgtgHMMdtRSX1nDILTSLJb5hgC7i5slrMCOumzRO4o5vdu1Mdqw1YZJTmJYQC9SaR8kv3IlBmcmM_qgRsXeS2ZXQ4TkwcIT8MwJ2GZXoqNchp-L_G22LthnvLdIcskbcN0cQgGHfu0eKb82CHfoXhkfgKVzCN2emzswh-opPqG7Yd67Ne_Aon2P4YYPQiiteC_6M_0JzqezJnMZ-X6XfalLIecfvc87Q3u4up0kWnGhmAgwAX1K7fW54V5TpHOG5JZ2ylcV-or4eZLOA2yCV9mAGvubbFIZOWmuWNsWctMzfShljTf6B3tch00" target="_blank">A HBR study published in August</a>&nbsp;contrasted surveys of knowledge workers from 2013 and 2020, found that remote working was in fact helping address long-held frustrations about the rhythm of office work. </p>



<ol><li>Lockdown helps us focus on the work that really matters. We are spending 12% less time drawn into large meetings and 9% more time interacting with customers and external partners.</li><li>Lockdown helps us take responsibility for our own schedules. We do 50% more activities through personal choice — because we see them as important — and half as many because someone else asked us to.</li><li>During lockdown, we view our work as more worthwhile.&nbsp; We rate the things we do as valuable to our employer&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;to ourselves. The number of tasks rated as tiresome drops from 27% to 12%, and the number we could readily offload to others drops from 41% to 27%.</li></ol>



<p>The key phrase here is: <em>managed and supported appropriately</em>. Certainly managers need to reinvent themselves as mentors to this style of working and then – forgive me – get the hell out of the way. </p>



<p>The office as the default way of working is dead. But the office itself isn’t dead. With working from home, what we gain in work-life balance we might lose in innovation and creativity. There are people who could directly challenge that sentence but I suspect they will come from highly mature companies who have fully mastered the remote working learning curve. Many of us are still at the stage of doing what we did in the office , just remotely. The timorous amongst us may use the lack of productivity net gains as a reason to regress rather than push through the ‘pain barrier’ <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://paulitaylor.com/2020/07/11/nirvana-or-business-as-usual-navigating-the-new-future-of-work/" target="_blank">as Matt Mullenweg describes it.</a> </p>



<p>We can do so much better, for ourselves, our customers and society if we stop being so frightened or so certain of the future. </p>



<p>We are going to have fewer offices and spend more time at home. </p>



<p>Our efforts would be a lot better spent improving the experience and outcomes of both rather than arguing about preserving a status quo whose time has truly run out. </p>



<p><em>The office versus remote work?</em> It’s not a binary choice we need to make. </p>



<p>The best thing you can do in any period of change is to bet on neither black or white. The future will be made up instead of shades of grey where few things are certain and <em>the best you can do to prepare is to be endlessly adaptable</em>. </p>



<hr>



<p><em>Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@bchild311?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Benjamin Child</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></em></p>
			
			
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paulitaylor.com/2020/09/12/why-do-so-many-people-want-us-back-in-the-office/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24452280</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 13:32:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Jellyfish: Toxic but fascinating]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24451504">thread link</a>) | @dnetesn
<br/>
September 12, 2020 | http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/615/toxic-but-fascinating | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/615/toxic-but-fascinating">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <p><span>I</span>t was in 1752 that Linnaeus gave jellyfish the alternative name â€˜medusaâ€™ from the Greek myth of the same name. The term was well chosen. The bell of a jellyfish is a reminder of the head of the Gorgon sister, with its tentacles, like snakes, substituting for hair. Both the mythical Medusa and her animal counterpart were capable of causing paralysis and even death.&nbsp;</p>

<p>In the version of the Medusa myth found in Ovidâ€™s <em>Metamorphoses</em>, Medusa, one of three Gorgon sisters, was originally depicted as a great beauty whose attractive powers did not go unnoticed. Her hair was only transformed into serpents by the goddess Athena as a punishment. Medusa had been ravished by the sea god Poseidon in Athenaâ€™s own temple and because the temple had been defiled, Athena gave Medusa the power to change any human who looked upon her into stone. Perseus, the son of Zeus and half-brother of Athena, was asked by Polydectes to secure the head of Medusa. Instead of gazing on the Gorgon sister and risking being petrified, Perseus used the reflection on his shield to guide him while removing Medusaâ€™s head with his sword. From her decapitated torso sprang two children, Pegasus, a flying horse, and Chrysaor, a warrior with a golden sword. The transformative powers of Medusaâ€™s head were retained following its separation from the body and when Perseus laid down the head on the seashore, the escaping blood was said to be the origin of red coral (intriguing, knowing the close relationship that exists between jellyfish and coral).&nbsp;<br></p>
<p>Caravaggioâ€™s depiction of Medusa, painted towards the end of the sixteenth century, echoes her destructive yet beautiful power while another painting, initially thought to be by Leonardo da Vinci, was to inspire a famous poem by Shelley:&nbsp;</p>
<p><span>â€™Tis the tempestuous loveliness of terror; <br>For from the serpents gleams a brazen glare <br>Kindled by that inextricable error,<br>Which makes a thrilling vapour of the air <br>Become a [ ] and ever-shifting mirror.<br>Of all the beauty and the terror there-
A womanâ€™s countenance, with serpent locks, <br>Gazing in death on heaven from those wet rocks.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>A more up-to-date version of Medusa is seen in Frank Mooreâ€™s painting <em>To Die For</em>. It features the model Kate Moss, her severed head alive with serpents. It was a painting commissioned by Gianni Versace, who never saw it since he was killed before Moore had completed the work. Moore himself died prematurely of AIDS in 2002, aged 48. The picture featured in an exhibition in New York called <em>Toxic Beauty: The Art of Frank Moor</em>e.<br></p>
<figure><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/nautilus-vertical/oceans_805b7becd4587e52023de0fe709ad787.jpg" alt="Medusa_by_Carvaggio"><figcaption><span>A ceremonial shield depicting the severed head of Medusa, painted in the late 16th century by Caravaggio. </span><br><span>Wikimedia Commons</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>In her poem â€˜Medusa,â€™ Sylvia Plath successfully combines the mythical creature and the sea animal. Written shortly before her own death, it portrays her mother, with whom she had a difficult relationship, as a destructive monster clinging to her by a â€˜cableâ€™, akin to a jellyfish tentacle, and intent on controlling, indeed paralysing, her. It is as though Plath felt the need to exorcize her mother from her life in order to achieve some emotional distance, as well as to afford her greater freedom to write and compose. Plath could be said to have used the device of the snake-haired Gorgon to describe her own internal image of a monstrous mother. Ironically, her mother shared her first name with that of a common genus of jellyfish, <em>Aurelia</em>.&nbsp;<br></p>
<p>Freud came to regard Medusaâ€™s head as a symbol of castration. In a short, posthumously published essay, â€˜Das Medusenhauptâ€™, he equates decapitation with being castrated, arguing that when a boy views female genitalia for the first time he suddenly realizes the possession of a penis cannot be taken for granted, leading to a specific anxiety about castration. In the same way, glimpsing the Medusaâ€™s head causes a male observer to be struck dumb, on the one hand fascinated by what he sees and, on the other, paralysed with fear.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Medusa myth, with its built-in ambiguity (deadly but fascinating), has served to reinforce our own ambivalence towards this sea creature. It may also have created a reluctance on the part of scientists to work with these animals. There is however no doubting that, when seen in its natural environment, the jellyfish displays that other, more positive quality, an ability to hold our attention, indeed to fascinate. This is explored in Marianne Mooreâ€™s poem â€˜A Jelly-fishâ€™, where the creature exerts â€˜a fluctuating charmâ€™.</p>
<center>
<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/456062181?color=ffcd05&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
<p>A <em>Crossota</em> jellyfish filmed at the Enigma Seamount in the Marianas Trench, more than two miles beneath the ocean surface. CREDIT: Courtesy of the NOAA Office of Ocean Exploration and Research.</p>
</center>
<p>&nbsp;Jellyfish escape as quickly as they appear and while they may be allowed to touch us, they themselves often resist capture. They appear both alluring and elusive. The very nature of their movement contributes to their ethereal beauty, and where better to observe this than in a tropical lagoon? The Raja Ampat islands off West Papua boast several. Others can be found on the Kakaban islands off Borneo. In both places the jellyfish have lost their ability to sting humans, making it possible to appreciate their delicacy and movement in safety. In the Ampat islands, the lagoons are connected to the ocean through underwater channels that limit the entry and exit of seawater. In addition, the water there is stratified into an oxygen-rich surface layer where the jellyfish live and a deeper layer, devoid of oxygen, where they are absent. Two genera of jellyfish, the so-called golden jellyfish, <em>Mastigias</em>, and the moon jellyfish, <em>Aurelia</em>, coexist there. The species of <em>Mastigias</em> found in Ampat has lost the spots on its bell and oral arms and the marine biologist Michael Dawson believes this indicates a new subspecies has evolved there with no appreciable sting, presumably as the result of geographical isolation.</p>
<p>The slow, seemingly directionless pulsation of jellyfish can have a calming effect and lends itself to hospital and general practice waiting rooms, a feature as yet unexploited. Its languid movement calls into question how efficient this is as a means of locomotion. Work done at Woods Hole Marine Biological Laboratory in Massachusetts is providing the answer. It seems that jellyfish have a special way of recapturing some of the energy expended on each swimming stroke. When a medusa contracts its bell, it creates two vortex rings. The first is shed in its wake, propelling the animal forwards. The second, during the relaxa- tion phase, rolls under the bell. This second vortex ring spins faster than the first and, as it does so, sucks in water which pushes up against the underside of the bell, giving the jellyfish a second- ary boost. It is a technique that works only at slow speeds and when the body size is small. The conclusion reached by Brad Gemmell and his team at Woods Hole is that a jellyfish expends less energy in travelling a given distance than any other marine animal so far studied. Its efficiency, however, comes at a price, namely low speed and virtually no maneuverability.&nbsp;</p>
<p>It would be wrong, however, to dismiss the humble jellyfish as a primitive automaton, unable to modify its movement and behaviour. By attaching accelerometers to the barrel jellyfish, <em>Rhizostoma pulmo</em>, it has been shown that it is able to orientate its swimming in relation to the direction of the tides. When the tide withdraws from the shore, this particular jellyfish orientates itself so as to swim against the current. When the tide flows towards the shore, it also swims in a consistent direction, either with or against the current, depending on the depth of the water. This appears to be a mechanism for keeping jellyfish together as a swarm and avoiding their becoming stranded on the shore.</p>
<center>
<iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/456062042?color=ffcd05&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen=""><span id="selection-marker-1" class="redactor-selection-marker"></span></iframe>
<p><em>Cassiopea</em>, the upside-down jellyfish, are the most evolutionarily ancient creature known to sleep. CREDIT: Caltech</p>
</center>
<p>The fascination that jellyfish engender in us deepens when we consider recent discoveries about another aspect of their behaviour, one which mirrors our own. In the so-called upside- down jellyfish, <em>Cassiopea</em>, it is possible to witness periods of diminished activity resembling sleep from which the creature is only slowly aroused (reminiscent of our own behaviour when sleep deprived). Like us, this jellyfish becomes â€˜sleepyâ€™ when exposed to the naturally occurring chemical melatonin. Sleep, or at least periods of cyclical inactivity, would appear to have arisen early on in evolution, well in advance of the possession of advanced nervous systems.&nbsp;<br></p>
<p>Earlier in the book, I stressed how the anatomy and the life cycle of jellyfish proved to be more complex than previously imagined. The behaviour of jellyfish in their natural habitat is proving equally complicated. We know that migrations of jellyfish in a horizontal direction are guided by the position of the sun. The golden jellyfish in Palau, for example, follow the sunâ€™s arc across the sky. Before sunrise, they cluster at the western end of Jellyfish Lake. With the dawn, they swim in an easterly direction towards the light, following the sun until they reach the eastern shore. As the sun continues towards the western horizon, the jellyfish reverse their course and return to the western shore to await the new day.&nbsp;</p>
<figure><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/nautilus-vertical/oceans_4fb5ec979b6ccebb925978ba8c39ebd6.jpg" alt="Palau Jellies"><figcaption><span>Golden jellyfish following the sun in Jellyfish Lake, Palau. </span><br><span>Richard Schneider</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Vertical migration also occurs. Using echo sounders in a deep Norwegian fjord, the movements of individual helmet jellyfish,&nbsp; <em>Periphylla</em> <em>periphylla</em>, were monitored. This species of jellyfish segregates itself into assemblages. Each assemblage shows a different preference as far as vertical positioning in the water is concerned. Night-time groups congregate for the purpose of feeding and reproduction while other groups form for brief periods in other situations, only to disperse and then re-group. It has been suggested that this represents a type of social behaviour and …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/615/toxic-but-fascinating">http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/615/toxic-but-fascinating</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/615/toxic-but-fascinating</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24451504</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 10:51:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[EduTech Spyware Is Still Spyware: Proctorio Edition]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24450248">thread link</a>) | @some_furry
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://soatok.blog/2020/09/12/edutech-spyware-is-still-spyware-proctorio-edition/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soatok.blog/2020/09/12/edutech-spyware-is-still-spyware-proctorio-edition/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p>Spyware written for educational institutions to flex their muscles of control over students and their families when learning from their home computer is still, categorically, spyware.</p>



<p>Depending on your persuasion, the previous sentence sounds like either needless pedantry, or it reads like tautology. But we need to be clear on our terms.</p>



<ol><li>Educational spyware is still spyware.</li><li>Spyware is categorized as a subset of malware.</li></ol>



<p>When vulnerabilities are discovered in malware, the normal rules of <a href="https://adamcaudill.com/2015/11/19/responsible-disclosure-is-wrong/">coordinated disclosure</a> are out of scope. Are we clear?</p>







<p>So let’s talk about Proctorio!</p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">For anyone unfamiliar with it, Proctorio is a browser extension used to eliminate cheating through intense surveillance techniques. It records the computer screen while you take the exam to ensure you don’t look anything up. However, it’s more than that. (Thread 1/11)</p>— Cassie (@Angry_Cassie) <a href="https://twitter.com/Angry_Cassie/status/1301360994044850182?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 3, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div><figcaption>The entire thread is unrolled <a href="https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1301360994044850182.html">here</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>I won’t go into the details of Proctorio or why it’s terrible for (especially disadvantaged) students. Read Cassie’s Twitter thread for more context on that. Seriously. I’m not gonna be one of those guys that <em>talks over</em> women, and neither should you.</p>



<p>What I am here to talk about today is these dubious claim about the security of their product:</p>







<h2 id="zero-knowledge">Zero-Knowledge Encryption? OMGWTFBBQ!</h2>



<p>In cryptography, there are a class of algorithms called Zero-Knowledge Proofs. In a Zero-Knowledge Proof, you prove that you possess some fact without revealing any details <em>about</em> the fact.</p>



<p>It’s kind of abstract to think about (and until we’re ready to talk about Pedersen commitments, I’m just going to defer to <a href="https://openprivacy.ca/work/swisspost-scytl-evoting/">Sarah Jamie Lewis</a>), but the only thing you need to know about “Zero Knowledge” in Cryptography is that the output is a boolean (True, False).</p>



<p>You can’t use “Zero Knowledge” <em>anything</em> to encrypt. So “Zero-Knowledge Encryption” is a meaningless buzzword.</p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">As a cryptographer, I would like details on how on Earth it is using zero knowledge proofs in this situation. In all likelihood they're not doing what "zero knowledge" usually means, which quite frankly has me more worried about the security, not less.</p>— Buchberger's algorithm fan account (@SchmiegSophie) <a href="https://twitter.com/SchmiegSophie/status/1304407483658592256?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 11, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div></figure>



<p>So what are they actually describing when they say Zero Knowledge Encryption?</p>







<p>Okay, so they’ve built their own key distribution system and are encrypting with AES-GCM… and shipped this in a Chrome extension. But before we get to that, look at this <strong>Daily Vulnerability Tests</strong> claim.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1204" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-04/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-04" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/soatoktelegrams2020-04.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Bullshit.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Running Nessus (or equivalent) on a cron job isn’t meaningful metric of security. At best, it creates alert fatigue when you accidentally screw up a deployment configuration or forget to update your software for 4+ years. (Y’know, like JsZip 3.2.1, which they bundle.)</p>



<p>A dumb vulnerability scan isn’t the same thing as a routine (usually quarterly) penetration test or a code audit. And if you’re working in cryptography, <em>you better have both</em>!</p>



<h2 id="vulnerability">Timing Leaks in Proctorio’s AES-GCM Implementation</h2>



<p>If you download version 1.4.20241.1.0 of the Proctorio Chrome Extension, run <code>src/assets/J5HG.js</code> through a JS beautifier, and then look at its contents, you will quickly realize this is a JavaScript cryptography library.</p>



<p>Since the “zero knowledge” encryption they’re so proud about uses AES-GCM, let’s focus on that.</p>



<p>Proctorio’s AES-GCM implementation exists in an object called <code>dhs.mode.gcm</code>, which is mildly obfuscated, but contains the following functions:</p>



<ul><li><code>encrypt()</code> – Encrypt with AES-GCM</li><li><code>decrypt()</code> – Decrypt with AES-GCM</li><li><code>aa()</code> – GHASH block multiplication</li><li><code>j()</code> – XOR + GMAC utility function</li><li><code>O()</code> – Called by encrypt() and decrypt(); does all of the AES-CTR + GMAC fun</li></ul>



<p>If you’re not familiar with <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/05/13/why-aes-gcm-sucks/">AES-GCM</a>, just know this: <a href="https://cryptologie.net/article/361/breaking-https-aes-gcm-or-a-part-of-it/">Timing leaks</a> can be used to leak your GMAC key to outside applications, which completely breaks the authentication of AES-GCM and opens the door to chosen-ciphertext attacks.</p>



<p>So is their implementation of AES-GCM constant-time? Let’s take a look at <code>aa()</code>:</p>


<pre title="">aa: function(a, b) {
  var c, d, e, f, g, h = dhs.bitArray.ba;
  for (e = [0, 0, 0, 0], f = b.slice(0), c = 0; 128 &gt; c; c++) {
    for (
      (d = 0 !== (a[Math.floor(c / 32)] &amp; 1 &lt;&lt; 31 - c % 32)) &amp;&amp; (e = h(e, f)),
        g = 0 !== (1 &amp; f[3]),
        d = 3;
      d &gt; 0;
      d--
    )
      f[d] = f[d] &gt;&gt;&gt; 1 | (1 &amp; f[d - 1]) &lt;&lt; 31;
    f[0] &gt;&gt;&gt;= 1,
    g &amp;&amp; (f[0] ^= -520093696)
  }
  return e
},
</pre>


<p>This is a bit obtuse, but this line leaks the lowest bit of <code>f</code> with each iteration: <code>g = 0 !== (1 &amp; f[3])</code>.</p>



<p>Since <code>f</code> gets bitwise right-shifted 128 times, this actually leaks the bit of every value of <code>f</code> in each block multiplication, since the execution of <code>(f[0] ^= -520093696)</code> depends on whether or not <code>g</code> is set to <code>true</code>.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="1387" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatoktelegrams2020-11/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="SoatokTelegrams2020-11" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/soatoktelegrams2020-11.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Timing leaks? So much for “zero-knowledge”!</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Also, they claim to be FIPS 140-2 compliant, but this is how they generate randomness in their cryptography library.</p>



<figure><div>

</div></figure>



<p>(Although, <a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/projects/cryptographic-module-validation-program/validated-modules/search?SearchMode=Basic&amp;Vendor=Proctorio&amp;CertificateStatus=Active&amp;ValidationYear=0">that’s probably a lie</a>.)</p>



<p>To mitigate these vulnerabilities, one needs look no further than <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/08/27/soatoks-guide-to-side-channel-attacks/#conditional-select">the guide to side-channel attacks</a> I published last month. </p>



<p>(Also, use WebCrypto to generate entropy! What the fuck.)</p>



<h2>If Proctorio is Insecure, What Should We Use Instead?</h2>



<p><strong>Nothing.</strong></p>



<p>Schools that demand students install spyware on their personal computers are only a step removed from domestic abusers who install stalkerware on their victims’ phones.</p>



<p>Proctorio isn’t the problem here, they’re only a symptom.</p>



<p>Schools that insist on violating the integrity and parental dominion of their students’ home computers are the problem here.</p>



<figure><div>
<div><blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Zoom school is really showing how much of American Education is just about controlling and punishing children and not actually, you know, teaching and educating them</p>— Lawrence of A Labia (@lex_about_sex) <a href="https://twitter.com/lex_about_sex/status/1304156305398140928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2020</a></blockquote></div>
</div><figcaption>Preach!</figcaption></figure>



<p>If you want to ensure the integrity of students’ education, try teaching them about consent and ethical computing. (Y’know, concepts that are fundamentally incompatible with the business model of Proctorio and Proctorio’s competitors.)</p>



<h2 id="timeline">Disclosure Timeline</h2>



<p>Really? <em>Really?</em></p>



<p>This was a zero-day disclosure, because full disclosure is the responsible choice when dealing with spyware. Don’t even @ me.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="70" data-permalink="https://soatok.blog/soatok_stickerpack-hacker/" data-orig-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png" data-orig-size="512,512" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="soatok_stickerpack-hacker" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=512" src="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=512" alt="" srcset="https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png 512w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=150 150w, https://soatok.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/soatok_stickerpack-hacker.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"><figcaption>Disclaimer: This security research was conducted by Soatok– some furry on the Internet–while bored on his off-time and does not reflect the opinions of any company.</figcaption></figure></div>



<h2 id="sinkhole">Domains to Sinkhole</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to protect your home network from this spyware, here are a list of domains to sinkhole (i.e. with <a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi-Hole</a>).</p>



<ul><li>proctorauth.com</li><li>proctordata.com</li><li>getproctorio.com</li><li>proctor.io</li><li>proctor.in</li><li>az545770.vo.msecnd.net</li></ul>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soatok.blog/2020/09/12/edutech-spyware-is-still-spyware-proctorio-edition/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24450248</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 06:09:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Sketching Algorithms for High Dimensional, Large Datasets]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24448669">thread link</a>) | @ArtWomb
<br/>
September 11, 2020 | https://www.sketchingbigdata.org/fall20/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.sketchingbigdata.org/fall20/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            



<h2 id="cs-294-165-fall-2020-syllabus-fall20-syllabus">CS 294-165 - Fall 2020 (<a href="https://www.sketchingbigdata.org/fall20/syllabus">Syllabus</a>)</h2>

<p><strong><strong>Sketching algorithms</strong></strong> compress data in a way that is still useful for answering some pre-specified family of queries, possibly across datasets by comparing sketches. This course will cover mathematically rigorous models for developing such algorithms, as well as some provable limitations of algorithms operating in those models. Some topics covered include:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Streaming algorithms.</strong> Compute useful statistics over a dataset making only one pass over it, while using little memory.</p></li>

<li><p><strong>Dimensionality reduction.</strong> General techniques and impossibility results for reducing data dimension while still preserving geometric structure.</p></li>

<li><p><strong>Randomized linear algebra.</strong> Algorithms for big matrices (e.g. a user/product rating matrix for Netflix or Amazon). Regression, low rank approximation, clustering, etc.</p></li>

<li><p><strong>Compressed sensing.</strong> Recovery of (approximately) sparse signals based on few linear measurements.</p></li>
</ul>

<p>This is a graduate course, though there may be room for a limited number of advanced undergraduate students satisfying the following prerequisites: mathematical maturity and comfort with algorithms (e.g. CS 170), discrete probability, and linear algebra.</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.sketchingbigdata.org/fall20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24448669</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:08:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
