<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 20:23:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 20:23:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Satoshi Did Not Know (2015) [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 138 | Comments 139 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24378055">thread link</a>) | @MrXOR
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://www.ifca.ai/pub/fc15/89750001.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ifca.ai/pub/fc15/89750001.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ifca.ai/pub/fc15/89750001.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24378055</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 19:21:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Build a State]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24377232">thread link</a>) | @tnorthcutt
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://www.worksinprogress.co/issue/how-to-build-a-state/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.worksinprogress.co/issue/how-to-build-a-state/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
					<div>
						<p>It’s easy to imagine that governments were always as bureaucratic as they are today. Certain policies, like the widespread granting of monopolies in the seventeenth century, or the presence of a powerful landed aristocracy, seem like archaic products of a past that was simply more corrupt. The fact that governments rarely got involved with healthcare or education before the mid-nineteenth century seems the product of a lack of imagination, or perhaps yet another product of our ancestors’ venality – simply what happens when you put the war-hungry knights and nobles in charge.</p>
<p>But the bureaucratic state of today, with its officials involving themselves with every aspect of modern life, is a relatively recent invention. In a world without bureaucracy, when state capacity was relatively lacking, it’s difficult to see what other options monarchs would have had. Suppose yourself transported to the throne of England in 1500, and crowned monarch. Once you bored of the novelty and luxuries of being head of state, you might become concerned about the lot of the common man and woman. Yet even if you wanted to create a healthcare system, or make education free and universal to all children, or even create a police force (London didn’t get one until 1829, and the rest of the country not til much later), there is absolutely no way you could succeed.</p>
<p>For a start, you would struggle to maintain your hold on power. Fund schools you say? Somebody will have to pay. The nobles? Well, try to tax them — in many European states they were exempt from taxation — and you might quickly lose both your throne and your head. And supposing you do manage to tax them, after miraculously stamping out an insurrection without their support, how would you even begin to go about collecting it? There was simply no central government agency capable of raising it. Working out how much people should pay, chasing up non-payers, and even the physical act of collection, not to mention protecting that treasure once collected, all takes substantial manpower. Not to mention the fact that the collecting agents will likely siphon most of it off to line their own pockets.</p>
<p>As a monarch in 1500, you would be forced to rely heavily on delegation. As the economic historian Jared Rubin emphasizes, every ruler requires agents to propagate their rule. These can take the form of big burly blokes with heavy weapons — your enforcers — and they can take the form of people spreading the ideology of your right to rule, lending your orders legitimacy and more generally spreading social norms of obedience — the local officials, jurists, and clerics. Crucially, these propagating agents needed to be kept on-side at all costs. Hence the tax exemptions for nobles, many of whom were rich enough to support their own private armies, and whose ancestors might have been granted such a privilege by one of your predecessors.</p>
<p>Joan of Arc’s village, for example, was exempted from taxation <i>forever,</i> because of her role in restoring the French king’s military fortunes. And hence the control often exerted over policy by religious figures, who could give one’s rule divine sanction in the eyes of the people. It is no surprise that the emperors of China carefully cultivated themselves at the head of as many religions as possible (one of the reasons that Christianity, with its rather awkward stress on Jesus being the king of kings, was occasionally banned from the empire). As economic historians Mark Koyama and Noel Johnson argue, this focus on appeasing religious legitimisers was one of the reasons rulers so often sought to stamp out heretics and heathens.</p>
<p>Even beyond satisfying the propagating agents, however, core state activities like tax collection were heavily reliant on delegation of authority. Absent an expensive bureaucracy to do it on your behalf, it was much easier to farm out the activity to others. When taxing a predominantly agrarian society — in 1500, only 3.6% of England’s population lived in cities — it made most sense to appoint a local noble to be tax farmer for an area. As a local, they would know the area well, and the products of the land are relatively straightforward to tax. It’s not exactly easy to hide. And as for the tax farmer, they could be remunerated by taking a cut of what they collected. Corrupt, yes. But inevitable and even seen as legitimate, given the lack of alternatives.</p>
<p>Your capacity as a ruler was thus entirely governed by the <em>quid pro quo</em>, and heavily restricted by the deals made by your predecessors. Cities were granted charters, giving them various rights of self-governance, in return for collecting taxes from among their own members (commerce and industry being much harder to tax than land, and thus requiring more consent). And, of course, there were occasionally times when the defence of the realm might require extra taxes — for such instances, rulers convened parliaments. Taxes raised by parliaments were referred to, somewhat confusingly, as “subsidies”. But that is exactly what they were: special subsidies granted to the monarch, by the collected representatives of the nobles and the various other propagating agents, for a one-off extraordinary purpose – albeit giving those collected agents some say over policy.</p>
<p>It was not until 1689, when there was a coup, that an incoming ruler allowed the English parliament to sit whenever it pleased. Before that, it was convened only at the whim of the ruler, and dispersed even at the slightest provocation. In 1621, for example, when James I was planning to marry his heir to a Spanish princess, Parliament sent him a petition asserting their right to debate the matter. Upon hearing of it, he called for the official record of parliamentary proceedings, personally ripped out the page with the offending vote, and promptly dissolved the Parliament. The downside, of course, was that James could not then acquire any parliamentary subsidies.</p>
<p>Ruling was thus an intensely personal affair, of making deals and finding ways to circumvent deals you had inherited. Increasing your capabilities as a ruler – state capacity – was thus no easy task, as the typical ruler was stuck in an essentially medieval equilibrium. Imposing a policy costs money, but raising money involves imposing policy. Breaking out of this chicken-and-egg problem took centuries of canny leadership. The rulers who achieved it most would today seem hopelessly corrupt.</p>
<p>To gain extra cash without interference from Parliament, successive monarchs first asserted and then abused their ancient prerogative rights to grant monopolies over trades and industries. They eventually granted them to whomever was willing to pay, establishing monopolies over industries like gambling cards or alehouses under the guise of regulating unsavoury activities. They also sold off knighthoods and titles, and in 1670 Charles II even made a secret deal with the French that he would convert to Catholicism and attack the Protestant Dutch, all in exchange for cash. Anything to not have to call a potentially pesky Parliament. At times, the most effective rulers even resembled mob bosses. Take Elizabeth I’s anger when a cloth-laden merchant fleet bound for an Antwerp fair in 1559 was allowed to depart. Her order to stop them had not arrived in time, thus preventing her from extracting “loans” from the merchants while she still had their goods within her power.</p>
<p>Yet, ironically, it was when monarchs lost control that they did most to boost the capabilities of the centralised state. It was under Parliament, first in the 1650s when it briefly overthrew the monarchy, and then from the late 1680s following its deal with the usurping William III, that British state capacity began to most rapidly and inexorably grow. Likewise, in France, it was following the French Revolution that the steady rise of state capacity was boosted — it was then, over three centuries after the fact, that the perpetual tax exemptions for Joan of Arc’s village were finally rescinded.</p>
<p>Parliaments, as bodies of legitimising agents, despite their lack of representation in any modern democratic sense, had the unquestioned legitimacy with which to raise taxes, change policy, and undo the deals of previous monarchs. In the process, they often trampled on the ancient liberties of citizens and subjects. But, unlike monarchs, they found it much easier to force the changes through. When motivated by the needs of war — often the one thing members could agree on — parliaments in the eighteenth century were able to raise cash that would have been unfathomable to the monarchs of even a few decades before. And it was parliaments, also, that were eventually susceptible in the nineteenth century to the lobbying of those who wished the state to involve itself in areas like education, health, and policing.</p>
<p>The route to state capacity thus took centuries of blood, dirty dealing, corruption and campaigning to make the states we have to today. But it is difficult to see how it could have been done in any other way.</p>
					</div>
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.worksinprogress.co/issue/how-to-build-a-state/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24377232</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 17:50:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: AnyLeaf – PH Sensor for Microcontrollers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24376990">thread link</a>) | @the__alchemist
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://www.anyleaf.org/ph-module | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.anyleaf.org/ph-module">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

        <div>
            <p><img src="https://www.anyleaf.org/static/logo.png" width="300" alt="AnyLeaf"></p>
            <h2>For Arduino, Raspberry Pi, embedded</h2>
        </div>

        <p>
            <h2>Accurate</h2>
            <h2>Easy to use</h2>
            <h2>Affordable</h2>
        </p>

        <div>
            <div>
                <p><img src="https://www.anyleaf.org/static/ph_with_probe_cropped.jpg" width="640px">
                </p>
                
                <p onclick="addToCart(1)">
                    <h2>Buy with pH probe for $60</h2>
                </p>
            </div>

            <div>
                <p><img src="https://www.anyleaf.org/static/ph_cropped.jpg" width="640px">
                </p>

                <p onclick="addToCart(2)">
                    <h2>Buy without probe for $20</h2>
                </p>
            </div>

        </div>

        <p><img src="https://www.anyleaf.org/static/ph_probe_cropped.jpg" width="640px">
        </p>

        <h2>For laboratory, hydroponics, aquarium, and brewing</h2>

        <p>Available with lab-grade pH probe. Connects directly to your
            device (Arduino, Raspberry Pi, or embedded) - no other parts required. Our
            open-source software makes measuring fast and easy.</p>

        <h2>Suitable for continuous immersion</h2>

        <h3>Beyond pH</h3>
        <p>Includes temperature compensation, with built in sensor. Can be used with
            Oxidation Reduction Potential(ORP) , and other ion-selective electrodes.
            (Nitrate, Potassium, etc)

            probes.</p>

        <p>This module can be used with any probe with a BNC connection.
            The I2C interface can send data to nearly any microcontroler.</p>

        <h3>Fully tested on <a href="https://www.arduino.cc/">Arduino</a>,
            <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/">Raspberry Pi</a>, and
            <a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f3-series.html">STM32</a></h3>

        <h4>Output pins are labeled on the board, as follows:</h4>
        <ul>
            <li>+VCC: 2V – 5V power input</li>
            <li>SDA: I²C digital output</li>
            <li>SCL: I²C digital output</li>
            <li>GND: Ground</li>
        </ul>

        <h2>Arduino wiring</h2>
        <p><img src="https://www.anyleaf.org/static/arduino_diagram.png" width="500">
        </p>

        <h2>Raspberry Pi wiring</h2>
        <p><img src="https://www.anyleaf.org/static/pi_diagram.png" width="600">
        </p>

        
        <p><b>Arduino: </b> From the Arduino IDE: <i>Sketch</i> → <i>Include Library</i> →
            <i>Manage Libraries</i> → select <i><a href="https://www.arduino.cc/reference/en/libraries/anyleaf/">Anyleaf</a></i></p>
        <p><b>C++: </b>Download <i>Anyleaf.cpp</i>
            and <i>Anyleaf.h</i> from the C++ Github link below, and place them in your project directory
        </p>
        <p><b>Python: </b>Run <i>sudo apt install python3-scipy</i>, then
            <i>pip3 install <a href="https://pypi.org/project/anyleaf/">anyleaf</a></i>

        </p>
        <ul>
            <li><h3><a href="https://github.com/anyleaf/ph-cpp" target="_blank">Arduino and C++</a></h3></li>
            <li><h3><a href="https://github.com/anyleaf/anyleaf-python" target="_blank">Python</a></h3></li>
            <li><h3><a href="https://github.com/anyleaf/anyleaf-rust" target="_blank">Rust</a></h3></li>
        </ul>

        <h2>A miminal Arduino example</h2>

        <!--
        Syntax highlighting by http://hilite.me/


#include <Anyleaf.h>

PhSensor ph_sensor;

void setup(void) {
    Serial.begin(9600);

    ph_sensor = PhSensor();

    ph_sensor.calibrate_all(
        CalPt(0., 7., 25.), CalPt(0.18, 4., 25.)
    );
}

void loop(void) {
    Serial.print("pH: "); Serial.println(ph_sensor.read());

    delay(1000);
}
        !-->



        <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>#include &lt;Anyleaf.h&gt;</span>

PhSensor ph_sensor;

<span>void</span> <span>setup</span>(<span>void</span>) {
    Serial.begin(<span>9600</span>);

    ph_sensor = PhSensor();

    ph_sensor.calibrate_all(
        CalPt(<span>0.</span>, <span>7.</span>, <span>25.</span>), CalPt(<span>0.18</span>, <span>4.</span>, <span>25.</span>)
    );
}

<span>void</span> <span>loop</span>(<span>void</span>) {
    Serial.print(<span>"pH: "</span>); Serial.println(ph_sensor.read());

    delay(<span>1000</span>);
}
</pre></div>

        <!--
import time
import board
import busio
from anyleaf import PhSensor, CalPt, OnBoard

def main():
    i2c = busio.I2C(board.SCL, board.SDA)
    delay = 1  # Time between measurements, in seconds
    ph_sensor = PhSensor(i2c, delay)

    ph_sensor.calibrate_all(
        CalPt(0., 7., 25.), CalPt(0.18, 4., 25.)
    )

    while True:
        print(f"pH: {ph_sensor.read(OnBoard())}")

        time.sleep(delay)


if __name__ == "__main__":
    main()
        -->

        <h2>A miminal Raspberry Pi Python example</h2>

        <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>import</span> <span>time</span>
<span>import</span> <span>board</span>
<span>import</span> <span>busio</span>
<span>from</span> <span>anyleaf</span> <span>import</span> PhSensor, CalPt, OnBoard

<span>def</span> <span>main</span>():
    i2c = busio.I2C(board.SCL, board.SDA)
    delay = <span>1</span>  <span># Time between measurements, in seconds</span>
    ph_sensor = PhSensor(i2c, delay)

    ph_sensor.calibrate_all(
        CalPt(<span>0.</span>, <span>7.</span>, <span>25.</span>), CalPt(<span>0.18</span>, <span>4.</span>, <span>25.</span>)
    )

    <span>while</span> <span>True</span>:
        <span>print</span>(f<span>"pH: {ph_sensor.read(OnBoard())}"</span>)

        time.sleep(delay)


<span>if</span> __name__ == <span>"__main__"</span>:
    main()
</pre></div>

    <h2><a href="https://www.anyleaf.org/static/ph-module-datasheet.pdf">Datasheet</a></h2>

    <p>Regular calibration is required for accurate measurements.
        The official drivers support 2 or 3 point calibration. 2 point is sufficient for
        hydroponics, aquarium, or brewing use. 3 points, or 2 carefully chosen points are required
        for sufficient accuracy for lab use.</p>

    <h2>Specifications:</h2>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Module dimensions:</b> 50 × 25 × 17(height) mm</li>
        <li><b>Module weight:</b> 14 grams</li>
        <li><b>pH precision:</b> .01, with a suitable sensor</li>
        <li><b>pH Range:</b> 0 - 14</li>
        <li><b>Digital precision:</b> 16 bit</li>
        <li><b>Input voltage:</b> 2 - 5V</li>
        <li><b>Mounting screws:</b> 4 × M3, 6mm len (included)</li>
        <li><b>I2C address:</b> 0×48 or 0x49 (selectable)</li>
        <li><b>Sensor interface:</b> BNC male (Accepts BNC female sensors)</li>
        <li><b>Power consumption:</b> 375μA</li>
        <li><b>UPC / GTIN:</b> 860004179009</li>
    </ul>

    <h2>Specifications pertaining to the pH probe only:</h2>
    <ul>
        <li><b>Design:</b> Double junction glass hydrogen-sensitive electrode</li>
        <li><b>Dimensions:</b> 155 × 12 mm</li>
        <li><b>Weight:</b> 24g</li>
        <li><b>Measurement range:</b> 0 - 14</li>
        <li><b>Outer tube material:</b> Plastic</li>
        <li><b>Bulb shape:</b> Spherical</li>
        <li><b>Cable length:</b> 1 m</li>
        <li><b>Connector:</b> BNC female</li>
        <li><b>Temperature range: </b>0-80°C</li>
    </ul>

    <p>Compatible with the <a href="https://kizniche.github.io/Mycodo/">Mycodo Environmental
        Monitoring and Regulation System</a>. If you're using a Raspberry Pi, this is a simple
        way to get it running with a GUI, charts, and logging. Just follow the installation instructions
        on that page, and add <i>Anyleaf pH</i> as an <i>input</i>.
    </p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.anyleaf.org/ph-module</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24376990</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 17:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Massacring C Pointers (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 148 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24376622">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/1/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/1/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<p>
I'm taking a break from debugging books to talk about a calamitous shitshow of textbook writing: <i>Mastering C Pointers: Tools for Programming Power</i>, by Robert J. Traister.
</p>

<p>
I learned of the book through a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8SUkrR7ZfTA">talk</a> by Brian Kernighan where he refers to the book as probably “the worst C programming textbook ever written.”<span>[<a id="fnr.1" href="#fn.1">1</a>]</span>
He doesn't name it but <a href="https://twitter.com/johnregehr/status/1003411102791692288">with some help</a> I was able to track down his obliquely accurate reference.
</p>

<p>
This book has become my <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=white%20whale">white whale</a>.
Since I started reading debugging books, and especially now that I'm digging through older ones, I find bits of advice that simply don't work today.
While some of it could be construed as useless or idiotic, I've always found the authors come from a position of earnestness, attempting to draw the best conclusions based on decent principles and what they knew at the time they wrote it.
In some cases they may not have known much, but they're honestly and humbly trying to impart some wisdom.
</p>

<p>
When Kernighan put up the following example, I saw what seemed to be the opposite of that.
</p>

<pre>char *combine(s, t)
char *s, *t;
{

      int x, y;
      char r[100];

      strcpy(r, s);
      y = strlen(r);
      for (x = y; *t != '\0'; ++x)
           r[x] = *t++;

      r[x] = '\0';

      return(r);

}
</pre>

<p>
This program (formatting preserved) is taken from the first edition of the book (p.146).
It's horrific (Kernighan calls it “malpractice”).
It does not exhibit the genuineness I have seen with, say, books from the late 1970s on how to debug BASIC programs.
I didn't know what it was.
Deceit?
Laziness?
Unremitting ignorance?
What is the mindset of someone who writes this, presumably thinking it's a good idea?
Can the whole book be that bad?
Kernighan said it was.
I had to know.
</p>

<p>
The book has two editions: the first was published in 1990, the second in 1993.
The fact that there are two editions piqued my curiosity even more.
It sold enough to make another version?
Is that horrible example corrected?
I obtained a copy of each and read them.
</p>

<p>
Reviewing the book is pointless.
Kernighan was right: it's garbage.
And the second edition only makes things worse.
Teaching from either one would be a breach of ethics.
If you follow Traister’s coding practices, even adjusted for today's standards, you are <i>guaranteed</i> to create defects and vicious, latent bugs.
A subtly pernicious aspect of the book is the casual tone of the writing.
It’s informal enough that if you don’t really know much about C what he says sort of makes sense, despite the sloppy terminology and mixed, inaccurate metaphors.
</p>

<p>
Any trained programmer will recognize the lessons as worthless.
His terminology is all over the map and typically inaccurate, if not plainly wrong.
Expressions “return a value.”
Values are “handed” into locations.
Constants are “written directly into the program.”
A union is a “specialized pointer.”
The terminology isn’t even consistent.
Micro-optimizations are stressed at all times, and program efficiency is valued over comprehension.
He can’t even define a pointer correctly: “A pointer is a special variable that returns the address of a memory location.”
It does not take long to realize Traister has no idea what he’s talking about.
</p>

<p>
Although I’m not going to go over the content (that would take far too long since there’s nothing redeeming there), I did take extensive notes.
You can <a href="https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/1/notes.html">read them</a>, if you are so inclined.
</p>

<p>
I must, however, take a moment to single out the code.
It is universally bad and much of it is simply wrong.
(Imagine trying to learn programming principles from a book that contains a large number of programs that don’t even compile.)
I’ve <a href="https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/1/code.html">transcribed</a> some of the programs and annotated them with comments so that you can get a taste of how inept Traister is as a C programmer.
One thing to keep in mind (both for the programs and the notes) is that C89/C90 was new at the time and that the code was written on (and for) MS-DOS systems of the late 1980s/early 1990s.
Things were a bit different then.
</p>

<p>
Enough about the material.
I want to explore the question of how something so wrong even got written.  It’s not that everything in the book is wrong, but it feels like when it’s right, it’s right by accident.
</p>

<p>
Traister has <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Robert-J.-Traister/e/B001H6UPHY/ref=sr_ntt_srch_lnk_1?qid=1529540256&amp;sr=1-1">written</a> other books, some about electronics and some about programming, one called <i>Going from BASIC to C</i>.
In <i>Mastering C Pointers</i>, he talks about a product he created called CBREEZE that converts BASIC code to C.
Throughout the book he makes passing, roundabout references to BASIC and uses terminology that suggests he’s written a lot of BASIC code.
For example, there is a whole chapter on using pointers to access memory, where reading and writing memory is instead called “peeking” and “poking”, based on the PEEK and POKE instructions in BASIC.
He also says that it took him a couple of tries to learn C coming from BASIC.
In short, I’m convinced he’s knowledgeable about BASIC and has worked on writing software for small, electronic devices.
</p>

<p>
Why is this important?
As I read the book (and if you read my notes, you know where this is going) I started to notice something in the wording and tone.
The further I progressed the more I became convinced of it, and I think it explains how he managed to mangle the explanation of C pointers so badly.
</p>

<p>
I don’t think he understands the call stack.
</p>

<p>
My argument for this interpretation requires a little knowledge of BASIC and embedded devices.
</p>

<p>
With BASIC, the key thing to know about most implementations at the time is that there were no functions and no scope aside from the global scope.<span>[<a id="fnr.2" href="#fn.2">2</a>]</span>
The closest thing to a function in BASIC is the GOSUB command.
The GOSUB command jumps to a line and executes code until it gets to a RETURN statement, where control is transferred back to the line following the GOSUB command.
Within a GOSUB you can jump somewhere else with another GOSUB.
The control follows a stack principle, but no arguments are passed.
GOSUB routines are a way to factor out common code, but that common code has to work on global variables.
(And yes, it’s as terrible as it sounds.)
</p>

<p>
Now, consider the case of simple electronic devices.
Even today some embedded devices, usually programmed using C, do not have a call stack that dynamically allocates space for automatic variables.
There simply isn’t enough memory for it.
Instead, the compiler lays out memory such that each function’s local variables have fixed memory addresses (a “compiled stack” model).
The only stack you have is for return addresses and it is probably handled in hardware.
</p>

<p>
Suppose you’re used to writing BASIC for small memory electronic devices and you learn about C.
You read about pointers and realize something: it’s possible to write a subroutine that can change variables <i>without knowing their names</i>.
It’s manna from heaven!
You don’t have to devote global variables to being the “parameters” of your subroutines anymore.
Life is great.
</p>

<p>
This is the mindset I think Traister had and never got past.
In the book there is one fleeting mention of the stack in reference to excessive (automatic) memory allocation.
(On MS-DOS, if the space for local variables is too large in the program, it might not compile.)
He consistently describes variables as having “exclusive” addresses in the program.
His writing about pointers suggests that he thinks, for each function, space is set aside to hold the local variables for the duration of the program, but you can only access them when inside the function in which they were declared.
So pointers are really powerful because you can provide this address to another function and it can change the value using only a parameter.
</p>

<p>
Further evidence for his lack of understanding is that he frequently cites ridiculous space micro-optimizations within functions, such as avoiding the use of integers for index variables, if possible.
Another one, mentioned often, is local <code>char</code> arrays that have a fixed size.
There are good reasons to not use them but his are not among them.
His admonishment is that they waste space.
Technically, that is true, but they don't exist until they're on the stack.
And he never talks about global or file variables.
He only refers to locals with “exclusive” addresses “set aside” for variables.
</p>

<p>
This interpretation runs into some problems once you start asking how functions with malloc will work, but it's worth pointing out that there is almost no discussion about memory management.
In a book devoted to C pointers, that's a toxic mix of gross negligence and incompetence.
There is literally one short paragraph devoted to talking about the <code>free</code> function—and it's characterized as a “side note.”
</p>

<p>
Another sticking point in this interpretation is Traister’s incomprehensible approach to writing functions that take a variable number of arguments.
He does this by passing an arbitrary number of arguments to a function (the first being the number of arguments) and accessing them using offsets from the address of the first argument.
This suggests he has some idea about parameters being passed in a dynamic fashion, but it is so spectacularly wrong<span>[<a id="fnr.3" href="#fn.3">3</a>]</span> you’re left wondering if he even tried his programs out before publishing them.
</p>

<p>
Honestly, this is the most generous interpretation of the text I could come up with, and it still paints a terrible picture.
Occam's Razor suggests that Traister is just clueless.
But like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=01l1WIC9mBo">analyzing a terrible movie</a> that somehow gets made, it's more fun to reason through the “behind the scenes” parts.
</p>

<p>
Given the ineptness of the book, you'd think it was self-published.
You would be wrong.
It was published through Academic Press, which was a division of Harcourt, Brace &amp; World at the time, but is now an “imprint of Elsevier.”
</p>

<p>
In the preface of the second edition it says that the first edition was reviewed “by a professional C programmer hired by the publisher.”
That programmer said it should not be published.
That programmer was right, but the publisher went ahead and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/1/index.html">https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/1/index.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wozniak.ca/blog/2018/06/25/1/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24376622</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 16:49:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Standards for Gloves]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24375011">thread link</a>) | @brudgers
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://guidegloves.com/en/knowledge/standards | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://guidegloves.com/en/knowledge/standards">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <h4>About Guide</h4>
        <p>For over 30 years, our mission has been to protect and improve the performance of working hands. By being the fastest, most sustainable and innovative manufacturer of premium work gloves for a wide range of industries, we aim to make people safer and healthier at work.</p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://guidegloves.com/en/knowledge/standards</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24375011</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 14:04:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[List of YouTube channels for improving web development and programming skills]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 268 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24374979">thread link</a>) | @bojanvidanovic
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://devandgear.com/posts/the-ultimate-list-of-youtube-channels-to-boost-your-web-development-and-programming-skills/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://devandgear.com/posts/the-ultimate-list-of-youtube-channels-to-boost-your-web-development-and-programming-skills/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<header>
<figure>
<img data-srcset="https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/480 480w,
                  https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/640 640w,
                  https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/960 960w,
                  https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/1280 1280w" data-sizes="auto" src="https://source.unsplash.com/4-EeTnaC1S4/50x0" alt="A man watching his laptop">
<figcaption>
<a href="https://unsplash.com/@sickhews" target="_blank">
Wes Hicks
</a>
</figcaption>
</figure>
<div>
<p><time>
Sep 4, 2020
</time></p>
<p>These YouTubers are followed by thousands for their high-quality programming tutorials, find your favorite channel in this ultimate list to learn and boost your web development skills today.</p>
<p>
<span>in
<a href="https://devandgear.com/categories/learning"><b>Learning</b></a>
</span>
</p>
</div>
</header>
<div>
<div>
<p>Reading and listening to someone might not be the same, especially when learning
hard technical topics. With the rise of developers turned YouTubers, there is
a vast choice of technical videos from all areas of software development
available on YouTube. With that in mind, it has never been easier to learn the web
development from scratch or just boost the level of your skills thanks to the
enormous YouTube community.</p>
<p>But finding the right YouTube channel might not be easy, so we created an
ultimate list of channels for you to follow and start learning today.</p>
<p>Don’t forget to share, and let us know in the comments if your
favorite YouTube channel is not listed.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/DevEd">Dev Ed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/WebDevSimplified">Web Dev Simplified</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/TheNetNinja">The Net Ninja</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/TraversyMedia">Traversy Media</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/BenAwad97">Ben Awad</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/coreyms">Corey Schafer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/aniakubow">Ania Kubów</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvI5azOD4eDumpshr00EfIw">Codú Community</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCd-EhXGbXSozuzsAAdPIn3A">Tuts+ Code</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCVTlvUkGslCV_h-nSAId8Sw">LearnCode.academy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCADyUOnhyEoQqrw_RrsGleA">Chris Coyier</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/webcrunch">Web-Crunch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCyU5wkjgQYGRB0hIHMwm2Sg">LevelUpTuts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCO1cgjhGzsSYb1rsB4bFe4Q">FunFunFunction</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCxSITxL2JbF229OGCqieVZw">Garrett Love</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpOIUW62tnJTtpWFABxWZ8g">Codecourse</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/florinpop">Florin Pop</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwRXb5dUK4cvsHbx-rGzSgw">Derek Banas</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoebwHSTvwalADTJhps0emA">Wes Bos</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/thenewboston">thenewboston</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/williamprey">Alessandro Castellani</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpzRDg0orQBZFBPzeXm1yNg">Adam Khoury</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCt0ya0xGvXu01zfXjNrGqzg">flavio</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnUYZLuoy1rq1aVMwx4aTzw">Google Chrome Developers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCRxWW_Ncs308nW4An23Yeig/">Simple Programmer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChByJR-sX8CooIAc5nkV7Mg">Matt Stauffer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCvM5YYWwfLwpcQgbRr68JLQ">Adria Twarog</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/kepowob">Kevin Powell</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-T8W79DN6PBnzomelvqJYw">James Q Quick</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SteveGriffith-Prof3ssorSt3v3">Steve Griffith</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/programmingwithmosh">Programmming with Mosh</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/CalebTheVideoMaker2">Caleb Curry</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC4JX40jDee_tINbkjycV4Sg">Tech With Tim</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8A0M0eDttdB11MHxX58vXQ">Meth Meth Method</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrqAGUPPMOdo0jfQ6grikZw">Colt Steele</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/shiffman">The Coding Train</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/andrewjosephmead1">Andrew Mead</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHkqtrnQO2HMyW50ixOtJGw">This Dot Media</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/KentCDodds-vids">Kent C. Dodds</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Weibenfalk">Weibenfalk</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCtb40EQj2inp8zuaQlLx3iQ">Andre Madarang</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8butISFwT-Wl7EV0hUK0BQ">freeCodeCamp.org</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJq6AEgtWeZt7ziQ-fLKOeA">Prismic</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCWr0mx597DnSGLFk1WfvSkQ">Kalle Hallden</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCtxCXg-UvSnTKPOzLH4wJaQ">Coding Tech</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsBjURrPoezykLs9EqgamOA">Fireship</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCRLEADhMcb8WUdnQ5_Alk7g">Aaron Jack</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/irideabanana">uidotdev</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCDCHcqyeQgJ-jVSd6VJkbCw">codeSTACKr</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsUalyRg43M8D60mtHe6YcA">Honeypot</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/unsureprogrammer">Unsure Programmer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJUmE61LxhbhudzUugHL2wQ">codedamn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC80PWRj_ZU8Zu0HSMNVwKWw">Codevolution</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC8n8ftV94ZU_DJLOLtrpORA">Code Explained</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/DesignCourse">DesingCourse</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/simplesnippets">Simple Snippets</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCxA99Yr6P_tZF9_BgtMGAWA">Faraday Academy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/SteveSchoger">Steve Schoger</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCDrekHmOnkptxq3gUU0IyfA">Devon Crawford</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/javaboynavin">Telusko</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/ackzell/videos">ackzell</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Academind">Academind</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCQI-Ym2rLZx52vEoqlPQMdg">iCoder’s Tape</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/IAmTimCorey">IAmTimCorey</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/CodingEntrepreneurs">CodingEntrepreneurs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/codinggardenwithcj">Coding Garden with CJ</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCksTNgiRyQGwi2ODBie8HdA">Adam Bien</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/SimonHoiberg">Simon Hoiberg</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC54NcJvLCvM2CNaBjd5j6HA">RealToughCandy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/QuickProgramming">Quick programmming</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/TheCharmefis">Dani Krossing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/RodtheITGuy">Rod the IT guy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjX0FtIZBBVD3YoCcxnDC4g">dcode</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/hiteshitube">Hitesh Choudhary</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/Lengstorf">Jason Lengstorf</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbwXnUipZsLfUckBPsC7Jog">Online Tutorials</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/WrongAkram">Wrong Akram</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/binarythistle">Les Jackson</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/cleverprogrammer">Clever Programmer</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Conutant">Tyler Moore</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/GeekyShow1">Geeky Shows</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-Zcse8tC53G34Uo4kzLeAg">Chris Blakely</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCNFmBuclxQPe57orKiQbyfA">Tanay Pratap</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/techsithtube">techsith</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/hswolff">Harry Wolff</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/FKnight">ForrestKnight</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Tychos1">Joshua Fluke</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/sentdex">sentdex</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/BeforeSemicolon">Before Semicolon</a></li>
</ul>

</div>

</div>

<section>
<section id="comments">
<h2>Comments</h2>



</section>
</section>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://devandgear.com/posts/the-ultimate-list-of-youtube-channels-to-boost-your-web-development-and-programming-skills/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24374979</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 13:59:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Snake in a QR Code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 266 | Comments 79 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24374570">thread link</a>) | @phit_
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>The above QR code contains a complete Windows executable that will run on Windows 7 and up. It's a simple but fully playable implementation of Snake.</p>
<p>A QR code is a data storage medium like any other, and while it's almost always used to store ASCII text, it can also be used to store binary data. As such, virtually any computer data can theoretically be stored in a QR code provided it can fit within the size limitations.</p>
<p>A QR code comes in various standard sizes, the largest being version 40 which can store up to 2,953 bytes (roughly 2.9 KB) of binary data. The above code is not quite that large, it's only storing around 1.4 KB of data (shrunk down from 3.2 KB with <a href="http://www.crinkler.net/" target="_blank">Crinkler</a>, slightly larger than the executable shown in the video because I decided to add a little more functionality).</p>

<p><b>Method 1: Webcam (automatic)</b></p>
<p>You can treat this QR code much like a QR code in the real world by using your computer's webcam to read it (e.g. after loading this page on a phone or printing the QR code out). For this, I recommend using zbarcam. I've included a download link with everything you need:</p>
<ol>
    <li><a href="https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/zbarcam.zip">Download zbarcam</a></li>
    <li>Open "Read Snake From QR.bat". After a moment, your webcam will activate.</li>
    <li>Using either your phone screen or a print-out, hold the QR code up to the camera.</li>
    <li>Once it recognizes the code, it will close and Snake will appear, freshly read from the QR code.</li>
</ol>
<p><b>Method 2: Webcam (manual)</b></p>
<p>This method is the same as the above, however if you'd rather input the commands manually than running my script, go for it:</p>
<ol>
    <li><a href="https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/zbarcam.zip">Download zbarcam</a></li>
    <li>Open Command Prompt</li>
    <li><span>cd</span> to the zbarcam folder.</li>
    <li>Run the following command:
        <p>zbarcam --raw --oneshot -Sbinary &gt; snake.exe</p>
        <p>The arguments used are as follows:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><span>--raw</span> - Disables any character encoding conversion.</li>
            <li><span>--oneshot</span> - Stops reading and closes zbarcam after the code has been successfully read.</li>
            <li><span>-Sbinary</span> - Informs zbarcam that the data in the code is binary data.</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li>Using either your phone screen or a print-out, hold the QR code up to the camera.</li>
    <li>Once it recognizes the code, it will close and an executable called "snake.exe" will appear in the same folder.</li>
    <li>Open "snake.exe".</li>
</ol>

<ul>
    <li>The version of zbarcam provided above has been patched to correctly output binary data on Windows. This project exposed a bug in zbarcam where binary data was incorrectly treated as text, inadvertently corrupting it as Windows attempted to convert LF line endings to CRLF. The fix used here has since been merged into zbar's master source code, but as of July 2020 no stable release version has included the fix yet.</li>
    <li>The version of zbarcam provided above has been compiled with DirectShow support for greater compatibility with webcam devices. In my video, I use a build that has not been compiled for DirectShow (using VfW instead) which leads to a black and white webcam feed. This build provides a feed in color.</li>
</ul>

<p>As a proof-of-concept, I wrote an implementation of Snake in JavaScript that, when minified, could also fit into the maximum QR code size which I briefly showcased in the video. Some people were interested in playing this, so <a href="https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/snake-minified.html">it is available here</a>.</p>

<p>
    • <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QR_code">QR code on Wikipedia</a><br>
    • <a href="https://github.com/mchehab/zbar">ZBar on GitHub</a><br>
</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://itsmattkc.com/etc/snakeqr/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24374570</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 13:08:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bread, How Did They Make It? Addendum: Rice]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24373939">thread link</a>) | @Kednicma
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://acoup.blog/2020/09/04/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-addendum-rice/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2020/09/04/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-addendum-rice/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>As an addendum on to our four-part look at the general structures of the farming of cereal grains (<a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/24/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-farmers/">I</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/31/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-ii-big-farms/">II</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/08/06/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iii-actually-farming/">III</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/08/21/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iv-markets-and-non-farmers/">IV</a>) this post is going to briefly discuss some of the key ways that the structures of <strong><em>rice</em> <em>farming </em></strong>differ from the structures of wheat and barley farming.  We’ll start with some of the key differences in the mechanics of rice farming itself, before moving into how those differences might motivate different social and economic organization in the countryside, before finally discussing some of the theories as to how rice farming might – or might not – impact larger structures like the state.</p>



<p>As always, if you like what you are reading here, please share it. If you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click the button below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts, as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or pop-culture thoughts. And if you want to ensure that I can continue to get my rice, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>.</p>






<p>(Quick bibliographic aside: I relied primary for this on Hsu, <em>Han Agriculture: The Formation of Early Chinese Agrarian Economy</em> (206 B.C. – A.D. 220) (1980) and F. Bray, <em>The Rice Economies: Technology and Development in Asian Societies </em>(1986) which were recommended to me by specialists in the field.  The latter is a wealth of technical details on rice cultivation, although it is as focused on the transition to mechanization and modern agriculture as to the conditions of pre-modern rice cultivation.)</p>



<h2>Rice Cultivation</h2>



<p>We want to start with the rice cultivation process.  There are a <em>lot</em> of varieties of rice out there, but the key divide we want to make early is between dry-rice and wet-rice.  When we’re talking about ‘rice cultures’ or ‘rice agriculture,’ generally, we mean wet-rice farming, where the rice is partially submerged during its growing.  Wild rice, as far as we can tell, began as a swamp-grass and thus likes to have quite a lot of water around, although precisely controlling the water availability can lead the rice to be a lot more productive than it would be in its natural habitat.  While there are varieties of rice which can be (and are) farmed ‘dry’ (that is, in unflooded fields much like wheat and barley are farmed), the vast majority of rice farming is ‘wet.’  As with grains, this is not merely a matter of different methods of farming, but of different varieties of rice that have been adapted to that farming; varieties of dry-rice and wet-rice have been selectively bred over millennia to perform best in those environments.</p>



<p>Wet-rice is farmed in paddies, small fields (often <em>very</em> small – some Chinese agronomists write that the ideal size for an individual rice field is around 0.1 hectare, which is just 0.24 acres) surrounded by low ‘bunds’ (small earthwork walls or dykes) to keep in the water, typically around two feet high.  Because controlling the water level is crucial, rice paddies must be very precisely flat, leading to even relatively gentle slopes often being terraced to create a series of flat fields.  Each of these rice paddies (and there will be many because they are so small) are then connected by irrigation canals which channel and control the water in what is often a quite complex system.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="4363" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/535232001/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg" data-orig-size="1667,2500" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="535232001" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=200" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=683" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=683" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=683 683w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=1366 1366w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=100 100w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=200 200w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/535232001.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px"><figcaption><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/A_1915-0823-0-749">Via the British Museum</a>, a Japanese color woodblock print (1855) showing rice farmers working in the fields.</figcaption></figure>



<p>The exact timing of rice production is more complex than wheat because a single paddy often sees two crops in a year and the exact planting times vary between areas;  one common cycle on the Yangtze is for a February planting (with a June harvest) followed by a June planting (with a November harvest).  In other areas, paddies planted with rice during the first planting might be drained and sown with a different plant entirely (sometimes including wheat) in the intervening time.</p>



<p>The cycle runs thusly: after the heavy rains of the monsoons (if available), the field is tilled (or plowed, but as we’ll see, manual tillage is often more common).  The seed is then sown (or transplanted) and the field is, using the irrigation system, lightly flooded, so that the young seedlings grow in standing water.  Sometimes the seed is initially planted in a dedicated seed-bed and then transferred to the field, rather than being sown there directly; doing so has a positive impact on yields, but is substantially more labor intensive.  The water level is raised as the plant grows; agian this is labor intensive, but increases yields.  Just before the harvest the fields are drained out and allowed to dry out, before the crop is harvested and then goes into processing.</p>



<p>Rice is threshed much like grain (more often manually threshed and generally not threshed with flails) to release the seeds, the individual rice grains, from the plant.  That is going to free the endosperm of the speed, along with a hull around it and a layer of bran between the two.  Hulling was traditionally done by hand-pounding, which frees the seed from the hull, leaving just the endosperm and some of the bran; this is how you get <em>brown</em> rice, which is essentially ‘whole-grain’ rice.  While it is generally less <em>tasty</em>, the bran actually has quite a lot of nutrients not present in the calorie-rich endosperm.  Whereas <em>white rice</em> is produced by then milling or polishing away the bran to produce a pure, white kernal of the endosperm; it is very tasty, but lacks many of the vitamins that brown rice has.</p>



<p>Consequently, while a diet of mostly brown rice can be healthy, a diet overwhelmingly of <em>white rice</em> leads to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thiamine_deficiency">Thiamine deficiency</a>, known colloquially as <em>beriberi</em>.  My impression from the literature is that this wasn’t as much an issue prior to the introduction of mechanical milling processes for rice. Mechanical milling made producing white rice in quantity cheap and so it came to dominate the diet to the exclusion of brown rice, producing negative health effects for the poor who could not afford to supplement their rice-and-millet diet with other foods, or for soldiers whose ration was in rice.  But prior to that mechanical milling, brown rice was all that was available for the poor, which in turn meant less Thiamine deficiency among the lower classes of society.</p>



<h2>Farmer Terrain</h2>



<p>Because rice is such a different crop than wheat or barley, there are a lot of differences in the way that rice cultivation shapes the countryside.  We’ll move here from the relatively direct impacts on the organization of farmers and then discuss the more speculative impacts on the organization of whole societies.</p>



<p>The thing to note about <strong>rice is that it is both <em>much</em> more productive on a per-acre basis than wheat or barley, but also <em>much</em> more labor intensive</strong>; it also relies on different forms of capital to be productive.  Whole-grain wheat and brown rice have similar calorie and nutritional value (brown rice is somewhat better in most categories) on a unit-weight basis (so, per pound or ton), but the yield difference is fairly large: rice is typically around (very roughly) 50% more productive per acre than wheat.  Moreover, rice plants have a more favorable ratio of seeds-to-plants, meaning that the demand to put away seeds for the next harvest is easier – whereas crop-to-seed ratios on pre-modern wheat range from 3:1 to 10:1, rice can achieve figures as high as 100:1.  As a result, not only is the gross yield higher (that is, more tons of seed per field) but a lower percentage of that seed has to be saved for the next planting.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="4365" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/1613316772/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg" data-orig-size="1565,1406" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="1613316772" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/1613316772.jpg 1565w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://www.britishmuseum.org/collection/object/A_1939-0311-0-6-56">Via the British Museum</a>, a map made of Kaliwungi, Java (1807) showing a collection of rice fields.  Of particular note is how small each individual field is (compare the village on the right-hand side!).</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>At the same time, the irrigation demands for effective production of wet-rice requires a <em>lot</em> of labor to build and maintain</strong>.  Fields need to be flooded and drained; in some cases (particularly pre-modern terrace farming) this may involve moving the water manually, in buckets, from lower fields to higher ones.  Irrigation canals connecting paddies can make this job somewhat easier, as can bucket-lifts (there’s a picture of a simple one below), but that still demands moving quite a lot of water.  In any irrigation system, the bunds need to be maintained and the water level carefully controlled, with also involves potentially quite a lot of labor.</p>



<p>The consequence of all of this is that while the rice farming household seems to be roughly the same size as the wheat-farming household (that is, an extended family unit of variable size, but typically around 8 or so members), <strong>the farm is much smaller</strong>, with common household farm sizes, even in the modern period, clustering around 1 hectare (2.47 acres) in comparison to the standard household wheat farms clustered around 4-6 acres (which, you may note with the yield figures above, lands us right back at around the same subsistence standard).</p>



<p>Moreover, rice cultivation is less soil dependent (but more water dependent) because wet-rice farming both encourages nitrogen fixation in the soil (maintaining the fertility of it generally without expensive manure use) and because rice farming leads naturally to a process known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Podzol">pozdolisation</a>, slowly converting the underlying soil over a few years to a set of characteristics which are more favorable for more rice cultivation.  So whereas with wheat cultivation, where you often have clumps of marginal land (soil that is too wet, too dry, too rocky, too acidic, too uneven, too heavily forested, and so on), rice cultivation tends to be able to make use of almost any land where there is sufficient water (although terracing may be needed to level out the land).  The reliance on the rice itself to ‘terraform’ its own fields does mean that new rice fields tended to under-produce for the first few years.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="4357" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg" data-orig-size="2000,1295" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/09/terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rice_production_in_China#/media/File:Terrace_field_yunnan_china_denoised.jpg">Via Wikipedia</a>, terraced rice paddies in Yunnan, China, showing how uneven land can be terraced to create level fields …</figcaption></figure></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/09/04/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-addendum-rice/">https://acoup.blog/2020/09/04/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-addendum-rice/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2020/09/04/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-addendum-rice/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24373939</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 11:21:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rust testing or verifying: Why not both?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 135 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24372760">thread link</a>) | @adreid
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://alastairreid.github.io/why-not-both/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alastairreid.github.io/why-not-both/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Dijkstra famously dissed testing by saying “Program testing can be used to show
the presence of bugs, but never to show their absence!”
As if you should choose one over the other.
I don’t see them as opposites but as complementary techniques that
should both be used to improve the quality of your code.</p>

<p>I am a big fan of formal verification.
Formal verification tools can be the best bug-finding tools you have
ever used.
And they can completely eliminate entire classes of bugs from your code.
But, formal verification won’t find bugs in your
specification; or in your assumptions about your dependencies; or in your
build/CI harness, etc. (See <a href="https://alastairreid.github.io/RelatedWork/papers/fonseca:ecs:2017">Fonseca</a> for more examples
of where testing has found bugs in formally verified systems.)</p>

<p>And, we all reluctantly agree that Dijkstra was right: even a thorough,
perfectly executed test plan can miss bugs.</p>

<p>So, for the last few months, I have been trying to have both.
We (my team and I at Google) have been reimplementing Jason Lingle’s
<a href="https://github.com/AltSysrq/proptest">proptest</a> property-testing library for use with Rust formal verification tools.
The original proptest lets you write test harnesses to test that your code
(probably) satisfies properties.
Today, we are releasing <a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools">a reimplementation of the proptest interface</a>
that enables you to use exactly the same test harnesses to
formally verify that the properties hold.
So far, we have only tried this with the <a href="https://klee.github.io/">KLEE symbolic execution engine</a>
but our implementation is based on the verification
interface used in <a href="https://alastairreid.github.io/verification-competitions/">verification competitions</a> so it should be
possible to port our library to many other verification tools.<sup id="fnref:for-Rust" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:for-Rust">1</a></sup></p>

<p><em>[Before I go any further, I should mention that what we are <a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools">releasing this
week</a> is a very early research prototype.  It is not ready for serious use
and it is definitely not an official, supported Google product.  We are
releasing it now, in its current, immature state because we want to have
a conversation about how programmers want to formally verify Rust code
and we think that it is helpful to have something to push against.
We welcome pull requests that add support for other verifiers, or that
push the design in a better direction.]</em></p>

<h2 id="a-proptest-test-harness">A proptest test harness</h2>

<p>To get an idea for what property testing looks like in <code>proptest</code>,
we’ll look at an example from the <a href="https://altsysrq.github.io/proptest-book/proptest/tutorial/macro-proptest.html">proptest book</a>.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>fn add(a: i32, b: i32) -&gt; i32 {
    a + b
}

proptest! {
    #[test]
    fn test_add(a in 0..1000i32, b in 0..1000i32) {
        let sum = add(a, b);
        assert!(sum &gt;= a);
        assert!(sum &gt;= b);
    }
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This example defines a property called <code>test_add</code> that tests a function called
<code>add</code>.  In particular, it checks that, for non-negative values <code>a</code> and <code>b</code>, the
result of <code>sum(a, b)</code> is at least as large as <code>a</code> and as <code>b</code>.</p>

<p>The notation <code>0..1000i32</code> represents the set of all values in the range <code>[0 ..
1000)</code> and the notation <code>a in 0..1000i32</code> says that a value <code>a</code> should be
chosen from that set.</p>

<p>The <code>proptest!</code> macro converts this property into a test function
that repeatedly generates random values for <code>a</code> and <code>b</code> and executes the
body of the property.</p>

<p>(After adding in <a href="https://altsysrq.github.io/proptest-book/proptest/tutorial/macro-proptest.html">some additional glue code</a>) we can run this example with the command</p>



<p>which produces the following output</p>

<div><div><pre><code>running 1 test
test test_add ... ok

test result: ok. 1 passed; 0 failed; 0 ignored; 0 measured; 0 filtered out
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and, if we deliberately write a property that doesn’t hold, then <code>cargo test</code>
produces output more like this</p>

<div><div><pre><code>running 1 test
test test_add ... FAILED

failures:

---- test_add stdout ----
thread 'test_add' panicked at 'assertion failed: sum &gt;= a + 100', src/main.rs:11:9
thread 'test_add' panicked at 'Test failed: assertion failed: sum &gt;= a + 100; minimal failing input: a = 0, b = 0
        successes: 0
        local rejects: 0
        global rejects: 0
', src/main.rs:7:1


failures:
    test_add

test result: FAILED. 0 passed; 1 failed; 0 ignored; 0 measured; 0 filtered out
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="verifying-with-propverify">Verifying with propverify</h2>

<p>Proptest checks the above property by generating random values and testing.
But we can also interpret the property as saying that for all values
<code>a</code> and <code>b</code> in the sets, the body of the property will not panic.
That is, we can interpret it as a universally quantified specification.</p>

<p>To verify the above property, we use a script that compiles the Rust
code, invokes the <a href="https://klee.github.io/">KLEE symbolic execution engine</a> and filters
the output of KLEE to determine whether there is any choice of <code>a</code> and
<code>b</code> that can cause the body of the property to panic.</p>



<p>This produces output like this: confirming that the property does hold</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Running 1 test(s)
test test_add ... ok

test result: ok. 1 passed; 0 failed
VERIFICATION_RESULT: VERIFIED
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And, if we change the example property so that the property does not hold,
<code>cargo-verify</code> produces this output.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>thread 'test_add' panicked at 'assertion failed: sum &gt;= a + 100', src/main.rs:11:9

running 1 test
  Value a = 0
  Value b = 0
test test_add ... FAILED

failures:

failures:
    test_add

test result: FAILED. 0 passed; 1 failed; 0 ignored; 0 measured; 0 filtered out
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>On this example, random testing and formal verification produced similar
results.
I could have chosen an example where formal verification found a bug that
random testing misses.
Or I could have chosen an example where random testing easily finds
a bug but formal verification spins forever.
But, in this post, I wanted to focus on the similarity between the two
approaches, not the differences.</p>

<h2 id="learning-more">Learning more</h2>

<p>In this article, we used an example that was easy to explain but
does not really show off the power of <code>propverify</code>.
Some slightly better examples are</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools/blob/main/compatibility-test/src/collections.rs#L60">collections.rs</a>
where we check properties involving standard Rust collection
types such as vectors and B-trees.
(This should be read in conjunction with the <a href="https://altsysrq.github.io/rustdoc/proptest/latest/proptest/collection/index.html">proptest
documentation</a>.)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools/blob/0a6a0ff2b3880eb4a19d8161bfae8d163b0a65ec/compatibility-test/src/dynamic.rs#L82">dynamic.rs</a>
where we check properties involving trait objects by
quantifying over a subset of the possible instances of the trait.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>And, we have more documentation about</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools/blob/main/docs/using-propverify.md">Using the propverify library</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools/blob/main/docs/using-annotations.md">Using the lower level <code>verification-annotations</code> API</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools/blob/main/docs/using-klee.md">The many, many flags we use when compiling Rust code so that it can be verified with KLEE</a></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>The latter two are mostly for the benefit of verification tool developers.</p>

<h2 id="our-next-steps">Our next steps</h2>

<p><em>[You can either read this as a sketch of what we plan to do or
as an admission of what we have not yet done.
As <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LOILZ_D3aRg">Fred and Ginger said</a>,
“Tomato. Tomato.”]</em></p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>The tools have a horrifically complicated set of dependencies.</p>

    <p>This is partly because formal verification is not quite popular
enough for enough Debian/Homebrew packages to exist and partly
because we need some very specific versions.
(It may also be possible to remove some dependencies!)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>We are in the process of adding <a href="https://github.com/GaloisInc/mir-verifier">Crux-MIR</a> support to the library
and tool.
Crux-MIR is a new part of Galois’
<a href="https://galois.com/project/software-analysis-workbench/">Software Analysis Workbench (SAW)</a>
that verifies the MIR code generated by the Rust compiler.</p>

    <p>This is taking us a bit longer than using KLEE
because the functionality of our <code>cargo-verify</code> script
overlaps with the functionality of Crux-MIR but they have slightly different
approaches – we’re still working on the best way to handle the resulting
conflicts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>It can be useful to focus our attention on a single crate at a time.
We have some ideas for how to do that with fuzzing and verification
but we have not had a chance to try them yet.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>We have not looked seriously at how well this approach scales.</p>

    <p>The collections support in the <code>propverify</code> library has a few
tricks to avoid some obvious scaling issues, but we don’t know if
those tricks work well for all verification tools and they
probably only scratch the surface of what needs to be done.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>

<p>Testing and formal verification are usually portrayed as mortal enemies.
I think that misses a huge opportunity to use your existing familiarity and
comfort with testing to let you get value out of formal verification tools.</p>

<p>I encourage you to download <a href="https://github.com/project-oak/rust-verification-tools">our library and tool</a>,
try it out and give us feedback.
If you are working on a Rust verification tool, we would love it
if you tried to use our library with your tool.
And we would love it even more if you sent us a pull request.</p>

<p>It’s probably not a good idea to commit to using the library at this stage:
it is not very robust at the moment and I expect that it will change a lot
as we gain experience from porting the library to other types of
formal verification tools.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>

<hr>



<p>If you found this article interesting, you might also enjoy these related posts</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://alastairreid.github.io/verification-competitions/">Verification competitions</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://alastairreid.github.io/rust-verification-tools/">Rust verification tools</a></li>
</ul>

<p>And these papers:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://alastairreid.github.io/RelatedWork/papers/goodman:ndss:2018">goodman:ndss:2018</a> applied some very similar ideas to C++ testing
in 2018 using the <a href="https://github.com/google/googletest">GoogleTest</a> DSL as a starting point and providing
support for <a href="https://angr.io/">angr</a>, <a href="https://blog.trailofbits.com/2017/04/27/manticore-symbolic-execution-for-humans/">Manticore</a> and <a href="https://dynamorio.org/drmemory_docs/page_drfuzz.html">Dr. Fuzz</a>.</p>

    <p>They ran into and solved problems related to logging (causing a path
explosion), symbolic loop bounds and symbolic array indices (causing
a path explosion) and how to combine swarm testing with verification.</p>

    <p>Highly recommended!</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr>



  </div><p>
    Written on September  3, 2020.
    <br>
    The opinions expressed are my own views and not my employer's.
  </p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alastairreid.github.io/why-not-both/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24372760</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 07:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Preserving data integrity: A ZFS-inspired storage system]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24372662">thread link</a>) | @d2wa
<br/>
September 4, 2020 | https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
		<p>
			
			
			<h2>A ZFS-inspired storage system</h2>
			
		</p>
		<h2>07. Mar 2020</h2>
		<ul>
	<li><a href="https://insanity.industries/tags/funwithdata">#funwithdata</a></li>
	
	<li><a href="https://insanity.industries/tags/linux">#Linux</a></li>
	</ul>

		<section>
			<p>When we are storing data, we typically assume that our storage system of choice returns that data later just as we put it in.
However what guarantees do we have that this is actually the case?
The case made here is the case of <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/what-bit-rot-and-how-can-i-detect-it-rhel">bitrot</a>, the silent degradation of the physical charges that physically make up today’s storage devices.</p>
<p>To counter this type of problem, one can employ data checksumming, as it is done by both btrfs and ZFS.
However, while in the long run btrfs might be the tool of choice for this, it is fairly complex and not yet too mature, whereas ZFS, the most prominent candidate for this type of features, is <a href="https://github.com/zfsonlinux/zfs/issues/8314">not</a> <a href="https://sfconservancy.org/blog/2016/feb/25/zfs-and-linux/">without</a> <a href="https://ubuntu.com/blog/zfs-licensing-and-linux">hassle</a> and it must be recompiled for every kernel update (although <a href="https://github.com/zfsonlinux/zfs/wiki/Custom-Packages">automation exists</a>).</p>
<p>In this blogpost, we’ll therefore take a look into a storage design that actually checks whether the returned data is actually valid and not silently corrupted inside our storage system and is completely designed with components available in Linux itself without the need to recompile and test your storage layer on every kernel upgrade.
We find that this storage design, while fulfilling the same purpose as ZFS, does not only yield comparable performance, but actually in some cases even able to significantly outperform it, as the benchmarks at the end indicate.</p>

<p>The system we will test in the following will be constructed from four components (including the filesystem):</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>dm-integrity</strong> provides blocklevel checksumming for all incoming data and will check said checksum for all data read through it (and return a read error if it doesn’t match).</li>
<li><strong>mdraid</strong> provides redundancy if a disk misbehaves, avoiding data loss. If the dm-integrity-layer detects invalid data from the disk, mdraid will see a read-error and can immediately correct this error by reading it from somewhere else in the redundancy pool.</li>
<li><strong>dm-crypt</strong> on top of the RAID, right below the filesystem will encrypt the data<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></li>
<li><strong>ext4</strong> as a filesystem to actually store files on it</li>
</ul>
<p>The order matters, dm-integrity must be placed between the harddisks and the mdraid, to ensure that data corruption errors can be corrected by mdraid after they have been detected by dm-integrity. Similarly, dm-crypt has nothing to do with redundancy, therefore it should be placed on top of of mdraid, to only having to be passed once, and not multiple times as it would be the case for placing it alongside dm-integrity.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>This yields the following storage design:</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Storage system architecture</h4>
    <img src="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/architecture.svg" alt="Architecture of the storeage system. Grey depicts physical hardware, green depicts device mapper technologies, yellow indicates mdraid and blue indicates filesystems. The encryption layer will later be ommitted when comparing performance to ZFS." height="500"> <figcaption><p>Architecture of the storeage system. Grey depicts physical hardware, green depicts device mapper technologies, yellow indicates mdraid and blue indicates filesystems. The encryption layer will later be ommitted when comparing performance to ZFS.</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><a href="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/mkstorage.sh.txt">This script will assemble the above depicted system and mount it to /mnt.</a></p>

<p>Now that we have an assembled system, we’d like to quantify the performance impact of the different layers.
The test setup for this is a <a href="https://kobol.io/helios4/">Kobol Helios4</a> (primarily because it’s the intended target platform for this storage system) with four disks<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> running Debian 10 “Buster”.
The Helios4 is powered by an energy efficient dual-core ARM SoC optimized for storage systems.
The setup was not built based on the entire disks, but on partitions of a size of 10GiB each, allowing multiple parallel designs and therefore easing the benchmarking procedure, as well as speeding up the experiments<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>.</p>
<h2 id="layer-analysis-of-performance-impact">Layer analysis of performance impact</h2>
<h3 id="throughput">Throughput</h3>
<p>To benchmark throughput, the following commands were used:</p>
<pre><code># write:
echo 3 &gt; /proc/sys/vm/drop_cache  # drop all caches
dd if=/dev/zero of=/path/to/testfile bs=1M count=8000 conv=fdatasync

# read
echo 3 &gt; /proc/sys/vm/drop_cache  # drop all caches
dd if=/path/to/testfile of=/dev/zero conv=fdatasync
</code></pre>
<p>This procedure was repeated ten times for proper statistics for the different cases for both read (<code>r</code>) and write (<code>w</code>):</p>
<ul>
<li>ext4 filesystem only (<code>f</code>, one disk only)</li>
<li>encryption, topped by ext4 (<code>cf</code>, one disk only)</li>
<li>mdraid (RAID6/double parity), topped by the former (<code>rcf</code>, 4 disks)</li>
<li>the final setup, including integrity (<code>ircf</code>, 4 disks)</li>
</ul>
<figure>
    
    <img src="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/layers.svg" alt="Throughput for different arrangements of layers on Kobol Helios4 system for both read (top row) and write (bottom row). Each dot indicates one measurement. f: filesystem, cf: crypto+f, rcf:raid+cf, ircf: integrity+rcf. Testplatform"> <figcaption><p>Throughput for different arrangements of layers on Kobol Helios4 system for both read (top row) and write (bottom row). Each dot indicates one measurement. f: filesystem, cf: crypto+f, rcf:raid+cf, ircf: integrity+rcf. <a href="https://kobol.io/helios4/">Testplatform</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>We see different interesting results in the data:
First of all, the encryption engine on the helios4 is not completely impact free, although the resulting performance is still more than sufficient for the designated uses for a Helios4.</p>
<p>Secondly, we see that adding integrity layer does have a noticable impact on writing, but a negligible impact on reading, indicating that especially for systems primarily intended to read data from adding the integrity layer is a matter of negligible cost.</p>
<p>For write-heavy systems, the performance impact is more considerable, but for certain workloads, such as the home-NAS-case the Helios is designed for, the performance can still be considered fully sufficient, especially as normally the system would cache those writes to a certain extend, which was explicitly disabled for benchmarking purposes (see <code>conv=fdatasync</code> in the benchmark procedure).</p>
<p>The reason for the degradation in write (but not in read) is likely due to the fact that the integrity layer and the mdraid layer are decoupled from one another, the raid-layer is not aware that for a double parity setup it effectively has to write the same information three times, and the integrity layer has to account for all three writes before the data is considered synced as required by <code>conv=fdatasync</code>.</p>
<h3 id="latency">Latency</h3>
<p>We have found that the throguhput of such a storage design is yielding useful throughput-rates.
The next question is about the latency of the system, which we will, for simplicity, only estimate for random 4K-reads.
Again, just as above, we will investigate the impact of the different layers of the system.
To do so, we read 100.000 sectors randomly from an 18GB sized testfile filling the storage mountpoint for each configuration after dropping all caches.</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Latency comparison of system layers</h4>
    <img src="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/layerlatencies.svg" alt="Distribution of latencies in milliseconds for different arrangements of layers on Kobol Helios4 system. green denotes the median, black denotes the average of the latencies of the respective setup, access times below 1ms were considered cache hits and therefore excluded for the computation of mean and average. Testplatform"> <figcaption><p>Distribution of latencies in milliseconds for different arrangements of layers on Kobol Helios4 system. green denotes the median, black denotes the average of the latencies of the respective setup, access times below 1ms were considered cache hits and therefore excluded for the computation of mean and average. <a href="https://kobol.io/helios4/">Testplatform</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The figure above yields several interesting insights:
First of all, we do see cache hits close to zero milliseconds, furthermore, we see that the latency distribution is fairly evenly distributed over the available range and finally and most interestingly, we see that the impact of the several layers onto the latency is measurable, but rather irrellevant for typical practical purposes.</p>
<h2 id="performance-comparison-with-zfs">Performance comparison with ZFS</h2>
<p>So far we have tested the setup on its intended target platform, the Helios4.
To compare the resulting system against the elephant in the room, ZFS, we will use a different test platform, based on an Intel i7-2600K as CPU and 4x1TB disks, as the <code>zfs-dkms</code> was not reliably buildable on Debian Buster on ARM, and when it actually built, it explicitly stated that 32bit-processors (as the Helios’ CPU) are not supported by upstream, although technically the system would run.</p>
<p>To allow for a cleaner comparison, the testbed was accordinly changed to accomodate for ZFS’s preferences.
As ZFS did not adhere to <code>conv=fdatasync</code><sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>, the main memory was restricted to 1GB, swap was turned off and the size of the testfile was chosen to be 18GB.
This way, any caching happening would be at least significantly reduced as there was little space next to the OS inside of the main memory for caching.</p>
<p>All tests were run on a Debian 10 “Buster” with Linux 4.19, ZFS was used in form of the package <code>zfs-dkms</code> in version 0.8.2 from backports.
The storage layer for both setups was layouted with double parity (RAID6/raidz2) and, as the <code>zfs-dkms</code> package in Debian was not able to do encryption, the mdraid-based setup was also setup without the encryption layer.</p>
<h3 id="throughput-1">Throughput</h3>
<p>The commands used for benchmarking throughput were conceptually the same as above:</p>
<pre><code># write:
echo 3 &gt; /proc/sys/vm/drop_cache  # drop all caches
dd if=/dev/zero of=/path/to/testfile bs=1M count=18000 conv=fdatasync

# read
echo 3 &gt; /proc/sys/vm/drop_cache  # drop all caches
dd if=/path/to/testfile of=/dev/zero conv=fdatasync
</code></pre>
<p>Although ZFS seemingly does not adhere to any cache dropping or syncing instructions, they were still performed and adhered to by the mdraid-based setup.</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Throughput comparison, zfs &amp; md</h4>
    <img src="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/zfs-md-throughput.svg" alt="Throughput for both ZFS and the md-based setup for both read and write. Each dot indicates one measurement, the green line indicates the median of all measurements. Testplatform"> <figcaption><p>Throughput for both ZFS and the md-based setup for both read and write. Each dot indicates one measurement, the green line indicates the median of all measurements. <a href="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/zfs-testbed.txt">Testplatform</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The results are very interesting: While the md-based setup performs less consistent in and of itself, it still consistently outperforms ZFS in read performance.
When it comes to write, though, ZFS performs noticably better.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup></p>
<p>To investigate the cause of this unexpected balance, we note that while ZFS combines raid, integrity and filesystem in one component, for the md-based setup these are separate components.
Of these components, not only the filesystem, but also the <code>dm-integrity</code> implements journalling to avoid inconsistencies in case of a power outage.
This leads to increased work until the transaction has been fully flushed to disk, which can be seen in the next figure, where the md-based system (without the encryption layer) is tested with both journalling enabled and disabled in the integrity layer:</p>
<figure>
    <h4>Throughput effect of integrity journaling</h4>
    <img src="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/mdraid-journalling.svg" alt="Throughput for the md-based setup, with journalling enabled and disabled in the integrity-layer for both read and write. Each dot indicates one measurement, the green line indicates the median of all measurements. Testplatform"> <figcaption><p>Throughput for the md-based setup, with journalling enabled and disabled in the integrity-layer for both read and write. Each dot indicates one measurement, the green line indicates …</p></figcaption></figure></section></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/">https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://insanity.industries/post/preserving-data-integrity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24372662</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 07:41:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Costs of running a Python webapp for 55k monthly users]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 281 | Comments 243 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24372084">thread link</a>) | @caspii
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <div>

          


<article>
  <header>
    <h2 dir="auto"><a href="https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/">Costs of running a Python webapp for 55k monthly users</a></h2>
    <p><time datetime="2020-09-04T00:00:00+02:00">Fri Sep 4, 2020</time> by Caspar</p>
  </header>
  

<p>How much does running a webapp in production actually cost? Maybe more than you think. Keepthescore.co is a Python flask application running on DigitalOcean and Firebase. It currently has around 55k unique visitors per month, per day it’s around 3.4k.</p>

<p><img src="https://keepthescore.co/blog/money-tree.jpg" alt="A money tree">
<em>Image by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@micheile">Micheile Henderson</a></em></p>

<p>Here’s a monthly breakdown with some background information on each cost:</p>

<h3 id="servers-and-database-on-digitalocean">Servers and database on DigitalOcean</h3>

<p><strong>Costs per month: $95</strong></p>

<p>The webapp runs on two identical DigitalOcean servers (4 vCPUs, 8GB RAM, 80GB disk). We use a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue-green_deployment">blue-green deployment</a>, which is a great way of running and hosting a webapp (more on that in a future post) but it does mean that you need 2 identical production servers.</p>

<p>The database is a hosted Postgres instance also on DigitalOcean.</p>

<p>Note: the servers are oversized for the load we’re currently seeing. The reason for that is that we tried to solve a production issue by increasing the server specs. It didn’t solve the problem, and now we can’t down-size the servers without re-provisioning them 🤷‍♀️.</p>

<hr>

<h3 id="code-repo-on-github">Code repo on GitHub</h3>

<p><strong>Costs per month: $0</strong></p>

<p>This is free. Thanks GitHub!
</p><hr>

<h3 id="amazon-web-services">Amazon Web Services</h3>

<p><strong>Costs per month: $60</strong></p>

<p>We use a reporting tool called <a href="https://www.metabase.com/">Metabase</a> to generate insights and reports from the database. The tool itself is opensource and free, but hosting it is fairly expensive. Currently it runs on an EC2 instance. There are definitely some savings that could be realised here.
</p><hr>

<h3 id="google-cloud">Google Cloud</h3>

<p><strong>Costs per month: $1.32</strong></p>

<p>We use Firebase for the <a href="https://keepthescore.co/basketball-scoreboard/">realtime basketball scoreboard</a>. We also use the Google Sheets API for some custom scoreboards. Overall it must be said that the Google Cloud APIs are great value for money (so far).</p>

<p>We have plans to move away from DigitalOcean and onto Google Cloud infrastructure in the next year.
</p><hr>

<h3 id="dns-hosting">DNS hosting</h3>

<p><strong>Costs per month: $5</strong></p>

<p>Our domain is registered with <a href="https://dnsimple.com/">DNSimple.com</a>.
</p><hr>



<p><strong>Costs per month: $10</strong></p>

<p>Scoreboards and this blog have the option of allowing a discussion on the same page – this uses the <a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a> service. Disqus has a free tier but they began showing ads so we were forced to move to the paid tier.</p>

<p>We are planning to move to <a href="https://commento.io/">Commento</a> in the future, which is cheaper, has no ads, and respects your privacy.
</p><hr>

<h2 id="is-it-worth-it-is-there-revenue">Is it worth it? Is there revenue?</h2>

<p>In total that’s around <strong>$171 USD per month</strong>. If you’re running a company with employees that would be peanuts, but in this case the cost is being borne by a single indie-developer out of his own pocket.</p>

<p>The bigger issue is that on the revenue side there’s a big fat zero. This is the reason why we are currently working on monetization. This will include banner ads and payments via Stripe. Expect to see these features land by next week! Anyway, more about that in a future post.</p>

<h2 id="you-are-spending-way-too-much-money">You are spending way too much money!</h2>

<p>This post generated an interesting discussion on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24372084">Hacker News</a>. One recurring theme
was that our stack is large and expensive and that we could massively reduce costs.</p>

<p>This is true. But here are some things that are also true:</p>

<ul>
<li>“Reducing costs” is not our primary objective at the moment: time is more valuable than money right now.</li>
<li>Our primary objective right now is velocity of product development.</li>
<li>We are not devops experts and optimizing operations takes time.</li>
</ul>

<p>There will be a follow up post once we do optimize our stack.</p>

<p>Thanks for listening and so long, 👋</p>


  

  
  <hr>
  
  

</article> 



        </div> <!-- /.blog-main -->

        


      </div> <!-- /.row -->
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://keepthescore.co/blog/posts/costs-of-running-webapp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24372084</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 05:46:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Libvirt – The Unsung Hero of Cloud Computing (2013)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 211 | Comments 106 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24370966">thread link</a>) | @vikrantrathore
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><article><p><span>December 17, 2013</span>
        </p>
    <div id="libvirt-the-unsung-hero-of-cloud-computing">

<p><img alt="Libvirt The Unsung Hero of Cloud Computing Platforms" src="https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_the_unsung_hero.png"></p><p>Initially my intention was to write an article on <strong>Round up of open source Cloud Management Platforms (CMP)</strong>, but while doing research found one piece of software library so fundamental, that it holds the key to very existence of Cloud Computing services and platforms as we know it today (that includes Amazon AWS, OpenStack and CloudStack). So I decided to postpone my idea and started to write an article on this <strong>Unsung hero of Cloud Computing</strong> called libvirt <a href="#f1" id="id1">[1]</a>, which I believe many people won’t have heard of. Obviously talking about software library tend to be technical, so this article will have a technical tone, but I will attempt to make it readable for everyone interested in Cloud Computing.</p>
<p>Libvirt is an open source API, daemon and management tool for managing platform virtualzation and these APIs are widely used in the orchestration layer of Cloud Management Platform. Libvirt makes it possible to control and manage millions of compute nodes, storage and network devices via common programmable interface. Its like being able to control and orchestrate fleet of millions of car irrespective of different manufacturer, model, or engine through a common interface from a single car (it can be more then one car for redundancy and high availability). What started as a management API for Xen, today has been extended to support major components of Cloud Computing platforms.</p>
<div id="libvirt-goals-architecture">
<h2>Libvirt Goals &amp; Architecture</h2>
<p>Libvirt defines following terms for its goals <a href="#f2" id="id2">[2]</a>:</p>
<p><img alt="Mapping of libvirt terms to virtualized or containerized physical machine" src="https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_terms_mapping.png"></p><ul>
<li><strong>Node</strong> is a single physical machine.</li>
<li><strong>Hypervisor</strong> is a layer of softeare allowing to virtualize a node in a set of physical machines with possible different configurations that the node itself.</li>
<li><strong>Domain</strong> is an instance of an operating system (or subsystem in case of container virtualization like OpenVZ and lxc) running on a virtualized machine provided by the hypervisor.</li>
</ul>
<p>Based on above terms <strong>“The goal of libvirt is to provide a common and stable layer sufficient to securely manage domains on a node, possibly remote”</strong>. So libvirt should provide all APIs needed to do the management, such as: provision, create, modify, monitor, control, migrate and stop the domains - within the limits of the support of the hypervisor for those operations. This implies following sub-goals:</p>
<ul>
<li>All API can be carried remotely though secure APIs</li>
<li>While most API will be generic in term of hypervisor or Host OS, some API may be targeted to a single virtualization environment as long as the semantic for the operations from a domain management perspective is clear</li>
<li>the API should allow to do efficiently and cleanly all the operations needed to manage domains on a node, including resource provisioning and setup</li>
<li>the API will not try to provide high level virtualization policies or multi-nodes management features like load balancing, but the API should be sufficient so they can be implemented on top of libvirt</li>
<li>stability of the API is a big concern, libvirt should isolate applications from the frequent changes expected at the lower level of the virtualization framework</li>
<li>the node being managed may be on a different physical machine than the management program using libvirt, to this effect libvirt supports remote access, but should only do so by using secure protocols.</li>
<li>libvirt will provide APIs to enumerate, monitor and use the resources available on the managed node, including CPUs, memory, storage, networking, and NUMA partitions.</li>
</ul>
<p>So libvirt is intended to be a building block for higher level management tools and for applications focusing on virtualization of a single node (the only exception being domain migration between node capabilities which involves more than one node).</p>
<div id="libvirt-driver-based-architecture">
<h3>Libvirt Driver Based Architecture</h3>
<p><img alt="libvirt driver based architecture" src="https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_architecture.png"></p><p>Libvirt to support wide variety of hypervisor implements a driver-based architecture. Based on car analogy, it means delegating the actual implementation of control of different cars to the drivers specifically designed for make, model and engine of the specific car. Libvirt currently supports:</p>
<p><strong>Hypervisor</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>LXC - Linux Containers</li>
<li>OpenVZ</li>
<li>QEMU</li>
<li>Test - Used for testing</li>
<li>UML - User Mode Linux</li>
<li>VirtualBox</li>
<li>VMware ESX</li>
<li>VMware Workstation/Player</li>
<li>Xen</li>
<li>Microsoft Hyper-V</li>
<li>IBM PowerVM (phyp)</li>
<li>Parallels</li>
<li>Remote - Accessing libvirt on remote node through libvirtd (libvirt daemon)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Storage</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Directory backend</li>
<li>Local filesystem backend</li>
<li>Network filesystem backend</li>
<li>Logical Volume Manager (LVM) backend</li>
<li>Disk backend</li>
<li>iSCSI backend</li>
<li>SCSI backend</li>
<li>Multipath backend</li>
<li>RBD (RADOS Block Device) backend</li>
<li>Sheepdog backend</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Virtual Networks</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Bridging</li>
<li>NAT</li>
<li>VEPA (Virtual Ethernet Port Aggregator)</li>
<li>VN-LINK</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="libvirt-api-structure">
<h3>Libvirt API structure <a href="#f3" id="id3">[3]</a></h3>
<p><img alt="libvirt API structure" src="https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_api_structure.png"></p><p>The figure above shows the five main objects exported by the API:</p>
<dl>
<dt><strong>virConnectPtr</strong></dt>
<dd>Represents the connection to a hypervisor. Use one of the virConnectOpen functions to obtain connection to the hypervisor which is then used as a parameter to other connection API’s.</dd>
<dt><strong>virDomainPtr</strong></dt>
<dd>Represents one domain either active or defined (i.e. existing as permanent config file and storage but not currently running on that node). The function virConnectListAllDomains lists all the domains for the hypervisor.</dd>
<dt><strong>virNetworkPtr</strong></dt>
<dd>Represents one network either active or defined (i.e. existing as permanent config file and storage but not currently activated). The function virConnectListAllNetworks lists all the virtualization networks for the hypervisor.</dd>
<dt><strong>virStorageVolPtr</strong></dt>
<dd>Represents one storage volume generally used as a block device available to one of the domains. The function virStorageVolLookupByPath finds the storage volume object based on its path on the node.</dd>
<dt><strong>virStoragePoolPtr</strong></dt>
<dd>Represents a storage pool, which is a logical area used to allocate and store storage volumes. The function virConnectListAllStoragePools lists all of the virtualization storage pools on the hypervisor. The function virStoragePoolLookupByVolume finds the storage pool containing a given storage volume.</dd>
</dl>
<p>These names follow C conventions, but developers of cloud computing platforms and applications do not need to use C directly, there are language bindings available for major languages. Currently libvirt API language bindings <a href="#f4" id="id4">[4]</a> are available for C#, Java, OCaml, Perl, PHP, Python, Ruby.</p>
</div>
<div id="domain-management-architecture">
<h3>Domain Management Architecture</h3>
<p>There are two distinct means for domain management using libvirt API.</p>
<p><strong>1. Single node domain management</strong></p>
<p><img alt="libvirt API structure" src="https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_single_node_domain_management.png"></p><p>As illustrated in the figure above in this mode applications (cloud management platform i.e. CMP applications) and domains exist on the same node. In this scenario applications directly works through the libvirt api on the host operating system (os) to control and manage the local domains.</p>
<p><strong>2. Multi node domain management</strong></p>
<p><img alt="libvirt API structure" src="https://vyomtech.com/_images/libvirt_multi_node_domain_management.png"></p><p>As shown in the figure above, applications (CMP applications) using libvirt API and the domains to manage or control are on separate nodes. In this mode a special domain called <strong>libvirtd</strong> (libvirt daemon) needs to run on remote nodes. The management application nodes use the nodes underlying network communicattion to communicate with remote <em>libvirtd</em> through the local libvirt using custom protocol. Actually libvirt uses Remote <a href="#f6" id="id5">[6]</a> driver for communicating with remote node and remote API calls are handled synchronously. Remote driver for libvirt supports a range of transports like:</p>
<dl>
<dt><em>tls</em></dt>
<dd>TLS 1.0 (SSL 3.1) authenticated and encrypted TCP/IP socket, usually listening on a public port number. To use this you will need to generate client and server certificates. The standard port is 16514. This is the <strong>default</strong> transport, if no other is specified.</dd>
<dt><em>unix</em></dt>
<dd>nix domain socket. Since this is only accessible on the local machine, it is not encrypted, and uses Unix permissions or SELinux for authentication. The standard socket names are /var/run/libvirt/libvirt-sock and /var/run/libvirt/libvirt-sock-ro (the latter for read-only connections).</dd>
<dt><em>ssh</em></dt>
<dd>Transported over an ordinary ssh (secure shell) connection. Requires Netcat (nc) installed and libvirtd should be running on the remote machine. You should use some sort of ssh key management (eg. ssh-agent) otherwise programs which use this transport will stop to ask for a password.</dd>
<dt><em>ext</em></dt>
<dd>Any external program which can make a connection to the remote machine by means outside the scope of libvirt.</dd>
<dt><em>tcp</em></dt>
<dd>nencrypted TCP/IP socket. Not recommended for production use, this is normally disabled, but an administrator can enable it for testing or use over a trusted network. The standard port is 16509.</dd>
<dt><em>libssh2</em></dt>
<dd>Transport over the SSH protocol using libssh2 instead of the OpenSSH binary. This transport uses the libvirt authentication callback for all ssh authentication calls and therefore supports keyboard-interactive authentication even with graphical management applications. As with the classic ssh transport netcat is required on the remote side.</dd>
</dl>
</div>
</div>
<div id="libvirt-project">
<h2>Libvirt Project <a href="#f5" id="id6">[5]</a></h2>
<p>According to statistics on ohloh libvirt in a nutshell:</p>
<ul>
<li>15,188 commits made  by 331 contributors representing 481,506 lines of code</li>
<li>Mostly written in C</li>
</ul>
<table>
<colgroup>
<col width="50%">
<col width="50%">
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr><th colspan="2">Libvirt project</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr><td>C</td>
<td>74%</td>
</tr>
<tr><td>C++</td>
<td>9%</td>
</tr>
<tr><td>XML</td>
<td>6%</td>
</tr>
<tr><td>14 Other</td>
<td>11%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<ul>
<li>Established, mature codebase maintained by a very large development team with increasing year on year commits.</li>
<li>Estimated 128 years of efforts (COCOMO model)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div id="conclusion">
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Libvirt is one very important library on whose giant shoulders cloud computing services and platforms like Amazon AWS, Google Compute Engine, OpenStack, CloudStack, Eucalyptus and numberous others are standing. Also this API enables developers and companies to build new and innovative cloud computing services or platforms and build awesome applications or services on top of it. Libvirt started in 2005 and with growing popularity of cloud computing, this project will continue to grow. But in most of the conferences, talks and papers related to Cloud Computing I did not find much coverage of libvirt, so while researching Cloud Management platform thought of writing and article on it. Kudos to all the libvirt code contributors for building a beautiful abstraction layer and making life easier for cloud computing services and platform developers. In spite of not getting as much press and coverage as …</p></div></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html">https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vyomtech.com/2013/12/17/libvirt_the_unsung_hero_of_cloud_computing.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24370966</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 01:46:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Daniel Stenberg (curl) has been denied entry to the US for 870 days]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 323 | Comments 178 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24369233">thread link</a>) | @tehwebguy
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/us-visa.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/us-visa.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p> Time passed since Daniel applied for a US visa </p>
<p><span>
  <span id="days">00</span> days, <span id="hours">00</span> hours,
  <span id="minutes">00</span> minutes and <span id="seconds">00</span> seconds
</span></p><p> Background </p>
<p>
 On June 26th 2017, Daniel was denied to travel to the US - while still having
 a valid ESTA and passport. He was then denied ESTA on April 3, 2018. When
 subsequently applying for a visa instead, there has been no response for over
 two years. (To <i>visit</i>, not to apply for permanent residency.)
</p><p>
 This page was edited with new content on: <b>September 4, 2020</b>.
</p><p> Blog posts </p>
<p> First blog post: <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2018/07/28/administrative-purgatory/">Administrative

 purgatory</a>
</p><p> The one year anniversary: <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2019/04/17/one-year-in-still-no-visa/">One

year in still no visa</a>.
</p><p> <a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/04/17/two-years-in/">Two years in</a>

</p><p> FAQ </p>
<p>
<a href="#long">Do you know why this takes so long?</a>
</p><div>
<p> No. They've just informed me "someone is working on it" and that it "may take a long time" but without qualifying what that means.
</p><p> I've talked to several persons who've experienced similar situations, and
  I've learned about waiting times up to 20 months until a definite "no". I used
  to think of that as a sort of "worst case" waiting time. Now we know it can
  take longer...
</p></div>
<p>
<a href="#esta">Why don't you just apply for an ESTA?</a>
</p><p>
  I already did and they denied me that. See one of the <a href="#images">images below</a>.
</p>
<p>
Why did they deny you ESTA?
</p><p>
  I don't know as they won't tell. And I also don't know why they can't respond to my visa application.
</p>
<p>
<a href="#working">So, someone is working on it?</a>
</p><p>
  Allegedly, yes. I'm sure that person must be working very hard...
</p>
<p>
<a href="#eventually">Do you think they will grant you a visa eventually?</a>
</p><div>
<p>
  No. I've been in contact with many people who have been in similar
  situations such as this, as well as many people who have applied for visas
  for very complicated matters, and it is basically unheard of that it would
  take this long time and still end up with a positive response in the end.
</p><p>
  Someone emailed me and explained how they got their visa approved after 10
  months waiting - so it obviously <i>can</i> happen after a fairly
  long time!
</p></div>
<p>
<a name="#arab">Did you travel to any arab countries, middle-east, North Korea, Sudan, Iran or Iraq?</a>
</p><p>
 No.
</p>
<p>
<a name="#ever">Did you ever visit the US?</a>
</p><div>
<p> Yes, I've visted the US around a dozen times over a time period of almost
 twenty years. I've applied and gotten ESTA permissions several times. I have
 many friends living and working in the US.
</p><p> My latest visit to the US was in December 2016 - using the same ESTA and
 passport I subsequently wanted to use in the summer of 2017 when I was first
 denied travelling to the US.
</p></div>
<p>
<a href="#blocked">How many trips have this blocked you from taking so far?</a>
</p><div>
<p> I've been invited personally to several meetings in the US that I couldn't
 attend. (excluding IETF, HTTPbis or QUIC meetings)
</p><ol>
<li> San Francisco June 2017. Mozilla All Hands.
</li><li> San Francisco June 2018. Mozilla All hands.
</li><li> San Francisco October 2018. Conference speaking engagement.
</li><li> Orlando, Florida December 2018. Mozilla All hands.
</li><li> Portland, Oregon January 2019. Conference speaking engagement.
</li><li> California, March 2019. Conference speaking engagement.
</li><li> Summer of 2019. Wedding.
</li></ol>
</div>
<p>
<a href="#employer">Can't your employer help you?</a>
</p><p> We've already tried all available ways to get information or otherwise
bring this effort forward. To no avail.
</p>
<p>
<a href="#Mozilla">Will Mozilla move more meetings outside of the US?</a>
</p><p> Yes. Several of the coming All hands are now planned and scheduled to
happen outside of the US, for example in Canada and Germany. But I will not be
there to experience them since I quit Mozilla in December 2018.
</p>
<p>
Will your visa situation change when you've quit Mozilla?
</p><p> Unfortunately, there is no reason to suspect or hope so.
</p>
<p>
<a href="#lost">Maybe they lost your application?</a>
</p><div>
<p> I emailed them in July 2019 just to make sure they just hadn't
 forgot about my case or similar over the past year, and I received their
 reply on August 1st 2019. The response said "I have forwarded your email to
 my supervisor to highlight the problem."  - but then nothing more came.
</p><p> I emailed them again on January 28, 2020.<br>
<img src="https://daniel.haxx.se/media/651-days-email.png">
</p><p>
 They responded very politely:
 </p><pre>Dear Sir,
&nbsp;
All applications are processed in the most expeditious manner
possible. While we understand your frustration, we are required to follow
immigration law regarding visa issuances. This process cannot be expedited or
circumvented. Rest assured that we will contact you as soon as the
administrative processing is concluded.
</pre>
</div>
<p>
<a href="#likely">What do you think is the most likely explanation for this treatment?</a>
</p><div>
<p> I think one of the likelier explantions is that someone somewhere has
 found my name and my code used in some evil or malicious manner and drawn the
 wrong conclusions about how my code ended up there or how I could've been
 involved. Like for example in some malware, virus or other attack software. I
 make tools and code available for free and openly and sometimes those are
 unfortunately used in ways I don't condone.
</p><p> Since they won't tell me why, basically all theories are equally likely.
 We just won't know.
</p></div>
<p>
Any other plausible explanations?
</p><div>
<p> People have mentioned my domain name <b>haxx.se</b> or suggested it is
because I've referred to myself as "a hacker" at times. I find that unlikely
since I used the domain and used the term for decades before this.
</p><p> Others have offered the explanation that the immigration authorities
might've decided that I violated the ESTA rules in a previous visit. I can of
course not know what they think, but I have not violated those rules.
</p></div>
<p>
<a href="#crime">Convicted of a crime?</a>
</p><p>
No, I've never been convicted of a crime in Sweden and not anywhere else. Not even
charged. Nor have I ever been involved in a lawsuit of any kind.
</p>
<p>
<a href="#license">Can you change the curl license?</a>
</p><div><p>
Lots of people suggest this, most probably in jest, but let me be perfectly
clear: no I won't change the curl license.
</p><ol>
 <li> excluding a specific user would make a license to not be open source anymore
 </li><li> curl has many more copyrights than mine, it would be hard
 </li><li> curl is bigger than me personally, I wouldn't do it anyway
</li></ol>
</div>
<p>
<a href="#covid">But Covid-19?</a>
</p><p>
During the Corona pandemic (starting in spring 2020), the US has closed its
borders for a lot of more people who otherwise would have been allowed
entry. I suspect the visa processing has slowed down during this period since
people can't go there anyway. But I have not been notified about anything and
I still expect to get a rejection at some point. Pandemic or not.
</p>
<p>
<a href="#officials">Have you contacted any US officials?</a>
</p><div><p>
A US citizen friend of mine sent the following text in an email to the
U.S. Congressman Gerry Connolly on September 3, 2020.
</p><pre>Dear Representative Gerry Connolly:
&nbsp;
Could you please help my friend Daniel Stenberg *finally* gain permission to
travel to the US? He has been denied permission to travel to the US for years,
yet there is no cause for it.
&nbsp;
On June 26, 2017, Mr. Stenberg was denied to travel to the US, even though he
had a valid ESTA and passport. He was then denied ESTA on April 3, 2018. He
then applied for a visa in April 2018, and has *still* not heard anything.
&nbsp;
This is especially galling because is a widely-known leader in the computer
community. He developed and maintains the "curl" program, a program used
worldwide by many software developers and computer system administrators. In
October 2017 he won the "Polhem prize" for his work on curl; in that ceremony
the Swedish king personally handed Daniel a gold medal. In February 2019 he
joined wolfSSL, an American company (he's their only Swedish hire), and yet
he's still not allowed to travel to the US.
&nbsp;
Perhaps there is a confusion about the word "hacker". In the computer
community, a "hacker" is NOT someone who breaks into computers, a hacker
is "a person who delights in having an intimate understanding of the
internal workings of a system, computers and computer networks in
particular."  ( IETF RFC 1983, https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1983).

Mr. Stenberg does *not* break into computers without authorization.
&nbsp;
At the least, the State Department should have asked questions instead of
reflexively denying entry to a world leader in the computer industry.
&nbsp;
More information is available on his personal website:
https://daniel.haxx.se/us-visa.html

https://daniel.haxx.se/about.html

&nbsp;
Thank you very much!
&nbsp;
--- [name redacted]
</pre>
</div>
<p> Images </p>
<p> This is what the online visa application status site showed for my case on
July 30, 2019:
</p><center>
<img src="https://daniel.haxx.se/media/Administrative-Processing.png"></center>
<p> This is what an ESTA rejection looks like:
</p><center>
<img src="https://daniel.haxx.se/media/ESTA-travel-not-authorized.png"></center>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/us-visa.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24369233</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 21:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Writing an Efficient Vulkan Renderer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 104 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24368353">thread link</a>) | @noch
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://zeux.io/2020/02/27/writing-an-efficient-vulkan-renderer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://zeux.io/2020/02/27/writing-an-efficient-vulkan-renderer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p><span>

27 Feb 2020

</span></p><p>In 2018, I wrote an article “Writing an efficient Vulkan renderer” for GPU Zen 2 book, which was published in 2019. In this article I tried to aggregate as much information about Vulkan performance as I could - instead of trying to focus on one particular aspect or application, this is trying to cover a wide range of topics, give readers an understanding of the behavior of different APIs on real hardware and provide a range of options for each problem that needs to be solved.</p>

<p>At the time of publishing this article, the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/GPU-Zen-Advanced-Rendering-Techniques-ebook/dp/B07SYP7P6B">Kindle edition of the book</a> is available for $2.99 on Amazon - that’s cheaper than a cup of coffee and it’s definitely worth your time and money. It contains many great articles about rendering effects and design.</p>

<p>This, however, is the full, free of charge copy of the article - hopefully it will help graphics programmers to understand and use Vulkan to the full of its ability. The article has been lightly edited to mention Vulkan 1.1/1.2 promotions where applicable - fortunately, not much has changed in the last two years for Vulkan performance, so the content should still be mostly accurate.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>

<!--more-->



<p>Vulkan is a new explicit cross-platform graphics API. It introduces many new concepts that may be unfamiliar to even seasoned graphics programmers. The key goal of Vulkan is performance – however, attaining good performance requires in-depth knowledge about these concepts and how to apply them efficiently, as well as how particular driver implementations implement these. This article will explore topics such as memory allocation, descriptor set management, command buffer recording, pipeline barriers, render passes and discuss ways to optimize CPU and GPU performance of production desktop/mobile Vulkan renderers today as well as look at what a future looking Vulkan renderer could do differently.</p>

<p>Modern renderers are becoming increasingly complex and must support many different graphics APIs with varying levels of hardware abstraction and disjoint sets of concepts. This sometimes makes it challenging to support all platforms at the same level of efficiency. Fortunately, for most tasks Vulkan provides multiple options that can be as simple as reimplementing concepts from other APIs with higher efficiency due to targeting the code specifically towards the renderer needs, and as hard as redesigning large systems to make them optimal for Vulkan. We will try to cover both extremes when applicable – ultimately, this is a tradeoff between maximum efficiency on Vulkan-capable systems and implementation and maintenance costs that every engine needs to carefully pick. Additionally, efficiency is often application-dependent – the guidance in this article is generic and ultimately best performance is achieved by profiling the target application on a target platform and making an informed implementation decision based on the results.</p>

<p>This article assumes that the reader is familiar with the basics of Vulkan API, and would like to understand them better and/or learn how to use the API efficiently.</p>



<p>Memory management remains an exceedingly complex topic, and in Vulkan it gets even more so due to the diversity of heap configurations on different hardware. Earlier APIs adopted a resource-centric concept – the programmer doesn’t have a concept of graphics memory, only that of a graphics resource, and different drivers are free to manage the resource memory based on API usage flags and a set of heuristics. Vulkan, however, forces to think about memory management up front, as you must manually allocate memory to create resources.</p>

<p>A perfectly reasonable first step is to integrate <code>VulkanMemoryAllocator</code> (henceforth abbreviated as VMA), which is an open-source library developed by AMD that solves some memory management details for you by providing a general purpose resource allocator on top of Vulkan functions. Even if you do use that library, there are still multiple performance considerations that apply; the rest of this section will go over memory caveats without assuming you use VMA; all of the guidance applies equally to VMA.</p>

<h2 id="memory-heap-selection">Memory heap selection</h2>

<p>When creating a resource in Vulkan, you have to choose a heap to allocate memory from. Vulkan device exposes a set of memory types where each memory type has flags that define the behavior of that memory, and a heap index that defines the available size.</p>

<p>Most Vulkan implementations expose two or three of the following flag combinations<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_DEVICE_LOCAL_BIT</code> – this is generally referring to GPU memory that is not directly visible from CPU; it’s fastest to access from the GPU and this is the memory you should be using to store all render targets, GPU-only resources such as buffers for compute, and also all static resources such as textures and geometry buffers.</li>
  <li><code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_DEVICE_LOCAL_BIT | VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_HOST_VISIBLE_BIT</code> – on AMD hardware, this memory type refers to up to 256 MB of video memory that the CPU can write to directly, and is perfect for allocating reasonable amounts of data that is written by CPU every frame, such as uniform buffers or dynamic vertex/index buffers</li>
  <li><code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_HOST_VISIBLE_BIT | VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_HOST_COHERENT_BIT</code><sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>  – this is referring to CPU memory that is directly visible from GPU; reads from this memory go over PCI-express bus. In absence of the previous memory type, this generally speaking should be the choice for uniform buffers or dynamic vertex/index buffers, and also should be used to store staging buffers that are used to populate static resources allocated with <code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_DEVICE_LOCAL_BIT</code> with data.</li>
  <li><code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_DEVICE_LOCAL_BIT | VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_LAZILY_ALLOCATED_BIT</code> – this is referring to GPU memory that might never need to be allocated for render targets on tiled architectures. It is recommended to use lazily allocated memory to save physical memory for large render targets that are never stored to, such as MSAA images or depth images.
On integrated GPUs, there is no distinction between GPU and CPU memory – these devices generally expose <code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_DEVICE_LOCAL_BIT | VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_HOST_VISIBLE_BIT</code> that you can allocate all static resources through as well.</li>
</ul>

<p>When dealing with dynamic resources, in general allocating in non-device-local host-visible memory works well – it simplifies the application management and is efficient due to GPU-side caching of read-only data. For resources that have a high degree of random access though, like dynamic textures, it’s better to allocate them in <code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_DEVICE_LOCAL_BIT</code> and upload data using staging buffers allocated in <code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_HOST_VISIBLE_BIT</code> memory – similarly to how you would handle static textures. In some cases you might need to do this for buffers as well – while uniform buffers typically don’t suffer from this, in some applications using large storage buffers with highly random access patterns will generate too many PCIe transactions unless you copy the buffers to GPU first; additionally, host memory does have higher access latency from the GPU side that can impact performance for many small draw calls.</p>

<p>When allocating resources from <code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_DEVICE_LOCAL_BIT</code>, in case of VRAM oversubscription you can run out of memory; in this case you should fall back to allocating the resources in non-device-local <code>VK_MEMORY_PROPERTY_HOST_VISIBLE_BIT</code> memory. Naturally you should make sure that large frequently used resources such as render targets are allocated first. There are other things you can do in an event of an oversubscription, such as migrating resources from GPU memory to CPU memory for less frequently used resources – this is outside of the scope of this article; additionally, on some operating systems like Windows 10 correct handling of oversubscription requires APIs that are not currently available in Vulkan.</p>

<h2 id="memory-suballocation">Memory suballocation</h2>

<p>Unlike some other APIs that allow an option to perform one memory allocation per resource, in Vulkan this is impractical for large applications – drivers are only required to support up to 4096 individual allocations. In addition to the total number being limited, allocations can be slow to perform, may waste memory due to assuming worst case possible alignment requirements, and also require extra overhead during command buffer submission to ensure memory residency. Because of this, suballocation is necessary. A typical pattern of working with Vulkan involves performing large (e.g. 16 MB – 256 MB depending on how dynamic the memory requirements are) allocations using <code>vkAllocateMemory</code>, and performing suballocation of objects within this memory, effectively managing it yourself. Critically, the application needs to handle alignment of memory requests correctly, as well as <code>bufferImageGranularity</code> limit that restricts valid configurations of buffers and images.</p>

<p>Briefly, <code>bufferImageGranularity</code> restricts the relative placement of buffer and image resources in the same allocation, requiring additional padding between individual allocations. There are several ways to handle this:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Always over-align image resources (as they typically have larger alignment to begin with) by bufferImageGranularity, essentially using a maximum of required alignment and <code>bufferImageGranularity</code> for address and size alignment.</li>
  <li>Track resource type for each allocation, and have the allocator add the requisite padding only if the previous or following resource is of a different type. This requires a somewhat more complex allocation algorithm.</li>
  <li>Allocate images and buffers in separate Vulkan allocations, thus sidestepping the entire problem. This reduces internal fragmentation due to smaller alignment padding but can waste more memory if the backing allocations are too big (e.g. 256 MB).</li>
</ul>

<p>On many GPUs the required alignment for image resources is substantially bigger than it is for buffers which makes the last option attractive – in addition to reducing waste due to lack of extra …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://zeux.io/2020/02/27/writing-an-efficient-vulkan-renderer/">https://zeux.io/2020/02/27/writing-an-efficient-vulkan-renderer/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://zeux.io/2020/02/27/writing-an-efficient-vulkan-renderer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24368353</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 20:13:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pachyderm Hub: data science without the hassle of managing infrastructure]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 107 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24365697">thread link</a>) | @jdoliner
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://www.pachyderm.com/blog/pachyderm-hub-is-now-in-production/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.pachyderm.com/blog/pachyderm-hub-is-now-in-production/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content"><article><div><div><p><img src="https://www.pachyderm.com/images/blog-images/hub-ga-announcement-hero.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Today we’re announcing the production ready availability of <a href="https://hub.pachyderm.com/">Pachyderm Hub</a>, our powerful end-to-end machine learning and data lineage platform in the cloud. Hub delivers all the key features of the <a href="https://www.pachyderm.com/">Pachyderm</a> suite but in a completely managed cloud-native environment. You no longer need to have Kubernetes and cloud infrastructure expertise in-house, Pachyderm Hub let’s you seamlessly spin up a cluster in minutes.</p><p>While Pachyderm always delivered the power teams needed to do data science at scale, you also needed a strong systems administration and architecture team to get Kubernetes and containers into production. Kuberenetes is way more than just software you download and install. It needs monitoring and management, backup, redundancy, capacity and upgrade planning, to name just a few. That represents a real challenge for some organizations. Now, we’ve removed the barriers to entry, which makes it possible for smaller teams to start doing data science faster.</p><p>Pachyderm Hub includes all of the features that were challenging for teams to set up, like autoscaling with GPUs, security and isolation, backup, and automation. Now you can rely on Pachyderm’s trained team of Kubernetes experts to handle the infrastructure for you and concentrate on data science instead of systems administration. Kubernetes is powerful, but the real power comes from the applications you can run on it.</p><blockquote><h4 id="you-simply-bring-your-code-and-data-pachyderm-hub-handles-all-the-infrastructure">You simply bring your code and data, Pachyderm Hub handles all the infrastructure.</h4></blockquote><p>More than anything, Pachyderm Hub delivers on our ultimate vision for a fully collaborative, shareable, and reproducible data science platform. It does what Git did for data, bringing powerful version control and collaboration to your AI applications development. Pachyderm Hub makes team collaboration and sharing data, code, and infra totally seamless. Team members can create and share workspaces, invite other team members to collaborate, and behind the scenes the platform scales transparently as you add workloads.</p><p>Since our launch 2014, Pachyderm’s data science platform has quickly become a foundation for the <a href="http://ai-infrastructure.org/">emerging Canonical Stack (CS) in machine learning</a>. Because other platforms only let you track metadata, they lack the true iron-clad immutability of a robust version controlled file system. If your data can change after you’ve recorded your metadata then you can’t reproduce critical data science results. Our customers understand the need for true data lineage and data versioning. That’s why over the past year, Pachyderm has attracted tremendous new enterprise customers like Shell, LogMeIn, Battelle Ecology, and AgBiome, as well as multiple government agencies, pharmaceutical and bioinformatics companies, two major North American banks, and other Fortune 500 powerhouses.</p><p>Beyond data versioning, customers choose Pachyderm because they need a clean, simple and elegant data science pipeline system that delivers data science at scale. The Pachyderm platform allows teams to bring any framework, language or library and fit them together into a smooth, automated workflow with ease. If it can run in a Docker container it can run on Pachyderm.Customers aren’t locked into one tool like Spark, R or Python, or one machine learning framework, like Pytorch or Tensorflow. They can use it all on one complete system.</p><blockquote><h4 id="launch-your-free-workspace-todayhttpshubpachydermcom"><a href="https://hub.pachyderm.com/">Launch your free workspace today!</a></h4></blockquote><p>If you’re ready to do production workloads you can easily upgrade to benefit from GPUs and enterprise team collaboration, just <strong><a href="https://www.pachyderm.com/request-a-demo/">talk with one of our experts</a></strong>, or join our <strong><a href="https://www.pachyderm.com/slack/">open source community on Slack</a></strong> and check out the Pachyderm codebase on <strong><a href="https://github.com/pachyderm/pachyderm">Github</a></strong>.</p></div></div></article></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.pachyderm.com/blog/pachyderm-hub-is-now-in-production/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24365697</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 16:28:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Home Office Projects Series: Air conditioner setup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 161 | Comments 168 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24364080">thread link</a>) | @gcds
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://www.techprowd.com/home-office-projects-series-air-conditioner-setup/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.techprowd.com/home-office-projects-series-air-conditioner-setup/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <p>After I have moved from a tiny tiny apartment 9m^2 in Tokyo to a big one 3LDK (2 western-style rooms, kitchen, living/dining room, and tatami room) I decided that I am going to use one of the westerner rooms as my home office/laboratory and with this idea, a lot of project ideas appeared in my head what I could do with my home office. One of the first projects which I have already finished was getting an Air Conditioner in the home office room</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-7.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-7.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-7.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-7.png 1024w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>I bought two Panasonic ACs for the home office and bedroom. The living room already had an air conditioner. They are pretty small and. efficient units for 6 tatamis sized room (~9.72m^2)</p><p>As a European from North Europe Japanese spring/summer has hitten hard for an unexpected guy coming from a different continent. The weather until late May was without any issues pleasant temperatures sunny days and then <strong>THE Rainy Season</strong> came which introduced me with the new term <strong>Humidity</strong> to which I was never used or never had much concern living in Europe. When your room humidity level reaches 70-80% you would want to reduce the humidity level quickly as high humidity can introduce a lot of problems for your apartment. This is where Air Conditioner comes which helps with these issues by utilizing Dehumidifier mode which reduces humidity in the room pretty quickly.</p><p>After this unexpectedly pretty long Rainy season the real summer came up with really high temperatures as far as 35-45ºC which were devastating as my apartment was the top floor so it would heat up to around 32ºC in the home office room as soon as 8 AM. So the air conditioner was a must item in my home office!</p><p>Not to forget the winters in Tokyo can get mildly cold too, but so you know Japanese apartments in most cases lack any central heating system so you have few options to warm up urself:</p><ul><li>Electric Fan Heater (Most common device in Europe I think)</li><li>Electric Radiator</li><li>Electric Infrared Heater</li><li>Electric Blanket</li><li>Kerosine Heater</li><li>Gas Fan Heater</li><li>Gas Heater</li></ul><p>Yes I know burning stuff inside the apartment for westerners would sound crazy but most Japanese apartments there are special pipes/tubes in walls with covers for exhaust fumes, etc. same with air conditioners their special pipes for passing air conditioner refrigerant/electrical lines to the outside.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-8.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-8.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-8.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-8.png 1002w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>You probably would not believe if I told you that the small square socket near the bottom big pipe is a gas outlet. Yes, <strong>GAS </strong>outlet and the most interesting thing is it is in every room so technically I could run Gas heaters (which someone told me are cheaper than electrical counterparts) to heat rooms but that's for later on it is still just the beginning of Autumn!</p><h2 id="the-reason-why-i-choose-panasonic-air-conditioners"><br>The reason why I choose Panasonic Air Conditioners</h2><p>One of the main reasons I choose Panasonic was because my living room had Panasonic AC cs-409cfr2-w which was provided with an apartment from all 4 rooms only one living room had AC preinstalled. I had in plan to make my apartment a bit smarter I guess so I found out that Panasonic AC (In Japan don't know other countries as they heavily differ in features) I decided to go with Panasonic as they had special modules which are plugged into AC and then connects to Gateway module which would allow me to control all AC remotely.</p><h2 id="i-wouldn-t-be-an-engineer-if-i-would-not-try-to-take-apart-them-before-they-were-installed-by-professionals">I wouldn't be an engineer if I would not try to take apart them before they were installed by professionals</h2><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-10.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-10.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-10.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-10.png 1024w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-11.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-11.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-11.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-11.png 1024w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-12.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-12.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-12.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-12.png 1024w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>I had to take them apart as I will need to install radio modules myself as I was scared that AC installers going to charge extra as in Japan all services usually cost extra and it's not cheap!</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-13.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-13.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-13.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>One of the things I like about Japan that almost everything has a schematic on there somewhere hidden makes trying to understand things much easier.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-14.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-14.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-14.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Everything looks so clean!</p><p>This module connects to the LAN and bridges all Panasonic 920Mhz compatible devices to the network.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-15.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-15.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-15.png 640w"></figure><p>At first look, it didn't look that small, and first thought it was running some arm embedded Linux or similar stuff as it is usual with IoT devices. When it arrived from Amazon I was amazed by how small it is:</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-16.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-16.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-16.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/09/image-16.png 1600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w2400/2020/09/image-16.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Again how I would not be tinkerer if I don't take it apart and see which SoC it runs?</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-17.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-17.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-17.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-18.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-18.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-18.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-20.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-20.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-20.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>I was amazed as you! I guess it's custom labeled <a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f417ve.html">STM32F417VET6</a> 168Mhz ARM Cortex-M4! It's not even ARM9 or anything. </p><p>Considering it managers something similar to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/6LoWPAN">6LoWPAN</a> network, act as <a href="https://echonet.jp/hems_en/">Echonet Lite (Japanese home automation internet protocol)</a> gateway, and also communicates with Panasonic servers as the Panasonic AC app works even outside the home internet network. I was amazed at how much they cramped inside it.</p><p>It uses <a href="http://file.elecfans.com/web1/M00/99/0F/o4YBAF0VytaAI7ezABH66fmIRIg854.pdf?filename=RTL8201F-VB-CG.pdf">Realtek RTL8201FR</a> Ethernet PHY Receiver for ethernet communication and <a href="https://www.silabs.com/wireless/proprietary/ezradiopro-sub-ghz-ics/device.si4432">Silicon Labs Si4432</a> Wireless Transceiver.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-21.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-21.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-21.png 640w"></figure><p>This module plugs into the AC indoor unit mainboard.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-22.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-22.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-22.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Same radio transceiver but no idea about MCU as it proprietary something sad...</p><h2 id="installation-day">Installation day</h2><p>Early morning Japanese AC installers ringed at the door and came to install my AC's for which I have waited for over a month (It is summer period pretty busy I guess) I was already ready to install myself as I have watched enough of youtube videos to know how everything goes just needed to rent tools but sadly I had already paid for installation when I bought them.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-23.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-23.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-23.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>The installers were pretty clean and quick-witted with their work it took a few hours to get two units installed!</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-24.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-24.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-24.png 768w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>They have some special playdough or something similar to seal the hole.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-25.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-25.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-25.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1600/2020/09/image-25.png 1600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w2400/2020/09/image-25.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><h2 id="air-conditioner-automation">Air Conditioner Automation</h2><p>Panasonic has a pretty decent mobile application to control the air conditioners. (Sadly it's in Japanese)</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-27.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-27.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-27.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-27.png 1242w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>The app was nice but I wanted it to integrate into some other automation services which technically according Panasonic not possible apart Echonet Lite protocol.</p><p>So I spent one Saturday reverse engineering the communication protocol between iOS application and Panasonic Web Servers and managed to make NodeJS based client to their API.</p><figure><a href="https://github.com/aurimasniekis/eolia-client"><div><p>aurimasniekis/eolia-client</p><p>A NodeJS Panasonic Eolia Air Conditioner App API Client - aurimasniekis/eolia-client</p><p><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg"><span>GitHub</span></p></div><p><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/15481?s=400&amp;v=4"></p></a></figure><p>Afterward, I spend some time trying to integrate this client with <a href="https://homebridge.io/">HomeBridge</a>. </p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-28.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-28.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-28.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-28.png 1242w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-29.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-29.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-29.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-29.png 1242w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Everything went smoothly until I reached Panasonic API rate limitations some calls required a 2min delay in between calls which made using HomeKit practically impossible as HomeKit updates the accessory state every time you change some parameters. Of course, I could try to buffer those changes and send one request but then it would deny the whole idea of making it quicker to use. So I scrapped the idea but the code is still here if anybody is interested:</p><figure><a href="https://github.com/aurimasniekis/homebridge-eolia"><div><p>aurimasniekis/homebridge-eolia</p><p>A Panasonic Eolia Air Conditionner integration into HomeBridge - aurimasniekis/homebridge-eolia</p><p><img src="https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg"><span>aurimasniekis</span><span>GitHub</span></p></div><p><img src="https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/15481?s=400&amp;v=4"></p></a></figure><p>So what I can do to make it better. Then I found out that Panasonic Wireless Gateway also exposes as Echonet Lite gateway and all air conditioners are available to be commanded via it without any limitations. After playing around with several libraries (Compared to other protocols and automation standards these severely lacks community libraries 😣) I managed to produce some code that was able to control ACs with the easy and best thing it's instant and no Beeping sound perfect for thermostat style operation!</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-26.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-26.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-26.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-26.png 1045w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>So far I haven't done anything more regarding Echonet Lite integration but I have some plans which I want to work on one of them is to make the Echonet Lite to Web API bridge interface but this time to use Golang as I have done some light coding in a different project (Which I am going to soon release an article about pretty soon)</p><p>The next article in this series will be my home office workbench design and construction.</p>
                </div>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.techprowd.com/home-office-projects-series-air-conditioner-setup/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24364080</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 13:57:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Picasso, Schoenberg, Moss: how humans unlock social capital and spark progress]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24363273">thread link</a>) | @anacleto
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://blog.leonardofederico.com/2020/08/how-humans-unlock-social-capital.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.leonardofederico.com/2020/08/how-humans-unlock-social-capital.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<h3>
<a href="https://blog.leonardofederico.com/2020/08/how-humans-unlock-social-capital.html">Picasso, Schoenberg, Moss: how humans unlock social capital</a>
</h3><p>
(See <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24363273">HN thread</a> here.)</p><p>

Once every while I read something that changes my perspective on things. Usually, not because it reveals a ground-breaking truth, but because it helps me connect the dots backward. Suddenly, things are now integral parts of a larger picture and everything makes more sense.</p><p>

A year ago I read this piece from Eugene Wei: <a href="https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2019/2/19/status-as-a-service" target="_blank">Status as a Service</a>.</p><p>

Eugene writes:</p><blockquote>
Why does proof of work matter for a social network? If people want to maximize social capital, why not make that as easy as possible? As with cryptocurrency, if it were so easy, it wouldn't be worth anything. Value is tied to scarcity, and scarcity on social networks derives from proof of work. Status isn't worth much if there's no skill and effort required to mine it. It's not that a social network that makes it easy for lots of users to perform well can't be a useful one, but competition for relative status still motivates humans. Recall our first tenet: humans are status-seeking monkeys. Status is a relative ladder. By definition, if everyone can achieve a certain type of status, it’s no status at all, it’s a participation trophy.</blockquote><p>
He continues:</p><blockquote>
Read Twitter today and hardly any of the tweets are the mundane life updates of its awkward pre-puberty years. We are now in late-stage performative Twitter, where nearly every tweet is hungry as hell for favorites and retweets, and everyone is a trained pundit or comedian. It's hot takes and cool proverbs all the way down. The harmless status update Twitter was a less thirsty scene but also not much of a business. Still, sometimes I miss the halcyon days when not every tweet was a thirst trap. I hate the new Kanye, the bad mood Kanye, the always rude Kanye, spaz in the news Kanye, I miss the sweet Kanye, chop up the beats Kanye.</blockquote><p>
Then, goes:</p><blockquote>
So, to answer an earlier question about how a new social network takes hold, let’s add this: a new Status as a Service business must devise some proof of work that depends on some actual skill to differentiate among users. If it does, then it creates, like an ICO, some new form of social capital currency of value to those users.</blockquote>
<p>
This didn't just resonate with me. It helped me understand on a deeper level how and why visual arts, aesthetics, music, and human taste in general develop.</p><p>

Let’s start from the ground up.</p><p>

In a few words, the article states that:</p><ul>
<li>Social Networks to thrive need a <i>proof of concept</i></li>
<li>Prohibitions spark human creativity in a newly formed area</li>
<li>Humans, then, leverage that creativity to attract social capital and compete against each other in the newly formed arena</li>
</ul><p>
Over a long enough timeline, all the social capital available in a certain system gets allocated.</p><p>

The more we understand a system, the more effective we are at allocating social capital in it. Hence, we need new restrictions to unlock new human creativity and feed new social capital back into the system.</p><p>

This can explain on some levels how Social Networks develops, but I wondered what else? Are there are other fields where this theory applies just as well?</p><h3>
1. Painting: Cubism</h3>
<p>
For centuries, visual arts was one of the major arenas where human intellects competed. For centuries, humans challenged each other by representing reality through mere copies of the same instance.</p><p>

And gradually, we were able to go from this..</p><p>

<img alt="La pinacoteca del deserto | Wall Street International Magazine" src="https://media.wsimag.com/attachments/b875394fe3e10f195aaf936aedab87d5379b5f93/store/fill/930/523/d201b041400d593bd503ef96371789c31f312481cfd248f0a901c5876477/Pitture-rupestri-di-Jabbaren-nominate-le-libere-donne-di-Jabbaren.jpg"></p><p>

To this:</p><p>

<img alt="Frederic Edwin Church | Biography, Art, &amp; Facts | Britannica" src="https://cdn.britannica.com/88/69588-050-87EF851C/View-Cotopaxi-oil-canvas-Frederic-Edwin-Church-1857.jpg"></p><p>

Connects the dots and see how linear was the progression in the aesthetic. Over time, humans became quite extraordinary at this exercise.</p><p>

Renaissance, impressionism, pointillism, abstract expressionism, realism, etc, were all micro-steps part of the same bigger effort: representing the reality for what it is.</p><p>

Social capital in that area was progressively getting allocated up to the point where there was no much left to. Over centuries of incremental progress, we got the point where we mastered the <i>proof of work</i>.</p><p>

So, we needed a radically new thing. A new greenfield and new proofs of concept.</p><p>

Introducing cubism.</p><p>

<img alt="Georges Braque 1882–1963 | Tate" src="https://www.tate.org.uk/art/images/work/T/T00/T00445_9.jpg"></p><p>

Unlike any of the prior movements, cubisms challenged the fundamental rules, the basic assumptions upon which the system was constructed. Reality should be represented as<i>&nbsp;it is</i>.</p><p>

This new <i>proof of work</i> emphasized a flat, two-dimensional surface. It rejected the traditional techniques of perspective, foreshortening, modeling, chiaroscuro, etc, and refuted time-honored theories of art as the imitation of nature.</p><p>

For the first time in history, painters were not bound to copying form, texture, color, space, etc. That was too well understood. They were called to present reality in radically fragmented objects, whose several sides were seen simultaneously.</p><p>

The movement was pioneered by Braque who made the original proof of concept but it was Picasso who really extracted much of the social capital that came out of it.</p><h3>
2. Music: Dodecaphony (or Twelve-tonic technique, or Chromaticism)</h3><p>
First, Bach, the real explorer of Classic composition.</p><p>

Then Mozart, and Beethoven.</p><p>

Then Chopin, Debussy, and Ravel.</p><p>

Different styles emerged across centuries (from Baroque to Late Romantic) but the ground rules in the classical composition didn’t really change.</p><p>

Let me explain.</p><p>

In traditional Western music, tonality is a means of organizing pitch in accordance with the physics of sound. A fundamental tone — say, C in a C major scale — is central; the other pitches relate to it in a hierarchy of importance based on natural overtone relationships. So, whatever happens, the music keeps returning to that fundamental tonal mooring.</p><p>

This is such a key aspect in music because it provides a sense of arrival and rest.</p><p>

All Western classical and pop music relies on the idea that, no matter what, we'll eventually get to "home base".</p><p>

Leveraging this musical axiom, musical composition techniques that had been prepared over centuries&nbsp;made it possible in the 18th century to write music that was original and immediately appealing but also sophisticated under the surface.</p><p>

And by the end of the 18th century, a lot of low-hanging fruit was picked and much of the social capital in the system was already allocated in the hands of few. There wasn't much left to discover.</p><p>

In 19th-century composers,&nbsp;Wagner, Mahler, Debussy, originality frequently came at the cost of greater surface complexity, and a less direct, cheerful tone.</p><p>

It was clear that humans needed new ground-up rules to compete.</p><p>

Schoenberg was one of the first to realize&nbsp;that new innovation could only be unlocked by re-thinking the ground-rules. So he invented a new<a href="http:/#" target="_blank">&nbsp;compositional technique:&nbsp;</a><a href="http:/#" target="_blank">twelve-tonic.</a></p><p>

<img alt="Arnold Schoenberg : Quartetto per Archi - Analisi Musicale" src="https://www.armoniamusicale.com/wp-content/uploads/Schoenberg-quartetto.jpg"></p><p>

Shoenberg's twelve tonic technique comes with no musical tonality. All 12 pitches of the chromatic scale are sounded as often as one another in a piece of music without emphasis on any specific note. In other words, all 12 notes are thus given more or less equal importance, and the music avoids being in a key. Consequentially, there can't home base.</p><p>

It was a radically new game.</p><p>

Shoenberg's new musical arena unlocked new social capital and many of the composers of the 20th century competed on those new rules.</p><p>

Several giants explored the 12-tone technique as well: not only Stravinsky, whose move into the enemy camp shook up the world of modern music but also Messiaen and Copland.</p><p>

Looking backward, we can say the invention of the 12-tone system was arguably the most audacious and influential development in 20th-century music.</p><h3>
3. Fashion: Kate Moss</h3>
<p>
The world of the 19th century was a world in which the canons of beauty were sculptured.</p><p>

Up to the point where the whole fashion scene was dominated by the same characters: Cindy Crawford, Naomi Campbell, Sharon Stone, etc.</p><p>

That was a solved game.</p><p>

It was in that world, that <a href="http://fashion.telegraph.co.uk/news-features/TMG10364017/Corinne-Day-the-woman-who-discovered-Kate-Moss.html" target="_blank">Corinne Day discovered a new way to represent beauty</a>.</p><p>

Not through the canonical blonde/long hair, nor the perfect-looking skin or the mesmerizing white of the teeth.</p><p>

C. Day used the cheeky expression of a 16yo suburban skinny girl named Kate Moss to show the world an entirely new idea of aesthetics.</p><p>

Way far from what were the conventions of the time.</p><p>

Not colorful, but black and white photos.<br>
Not sinuous, but skinny body forms.<br>
Not perfect-looking, but seemingly sloppy dresses.<br>
Not cheerful, but melancholic tones.</p><p>

<img alt="calvin klein kate moss Tiziano Magni kate-jam-and-diamonds •" src="https://38.media.tumblr.com/0d7209dc40fe05243c9a9ea65b3da5b1/tumblr_n22mc1djTU1r9tciko1_500.jpg"></p><p>

It was a totally different game with totally different rules.</p><p>

The effects were immediate. Existing players were&nbsp;outplayed, new social capital was unlocked, and new icons emerged.</p><p>

Moss did to Campbell, what Braque did to Manet, and what Shoenberg did to centuries of Mozart.</p><p>

Centuries of slow but incremental linear development lost in a matter of a few years.</p><p>

Visual arts, philosophy, music, and many realms get periodically rearranged according to the same principles: when there’s no more Social Capital left on the table either because it eroded over centuries or because it was consolidated in the hands of just a few winners.</p><p>

After all, we're all are status-seeking monkeys seek out the most efficient path to maximizing social capital.</p><p>


Others essays to further explore this topic:</p><ul>
<li><a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/CeZXDmp8Z363XaM6b/discontinuous-progress-in-history-an-update">https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/CeZXDmp8Z363XaM6b/discontinuous-progress-in-history-an-update</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RWiABXiKSKo">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RWiABXiKSKo</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2007/10/14/arts/music/14tomm.html">https://www.nytimes.com/2007/10/14/arts/music/14tomm.html</a></li>
</ul>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.leonardofederico.com/2020/08/how-humans-unlock-social-capital.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24363273</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 12:22:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Earth's mountains form in millions of years, Moon ones near instantaneously]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24363074">thread link</a>) | @uncertainquark
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://jatan.space/exploring-moon-mountains/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jatan.space/exploring-moon-mountains/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
		
	<main id="content" role="main">

	<div>
		<div>
						<article id="post-4045">
				<div>
<p>Unlike the millions of years it takes for most mountains on Earth to form, lunar mountains crop out near instantaneously, geologically speaking.</p>



<p>Earth’s mountains primarily form when two colliding plates of the Earth’s crust lift up volumes of rock, slowly creating an elevated landform. Over millions of years, wind, water and gravity erode these uplifted sections, wearing their surface to make the mountains we are familiar with today.</p>



<p>But the Moon has no plate tectonics, atmosphere or running water. How then does it boast mountains several kilometers high? For instance, <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2019/03/18/mount-as-high-as-everest-zeeman-mons/">Zeeman Mons</a> on the lunar farside peaks as tall as Mount Everest.</p>



<p>The answer lies in the one of the most apparent features on the Moon – craters.</p>



<p>Most lunar craters are <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2019/05/27/what-does-a-fresh-crater-look-like-hell/">small and bowl-shaped</a>, formed when asteroids and comets impact the surface. This shape persists for crater sizes up to about 20 kilometers. Larger craters display more complexity.</p>



<p>The force imparted on the Moon’s surface by larger asteroids and comets, especially those with high velocities, can be tremendous. In such cases, in addition to a crater being formed, the surface in and around the impact point is compressed further. This causes the crust to melt. When the melted crust can’t be compressed any further, it bounces right back up, forming a central mountain. This process is visualized in the GIF below.</p>







<p>Most lunar mountains are formed by this highly energetic process that takes a geologically negligible passage of time. The kilometer-plus high central peaks of the young, city-sized <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2019/03/11/glorious-aristarchus/">Aristarchus crater</a> and 86-kilometer-wide <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2018/10/15/tycho-crater/">Tycho crater</a> are fine examples.</p>







<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1200" height="633" src="https://i2.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tycho-mountain-lro.jpg?resize=1200%2C633&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tycho-mountain-lro.jpg?w=1870&amp;ssl=1 1870w, https://i2.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tycho-mountain-lro.jpg?resize=1024%2C540&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tycho-mountain-lro.jpg?resize=200%2C105&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i2.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tycho-mountain-lro.jpg?resize=768%2C405&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tycho-mountain-lro.jpg?resize=1536%2C810&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tycho-mountain-lro.jpg?resize=1200%2C633&amp;ssl=1 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>The central peak of Tycho crater.&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://lroc.sese.asu.edu/posts/384" target="_blank">Credit: NASA LRO</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Aristarchus crater was one of the candidate landing sites for the now-cancelled Apollo 17+ missions. Visiting Aristarchus or Tycho in a future surface mission will allow us to study the exposed lunar interior by the virtue of their central mountains. Craters larger than these offer two central peaks.</p>



<p>The mechanics work such that for larger crater sizes or more energetic impacts, the newly formed central peak splits into two before it can solidify. The 93-kilometer-wide <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2019/04/08/a-peak-inside-the-moon-with-copernicus/">Copernicus</a> and 77-kilometer-wide <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2019/01/21/y-shaped-mountains-in-king-crater/">King</a> craters respectively host two distinct peaks, each towering more than six kilometers!</p>











<p>Apart from allowing scientists to study the lunar interior, such places are key to understanding mechanics of impacts that form such features, found not just on the Moon but across the Solar System.</p>



<h3>Put a ring on it </h3>



<p>For even larger craters, the twin peaks widen into a ring of mountains, like a liquid drop causing a ripple on still water. The 312-kilometer-wide <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2019/06/10/the-crowned-crater-of-schrodinger/">crater of Schrödinger</a> on the Moon’s farside is a well preserved example, despite being almost four billion years old.</p>







<p>A <a href="https://earthandsolarsystem.wordpress.com/2016/06/21/new-paper-a-robotic-mission-concept-to-return-samples-from-the-schrodinger-basin/">mission to Schrödinger</a> can help solve fundamental mysteries about the Moon’s evolution, like if the Moon indeed had a global magma ocean–a hypothesis tied to <a href="https://jatan.space/apollo-moon-origin/">its origin</a>. Further, Schrödinger lies inside the Moon’s largest impact crater, the 2,500-kilometer-wide South Pole-Aitken basin. The impact that created the basin excavated deep into the lunar crust, and perhaps even the mantle. Since Schrödinger formed later, its impact could’ve penetrated deeper and uplifted more materials, offering insights–literally and figuratively–into the lunar interior.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicxulub_crater">Chicxulub crater</a> on Earth, linked to the extinction of dinosaurs, is also thought to have formed as a ringed crater, but wore down of its original form due to Earth’s active weathering. As such, Schrödinger offers an analog to better understand Chicxulub.</p>



<p>For crater sizes beyond 500 kilometers, you get not one but multiple rings of mountains. The 930-kilometer-wide ancient crater of <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2019/01/07/outstanding-orientale-multi-ring-basin-on-the-moon/">Orientale</a> on the Moon’s farside boasts three mountain rings, most of which is preserved.</p>







<p>Missions to both Schrödinger and Orientale can tell us exactly when did large asteroids and comets excessively bombard bodies in the Solar System. This period of blistering impacts is particularly important as Earth is thought to have gotten its water during this time.</p>



<p>For some ancient craters, like Imbrium on Moon’s nearside, only parts of the outermost mountain ring are visible today. The rest of the interior has been drowned in lava, which you see as dark regions on the Moon. The prominent, arc-shaped mountain range of <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2018/10/08/the-mountain-range-montes-apenninus/">Montes Apenninus</a>, forming Imbrium’s southeast border, stretches 600 kilometers long.</p>







<p>Multi-ring impact basins exist on many other worlds in the Solar System, like <a href="https://airandspace.si.edu/multimedia-gallery/9780640jpg">Caloris</a> on Mercury, <a href="https://www.planetary.org/space-images/20130614_g8gsrngbas01">an unnamed basin</a> on Jupiter’s moon Ganymede, <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Dione_-_Evander_basin.jpg">Evander</a> on Saturn’s moon Dione, and more. Jupiter’s moon Callisto boasts the largest multi-ring basin of the solar system, called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Valhalla_(crater)">Valhalla</a>, spanning 3800 kilometers wide.</p>







<p>The ubiquity of mountains formed by impacts across the Solar System and their consistent patterns indicate common geological mechanisms. And the Moon being so close to us presents us with an opportunity to study these fundamental processes in planetary science.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1200" height="858" src="https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?resize=1200%2C858&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?w=2233&amp;ssl=1 2233w, https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?resize=1024%2C732&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?resize=200%2C143&amp;ssl=1 200w, https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?resize=768%2C549&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?resize=1536%2C1099&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?resize=2048%2C1465&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i1.wp.com/jatan.space/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/moon-mountains.jpg?resize=1200%2C858&amp;ssl=1 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" data-recalc-dims="1"><figcaption>Changing morphology of mountains and craters on the Moon with increasing size. Graphic: Jatan Mehta</figcaption></figure>



<h3>Exploring the mountains</h3>



<p>Moon orbiters use remote sensing techniques to understand the composition of the lunar mountains. But to better understand the composition, structure and origin, surface missions are needed, especially sample return ones to determine precise ages. To that end, NASA had selected several of the above mentioned places as <a href="https://www.lpi.usra.edu/meetings/leag2009/presentations/Day-2%20PM/03-35_Gruener.pdf">candidate landing sites</a> for the now cancelled Constellation program to return humans to the Moon.</p>



<p>However, sending landing and roving missions to lunar mountains is a bit of an engineering hurdle. Most surface missions of the past landed in the dark lunar plains – vast, solidified lava regions that provide a relatively uniform surface for spacecraft to land on. The rocky nature of the mountainous regions make it more difficult to safely touch down on. However, things may change with NASA’s upcoming Artemis missions.</p>



<p>The Artemis program aims to explore the lunar poles in this decade, both <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/content/commercial-lunar-payload-services-overview">robotically</a> and with <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/nasa-names-companies-to-develop-human-landers-for-artemis-moon-missions">humans</a>. This requires developing precision landing technologies for safe descent on the challenging polar terrain, as a result also enabling surface missions to the lunar mountains. But there is a type of mountain that spacecraft can visit even with present-day technologies.</p>



<p>The Moon has experienced several distinct periods of volcanism in the last four billion years. Lava slowly oozing out of openings on the surface during such times have formed <a href="https://moontoday.jatan.space/2018/11/05/unique-volcanic-domes-of-gruithuisen/">volcanic domes</a>. These domes aren’t as tall as the impact-created mountains and have gentle slopes. China’s third Moon landing mission, Chang’e 5, launching end of 2020 is targeting the largest such lunar dome, Mons Rümker.</p>







<p>The 70-kilometer-wide Mons Rümker is thought to have formed less than two billion years ago. The Chang’e 5 mission aims to bring back samples from the dome and determine its exact age. Since scientists use the Moon to <a href="https://www.planetary.org/articles/0401-the-lunar-chronology">calibrate the timing</a> of events across bodies in the Solar System, analysis of Chang’e 5 samples would be an invaluable addition to happenings in the geologically recent past.</p>



<p>Mountains on the Moon are a marvel that give us a peak (pun intended) into the lunar interior, help discern the chain of events in the Solar System’s evolution and improve our understanding of the physical processes that shape airless worlds everywhere.</p>



<hr>



<blockquote><p>This post was made possible thanks to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.patreon.com/uncertainquark">my Patreon</a> supporters. I don’t display ads to run my blog and instead rely on my readers so if you like my work, consider&nbsp;<a href="https://www.patreon.com/uncertainquark">supporting me</a>.&nbsp;🚀</p></blockquote>



<p><em><a href="https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/lunar-mountains-craters-landing-sites-solar-system/">Republished</a> by The Wire Science.</em></p>

</div>

			</article>
					</div>
	</div>
</main><!--/.neve-main-->




</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jatan.space/exploring-moon-mountains/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24363074</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 11:54:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[India authorises sale of electric vehicles without batteries]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 127 | Comments 121 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24362305">thread link</a>) | @baybal2
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://www.electricmotorengineering.com/india-sale-of-electric-vehicles-without-batteries/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.electricmotorengineering.com/india-sale-of-electric-vehicles-without-batteries/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p>Batteries comprise 30-40% of the upfront cost. To push electric mobility, the Ministry of Road Transport and Highway (MORTH) of India, announced that all the states and union territories (UTs) <strong>have now been allowed the registration and sale of electric vehicles (EVs) without pre-fitted batteries</strong>.<br>
The move is likely to provide the necessary boost for the<strong> wider adoption of EVs across the country.</strong><br>
Practically, the government is striving to create an ecosystem to accelerate the uptake of electric mobility in the country. This will not only protect the environment and reduce the oil imports but also provide opportunities to the sunrise industry.<br>
What is the situation in India? According to the <a href="https://www.smev.in/"><strong>Society of Manufacturers of Electric Vehicles</strong></a>, the sale of electric vehicles in this country increased by 20% in 2019-20, mainly driven by rising sales of two-wheelers.</p>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.electricmotorengineering.com/india-sale-of-electric-vehicles-without-batteries/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24362305</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 09:32:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Unix `Who` Command]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 96 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24361957">thread link</a>) | @warenhor
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://gauthier.uk/blog/who/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gauthier.uk/blog/who/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="contentBody"><p>While working on a completely different project, I started to ask myself how the <code>who</code> command was working under the hood. In the end, I thought it was a good topic for a blog post.</p><h2 id="who-is-who">Who is <code>who</code></h2><p>Let’s start with the basics. the <code>who</code> command allows you to list the users currently logged on the system.
For example, on my machine:</p><pre><code>$ who
gauthier tty2         2020-08-30 15:06 (tty2)
gauthier pts/1        2020-08-30 15:06 (tmux(1555).%0)
gauthier pts/2        2020-08-30 16:41 (tmux(1555).%6)
gauthier pts/4        2020-08-30 15:57 (tmux(1555).%3)
</code></pre><p>It tells me that I am logged on the “physical” terminal <code>tty2</code> and on three pseudo terminals. Indeed my current session of Gnome Shell is running on <code>tty2</code> and I have 3 <code>tmux</code> windows open.</p><p>But where is it getting those information? Probably from a file as everything is a file with Linux, but let’s check which one and how the data is stored there.</p><h2 id="a-bit-of-reverse-engineering">A bit of reverse engineering</h2><p>In order to see what the <code>who</code> command is doing I could try to find the source code and dig into it. But I found it fun to use <code>strace</code> to check what the process was doing instead. Since we are expecting <code>who</code> to read system files, we can only focus on the <code>open</code> syscalls.</p><pre><code>$ strace who 2&gt;&amp;1 | grep open
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/etc/ld.so.cache", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/usr/lib/libc.so.6", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/usr/lib/locale/locale-archive", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/var/run/utmp", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/etc/localtime", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
</code></pre><p>We can quickly filter what is interesting and what is not. The first files two files <code>/etc/ld.so.cache</code>, <code>/usr/lib/libc.so.6</code> are shared libraries loaded by the process, those are interesting us.</p><p>Then <code>/usr/lib/locale/locale-archive</code>, <code>/var/run/utmp</code> and <code>/etc/localtime</code> are opened. Let’s see what those files are storing.</p><p>When exploring this kind of topics, it is always interesting to first search into the man pages before starting browsing the web. The 5th section of the manual is dedicated to “file formats and conventions” and seems a good place to start.</p><h3 id="locale-archive">locale-archive</h3><pre><code>$ man -wK 5 '/usr/lib/locale/locale-archive'
</code></pre><p>Sends us to <code>locale(5)</code> where we can read:</p><pre><code>The  locale  definition file contains all the information that the localedef(1) command needs to convert it into the binary locale data‐base.
</code></pre><p>The page also sends us to <code>locale(7)</code> for more explanation about those informations:</p><pre><code>A  locale is a set of language and cultural rules. These cover aspects such as language for messages, different character sets, lexico‐graphic conventions, and so on. A program needs to be able to determine its locale and act accordingly to be portable to different cultures.
</code></pre><p>So the <code>who</code> command read from this file, probably using the <code>setlocale(3)</code> function, to find out how the information should be formated and displayed.</p><p>We can actually check it:</p><pre><code>$ LC_ALL='fr_FR.utf8' who
gauthier tty2         Sep  2 11:38 (:1)
gauthier pts/1        Sep  2 12:11 (tmux(2445).%0)
gauthier pts/2        Sep  2 12:37 (tmux(2445).%1)
gauthier pts/3        Sep  2 13:04 (tmux(2445).%2)
</code></pre><p>Indeed, the date is is not formated the same way!</p><h3 id="localtime">localtime</h3><pre><code>$ man -wK 5 '/etc/localtime'
</code></pre><p>Sends us to <code>localtime(5)</code> which explains:</p><pre><code>The /etc/localtime file configures the system-wide timezone of the local system that is used by applications for presentation to the user.
</code></pre><p>Probably <code>who</code> uses this file (or uses a function that is using this file) to print timestamps (columns 4 and 5 of <code>who</code>'s output) using the correct timezone configured by the user.</p><h3 id="utmp">utmp</h3><p>Finally comes <code>/var/run/utmp</code>:</p><pre><code>$ man -wK 5 '/var/run/utmp'
/usr/share/man/man5/utmp.5.gz
</code></pre><p>Where we can read:</p><pre><code>The  utmp  file  allows  one to discover information about who is currently using the system.  There may be more users currently using the system, because not all programs use utmp logging.
</code></pre><p>Great! We found where the <code>who</code> command is getting its data. It would be nice to be able to read this file to get those data without using the <code>who</code> command. Unfortunately:</p><pre><code>The file is a sequence of utmp structures, declared as follows in &lt;utmp.h&gt; (note that this is only one of several definitions around; details depend on the version of libc):
</code></pre><p>At this point we understood what the <code>who</code> command is doing: it is reading <code>/var/run/utmp</code>, parsing the content and formating it nicely. Let’s see if we can reproduce this simple behavior.</p><h3 id="my-own-who">My own <code>who</code></h3><p>What we simply need to do is: open <code>/var/run/utmp</code>, read <code>n</code> bytes (where <code>n</code> is the size of the <code>utmp</code> structure), print the info contained in each structure, continue until we reach the end of the file. With a bit of formating, we can even make it look like the original <code>who</code> command.</p><pre><code>#include &lt;utmp.h&gt;
#include &lt;stdlib.h&gt;
#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;
#include &lt;time.h&gt;
#include &lt;locale.h&gt;

int main() {
  // set the right locale to display the information nicely
  setlocale(LC_ALL, "");

  // open the file
  FILE * file= fopen("/var/run/utmp", "rb");

  // just for safety
  if (file == NULL) {
    return 1;
  }

  // initialize the utmp structure
  struct utmp entry;

  // read the entries from the file one by one
  while (fread(&amp;entry, sizeof(struct utmp), 1, file) != 0) {
    if (entry.ut_type != USER_PROCESS)
      continue;

    // format the date (remember who uses the /etc/localtime?)
    char date[80];
    time_t raw_time = entry.ut_tv.tv_sec;
    struct tm *ts = localtime(&amp;raw_time);
    strftime(date, sizeof(date), "%Y-%m-%d %H:%M", ts);

    // print the output for this entry, tries to mock who's output
    printf("%-8s %-12s %s (%s)\n", entry.ut_user, entry.ut_line, date, entry.ut_host);
  }

  fclose(file);
}
</code></pre><pre><code>$ clang -o who who.c
$ ./who
gauthier tty2         2020-08-31 10:02 (tty2)
gauthier pts/1        2020-08-31 10:03 (tmux(2220).%0)
gauthier pts/2        2020-08-31 10:08 (tmux(2220).%1)
gauthier pts/3        2020-08-31 10:33 (tmux(2220).%5)
</code></pre><p>TADA!</p><p>We can also check with <code>strace</code> if the behavior is the same:</p><pre><code>$ strace ./who 2&gt;&amp;1 | grep -e open
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/etc/ld.so.cache", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/usr/lib/libc.so.6", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/usr/lib/locale/locale-archive", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/var/run/utmp", O_RDONLY) = 3
openat(AT_FDCWD, "/etc/localtime", O_RDONLY|O_CLOEXEC) = 4
</code></pre><p>Indeed our program is doing the same as the original <code>who</code>.</p><p>Of course, this only mocks the most basic features of the <code>who</code> command and doesn’t handle any option, like the famous <code>who am i</code> or <code>who mom hates</code>.</p><h3 id="going-further">Going further</h3><p>There is still a lot to say about the <code>who</code> command. We could for example mention the <code>lastlog</code> command and its corresponding file <code>/var/log/wtmp</code>, dig into the <code>utmp</code> structure, or just try to understand what <code>utmp</code> stands for.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gauthier.uk/blog/who/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24361957</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:33:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Automatic SSL Certificates for internal IP's for home k8 setup using LetsEncrypt]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 152 | Comments 85 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24361930">thread link</a>) | @gcds
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://www.techprowd.com/automatic-ssl-certificates-for-home-microk8s-setup-using-letsencrypt/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.techprowd.com/automatic-ssl-certificates-for-home-microk8s-setup-using-letsencrypt/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <p>One of the issues I discovered while playing with microk8s Kubernetes setup locally was that many services and tools like <code>Kubernetes Dashboard</code> uses HTTPS for access and I don't want to use Self-Signed SSL certificates as it would require me installing these certificates in every device I use which would be a pain in the butt. So I was on the journey finding a way to have an SSL Certificate for my internal IP addresses. This article will document my journey of getting automatic SSL certificates for my internal microk8s Kubernetes setup.</p><h2 id="ssl-certificate-for-internal-ip-address">SSL Certificate for internal IP address?</h2><p>My first question was is there a way to get an SSL certificate from Public trusted Certificate Authority after looking at many free services like Let's Encrypt and similar services don't provide certificates to IP addresses, but only to domain names.</p><p>After discovering the issue with no way to get an SSL certificate for internal IP I was looking into other options for my problem. After racking my brains for a few minutes I had a question: Could I create a DNS A record for internal IP and would it work? A quick visit to my DNS control panel adding A record to the local IP address and visiting the domain name and seeing my local IP address served website I was amazed that it worked.</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image.png 1212w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-1.png" alt=""></figure><p>Discovering that I can have a domain name for internal IP working I was surprised now I had curiosity if I will be able to use service like Let's Encrypt to generate an SSL Certificate for this domain name but if I remember correctly the Let's Encrypt requires external access to verify domain name ownership. Hmm, maybe there is a way to verify domain name ownership without external access? After some digging around Let's Encrypt documentation, I found that there many ways to verify domain ownership one of them is DNS plugins which have many DNS providers to automatically verify domains by modifying DNS records using API from those providers. In my case it is DigitalOcean.</p><p>Following <code>certbot-dns-digitalocean</code> <a href="https://certbot-dns-digitalocean.readthedocs.io/en/stable/">documentation</a>I tried to generate a certificate for internal IP but I ran into the issue that default macOS <code>certbot</code> installation from <code>brew install certbot</code> had no <code>certbot-dns-digitalocean</code> plugin available.</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>After a quick search online I found that DNS Plugins are not installed by default with <code>certbot</code>. I needed to install <code>certbox-dns-digitalocean</code> plugin using PIP</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Afterward, I was able to generate a certificate without many issues:</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Applying SSL certificate to local HTTPS server I was able to get HTTPS valid response from the internal IP address using a domain name</p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-5.png" alt=""></figure><p>Now that I know that I can generate &amp; use an SSL certificate for internal IP address just by using a domain name. Now I can try to migrate this knowledge to integrate this to microk8s local setup.</p><h2 id="integrating-let-s-encrypt-with-dns-challenge-into-microk8s-setup-using-cert-manager">Integrating Let's Encrypt with DNS challenge into microk8s setup using <code>cert-manager</code></h2><p>I am not going to describe microk8s Kubernetes setup as it is pretty straightforward compared to the plain Kubernetes setup.</p><p>The first step is to install <code>cert-manager</code> I will be using Helm to install it.</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Now let's configure Certificate Issuer. I will be using the configuration for DigitalOcean but it should be pretty easy to follow instructions from <a href="https://cert-manager.io/docs/configuration/acme/dns01/">documentation</a>.</p><p>First, we need DigitalOcean API token Base64 encoded to be saved in secrets</p><p>You can encode token to base64 using <code>echo -n "Token" | base64</code></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Now we need to configure Certificate Issuer. (I had to change kind from <code>Issuer</code> to <code>ClusterIssuer</code> because of namespace issues)</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Now that we configured everything we should use the SSL certificate somewhere for this article I will configure microk8s ingress to allow access to <code>kubernetes-dashboard</code> via <code>https://server.techprowd.com/dashboard</code></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Now after applying the resources we can check if our certificate resource was created and check if our Let's Encrypt Certificate was created too</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>Now that everything created we should be able to access <code>https://server.techprowd.com/dashboard</code></p><figure><img src="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-6.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/09/image-6.png 600w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/09/image-6.png 1000w, https://www.techprowd.com/content/images/2020/09/image-6.png 1135w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>If I understood correctly the Certificate will be automatically renewed when expiration time comes up.</p><p>So that's all for this article. I hope this helped other people who had similar ideas like me when started working with Kubernetes.</p><p>P.S. I am not a professional Kubernetes engineer and everything mentioned in this article is just my assumptions and trying out practices in the local environment.</p>
                </div>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.techprowd.com/automatic-ssl-certificates-for-home-microk8s-setup-using-letsencrypt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24361930</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 08:27:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[All forms of signing email are generally solving the wrong problem]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24361675">thread link</a>) | @fomine3
<br/>
September 3, 2020 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/SignedEmailWrongProblem | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/SignedEmailWrongProblem">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>All forms of signing email are generally solving the wrong problem (a thesis)</h2>

	<p><small>August 30, 2020</small></p>
</div><div><p>Modern email is full of forms of signed email. Personally signed
email is the old fashioned approach (and wrong), but modern email
on the Internet is laced with things like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DomainKeys_Identified_Mail">DKIM</a>, which
have the sending system sign it to identify at least who sent it.
Unfortunately, the more I think about it, the more I feel that
signed email is generally solving the wrong problem (and if it's
solving the right one, we won't like that solution in the long run).</p>

<p>A while ago I wrote about <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/EmailVsModernProtocols">why email often isn't as good as modern
protocols</a>, which is because it's what I
described as an <em>anonymous push</em> protocol. An anonymous push protocol
necessarily enables spam since it allows anyone to send you things.
Describing email as 'anonymous push' makes it sound like the anonymity
is the problem, which would make various forms of signing the
solution (including DKIM). But this isn't really what you care about
with email and requiring email to carry some strong identification
doesn't solve the problem, as we've found out with all of the spam
email that has perfectly good DKIM signatures for some random new
domain.</p>

<p>(This is a version of <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/TwoSidesOfIdentity">the two sides of identity</a>.
On the Internet people can trivially have multiple identities, so
while an identity is useful to only let selected people in, it's
not useful to keep someone out.)</p>

<p>I think that what you really care about with modern communication
protocols is <em>revocable authorization</em>. With a pull protocol, you
have this directly; you tacitly revoke authorization by stopping
pulling from the place you no longer like. With a push protocol,
you can still require authorization that you grant, which lets you
revoke that granted authorization if you wish. The closest email
comes to this is having lots of customized email addresses and
carefully using a different one for each service (which Apple has
recently automated for iOS people).</p>

<p>Obviously, requiring authorization to push things to you has a
fundamental conflict with any system that's designed to let arbitrary
strangers contact you without prearrangement (which is <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/spam/FundamentalSpamProblem">the
fundamental problem of spam</a>).
Modern protocols seem to deal with this in two ways (even with
revocable authorization); they have some form of gatekeeping (in
the form of accounts or access), and then they evolve to provide
settings that let you stop or minimize the ability of arbitrary
strangers to contact you (for example, Twitter's settings around
who can send you Direct Messages).</p>

<p>(The modern user experience of things like Twitter has also evolved
to somewhat minimize the impact of strangers trying to contact you;
for example, the Twitter website separates new DMs from strangers
from DMs from people you've already interacted with. It's possible
that email clients could learn some lessons from this, for example
by splitting your inbox into 'people and places you've interacted
with before' and 'new contacts from strange people'. This would
make DKIM signatures and other email source identification useful,
apart from the bit where senders today feel free to keep changing
where they're sending from.)</p>

<p>PS: In this view, actions like blocking or muting people on Twitter
(or the social network of your choice) is a form of revoking their
tacit authorization to push things to you.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/SignedEmailWrongProblem</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24361675</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 07:39:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Heuristics to Generate Startup Ideas (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24361055">thread link</a>) | @docuru
<br/>
September 2, 2020 | https://avichal.com/2019/02/24/heuristics-to-generate-startup-ideas/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://avichal.com/2019/02/24/heuristics-to-generate-startup-ideas/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-2992">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>I regularly help pre-seed entrepreneurs identify and evaluate potential startup opportunities. The following is a set of heuristics I’ve developed and collected over the years that might of use.</p>



<p>These heuristics are just a starting point to <strong>identify interesting, unsolved problems</strong> in the world that may turn in to great startups. Entrepreneurs must still go deep on understanding their customers, the business model, have a clear answer to <a href="https://avichal.com/2017/11/27/why-now/">Why Now?</a> there is a big shift in the market, and <a href="http://paulgraham.com/startupideas.html">focus on identifying problems rather than generating ideas that <em>sound</em> good.</a></p>



<ol><li>Tools inside a big company — High growth companies often first experience a problem other companies will soon face and solve it internally. Bringing these tools to everyone else can work well, e.g. Asana was inspired by the Facebook internal tasks tool, Cloudera was inspired by Facebook’s internal data infrastructure. </li><li>Consumer generation shift — Think about a consumer company that started ~7 years ago. Generations shift in about 7-10 years, thus tastes evolve, and platforms shift. Thus there is an opening to acquire customers, e.g. Snapchat started 2011 while Facebook started 2004</li><li>Big company acquisitions — If a company is acquired for $5B+, consider a competitor. This may indicate product maturity, a departure of talent after earnouts, or becoming focused on profits vs. product investment. Now may be a great time to re-imaginge LinkedIn or Github</li><li>Market validation from other startups — Find a company that recently raised a series A and approach solving the problem differently. Often the first company to identify an opportunity will not win but does indicate customers have a real problem they want solved.</li><li>Revisit ideas that were too early — Look back at ideas that were hot 10 years ago because entrepreneurs have a tendency to be too early. See if any might make sense now, e.g. Instacart vs. Webvan.</li><li>Invert a successful company’s core competency — Take the core strength of a company and flip it on its head to see what a product experience may be if you did the opposite, e.g. Snapchat was based on ephemerality and Facebook based on permanence of identity, or Southwest was based on a point-to-point model with only one type of plane whereas other airlines use a hub and spoke model with multiple types of planes.</li><li>Extend consumer behaviors to businesses — Take a product used by consumers and think about how it might apply to prosumers, enterprises, and small businesses, e.g. LinkedIn vs Facebook.</li><li>Turn open source projects in to SAAS businesses — Find open source projects that are very popular and turn these in to out of the box services for enterprises, e.g. PagerDuty is like Nagios.</li><li>Compete with old world industries using software — Find an industry that is resistant to using software and build a vertically integrated version to compete with that industry, e.g. Atrium vs. law firms.</li><li>Low NPS, fragmented industries — Identify a large, a highly-fragmented industry with terrible net-promoter-score and build a modern, software-first version of their product, e.g. OpenDoor (credit to <a href="https://twitter.com/rabois">Keith Rabois</a> for this one) </li><li>Make things programmable — Take a desktop utility, move it online, and make it more powerful by making it more programmable, e.g. Airtable and Notion (similar to <a href="http://blog.eladgil.com/2019/01/interesting-markets-2019-edition.html">Elad Gil’s idea around devsumers</a>)</li><li>Unbundle a company — Look at the functions of modern companies and unbundle them to make them available for companies of all sizes, e.g. WeWork is the unbundled facilities group at most big companies</li><li>Look to engineers’ hobbies — Figure out where hobbyist engineers are spending their spare time and how to productize that (<a href="http://cdixon.org/2013/03/03/what-the-smartest-people-do-on-the-weekend-is-what-everyone-else-will-do-during-the-week-in-ten-years/">Chris Dixon’s idea</a>)</li><li>Understand how teens communicate — Figure out where teenagers are spending their time to see what the communication products of the next decade may be. Teens are unencumbered and very creative, so seek to understand the motivations instead of judge.</li><li>Travel and observe non-software solutions — Travel to new places to discover non-software solutions that other countries/people/markets have come up with to various problems, e.g. I was in Moscow in 2006 and people could just hail any stranger on the street to drive them somewhere like a cab. It may not have been a big leap if you saw this behavior to Uber/Lyft on your phone.</li><li>Look at behaviors in certain geographies — Smaller, homogenous culture countries (Sweden, Korea, Japan) are early adopters of many technologies. Spend time there to understand what they are doing that isn’t globally popular yet, e.g. watching other people play video games or mobile payments took off in these markets very early relative to the US.</li><li>Unbundle the government — Think about what services the government offers and how you might build a profitable business model around these, perhaps even by offering these services in a more cost-effective way back to the government, e.g. SpaceX is a private NASA, FedEx is a private postal service.</li><li>Verticalize an already successful business — Find a massively successful business such as Salesforce and target it for a vertical that is traditionally challenging to access, e.g. Veeva is a pharma industry specific CRM worth $15B+ and raised only $7M in funding.</li><li>Build something for a distribution channel — Identify a new distribution channel that would enable access to a new customer, and then think through what that customer wants that the distribution channel does not want to provide, e.g. Pinterest and Yelp built on SEO, Paypal built on eBay, YouTube embedded inside MySpace before MySpace had a video product.</li><li>Draft on a regulatory shift — Build behind a big regulatory shift to compete with large incumbents who will be slow to move and have regulatory + technical baggage, e.g. Oscar Health after Obamacare. I’m sure some companies will spin up to help people transition to a post-GDPR world.</li></ol>



<p>I’m sure there are other good heuristics to use as a starting point. If anyone sends me others, I’ll add them to my blog post as a reference for others.</p>




			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

		<!-- .entry-auhtor -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://avichal.com/2019/02/24/heuristics-to-generate-startup-ideas/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24361055</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 05:37:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Coping with Cats]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 138 | Comments 156 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24361029">thread link</a>) | @luu
<br/>
September 2, 2020 | https://acesounderglass.com/2020/09/02/coping-with-cats/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acesounderglass.com/2020/09/02/coping-with-cats/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-10918">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		<p>I love my two cats dearly and they bring a lot of joy to my life, but they also bring other things, like poop, and fur.&nbsp; When I tried to research mitigations for any of these it was 100% SEO listicles, so I’m sharing my raw data in the hopes that the next person can find something real-if-incomplete instead of a list of every automated litter box that has ever been manufactured.</p>
<p>I wrote the bulk of this in February, but then one of the cats developed dermatitis and I put it on pause until I could make sure it wasn’t caused by anything on this list. Alas, it wasn’t, she’s just allergic to my new apartment. But then I wanted to test something else, and suddenly six months had passed. So if the tenses seem weird, that’s why.</p>
<p>(Links are affiliate links when possible)</p>

<p>I screwed up choosing my new apartment (this was written before the allergy thing). I remembered to check for space to put the litter box in the bathroom, but in my joy at finding a place that allowed that at all after so many that did not,&nbsp; I forgot to check if that space was also where you stood to wash your hands. So I ended up having to put the box in the living room. I’ve done that before and didn’t want to go back to having to keep the window open year round and still smelling poop. I also didn’t love the aesthetic.&nbsp; So I set up something kind of elaborate.</p>
<h2><a href="https://kittyvent.com/products/kitty-vent">KittyVent Litter Box Ventilator</a></h2>
<p>This is a long piece of hosing with a gentle fan in it, and a plastic thingy to block off a window that has a hole for the hose to connect to (similar to what you’d use for a portable air conditioner)</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2969/4434/products/IMG_0842_075fb887-2c88-400b-9bc8-3973573e3915_1024x1024@2x.jpg?v=1545953794" width="423" height="282"></p>
<p>The window-blocking thing works vertically but won’t stay up on its own, I had to tape it. The fan is extremely quiet, you can’t tell it’s on from more than six inches away. I’m very sure it works because the first time I noticed a smell, I found the fan had been turned off.</p>
<p>There are instructions for how to DIY this available online (e.g. <a href="https://www.instructables.com/id/Cat-Litter-Box-Odor-Eliminator-Fan-FlowCat/">here</a>), but I just bought it and it worked fine.</p>
<h2>Litterbox Holding End Table</h2>
<p>To make it less hideous, I got an end table designed to hold a litter box. Amazon is full of these, but most have only a single entrance and no ventilation. I assume these are aimed at people who haven’t thought things through. I wanted something I could connect a vent to and actually get rid of the smell. You might be able to cut a hole in one of the ventless ones to attach the hose to but I didn’t feel like bothering, so I got one with ventilation.</p>
<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/91iP7ZrigoL._AC_SL1500_.jpg" width="443" height="420"></p>
<p>I chose ecoFlex (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01BM8E4KK/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B01BM8E4KK&amp;linkId=12a658675d21d4d4f9cad298d5ba2314">affiliate link</a>)&nbsp; because matched my it existing furniture and was the only option with both ventilation holes and a second shelf. For this, I accepted it being really much larger than it needed to be. Also the copytext said something about liquid-proof, non-smell-absorbant material, although who knows how true that is. Then I packing taped the ventilation hose to a hole in the back that wasn’t shown in the pictures, apparently intended for electric cords to automated litter boxes.</p>
<p>My cats adapted stupidly well to this- when I set up the litter box with the door open, they both used it within 10 minutes, despite their other litter box still being available. They did just as well when I closed the door.</p>
<p>Some litter does escape the table, so have a plan for that.</p>
<h2>Dog Poop Bags</h2>
<p>My weird conservation instincts push me not to empty the litter box until I can fill a bag. Otherwise I’m wasting valuable bag. So I bought a bunch of very small, very cheap bags and stored them in that shelf in the litter box end table, which is why I wanted it so much. I chose Amazon Basics Dog Poop Bags (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NABTGY2/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B00NABTGY2&amp;linkId=4d1641dea9b445b48539e119879ecada">affiliate link</a>) based on WireCutter’s <a href="https://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-dog-poop-bags/">recommendation</a> and so far they are resoundingly fine.</p>
<h2>Dr Esley Cat Litter (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07L9WFY14/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07L9WFY14&amp;linkId=37e0a6f0fb2ce49f0ba47c52c36791d7">affiliate link</a>)</h2>
<p>I got this because Sweethome recommended it. I didn’t appreciate how much better it was working until a delivery screw up made me use <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B06ZZYMWVT/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B06ZZYMWVT&amp;linkId=e9f8cccc7ed36fc1765011ac565da4d4">Arm and Hammer</a> and there started to be a smell where there hadn’t been before.</p>

<h2><a href="https://www.litter-robot.com/litter-robot-3.html">Litter Robot 3</a></h2>
<p>This is so close to being a truly great product, but isn’t quite reliable enough to be the only litter box. It had a tendency to get stuck in an unusable position, which eventually forces the cats to go elsewhere. The drawer the poop stays in doesn’t completely contain the smell. Also the range of litter between “excess will get dumped” and “too low” is uncomfortably thin. I’d still recommend it as a second litter box to cut down on scooping, or in a populous household where there will always be someone to turn it off and on again.</p>
<h2>Two Layer Litter Mat (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00G67FD6W/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B00G67FD6W&amp;linkId=9e1bbec26c9a003b834013f6cbb1bc7d">affiliate link</a>)</h2>
<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/81BjAf-AA6L._AC_SL1000_.jpg"></p>
<p>This actually worked great at its stated purpose of catching litter the cats track out of the box, but when the cats pooped on it (say, because the litter box had been upside down for six hours), it was almost impossible to clean, especially if I caught it less than instantly. Plus it is ugly.</p>
<h2>Open Window with a Fan</h2>
<p>This was definitely better than not having an open window with a fan, but there’s no comparison between it and the vent-with-hose.</p>


<h2>Silicone Grooming Gloves (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01N9KSITZ/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B01N9KSITZ&amp;linkId=cf4e5b0147e03c93e42da573c5afaf32">affiliate link</a>)</h2>
<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/713JHXyZS9L._AC_SL1000_.jpg" width="356" height="321"></p>
<p>These collect a lot of hair, plus their squishiness means you can brush bony areas that would be a problem for a metal comb. The cats start purring the instant I pet them with these.</p>
<p>Downside: kind of a pain to get the hair off the glove, does not pick up 100% of the fur it loosens, so be sure to use it somewhere easy to vacuum or at least not your own lap.</p>

<h2>The Dryer</h2>
<p>Turns out dryers are reasonably good at removing cat hair if you wait long enough. Remember to clean the lint trap frequently.</p>
<h2>Reusable Lint Roller</h2>
<p>I tried two made of the same material- a paddle shaped one (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07SBM761G/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07SBM761G&amp;linkId=94a8f23a77ace6722af2df51d72f696b">affiliate link</a>)</p>
<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/71Dh0-dIIwL._SL1467_.jpg" width="341" height="324"></p>
<p>and a more traditional roller shaped one (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00BAGTNAQ/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B00BAGTNAQ&amp;linkId=cb9987743b51a7b5feea72739bf6ac92">affiliate link</a>)</p>
<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/61VbLSzuCrL._SL1500_.jpg" width="340" height="272"></p>
<p>Of these, I found the wand shaped one easier to use, and the roller easier to clean. I prioritized use, but your mileage may vary. Also, you need to actually read the instructions on how to use it, running it back and forth like disposable lint roller just redistributes the hair.</p>
<p>Here is a picture of a pillow after I ran the paddle shaped one over part of it several times. I think this gives a good idea of what it’s capable of, i.e. it’s a significant improvement but doesn’t get everything.</p>
<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/CdwlDpVYOYR7uoDoi2G-hNc8DLvvdJcuKTEiekukqxS_Ao3h9i5dMpu5j-s6GWrwGTe-34ILa7rc-Y83frrUc5SpqWEqErREaYHV8QACkzN1Qc7ziND_ZkQ7bPRcB2J6jcr9cxcOWwBpDKwT-zVo5dalEK1QTcm5cntNpZpe213JKFvj0cH-3aSXp9gjvW_yvmj_PRXNWBOEbkCwYiz_sVkrhebNvKv48qHgcu0hq7P-cW5DGbFncCoHJYGk0hn5zUSJGTfBZycsdWoq9wwXV3fepvtl8koVwGgAZTu-eGAifmoPK1RIQurOfZd8aYCANtifgD21PKFn0UTrFUx6gJ1paCdQ2uEVuYunpuxPVALjhQddhCI74D525eMhQ2b7-pj7q74Q9s-DI1_DHsmdvxwlGAzbPKowjkgj_XCi3kcq6MgV4ApNaZvSE89ZV3dok7peQEkh3WdP6p_V5WZbTMLdxwSqrUWU2gWNgt5R9Su6mxnSad_vpkMcSmCmln5j5aLfC0hBCOPWtYBiZ20pr0x9q2atPvG6kUhElanjCNtJBYvsgewnqxSCbzqB0tcfJ3UNFuETuFCgQ_kSU_5JMMeqa2oi94i1GH2Gogjm9wMKO3iruENNYaRmHW-9ogCsfvOHPPP558lJu78AOFY3Ld2zEjEfijgu22QP1U3vxkZBFGR_fKbfkvI=w1760-h1320-no" width="340" height="255"></p>
<p>Note: inbetween writing this and publishing, the paddle brush people offered me actual money to publish a review, which I plan on taking them up on, assuming I can find the form.</p>
<h2>Shark Pet-Perfect II Handheld Vacuum (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0037HHFMO/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B0037HHFMO&amp;linkId=4140bcc636b3132e9c69552f56ebb21e">affiliate link</a>)</h2>
<p>Sweethome’s top handheld vacuum pick was sold out everywhere and their second is specifically called out as being bad at fur, so I selected based on Amazon reviews. As a vacuum cleaner it is Not Fucking Around- it is super powerful and sucks anything off my floors. It advertises a special whirling brush aimed specifically at pet hair, but I found it choked on soft surface I tried it on, and the bristles were better. The biggest complain on Amazon was the battery life, but I got it for spot cleaning not marathons, so it’s been fine and I appreciate not paying for a feature I don’t use.</p>
<p>All of the anti-cat-hair devices work better if I stay very on top of them. Given time, the fur works itself deeper into the fabric and nothing will work except picking it out with actual human fingers.</p>

<h2>The Furminator (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07MZLNVSW/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07MZLNVSW&amp;linkId=ea4961e2a9d1ed7f9540a55d8364f886">affiliate link</a>)</h2>
<p>This is another one that was great at its official objective but failed a secret objective. It was absolutely amazing at removing fur from the cats (on areas broad and unbony enough to support the comb), and they liked it, but it left them less soft. I did not get these cats to have them at less than their maximum softness.</p>
<h2><span>Rubber Thingies You Throw in the Washer and Dryer&nbsp;</span></h2>
<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/71uRMoJP33L._AC_SL1500_.jpg" width="402" height="402"></p>
<p>I ran an experiment and as far as I can tell these are no better than just running an article through the dryer. Before/after photos (which I unfortunately didn’t save) didn’t show more hair being removed and the thingies are completely free of hair after many uses, which suggests to me they’re not helping much.</p>
<p>I tried wetting them and running them over a pillow case and they indeed picked up something, so I’m leaving them in my washer just in case.</p>
<p>I used LEADTEAM (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07THZ68TT/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07THZ68TT&amp;linkId=8efe81ab9e97d47fa558f5f04ff3d1f9">affiliate link</a>) and didn’t test any others, they looked identical.</p>
<h2>Wool Dryer Balls (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00S0U2NVG/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B00S0U2NVG&amp;linkId=6ab6affdfd3d806f607cc564889f6bbf">affiliate link</a>)</h2>
<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/410dKWoCFkL._AC_.jpg" alt="Smart Sheep Reusable Wool Dryer Balls, 3-Pack" width="337" height="320"></p>
<p>Testing the dryer inserts is difficult because it’s really hard to get a control group. I can’t put in half a blanket and see what the other half does. I can’t even use my two identical blankets, because they’re not guaranteed to have identical amounts of hair on them. I tried with socks but was kind of out of patience by that point. I was pretty confident the rubber ones were doing nothing, but despite a really silly amount of rigor involving photos and test swabs with the lint roller, I just can’t tell with these.</p>
<h2>Disposable Lint Rollers</h2>
<p>These were better than nothing but not as good as the reusable roller.</p>

<p>My cats were never great at eating but had gotten to the point where between the two of them someone was vomiting almost every day without cause (cause = “I went too long without eating”, “I ate too fast because I went too long without eating” and hairballs), and one had lost a noticeable amount of weight (her current weight would be fine if she’d started there, but losing almost 20% of her body weight for no known reason is concerning). There was also behavior that made me think they didn’t like their food- things like persistently begging and then when I put new food down, sniffing it, looking upset and begging more. So I talked to the vet.</p>
<h2>Prescription Food and/or B12 vitamins (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07MWKYP86/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=acesoundergla-20&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;creativeASIN=B07MWKYP86&amp;linkId=8707696381553f9939f9fdf6dda878ff">affiliate link</a>)</h2>
<p>I started both of these at the same time and now the cats are down to vomiting once a week, tops, some of which is for cause. They don’t love the prescription food by they will eat it. They’re fine with the vitamins.</p>
<p>In terms of specific brands:</p>
<ul>
<li>They hate <a href="https://www.royalcanin.com/us/cats/products/vet-products/feline-selected-protein-adult-pd-canned-cat-food">Royal Canin Duck and Pea protein</a>. When I included this in their diet they ate only two cans of food per day (one Royal Canin, one of their old food, Friskies), which is little enough that the already-underweight one was losing …</li></ul></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acesounderglass.com/2020/09/02/coping-with-cats/">https://acesounderglass.com/2020/09/02/coping-with-cats/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acesounderglass.com/2020/09/02/coping-with-cats/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24361029</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 05:32:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Understanding Daemons]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 154 | Comments 85 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24361013">thread link</a>) | @aryamansharda
<br/>
September 2, 2020 | https://blog.digitalbunker.dev/2020/09/03/understanding-daemons-unix/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.digitalbunker.dev/2020/09/03/understanding-daemons-unix/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="mainEntityOfPage">
		
<p>In this article, we’ll take a closer look at daemons. We’ll understand exactly what they are, how they’re implemented, and the scope of their responsibility.&nbsp;</p>



<h2><strong>Overview</strong></h2>



<p>Simply put, a daemon (pronounced dee-mon) is an intentionally orphaned background process. Additionally, daemons are detached from the terminal in which they’re spawned, operate without user interaction, and are descendants of the system’s init process.</p>



<p>Daemons will silently wait in the background for specific events to occur or conditions to be met before executing.</p>



<p>At boot time, Linux will start the init process (init is itself a daemon) which will serve as the parent of all processes and assign it PID 1 (process identification number). It’s important to mention that the init function is a special process that is not attached to any terminal.</p>



<p>After the boot sequence is complete, Linux will start up any previously declared daemons. These will be created through a series of fork() and exit() commands which will intentionally create an orphaned process that will eventually be adopted by the init process – more on this soon.</p>



<h2><strong>Use Cases</strong></h2>



<p>Conventionally, daemon process names end with the letter “d”. If you’re interested in seeing all daemons installed on your Linux machine, use this command:</p>



<p><code>service --status-all</code></p>



<p>You’ve certainly encountered daemons whether you were aware of them or not:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>A web server is simply a process that runs continuously in the background waiting to process and respond to HTTP requests (http daemon)</li><li>sshd is the dameon responsible for SSH operations</li><li>“MAILURE_DEMON” is a daemon that notifies the sender of invalid email recipients&nbsp;</li><li>Monitoring hardware activity like hard drive health&nbsp;</li><li>cron jobs</li></ul>



<h2><strong>Implementation</strong></h2>



<p>We’ll take a look at the code to create a daemon shortly, but let’s establish some basics first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Calling the fork() function creates a new process referred to as the child process. The child process runs in parallel with the process that triggered the fork() (the parent process).&nbsp;</p>



<p>A child process shares the same program counter and CPU registers as its parent. So, when a new child process is created, both the child and parent processes will execute the next instruction after the fork() call in parallel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here’s a simple example from Michigan Tech:&nbsp;</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Q9blfMxaFBFWjoLw_h9HxBAJYRhW5WO6ws4atHZKsY-6Bf5y9bu-EBQJ7qJ8F_piFCvK6wct0U-l9ykXRpt1DZZy_XdJZRCjnjx7WNjLpQu8sx59rsdAxQ25y-PGCJdGJ_VvpzwL" alt="" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>



<p>After fork(), both the parent and the child processes execute the following code in parallel.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/OeO_ztEonrxuE5Lw-N_7YS-3gOl0G0h8lQHUdax3632W6aooeiDSf7wOBIGU1aqyF_yCs6hnHv1IqJxtreeTsS_mkdukzMqcfbw2wPp_eEisclimHbtDUC45tetfvxQ_moeOVIvb" alt="" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>



<p>You can also make their execution paths differ if desired. If the fork() call succeeds, the PID of the child process is returned in the parent, and 0 is returned in the child.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In order to create a daemon, we’ll fork() to create a child process and then exit() the parent. This, as previously mentioned, will purposefully create an orphaned process that will be adopted by init. </p>



<p>Our new daemon is now free to sit silently in the background outside of any terminal and perform its task.</p>



<p>While this is a practical understanding, the actual implementation is a bit more nuanced. </p>



<p>We’ll need to make sure to do the following:</p>



<ul><li>Close all open file descriptors</li><li>Change the working directory</li><li>Separate from the terminal and ignore I/O signals</li><li>Disassociate from the process group and control terminal</li><li>Don’t reacquire a control terminal </li><li>Reset the file access creation mask</li></ul>



<p>The following implementation is inspired by Pascal Werkl’s work. I’ve added additional documentation to make it more approachable for someone that is unfamiliar with C and/or Linux systems. I encourage you to <a href="https://github.com/pasce/daemon-skeleton-linux-c/">checkout the original code here</a>.</p>







<h2>Understanding the double fork()</h2>



<p>Let’s try and understand why we need 2 fork() calls in the code above.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When we run this program in the terminal, several environmental settings – specifically the shell we’re working in – are replicated to our child process. So, we’ll need to disassociate our daemon from its spawning terminal.</p>



<p>That’s why we call <code>setsid()</code> and create our own independent session for the child process. </p>



<p>However, in doing so, this child process will be in its own session and process group and therefore it’ll be its own session leader. The main takeaway here is that there is potential for the session leader to reacquire a terminal later on (i..e. if say the user were to open up another terminal). </p>



<p>We don’t want that. Remember, we want to be completely independent of the terminal and any user-input.</p>



<p>By calling fork() a second time, we ensure that this new process (fork-2) will have a PID outside the bounds of fork-1’s session. Since we are not calling <code>setsid()</code> on the fork-2 process, no new session is being made. In other words, we know that fork-2 is <em><strong>not</strong></em> a session leader and therefore there’s no risk of it acquiring a terminal in the future. </p>



<p>Finally, by killing fork-2’s parent, we know that we’ve created an orphaned process that is adopted by init and can’t reacquire a terminal or be affected by user input.</p>



<blockquote><p>TLDR: The 2 fork() calls removes any chance of the daemon reacquiring a controlling terminal and helps ensure that the daemon is re-parented onto init. </p><p>If the use of the secondary fork() isn’t clear, don’t worry – it’s more to do with handling a potential edge case in the environment than a necessity in a generic daemon implementation.</p></blockquote>



<h2><strong>Wrapping Up</strong></h2>



<p>Thanks for checking out this article! If you have any topic requests, please contact me or leave a comment below!</p>



<p>If you’re interested in seeing all installed daemons on your machine, use this command on Linux machines:&nbsp;</p>



<p><code>service --status-all</code></p>



<blockquote><p>Remember daemon names generally end in “d”</p></blockquote>



<h4>Feel free to check out some of my other websites!</h4>



<p><a href="http://stickerspot.digitalbunker.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">http://stickerspot.digitalbunker.dev/</a></p>



<p><a href="http://halfway.digitalbunker.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">http://halfway.digitalbunker.dev/</a></p>



<p><a href="https://mixrecipes.digitalbunker.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://mixrecipes.digitalbunker.dev/</a></p>



<p><a href="http://http//lowpolygonart.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">http://www.lowpolygonart.com/</a></p>




			
				</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.digitalbunker.dev/2020/09/03/understanding-daemons-unix/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24361013</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 05:27:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Be Indistractable]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24360966">thread link</a>) | @nireyal
<br/>
September 2, 2020 | https://psyche.co/guides/to-become-indistractable-recognise-that-it-starts-within-you | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://psyche.co/guides/to-become-indistractable-recognise-that-it-starts-within-you">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><div><h2 data-guide-section-number="1"><span>Need to know</span></h2><div><p>â€˜Just a second. I just need to respond to this one thing,â€™ I said to my daughter, as I attended to my iPhone.</p>
<p>Only much later could I count the mistakes in that statement. No, it wouldnâ€™t take â€˜just a secondâ€™; no, I didnâ€™t â€˜needâ€™ to respond to the email â€“ Iâ€™m an author and researcher, and thus rarely receive messages that have a drop-everything-and-answer urgency to them. And no, it wouldnâ€™t be â€˜one thingâ€™. My brain would be too tempted, Iâ€™d feast on it all.</p>
<p>After I finished, I looked up and my daughter was gone. The worst part: before I became distracted, we had been playing a lovely game, telling each other what superpower we most wished for. It could have brought us closer together, but Iâ€™d just blown the spirit and substance of it big-time.</p>
<p>If youâ€™re a parent in the 21st century, I bet youâ€™ve experienced your own version of this. But itâ€™s not just parents, itâ€™s all of us in our interactions with each other. Distraction has become the norm. Weâ€™re blessed with pocket-sized supercomputers that connect us to anyone and everyone, and a buffet of information. But thereâ€™s a dark side: those same gadgets distract us, often at the moments that matter most.</p>
<p>Of course, smartphones didnâ€™t invent distraction â€“ theyâ€™re just the latest culprit. Before that, we blamed television. And before that, it was the telephone, or comic books, or the radio. Go back more than 2,000 years, and Socrates was even criticising the written word, for causing â€˜forgetfulness in the learnersâ€™ soulsâ€™.</p>
<p>Still, our present feels different, with the sources of distraction seeming greater in number and more ubiquitous. One <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/0013916514539755">study</a> in 2014 showed that when two people are talking, the mere presence of a smartphone resting on a table is enough to change the character of their conversation. Thatâ€™s a tame example. To see the seriousness of the problem, look at the sobering <a href="https://www.nhtsa.gov/risky-driving/distracted-driving">statistics</a> on â€˜distracted drivingâ€™ in the United States.</p>
<p>After I abandoned my daughter and our game for an utterly inconsequential email, I realised I needed to deal with my distraction problem. First, I tried a popular approach: I blamed technology and made a serious attempt at a â€˜digital detoxâ€™. I bought a flip phone, subscribed to a print newspaper, and even purchased a 1990s-era word processor without an internet connection. I convinced myself that, once I banished all the technology from my life, Iâ€™d become the disciplined writer and focused father Iâ€™d always strived to be.</p>
<p>Talk about a rude awakening. Sitting at my ancient word processor, my eyes began to peer over to my now-tantalising bookshelf. â€˜Hmmm,â€™ I said to myself, â€˜I really should take a glance at this bookâ€™. Iâ€™d justify the distraction as necessary for â€˜researchâ€™. And if it wasnâ€™t reading, then Iâ€™d find something else â€“ the laundry that <em>needed</em> to be folded right now, my desk that <em>needed</em> to be tidied-up this minute. The technology wasnâ€™t distracting me. <em>I</em> was distracting me.</p>
<p>Thatâ€™s when I started a five-year journey to understand <a href="https://www.nirandfar.com/distractions/">distraction</a>, its causes and its cures. I discovered a great deal that I found surprising and counterintuitive, and I developed methods to deal with my distraction that actually worked â€“ and didnâ€™t involve me trying to turn back time and operate a flip phone. I realised that distraction often begins from within, not without, and found that the fix came from identifying and managing the psychological discomfort that leads us off track.</p>
<p>As often as not, distraction is your brain ducking challenging feelings such as boredom, loneliness, insecurity, fatigue and uncertainty. These are the internal triggers â€“ the <a href="https://www.nirandfar.com/kids-video-game-obsession/">root causes</a> â€“ that prompt you to find the comfort of distraction and open a browser tab, Twitter or email, instead of focusing on the matter at hand. Once you identify these internal triggers, you can decide to respond in a more advantageous manner. You wonâ€™t always be able to control how you feel â€“ but you can learn to control how you react to the way you feel. A trigger that once sent you to Twitter can perhaps lead instead to 10 deep breaths.</p>
<p>Distraction, in other words, is a symptom of a problem â€“ not the problem itself. Those deeper and systemic reasons â€“ such as an inability to cope with fear, anxiety or stress â€“ deserve our concern, because itâ€™s only when we start to address them that we can make real progress. When we begin to understand what weâ€™re trying to avoid by clicking over to Twitter or checking the news for the 10th time today, we can begin to address the issue itself, and not medicate it through more distraction. We also begin to appreciate how habitual the act of avoiding discomfort via distraction can be, and how much itâ€™s become a part of how we work and live.</p>
<p>The good news is that thereâ€™s something paradoxical about discomfort: itâ€™s actually the best tool we have for evolving and developing as a species. Feeling bad isnâ€™t actually bad; itâ€™s what helped us survive. Writing in 2001, the American psychologist Roy Baumeister and his colleagues <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-70020-001">observed</a>: â€˜If satisfaction and pleasure were permanent, there might be little incentive to continue seeking further benefits or advances.â€™ If we didnâ€™t feel bad, in other words, weâ€™d never achieve good.</p>
<p>Once you understand the depth of distraction, you can start to manage it and improve. After years of experiments, I found myself less distracted â€“ a quality that improved nearly every aspect of my life. It turns out that being able to focus on the subjects and people in my life who matter improved everything from my health to my happiness to my productivity. That can seem obvious, but I couldnâ€™t have fully appreciated the joys of living an indistractable life if I hadnâ€™t gotten there on my own after a five-year journey. Being indistractable can lead you to not just change your life for the better, but also experience life fully.</p></div></div></section><section><div><h2 data-guide-section-number="2"><span>What to do</span></h2><div><p><strong>Self-explore</strong></p>
<p>Identifying the triggers that made you feel bad in the first place requires self-exploration. When you notice yourself feeling distracted, pause and ask yourself what youâ€™re feeling. Are you worried? Are you afraid? Then go one step deeper. What caused the sensation? How does it feel in your body?</p>
<p>In exploring my own internal triggers, I began to appreciate that my anxiety about a project, which might lead me to find a tempting Wikipedia rabbit hole, was actually adaptive: the fact that I was anxious was good because it meant I was trying to become better. It was sometimes even as easy as saying to myself: â€˜Youâ€™re getting distracted right now because youâ€™re worried this wonâ€™t be up to snuff. Thatâ€™s okay. It means youâ€™re trying to do your best work, and thatâ€™s something to feel good about.â€™ It seems like a simple mental trick, but even that thought can have a profound influence in keeping you on track.</p>
<p>Thereâ€™s an interesting paradox about internal triggers: they can be big, imposing, powerful issues, and yet the fixes can sometimes be easy and quick. Hereâ€™s an example: letâ€™s say that an internal trigger when youâ€™re about to get started on a looming project is boredom. You just canâ€™t bring yourself to get excited about doing your taxes. And because you get bored, you get distracted. But if you know youâ€™re going to get bored, you can find ways to avoid the distraction that will soothe the boredom. For instance, if you set a time limit to work on the otherwise mind-numbing task that is so short, you wonâ€™t have a chance to get bored. Anyone can work on their taxes for just 10 minutes. This is called the <a href="https://www.nirandfar.com/strange-sex-habits-of-silicon-valley/">10-minute rule</a>, and itâ€™s an effective way to avoid distractions of all sorts. The point is to anticipate the internal trigger and then intercept it with a new routine rather than allowing yourself to slink away into doing something you didnâ€™t intend to do.</p>
<p>In the case of my interaction with my daughter, the internal trigger might have been anxiety about work or <a href="https://www.nirandfar.com/fomo/">fear of missing out</a> (on an email). But I can address both of those proactively, so that they donâ€™t interfere with precious daddy-daughter time. In the case of my work anxiety, I could make sure that someone on my team is monitoring incoming messages. I could put up an â€˜out of officeâ€™ email that encourages people to call me if thereâ€™s really an emergency. Or in reality, I could get comfortable with the discomfort that I might indeed be missing out on something, but thatâ€™s all right too. Any one of those is a better and more constructive response to the internal trigger than being distracted.</p>
<p>Whatever approach you take to address your inner triggers, itâ€™s encouraging to note that merely recognising uncomfortable feelings and identifying them could be beneficial. For instance, in a smoking-cessation <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0376871611002535?via%3Dihub">study</a>, researchers found that participants who learned to acknowledge and explore their cravings managed to quit smoking at double the rates of those in the American Lung Associationâ€™s best-performing cessation programme. Just identifying and investigating a craving had a tremendous impact.</p>
<p><strong>Reframe</strong></p>
<p>Once youâ€™ve identified the triggers, you can reframe the task at hand. Sure, you might be â€˜forced to do your taxesâ€™. But another way of thinking about that is that you â€˜get to review last yearâ€™s business successesâ€™. It sounds laughable, but it works. When I hit rough patches mid-book writing, I would say: â€˜I get to share this with my audience,â€™ as opposed to: â€˜I really have to work on the book today.â€™</p>
<p>Hereâ€™s one strategy: I found the fun in whatever I was doing. Yes, I know, this is where you roll your eyes, but hear me out. I learned to stay focused on the tedious work of writing books by looking for and finding the mystery embedded in my work. I wasnâ€™t â€˜writingâ€™, I was â€˜exploringâ€™. I wasnâ€™t Ernest Hemingway; I was Scooby-Doo. Research indicates that even the simple act of thinking of something that you donâ€™t enjoy as …</p></div></div></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://psyche.co/guides/to-become-indistractable-recognise-that-it-starts-within-you">https://psyche.co/guides/to-become-indistractable-recognise-that-it-starts-within-you</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://psyche.co/guides/to-become-indistractable-recognise-that-it-starts-within-you</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24360966</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 05:12:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Even in Go, concurrency is still not easy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 103 | Comments 119 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24359650">thread link</a>) | @benhoyt
<br/>
September 2, 2020 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/GoConcurrencyStillNotEasy | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/GoConcurrencyStillNotEasy">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Even in Go, concurrency is still not easy (with an example)</h2>

	<p><small>September  1, 2020</small></p>
</div><div><p>Go is famous for making concurrency easy, through good language
support for <a href="https://golangbot.com/goroutines/">goroutines</a>. Except
what Go makes easy is only one level of concurrency, the nuts and
bolts level of making your code do things concurrently and communicating
back and forth through channels. Making it do the right things
concurrently is still up to you, and unfortunately Go doesn't
currently provide a lot of standard library support for correctly
implemented standard concurrency patterns.</p>

<p>For example, one common need is for a limited amount of concurrency;
you want to do several things at once, but only so many of them.
At the moment this is up to you to implement on top of goroutines,
channels, and things like the <a href="https://golang.org/pkg/sync/"><code>sync</code></a>
package. This is not as easy as it looks, and quite competent people
can make mistakes here. As it happens, I have an example ready to
hand today.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/google/gops">Gops</a> is a convenient command to
list (and diagnose) Go processes that are currently running on your
system. Among other things, it'll tell you which version of Go they
were compiled with, which is handy if you want to see if you have out
of date binaries that should be rebuilt and redeployed. One of the
things <code>gops</code> needs to do is look at all of the Go processes on your
system, which it does concurrently. However, it doesn't want to look
at too many processes at once, because <a href="https://github.com/google/gops/pull/118">that can cause problems with
file descriptor limits</a>. This
is a classic case of <em>limited concurrency</em>.</p>

<p>Gops implements this at the moment with code in <a href="https://github.com/google/gops/blob/6fb0d860e5fa50629405d9e77e255cd32795967e/goprocess/gp.go#L29">goprocess.FindAll()</a>
that looks like this, in somewhat sketched and reduced form:</p>

<blockquote><pre>func FindAll() []P {
   pss, err := ps.Processes()
   [...]
   found := make(chan P)
   limitCh := make(chan struct{}, concurrencyProcesses)

   for _, pr := range pss {
      limitCh &lt;- struct{}{}
      pr := pr
      go func() {
         defer func() { &lt;-limitCh }()
         [... get a P with some error checking ...]
         found &lt;- P
      }()
   }
   [...]

   var results []P
   for p := range found {
      results = append(results, p)
   }
   return results
}
</pre>
</blockquote>

<p>(In the real code there's a WaitGroup for coordination, and the
<code>found</code> channel gets closed appropriately.)</p>

<p>How this works is clear, and is a standard pattern (covered in eg
Go 101's <a href="https://go101.org/article/channel-use-cases.html">Channel Use Cases</a>). We use a
buffered channel to provide a limited number of tokens; sending a
value into the channel implicitly takes a token (and blocks if the
token supply is exhausted), while receiving a value from it puts a
token back in. We take a token before we start a new goroutine, and
the goroutine releases the token when it's done.</p>

<p>Except that <a href="https://github.com/google/gops/issues/123">this code has a bug if there are too many processes
to examine</a>. Even knowing
that there is a bug in this code, it may not be obvious.</p>

<p>The bug is that the goroutines only receive from <code>limitCh</code> to release
their token after sending their result to the unbuffered <code>found</code>
channel, while the main code only starts receiving from <code>found</code>
after running through the entire loop, and <strong>the main code takes
the token in the loop and blocks if no tokens are available</strong>. So
if you have too many processes to go through, you start N goroutines,
they all block trying to write to <code>found</code> and don't receive from
<code>limitCh</code>, and the main <code>for</code> loop blocks trying to send to <code>limitCh</code>
and never reaches the point where it starts receiving from <code>found</code>.</p>

<p>At one level, this bug is a very fragile bug; it only exists because
of multiple circumstances. If the goroutines took the token by
sending to <code>limitCh</code> instead of the main <code>for</code> loop doing it, the
bug would not exist; the main <code>for</code> loop would start them all, many
would stop, and then it would go on to receive from <code>found</code> so that
they could receive from <code>limitCh</code> and release their token so other
goroutines would run. If the goroutines received from <code>limitCh</code> to
release their token before sending to <code>found</code>, it wouldn't exist
(but because of error handling, it's simpler and more reliable to
do the receive in a <code>defer</code>). And if the entire <code>for</code> loop was in
an additional goroutine, the main code would go on to receive from
<code>found</code> and unblock completed goroutines to release their tokens,
so the fact that the <code>for</code> loop was blocked waiting to send to
<code>limitCh</code> wouldn't matter.</p>

<p>At another level, this shows how concurrency is not easy as easy
as it looks in Go. All you need is one mistake and things skid to
a halt, and all of the code involved can look good to a casual
examination. Getting concurrency correct is simply hard for people
(we can debate about why, but I think that it is is very clear).</p>

<p>(I'm sure that the people who wrote and approved the change that
added this concurrency limiting code to gops were good programmers.
A tricky case still tripped them up, passing all of their scrutiny.
Even when I knew that there was a concurrency problem in the code
and where it was (because my <code>gops</code> was hanging all of a sudden,
and <a href="https://github.com/go-delve/delve">Delve</a> told me where
everything was stuck), it still took me some time to see what the
exact problem was.)</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/GoConcurrencyStillNotEasy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24359650</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:15:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
