<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 08:31:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 08:31:32 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I am an 80 column purist]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25251494">thread link</a>) | @Spiritus
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I write and prefer code that fits within 80 columns in <a href="https://curl.haxx.se/">curl</a> and other projects – and there are reasons for it. I’m a little bored by the people who respond and say that they have 400 inch monitors already and they can use them.</p>



<p>I too have multiple large high resolution screens – but writing wide code is still a bad idea! So I decided I’ll write down my reasoning once and for all!</p>



<h2>Narrower is easier to read</h2>



<p>There’s a reason newspapers and magazines have used narrow texts for centuries and in fact even books <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line_length">aren’t using long lines</a>. For most humans, it is simply easier on the eyes and brain to read texts that aren’t using really long lines. This has been known for a very long time.</p>



<p>Easy-to-read code is easier to follow and understand which leads to fewer bugs and faster debugging.</p>



<h2>Side-by-side works better</h2>



<p>I <em>never</em> run windows full sized on my screens for anything except watching movies. I frequently have two or more editor windows next to each other, sometimes also with one or two extra terminal/debugger windows next to those. To make this feasible and still have the code readable, it needs to fit “wrapless” in those windows.</p>



<p>Sometimes reading a code diff is easier side-by-side and then too it is important that the two can fit next to each other nicely.</p>



<h2>Better diffs</h2>



<p>Having code grow vertically rather than horizontally is beneficial for diff, git and other tools that work on changes to files. It reduces the risk of merge conflicts and it makes the merge conflicts that still happen easier to deal with.</p>



<h2>It encourages shorter names</h2>



<p>A side effect by strictly not allowing anything beyond column 80 is that it becomes really hard to use those terribly annoying 30+ letters java-style names on functions and identifiers. A function name, and especially local ones, should be short. Having long names make them really hard to read and makes it really hard to spot the difference between the other functions with similarly long names where just a sub-word within is changed.</p>



<p>I know especially Java people object to this as they’re trained in a different culture and say that a method name should rather include a lot of details of the functionality “to help the user”, but to me that’s a weak argument as all non-trivial functions will have more functionality than what can be expressed in the name and thus the user needs to know how the function works <em>anyway.</em></p>



<p>I don’t mean 2-letter names. I mean long enough to make sense but not be ridiculous lengths. Usually within 15 letters or so.</p>



<h2>Just a few spaces per indent level</h2>



<p>To make this work, and yet allow a few indent levels, the code basically have to have small indent-levels, so I prefer to have it set to two spaces per level.</p>



<h2>Many indent levels is wrong anyway</h2>



<p>If you do a lot of indent levels it gets really hard to write code that still fits within the 80 column limit. That’s a subtle way to suggest that you should not write functions that needs or uses that many indent levels. It should then rather be split out into multiple smaller functions, where then each function won’t need that many levels!</p>



<h2>Why exactly 80?</h2>



<p>Once upon the time it was of course because terminals had that limit and these days the exact number 80 is not a must. I just happen to think that the limit has worked fine in the past and I haven’t found any compelling reason to change it since.</p>



<p>It also has to be a hard and fixed limit as if we allow a few places to go beyond the limit we end up on a slippery slope and code slowly grow wider over time – I’ve seen it happen in many projects with “soft enforcement” on code column limits.</p>



<h2>Enforced by a tool</h2>



<p>In <a href="https://curl.se/">curl</a>, we have ‘checksrc’ which will yell errors at any user trying to build code with a too long line present. This is good because then we don’t have to “waste” human efforts to point this out to contributors who offer pull requests. The tool will point out such mistakes with ruthless accuracy.</p>



<h2>Credits</h2>



<p>Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/piotrarssale-15944391/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5016297">piotr kurpaska</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5016297">Pixabay</a></p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25251494</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:31:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Am Not Fat]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 115 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25251082">thread link</a>) | @snow_mac
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content" role="main">
      <p> <em>Published: </em> 11/28/2020</p>

      <p>I’m not fat. There I said it, I should feel better about myself, right? Size is just a number. Right? Come on you know it’s true, size, weight and all that jazz is just a BS figure on the scale. That’s what we tell ourselves to make us feel better.</p>

<p>I’m obese, my medical BMI is 42.0. I’m 335 pounds. As Penn Jillette would say, I’m a “fat fuck”. I’m tired of being a “fat fuck” or as my wife prefers a “big guy”.</p>



<p>I’m an audiobook guy. I’m in love with Audible, she is very wonderful service to have, she reads to me every day, all day. About two weeks ago, I was bored, and she suggested Presto, a book by Penn Jillette about how he lost 100 pounds. I was bored, lazy and waiting for someone so I bought the book. Oh my gosh, the language is obscene, but the author is hilarious and entertaining. I could not put the book down. It made me want to toss the skinny white peppermint mocha and bananas in the trash…</p>

<p>Basically, Penn is a obese guy like me, well he was, he was 330 pounds at his highest. He went to the hospital for heart issues and nearly died. On a fist full of pills to keep his blood pressure less than the voltage of an outlet in Europe he embarked on a crazy, all in diet consisting of potatoes for two weeks. I like his style, he’s an all or nothing guy like me. Either give me the steak, the ice cream and the sides or give me nothing. I want to eat big; I want to live big. Moderation is bullshit as Penn would say, I would agree! I don’t do anything in moderation. If I’m going to do something, it’s all-in baby. When in Vegas last summer, I was the dipshit who went all in with a pair of kings in my hand and straight on the table; that’s me baby, not the smartest guy but hey I like to live it big.</p>

<p>I don’t do keto, I don’t do paleo, but when I do diet, I go really big, I go to Costco and literally buy everything I need to be successful on that plan, I research, I plan. It’s just like thanksgiving this year; I researched, I planned, I went to Costco and planned out each and every ingredient. I was diligent. Every doctor, health coach and fitness instructor has told me that my relationship with food is fucked up. Well, not fucked up, but bad; unhealthy. As Penn would say your life sucks if you’re taking diet advice from a Las Vegas Magician, well, Penn, my life does suck. I can’t breathe outside very well, hell, I get windy walking to the park. I’m an obese guy, I have a CPAP machine, I’m 335 pounds, I can barely do the things I want to do, basic stuff; sleep and wake rested, eat and not feel sick, go for a walk and not get winded. I’m half Penn’s age and his same weight… It’s time for a change.</p>



<p>The plan according to Penn’s buddy, Cray Ray, aka “Ray Cronise” is to do the following:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Eat nothing but potatoes for two weeks. Boiled, baked, steamed, roasted; does not matter, just no salt, oil, or sugar. Plain, nothing added, no salt, no butter, no pepper, no olive oil, just a plain, boring potato. Sweet, red, yellow, gold, purple, do not be a racist pig about potatoes, eat the potato rainbow, but just potatoes. Feel free to pig out on potatoes; just no fries or chips, that’s the beautiful potato ruined by Americans</li>
  <li>Contrast showers: Humans have conquered winter &amp; cold. Therefore, in order to get back to the biologically true lifestyle we’ve grown as a species as, we need to bring back the cold. Turn down the thermostat and cycle 10 seconds hot; 30 seconds cold showers for 5 minutes. It’s brutal but the time goes by shockingly fast</li>
  <li>After two weeks on potatoes, you go to a plant based, vegan lifestyle until you hit your target weight</li>
</ol>



<p>One big thing with CrayRay and Penn is the need for a scale, the smartass of scales. On an impluse I plopped down $100 for the <a href="https://www.withings.com/us/en/body-plus">Withings Body + scale</a>. It’s been 10 days! 10 DAYS!!! I’m 326.4, on day 2 of the plan. In 10 days, 1 of which involving nothing but potatoes, I’ve lost 9 pounds. This is AMAZING.</p>

<p>On day 1, it’s black Friday, or sucker day of the year. Everyone piles in their car after a Thanksgiving Day hang over consisting of pie and turkey, to go buy more stuff to stuff into their garage in six months. It’s all American in style and glory. What am I do? Well, shopping for TVs on Amazon like every other fat guy scared out of his mind of COVID-19. I’m sitting on my couch waiting for the oven, 350 degrees for 45 minutes, to produce 9 potatoes. That’s right 9 potatoes, or about 1000 ish calories. Once done cooking, I scarf down one single sweet potato. It’s sweet (no shit sherlock), delicious and surprisingly moist. I like it, I chase it with 4 tiny petite potatoes and some black coffee. This diet is sure boring.</p>

<p>Lunch time rolls around and I make some food for the kiddo and thanksgiving dinner for lunch for the wife. What do I have? If you guessed potatoes, you’d win the prize! I had 2 potatoes, a red and white. It was bland, boring and good.</p>

<p>A car ride nap, so more black coffee and about 2 liters of water later, we’re sitting down to dinner. I made peanut noodles for the wife, mac and cheese with some TG leftovers for the baby. I have 3 more potatoes, a gold, a red and a sweet potato. 2 potatoes into the meal, I’m stuffed. STUFFED ON TWO POTATOES?!?!??! Yeah, I save the sweet potato for dessert and decide to count my potatoes.</p>

<p>A few days ago, while prepping for thanksgiving, I bought 10 pounds of potatoes. I thought that was a LOT of potatoes, but when I counted it out I had around 20 potatoes left. That’s enough to feed a family a four a potato a night for a week, but for a guy living on potatoes? It’s more like two days if I’m lucky, so I head to Costco.</p>

<p>I love Costco. Everything there is a deal, no matter what the idiots on Life Hacker tell you. I love their steak, their fruit and yes, I love their clothes and bedding. But potatoes, that’s where you really make off like bandits. The potatoes were on sale today too.</p>

<p>I knew to continue the diet I needed to account for 14 days of potatoes, less today and the 1.5 I had in revere; thus, I knew I need about 12 (rounding up) days of potatoes. I’m supposed to be on a calorie restricted diet of 1800 or less per day, which is helping, but to get 1800 calories a day eating just potatoes, I’d need to consume 5 POUNDS of potatoes. That’s right, every day on this thing to hit target calorie intake I’d need 5 POUNDS!?!?!? So, with 12 days needed to be shopped, a total of 60 pounds of potatoes, I headed to Costco.</p>



<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Potato Type</td>
      <td>Per Unit Cost</td>
      <td>Units</td>
      <td>Total Cost</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Creamer Potatoes</td>
      <td>$3.99 / 5 lb</td>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>$16</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Organic Sweet Potatos</td>
      <td>$6.99 / 6.5 lbs</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>$14</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Russet Potatoes</td>
      <td>$7 / 15 lbs</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>$7</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Gold Potatoes</td>
      <td>$6 / 10 lbs</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>$12</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>68 pounds of potatoes for a whopping $49!</p>

<p>Here’s what my shopping chart looked like:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/costco-potatoes.png" alt="Costco cart"></p>

<p>That’s a lot of potatoes! The berries are for my son, Luke, for him to eat with yogurt and breakfast for the next two weeks. Not pictured is the bottles of the sparkling water I got to enhance my diet this week.</p>



<p>If you don’t want to see me shirtless, it’s time to close the page. My starting stats on 11/20/2020 are: 335 LBS, but the offical, diet starting stats are: 333.4 lbs, BMI of 41.7. I’ll be updating this blog with progress, but here’s to my weightloss and success.</p>

<p>I’m off to eat more potatoes!</p>

<p><img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/11272020-front.png" alt="front"> 
<img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/11272020-side.png" alt="side"></p>



      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25251082</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:49:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[And this world’s a fickle measure]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25250968">thread link</a>) | @jseliger
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-12060">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>They told me, “You have to watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rhThso-PE_o">this interview where Mike Tyson talks about medieval history</a>,” and so I did, and there he was at the New York Public Library in 2013 being interviewed by curator Paul Holdengräber, whose German accent strikes the American ear as both effortlessly intellectual and lightly amusing, and who would seem to have nothing in common with the face-tattooed boxer.</p>



<p><img data-attachment-id="12067" data-permalink="https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11-57-11-pm-copy/" data-orig-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" data-orig-size="1816,934" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2020-11-28 at 11.57.11 PM copy" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=863" src="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" alt=""></p>



<p>The two men do, in fact, find much to talk about. Their discussion is mesmerizing, because to most of us Mike Tyson is nothing but a face and fists, not a man who reflects aloud and at length about his inner life. Holdengräber prompts a reticent Tyson to narrate clips of his greatest moments in the ring, and newcomers to boxing will easily see why Tyson was such a sensation, but Iron Mike grows more animated when other matters arise.</p>



<p>Half an hour into the interview, Holdengräber says that their mutual friend, eccentric German filmmaker Werner Herzog, urged him to ask Tyson why he’s so fascinated by Clovis, the founder of the Merovingian Frankish dynasty, and Pepin the Short, the first Carolingian king of the Franks. Tyson’s answer, however halting, makes him come alive: </p>



<blockquote><p>I don’t know—it all comes from my insecurity from being poor, and not having enough—to be insecure, and being—yeah, that’s what it is: obscure. I never wanted to be obscure. I was born in obscurity and I never wanted to deal with that again, never wanted to be that. And they came from obscurity.</p></blockquote>



<p>Tyson then narrates a capsule history of the Frankish kings. He rambles, he doesn’t get all the details right, and his mispronunciation of names marks him as an autodidact, but it’s a shame to hear the audience laugh when Holdengräber asks, “Mike, how do you know all this shit?” Whether Tyson is mapping his own experiences onto medieval history or hearing echoes of the Franks in his troubled life, the credentialed, status-conscious audience is uncomfortable with his sincere interest in a past they find trivial.</p>



<p>Yet Tyson is the real deal, a book lover not because his peer group yaks about whichever author the <em>New York Times</em> has dubbed fame’s latest love child, but because he’s hungry for ideas, for meaning, for connections across time. He speaks with undisguised emotion about Cus D’Amato, the trainer and manager who turned him into a lethal boxer. Obsessed with Nietzsche and Clausewitz, D’Amato taught Tyson to see boxing as war and war as the key to decoding the world. “That is just what I do,” Tyson explains, an attentive pupil and dutiful son. “I love war. I love the act of war. I love the players in war, the philosophy of war.”</p>



<p>Tyson is searching for more than war on the pages of the past. Having grown up amid crime and chaos and founded his life on violence, he now relies on books to make moral and ethical sense of the world:</p>



<blockquote><p>Yeah—they’re our most priceless possessions, because if you think about it, you know, a room without a book is like a body without a soul. It’s the only way that we can connect the future with the past. Without that, there’s no way that we can know about the future, and know about particularly the past, or the present, you know, that when you think about history, the value of history is not necessarily scientific but moral. By liberating our minds and deepening our sympathies and fortifying our will, we can control—pretty much history allows us to control not society but ourselves, which is a much more important thing to do, you know what I mean? And it would allow us to pretty much meet the future more so than foretell it, and for that reason alone, in order to predict the future we always have to look through the past, because very rarely does time not repeat itself, and it always will repeat itself. </p><p>I’ve heard a quote before in a book that we would be fools to think historically that the past is us in funny clothes, but the past <em><span>is</span></em> us in funny clothes, and that’s truly what it is. That’s from somebody who really said a really profound statement but he misquoted what he was saying, he must have been saying it backwards, because that’s really what the past was, it’s just us in funny clothes, in different times, that’s really what it is.</p></blockquote>



<p>Of course, to hear Tyson cite <a href="http://thecampvs.com/2011/08/03/cicero-on-books-and-the-soul/">a quip inaccurately attributed to Cicero</a>, “a room without books is like a body without a soul,” is to wonder if he’s putting us on. Late in the interview, he jokes that if you quote books, you fool people into thinking you’re smart—but Tyson, for all his malapropisms and mispronunciations and odd mannerisms, <em>is</em> intelligent. He’s going round after round with big questions that  many of the ostensibly educated attendees at his book-talk don’t bother to ask.</p>



<p>When Holdengräber suggests that Tyson’s knowledge of history didn’t improve his behavior, Tyson calmly disagrees. He compares himself to the fictional Ben-Hur, a fellow athlete and celebrity who achieved glory but was doomed to be unfree until he set his priorities in order: “He may not have been famous again,” Tyson points out, “but he got his family, and that was his success.” </p>



<p>After listening to Mike Tyson—childhood criminal, devastating fighter, struggling alcoholic and recovering drug addict, convicted rapist, pop-culture eidolon—speak for an hour and a half, I still don’t quite know who he is. He may be the closest thing 21st-century America has to <a href="https://quidplura.com/2011/11/03/but-the-answers-you-seek-will-never-be-found-at-home/">a Robert E. Howard character</a>, a born barbarian who’s ignorant of social niceties but possesses earned wisdom that the civilization around him disdains. I don’t know whether he’s all in on his bookish pursuits or one slight away from again gnawing off someone’s ear. Whether he’s a good man or a bad man feels foolish to ask about a professional punch-thrower who reads Nietzsche, but Tyson looks like a <em>better</em> man, one who has perhaps searched harder for his humanity than the onlookers snickering from the safety of their library seats. What has their pride gained them? Tyson’s, by contrast, has brought him perspective, and with it the humility to admit that his story is still being written—and has been before.</p>




			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25250968</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Victoria to fine drivers blocking EV chargers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25250936">thread link</a>) | @oxplot
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-to-fine-drivers-blocking-ev-chargers | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-to-fine-drivers-blocking-ev-chargers">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>Drivers who block electric vehicle chargers in Victoria will be fined under new road rules. </p>
<p>Non-electric vehicles, or electric cars that aren’t plugged in to the charger, face fines of $330.44 for “stopping in a parking area for electric-powered vehicles”. </p>
<p>The rules are designed to stop electric vehicle chargers, which are sparse in some parts of Australia, from being blocked by drivers looking for a convenient spot to park their internal-combustion vehicle. </p>
<p>Similar rules have been implemented in American states such as Colorado to prevent what’s known as ICEing. </p>
<div><figure><ul><li><div><figure><a data-fancybox="gallery" href="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/3000/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg" data-thumb="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/180/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg"><img alt="Victoria to fine drivers blocking EV chargers" srcset="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/1600/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg 2x, https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/800/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg 1x" loading="lazy"></a></figure></div></li></ul></figure></div>
<p>Although it has brought in new rules to protect electric vehicle drivers, Victoria has also made news for <a href="https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-aiming-to-raise-30-million-per-year-from-ev-road-tax">trying to tax them</a>. </p>
<p>The state has followed <a href="https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/south-australia-plans-ev-road-user-levy-but-also-pledges-to-buy-more-electric-cars-for-its-own-fleet">South Australia</a> in committing to a&nbsp;<strong>road tax for electric vehicle</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>plug-in hybrid vehicle</strong>&nbsp;owners.</p>
<p>The tax of&nbsp;<strong>2.5 cents per kilometre</strong>&nbsp;for pure electric vehicles and&nbsp;<strong>2.0 cents per kilometre</strong>&nbsp;for plug-in hybrid vehicles was announced by the Victorian Treasurer ahead of this week’s state budget, and will come into force in July 2021.</p>
<p>An electric vehicle owner who travels&nbsp;<strong>15,000km</strong>&nbsp;per year will be charged&nbsp;<strong>$375</strong>&nbsp;on top of their annual registration fee, while plug-in hybrid owners will pay an extra&nbsp;<strong>$300</strong>&nbsp;per year.</p>
<p>Although the estimated $30 million the tax will raise annually won’t be funnelled directly into electric vehicle infrastructure, the Treasurer said $45 million will be set aside in the budget to boost take-up of hybrid, plug-in hybrid, and electric vehicles.</p>
<div><figure><ul><li><div><figure><a data-fancybox="gallery" href="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/3000/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg" data-thumb="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/180/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg"><img alt="Victoria to fine drivers blocking EV chargers" srcset="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/1600/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg 2x, https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/800/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg 1x" loading="lazy"></a></figure></div></li></ul></figure></div>
<p>Chairman of the Electric Vehicle Council of Australia, Behyad Jafari, described Victoria’s tax as a “shameful abdication of Victoria’s intention to reduce emissions”.</p>
<p>South Australia’s proposed charge will include a fixed component, similar to current registration charging, and a variable charge based on distance travelled.</p>
<p>The proposal has been widely criticised, with chief executive of the peak body for carmakers in Australia, Tony Weber, describing it as “beyond belief”.</p>
<p>“We believe this charge will make South Australia the only jurisdiction in the world that actually opposes the uptake of low and zero emission vehicles,” Mr Weber added.</p>
<p>As state governments in Victoria, South Australia, and New South Wales have moved to tax electric vehicle owners, the Australian Capital Territory (ACT) has positioned itself as the friendliest jurisdiction in the nation for EV buyers.</p>
<p>It recently announced an ambitious target to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/all-act-new-car-sales-to-be-zero-emissions-by-2030-under-ambitious-plan">sell only zero-emissions new vehicles</a>&nbsp;by 2030.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-to-fine-drivers-blocking-ev-chargers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25250936</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:15:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Recruiters and Human Traffickers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249818">thread link</a>) | @Danieru
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<p>Japan's <a href="http://www.japaneselawtranslation.go.jp/law/detail_main?id=10&amp;vm=2&amp;re=">Employment Security Act</a> requires a recruitment business to obtain a license. Failure to do so can result in imprisonment of up to a year. While I've met sleazy recruiters, sending them to prison seems a tad excessive to me. Curious about why the industry is so harshly regulated, I started digging. This took me into the seemingly dry but surprisingly interesting topic of the history of recruitment in Japan. As virtually nothing about this is written in English, I'm sharing what I found.</p>

<h2 id="japans-first-employment-agency">Japan’s first employment agency</h2>

<p>The earliest account of an employment agency in Japan comes from the mid-Seventeenth century. <a href="http://shokugyo-kyokai.or.jp/shiryou/gyouseishi/01-1.html">Keian Yamato</a> was a doctor who was sometimes asked by his patients to introduce servants or help arrange marriages. He was compensated for these introductions, and eventually this side business grew so successful that it overtook his medical practice. In 1652, he quit his job as a doctor to focus on his introduction business instead. So much so was his early fame, that early employment agencies were called “Keian” after him.</p>

<p>Keian’s agency and others got started at that point in Japanese history because the economic conditions were right for them. For an employment agency to be a viable business, there needs to be both a large supply of people seeking employment, and employers seeking labor. By mid-Seventeenth century Japan, such a market for labor was flourishing in response to a shift in Japanese society that had started with the dawn of the Edo Period, fifty years earlier.</p>

<h2 id="the-labour-market-in-the-edo-period">The labour market in the Edo Period</h2>

<p>The Edo period started in 1603 when <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tokugawa_Ieyasu">Ieyasu Tokugawa</a> officially assumed control of Japan. Before he came to power, for the last century and a half, Japan had been in a state of near-constant civil war, leading to much of the country struggling to recover from the ongoing conflict.</p>

<p>Ieyasu chose Edo, modern day Tokyo, to be the center of his government and country. Previous to this, the political and cultural center was located in western Japan, and Edo and the surrounding region had been economically underdeveloped. But Ieyasu enacted policies that encouraged the urbanization of Edo, transforming it from a small castle town with only one hundred houses to a bustling metropolis of over 250,000 people by 1650.</p>

<p>Not only did Ieyasu pursue urbanization of Edo, but his policies encouraged it throughout Japan. The government divided all of Japan into specific regions, granting each to a local Daimyo, a powerful feudal lord, who built their own castles surrounded by Samurai residences. This lead to a growth in the number of artisans and merchants, who in turn needed staff, creating new employment opportunities.</p>

<p>Further driving demand for labour was the government policy of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sankin-k%C5%8Dtai">Sankin-kōtai</a>, which required Daimyo to alternate living between their holdings and Edo on a yearly basis, in an attempt to prevent them from gaining too much power. As it was infeasible for Daimyos to relocate their entire household to Edo, this led to a demand for temporary staff.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, Edo saw a large influx of job seekers. Traditionally in Japan, the eldest son inherited everything: the family name, business, and any assets. Other children were seen as a burden, particularly for poor families. Struggling families practiced “Kuchi-berashi”, literally translated as reducing the number of mouths, where they would place their children to work elsewhere. As Edo flourished, many second sons and daughters of poor rural families journeyed there in search of employment.</p>

<p>Not only did children seek employment in Edo, but so did adults. Often these were people from farming villages who were cast out by their family, or samurai who became masterless after their leader fell in battle.</p>

<p>As these job seekers didn’t have local connections, they sought out someone who could make introductions. With the burgeoning employment market, recruiting as a profession was born in Japan.</p>

<h2 id="employment-in-the-edo-period">Employment in the Edo period</h2>

<p>Employment is a relationship where an employer pays an employee for work. While this has been one type of relationship, there are others where people perform work without receiving compensation, such as slavery or indentured servitude. In the Edo Period, the division between compensated and forced labor was ambiguous, with the term <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A5%89%E5%85%AC">Hōkō</a>, roughly translated as “service” or “apprenticeship”, used to refer to a wide range of employment-like relationships.</p>

<p>The most straightforward kind of Hōkō was temporary labor, where a person tended to be paid daily. Another form was a long term contract of a year or more to work for a samurai house. With this contract, they were usually paid on a monthly or yearly basis, however the salary itself was low as they were also provided room and board while working for the family.</p>

<p>Unpaid apprenticeships also fall under the term Hōkō, whereby a person would work for an artisan or merchant to learn the business. While they usually wouldn’t be directly paid for their work, the expectation was that their previous employer would sponsor their new business.</p>

<p>Children could also be placed out to work under a Hōkō agreement, where they would often learn a craft while being given food, clothes, and a place to live, but not be directly financially compensated. The parents of the children would be given what was effectively an interest free loan: they’d get a lump sum payment when the child started the apprenticeship, which they’d need to pay back when it ended.</p>

<p>While Hōkō tended to refer to agreements of fixed duration, it also encompasses a slavery-like relationship, whereby a whole family was born to serve a wealthy family for their entire life. Near the beginning of the Edo period, this form of permanent Hōkō was banned, and restricted to a fixed period instead (a maximum of 3 years in 1616, but extended it to 10 years in 1625).</p>

<h2 id="recruiter-or-human-trafficker">Recruiter or human trafficker?</h2>

<p>In modern parlance, just like there is a clear divide between employment and forced labour, there is also a clear divide between recruiters who perform employment matchmaking, and human traffickers who provide uncompensated labourers to employers. In the Edo period, the difference between these two professions was murkier than it is today.</p>

<p>For instance, when children ventured into Edo in search of employment and didn’t have any local connections, they would sometimes make use of a local recruiter. These recruiters would sign a contract on behalf of the parents with an employer. While some of these were benevolent, it was easy for them to be exploitative, and force the children to take jobs with poor working conditions.</p>

<p>During this period, the government also established special regions called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Y%C5%ABkaku">Yukaku</a>, which became the only legal area to practice prostitution. The government saw Yukaku as a way of maintaining public order and collecting taxes. To ensure a steady stream of new prostitutes, the government allowed the “apprenticing” of young girls into prostitution. Unlike normal apprenticeships though, where the parents needed to pay back the “loan” that they received, the girl herself became responsible for paying it back. The amount the parents received was so much though, that even if the girl worked her entire life as a prostitute, she could never pay off the debt. The only way out was to have a wealthy man buy out her remaining debt, and become his mistress. Some recruiters took advantage of Yukaku, and effectively bought young girls from poor families in rural areas and sold them to brothels.</p>

<h2 id="first-steps-towards-regulation-of-recruitment">First steps towards regulation of recruitment</h2>

<p>In 1867, the Tokugawa shogunate was finally toppled, ushering in a new era in Japanese history, referred to as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meiji_(era)">the Meiji period</a>. Whereas the previous government had maintained an isolationist stance, the new government embraced western technology and culture, seeking to modernize the country before it was subjugated by western powers.</p>

<p>As part of this modernization, the government abolished the strict class system that divided Japanese into Samurai, peasants, artisans, and merchants, declaring that everyone who had been peasants, artisans, and merchants to be equal. People who were formerly Samurai and Daimyo however were still granted a status as nobles.</p>

<p>With this move modernity, the government sought to regulate the recruiting industry. In 1872, they introduced a requirement that recruiters be licensed and have a guarantor. They also limited the fee a recruiter could receive to be a maximum of 5% of the salary of the introduced employee. This fee was paid by both the employee and employer.</p>

<h2 id="international-attempts-to-ban-private-employment-agencies">International attempts to ban private employment agencies</h2>

<p>As part of the Treaty of Versailles that ended World War I, <a href="https://www.ilo.org/global/about-the-ilo/history/lang--en/index.htm">the International Labour Organization (ILO)</a> was founded to advance social and economic justice through setting international labour standards.</p>

<p>At their very first meeting in 1919, the ILO called on its members to establish free public employment agencies and move towards banning fee charging agencies. As a member of the ILO, Japan created a new law, which required municipal governments to establish public employment agencies and introduced stricter requirements for private employment agencies. While there had been 9,712 private agencies in 1926, the number dwindled to 2,541 by 1934.</p>

<p>The new regulation of the industry also saw stronger controls against unethical recruitment, such as using exaggerated or false claims to recruit people, forcing applications, recruiting women to be prostitutes, blocking applicants’ freedom, and so on.</p>

<p>In April 1938, the public employment agencies that had been operated at a local level were nationalized with a new law. This law also banned private agencies, except for some of the existing agencies, which were allowed to continue while facing even stricter regulations. Many of the private agencies who were banned merged into the national agency. The driving factor for this nationalization was not human rights though, but rather a response to a rapid increase in …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/">https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249818</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 01:19:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[It’s time to remove news from Facebook and Google]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249414">thread link</a>) | @anaxana
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <p>Pay up -- or we’re pulling the plug. </p><p>That’s the approach the news industry should take when it comes to Google and Facebook: Pay for our journalism or we’re banning it from your platforms. </p><p>For too long, journalists have given away their stories for free in exchange for distribution by the duopoly. At best, a story may go viral (rare) or hit the SEO lottery and experience a one-off traffic surge (unsustainable). </p><p>And for that, newsrooms have willingly handed over <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/09/business/media/google-news-industry-antitrust.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share">billions of dollars</a> in ad revenue to the tech giants that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/03/facebooks-siren-call/">threaten</a> their very existence. (Google and Facebook are No. 1 and No. 2 <a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/technology/facebook-ad-revenue-2019-2020">ad platforms</a> in the U.S., respectively).</p><p>The news industry as a whole needs to come together and demand to be fairly compensated for their contributions. Until Facebook and Google agree to pay up, they are simply exploiting journalism under the pretext of democratizing information. </p><p>News drives habit. Habit drives frequency. And frequency drives time spent. In the attention economy (read: ad-driven), news content entices people to come back and stay in platforms’ carefully crafted ecosystems. </p><p>In short, platforms need news. </p><p>Mark Zuckerberg said it himself when Facebook launched its news tab in 2019 (its most recent olive branch to publishers). In a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/25/opinion/sunday/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-news.html">piece for the<em> New York Times</em></a>, the Facebook founder pledged to “support the news industry” and said that journalism today is “more important than ever.” But only <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/10/23/facebook-offer-news-tab-users-pay-some-publishers-their-work/">some of the 200+ publishers</a> involved in the news tab were actually paid for their contributions. &nbsp;</p><p>These platforms are simply using their high-minded mission statements (e.g. Facebook: To “give people the power to build community and bring the world closer together” and Google: To “organize the world’s information”) as a thuggish pretext for exploiting journalism. </p><p>Instead, they should pay a licencing fee or provide a sizable cut of ad revenue to newsrooms that are populating the platforms (Murdoch analogized this to a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/jan/22/rupert-murdoch-facebook-should-pay-news-publishers">carriage fee</a>). &nbsp;</p><p>It’s not enough for them to attempt damage control by <a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/google-paying-publishers-is-more-about-pr-than-the-needs-of-the-news-industry/">spinning up funds</a> claiming to help journalism or offering some – but not all – publishers fees for their contributions. (If you want to know how Google really feels about paying for news, see <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/google-news/google-to-shut-down-news-site-in-spain-over-copyright-fees-idUSL1N0TV0S520141211">how they treated publishers</a> in Spain).</p><p>That’s why we’re building <a href="https://www.forthapp.com/?utm_source=nillium&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_campaign=frontpage">Forth</a>, a news-first platform that pays journalists for their work and offers the audience concise updates with context -- from the reporters they trust. All revenue generated on Forth is shared with our news partners. </p><p>We only allow trusted and credible journalists (vetted by our editorial team) to publish to the platform. It's a one-stop shop for accurate information about what's happening right now. &nbsp;</p><p>It’s one thing for Facebook and Google to out-innovate a slow-to-adapt industry -- it’s another to profit off of the same industry's work with impunity. </p><p>Newsrooms should be mad as hell -- and they don’t have to take it anymore. </p><p>Let’s Go Forth, </p><p>-- Xana</p><p><br><em>Xana O'Neill is the Co-Founder of Forth, a platform for concise updates with context from the reporters you trust.</em></p>
                </div>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249414</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Coup-Proofing the Startup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249332">thread link</a>) | @harporoeder
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>In the middle of an actual, like, actual workplace coup with secret meetings, purges, puppetmasters, frame-ups, leak investigations, and (rumored) slack DM surveillance, I was listening to the bombshell podcast and heard about this book about coup-proofing, and how it ruins teams.
I picked up a copy, and this year I read it.</p>

<p>The book (Caitlin Talmadge / <a href="https://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu/book/9781501700293/the-dictators-army">The Dictator’s Army</a>) is about how coup fears hamstrung management in two wars:
Saddam Hussein’s 8-year failed invasion of Iran, and South Vietnam’s final defense against the North.
This article is about private sector leadership lessons I took from the book.</p>

<p>Writing about private sector leadership on the eve of a plausible military coup seems like peeing into the ocean, but it’s this or doomscrolling and holding in your pee can kill you.</p>

<p>Most management books are aspirational and map out success.
This one is about repeated failure, despite great funding, first-mover advantage and better equipment, through repeated mistakes, and in the public eye.
Nothing that I would know anything about cough.</p>

<p>Startups sub 30 people have a hard time accessing experienced hires who combine domain skill and the ability to work on a team.
There are real reasons for this, and some boil down to something like Saddam’s coup fears.
But if our society plans to continue airlifting cash into small companies, onboarding good middle managers earlier can make more of these bets pay off.</p>

<p>If you prefer a soundtrack, play this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=thbICk05yPk">masterclass on management</a> (from GI Joe’s Cobra Commander) in the background.
It sometimes gets me through the week.</p>

<ol id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#despots-meddle" id="markdown-toc-despots-meddle">Despots meddle</a></li>
  <li><a href="#managing-up" id="markdown-toc-managing-up">Managing up</a></li>
  <li><a href="#demotions-temporary-and-permanent" id="markdown-toc-demotions-temporary-and-permanent">Demotions, temporary and permanent</a></li>
  <li><a href="#combined-arms" id="markdown-toc-combined-arms">Combined arms</a></li>
  <li><a href="#some-people-out-there-dont-have-maps" id="markdown-toc-some-people-out-there-dont-have-maps">Some people out there don’t <em>have</em> maps</a></li>
  <li><a href="#the-butchers-bill" id="markdown-toc-the-butchers-bill">The butcher’s bill</a></li>
  <li><a href="#professional-silence" id="markdown-toc-professional-silence">Professional silence</a></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="despots-meddle">Despots meddle</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>Despotism is a legitimate mode of government in dealing with barbarians, provided the end be their improvement, and the means justified by actually effecting that end.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Liberty, as a principle, has no application to any state of things anterior to the time when mankind have become capable of being improved by free and equal discussion.
– JS Mill</p>
</blockquote>

<p>By inference, if you’re not hiring barbarians and / or they don’t need improvement, or your team is capable of discussion, consider a lighter-weight leadership style.</p>

<p>‘Despot’ also means bronze age feudal landowners or the heir apparent of Byzantium, but we haven’t had those for a while.
Adaptive reuse of the term in revolutionary France gave the term its modern meaning:
an absolute ruler who governs without restraint by the law.
See also ‘frondeur’.</p>

<p>When growing teams take on more complex goals but don’t update their management, they encounter pathologies of delegation –
senior leadership who isn’t sure how to solve problems using middle managers, who give them the wrong length leash.
This is the 10 person to 30 person growth spurt.
Good companies outgrow it this <em>if</em> they survive.</p>

<p>Here’s what that looked like in Iraq:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>decision-making at the senior levels of the Iraqi military revolved more around the fear of what Saddam might do than what the Iranians might do.<sup id="fnref:senior-fear" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:senior-fear">1</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>by the middle of the war, Saddam was making a serious effort to inform himself about military matters in order to understand what was happening. However, Saddam was the only decision maker,<sup id="fnref:educate" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:educate">2</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Technocratic middle managers were spending most of their energy undoing their leader’s bad decisions, rather than fighting and winning.
There’s a spectrum between ‘own worst enemy’ and ‘annoying bandwidth bottleneck’, but new managers generally are on it somewhere.</p>

<p>Over-centralization of authority sends a message that people shouldn’t act on their own, which paralyzes your org.
Note that I’m not arguing against hierarchical authority or a clear chain of command, but rather against authority all concentrating at the top, making it impossible for middle managers to do their jobs.
In Vietnam:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>few officers who had come up in the Diem system were willing to do anything “in the absence of detailed orders.”<sup id="fnref:detailed" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:detailed">3</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Centralization also hamstrings the flexibility of a large team to adapt to new information.
Top leaders, often lacking domain skill or up-to-date information, are best at ‘do nothing without asking me’ orders that trap middle managers in bad positions.
In one case:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Because Saddam had decreed that units were not allowed to cede any ground, the Iraqi defense was poorly coordinated and ineffective, eventually inducing panic.<sup id="fnref:panic" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:panic">4</a></sup> …
Iraqi officers in the field lacked the authority to redeploy forward troops or to call on reserves.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>And because the dictators aren’t an expert in any part of the organization, lack the attention to focus on everything at once, and aren’t accountable to anyone, they have zero memory.
In one case in Vietnam, President Thieu’s personal intervention not only disrupted the existing strategy, but he had forgotten by the next day that he’d given the order.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>sudden change in orders from an uninformed Thieu was a disaster, resulting in neither a robust defense of the city nor a clean withdrawal.<sup id="fnref:sudden-change" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:sudden-change">6</a></sup> … Amazingly … Hue’s abandonment apparently came as a surprise to President Thieu<sup id="fnref:abandonment" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:abandonment">7</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unaccountable, illogical plans from inexpert leaders create hills to die on, in some cases literally.
They also come through unusual channels (because hands-on leaders prioritize fast action).
Unusual channels = coordination and preparation impossible for middle managers.
In one case in South Vietnam, a general:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>personally interceded at all levels, sometimes going so far as to personally issue orders by radio to individual brigade commanders without notifying the division operations center. Both Giai and his division advisers often learned of new orders only as they were being carried out.<sup id="fnref:all-levels" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:all-levels">8</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>By comparison, the North Vietnamese had good delegation and sane command structures in place.
From an internal document, they valued:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“unanimity of thought from the top to the bottom regarding the opportunity we faced and the tactics to be employed” but significant room for commanders to execute their plans<sup id="fnref:unanimity" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:unanimity">9</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>After the American revolution, George III was having a conversation with his American portraitist Benjamin West; he heard Washington was going to resign his commission and ‘return to his farm’.
The King was like ‘ha pull the other one’, recognizing that giving up power is very hard, and said something like ‘<em>if</em> he does it I take back everything I said about the guy.’
The point is that accepting the limits to authority is hard, but also critical for good leaders.</p>

<h2 id="managing-up">Managing up</h2>

<p>One of the lessons of 2020 is probably that sometimes the only person in the room who can stop a bad outcome is a middle manager,
and often they can only do it by managing up, not through direct action.</p>

<p>Middle managers are frequently in situations where their domain skills are better than senior leadership –
either because they’re technocrats with domain skills,
or because they’re dealing with the problem day-to-day and have better information, or both.</p>

<p>We still get shouted down a lot, resulting in waste:
of money, of time, of resources, of opportunities, of morale.
In a war it can be lives.</p>

<p>We speak out a few times but eventually converge to inaction as your <a href="https://danluu.com/wat/">wtfs trail off</a>.
We give up because we’re tired, but that’s not all of it:
We stop arguing because when a leader experiences argument as dissent, their reactions are unpredictable and poison the team.</p>

<p>The way around this way of thinking is to
(1) make very sure that you’re very right when you pick a fight with your boss,
(2) fight for better delegation, not just a correct decision this one time.
And (3) remember that if you succeed, things get permanently better; these are hard fights but companies need them to grow.</p>

<p>Middle managers are the only people who have the authority and connections to fight these fights.
That’s why they leak, that’s why they manage up.
The organization will fail if we don’t.
Employees depend on companies to put food on the table; you do have a moral obligation to help your employer not fail (if you can) (barring circumstances like if <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hn1VxaMEjRU">you’ve looked at these caps recently</a>).</p>

<p>I saw a <a href="https://twitter.com/FutureDocs/status/938173926953443328">JAMA article</a> about ‘professional silence’ by doctors.
Silence is not golden when an important argument is being suppressed.</p>

<p>Senior technocrats have a surprising amount of power when they align their story and band together. For Saddam, years into the war:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Iraqi generals blamed Saddam’s military organizational practices for both sets of losses, raising a serious danger of overthrow from within<sup id="fnref:blame" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:blame">10</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Because his leadership style was in conflict with their technical skills.
He punished losses in ways that deterred ground commanders from requesting backup, creating a losing cycle:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Saddam put great pressure on Iraqi commanders on the ground to avoid losses, which led them not to report failures. Withholding losses from reports and thus not receiving reinforcements or other support left commanders in impossible combat conditions. However, this was better than reporting their failures and suffering execution.<sup id="fnref:pressure" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:pressure">11</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The command-and-control system was incapable of transmitting the true tactical situation. Senior Iraqi officers later noted that they often got more timely information from the media than they did from their own commanders at the front.<sup id="fnref:media" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:media">12</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>In Vietnam, General Phu, a technocrat middle manager who had been brought in to fix the South Vietnamese army’s problems, tried to use his authority to salvage a bad campaign and was talked down.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Phu, who previously had enjoyed an excellent reputation as commander of the 1st Division, expressed grave reservations about the operation to those around him, complaining that he had done it only because of Thieu’s order<sup id="fnref:reservations" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:reservations">13</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>President Thieu’s realtime intervention, leading to a bad loss, demoralized him and he was never able to lead again:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Thieu’s absurd order to withdraw immediately from the Central Highlands essentially caused another corps commander, General Phu, …</p></blockquote></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html">https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249332</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Keep Data Consistency During Database Migration]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249208">thread link</a>) | @wb14123
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.binwang.me/2020-11-29-Keep-Data-Consistency-During-Database-Migration.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.binwang.me/2020-11-29-Keep-Data-Consistency-During-Database-Migration.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="article_content">
<article id="post">
  <header>
    
    
      <p>Posted on 29 Nov 2020, tagged <code>database</code><code>distributed system</code><code>consistency</code></p>
    
  </header>

  <p>When a system has been live for a long time, it’s not rare to use newer technologies to improve performance, maintainability, or add new features. One of such changes can be which database to use. This can be the most difficult kind of change. During the migration, there are two data sources, which makes it a distributed system. Make data consistent under a distributed system is very hard and can easily go wrong. In this article, we will explore a way to keep the data consistent during the migration, and maintain a low downtime at the same time.</p>

<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>

<p>There are some requirements in order to use the way described in this article:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The source database support capture data change (CDC) method like MySQL bin log.</li>
  <li>The source database can be dumped with a consistent view and mark the position in data change logs.</li>
  <li>The target database support ACID transactions.</li>
  <li>Both source and target database support read and write permission control.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="steps">Steps</h2>

<p>There are two basic ideas behind the steps:</p>

<ol>
  <li>The clients only write to one of the databases at a given time. So we can avoid distributed transaction which is error prone and slow.</li>
  <li>We make the switch of database by setup the database permissions. It’s faster than switch from client code and easier to make sure to switch all the clients.</li>
</ol>

<p>Here are the detailed steps:</p>

<h3 id="1-dump-the-source-database-to-target-database">1. Dump the source database to target database</h3>

<p>First, we need to dump the source database with a consistent view. And mark the position we’ve dumped. For example, in MySQL, you can use <code>mysqldump</code> with <code>--master-data</code> to dump the database with a bin log position. (<a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/mysqldump.html#option_mysqldump_master-data">Document about the usage</a>). After we get all the data from source database, we can insert them into the target database.</p>

<p>Since this is the first step, it’s very easy to handle failure: just start again from beginning. So it’s very important to capture any error while import the dumped data.</p>

<h3 id="2-capture-changes-from-source-to-target">2. Capture changes from source to target</h3>

<p>The next step is to use the capture data changes from the source database. For example, in MySQL, you can use <a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/binary-log.html">bin log</a> to capture the changes and insert them to the target database. Since we have the start position from last step, we know where to start parse and import the changes.</p>

<p>It’s very important to keep order of the changes while importing. So it’s better to use only one process to parse and import the changes. This part is challenging: the performance matters here. <strong>The time to sync all the changes is the downtime we need for migration</strong>.</p>

<p>We also need to make sure we don’t miss any changes or import any changes multiple times even there are system failures. So it’s very important to record the change log position. It’s convenience to write the position into the target database with the same transaction that imports the data. So the position will be synced with the data we imported.</p>

<h3 id="3-deny-writes-to-the-target-database-from-clients">3. Deny writes to the target database from clients</h3>

<p>The easy way to keep data consistency is to have a single source of truth. Until now, we are using the source database as the source of truth and sync changes to the target database. We don’t want to mess up the target database with other writes. So we need to setup the target database permission to deny all the writes from clients. For example, in MySQL, you can grant only <code>select</code> permission to the table for the clients and deny other operations. We allow the read permission so that we can compare the read results at the next step.</p>

<h3 id="4-modify-the-clients-to-read-and-write-both-databases">4. Modify the clients to read and write both databases</h3>

<p>The next step is to make the clients to read and write both source and target databases.</p>

<p>We want to read/write source database first. Use this result if there is no permission error, use the read/write result from target database otherwise.</p>

<p>The read/write to target database has two purposes:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Before switch to the target database, we can verify the target database works as expected by compare read results and write operations. Note that the target database may have lag to sync up, so the results may not always the same. But we can have an understanding of the correctness based on the percentage of same results.</li>
  <li>After we switch to the target database, the read/write results will be used as the real results.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>If you want to make sure the target database can handle the load, it’s a good idea to allow read/write to the target database for a while .But it’s just as a verification, the data in the target database will not be consistent after that. So after we verify the target database can handle the traffic, we need to cleanup the target database and start from step 1 again.</strong> (We don’t need to modify the client code during the steps).</p>

<p>For the error handling, there are two key points:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Only use target database result if there is permission error from source database. Throw other errors from source database.</li>
  <li>Ignore errors for the target database if the result is not used but make sure to log them, so that it will not affect the current operation while also make sure we don’t have errors before the switch.</li>
</ol>

<p>The client code would be like this:</p>

<div><div>
  <div><pre><span> <a href="#n1" name="n1">1</a></span>db_operation() {
<span> <a href="#n2" name="n2">2</a></span>  try {
<span> <a href="#n3" name="n3">3</a></span>    source_result = source_db_operation()
<span> <a href="#n4" name="n4">4</a></span>  } catch (PermissionException e) {
<span> <a href="#n5" name="n5">5</a></span>    return target_db_operation()
<span> <a href="#n6" name="n6">6</a></span>  }
<span> <a href="#n7" name="n7">7</a></span>  async {
<span> <a href="#n8" name="n8">8</a></span>    // do the following things async so it will not impact the performance
<span> <a href="#n9" name="n9">9</a></span>    try {
<span><strong><a href="#n10" name="n10">10</a></strong></span>      target_result = target_db_operation()
<span><a href="#n11" name="n11">11</a></span>      compare_result(source_result, target_result)
<span><a href="#n12" name="n12">12</a></span>    } catch (Exception e) {
<span><a href="#n13" name="n13">13</a></span>      log_error(e)
<span><a href="#n14" name="n14">14</a></span>    }
<span><a href="#n15" name="n15">15</a></span>  }
<span><a href="#n16" name="n16">16</a></span>  return source_result
<span><a href="#n17" name="n17">17</a></span>}
</pre></div>
</div>
</div>

<h3 id="5-deny-access-to-the-source-database-from-clients-and-wait-for-changes-to-by-synced">5. Deny access to the source database from clients and wait for changes to by synced</h3>

<p>After we are confident with the read and write to the target database, we can make the switch. We switch the database by change the database permissions. First, we deny all the access to the source database from clients. Then we wait for the changes to be full synced to the target database. During this time, the system is down. So how fast the changes are synced from source database to target database determines how much down time it will be.</p>

<h3 id="6-allow-write-to-target-database">6. Allow write to target database</h3>

<p>After the target database is fully synced, we can enable the target database permission for all the clients. After this, the system should be online again and the database is fully switched over.</p>

<h3 id="7-optional-fallback-to-source-database-if-anything-goes-wrong">7. Optional: Fallback to source database if anything goes wrong</h3>

<p>It’s good if everything works well so far. But that may not always the case. Maybe the target database cannot handle the new traffic (that’s why it’s important to test it in step 4). In this case, we need fallback to the source database.</p>

<p>If it’s fine to lost committed data during the migration time, it would be relatively easy to fallback:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Allow access to the source database. After this, the clients should be using the source database again.</li>
  <li>Cleanup the target database and start from the beginning.</li>
</ol>

<p>If it’s critical to save the committed data and make sure they are consistent, then before step 5, we should setup a mechanism to capture changes from target database to source database, and mark the change position after step 6. Then the fallback steps would be:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Deny all the writes to target database.</li>
  <li>Sync from target database to source database (make sure to stop it after fully synced).</li>
  <li>Allow access to the source database.</li>
  <li>Cleanup the target database and start from the beginning again.</li>
</ol>

<p>The sync from target database to source database is very dangerous and hard to test, so it’s really important to test the target database can handle the operations in step 4.</p>

<h3 id="8-cleanup-client-code">8. Cleanup client code</h3>

<p>Once the database is switched to the target database, we can cleanup the code that access the source database. Then the database is fully migrated and you can enjoin it!</p>

</article>







<!-- MathJax -->




</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.binwang.me/2020-11-29-Keep-Data-Consistency-During-Database-Migration.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249208</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 23:43:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Making Playstation 1 Modchips (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248660">thread link</a>) | @cwaffles
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
    <article>

        

        <section>
            <p>When I was young I owned a PlayStation 1 (PS1). It was one of the first, if not the first, game consoles I owned and it had a profound effect on my future. </p>

<p>I can trace the history of how I got involved in computers back to playing and modding video games. While I wasn't smart enough to mod game consoles when I was young, my dad wasn't bad at it. He modded my PS1 to have a little switch in the back that would allow it to play burnt games. They say the apple doesn't fall far from the tree. </p>

<p>Fast-forward to today and I no longer have my original PS1. I remember some games wouldn't load anymore and I had gotten a PS2. So why keep an old console? Turns out the answer is nostalgia and memories. You miss what you don't have anymore.</p>

<p>Recently a friend gifted me a PS1. And so then the journey begins, how do I mod this thing? </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you are looking for them I am selling <a href="http://rover.ebay.com/rover/1/711-53200-19255-0/1?icep_ff3=2&amp;pub=5575378759&amp;campid=5338273189&amp;customid=&amp;icep_item=223024408143&amp;ipn=psmain&amp;icep_vectorid=229466&amp;kwid=902099&amp;mtid=824&amp;kw=lg&amp;toolid=11111">flashed, prewired modchips</a>. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Very simply, the principles behind PS1 DRM work as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Sony baked (not the technical term) strings (i.e. <code>SCEA</code>, <code>SCEI</code>, <code>SCEE</code>, or in rare cases <code>SCEW</code>) into official PS1 games in locations which cannot be replicated by a regular reader. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XUwSOfQ1D3c">This video</a> and <a href="http://www.psxdev.net/forum/viewtopic.php?t=128">this post</a> discuss it reasonably well.  </li>
<li>The CD drive controller looks for those strings to identify a disc as official. Once the controller decides that the disc is/isn't official, the main CPU reads this decision and acts accordingly.  </li>
<li>If the string can't be found or is garbled, the PS1 knows the disc isn't an <strong>authentic</strong> PS1 game. However, because the PS1 needs to account for disc read errors, there's a good amount of leeway in what passes the authenticity check.  </li>
<li>Because region <small>(<strong>A</strong> for America, <strong>I</strong> for Japan, <strong>E</strong> for Europe, and <strong>W</strong> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_Yaroze">Net Yaroze</a>)</small> as well as authenticity are rolled into one string, Sony kills two birds with one stone here and achieves region locking as well as copy protection. </li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you want a real in-depth discussion you can read <a href="http://www.oldcrows.net/mcc2.html">the original posts by The Old Crow</a> or the <a href="https://problemkaputt.de/psx-spx.htm#cdromprotectionmodchips">No$PSX documentation page</a> or this <a href="http://psx-scene.com/forums/f10/psx-modchip-faq-64110/">Modchip FAQ</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>PSX modchips work by electrically stifling the output originally generated by whatever CD is inside the drive and then injecting a new, faked signal into the CD microcontroller. This causes the PS1 to believe that whatever disc is inside is legitimate and proceed to boot up. </p>

<p>Later on Sony added more complicated checks like:</p>

<ul>
<li>Checking for the magic strings during the game instead of at boot </li>
<li>Changing the overall process to make it more difficult to bypass by simply emitting the correct strings.</li>
</ul>

<p>However, modern modchips already deal with this. Modchips that work under these updated circumstances are known as "stealth modchips" because the console shouldn't be able to detect them at all. </p>



<p>The first "open source" modchip was reverse engineered by a guy named "The Old Crow". Surprisingly, The Old Crow specializes in electronic music synthesizers, not hacking video game consoles. It's from his modchip that most other modchips are derived from in some sense. He originally reverse engineered a commercial PS1 modchip that was designed by a western engineer working for a Chinese company. </p>

<p>Today, there are three main modchips which are still used by the community today.</p>

<p>The modchips include:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide/mm3/">Multimode 3 (MM3)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide/mayumi-v4/">Mayumi v4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee">PSNee</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The three have their pros and cons but generally they can be summarized as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>MM3 is the most common PS1 modchip seen/used today. Its only real downside is that it uses an internal oscillator which can become out of sync with the oscillator used by the CD drive. If this happens you simply need to reboot your console to try reading again.  </p></li>
<li><p>Mayumi v4 attempts to use the oscillator used by the CD drive. This reduces the chance of the oscillator sync issue from happening; however, Mayumi v4 is considered a bit difficult to install. </p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee">PSNee</a> is an open source modchip originally written by <a href="https://assemblergames.com/threads/psnee-a-stealth-modchip-for-all-ps1-models.57907/">TheFrietMan</a>. Development on it was <a href="http://www.psxdev.net/forum/viewtopic.php?t=1262">later continued by others</a> and it appears to work rather well on all Playstation 1/PSOne models. Based on the code I believe it attempts to infer where the PS1 is in the boot process to begin injecting fake <code>SCEX</code> strings. Unfortunately PSNee is complicated to install. The provided diagrams are atrocious and nowhere near as simple as the available diagrams for MM3 and Mayumi. I worked out <a href="https://gist.github.com/ColdHeat/be633b7eb6e25758ec80ae0115c1887a">the pinout for the Attiny45</a> but I ended up going with MM3 and Mayumi because it's easier. </p></li>
</ul>



<blockquote>
  <p>If you want them I am selling <a href="http://rover.ebay.com/rover/1/711-53200-19255-0/1?icep_ff3=2&amp;pub=5575378759&amp;campid=5338273189&amp;customid=&amp;icep_item=223024408143&amp;ipn=psmain&amp;icep_vectorid=229466&amp;kwid=902099&amp;mtid=824&amp;kw=lg&amp;toolid=11111">flashed, prewired modchips</a>. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>It's generally pretty easy to make a PS1 modchip provided you have the right tools. In this tutorial we will focus on making MM3 or Mayumi v4 modchips.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>While I do have an Arduino, I prefer to use the MM3 and Mayumi chips over PSNee. If you want to make a PSNee modchip, you can follow the <a href="http://www.instructables.com/id/Program-an-ATtiny-with-Arduino/">instructions here</a> to flash the <a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee/blob/master/PsNee.ino">.ino file</a> to your Attiny. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>You will need:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=PIC12F508+DIP">Microchip PIC12F508</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2tfdeP0">PICkit 3</a>
<ul><li>Also download and install <a href="http://www.microchip.com/mplab/mplab-x-ide">MPLAB IPE</a> from the MPLAB X IDE package. </li></ul></li>
<li>Some kind of <a href="https://amzn.to/2llKUG7">wiring &amp; breadboard</a> to connect the PIC to to the PICkit.</li>
<li>HEX codes for the modchip of your choice (provided below).</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Many tutorials call for the PIC12C508. This is an old model and continuing to use them is unnecessary unless you have them stockpiled. HEX codes that work for the 12C will work for the 12F. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>To begin you should first look your IC and determine which leg is which. The leg nearest the imprinted circle is Pin 1. The leg opposite it is Pin 8. </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/pic12f508-2.JPG" alt="This is a DIP chip. I accidentally got SOIC-8 (i.e. surface mount) and had to solder my chip to a breadboard but generally you can avoid that"></p>

<p>You can plug this into a bread board and then wire it into the Pickit according to the following diagrams. You want to match the following (the rest are unused for now):</p>

<ul>
<li>PICKit 1 ⟷ IC 4 (V<sub>PP</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 2 ⟷ IC 1 (V<sub>DD</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 3 ⟷ IC 8 (V<sub>SS</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 4 ⟷ IC 7 (ICSPDAT)</li>
<li>PICKit 5 ⟷ IC 6 (ICSPCLK)</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/pickit-12f508-1.jpg" alt="PICKit 3 on the left, PIC12F508 on the right"></p>

<p>Once you've properly wired up the chip, connect the PICKit to your computer and start MPLAB IPE. Under <code>Device</code> select <code>PIC12F508</code>. </p>

<p>Go into <code>Settings &gt; Advanced Mode</code>. The default password for <code>Advanced Mode</code> is <code>microchip</code>. I don't recommend changing it, not sure why the option is even available. </p>

<p>Go into the <code>Power</code> tab on the left and enable <code>Power Target Circuit from Tool</code>.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-8.39.15-PM.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Go back to the <code>Operate</code> tab and hit <code>Connect</code>.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-8.40.54-PM.png" alt=""></p>

<p>From here download the appropriate HEX code for your chip and console. They are different per console region. </p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3USA.HEX">MM3 for American Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3EUR.HEX">MM3 for European Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3JAP.HEX">MM3 for Japanese Consoles</a></li>
</ul>

<p>You can also use Mayumi v4 on the PIC12F508 if you choose.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-usa4.hex">MayumiV4 for American Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-eu4.hex">MayumiV4 for European Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-jap4.hex">MayumiV4 for Japanese Consoles</a></li>
</ul>

<p>In the <code>Source</code> file, select your hex code. </p>

<p>Hit the big <code>Program</code> button. </p>

<p>You should see something similar to the following text:</p>

<pre><code>2018-06-20 20:48:02 -0400 - Loading hex file. Please wait...  
Loading code from /Users/kchung/Repositories/PsNeePy.wiki/hexcodes/mm3/MM3USA.HEX...  
2018-06-20 20:48:03 -0400 - Hex file loaded successfully.

2018-06-20 20:48:20 -0400 - Programming...

Device Erased...

Programming...

The following memory area(s) will be programmed:  
program memory: start address = 0x0, end address = 0x1e7  
configuration memory  
Programming/Verify complete  
2018-06-20 20:48:25 -0400 - Programming complete  
</code></pre>

<p>If you'd like, you can hit the <code>Verify</code> button to make sure that your flash was correct. Your output should look something like the following:</p>

<pre><code>2018-06-20 20:50:10 -0400 - Verifying...

Verifying...

The following memory areas(s) will be verified:  
program memory: start address = 0x0, end address = 0x1ff  
configuration memory  
User Id Memory

Verification successful.  
2018-06-20 20:50:13 -0400 - Verify complete  
</code></pre>

<p>From here you can follow online diagrams for soldering your chip to the PSX that you own. I personally used <a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide">William Quade's excellent diagrams</a> and think you should as well.   </p>



<p>While looking at all these modchips, I figured it would be nice to read and write Python code instead of Assembly and C code so I started working on porting PSNee to Python. </p>

<p>By using <a href="https://micropython.org/">MicroPython</a> and an <a href="https://amzn.to/2K4HdTq">ESP8266</a> we can actually create a modchip that we can remotely update and modify through the <a href="https://amzn.to/2K4HdTq">ESP8266</a>'s WiFi.  </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/IMG_1084.jpg" alt="Effectively the very first WiFi enabled PS1!"></p>

<p>In the above photo (SCPH-7501), the ESP8266 is on the top left with the headers face up. The wires connect to the headers and route under the CD drive to a breadboard on the bottom right. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The breadboard has wires that are soldered to the correct MM3 points and then labeled with the corresponding pin number. By using this breadboard I can test modchips that I make much faster than soldering to the board over and over again. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>My modchip (named PsNeePy) is available on Github: <br>
<a href="https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy">https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy</a></p>

<p>While my test console is quite bad at reading discs and the console rarely boots into games, the modchip does work. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For the most part (ignoring stealth functionality), modchips are known to be working once you reach the black Playstation logo screen as this indicates that the CPU considers the game authentic. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>However, because the code is based off an older version of PSNee, stealth functionality does not seem to work on some newer PS1 revisions.</p>

<p>I mostly created this as a proof of concept and I'm unlikely to maintain it very much. While I don't recommend using my modchip, I hope that the community adopts it and helps improve it. Despite being a dead console, the PSX community is fairly active. </p>

<p>With <a href="https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy">PsNeePy</a>, you can remotely update the ESP8266 over WiFi, debug remotely, and also reset the chip easily. Having spent many hours working on the PS1 at this point, a more modern experience is quite refreshing. </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-21-at-2.47.33-AM.png" alt="Remotely controlling the modchip"></p>

<p>Thanks to an anonymous friend for my PS1, Sharan for fixing my PS1, <a href="https://quade.co/">William Quade</a> for the excellent diagrams, AssemblerGames for having good information despite not accepting me into the forum, and PSXDEV for answering some of my questions.</p>
        </section>

        

    </article>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248660</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 22:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Run a Ponzi Scheme for Tech People]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 382 | Comments 187 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248563">thread link</a>) | @nish1500
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article role="article" itemscope="" itemprop="blogPost" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">
<center>
<header>


</header>
</center>
<p>More people are online than ever before. More people are desperate than ever before. Learn how to use that 👇</p>
<h2>Is this the right course for me?</h2>
<p>Good question. My courses are NOT for everyone. You need to be a good fit. This is the prefect course for you if you check any of the following boxes:</p>
<ol><li>You like having a business card that says <strong>I’m CEO bitch</strong></li><li>You dream of petting elephants in a Southeast asian monarchy with a questionable human rights record</li><li>doTerra didn’t work out</li><li>You have $100 to spare</li></ol>
<h2>Basics first. What is a Ponzi scheme?</h2>
<p>Say I managed to save $500 from my day job. I find 5 people who begrudgingly agree to give me $100 because I told them I can turn it into $200 in a month. I give them $200 each at the end of the month.</p>
<p>Now, I am <strong>out of savings</strong> but I have 5 people who doubled their money in a month with no hard work at all.</p>
<p>I use their story as an example to show people that my idea works. Now it’s easier to find people who pay me. I take $100 from 10 more people, wait for a month, and use the proceeds ($1,000) to give $200 each to 5 of those people.</p>
<p>Now I have a <strong>proven business model</strong>, and a good number of people who will vouch for my method. I use the proceeds from each successive group to pay the previous cohort of people.</p>
<h2>But this is a tech community. Not Wall Street.</h2>
<p>A Ponzi scheme can be used in any part of your life. Let’s see how we can use this around us today:</p>
<h3>Example 1: Sell a Course</h3>
<p>Create a twitter account and manage to get 100 followers through a combination of spamming famous people, dad jokes, and paid followers. Write this blog post and share it:</p>
<blockquote><p>How I got 100 followers in my first week with no hard work at all.</p></blockquote>
<p>Over the next week 50 people will read your tweet / post and start following you. These people are curious, and it costs them nothing to follow you. 50 followers isn’t much but you get to write another exciting post:</p>
<blockquote><p>How I increased my twitter following by 50% in less than 3 days.</p></blockquote>
<p>Now people are intrigued, and you have 500 more followers. Write another post.</p>
<blockquote><p>How I got 500 followers overnight</p></blockquote>
<p>Does it remind you of something – like a <strong>for</strong> loop? When iteration = 5, <strong>sell a course</strong> on Gumroad.</p>
<h3>Example 2: Become a Digital Nomad</h3>
<p>Quit your job in Colorado and move to Thailand because a long-haired guy and his hot girlfriend shared a beach selfie telling you how they are living the digital nomad life, and how you can do it too. Best $100 you ever spent.</p>
<p>Except, it didn’t work out (teaching English in Thailand only pays so much), and now you’re stuck in Koh Samui running out of money and ideas. Go to the nearest beach, take a picture of your laptop with sunset in the background and write this blog post:</p>
<blockquote><p>How quitting my 9-5 job and moving to Thailand was the best thing I ever did.</p></blockquote>
<p>Congrats, now people are listening. Create a course, somehow manage to make $1,000. Now use that $1,000 to buy some food, rent a moped, and share more selfies about your perfect life. It’s a massive market – these regular folks working boring jobs in rich white countries who believe in the good intentions of strangers on the internet. Exploit them.</p>
<h3>Example 3: No Code, Only Money</h3>
<p>Aren’t you sick of all these I’m-so-smart programmers with their statically-typed-languages-are-fast on HackerNews? When you came across this priceless <strong>No Code</strong> directory of tools you realized it was the next big thing. You spend $100 on the site, and use the knowledge to create a form (using a form builder) and a Zapier hook that emails people on new responses. Genius idea. You try to sell it for $500. No buyers. It’s all your fault.</p>
<p>Time to pivot. You create a <strong>No Code</strong> website to teach people how to make money using No Code tools (like you did, haha) such as <strong>Airtable</strong> and <strong>Zapier</strong>.</p>
<p><em>Note: the lesson here is NOT that you can make money by creating a valuable tool like Airtable using code. No.</em></p>
<p>Between your <strong>No Code website</strong> and <strong>No Code podcast</strong> you manage to make $500. You take a screenshot of your Stripe dashboard and share it with the world. Now you are hot shit. Going from 0 to $500 was the hard bit; going from $500 to $5,000 is easier.</p>
<h2>FAQ</h2>
<h4>Are places like Indiehacker and Gumroad and just enablers of Ponzi schemes?</h4>
<p>Of course not. There are some amazing people there working on cool new ideas. They write comments here and there, and make a post once in a while, but mostly it’s busy work building something. Most such communities are started by a group of well-intentioned people, who slowly become the minority.</p>
<p>Not all courses are scams. I bought one on Gumroad yesterday. Except it wasn’t teaching me how to grow my twitter following; it was teaching me a cool programming language that I’ve been meaning to learn for a while.</p>
<h4>Will I be sharing fake milestones and fake Stripe dashboards?</h4>
<p>You didn’t read anything, did you? No, you will actually get 500 new followers, and actually make $5,000. The ones who won’t are the suckers who buy your course.</p>
<h4>Won’t people call me out when they buy my course and fail to become rich?</h4>
<p>That is the best part – they will blame <strong>themselves</strong>. You made money. The people who gave you Twitter testimonials apparently made money. If people fail they will think it’s them. In fact, sell them your <strong>Advanced Course</strong>.</p>
<h4>How do I convince people I am legit?</h4>
<p>Tell people you are open to <strong>speaking engagements</strong>. Talk about the number of <strong>trees you planted</strong> this month. Tell them someone else forced you to post on IH or HN because of how great your content is. Talk about <strong>failure</strong> so you seem relatable. Act <strong>quirky</strong> on Twitter.</p>
<h4>Wait, are you writing this just to make me a part of your Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<p>Do you really think I am going to spend half a Sunday writing and formatting this long-ass post (instead of using my magic formula to make money for myself) for any reason other than the goodness of my heart?</p>
<p>Of course not. I swear. I just want to share my success with the world, help the little guy, Build in Public™, like every other ‘How I Made $5,000’ post. Pinky promise.</p>
<h4>I am sold. So, how DO I run a Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<p>You see, my goal in sharing my success here is to see <strong>YOU grow</strong>. Just like the guy who sold me into his Ponzi scheme – I am only paying it forward 🙏🏼.</p>
<p>I do like to charge <strong>$100</strong> JUST to ensure that only serious people become a part of my Ponzi-family. We call it an investment.</p>
<p>Enough talk. Signup here:</p>
<p><a href="https://nish.formcrafts.com/ponzi-scheme" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://nish.formcrafts.com/ponzi-scheme</a></p>
<h4>How do I NOT run a Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<ol><li>Look around you for problems people would pay to resolve.</li><li>Create something of value.</li><li>Have fun while you do it.</li></ol>
<p>Discuss on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248563" target="_blank">HN</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nish_crafts" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">@nish_crafts</a></p>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248563</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 22:10:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Haskell runtime is what sets it apart from the competition]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248522">thread link</a>) | @harporoeder
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://harporoeder.com/posts/haskell-runtime/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://harporoeder.com/posts/haskell-runtime/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>This post is substantially directed to non Haskellers. Haskell frequently appears on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/news">hackernews</a>, or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/">/r/programming</a> but the content is commonly evangelizing some aspect of functional programming, strong types, and purity.</p>
<p>Haskell embodies all those things, but the practicality does not come from strongly typed functional programming. Other strongly typed functional languages such as <a href="https://ocaml.org/">OCaml</a> exist, but many aspects are <a href="https://github.com/ocaml-multicore/ocaml-multicore">not nearly as mature</a>. Here I explore some of the lesser talked about features that greatly contribute to the Haskells power, performance, and convenience.</p>
<p>Numerous Haskell implementation exist (<a href="https://github.com/IntelLabs/flrc">FLRC</a>, <a href="https://github.com/UU-ComputerScience/uhc">UHC</a>, <a href="http://repetae.net/computer/jhc/">JHC</a>) however we will specifically go over <a href="https://www.haskell.org/ghc/">GHC</a> which is by far the most used, and powerful.</p>
<h2 id="asynchronous-exceptions">Asynchronous exceptions</h2>
<p>In almost all languages exceptions are thrown by the executing thread. In <a href="https://www.cplusplus.com/">C++</a> throwing an exception would look something like this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="c++"><span>void</span> <span>doAction</span>() {
    <span>if</span> (<span>1</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span>) {
        <span>throw</span> std<span>::</span>runtime_error(<span>"the impossible happened"</span>);
    }
}

<span>try</span> {
    doAction();
} <span>catch</span> (<span>const</span> std<span>::</span>exception<span>&amp;</span> err) {
    cout <span>&lt;&lt;</span> err.what() <span>&lt;&lt;</span> std<span>::</span>endl;
}
</code></pre></div><p>In Haskell <em>any</em> thread can throw an exception to another thread. Let’s spawn a thread and then immediately kill it by throwing an exception from outside of it. No modification of the thread or function itself is required.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="haskell"><span>threadId</span> <span>&lt;-</span> forkIO myLongRunningAction
<span>throwTo</span> threadId <span>MyException</span>
</code></pre></div><p>This capability ends of being incredibly powerful. All of the sudden features that might normally be implemented as fundamental properties of the language can now be expressed within it.</p>
<p>An example of this is <code>timeout :: Int -&gt; IO a -&gt; IO (Maybe a)</code>. Timeout takes a timeout in microseconds, an action to run, and may or may not return a result depending on if the action completes in time. Internally it spawns a thread with a timer, and should a deadline be hit issues an exception to the other threads computation.</p>
<p>In a language like <a href="https://golang.org/">Go</a> a goroutine cannot be killed externally. A common pattern emerges where authors manually wait on channels to ensure can be controlled:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="go"><span>stop</span> <span>:=</span> make(<span>chan</span> <span>bool</span>)

<span>go</span> <span>func</span>() {
    <span>for</span> {
        <span>select</span> {
        <span>case</span> <span>&lt;-</span> <span>stop</span>:
            <span>return</span>
        }
    }
}()

<span>stop</span> <span>&lt;-</span> <span>true</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Should a mistake be made resources will leak, and more complicated control flows must be continually duplicated. Even killing a thread utilizing owned resources such as sockets is safe in Haskell because of constructs built on <code>bracket</code> that automatically cleanup resources.</p>
<h2 id="automatic-detection-of-failure-cases">Automatic detection of failure cases</h2>
<p><a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2015/04/10/Fearless-Concurrency.html">Fearless concurrency</a> is hard. Language features to make screwing up harder <a href="https://www.tweag.io/blog/2020-06-19-linear-types-merged/">are in the works</a>. While Haskell will not stop you from deadlocking your program, the runtime has tooling to detect when this happens and throw an exception such as <code>BlockedIndefinitelyOnMVar</code> in the deadlocked code.</p>
<p>Haskell is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lazy_evaluation">lazy</a> so while less common, if an unproductive infinite loop is detected a <code>NonTermination</code> exception may be thrown. This is however <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halting_problem">not perfect</a>.</p>
<p>Haskell has <a href="https://wiki.c2.com/?TailCallOptimization">tail call optimization</a> limiting required stack size however a recoverable <code>StackOverflow</code> can be thrown. Various arithmetic exceptions exist for numeric errors such as <code>Overflow</code>, or <code>DivideByZero</code>.</p>
<p>Each thread can have independently set allocation limits via <code>setAllocationCounter</code> which causes an <code>AllocationLimitExceeded</code> exception. This can be useful for handling <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multitenancy">multitenancy</a>.</p>
<h2 id="green-threads-and-asynchronous-networking">Green threads and asynchronous networking</h2>
<p>Most languages have some implementation of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_threads">green threads</a>, but few have it as the primary mode of computation. The success of <a href="https://golang.org/">Go</a>, and <a href="https://www.erlang.org/">Erlang</a> for writing networked applications is heavily tied to this model of concurrency. Languages such as <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> that implement the functionality as a <a href="https://tokio.rs/">library</a>, have <a href="http://journal.stuffwithstuff.com/2015/02/01/what-color-is-your-function/">substantial ergonomics implications</a>.</p>
<p>Standard POSIX <a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man7/pthreads.7.html">pthreads</a> consume substantially more resources than green threads, and utilize the operating systems scheduler. On my system:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">&gt; ulimit -a | grep stack
stack size <span>(</span>kbytes, -s<span>)</span> <span>8192</span>
</code></pre></div><p>the default thread stack size as 8 megabytes. Technically Linux does lazy allocation via virtual memory, however even <em>spawning and killing</em> a thread can take <a href="https://lemire.me/blog/2020/01/30/cost-of-a-thread-in-c-under-linux/">thousands of CPU cycles</a>.</p>
<p>Scaling to a large number of concurrent users (generally known as the <a href="http://www.kegel.com/c10k.html">C10K problem</a>), is usually accomplished via asynchronous IO operations. Asynchronous IO multiplexing combined with a low level of parallelism is how services such as <a href="https://nginx.org/">NGINX</a> attain such high performance.</p>
<p>GHC internally utilizes <a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man7/epoll.7.html">epoll</a>, or <a href="https://www.freebsd.org/cgi/man.cgi?query=kqueue&amp;sektion=2">kqueue</a> depending on platform. And support for the new <a href="https://kernel.dk/io_uring.pdf">io_uring</a> Linux API is being <a href="http://wjwh.eu/posts/2020-07-26-haskell-iouring-manager.html">experimented with already</a>, which can bring <a href="https://thenewstack.io/how-io_uring-and-ebpf-will-revolutionize-programming-in-linux/">substantial performance gains</a>.</p>
<p>Of green thread implementations Haskells is among the most powerful. For example with <code>threadStatus :: ThreadId -&gt; IO ThreadStatus</code> you can inspect the status of a thread, and if blocked even see <em>why</em>:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="haskell"><span>data</span> <span>BlockReason</span>
  <span>=</span> <span>BlockedOnMVar</span>
        <span>-- ^blocked on 'MVar'</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>BlockedOnBlackHole</span>
        <span>-- ^blocked on a computation in progress by another thread</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>BlockedOnException</span>
        <span>-- ^blocked in 'throwTo'</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>BlockedOnSTM</span>
        <span>-- ^blocked in 'retry' in an STM transaction</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>BlockedOnForeignCall</span>
        <span>-- ^currently in a foreign call</span>
  <span>|</span> <span>BlockedOnOther</span>
</code></pre></div><h2 id="performance-tuning-and-gc">Performance tuning and GC</h2>
<p>Some languages such as Java are famous for the <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/10/gctuning/introduction-garbage-collection-tuning.htm">tuning capabilities</a>. A garbage collector cannot be perfect for every workload. There exist <a href="https://engineering.linkedin.com/garbage-collection/garbage-collection-optimization-high-throughput-and-low-latency-java-applications">throughput and latency trade offs</a> among others.</p>
<p>By default a generational copying collector is used by the runtime. GHC has a wide variety of <a href="https://downloads.haskell.org/~ghc/latest/docs/html/users_guide/runtime_control.html">flags to flip, and knobs to turn</a>. One of particular interest is <code>--numa</code> to enable optimizations for high core count multi CPU servers which have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-uniform_memory_access">higher communication overhead</a>.</p>

<p>Haskell has a full range of tooling to support debugging and building complex applications:</p>
<ul>
<li>Code coverage reporting via <a href="https://ku-fpg.github.io/software/hpc/">HCP</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.fpcomplete.com/blog/2015/04/ghc-prof-flamegraph/">Time profiling flamegraphs</a> via <a href="https://github.com/fpco/ghc-prof-flamegraph">ghc-prof-flamegraph</a></li>
<li><a href="http://book.realworldhaskell.org/read/profiling-and-optimization.html#id678078">Space profiling graphs</a> via <a href="https://downloads.haskell.org/~ghc/6.12.1/docs/html/users_guide/hp2ps.html">hp2ps</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://harporoeder.com/posts/haskell-runtime/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248522</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 22:05:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Murder of Wilbur Wright]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248073">thread link</a>) | @tacon
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://applieddivinitystudies.com/murder-of-wilbur | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://applieddivinitystudies.com/murder-of-wilbur">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
       <p>How many of our greatest minds have we lost?</p>
<p>From The Dream Machine (p50) on John Atanasoff:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>He was determined to build a computing machine… But with all his teaching responsibilities, he’d had very little time to focus on the problem.</strong> Finally, however, on a bitterly cold winter night in late 1937, he just couldn’t take it anymore; he had to get away to concentrate. So he jumped into his car in Ames, Iowa, and drove east through the subzero temperature at more than eighty miles per hour. Almost three hours later, after he crossed the Mississippi River into Illinois, he stopped at a roadhouse to warm up. And there, somewhere between his first and second bourbons, he conceived four crucial ideas to make him computer work.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Incredible! Atanasoff was busy, but finally got down to doing the thing he really loved, the world recognized his genius, and he was given all the resources he needed to complete his work.</p>
<p>At least, that’s what would have happened in any reasonable society. Instead, we’re told:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Atanasoff didn’t develop his invention any further, as it happened. Soon after the United States entered the war, in December 1941, he went to the Naval Ordinance Laboratory in Washington, D.C., where he supervised the counting testing of mines. <strong>He never returned to computing.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Who knows what else he could have given us? Instead, his entire lifetime produces one brief period of real scientific producitivity, bookended by teaching responsibilities and war.</p>
<p>Once you start looking, these stories are everwhere. Here’s <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_Unix">The Daemon, the Gnu and the Penguin</a> on the invention of Unix:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In August 1969, Ken Thompson’s wife Bonnie took their year-old son on a trip to California to show off to their families. As a temporary bachelor, Ken had time to work. “I allocated a week each to the operating system, the shell, the editor and the assembler [he told me]… and during the month she was gone, it was totally rewritten in a form that looked like an operating system”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Maybe this is a greatly exaggerated myth, but how terrifying would it be if that was true? Is it possible that Thompson was burdened by responsibilities his entire life, and then in a brief moment of freedom did some of the most important work anyone has ever done?</p>
<p>And then from <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wright_brothers#Wilbur">Wikipedia</a>, on Wilbur Wright:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>…Wilbur never flew again. He gradually became occupied with business matters for the Wright Company and dealing with different lawsuits. Upon dealing with the patent lawsuits, which had put great strain on both brothers, Wilbur had written in a letter to a French friend, “<strong>When we think what we might have accomplished if we had been able to devote this time to experiments, we feel very sad</strong>, but it is always easier to deal with things than with men, and no one can direct his life entirely as he would choose.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But why on earth not? Why couldn’t Wilbur Wright, now admired as one of history’s greatest investors, find time to continue his most important work? The story continues:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wilbur spent the next year before his death traveling, where he spent a full six months in Europe attending to various business and legal matters… He was also constantly back and forth between New York, Washington and Dayton. All of the stresses were taking a toll on Wilbur physically. Orville would remark that he would “come home white”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then finally:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After returning to Dayton in early May 1912, worn down in mind and body, he fell ill again and was diagnosed with typhoid fever. He lingered on, his symptoms relapsing and remitting for many days. Wilbur died, at age 45, at the Wright family home on May 30.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>These were some of the most brilliant minds we had, and they were each nearly unable to fulfil even a tiny fraction of their potential. We should ask how much more each of them could have accomplished, but also how much we’ve lost from would-be inventors unable to find even a month of genuine free time with which to pursue their dreams. And of course, how many have been effectively barred from research by poverty or discrimination.</p>
<p>What hits me hardest is not the material loss, but the squandering of human spirit. As <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://vimeo.com/115154289">Bret Victor once explained</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We recognize that a dog has to be allowed the full free expression of its entire range of capabilities. Sticking him in a cage or constraining his range of experience, you’re not letting him do all the things that dogs can do. And this is exactly what we’ve done to ourselves.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And so the stories above strike me not even as tragedies, but as something more inhumane.</p>
<p>My greatest fear is that intelligent life will arrive on earth. It won’t be an invasion, or colonization, or anything horrible. They’ll just sit us down, and ask about the lives of our heroes.</p>
<p>We’ll proudly tell them about this guy Wilbur Wright. How he and his brother invented a machine to fly in the sky as gods. We’ll tell them about our culture of research and innovation, and how Wilbur, self-taught engineer from Ohio, changed the entire world.</p>
<p>And then we’ll have to explain how gruesomely we murdered him.</p>
<p>Not with sticks and stones, but with a barrage of patent lawsuits. We will have to tell the aliens how we used this great system of socially legitimate torture to slowly wear him down over the years.</p>
<p>We will tell them how in the end, poor brilliant Wilbur became old and tired and incapable of producing anything beautiful ever again.</p>
<p>I do not think they will forgive us. I am not sure we should forgive ourselves.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>See Also</strong><br><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://guzey.com/patronage-and-research-labs/">Reviving Patronage and Revolutionary Industrial Research</a></p>
<hr>
<p><em>Yes, I understand that Wilbur also sued people. I’m not claiming that he was a good person. My point is that in a humane world, no part of this story would even be possible.</em></p>
 
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://applieddivinitystudies.com/murder-of-wilbur</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248073</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 21:04:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Vancouver's empty home tax is increasing to 3% next year]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247904">thread link</a>) | @synack
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>VANCOUVER -- 
	The empty homes tax in Vancouver will more than double next year, the city announced Wednesday.</p>
<p>
	Council voted in favour of increasing the tax from 1.25 per cent to three per cent for 2021. The current rate still applies for 2020 declarations, which are due by Feb. 2.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	"I'm so glad that council backed my plan to stand up for renters and raise the empty homes tax to three per cent," said Mayor Kennedy Stewart in a news release.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	"This groundbreaking tool has helped move thousands of homes back onto the rental market to help house our neighbours, but there are still too many homes that remain empty."</p>
<p>
	When the tax was first introduced in 2017, it started at one per cent. Then council voted to increase it for the first time in 2019, to 1.25 per cent.</p>
<p>
	"By tripling the tax from one to three per cent since the tax launched, we're sending an even stronger message that homes are for people, not speculation," Stewart said.</p>
<p>
	According to the city, $61.3 million in net revenues from the tax has been used to support affordable housing initiatives. Vacant property has decreased by 25 per cent since the tax was introduced in 2017, the city says.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
                                              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247904</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 20:43:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Baricitinib treatment linked to reduced mortality in Covid-19 patients]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247544">thread link</a>) | @draugadrotten
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://news.ki.se/baricitinib-treatment-linked-to-reduced-mortality-in-covid-19-patients | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://news.ki.se/baricitinib-treatment-linked-to-reduced-mortality-in-covid-19-patients">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <a id="main-content" tabindex="-1"></a>      
  




  




<section id="RSID">

  

  <article>
    <div>
      
      <div>
        <p><span></span>Published:  2020-11-13 20:00 | Updated:  2020-11-17 09:25
        </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      
  

                      <div>
          <p><img src="https://news.ki.se/sites/default/files/styles/slideshow_article/public/qbank/GettyImages-1035411158-custom20201113183820.jpg?h=b82b5380" alt="Pink pills on blue background"></p>
        </div>
            
            <p>The rheumatoid arthritis drug baricitinib can block viral entry and reduce mortality in patients with moderate to severe COVID-19, according to translational research by an international team coordinated by researchers from Karolinska Institutet in Sweden. The findings, published in the journal Science Advances, support the continuation of ongoing randomized clinical trials.</p>
      
      
                

  <div>
                  <div>
          <p><img src="https://news.ki.se/sites/default/files/styles/article_full_width/public/qbank/Volker%2520Lauschke-custom20201113183952.jpg" alt=""></p><p>Volker Lauschke, associate professor at the Department of Physiology and Pharmacology.
Photo: Jannis Politidis</p>
                  </div>
            <div>
        
            <p>“We are pleased to report a 71 percent reduction in mortality for the group receiving baricitinib in addition to standard care,” says <a href="https://staff.ki.se/people/vollau">Volker Lauschke</a>, corresponding author and associate professor of personalized medicine and drug development at the <a href="https://ki.se/en/fyfa/department-of-physiology-and-pharmacology">Department of Physiology and Pharmacology</a>, Karolinska Institutet. “These results are especially encouraging seeing as the study included a large cohort of elderly patients, a group that is often excluded in other trials.”</p>

<p>In the study, 83 patients hospitalized with COVID-19 pneumonia in Italy and Spain were treated with baricitinib in addition to standard care. Of these, 17 percent suffered an adverse outcome that resulted in death or invasive mechanical ventilation. This compared to 35 percent in the matched control group of 83 patients who received standard care only. The patients had a median age of 81 years.</p>

<h2>Well tolerated</h2>

<p>The drug was generally well tolerated with a reduction in inflammation from the first treatment days, according to the researchers. Previously reported side-effects of long-term baricitinib use, including coagulopathy and thrombosis, were not evident in any of the patients, possibly due to treatment with anti-coagulating medicine. However, some adverse events including bacterial infections and gastrointestinal and cardiovascular complications were noted, although these were also observed in the control group so it is unclear what, if anything, can be ascribed to baricitinib.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://news.ki.se/rheumatoid-arthritis-drug-shows-promise-against-covid-19-study-finds">prior study</a>, the same team of researchers reported how they used artificial intelligence (AI) to identify baricitinib as a promising repurposing candidate for COVID-19. That study also showed how the drug inhibited inflammation and reduced the viral load of SARS-CoV-2.</p>

<h2>3D mini livers</h2>

<p>In the current study, the researchers elaborated on those findings by demonstrating that interferons, cytokines made and released by host cells in response to viruses, significantly increases the expression of the ACE2 receptor, which acts as an entry point for SARS-CoV-2 into human cells. While liver injury is commonly observed in severe COVID-19, mechanisms and dynamics of SARS-CoV-2 infections had not been investigated in this organ.</p>

<p>By combining 3D mini organs of human liver cells, RNA sequencing and super-resolution microscopy, the scientists were able to show that barcitinib reversed ACE2 gene expression changes triggered by interferons and reduced SARS-CoV-2 infectivity. Interestingly, interferons did not have the same effect on the ACE2 receptor in lung organoids, suggesting that these signaling proteins affect pulmonary and liver organs differently.</p>

<h2>Dual actions</h2>
      
      </div>
      </div>

              

  <div>
                  <div>
          <p><img src="https://news.ki.se/sites/default/files/styles/article_full_width/public/qbank/ali_mirazimi_1_foto_Martin_Stenmark-custom20201113182802.jpg" alt="Portrait of Ali Mirazimi outdoors in a park."></p><p>Ali Mirazimi, adjunct professor at the Department of Laboratory Medicine.
Photo: Martin Stenmark</p>
                  </div>
            <div>
        
            <p>“Our findings explain the dual anti-cytokine and anti-viral actions of baricitinib and support further evaluation in randomized control trials,” says <a href="https://staff.ki.se/people/alimir">Ali Mirazimi</a>, adjunct professor at the <a href="https://ki.se/en/labmed/department-of-laboratory-medicine">Department of Laboratory Medicine</a>, Karolinska Institutet, and co-author of the study.</p>

<p>The researchers note that a limitation of the study was the lack of a placebo control group, which is included in industry-sponsored randomized controlled trials that are currently ongoing.</p>

<p>The clinical study was led by researchers at Imperial College London, U.K., Complejo Hospitalario Universitario de Albacete, Spain, and the University of Pisa, Italy, while the mechanistic investigations on 3D human tissue models were conducted at Karolinska Institutet.</p>

<p>The research was funded by the Swedish Research Council, the Strategic Research Programmes in Diabetes and Stem Cells and Regenerative Medicine, EU/EFPIA/OICR/McGill/KTH/Diamond Innovative Medicines Initiative, Ricerca Corrente Linea 1 and 3, the National Science Foundation, the National Institutes of Health, the Department of Energy, CIBERFES, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Ministerio de Economía y Competitividad, España. Ayuda cofinanciada por el Fondo Europeo de Desarrollo Regional FEDER Una Manera de hacer Europa, Imperial BRC, ECMC, the NIHR and AAC.</p>

<p>The authors of the paper have reported several conflicts of interest, including lecture fees and research grants from pharmaceutical companies that own baricitinib. Some of the authors have founded companies that feature technologies mentioned in this study. For a complete list of disclosures, please see the full article.</p>
      
      </div>
      </div>

              
  <div>
    <div>
                      <div>
          <h2>Facts about baricitinib</h2>

<ul><li>Baricitinib is a once-daily oral drug used for treatment of adult patients with moderate to severe rheumatoid arthritis.</li>
	<li>It acts as an inhibitor of janus kinase, a type of enzyme that acts as an “on” or “off” switch in many cellular functions.</li>
	<li>The drug has dual functions and acts by interfering with the inflammatory processes of the immune system as well as by directly inhibiting viral entry. It is seen as a potential treatment candidate for COVID-19.</li>
</ul>
        </div>
          </div>
  </div>

              

  <div>
                <div>
        
            <h2>Publication</h2>

<p>“<a href="https://advances.sciencemag.org/lookup/doi/10.1126/sciadv.abe4724">JAK inhibition reduces SARS-CoV-2 liver infectivity and modulates inflammatory responses to reduce morbidity and mortality</a>,” Justin Stebbing, Ginés Sánchez Nievas, Marco Falcone, Sonia Youhanna, Peter Richardson, Silvia Ottaviani, Joanne X. Shen, Christian Sommerauer, Giusy Tiseo, Lorenzo Ghiadoni, Agostino Virdis, Fabio Monzani, Luis Romero Rizos, Francesco Forfori, Almudena Avendaño Céspedes, Salvatore De Marco, Laura Carrozzi, Fabio Lena, Pedro Manuel Sánchez-Jurado, Leonardo Gianluca Lacerenza, Nencioni Cesira, David Caldevilla Bernardo, Antonio Perrella, Laura Niccoli, Lourdes Sáez Méndez, Daniela Matarrese, Delia Goletti, Yee-Joo Tan, Vanessa Monteil, George Dranitsaris, Fabrizio Cantini, Alessio Farcomeni, Shuchismita Dutta, Stephen K. Burley, Haibo Zhang, Mauro Pistello, William Li, Marta Mas Romero, Fernando Andrés Pretel, Rafaela Sánchez Simón-Talero, Rafael García-Molina, Claudia Kutter, James H. Felce, Zehra F. Nizami, Andras G. Miklosi, Josef M. Penninger,Francesco Menichetti, Ali Mirazimi, Pedro Abizanda and Volker M. Lauschke, Science Advances, online November 13, 2020, doi: 10.1126/sciadv.abe4724</p>
      
      </div>
      </div>

        
          </div>

    
  </article>

  

</section>



  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://news.ki.se/baricitinib-treatment-linked-to-reduced-mortality-in-covid-19-patients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247544</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:53:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Software and Hardware for General Robots]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 36 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247499">thread link</a>) | @ericjang
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-6885150399029037702" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p><i>Disclaimer, these are just my opinions and not necessarily those of my employer or robotics colleagues.</i></p><p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247499">Hacker News Discussion</a></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moravec%27s_paradox">Moravec's Paradox</a> describes the observation that our AI systems can solve "adult-level cognitive" tasks like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MuZero">chess-playing</a> or passing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GPT-3">text-based intelligence tests</a> fairly easily, while accomplishing basic sensorimotor skills like crawling around or grasping objects - things one-year old children can do - are very difficult.</p><p>Anyone who has tried to build a robot to do anything<span>&nbsp;</span>will realize that Moravec's Paradox is not a paradox at all, but rather a direct corollary of our physical reality being so&nbsp;<i>irredeemably complex&nbsp;</i>and <i>constantly demanding</i><i>. </i>Modern humans traverse <i>millions </i>of square kilometers in their lifetime, a labyrinth full of dangers and opportunities. If&nbsp;we had to consciously process and deliberate all the survival-critical sensory inputs and motor decisions like we do moves in a game of chess, we would have probably been selected out of the gene pool by Darwinian evolution. Evolution has optimized our biology to perform sensorimotor skills in a&nbsp;split second and make it feel easy.&nbsp;</p><p>Another way to appreciate this complexity is to adjust your daily life&nbsp;to a major motor disability, like losing fingers or trying to get around San Francisco without legs.</p><p><b>Software for General Robots</b></p><p>The difficulty of&nbsp;sensorimotor&nbsp;problems is especially apparent to people who work in robotics and get their hands dirty with the messiness of "the real world". What are the consequences of an irredeemably complex reality on how we build software abstractions for controlling robots?&nbsp;</p><p>One of my pet peeves is when people who do not have sufficient respect for Moravec's Paradox propose a programming model where high-level robotic tasks ("make me dinner") can be divided into sequential or parallel computations with clearly defined logical boundaries: wash rice, de-frost meat, get the plates, set the table, etc. These sub-tasks can be in turn broken down further. When a task cannot be decomposed further because there are too many edge cases for conventional software to handle ("does the image contain a cat?"), we can attempt to invoke a Machine Learning model as "magic software" for that capability.</p><p>This way of thinking - symbolic logic that calls upon ML code - arises from engineers who are used to clinging to the tidiness of <a href="https://medium.com/@karpathy/software-2-0-a64152b37c35">Software 1.0 abstractions</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/programming-guide/concepts/async/">programming tutorials</a>&nbsp;that use cooking analogies.&nbsp;</p><p>Do you have any idea how much intelligence goes into a task like "fetching me a snack", at the very lowest levels of motor skill? Allow me to illustrate. I recorded a short video of me opening a package of dates and annotated it with all the motor sub-tasks I performed in the process.</p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="416" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b1lysnGFpqI" width="501" youtube-src-id="b1lysnGFpqI"></iframe></p><p>In the span of 36 seconds, I counted about 14 motor and cognitive skills. They happened so quickly that I didn't consciously notice them until I went back and analyzed the video, frame by frame.&nbsp;</p><p>Here are some of the things I did:</p><div><ul><li>Leverage past experience opening this sort of package to understand material properties and how much force to apply.</li><li>Constantly adapt my strategy in response to unforeseen circumstances (Ziploc not giving)</li><li>Adjusting grasp when slippage occurs</li><li>Devising an ad-hoc Weitlaner Retractor with thumb knuckles to increase force on the Ziploc.</li></ul></div><p>As a roboticist, it's humbling to watch&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/ericjang11/status/1315537835630358530?s=20">videos of animals</a>&nbsp;making decisions so quickly and then watch our own robots struggle to do the simplest things. We even have to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QzlI_ny4l8s">speed up the robot video 4x-8x&nbsp;</a>to prevent the human watcher from getting bored!&nbsp;</p><div><div><p>With this video in mind, let's consider where we currently are in the state of robotic manipulation. In the last decade or so, multiple research labs have used deep learning to develop robotic systems that can perform any-object robotic grasping from vision. Grasping is an important problem because in order to manipulate objects, one must usually first grasp them. It took the Google Robotics and X teams&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/blog/post/edit/842965756326639856/6885150399029037702#">2-3 years</a>&nbsp;to develop our own system, QT-Opt. This was a huge research achievement because it was a general method that worked on pretty much any object and, in principle, could be used to learn other tasks.&nbsp;</p></div><p>Some people think that this capability to pick up objects can be wrapped in a simple programmatic API and then used to bootstrap us to human-level manipulation. After all, hard problems are just composed of simpler problems, right?&nbsp;</p></div><p>I don't think it's quite so simple. The high-level API call&nbsp;"<span>pick_up_object()</span>" implies a clear semantic boundary between when the robot grasping begins and when it ends. If you re-watch the above video above, how many times do I perform a grasp? It's not clear to me at all where you would slot those function calls. Here is&nbsp;<a href="https://forms.gle/1GLHrf4PcBdHKXNS6">a survey</a>&nbsp;if you are interested in participating in a poll of "how many grasps do you see in this video", whose results I will update in this blog post.&nbsp;</p><p>If we need to solve 13 additional manipulation skills just to open a package of dates, and each one of these capabilities take 2-3 years to build, then we are a long, long way from making robots that match the capabilities of humans. Never mind that there isn't a clear strategy for how to integrate all these behaviors together into a single algorithmic routine. Believe me, I wish reality was simple enough that complex robotic manipulation could be done mostly&nbsp;in Software 1.0. However, as we move beyond pick-and-place towards dexterous and complex tasks, I think we will need to completely rethink how we integrate different capabilities in robotics.</p><p>As you might note from the video, the meaning of a "grasp" is somewhat blurry. Biological intelligence was not specifically evolved for grasping - rather, hands and their behaviors emerged from a few core drives:&nbsp; regulate internal and external conditions, find snacks, replicate.</p><div><div><p>None of this is to say that our current robot platforms and the Software 1.0 programming models are useless for robotics research or applications. A general purpose function&nbsp;<span>pick_up_object()&nbsp;</span>can still be combined with "Software 1.0 code" into a reliable system worth billions of dollars in value to Amazon warehouses and other logistics fulfillment centers. General pick-and-place for any object in any unstructured environment remains an unsolved, valuable, and&nbsp;<i>hard</i>&nbsp;research problem.</p></div><p><b>Hardware for General Robots</b></p><p>What robotic hardware do we require in order to "open a package of dates"?</p><p>Willow Garage was one of the pioneers in home robots, showing that a teleoperated PR2 robot could be used to tidy up a room (note that two arms are needed here for more precise placement of pillows). These are made up of many pick-and-place operations.</p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="374" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o7JH3UWO6I0" width="450" youtube-src-id="o7JH3UWO6I0"></iframe></p><p>This video was made in 2008. That was 12 years ago! It's sobering to think of how much time has passed and how little the needle has seemingly moved. Reality is hard.&nbsp;</p><p>The <a href="https://hello-robot.com/product">Stretch</a>&nbsp;is&nbsp;a simple telescoping arm attached to a vertical gantry. It can do things like pick up objects, wipe planar surfaces, and open drawers.</p><div><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="373" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2msVU0ygrqM" width="449" youtube-src-id="2msVU0ygrqM"></iframe></p><p>However, futurist beware! A common source of hype for people who don't think enough about physical reality is to watch demos of robots doing useful things in one home, and then conclude that the same robots are ready to do those tasks in <i>any home</i>.</p><div><p>The Stretch video shows the&nbsp;<a href="https://youtu.be/2msVU0ygrqM?t=41">robot pulling open a dryer door</a>&nbsp;(left-swinging) and retrieving clothes from it. The video is a bit deceptive - I think the camera&nbsp; physically cannot see the interior of the dryer, so even though a human can teleoperate the robot to do the task, it would run into serious difficulty when ensuring that the dryer has been completely emptied.</p><p>Here is a picture of my own dryer, which features a dryer with a <i>right-swinging</i>&nbsp;door close to a wall. I'm not sure if the Stretch actually can fit in this tight space, but the PR2 definitely would not be able to open this door without the base getting in the way.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-n8U9MC3ww-Q/X8MEUSH03jI/AAAAAAAAepg/JkqUn4xiirU2wiJ76aEC4av5ukvVqNtkACNcBGAsYHQ/s2048/128546115_197081455371161_5776583945816761781_n.jpg"><img data-original-height="2048" data-original-width="1536" height="320" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-n8U9MC3ww-Q/X8MEUSH03jI/AAAAAAAAepg/JkqUn4xiirU2wiJ76aEC4av5ukvVqNtkACNcBGAsYHQ/s320/128546115_197081455371161_5776583945816761781_n.jpg"></a><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Wxb4M30Yk3A/X8MEhN4mcvI/AAAAAAAAepo/Pv7jQZ_NXPU19mjwdHnZGQKf2FHcbrAmQCNcBGAsYHQ/s1920/128903470_992029601279712_5029308404263396832_n.png"><img data-original-height="1920" data-original-width="1080" height="400" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Wxb4M30Yk3A/X8MEhN4mcvI/AAAAAAAAepo/Pv7jQZ_NXPU19mjwdHnZGQKf2FHcbrAmQCNcBGAsYHQ/w225-h400/128903470_992029601279712_5029308404263396832_n.png" width="225"></a></p></div><div><p>Reality's edge cases are often swept under the rug when making robot demo videos, which usually show the robot operating in an optimal environment that the robot is well-suited for. But the full range of tasks humans do in the home is&nbsp;<i>vast</i>.&nbsp; Neither the PR2 nor the Stretch can crouch under a table to pick up lint off the floor, change a lightbulb while standing on a chair, fix caulking in a bathroom, open mail with a letter opener, move dishes from the dishwasher to the high cabinets, break down cardboard boxes for the recycle bin, go outside and retrieve the mail.&nbsp;</p><div><p>And of course, they can't even open a Ziploc package of dates. If you think <i>that </i>was&nbsp;complex, here is a first-person video of me chopping strawberries, washing utensils, and decorating a cheesecake. This was recorded with a GoPro strapped to my head. Watch each time my fingers twitch - each one is a separate manipulation task!</p></div><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Hd7JkOo0B8" width="482" youtube-src-id="_Hd7JkOo0B8"></iframe></p><br></div><p>We often talk about a future where robots do our cooking for us, but I don't think it's possible with any hardware on the market today. The only viable hardware for a robot meant to do <i>any task</i> in human spaces is an adult-sized humanoid, with two-arms, two-legs, and five fingers on each hand.&nbsp;</p><p>Just like I discussed about Software 1.0 in robotics, there is still an enormous space of robot morphologies that can still provide value to research and commercial applications. That doesn't change the fact that any alternative hardware can't do all the things a humanoid can in a human-centric space. Agility Robotics is one of the companies <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BKjRVlzKEMI">that gets it</a>&nbsp;on the hardware design front. People who build physical robots use their hands a lot -&nbsp;could you imagine the robot you are building assembling a copy of itself?&nbsp;</p><p><b>Why Don't We Just Design Environments to be More Robot-Friendly?</b></p><p>A compromise is to co-design the environment with the robot to avoid infeasible tasks like above. This can simplify both the hardware and software problems. Common examples I hear <i>incessantly </i>go like this:</p><div><ol><li>Washing machines are better than a bimanual robot washing dishes in the sink, and a dryer is a more efficient machine than a human hanging out clothes to air-dry.</li><li>Airplanes are better at …</li></ol></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html">https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247499</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:47:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ten Problems for Silicon Valley in the 2020s]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247429">thread link</a>) | @DrNuke
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.tenproblems.com/2020/11/29/ten-problems-for-silicon-valley-in-the-2020s/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tenproblems.com/2020/11/29/ten-problems-for-silicon-valley-in-the-2020s/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p><strong>Literature Review: Silicon Valley Problems for the 2020s</strong></p>



<p>Over the last 20 years, Silicon Valley has benefited from a once-in-a-lifetime alignment of advantages. American primacy, the ubiquity of cheap capital, the arrival of the smartphone (among other widely adopted tech innovations), and, perhaps most significantly, a benign regulatory environment, have all conspired to create a historic concentration of wealth and power. That might not be true for much longer, however. There are signs that the gilded age for consumer internet businesses may be drawing to a close [1].</p>



<p>In addition to Google’s dominant role in digital advertising and its alleged practice of steering users to search results beneficial to itself, U.S. lawmakers are eyeing Facebook’s overwhelming control of social media, Amazon’s mounting command of retail markets, and potential privacy violations by all the major platforms. But Big Tech’s most pernicious effects on economic growth and consumer welfare may stem less from “anticompetitive and exclusionary practices” than from its role in directing technological change more broadly [2].</p>



<p>As Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube have devoured the online world, they have undermined traditional media, empowered propagandists, and widened America’s political divides. The smartphone, for all its wonder and utility, has also proved to be a narcotizing agent. But what if, instead of focusing on Big Tech’s sins of commission, we paid equal attention to its sins of omission—the failures, the busts, the promises unfulfilled [3]?</p>



<p>The Valley’s most valuable product is the contrarian thinking that fuels its innovation culture. World-famous companies that have never turned a profit. A sprawling homeless epidemic cheek by jowl with some of the wealthiest zip codes in the world. Techies who are more likely to bond at Burning Man than at golf courses. Silicon Valley seems to make little sense from the outside. Silicon Valley start-ups have received the lion’s share of US-based venture capital funding over the past 10 years. Yet, many visiting executives struggle to find a foothold because they can’t seem to find the magic formula that makes Silicon Valley tick [4].</p>



<p>Why do tech elites believe they are the world’s greatest do-gooders and why does it matter what they say and (claim to) think? Solutionist ideas have become central to the (self-)image of today’s tech companies. Solutionism refers to the idea that the use of technologies – by inventive and cunning entrepreneurs – is the royal road to fixing social problems. Solutionist ideas are indeed central to the worldview of tech elites, and that they are also gaining ground in the broader tech milieu, although not yet in the normative discourse of capitalism at large [5].</p>



<p>Starting from such general references, this booklet identifies ten relevant areas from very recent contributions put forward at academic level in the form journal articles, conference proceedings and students’ theses. Ten freely accessible internet references have been selected for each area and direct links are provided at the end of each chapter for own consultation. Our selected references do not intend to mirror ranking indexes nor establish novel classifications. On the contrary, they are meant to represent peer-reviewed, diverse and scientifically-sound case studies for vertical dissemination aimed at non-specialist readers. They will also be able to scoop even more references through the bibliography that is reported at the end of each selected reference.</p>



<p>Without further ado, these are the “<a href="https://www.tenproblems.com/">Ten Problems for Silicon Valley in the 2020s</a>” that we are going to introduce in this booklet:</p>



<ol type="1"><li>solutionism,</li><li>monopolies,</li><li>diversity,</li><li>outsiders,</li><li>gig economy,</li><li>misuse,</li><li>narrowness,</li><li>obsolescence,</li><li>manipulation,</li><li>public mood.</li></ol>



<p>Each problem has its own dedicated chapter made of an introductory section, a short presentation of the ten selected references and a conclusions section.</p>



<p>The final chapter of this booklet will report the conclusions from each chapter again in order to provide a complete executive summary.</p>



<p><strong>GENERAL REFERENCES CITED</strong></p>



<p>[1] M. Gavet, “What’s Next for Silicon Valley?”, 30 Sep 2020, Harvard Business Review, online at <a href="https://hbr.org/2020/09/whats-next-for-silicon-valley" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://hbr.org/2020/09/whats-next-for-silicon-valley</a> , accessed on 23 Nov 2020</p>



<p>[2] D. Acemoglu, “Antitrust Alone Won’t Fix the Innovation Problem”, 31 Oct 2020, CGTN, online at <a href="https://news.cgtn.com/news/2020-10-31/Antitrust-alone-won-t-fix-the-innovation-problem-V2wpoN4Y7K/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://news.cgtn.com/news/2020-10-31/Antitrust-alone-won-t-fix-the-innovation-problem-V2wpoN4Y7K/index.html</a> , accessed on 23 Nov 2020</p>



<p>[3] D. Thompson, “The Real Trouble With Silicon Valley”, Jan/Feb 2020, The Atlantic, online at <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2020/01/wheres-my-flying-car/603025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2020/01/wheres-my-flying-car/603025/</a> , accessed on 23 Nov 2020</p>



<p>[4] G. Rangan et al., “Illogical Truths: The Paradoxes of Silicon Valley”, 27 Oct 2020, INSEAD Knowledge, online at <a href="https://knowledge.insead.edu/blog/insead-blog/illogical-truths-the-paradoxes-of-silicon-valley-15451" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://knowledge.insead.edu/blog/insead-blog/illogical-truths-the-paradoxes-of-silicon-valley-15451</a> , accessed on 23 Nov 2020 </p>



<p>[5] O. Nachtwey et al., “The Solutionist Ethic and the Spirit of Digital Capitalism”, 13 March 2020, University of Basel and European University Institute, SocArXiv, doi:10.31235/osf.io/sgjzq , online at <a href="https://edoc.unibas.ch/76426/1/Nachtwey%2C%20Seidl_The%20Solutionist%20Ethic%20and%20the%20Spirit%20of%20Digital%20Capitalism.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://edoc.unibas.ch/76426/1/Nachtwey%2C%20Seidl_The%20Solutionist%20Ethic%20and%20the%20Spirit%20of%20Digital%20Capitalism.pdf</a></p>



<hr>



<figure><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08P9TWKWV/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" width="512" height="800" src="https://www.tenproblems.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/23.jpg" alt="Silicon Valley Problems" srcset="https://www.tenproblems.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/23.jpg 512w, https://www.tenproblems.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/23-192x300.jpg 192w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px"></a><figcaption><em>“Ten Problems for Silicon Valley in the 2020s” booklet for Amazon Kindle, 2020; click on the cover to go to the dedicated Amazon listing page</em></figcaption></figure>



<hr>



<figure><p>
<iframe title="Ten Problems for Silicon Valley in the 2020s" width="580" height="326" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8LIrsUsLb08?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p></figure>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tenproblems.com/2020/11/29/ten-problems-for-silicon-valley-in-the-2020s/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247429</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:38:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Canadian and American leaders battle in video game for charity]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247242">thread link</a>) | @emptybits
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/among-us-singh-ocasio-cortez-200k-donations-1.5820831 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/among-us-singh-ocasio-cortez-200k-donations-1.5820831">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A video game livestream session between federal NDP Leader Jagmeet Singh and a U.S. lawmaker has raised more than $200,000 US in donations.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5820843.1606598686!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/singh-ocasio-cortez-among-us.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A video game livestream session between federal NDP Leader Jagmeet Singh, left, and U.S. Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez has raised more than $200,000 US in donations to help reduce food and housing insecurity in the U.S.<!-- --> <!-- -->(@theJagmeetSingh/Twitter, Samuel Corum/Getty Images)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>A video game livestream session between federal NDP Leader Jagmeet Singh and a U.S. lawmaker&nbsp;has raised more than $200,000 US in donations.</p>  <p>New York City Rep.&nbsp;Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez&nbsp;said on Saturday the funds raised during <a href="http://cbc.ca/1.5818907">her battle with Singh </a>on the popular online multiplayer game <em>Among Us</em>&nbsp;went toward a number of initiatives aimed at reducing food and housing insecurity in the United States.</p>  <p>"Grateful to all who joined us last night! Wonderful learning from you&nbsp;@theJagmeetSingh," the firebrand Democrat said on Twitter.</p>  <p>"Thank you for reminding us that another world is not only possible, but just a few hours' drive from NYC," she added,&nbsp;referring to affordable&nbsp;health care and more generous employment insurance north of the border.</p>  <p>Singh responded: "It was awesome chatting with you about how we can build a better world. In Canada, things aren't perfect and we face many of the same challenges. But, together we can do better."</p>  <p><strong><em>WATCH |&nbsp;Singh, Ocazio-Cortez square off in Among Us:</em></strong></p>  <p><span><span><div><div title="'There's no way I'm going after AOC': Singh, Ocazio-Cortez square off" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1825153603625-metadata-" title="'There's no way I'm going after AOC': Singh, Ocazio-Cortez square off"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/827/119/MPX_SINGH_GAMES.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>NDP Leader Jagmeet Singh and U.S. Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez talked politics while playing Among Us on Twitch.<!-- --> <!-- -->0:47</span></span></span></p>  <p>The New Democrat&nbsp;leader, who challenged Ocasio-Cortez on Thursday, said the aim of the friendly head-to-head was&nbsp;to connect with young people.</p>  <p>He told The Canadian Press that the two politicians&nbsp;share progressive values on health care, economic equality and climate change — views that align with a growing slice of younger voters.</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/among-us-singh-ocasio-cortez-200k-donations-1.5820831</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247242</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:15:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Simple Password Management with GPG]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247211">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <!--**This is a post about a password management system where you GPG encrypt markdown files on Linux and Syncthing them to Android.**-->

<!--Want to use GPG encrypted files to manage your passwords?-->

<!-- use the word `markdown files` instead of `plain-text files` is because people who care enough to read on are tech savvy people that knows markdown anyway, but then 会make it too 复杂吗, 再看吧, 感觉 say plain-text might 也比较好的 -->

<!--I'm not too fond of using password management tools like `Dashlane` or `1Password`, I've never really tried them, because there's no guarantee that they will live forever, nor that their security perfect.-->

<!--Even though some of them are open-source, they are still at the mercy of their developers unless I'm willing to modify it myself,-->
<!--so it is harder to modify it to fit my needs better.-->

<!--I just want a password management system that is simple, extensible and will live forever, this is my setup:-->
<p>If you want a password management system that is plain-text based, let me introduce to you my setup which utilizes GPG encrypted files to do that.</p>

<p>It uses GPG to encrypt markdown files containing my login credentials, and Syncthing to synchronize them to my Android phone to realize cross-device availability.</p>


<!--To be more exact, I create markdown files and store my login credentials plain-text, then-->

<ul>
  <li>On my computer, I use
    <ul>
      <li><code>gpg</code> to encrypt the markdown files</li>
      <li><a href="https://vimawesome.com/plugin/gnupg-vim">jamessan/vim-gnupg</a> Vim plugin to easily decrypt and edit the files</li>
      <li><code>Git</code> to version control the folder so I have full history of my login credentials</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>To access them from my phone, I use
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://syncthing.net/">Syncthing</a> to synchronize the folder to my phone</li>
      <li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.sufficientlysecure.keychain&amp;hl=en">OpenKeychain</a> app to decrypt and read the encrypted files</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I could just Syncthing the markdown files <em>without encryption</em> to my phone, but on the off chance that my phone is stolen / lost / hacked, I don’t want my passwords to go down with it, so it is safer to have it gpg encrypted.</p>

<p><del>I’m aware of <a href="https://www.passwordstore.org/">pass</a> and tried it before I came to this setup, but I want to put more info than just a password string in my files, so that’s why <code>pass</code> doesn’t fit my need.</del>
As many have pointed out in this <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247211">HackerNews thread</a>, pass allows multi-line edit, so this paragraph is incorrect.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-replicate-this-setup">How to replicate this setup</h3>

<p><strong>1. Generate a PGP keypair with GPG</strong></p>

<p>you can skip this if you already have a keypair.</p>

<p>$ <code>gpg --full-gen-key</code></p>

<p><strong>2. Install the Vim plugin and put in corresponding config</strong></p>

<p>Assuming you’re using VimPlug ( a vim plugin manager ),
put this into your ~/.vimrc and run <code>:PlugInstall</code> in Vim.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Plug 'jamessan/vim-gnupg'
" Armor files
let g:GPGPreferArmor=1
" Set the default option
let g:GPGDefaultRecipients=["youremail@provider.com"]"
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>NOTE: remember to modify the <code>youremail@provider.com</code> to the email associated with your PGP key</p>

<!--This plugin will auto decrypt encrypted files when you open them with Vim, making the only difference with opening a normal unencrypted file a slight delay of opening the file due to the decryption process.-->
<!--有点啰嗦 this ^ line, comment it out first-->

<p><strong>3. Create a markdown file</strong></p>

<p>$ <code>touch mygmail.md</code></p>

<p><strong>4. Encrypt the markdown file</strong></p>

<!--$ `gpg --recipient youremail@provider.com --armor --output %f.asc --encrypt %f`-->
<p>$ <code>gpg -e -r youremail@provider.com path/to/file</code></p>

<p>if you use <a href="https://github.com/ranger/ranger">Ranger</a>, you can put this mapping into your rc.conf to encrypt it easily by pressing <code>te</code> when the selection is hovering on the file:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>map te shell gpg --recipient youremail@provider.com --armor --output %f.asc --encrypt %f &amp;&amp; rm %f
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Open the file with Vim to make sure it can auto decrypt and open up the file.</p>


<p><strong>5. Setup Syncthing</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://syncthing.net/downloads/">Install Syncthing</a> on Linux and Android, then set it up to sync your password folder to your phone.</p>

<p><strong>6. Setup OpenKeychain</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Install <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.sufficientlysecure.keychain&amp;hl=en">OpenKeychain</a> Android app on your phone</p>
  </li>
  <li>export your PGP private key from Linux
    <div><div><pre><code>  $ gpg --export-secret-keys --armor youremail@provider.com &gt; privkey.asc
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>Transfer the file to your Android phone (for example through wire)</li>
  <li>Import the key file into <code>OpenKeychain</code> app</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>7. Try decrypting your files on Android</strong></p>

<p>To decrypt and view your password file:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Open the <code>OpenKeychain</code> app</li>
  <li>
    <p>Press the hamburger menu icon on the top left</p>
  </li>
  <li>Press <code>Encrypt/Decrypt</code></li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://tylerlmz1.github.io/assets/decrypt.png" width="200px"></p>

<ol>
  <li>Press <code>Select input file</code> and browse to the encrypted password file</li>
  <li>Enter your PGP key passphrase</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>8. Done</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://tylerlmz1.github.io/assets/view_decrypted_pw_file.png" width="200px"></p>

  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247211</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:13:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Only distributed fact-checking can keep up with democratized distribution]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 164 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25246733">thread link</a>) | @awinter-py
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><img src="https://abe-winter.github.io/assets/swift-ftl.png" alt="tweet: the problem with being faster than light is that you always live in darkness"></p>

<p>Has social media democratized reporting as promised?
We’ve democratized <em>writing and publishing</em> but this year has made the point that there’s more to journalism than hitting send.
The rest of the stuff that happens in the newsroom has stayed in the newsroom:
cultivating sources, editing for quality, and most importantly, fact-checking.</p>

<p>Lacking checks, social media is amplifying or at least fertilizing false beliefs,
and then people cross state lines to shoot up pizza joints.
If the newsroom’s adversarial functions can’t make the jump to social media,
life will continue to be this weird.</p>

<p>We’re starting to address fact-checking, and will do more.
<a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/why-cant-internet-companies-stop-awful-content/">Failing to curb antisocial behavior kills companies</a>, as well as communities.</p>

<p>Facebook has the technology to filter out the worst-quality content that their users think is ‘P(bad for the world)’ – <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinroose/status/1331257332538359810">but only at the cost of lower engagement</a>.
Given these incentives, nobody benefits if we leave this to platforms to solve.
Users should bring their own moderation to the web.</p>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles" id="markdown-toc-private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles">Private groups will decamp if they don’t like the fact bubbles</a></li>
  <li><a href="#conspiracies-are-topics-too" id="markdown-toc-conspiracies-are-topics-too">Conspiracies are topics too</a></li>
  <li><a href="#cranky-boomers-r-us" id="markdown-toc-cranky-boomers-r-us">Cranky boomers R us</a></li>
  <li><a href="#byo-vs-centralized-moderation" id="markdown-toc-byo-vs-centralized-moderation">BYO vs centralized moderation</a></li>
  <li><a href="#information-also-has-professional-customers" id="markdown-toc-information-also-has-professional-customers">Information also has professional customers</a></li>
  <li><a href="#conclusions" id="markdown-toc-conclusions">Conclusions</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles">Private groups will decamp if they don’t like the fact bubbles</h2>

<p>Filter bubbles don’t have to put up with fact bubbles.
By filter bubbles, I mean clique groups that see mostly content that supports their priors.
By fact bubbles, I mean those blue exclamation marks that say ‘official sources have called the election differently’.</p>

<p>Private groups have the power to resist centralized moderation if they don’t like it.
Private groups are sticky which is why facebook <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/30/18524188/facebook-f8-keynote-mark-zuckerberg-privacy-future-2019">bet their future on them</a>,
but this stickiness makes them hard to control.
Yes, their internal cohesion leads to engagement on FB, but it also allows them to move off the platform if they’re unhappy.
They own their slice of the network; their moat has a drawbridge.</p>

<p>A heavy hand will drive private groups to dark corners of the web –
not <em>un</em>-moderated exactly, because trust me, nobody wants that.
But ‘differently moderated’.
Reality is a participation sport and groups which don’t want to participate, won’t.</p>

<p>That said, deplatforming isn’t zero-cost for groups:
they recruit in public spaces, and are helped by ‘suggested groups’ features (which FB <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/facebook-suspended-group-recommendations-election">partially disabled</a> for the election).
Standalone forums can’t grow like that.
The fickle graces of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/5/20754943/8chan-epik-offline-voxility-service-cutoff-hate-speech-ban">hosts</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/4/20754310/cloudflare-8chan-fredrick-brennan-ddos-attack">DDOS-protection companies</a> also make it hard to go solo.</p>

<p>But it’s not like IRL networks will stop feeding online groups.
The counterargument to ‘social media gives bad politicians a voice’ is that once someone has been elected, they’ll probably <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f7131IkiSCg">have a voice anyway</a>.
FB’s design gives eyeballs to demagogues but <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triumph_des_Willens">so did Leni Riefenstahl</a>.</p>

<p>As I drafted this in early november, twitter was fact-bubbling multiple tweets in a row from the president,
the ‘uncensored’ social media app parler <a href="https://twitter.com/yashar/status/1325229370126991363">trended to #1</a> in apple’s store,
and local hero <a href="https://twitter.com/WilliamShatner/status/1326223481646665728">Bill Shatner took up the cause of moderation</a> to oppose them.
The ‘moderation drives exodus’ hypothesis is plausible.</p>

<p>But parler can’t really want to be unmoderated.
Their debut came with a quick correction that despite the sales pitch, <a href="https://twitter.com/viaCristiano/status/1277941967402553345">your username can’t be cumdumpster</a>.
(<a href="https://twitter.com/cumdumpster">Twitter has allowed this</a> since at least 2013).</p>

<p>My point: nobody wants to live in a trash can.
Every community has some kind of semi-official management.
I think even 8kun revoked someone’s access to the Q account after they had a falling out (admittedly, not over content I think, and also I don’t really understand this world).
But the <em>forms</em> of moderation we invent have to be trusted or at least tolerated, or people will ditch.</p>

<p>Fact-checking, if it’s trustworthy and useful, will be embraced IMO. But it can’t be imposed.</p>

<h2 id="conspiracies-are-topics-too">Conspiracies are topics too</h2>

<p>A swedish friend, trying to explain why their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweden_Democrats">far-right party</a> gained power in the Riksdag,
said something like ‘It’s not that we’re all nazis, but nobody else would even talk about immigration, and it’s a real problem’.</p>

<p>I like the ‘marketplace of ideas’ as a concept.<sup id="fnref:marketplace" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:marketplace">1</a></sup>
Markets are an interesting model for public discourse.
Like goods on markets, there are a limited number of explanations or ideologies available (assuming most people can’t coin our own – for various reasons, I believe we can’t).
Also, like a real market, it’s two-sided, in that in addition to the ideas on offer, there are buyers:
people looking for an action, belief, or political party that suits them.</p>

<p>The marketplace model explains why political parties get to lie out loud, be revealed for hypocrisy, and admit their strategy is disingenuous.
They’re <em>still</em> the only rallying point for ‘critical idea X’ that their buyers need.
It may not matter to the fighting faithful if the center is hollow.
They’re willing to ignore the cognitive dissonance.</p>

<p>I wonder if there’s a similar effect in the antivax movement –
autism seems to really be on the rise (0.7 to 1.5% in this century),
and if your family is affected by this, and there’s no other explanation, you ‘buy’ the idea that comes with a clear cause and a solution.</p>

<h2 id="cranky-boomers-r-us">Cranky boomers R us</h2>

<p>People are seeking answers that are plausible to them,
but may not be able or willing to dig deeply, and may not be ready to hear the truth if it means abandoning their hope, identity, or <a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-11-beliefs-world-filter.html">existing opinions</a>.
I suspect if someone is at the bottom of a rabbit hole and sees a fact bubble saying ‘this is stupid’, that’s the same as saying ‘you’re stupid’, and they won’t listen.
The challenge here is matching them with a well-meaning authority whom they’ll trust and find useful.</p>

<p>There was a measles outbreak in Minnesota enabled by high vaccine refusal rate in a single immigrant community.
Parents noticed a lot of their kids in special autism education<sup id="fnref:stat-antivax" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:stat-antivax">2</a></sup>, then fell prey to antivax lecturers or something.
But the parents had access to doctors.
And presumably they had access to other experts at the autism schools.
They ignored the fact bubble.
They chose who to trust.</p>

<p>On the flip side, community-owned moderation sometimes works rather well.
I’m thinking about subreddits, who tend to have very specific rules about what to post, and their users accept that these communities are actively moderated for the benefit of the community.
(Given that the community is a result of moderation, this is a little circular and feedback loop-y, but that may not be a bad thing).</p>

<p>I asked a friend who mods a small subbredit what it’s like:
“In six years, no one has ever said anything mean on my subreddit. I’ve never had to ban anyone and submitters and subscribers are respectful.”</p>

<p>Cranky boomers got us into this mess by believing everything they read on facebook.
Maybe Cranky-Boomers-R-Us™️ is the right branding for a community fact check to filter out some fast-spreading egregious claims.</p>

<p>We train people to consider the source, but mainstream mastheads like NYT feel ideologically hostile to readers who aren’t centrists over 55.
Their news coverage can be accurate without being neutral – factual claims in articles are fact-checked, but that’s mixed with interpretive conclusions.
The op-eds are <a href="https://www.cjr.org/the_media_today/james_bennet_tom_cotton_objectivity.php">far stranger</a>.</p>

<p>I don’t blame people for switching to ideologically comfortable news.
I just wish they had a fact-check that was ideologically comfortable, but also competent and reputation-bound, to go along with it.</p>

<p>Repentant neocon Francis Fukuyama writes about social trust now and is <a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-emergence-of-a-post-fact-world-by-francis-fukuyama-2017-01">worried about post-fact world</a> where
“all authoritative information sources are challenged by contrary facts of dubious quality and provenance”.
Readers have reasons for straying from reality.
Let’s give people an ideologically comfortable way to come back.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harm_reduction">Gentler public health messaging</a> that accepts people’s lifestyles can have higher efficacy;
I suspect the same is true of fact-checks.
Our goal isn’t to change minds; it’s to improve outcomes.</p>

<h2 id="byo-vs-centralized-moderation">BYO vs centralized moderation</h2>

<p>We need a market ecosystem of moderation vendors who provide different kinds of value to different kinds of users.
A moderation marketplace is good for platforms because they don’t want to be the arbiter of truth, they just want users to have a good experience.
(Platforms will still have some policing to do on their own).</p>

<p>It’s good for users because they’re not forced into anything; they can pick which web they want to dwell on.
This may sound like a filter bubble, where ‘everyone has their own truth’,
but moderation vendors will still need to maintain their reputation for being right –
whatever their ideological alignment.
Moderation vendors, unlike cable news channels, don’t produce content;
they just react to it and grade it.
BYO moderation isn’t BYO newspaper, it’s BYO snopes / politifact.</p>

<p>Centralized moderation has problems:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The costs are asymmetric, meaning it’s too expensive to do widely, well, and fast (see lego point below). Jimmy Wales of wikipedia describes the economics here leading to a <a href="https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/jimmy-wales-tyler-cowen-wikipedia-610b6e931d20">sweatshop model</a>.</li>
  <li>It’s susceptible to abuse by platforms and institutions and therefore will be less trusted by users, especially the more conspiracy-minded ones whom we want to deradicalize. Note I’m not saying ‘prone to abuse’ or ‘untrustworthy’. Just less trust-<em>ed</em>, and less able to balance minority viewpoints in a way that feels authentic to minorities.</li>
  <li>Private groups will turn off mod systems if not effective / ergonomic / trustable, or else deplatform.</li>
  <li>For messy issues, cookie-cutter moderation can <a href="https://www.eff.org/wp/caught-net-impact-extremist-speech-regulations-human-rights-content">support violence by hiding its proof</a>. Or like <a href="https://twitter.com/KatMurti/status/1276183164109697028">where’s the parler for breastfeeding</a>?</li>
</ul>

<p>Every community needs moderation.
Some get away without it because they moderate membership rather than content –
small workplaces, for example, have relatively informal content moderation processes, but can fire you.</p>

<p>This isn’t just a facebook / twitter issue anymore – it’s a problem for anyone with a supply of eyeballs and UGC or DM features, like <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/11/07/pinterest-linkedin-election-disinfo/">pinterest and linkedin</a>.
The older and funnier version of this is the <a href="https://www.managingcommunities.com/2015/06/04/lego-universes-penis-problem-and-why-moderation-efforts-arent-hopeless/">lego MMO’s penis problem</a> –
they …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html">https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25246733</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:01:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Study links mindfulness and meditation to narcissism and “spiritual superiority”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245512">thread link</a>) | @Bologo
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-5234" role="main"><div><div><div><p><strong>A <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ejsp.2721" target="_blank">new study</a> has found that some popular forms of spiritual training — such as energy healing, aura reading, and, to a lesser degree, mindfulness and meditation — correlate with both narcissism and “spiritual superiority.”</strong></p><p>An implicit feature of spiritual training is that it allows its adherents to distance themselves from their egos, and thereby from things such as the need for social approval or success. By encouraging self-compassion and non-judgmental self-acceptance, spiritual training should presumably make people less concerned with such things.</p><p>But as a new paper explains, spiritual training may have the opposite effect. Namely, spiritual training might in fact enhance people’s need to feel “more successful, more respected or more loved,” as the authors Roos Vonk and Anouk Visser write.</p><h2>The first study to measure spiritual superiority</h2><p>No previous studies had specifically examined topic, which prompted Roos Vonk and Anouk Visser to investigate. Their <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ejsp.2721" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new paper</a>, “An Exploration of Spiritual Superiority: The Paradox of Self‐Enhancement,” appears in the <em><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10990992" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">European Journal of Social Psychology</a></em>.</p><p>The authors developed a new measure they call “spiritual superiority.” It measures whether people feel superior to those “who lack the spiritual wisdom they ascribe to themselves.”<span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-4"></span></p><p>The measure’s questionnaires ask people to respond on a scale of 1 to 7 to a series of statements. Example statements include “I am more in touch with my senses than most others,” “I am more aware of what is between heaven and earth than most people,” and “The world would be a better place if others too had the insights that I have now.”</p><h2>Spiritual guidance, supernatural overconfidence, and self-worth</h2><p>The authors also created three scales that they hypothesized would correlate with spiritual superiority.</p><p>The first scale, “spiritual guidance,” relates to how much people try to help others acquire the same wisdom they have acquired. It includes statements such as “I help others whenever possible on their path to greater wisdom and insight,” “I gladly help others to acquire my insights too,” and “I am patient with others, because I understand it takes time to gain the insights that I gained in my life and my education.”</p><p>The second scale is “supernatural overconfidence,” and it encompasses self-ascribed abilities in the paranormal domain. Example statements include “I can send positive energy to others from a distance,” “I can get in touch with people who are deceased,” and “I can influence the world around me with my thoughts.”</p><p>The third scale, “spiritual contingency of self-worth,” measures how much a person’s self-esteem is derived from their spirituality. Sample statements include “My faith in myself increases when I acquire more spiritual wisdom” and “When I gain new spiritual insights, this increases my self-worth.”</p><p>In the three studies described below, the researchers found that their scale of spiritual superiority is a valid instrument. Moreover, it correlates significantly with the other three scales. It also correlates significantly with narcissism, self‐esteem, and other psychological variables. Finally, it also correlates, to varying degrees, with diverse forms of spiritual training.</p><h2><strong>Assessing spiritual superiority</strong></h2><p>For the first of the three studies included in the current paper, Vonk and Visser recruited 533 participants. They found them by contacting schools and spiritual centers that offer courses in subjects such as mindfulness and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Energy_medicine" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">energetic training</a>.</p><p>The participants in this first study were about 75% female, with an average age of 51. They indicated that they were currently following some form of spiritual training. The types mentioned included <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/category/mental-health/mindfulness/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mindfulness</a>, meditation, energetic therapy, reading/healing aura, haptotherapy, reiki, and others.</p><p>The respondents filled in the questionnaires described above, and also answered questions about their age, sex, education, religion, and spiritual training.</p><p>The researchers found that “spiritual superiority” correlated significantly with self-esteem, mindfulness, supernatural overconfidence, and spiritual guidance.</p><p>As the authors predicted, these correlations were strongest for participants following forms of “energetic” training. These participants rated higher than the <a href="https://amzn.to/36jmlSH" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored nofollow">mindfulness/meditation</a> students on all of the superiority-related scales, especially on the scale of supernatural overconfidence.</p><p>This makes sense, the authors write, as energetic training is meant to develop supernatural skills. This likely attracts students who already believe they have talents in this area.</p><p>Likewise, the training itself might further enhance their confidence. This is because no objective performance standards can conclusively demonstrate they are not in fact paranormally gifted.</p><h2><strong>What about people who don’t follow spiritual training</strong>?</h2><p>The second study broadened the pool of respondents to include people who are not currently undergoing spiritual training. The goal was to compare their results on the spiritual superiority scale to those of the spiritual training students.</p><p>For this study, the researchers recruited 2,223 participants via a Dutch popular psychology magazine. Of these, 1960 were women. Their ages ranged from 15 to 82, with an average age of 41.</p><p>About a third had never followed any spiritual training; another third had followed mindfulness or meditation training. About 10% had followed some form of energetic training (including aura healing/reading). Another 10% had followed other kinds of spiritual training.</p><p>The result of this second study also showed that “spiritual superiority” significantly correlates with all the other measures. Furthermore, it also found the same pattern in Study 1. Namely there was a gradual increase in spiritual superiority as one moved from the “no spiritual training” group to the “mindfulness training” group to the “energetic training” group. And again, the results for the “energetic” group were much higher than for both the “mindfulness” and the “no-training” groups.</p><h2>Correlations with <strong>narcissism</strong></h2><p>Study 3 tested the hypothesis that spiritual superiority is related to narcissism. As the researchers explain, past research has used the term “spiritual narcissism,” but none those studies empirically measured it.</p><p>For this study, the authors did not measure “agentic narcissism” (for example, “I am more special than others and deserve special privileges”), but rather “<a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/tech-support/201605/the-communal-narcissist-another-wolf-wearing-sheep-outfit">communal narcissism</a>,” which describes people who think of themselves as more nurturing and empathic than others. Example statements that characterize this trait include “I have a very positive influence on others” and “I am generally the most understanding person.”</p><p>This study recruited 965 participants via various channels. These included a Facebook page about psychology, spiritual schools, and participants who were not able to participate in the previous two studies due to a lack of space. The final sample included about 88% women, aged 19-79, with an average age of 46.</p><p>The participants answered the questionnaires for spiritual superiority and spiritual guidance, as well as several existing scales related to humility and overconfidence, a short 7-item version of the <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22889074/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Communal Narcissism scale</a>, and a three-item self-esteem scale.</p><p>The researchers found that the correlation between spiritual superiority and narcissism was 0.47. This is significantly stronger than the correlation with self-esteem. And once again, the same pattern emerged in terms of the type of spiritual training that the participants followed. The weakest correlations were among subjects with no spiritual training, and the highest for those who practiced energetic training. The mindfulness/meditation group was in between, though it was considerably closer to the “no-training” group than to the “energetic” group.</p><h2><strong>Why t</strong>he link between <strong>spiritual superiority and narcissism</strong>?</h2><p>The authors argue that the lack of objectivity in the spiritual domain plays a role here. “Like religiosity, spirituality is a domain that seems like a safe and secure investment for self-worth,” they write. “One’s spiritual attainments allow lots of room for wishful thinking, thus easily lending themselves to the grip of the self-enhancement motive.”</p><p>And because spiritual matters are generally “elusive to external objective standards,” that makes them a “suitable domain for illusory beliefs about one’s superiority.”</p><p>The results of these three studies do not imply any casual direction; the authors suggest the causal arrow may work in both directions. On one hand, people may use spirituality as a self-esteem booster: it allows them to see themselves as special, and they can achieve progress in the spiritual domain relatively easily, as there are no objectively measurable outcomes (in contrast to, for example, sports, academic success, or wealth accumulation).</p><p>On the other hand, spiritual training may attract people who already feel superior. And the “extensive exploration of one’s personal thoughts and feelings” that spiritual training encourages “may be particularly appealing” to <a href="https://amzn.to/3lhtAhZ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored nofollow">narcissists</a>, the authors write.</p><h2>Towards genuine spiritual growth</h2><p>The people who agreed to take part in this research might not represent spirituality students in general. “The question is whether a truly enlightened person would even participate in our studies,” the authors write. “Would such a person be interested in or even capable of answering all these ‘me’ questions?”</p><p>GIn any case, the researchers hope that future research can “reveal more insights into the effects of spiritual training, and possibly the conditions and personality characteristics that facilitate genuine spiritual growth.”</p><hr><p><strong>Study:</strong> “<a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ejsp.2721">An Exploration of Spiritual Superiority: The Paradox of Self‐Enhancement</a>“<br><strong>Authors: </strong>Roos Vonk and Anouk Visser<br><strong>Published in:</strong> <em><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10990992" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">European Journal of Social Psychology</a></em><br><strong>Publication date:</strong> October 1, 2020<br><strong>DOI:</strong> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsp.2721">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsp.2721</a><br><strong>Photo: </strong>by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/kalyanayahaluwo-1767926/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5353620">Bhikku Amitha</a>&nbsp;via&nbsp;<a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5353620">Pixabay</a>&nbsp;</p><p>For a weekly summary of the latest psychology news, subscribe to our <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/the-psych-news-weekly-newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Psych News Weekly …</a></p></div></div></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/">https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245512</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 15:09:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA['Leave shaming' employees needs to stop]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245244">thread link</a>) | @rustoo
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://m.dailyhunt.in/news/india/english/money+control+english-epaper-mconten/leave+shaming+employees+needs+to+stop+in+india-newsid-n232431602 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://m.dailyhunt.in/news/india/english/money+control+english-epaper-mconten/leave+shaming+employees+needs+to+stop+in+india-newsid-n232431602">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			 <p>Mumbai-based IT sector employee Shravan Manikandan had been working close to 14 hours a day since the Coronavirus (COVID-19) lockdown. Clubbing the Diwali holiday, he decided to take a week-leave in November, his first in 2020. But throughout the next two weeks, his team members and his reporting manager taunted for his leave.</p> <p>Manikandan felt humiliated because his colleagues made him feel guilty for taking leave that he was entitled to. They questioned him on why he needed to take this leave when nobody else took leave this year in his 7-member team.</p> <p>"It wasn't as if I took off without informing my team.                <!-- <div class="PT10 TAC PB10"><div id="crt_728x90a"></div></div> -->
                 It was a well-deserved vacation and I simply needed time off. Why should I be shamed for it," he says.</p> <p>Amidst the Coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak where long working hours at home is the new-normal, the culture of 'leave shaming' among corporates has cropped out. This involves the practice of singling out colleagues who take leave/vacations and shaming them, making them feel guilty for taking time off.</p> <p>Corporates may go great lengths to talk about how 'work-life balance' is the key mantra at their workplace. Look beyond that and you will find an inherent culture of overworking and leave shaming.</p> <p>Remote working means that work hours are inevitably extended on a daily basis. Rather than a 9-6 day, the working hours begin as early as 7am and end as late as 11pm. Mental health helplines are also seeing a rise in stress-related calls from working professionals primarily due to working without breaks.</p> <p>Amidst this, the basic perk of taking a vacation at least once or twice a year is being seen as a luxury. Worst still, organisations are even reprimanding younger colleagues seeking 'personal time off' once in three or four months.</p> <p>Bengaluru's Lakshmi Ray who works in the IT operations team of a global bank was discouraged from taking leaves even when she explicitly stated that she was facing anxiety issues.</p> <p>"I am already taking professional help for my anxiety. All I asked was for a day leave after four months. But I was discouraged saying that the senior management team hasn't taken even one day leave. Why should I take inspiration from this?" she added.</p> <p>Ray is also of the view that romanticising the concept of working without breaks is also a reason why corporates portray it as an achievement.</p> <p>Tesla's Elon Musk, for instance, publicly stated that he doesn't believe in taking time off or taking vacations and also gave instances of key projects failing when he went on a one-off leave.</p> <p>But remember that Musk is a billionaire and will be able to afford crores in treatment or medication for stress and anxiety. You and I may be sacked for long leaves of absence due to overworking-related stress and don't have the luxury to sit at home.</p> <p>Human resource officials are also of the view that such practices by the top management in a company sets unreasonable expectations from the staff.</p> <p>"If the CEO of a company says hey, I have never taken a day off in my life or I don't believe in vacations, what is the message that goes across to his/her team? It is unhealthy to work 365 days without a break," says Pune-based HR consultant Pradipta Satam.</p> <p>Satam also suggests that irrespective of what colleagues think, professionals must set aside time for themselves and family. She says that when it is part of the HR policy, every employee has the right to take their sanctioned leaves irrespective of the pandemic.</p> <p>The Japanese work culture is also cited commonly at Indian workplaces to show how long working hours without breaks will pay off. However, these corporations fail to mention that <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2017/oct/05/japanese-woman-dies-overwork-159-hours-overtime" rel="nofollow">death due to overworking</a> (called Karoshi in Japanese) isn't uncommon in that country.</p> <!--NH-END--><p><span color="#B5B5B5" face="sans-serif" size="0.6">Dailyhunt</span></p><!--NH-END--><!--DH-Disclaimer--><div><p><span><i>Disclaimer</i>: This story is auto-aggregated by a computer program and has not been created or edited by Dailyhunt. Publisher: Money Control English</span></p></div><!--DH-Disclaimer-->		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://m.dailyhunt.in/news/india/english/money+control+english-epaper-mconten/leave+shaming+employees+needs+to+stop+in+india-newsid-n232431602</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245244</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Little Things That Made Amiga Great]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 213 | Comments 172 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245206">thread link</a>) | @eitland
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



<p><b>A deep dive into a selection of ingenious AmigaOS features.</b></p>

<p><i>Autumn 2020</i></p>

<h2 id="toc">Table of Contents</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="#intro">Introduction</a></li>
  <li><a href="#jargon">Jargon buster</a></li>
  <li>
    <a href="#littlethings">The Little Things</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#ramdisk">The RAM Disk</a></li>
      <li><a href="#raddisk">The RAD Disk</a></li>
      <li><a href="#propscroll">Proportional scroll bars</a></li>
      <li><a href="#editors">The Text Editors</a></li>
      <li><a href="#arexx">ARexx</a></li>
      <li><a href="#nocd">No CD</a></li>
      <li><a href="#filesys">File Systems</a></li>
      <li><a href="#assigns">Assigns</a></li>
      <li><a href="#libs">Libraries</a></li>
      <li><a href="#asl">ASL</a></li>
      <li><a href="#datatypes">Datatypes</a></li>
      <li><a href="#readargs">ReadArgs</a></li>
      <li><a href="#guide">AmigaGuide</a></li>
      <li><a href="#installer">Installer</a></li>
      <li><a href="#filestruct">Standardized File Structure</a></li>
      <li><a href="#resident">Resident Programs</a></li>
      <li><a href="#reqchoice">RequestChoice</a></li>
      <li><a href="#infofiles">.info Files</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#closing">Closing words</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="intro">Introduction</h3>

<p>
To most people, the Amiga is probably synonymous with the Amiga 500 and that 
machine was, above all, a video game: something into which you plonked 
3.5" floppy disks that transported you to strange, wonderful worlds and 
hours of fun. To this group, the gamers, the operating system wasn't 
important. They probably booted Workbench 1.3 
only once, took a good look at the garish blue and orange interface,
and decided that enough was enough, before going back to blasting enemies 
in Silkworm.
</p>

<p>
And why not? The machine was great for games. There are tons of great 
texts about the groundbreaking audio and video capabilities of the 
Amiga.
</p>

<p>
This text is not one of those.
</p>

<p>
This text is about the later versions of AmigaOS produced by Commodore, 
from 2.0 to 3.1. While these newer versions (with majors released in 1990 
and 1992, respectively) certainly carried the Amiga heritage with pride 
and were - mostly - backwards compatible, the advent of AmigaOS 2.0 
marked a paradigm shift. The shift is best symbolized by the fact that 
AmigaBASIC - the ubiquitous and mandatory language of any 
self-respecting eighties home computer - was ditched and replaced by 
ARexx, a professional scripting language without any kind of graphics or 
sound features whatsoever.
</p>

<p>
This paradigm shift is also why so many of us who had the good fortune 
to come across those versions clung to the Amiga so desperately. A lot
of us stuck with it
well into the late nineties, years after Commodore's demise. And we were
fierce: if 
you think Apple fanboys are annoying today, be very happy you didn't meet an 
Amiga zealot in 1995. Things got personal quickly. It was downright ugly.
</p>

<p>
I still think there were some grounds for our fanaticism, though.
</p>

<p>
In a time when home PC:s were single tasking DOS boxes with 8 character 
file names and Ataris and Macs were single tasking GUI boxes, hampering
any hacker  with their glaring lack of a CLI, the Amiga was a champion of both 
worlds: It combined the CLI and GUI, leveraging both their strengths.
But there was more to it than that, something that's hard to convey
in so many words.
</p>

<p>
Many a time have I come across exasperated Amiga users who, on some 
online forum, tries to explain the greatness of the Amiga's operating 
system in a few short sentences. It often, quite understandably, boils 
down to something akin to "It's like UNIX", which I always think is 
unfair to both of the systems.
</p>

<p>
Sure, it was an early multitasking system with a capable command line. 
At the same time, it was also a mature and coherent desktop environment 
with levels of user friendliness much more like today's MacOS X than any 
traditional UNIX. But, contrary to today's MacOS, it never mollycoddled the
end user. It opened the machine up, rather than closing certain parts off.
</p>

<p>
Unlike UNIX, AmigaOS is a system designed for home computer use, lacking a 
lot of what makes UNIX so popular: memory protection, multi user 
support, source code portability and built in networking support.
</p>

<p>
They're very much alike in one aspect, though. Like UNIX, the Amiga's 
operating system is a collection of a lot of little strokes of genius 
that come together to make it bigger than the sum of its parts.
</p>

<p>
I invite you to explore this ingenuity with me. But first, let's get the 
terminology sorted.
</p>

<h3 id="jargon">Jargon buster</h3>

<p>
The Amiga's operating system has been called a lot of things by a lot of 
people, because it consists of many components that different types of 
users interacted more or less with. Let me try to clear things up a bit:
</p>


<dl>
<dt>AmigaOS</dt>

<dd>
This was never an official name during the Commodore days, but it's a 
handy way of describing all of the components below as a whole.
</dd>

<dt>Kickstart</dt>

<dd>
This is basically the firmware of the Amiga, residing in the ROM chip. 
On version 2.0 and up, the ROM chip was 512 kB large and contained not 
only code for self tests and bootstrapping but also quite sizable 
portions of the other parts of AmigaOS.
</dd>

<dt>AmigaDOS</dt>

<dd>
This is, roughly speaking, the command line interface, device drivers, 
file system management and so on. It was originally based on TRIPOS, a 
heritage that still shows to this day. (There are newer versions of AmigaOS
than 3.1, but this text will only cover the ones released by Commodore.)
</dd>

<dt>Intuition</dt>

<dd>
Best likened to a modern desktop compositor, Intuition handles screen 
updates and manages windows. The custom sound and video chips in the 
Amiga had mostly female names (Paula, Denise and later Alice), so I 
suppose Intuition is a fitting name for an abstraction layer that lets 
the OS interface with them.
</dd>

<dt>Workbench</dt>

<dd>
This is often used interchangeably with "AmigaOS" but it's really the 
name of just the desktop environment - which is a workbench, not a 
desktop: Programs are called tools, folders a called drawers and data 
files are called projects.
</dd>

</dl>

<h4>Other terminology</h4>

<dl>

<dt>Requesters</dt>

<dd>
Not really a major part of the OS per se, a requester is the Amiga's 
name for a dialog box. A "file requester" is a file selection dialog, 
for example. I still often use this term to describe any dialog on any 
platform, much to the confusion of friends and colleagues. Old habits 
die hard.
</dd>

<dt>Devices</dt>

<dd>
Devices, much like in UNIX, usually represent peripherals attached to the 
computer, such as storage media, printers, etc. The Amiga has a number 
of built-in devices that are automatically mounted,
for example the internal floppy drive, <code>DF0:</code>
and  the serial and parallel ports, <code>SER:</code> and <code>PAR:</code>
respectively. Other 
common devices are <code>DF1:</code>, the first external floppy drive,
<code>DH0:</code>, the 
common device name given to the bootable hard drive partition, and 
<code>CON:</code>, the text console.
There are also devices that can't
be mounted but only
be accessed using programming languages, such as <code>timer.device</code>
which is used to interface with hardware clocks.
</dd>

<dt>Volumes</dt>

<dd>
Mounted devices (such as <code>DF0</code>, <code>DF1</code>, <code>DH0</code>)
can contain a volume. In the 
case of <code>DH0:</code>, a bootable hard drive partition,
the volume is fixed and 
is represented by the name of the partition, such as <code>System:</code> or 
<code>Boot:</code>.
If you insert the Deluxe Paint program disk into the internal 
floppy drive, the current volume in device <code>DF0:</code>
will be <code>DPaint:</code>.
</dd>

</dl>


<h2 id="littlethings">The Little Things</h2>

<p>
<a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/cleanboot.png">
<img src="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/cleanboot.png" alt="The Amiga Workbench after a clean boot.">
</a>
</p>
<p>
<i>The Amiga Workbench after a clean boot. To the left are device icons,
for the RAM disk and hard drive partitions. The other icons represent various
applications, placed on the desktop for easy access.
Click the image for full resolution.</i>
</p>

<h3 id="ramdisk">The RAM Disk</h3>

<p>
The Amiga always has a RAM disk ready for use and the device name is 
always <code>RAM:</code>. No mounting, no third party software - it just sits 
there, waiting. That's clever in its own right, but the really ingenious 
part about it is that it's dynamically allocated. That means the size of the 
RAM disk corresponds to the amount of free memory currently available on 
the system, and that it never takes up more memory than is needed to
accommodate the files currently stored on it.
</p>

<p>
A RAM disk might sound esoteric today, but in the days of slow 
mechanical hard drives and floppy disks, it was a godsend for unpacking 
archives, running test compiles and storing temporary working documents.
</p>

<p>
The downside is that every time you reboot your computer, all the 
contents of the RAM disk are lost. Which brings us to...
</p>

<h3 id="raddisk">The RAD Disk</h3>

<p>
RAD, which (somehow) stands for Recoverable Ram Disk, is another 
testament to the flexibility and ingenuity of AmigaOS. The RAD disk is a 
fixed size RAM disk that can not only survive reboots but also itself
be booted from. It can be used as a small but extremely fast mini hard
drive, or  for extracting disk images to, for checking out their contents.
</p>

<h3 id="propscroll">Proportional scroll bars</h3>

<p>
A proportional scroll bar is a scroll bar that grows and shrinks to 
reflect the size of the scrollable content it represents:
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/propscroll.png">
<img src="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/propscroll.png" alt="Screenshot of proportional scroll bars">
</a>
</p>
<p>
<i>Click the image for full resolution.</i>
</p>

<p>
Highlighting a feature like this might 
seem like a silly point to make, because today all scroll bars are 
proportional. Not so in the bad old days: Microsoft 
didn't implement them until Windows 95 and Apple, as far as I know,
didn't make the move until MacOS 9 in 1999. In a time when computer mice 
had no scroll wheels, this was a nifty feature indeed.
</p>

<h3 id="editors">The Text Editors</h3>

<p>
<a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/ed.png">
<img src="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/ed.png" alt="Screenshot of Ed in full screen mode.">
</a>
</p>
<p>
<i>
Above, Ed is used to edit S:Shell-Startup, the equivalent of .bashrc for
AmigaShell. The editor is currently in command mode, getting ready to delete
a line of text.
Click the image for full resolution.</i>
</p>

<p>
AmigaOS shipped with three different text editors: Ed, Edit and MEmacs. 
The latter is a port of, you guessed it, Micro Emacs, and will of course 
appeal to Emacs fans. The other two are sort of curiously named: Edit is 
a line editor mostly resembling ed on UNIX. The Amiga's Ed, on the other 
hand, is a full screen editor with both mouse support and an 
extensive command language. Amiga Ed is probably best likened with vi.
</p>

<p>
All three of them are capable and powerful editors. Both MEmacs and Ed 
make use of the Amiga's drop down GUI menus and feature support for 
macros and extensive configuration.
</p>

<p>
Ed's command mode is, as mentioned earlier, somewhat reminiscent of vi. 
Consider the following examples:
</p>

<p>
Change the next three occurrences of "data" to "gubbe":<br>
<code>3 E/data/gubbe/</code>
</p>

<p>
Move to top of file, repeat (RP) replace of "data" with "gubbe" until 
end of file:<br>
<code>T; RP E/data/gubbe/</code>
</p>

<p>
Move to top of file, find all occurrences of "gubbe" and insert three 
blank lines after every occurrence, repeat until end of file:<br>
<code>T; RP (F /gubbe/; 3A//)</code>
</p>

<p>
Ed also has something called an ARexx port, which completely </p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/">https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245206</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:14:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pijul – The Mathematically Sound Version Control System Written in Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245129">thread link</a>) | @initialcommit
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245129</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:01:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Poisson distribution is a special case of the Binomial]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25244724">thread link</a>) | @lordgrenville
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.andrewchamberlain.com/field-notes/simple-math-of-poisson-and-binomial-distributions | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.andrewchamberlain.com/field-notes/simple-math-of-poisson-and-binomial-distributions">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-nc-base="header" data-controller="AncillaryLayout">
      

      

      <div>

        

        <div>
          

          <main>
            
              <section data-content-field="main-content">
                <article id="post-5f2dca629a534f6ff99a8a66" data-item-id="5f2dca629a534f6ff99a8a66">

    
      
    

    <div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1596836450041" id="item-5f2dca629a534f6ff99a8a66"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-308a2399fefae0cb076a"><div><p>The binomial and Poisson distributions are two of the most commonly used in applied data science. And they are integrally linked. The Poisson distribution is really just a special case of the binomial — where the number of trials is large, and the probability of success in any given one is small.</p><p>In  this post I’ll walk through a simple proof showing that the Poisson distribution is really just the binomial with n approaching infinity and p approaching zero.</p><p><strong>The Proof</strong></p><p>The binomial distribution works when we have a fixed number of events n, each with a constant probability of success p. Imagine we don’t know the number of trials that will happen. Instead, we only  know the average number of successes per time period. So we know the  rate of successes per day, but not the number of trials n or the probability of success p that led to that rate.</p><p>Define a number lamba = np.</p><p>Let this be the rate of successes per day. It’s equal to np. That’s the number of trials n — however many there are — times the chance of success p for each of those trials. Think  of it like this: if the chance of success is p and we run n trials per day, we’ll observe np successes per day on average. That’s our observed success rate lambda.</p><p>Recall that the binomial distribution looks like this:</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_61920"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087586802-21QRYF1Q4VK5IFZ82NBM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJnLJdM8l6BQFYojWP5ahkvlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnb-Xs857K_cPy1IuVCwF9Ynf7s95dhI51bYhESwT0hj4AoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087586802-21QRYF1Q4VK5IFZ82NBM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJnLJdM8l6BQFYojWP5ahkvlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnb-Xs857K_cPy1IuVCwF9Ynf7s95dhI51bYhESwT0hj4AoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="316x45" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f319f629a996b6a4f4afa29" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_76429"><p>As mentioned above, let’s define lambda = np. Solving for p, we get p = lamda / n. What  we’re going to do here is substitute this expression for p into the  binomial distribution above, and take the limit as n goes to infinity, and try to come up with something useful. That is,</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_77125"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087677711-6LJNKVE9PCSHEKA4O2EU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH4AXBgIedTA1gdPQR3I4bTlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnZ42qoJEQyw5ws8PHQ_0PYG3KA-xefyJOo79wFHgybI7QoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087677711-6LJNKVE9PCSHEKA4O2EU/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH4AXBgIedTA1gdPQR3I4bTlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnZ42qoJEQyw5ws8PHQ_0PYG3KA-xefyJOo79wFHgybI7QoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="409x49" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f319fbd5350e646da17dcde" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_80865"><p>Pulling out the constants and splitting the term on the right that’s to the power of (n-k) into a term to the power of n and one to the power of -k, we get,</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_81399"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087743410-3W7Q1CG0ZVAA1GI77RXL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMzDxksFjHBgZHUcTgpaEQrlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnZ_AVdRRj0qh6vKJyEZyc08doPF8w5AIjIzQU6ickmlQQoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087743410-3W7Q1CG0ZVAA1GI77RXL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kMzDxksFjHBgZHUcTgpaEQrlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnZ_AVdRRj0qh6vKJyEZyc08doPF8w5AIjIzQU6ickmlQQoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="380x49" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f319fffb9ba4944b7972f08" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_85076"><p>Now let’s take the limit of this right-hand side one term at a time.  We’ll do this in three steps. The first step is to find the limit of:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_85539"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087792224-LSUII3YL0GGLZMW7XUST/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA7RhMLX9Rbx8mfiBW4kka7lfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRbmqciHjXi_oMmEa9t4p0PJPajQOtspepRBkH48-lMYL12cBNoFd1dM2xsSC9c80Wg/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087792224-LSUII3YL0GGLZMW7XUST/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kA7RhMLX9Rbx8mfiBW4kka7lfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRbmqciHjXi_oMmEa9t4p0PJPajQOtspepRBkH48-lMYL12cBNoFd1dM2xsSC9c80Wg/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="151x45" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a030f5cb9c0f2d04bce6" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_89143"><p>In  the numerator, we can expand n! into n terms of (n)(n-1)(n-2)…(1). And  in the denominator, we can expand (n-k) into n-k terms of  (n-k)(n-k-1)(n-k-2)…(1). That is,</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_89598"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087816803-WIH8KAAIRMLHBKS2GLO5/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kP66QxYrW1rWDoX3taGYNDPlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnaUDTkcLiIObv4Az51GL1TM7EX_s6w27CqphmP_QXTpQQoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087816803-WIH8KAAIRMLHBKS2GLO5/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kP66QxYrW1rWDoX3taGYNDPlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnaUDTkcLiIObv4Az51GL1TM7EX_s6w27CqphmP_QXTpQQoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="409x45" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a04897beb327b1a98d58" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_93270"><p>Written  this way, it’s clear that many of terms on the top and bottom cancel  out. The (n-k)(n-k-1)…(1) terms cancel from both the numerator and  denominator, leaving the following:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_93724"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087883073-7WH745RAYAMOELT9OU04/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCFKX-8fwr5EArakrmiO1lzlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRQEb4qUtj5NnpBvQ-YpvJYdKZHvlKAM8wPBo-PIXawxsfTuGUP4aUF-8cu_6QKX6SQ/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087883073-7WH745RAYAMOELT9OU04/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kCFKX-8fwr5EArakrmiO1lzlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRQEb4qUtj5NnpBvQ-YpvJYdKZHvlKAM8wPBo-PIXawxsfTuGUP4aUF-8cu_6QKX6SQ/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="265x39" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a08bdd4ff01d8bea5de4" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_97328"><p>Since  we canceled out n-k terms, the numerator here is left with k terms,  from n to n-k+1. So this has k terms in the numerator, and k terms in the denominator since n is to the power of k. Expanding out the numerator and denominator we can rewrite this as:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_97805"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087933323-WM8WBQQ4RMN16PZ8HBFF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIO_OAMJXD1inhMLhdG-LevlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnYYT6QRR55m_Oszg5M7jY35qExCVbJCnnK3GVBw9MGJugoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087933323-WM8WBQQ4RMN16PZ8HBFF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIO_OAMJXD1inhMLhdG-LevlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnYYT6QRR55m_Oszg5M7jY35qExCVbJCnnK3GVBw9MGJugoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="346x45" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a0bd115f6d75cb9efe2d" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_120084"><div><p>This  has k terms. Clearly, every one of these k terms approaches 1 as n  approaches infinity. So we know this portion of the problem just simplifies to one. So we’re done with the first step.</p><p>The second step is to find the limit of the term in the middle of our equation, which is</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_120556"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087987320-BKU0E2HTCJBRCYHM3MKI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGv3dMzNj9HI_xS5MVUt6cDlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRcmWYEP8QnDdzp7XEe63rVZ5BnCvfD2Ub1Px6-nBGoCkA62_2X8WX2SRxlD0L7r-UQ/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597087987320-BKU0E2HTCJBRCYHM3MKI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGv3dMzNj9HI_xS5MVUt6cDlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRcmWYEP8QnDdzp7XEe63rVZ5BnCvfD2Ub1Px6-nBGoCkA62_2X8WX2SRxlD0L7r-UQ/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="117x46" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a0f30d9770770a617365" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_124191"><p>That looks a lot like the definition of e. Letting x = -n/lambda, we can substitute that into the above expression and take the limit as follows:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_124912"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597088109094-HD5XVQE3IRL307YNIAZE/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIgTw2_yHAWgGA-FHXZkj6TlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnYbOH6c0ntmvpX1VXBOQ9EcLYrGlml14Us4Xr9s9fEnCAoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597088109094-HD5XVQE3IRL307YNIAZE/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIgTw2_yHAWgGA-FHXZkj6TlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qLijIv1YpVq4N1RMuCCrb3iJz4vYg48fcPCuGX417dnYbOH6c0ntmvpX1VXBOQ9EcLYrGlml14Us4Xr9s9fEnCAoyyEsAbPHhHcQMU6bWQFI/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="336x51" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a16dacb31f23dbc7c33b" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_128517"><p>Our third and final step is to find the limit of the last term on the right. As n approaches infinity, this term just becomes 1^(-k) which is equal to one. And that takes care of our last term. Putting these three results together, we can rewrite our original limit as</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_129027"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597088183709-QTX59AZL10T41WLTFVSC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kECzhidq9Op-f6v7y2YsdmXlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qgRUppHe6ToX8uSOdETM-XldvY_sAIyUlfjhoEMtv77EE6DaWbNfF-Ujv1VqX_3Xls60_yeCJw5hnrNhQaJeSeinVsJ7BK-csjQOiHsycAYY/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597088183709-QTX59AZL10T41WLTFVSC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kECzhidq9Op-f6v7y2YsdmXlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qgRUppHe6ToX8uSOdETM-XldvY_sAIyUlfjhoEMtv77EE6DaWbNfF-Ujv1VqX_3Xls60_yeCJw5hnrNhQaJeSeinVsJ7BK-csjQOiHsycAYY/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="551x49" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a1b772b09257edf83f5c" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_132636"><p>Which just simplifies to the following:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_133109"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597088219140-KGU35ZDEE71Z04A44XUZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEyUvvPLBbuY9CyyTt06y9rlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRQUl7UjFU1HWO2Ysc5szOxbUH9DsgjSytpf-oaWdL_OiewQNTizxVCmf3LH3k3ugIA/image-asset.gif" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5f176107ca4673614d503f89/1597088219140-KGU35ZDEE71Z04A44XUZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEyUvvPLBbuY9CyyTt06y9rlfiSMXz2YNBs8ylwAJx2qrCLSIWAQvdC7iWmC9HNtRQUl7UjFU1HWO2Ysc5szOxbUH9DsgjSytpf-oaWdL_OiewQNTizxVCmf3LH3k3ugIA/image-asset.gif" data-image-dimensions="153x46" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f31a1db68ee975f4d92875c" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597066285615_136716"><div><p>That’s the familiar probability density function for the Poisson distribution, which gives us the probability of k successes per period given our parameter lambda.</p><p>So we’ve shown that the Poisson distribution is just a special case of the binomial, in which the number of n trials grows to infinity and the chance of success in any particular trial approaches zero. And that completes the proof!</p></div></div></div></div></div>

    

    

    

  </article>





  
              </section>
            
          </main>

        </div>
      </div>

      


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.andrewchamberlain.com/field-notes/simple-math-of-poisson-and-binomial-distributions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25244724</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 12:16:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A better Kubernetes from the ground up]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 249 | Comments 147 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25243159">thread link</a>) | @mr-karan
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<div>
		<p><span>Written by</span>
        David Anderson
        <br>
        <span>on&nbsp;</span><time datetime="2020-11-28 00:00:00 +0000 UTC">November 28, 2020</time>
</p>
		


		

		<p>Recently I had a chat with the excellent <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery Lancey</a>, about Kubernetes. Specifically, what we would do differently if we built something new, from the ground up, with no regard for compatibility with Kubernetes. I found that conversation so stimulating that I feel the need to write things down, so here we are.</p>

<p>Before we get started, I want to stress a few things.</p>

<ul>
<li>This is not a fully formed design. Some of these things may not work at all, or require significant redesign. Each section is one random piece of the entire puzzle.</li>
<li>These are not solely my ideas. Some I <em>think</em> are original, but like many things in the Kubernetes community it’s the product of collective thinking. I know at least <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/maisem_ali">Maisem Ali</a> have influenced my thinking at one time or another, and I’m forgetting many more. If you like an idea, it was a group effort. If you hate it, it’s entirely mine.</li>
<li>Some of these things are polarizing. I’m designing something that makes <em>me</em> happy.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="guiding-principles">Guiding principles</h2>

<p>My experience of Kubernetes comes from two very different places: authoring <a href="https://www.metallb.org/">MetalLB</a> for bare metal clusters, and operating a large fleet of clusters-as-a-service in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine">GKE SRE</a>. Both of these taught me that Kubernetes is extremely complex, and that most people who are trying to use it are not prepared for the sheer amount of work that lies between the marketing brochure and the system those brochures promise.</p>

<p>MetalLB taught me that it’s not possible to build robust software that integrates with Kubernetes. I think MetalLB makes a damn good go of it, but Kubernetes still makes it far too easy to construct broken configurations, and far too hard to debug them. GKE SRE taught me that even the foremost Kubernetes experts cannot safely operate Kubernetes at scale. (Although GKE SRE does a spectacular job with the tools they’re given.)</p>

<p>Kubernetes is the C++ of orchestration software. Immensely powerful, includes all the features, looks deceptively simple, and <em>will</em> hurt you repeatedly until you join its priesthood and devote your life to its mysteries. And even then, the matrix of possible ways to configure and deploy it is so large that you’re never on firm footing.</p>

<p>Continuing that analogy, my guide star is Go. If Kubernetes is C++, what would the Go of orchestration systems look like? Aggressively simple, opinionated, grown slowly and warily, and you can learn it in under a week and get on with what you were actually trying to accomplish.</p>

<p>With that, let’s get going. Starting with Kubernetes, and with a license to completely and utterly break compatibility, what would I do?</p>

<h2 id="mutable-pods">Mutable pods</h2>

<p>In Kubernetes, pods are mostly (but not entirely) immutable after creation. If you want to change a pod, you don’t. Make a new one and delete the old one. This is unlike most other things in Kubernetes, which are mostly mutable and gracefully reconcile towards the new spec.</p>

<p>So, I’m going to make pods be not special. Make them entirely read-write, and reconcile them like you would any other object.</p>

<p>The immediately useful thing I get from that is in-place restarts. If scheduling constraints and resource allocations haven’t changed, guess what? SIGTERM runc, restart runc with different parameters, and you’re done. Now pods look like regular old systemd services, that can move between machines <em>if necessary</em>.</p>

<p>Note that this doesn’t require doing mutability at the runtime layer. If you change a pod definition, it’s still mostly fine to terminate the container and restart it with a new configuration. The pod is still holding onto the resource reservation that got it scheduled onto this machine, so conceptually it’s equivalent to <code>systemctl restart blah.service</code>. You could try to be fancy and make some operations actually update in place at the runtime level as well, but don’t have to. The main benefit is decoupling scheduling, pod lifetime, and lifetime at the runtime layer.</p>

<h2 id="version-control-all-the-things">Version control all the things</h2>

<p>Sticking at the pod layer for a bit longer: now that they’re mutable, the next obvious thing I want is rollbacks. For that, let’s keep old versions of pod definitions around, and make it trivial to “go back to version N”.</p>

<p>Now, a pod update looks like: write an updated definition of the pod, and it updates to match. Update broken? Write back version N-1, and you’re done.</p>

<p>Bonus things you get from this: a diffable history of what happened to your cluster, without needing GitOps nonsense. By all means keep the GitOps nonsense if you want, it has benefits, but you can answer a basic “what changed?” question using only data in the cluster.</p>

<p>This needs a bit more design. In particular, I want to separate out external changes (human submits a new pod) from mechanical changes (some internals of k8s alter a pod definition). I haven’t thought through how to encode both those histories and make both accessible to operators and automation. Maybe it could also be completely generic, wherein a “changer” identifies itself when submitting a new version, and you can then query for changes by or excluding particular changers (think similar to how label queries work at the minute). Again, more design needed there, I just know that I want versioned objects with an accessible history.</p>

<p>We’ll need garbage collection eventually. That said, changes to single pods should delta-compress really well, so my default would be to just keep everything until it becomes a truly dumb amount of data, and figure something out at that point. Keeping everything also acts as a useful mild pressure to avoid “death by a thousand changes” in the rest of the system. Prefer to have fewer, more meaningful changes over a flurry of control loops each changing one field in pursuit of convergence.</p>

<p>Once we have this history, we can do some neat minor things too. For example, the node software could keep container images for the last N versions pinned to the machine, so that rollbacks are as fast as they can possibly be. With an accessible history, you can do this more precisely than “GC older than 30 days and hope”. Generalizing, all the orchestration software can use older versions as GC roots for various resources, to make rollbacks faster. Rollbacks being the primary way of ending outages, this is a very valuable thing to have.</p>

<h2 id="replace-deployment-with-pinneddeployment">Replace Deployment with PinnedDeployment</h2>

<p>This is a short section to basically say that <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery</a> knocked it out of the park with her <a href="https://timewitch.net/post/2019-12-30-pinneddeployments/">PinnedDeployment</a> resource, which lets operators explicitly control a rollout by tracking 2 versions of the deployment state. It’s a deployment object designed by an SRE, with a crisp understanding of what SREs want in a deployment. I love it.</p>

<p>This combines super well with the versioned, in-place pod updates above, and I really don’t have anything to add. It’s clearly how multi-pod things should work. There’s probably some tweaking required to adapt from the Kubernetes-constrained world to this new wonderful unconstrained universe, but the general design is perfect.</p>

<h2 id="explicit-orchestration-workflows">Explicit orchestration workflows</h2>

<p>The biggest issue I have with the “API machinery” bits of Kubernetes is the idea of orchestration as a loose choreography of independent control loops. On the surface, this seems like a nice idea: you have dozens of little control loops, each focused on doing one small thing. When combined in a cluster, they indirectly cooperate with each other to push the state forward and converge on the desired end state. So, what’s the problem?</p>

<p>The problem is that it’s entirely impossible to debug when it goes wrong. A typical failure mode in Kubernetes is that you submit a change to the cluster, then repeatedly refresh waiting for stuff to converge. When it doesn’t… Well, you’re screwed. Kubernetes doesn’t know the difference between “the system has converged successfully” and “a control loop is wedged and is blocking everything else.” You can hope that the offending control loop posted some events to the object to help you, but by and large they don’t.</p>

<p>At which point your only option is to cat the logs of every control loop that might be involved, looking for the one that was wedged. You can make this a bit faster if you have intimate knowledge of all the control loops and what each one does, because that lets you infer from the object’s current state which loop might be trying to run right now.</p>

<p>The key thing to notice here is that the complexity has been shifted from the designer of the control loop to the cluster operator. It’s easy (though not trivial) to make a control loop that does a dinky little thing in isolation. But to operate a cluster with dozens of these control loops requires the operator to assimilate the behavior of all of them, their interactions with each other, and try to reason about an extremely loosely coupled system. This is a problem because you have to write and test the control loop once, but work with it and its bugs many more times. And yet, the bias is to simplify the thing you only do once.</p>

<p>To fix this, I would look to systemd. It solves for a similar lifecycle problem: given a current state and a target, how do you get from A to B? The difference is that in systemd, the steps and their dependencies are made explicit. You <em>tell</em> systemd that your unit is a required part of <code>multi-user.target</code> (aka “normally-booted happy system”), that it must run after filesystems have been mounted, but before networking it brought up, and so forth. You can also depend on other concrete parts of the system, for example to say that your thing needs to run whenever sshd is running (sounds like a sidecar, right?).</p>

<p>The net result of this is that systemd can tell you precisely what piece of the system malfunctioned, or is still working on its thing, or failed a precondition. It can also print you a graph of the system’s boot process, and analyze it for things like “what’s the long pole of bootup?”</p>

<p>I want to steal all this wholesale, and plop it into my cluster orchestration …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/">https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25243159</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 05:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Undeleting a file overwritten with mv]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 262 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25242444">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">

    <article>

        

<!--         <header class="post-header">
            <a id="blog-logo" href="https://behind.pretix.eu">
                
                    <span class="blog-title">pretix – behind the scenes</span>
                
            </a>
        </header> -->

        <!-- <span class="post-meta">
            <time datetime="2020-11-28">28 Nov 2020</time>
            
                on Technology, Forensics, and Linux
            
        </span> -->

        <!-- <h1 class="post-title">Undeleting a file overwritten with mv</h1> -->

        <section>
            <p>It’s been a while since we shared the story of an incident with you, and that’s probably a good thing –
most operational incidents we had in the past year were “boring” enough in nature to fix them easily.
This time, we’ve got a story of a data loss, caused by pure and simple human error – and the story of
how we recovered the data.</p>

<p>Even though it is quite embarrassing how the data loss happened, we think it’s worth sharing the story
of its recovery, as it might allow you to learn a few useful things in case you ever end up in a
similar situation.</p>

<p>As you might have seen, over the last 7 months we’ve extended our offerings beyond ticketing to allow
our customers to transform their events into the digital space as long as the global pandemic makes
traditional event formats impossible. The result of our effort is a joint venture called 
<a href="https://venueless.org/">Venueless</a> that you should absolutely check out if you haven’t yet.</p>

<p>One component of the virtual events we run on venueless is <strong>live video streaming</strong>. In this process,
our customers use a tool like <a href="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a> or <a href="https://streamyard.com/">StreamYard</a>
to create a live video stream. The stream is then sent to an <strong>encoding server</strong> of ours via RTMP.
On the encoding server, we re-encode the stream into different quality levels and then distribute
it to our very own tiny streaming CDN.</p>

<p>Venueless currently does <strong>not yet</strong> include a video-on-demand component and usually, our customers record
their content at the source, e.g. with OBS or StreamYard, and process or publish them on their own.
However, just to be safe, we keep a recording of the incoming stream as well. This isn’t currently
part of our promoted service offering, we rather see it as a free backup service to our clients in case they
lose their recording. Given that we already consider it to just be a backup, we currently don’t make any
further backups of this data.</p>

<h4 id="data-loss">Data loss</h4>

<p>Usually, we delete these recordings after a while, but in some cases, our customers ask us to get them, e.g.
because their own recording failed, or because StreamYard only records the first 8 hours of every
stream. Since this doesn’t happen a lot, it’s not yet an automated process in our system. Whenever a customer
requests a recording we SSH into the respective encoding server and move the recording file to a
directory that’s accessible through HTTP, like this:</p>

<pre><code>/var/recordings $ mv recording-12345.flv public/
</code></pre>

<p>That’s it, we share the link with the customer, and the process is done. One of the simplest steps possible
in all this. Yesterday, a customer asked us for the recordings of the two last streams of their event. Just
before finishing up for the week, I wanted to supply them with the required file, SSH’d into the server,
looked for the correct files and typed…</p>

<pre><code>/var/recordings $ mv recording-16678.flv recording-16679.flv
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Oops.</strong> I hit return before typing out <code>public/</code>, and therefore replaced the last stream with the
second-last, losing one of the videos.</p>

<h4 id="damage-control">Damage control</h4>

<p>Having a very naive understanding of how file systems work, I knew that the <code>mv</code> command has only
changed the directory listing of the file system, but hasn’t actually wiped the file from the disk,
so I knew there is likely still a chance to recover the file, if it’s not overwritten by something
else in the meantime.</p>

<p>Since I didn’t manage to re-mount the root partition as read-only to avoid further damage softly,
I used the <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/sysrq.html">big hammer</a> to remount
everything read-only immediately:</p>

<pre><code># echo u &gt; /proc/sysrq-trigger
</code></pre>

<p>Uhm, okay, this worked, but how do I install any data recovery tools now? After some experiments,
I decided it would be easiest to reboot into the recovery system provided by our server provider
<a href="https://www.hetzner.com/">Hetzner</a>. So I configured the boot loader to boot their recovery system
from the network and forcefully rebooted the server.</p>

<p>To be able to perform disk dumps and have some operational flexibility without downloading a 2 TB
disk image to my local machine (which would take rougly a week), I also quickly purchased
a <a href="https://www.hetzner.com/storage/storage-box">Hetzner Storage Box</a> with 5 TB space.</p>

<h4 id="failed-attempts">Failed attempts</h4>

<p>Just before I executed my fatal <code>mv</code> command, I executed <code>ls -lisah</code> to get a directory listing
of the files:</p>

<pre><code>3146449 1.1G -rw-r--r-- 1 www-data www-data 1.1G Nov XX XX:XX recording-16678.flv
3146113 1.6G -rw-r--r-- 1 www-data www-data 1.6G Nov XX XX:XX recording-16679.flv
</code></pre>

<p>This meant I <strong>knew</strong> the inode number of the deleted file! As I mentioned before, my understanding
of file systems was (and is) rather naive, and I was pretty optimistic to be able to recover the
file using that information. Isn’t that sort of what a journaling file system is for?</p>

<p>Recovering the file this way hover appeared to be impossible. <a href="http://ext4magic.sourceforge.net/howto_en.html">ext4magic</a>
and <a href="http://extundelete.sourceforge.net/">extundelete</a> are powerful tools that did find some 
deleted files on my disk – but not the one I was looking for, even after trying different options
for over two hours.</p>

<p>I did not spend the time to really understand how ext4 works, but from what I gathered from various
blogs, I was pretty much out of luck since the inode did no longer contain the relevant information
and ext4magic also wasn’t able to <a href="http://ext4magic.sourceforge.net/howto_en.html#Recovery_process_5">recover the neccessary information from the journal</a>
either.</p>

<pre><code>debugfs:  inode_dump &lt;3146113&gt;
0000  a081 0000 8503 0000 e83a c15f e83a c15f  .........:._.:._
0020  e83a c15f 0000 0000 7200 0100 0800 0000  .:._....r.......
0040  0000 0800 0100 0000 0af3 0100 0400 0000  ................
0060  0000 0000 0000 0000 0100 0000 e6eb c000  ................
0100  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000  ................
*
0140  0000 0000 92d0 2cf5 0000 0000 0000 0000  ......,.........
0160  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 6fb2 0000  ............o...
0200  2000 e3fb 208a 515b 7c65 5d5a 7c65 5d5a   ... .Q[|e]Z|e]Z
0220  e83a c15f 7c65 5d5a 0000 0000 0000 0000  .:._|e]Z........
0240  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000  ................
*
</code></pre>

<p>However, if you’re in a similar situation – the ext4magic how-tos are really helpful and worth a try.</p>

<h4 id="successful-recovery">Successful recovery</h4>

<p>There is this one other approach to file recovery that is often recommended on the internet, usually
for “small text files”: Just <code>grep</code> your whole disk for known parts of its contents! So why wouldn’t
this work on larger non-text files as well?</p>

<p>The first problem is obviously what to grep for. The only thing I know about the missing file, apart
from its rough size, is that it’s a FLV video file. Luckily, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_Video#Flash_Video_Structure">all FLV files</a>
that contain video start with the byte sequence <code>FLV\x01\x05</code>. So let’s search our 2 TB disk for
that byte sequence and print out the byte offset of all occurences!</p>

<pre><code>cat /dev/md2 \
	| pv -s 1888127576000 \
	| grep -P --byte-offset --text 'FLV\x01\x05' \
	| tee -a /mnt/storagebox/grep-log.txt
</code></pre>

<p>This took roughly 7 hours. The <code>pv</code> command with the (rough) total size of the disk is optional, but gives you
a nice progress bar. Overall, this took a little over 6 hours on our server.</p>

<p><code>grep</code> works line-based, which in a binary file menas “any byte sequence between two ASCII line breaks”. The
log file therefore contained lots of lines like this:</p>

<pre><code>184473878409:&lt;some binary data&gt;FLV&lt;some binary data&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>In total, the search found 126 FLV file headers on our disk. This was pretty reassuring, since we had 122 FLV files
still known to the file system – so there are at least four FLV byte sequences without a filename!</p>

<pre><code># find /mnt/disk/var/recordings/ -name '*.flv' -not -empty -ls | wc -l
122
</code></pre>

<p>Now, I needed to find out which of the 126 byte sequences did not have a filename. Since I really didn’t want
to spend all weekend with a deep-dive into the ext4 disk layout, I went for an easier solution: For every file
still known in the file system, I computed a hash of the first 500 kilobytes of the file:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>#!/usr/bin/python3
</span><span>import</span> <span>glob</span>
<span>import</span> <span>hashlib</span>
<span>import</span> <span>os</span>

<span>hashsize</span> <span>=</span> <span>500</span> <span>*</span> <span>1024</span>
<span>known_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>not_deleted_files</span> <span>=</span> <span>sorted</span><span>(</span>
    <span>glob</span><span>.</span><span>glob</span><span>(</span><span>'/mnt/disk/var/recordings/*.flv'</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> 
    <span>glob</span><span>.</span><span>glob</span><span>(</span><span>'/mnt/disk/var/recordings/public/*.flv'</span><span>)</span>
<span>)</span>
<span># Ignore files shorter than our hash size
</span><span>not_deleted_files</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>f</span> <span>for</span> <span>f</span> <span>in</span> <span>not_deleted_files</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>os</span><span>.</span><span>stat</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>).</span><span>st_size</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>hashsize</span>
<span>]</span>

<span>for</span> <span>fname</span> <span>in</span> <span>not_deleted_files</span><span>:</span>
    <span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
        <span>h</span> <span>=</span> <span>hashlib</span><span>.</span><span>md5</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>hashsize</span><span>)).</span><span>hexdigest</span><span>()</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"duplicate hash found:"</span><span>)</span>
        <span>known_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>fname</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>fname</span><span>)</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span>
    <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>not_deleted_files</span><span>),</span> <span>"files with"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>known_hashes</span><span>),</span> <span>"hashes"</span>
<span>)</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Interestingly, two files from the completely different customers shared the same hash of the first 500 kilobytes.
I haven’t tested it yet, but my theory is that those were streams that just did not contain any audio or video
in their first minutes, but only empty frames. However, since I knew this isn’t the case for my missing file,
I felt confident in proceeding with this approach.</p>

<p>Next, I computed the same hash for every byte offest found by grep and compared it to the hashes found in the
previous step:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>grep_log</span> <span>=</span> <span>'/mnt/storagebox/grep-log.txt'</span>
<span>disk</span> <span>=</span> <span>'/dev/md2'</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Parsing grep log…"</span><span>)</span>
<span>positions</span> <span>=</span> <span>[]</span>
<span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>grep_log</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>line</span> <span>in</span> <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>().</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>b'</span><span>\n</span><span>'</span><span>):</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>line</span><span>:</span>  <span># ignore empty line e.g. at end of file
</span>            <span>continue</span>
        <span>pos</span><span>,</span> <span>data</span> <span>=</span> <span>line</span><span>.</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>b':'</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span>
        <span>pos</span> <span>=</span> <span>int</span><span>(</span><span>pos</span><span>.</span><span>decode</span><span>())</span>
        <span># add offset of FLV within line
</span>        <span>binoffset</span> <span>=</span> <span>data</span><span>.</span><span>index</span><span>(</span><span>b"FLV</span><span>\x01</span><span>"</span><span>)</span>
        <span>pos</span> <span>+=</span> <span>binoffset</span> 
        <span>positions</span><span>.</span><span>append</span><span>(</span><span>pos</span><span>)</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Computing hashes of files on disk…"</span><span>)</span>
<span>found_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>disk</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>p</span> <span>in</span> <span>positions</span><span>:</span>
        <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>seek</span><span>(</span><span>p</span><span>)</span>
        <span>d</span> <span>=</span> <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>hashsize</span><span>)</span>
        <span>h</span> <span>=</span> <span>hashlib</span><span>.</span><span>md5</span><span>(</span><span>d</span><span>).</span><span>hexdigest</span><span>()</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"At offset"</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span><span>,</span> <span>"found known hash"</span><span>,</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span>
                  <span>"corresponding to"</span><span>,</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>])</span>
        <span>else</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"At offset"</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span><span>,</span> <span>"found unknown hash"</span><span>,</span> <span>h</span><span>)</span>
        <span>found_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>p</span>

<span>unknown_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>h</span><span>:</span> <span>p</span> <span>for</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span> <span>in</span> <span>found_hashes</span><span>.</span><span>items</span><span>()</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>not</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>files_not_found</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>fname</span> <span>for</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>fname</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>.</span><span>items</span><span>()</span>
   …</code></pre></figure></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/">https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25242444</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 02:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
