<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 12:35:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 12:35:41 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bekk.christmas – 264 articles about tech, design, strategy and innovation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25263682">thread link</a>) | @selbekk
<br/>
December 1, 2020 | https://blogg.bekk.no/wishing-you-all-a-very-bekk-christmas-8505a0a332e2 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blogg.bekk.no/wishing-you-all-a-very-bekk-christmas-8505a0a332e2">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><div><div><p id="d520">Bekk is a Norwegian consultancy that merges the disciplines of technology, user experience, design, product innovation and strategy, and helps Norwegian businesses improve their products and services.</p><p id="4d8f">But mostly, we’re people that are really passionate about what we do. We see that every day on our company Slack, where we ask questions about challenging topics, and get tons of replies in a matter of minutes. We see that every time one of our colleagues is a featured speaker at international conferences. We see that every time we host a meetup, or a workshop, or meet students both online and on site.</p><p id="b7de">We love sharing what we know, because it helps us grow. That’s why we’re continuing our great tradition of sharing some of the stuff we know every December.</p><p id="e0e1">This year, we’ve created 11 advent calendar sites, each with its own particular topic, and each with 24 different entries. 10 of them contain 24 articles each, and one contains a set of 24 podcast episodes. The articles will be short, to the point and will try to inspire you to learn something new every day this December.</p><p id="b8c3">We’re incredibly proud to share the following calendars with you this year:</p><h2 id="785a">elm.christmas</h2><p id="f171">Bekk ❤️ Elm. We’ve been using it for years at <a rel="noopener" href="https://blogg.bekk.no/using-elm-at-vy-e028b11179eb">some of our biggest clients</a>, we have helped organize <a href="https://2020.osloelmdays.no/" rel="noopener">one of the world’s greatest Elm conferences</a>, and even help <a href="https://elm-lang.org/news/elm-and-bekk" rel="noopener">sponsor the development of Elm itself</a>. This year, we’re sharing 24 interesting things you might not know about Elm!</p><h2 id="9bd3">javascript.christmas</h2><p id="cecd">JavaScript is a huge part of most of what we do today. Whether it’s through Node, Vue or React, it’s one of the most versatile languages out there. This year — which marks the third year of our JavaScript calendar — we’re diving into a bunch of topics that will help you understand this wonderful language even better.</p><h2 id="77b9">functional.christmas</h2><p id="929e">The functional programming paradigm has been with us for decades, but has definitely seem an up-turn in interest the last couple of years. This calendar aim to teach you how to up your functional programming game in a matter of 24 days.</p><h2 id="4c60">kotlin.christmas</h2><p id="893a">Kotlin has become incredibly popular the last couple of years, and is one of our favorite languages to implement advanced backends in. It’s a great language to learn, and to introduce bit-by-bit on legacy Java codebases. This year, we’re excited to share yet another 24 tips and tricks on how you can up <em>your</em> Kotlin game.</p><h2 id="4c7e">innovation.christmas</h2><p id="5607">Product development and innovation are two of the coolest things we do at Bekk. That’s why we’re sharing 24 different conversations with entrepreneurs, innovators, specialists and strategists, each pertaining to a particular topic. Note that these podcast episodes are available in Norwegian only.</p><h2 id="4be8">react.christmas</h2><p id="f73a">For the fourth year in a row, this calendar keeps teaching you new React tips, tricks and techniques in a small bite-sized way. We share our experiences with different tools, and help you understand how to use the world’s most popular frontend framework.</p><h2 id="e4af">security.christmas</h2><p id="2241">Creating secure solutions is one of the hardest challenges we’ve tasked to do. That’s why we have a dedicated group within Bekk to teach ourselves — and others — how to do it right. We’re excited to share 24 new articles about how you can do the same.</p><h2 id="34ad">strategy.christmas</h2><p id="3077">Developing modern strategies for a modern marketplace is incredibly important. Some of our best product and business strategists have sat down to share some of their best insights on how you can change your business for the better — from within.</p><h2 id="94eb">talks.christmas</h2><p id="0202">We do a lot of talks, presentations and workshops, both for ourselves, our customers, and at external meetups and conferences. It’s not as easy at it looks — but with the right training, we believe anyone can do it. This year, we’re sharing 24 articles, listicles, tipsicles (is that a thing?) and experience reports from some of the most seasoned speakers in the business.</p><h2 id="5fd1">thecloud.christmas</h2><p id="ec69">We were kidding about doing on-prem.christmas this year, but the cloud just makes everything so easy (and hard!) that we decided to go with the latter. This year’s cloud calendar will teach you more than you wish you knew about Kubernetes, Azure, AWS and GCP.</p><h2 id="423e">ux.christmas</h2><p id="3692">Last, but definitely not least, we’re continuing last year’s success of sharing the thoughts and knowledge of some of the best user experience designers we know. Look forward to learning a ton about UX, design and our experiences with our clients</p></div></div></section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blogg.bekk.no/wishing-you-all-a-very-bekk-christmas-8505a0a332e2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25263682</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 09:05:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Busybox-based Linux distro from scratch]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25263398">thread link</a>) | @pfrog
<br/>
December 1, 2020 | https://re-ws.pl/2020/11/busybox-based-linux-distro-from-scratch/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://re-ws.pl/2020/11/busybox-based-linux-distro-from-scratch/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1624">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p><img width="257" height="303" src="https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/logo.gif" alt="linux logo" loading="lazy"></p><figure id="attachment_1648" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1648"><a href="https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmc16mib.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmc16mib-263x300.jpg" alt="Canon SD MMC card 16 MiB" width="263" height="300" srcset="https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmc16mib-263x300.jpg 263w, https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmc16mib-899x1024.jpg 899w, https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmc16mib-768x875.jpg 768w, https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmc16mib-1348x1536.jpg 1348w, https://re-ws.pl/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mmc16mib.jpg 1443w" sizes="(max-width: 263px) 100vw, 263px"></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1648">16 MiB SD/MMC card. Made in Japan in 2005</figcaption></figure>
<p>Today, I would like to show something different, than usual reverse-engineering, that appears on my blog usually. I needed to prepare a Linux distro for myself to be able to run it on my PC. But not the ordinary operating system that we download from webpage, then use fancy graphical installer to select, what we want and where. My goals were very specific. First was to have it custom-compiled. With that in mind there aren’t many choices left (maybe Gentoo?). Second was to not cross 16 MiB boundary. Why exactly that? That’s simple. I have old (15 years old to be precise) SD/MMC card made for Canon of exactly that size. Quick check showed me that this is possible. I tried buildroot and it failed to fulfill second requirement and I decided not to continue, despite the obvious optimizations on kernel modules, I could do. It’s simply too complex for such a simple task. If not buildroot, then let’s go and see how to do such thing from scratch!</p>

<p>Basically the plan is to have custom Linux distro compiled from scratch. It may sound like something incredibly complex and hard to do. But it’s not. There are just few problems one must learn on how to overcome. The most problematic constraint in my case is, obviously, 16 MiB limit. To not exceed it, I have to use busybox as my userspace. This by the way simplifies distro development significantly. Busybox works the way, that, if linked statically, requires only one, single binary to be able to work correctly. So, to sum up, on software side, we need Linux and busybox. You may wonder, how do I want to boot that system, then? Well. I said I need Linux 🙂 Maybe some people know, some does not, that Linux is itself a boot loader of some kind. At least, when using UEFI and this is what I want to use, it can be loaded directly by UEFI firmware. But that’s another thing to note – I will describe a way to prepare a distro for UEFI – it won’t be as simple as that, for legacy BIOS.</p>
<p>The whole plan will look as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>Get compiler</li>
<li>Compile Linux kernel</li>
<li>Compile busybox (statically and stripped!)</li>
<li>Prepare initramfs with whole userspace</li>
<li>Format drive as EFI System Partition</li>
<li>Combine kernel and initramfs into single binary</li>
<li>Optionally sign the binary, in case we want Secure Boot to be enabled</li>
<li>Add entry to embedded UEFI boot manager</li>
</ol>
<p>In the meantime, I am going to show few ways to debug the system, in case of any problems.<span id="more-1624"></span></p>

<p>This is maybe not so obvious, but you need new compiler. Most likely, you could use the one that your distro provides, aliased as simply gcc. But this way, you will by the way use glibc as your standard library. For a lightweight system, glibc does not fit well, as this is most heavyweight libc, we have available. Therefore, I will use uClibc. And for that, we need a compiler. Or, to be precise, a toolchain. A toolchain, consisting of kernel headers, uClibc and gcc. Here, I could show, how to build such thing from scratch. But it’s not a tutorial about building a toolchain. This requires knowledge that can fill another tutorial. Instead, I will use the toolchain prepared by my latest project – <a href="https://github.com/v3l0c1r4pt0r/cc-factory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cc-factory</a>. For those, who did not read <a href="https://re-ws.pl/2020/10/meet-cc-factory-a-factory-for-cross-compilers/">my previous post</a>, it is toolchain factory running in Docker container, that provides a recipe for a toolchain that just works. If you tried compiling a toolchain from scratch in the past, then you know that this can fail, even if you use crosstool-ng. With cc-factory, it works as long as Docker can start a service and has Docker Hub working. But enough of that. In cc-factory, I am experimenting with releasing binary distributions of my toolchain. And <a href="https://github.com/v3l0c1r4pt0r/cc-factory/releases/tag/x86_64-gcc10.2.0-linux5.9.13-uclibc1.0.36-1">newest one</a> is special-made for this job. You can simply download it to you disk with:</p>
<pre>wget <span>'</span><span>https://github.com/v3l0c1r4pt0r/cc-factory/releases/download/x86_64-gcc10.2.0-linux5.9.13-uclibc1.0.36-1/x86_64-gcc10.2.0-linux5.9.13-uclibc1.0.36-1.tar.gz</span><span>'</span>
</pre>
<p>After that, you have to install it to your <code>/opt</code> directory with:</p>
<pre>tar <span>-xvf</span> x86_64-gcc10.<span>2</span>.0-linux5.<span>9</span>.13-uclibc1.<span>0</span>.36-1.tar.gz <span>-C</span> /
</pre>
<p>If you prefer another installation path, then head onto cc-factory project to see, how to build one from source. Then, you can choose whatever path, you like for this SDK.</p>
<p>Next step is to export SDK’s bin directory to you PATH for convenience:</p>
<pre><span>export</span> <span>PATH</span>=<span>"</span><span>$PATH</span><span>:/opt/x86_64-linux-uclibc/bin</span><span>"</span>
</pre>
<p>Now, it’s nice to check, if toolchain works. Let’s write one-liner C hello world program to your temp directory, compile and run:</p>
<pre><span>echo</span><span> -e </span><span>'</span><span>#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;\nint main() {printf("Hello, World!\\n");}</span><span>'</span> <span>&gt;</span>/tmp/main.c
x86_64-linux-uclibc-gcc <span>-static</span> <span>-o</span> /tmp/main /tmp/main.c
/tmp/main
</pre>
<p>And you should see the familiar text on your screen. You are ready to go!</p>

<p>That is, in my opinion, the easiest part. First, we have to download kernel image, that we want to use. For that purpose, we need to go to <a href="https://www.kernel.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kernel Archives</a> and download latest stable tarball. Optionally, we can download PGP signature and verify its correctness. But this is outside the scope of this tutorial. Another option to get kernel is to clone its stable repo with:</p>
<pre>git clone git://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/stable/linux.git
</pre>
<p>This is the path, I chose, because I don’t like leaving multiple copies of kernel sources on my hard drive, so I prefer to have one, central clone of repo and use for any project, I need it to.</p>
<p>In case of tarball, it now has to be unpacked with usual:</p>
<pre>tar <span>-xvf</span> linux-*.tar.gz
</pre>
<p>Then, in case of tarball, you got directory with name dependent on you kernel version, in case of git repo, it is simply linux. So we can cd into it, in any of the above cases:</p>
<pre><span>cd</span> linux*
</pre>
<p>In theory at this point, we could set the compiler, we prepared to be run by kernel buildsystem. But this is optional, as we target <code>x86_64</code> platform, that we run our host on, so default compiler should be as good as uClibc variant. I case, you want to use custom one, you have to export the following:</p>
<pre><span>export</span> <span>CROSS_COMPILE</span>=x86_64-linux-uclibc-
</pre>
<p>Now, we have to configure our kernel.</p>
<p>First step is to choose defconfig. Possible values can be listed in case of x86 with:</p>
<pre><span>ls</span> arch/x86/configs/
</pre>
<p>At the time of writing this returned the following options:</p>
<pre>i386_defconfig tiny.config x86_64_defconfig xen.config
</pre>
<p>As you can see, there are only a few. So, we do:</p>
<pre>make x86_64_defconfig
</pre>
<p>At this point, we are ready to compile. In case, you want to do some modifications, you could do:</p>
<pre>make menuconfig
</pre>
<p>And select (or deselect) some options there. If you think, you are ready, you can type:</p>
<pre>make <span>-j</span>
</pre>
<p>And wait couple of minutes (up to half an hour), depending on speed of your PC. Afterwards, you should see that <code>bzImage</code> has been made and is available at <code>arch/x86/boot/bzImage</code>. We can copy it somewhere in order to not accidentally start its recompilation:</p>
<pre>cp arch/x86/boot/bzImage ../
</pre>
<h2>Testing on hardware</h2>
<p>At this point, it is possible to run the kernel on our system. If you don’t have Secure Boot enabled, then you can try to copy the kernel to you EFI System Partition (wherever it is, I will call this path <code>ESP</code> from now on). But first create new directory for your distro:</p>
<pre><span>mkdir</span> <span>-p</span> ESP/EFI/linux
cp arch/x86/boot/bzImage ESP/EFI/linux/linuxx64.efi
</pre>
<p>I am changing the name in the meantime, as I heard that some systems does not like binaries without <code>.efi</code> extension. Now, we can try to boot.There is more than one way to do it. The one that works always is to utilize EFI firmware directly. But this one differs significantly between manufacturers, so if you prefer that one, please refer to his support pages. The other is to use one of existing tools. For sure KeyTool, that manages Secure Boot keys, is able to start any executable from ESP by browsing the filesystem. But the way I would like to show is, by using so called EFI shell. Why? Because EFI shell allows us to experiment with kernel parameters, by simply typing them, as we would start new user program. And, in fact, from EFI perspective, we simply start a new program.</p>
<p>There are many shells in the wild. I tried EDK2, that is available on Arch as <code>edk2-shell</code> package. It is then available at <code>/usr/share/edk2-shell/x64/Shell.efi</code> You can simply copy it to <code>ESP</code>, just like with kernel, then you have to add it to your EFI boot manager, or use boot manager that is able to autodetect it. You can find a bunch of resources on how to do it, even from inside Linux. But, please do not add the kernel, you copied in such way, to boot manager, as we will play with it a bit, later. Now, in EFI shell, you will be presented with a list of partitions, that the shell has detected. This might be not so obvious at first, but, somehow, you have to identify the one, that is you EFI partition. You should see a similar numbering to the one you see in Linux console, when you list with e.g. <code>lsblk</code>. You can try guessing it by typing its name, in similar way as in Windows, e.g.:</p>
<pre>FS0:
</pre>
<p>to switch to <code>FS0</code> partition. Then you can simply type ls to list its content. Once, you found the right one, it’s worth to remember it, as you might need it couple of times. How many, depends on how many problems, you would have.</p>
<p>Then go to the directory, where you copied your kernel:</p>
<pre><span>cd</span> EFI\linux
</pre>
<p>And ls to make sure, it is there. Now, we are ready to call it:</p>
<pre>linuxx64.efi
</pre>
<p>Yes. It’s as simple as that. But this will fail. We did not provide any root filesystem for our kernel, so it will gonna panic. But don’t worry, as long as reason of the panic is like that:</p>
<pre>not syncing: VFS: Unable to mount root fs on unknown-block(0,0)
</pre>
<p>then it was expected. In case of any other error, act accordingly, as this may be hardware dependent. So, probably, something has to be reconfigured in menuconfig.</p>
<h2>Testing in qemu</h2>
<p>It’s quite a nice option to be able to test your work on real hardware. However, in my opinion, it is much easier to do it in virtualized environment, that you can quickly reset at any time and where you would have latest binaries for testing, all the time, without wasting time for flashing them somewhere. Therefore I recommend to prepare qemu as such environment.</p>
<p>For that, you will need …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://re-ws.pl/2020/11/busybox-based-linux-distro-from-scratch/">https://re-ws.pl/2020/11/busybox-based-linux-distro-from-scratch/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://re-ws.pl/2020/11/busybox-based-linux-distro-from-scratch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25263398</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 08:10:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Is Functional Programming?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25263365">thread link</a>) | @bendiksolheim
<br/>
December 1, 2020 | https://functional.christmas/2020/1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://functional.christmas/2020/1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><div><section><p>Welcome to another year of the functional programming advent calendar! Every day until December 24th you will get an article, video or other functional programming related content that hopefully will make the waiting feel a bit shorter! 😄</p>
</section><article><section><p>As previous years the articles will span a large range of topics and complexity. If you are looking for something beginner friendly, or more advanced topics, there should be something for everyone these next 23 days.</p>
<p>Let’s start this advent of with a look at the basics: what is functional programming (FP)? This question has been answered many times before, in many different ways. <a href="https://functional.christmas/2019/1">We took our own stab at it last year</a>. Even though there are no single definition for FP and many different ways to approach it, there are some things that are shared throughout the related communities.</p>

<p>Today I want to use the words and pictures of Russ Olsen and highlight his talk from GOTO 2018. Russ is a great communicator and I love the down to earth and practical perspective he brings in this talk. He explains functional programming in an understandable way and shows why people prefer FP. I hope you enjoy! </p>
<p>Link: <a href="https://youtu.be/0if71HOyVjY">https://youtu.be/0if71HOyVjY</a></p>
<p> <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/0if71HOyVjY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe> </p>
<p>What is your favorite FP intro talk?</p></section></article></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://functional.christmas/2020/1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25263365</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 08:03:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[QEMU Advent Calendar 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25262608">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    


    <div id="myCarousel">
      <div>
        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <p><img src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/qemu-winter.png" alt="QEMU"></p>
              <h2>Brightening your days in the winter holiday season.</h2>
              <p>
               This advent calendar is brought to you by the
               <a href="https://www.qemu.org/">QEMU community</a>.
              </p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div><!-- /.carousel -->

    <div id="day-1">
     <p>
	<img id="img-day01" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 1" onclick="opendoor('day01', 'Day 1 - Tweetable bootsector game');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day01">Day 1</h2>
     <div id="desc-day01">
      <p>
        This bootloader game can be generated from text that fits in a tweet.
      </p>
      <p>
       Size of download is 893 bytes.
      </p>
      
     </div>
     <p>
       <a href="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/download/day01.tar.gz" role="button">Download</a>
     </p>
    </div>

    <div id="day-2">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day02" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 2" onclick="opendoor('day02', 'Day 2 - QEMU 5.2.0-rc4');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day02">Day 2</h2>
     <div id="desc-day02">
      <p>
       No disk image today, but a new release candidate for QEMU: Version 5.2.0-rc4 has just been published yesterday – please download the package and give it a try! 
      </p>
      <p>
       Size of download is 102 MB
      </p>
      
     </div>
     <p>
       <a href="https://download.qemu.org/qemu-5.2.0-rc4.tar.xz" role="button">Download</a>
     </p>
    </div>

    <div id="day-3">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day03" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 3" onclick="opendoor('day03', 'Day 3 - GW-BASIC');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day03">Day 3</h2>
     <div id="desc-day03">
      <p>
	GW-BASIC is a dialect of the BASIC programming language and it came with MS-DOS. It was open-sourced on May 21st 2020 under the MIT License. The famous BASIC game DONKEY.BAS is included as a demo.
      </p>
      <p>
       Size of download is 10.2 MB
      </p>
      
     </div>
     <p>
       <a href="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/download/gw-basic.tar.xz" role="button">Download</a>
     </p>
    </div>

    <div id="day-4">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day04" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 4" onclick="zonk('day04');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day04">Day 4</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 4th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-5">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day05" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 5" onclick="zonk('day05');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day05">Day 5</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 5th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-6">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day06" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 6" onclick="zonk('day06');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day06">Day 6</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 6th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-7">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day07" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 7" onclick="zonk('day07');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day07">Day 7</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 7th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-8">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day08" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 8" onclick="zonk('day08');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day08">Day 8</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 8th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-9">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day09" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 9" onclick="zonk('day09');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day09">Day 9</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 9th.
      </p>
     
    </div>


    <div id="day-10">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day10" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 10" onclick="zonk('day10');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day10">Day 10</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 10th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-11">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day11" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 11" onclick="zonk('day11');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day11">Day 11</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 11th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-12">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day12" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 12" onclick="zonk('day12');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day12">Day 12</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 12th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-13">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day13" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 13" onclick="zonk('day13');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day13">Day 13</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 13th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-14">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day14" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 14" onclick="zonk('day14');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day14">Day 14</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 14th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-15">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day15" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 15" onclick="zonk('day15');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day15">Day 15</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 15th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-16">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day16" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 16" onclick="zonk('day16');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day16">Day 16</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 16th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-17">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day17" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 17" onclick="zonk('day17');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day17">Day 17</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 17th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-18">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day18" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 18" onclick="zonk('day18');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day18">Day 18</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 18th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-19">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day19" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 19" onclick="zonk('day19');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day19">Day 19</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 19th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-20">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day20" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 20" onclick="zonk('day20');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day20">Day 20</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 20th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-21">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day21" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 21" onclick="zonk('day21');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day21">Day 21</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 21th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-22">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day22" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 22" onclick="zonk('day22');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day22">Day 22</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 22th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-23">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day23" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 23" onclick="zonk('day23');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day23">Day 23</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 23th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <div id="day-24">
     <p>
       <img id="img-day24" src="https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/images/closed-door.png" alt="Day 24" onclick="zonk('day24');">
     </p>
     <h2 id="title-day24">Day 24</h2>
     <p>
       Image will be available on December 24th.
      </p>
     
    </div>

    <hr>

    <div>

      <div id="about">
        <h2>About</h2>
        <p>
          The QEMU Advent Calendar 2020 features a QEMU disk image each day of
          December until the 24th. Each day a new package becomes available
          for download.
        </p>
        <p>
          Every download contains a little 'run' shell script that starts the
          QEMU emulator with the recommended parameters for the disk image.
          Disk images are either contained directly in the download or are
          downloaded by the 'run' script (you need to have installed 'curl' or
          'wget' in that case).
        </p>
        <p>
          The disk images contain interesting operating systems and software
          that run under the QEMU emulator. Some of them are well-known or
          not-so-well-known operating systems, old and new, others are custom
          demos and neat algorithms.
        </p>
        <p>
          The 'run' scripts (and disk images if included in the download)
          were created by volunteers from the QEMU community to showcase cool
          software that QEMU can run.
        </p>
      </div>

      

      <hr>

      

    </div><!-- /.container -->


    <!-- Bootstrap core JavaScript
    ================================================== -->
    <!-- Placed at the end of the document so the pages load faster -->
    
    
  

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.qemu-advent-calendar.org/2020/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25262608</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 05:23:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why do I care the open web is dying?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 239 | Comments 167 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25261132">thread link</a>) | @archajain
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://insightbrowser.com/blog/open-web-dying-why-care | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://insightbrowser.com/blog/open-web-dying-why-care">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><div><div><p><em>Part 1: How your user experience changes for the worse as the open web gives way to walled gardens</em></p><p>I hang out in two circles. Open web enthusiasts that are lamenting its demise, and regular users who are happy with their fast snappy apps and couldn't care less. </p><p>These groups have a hard time talking because the "open web" too often comes across as an idealistic abstract notion and most end users just don't tangibly feel the bad consequences. In fact, they're often happier with the snappy, vertically integrated experience of closed app ecosystems. </p><p>My goal here is to make it more palpable how everyday apps, searches and tools get worse when we let big centralized companies take over the web, and explore some paths for reversing it.</p><h2>What is the open web?</h2><p>Most definitions of the "open web" I've seen are either too technical to be accessible or too abstract to be usable and getting gridlocked in this debate often means watching from the sidelines while actual user welfare slowly diminishes.</p><p>Three characteristics that proponents of the open web will agree to in roughly descending order are:</p><ul><li><strong>Ease of publishing</strong>: anyone can publish to it freely or at least very cheaply, and is on the same footing with a globally accessible URL</li><li><strong>Ease of consuming</strong>: Net neutrality — ISP's dont cut deals with corporations to make some websites load faster or cheaper than others.</li><li><strong>Ease of remixing</strong>. You can see the source code. Content licenses and tools are permissive for derived works.</li></ul><h2>Detour: A framework to break down how people use the web</h2><p>I want to focus on the user experience point of view. To do this, I'm going to introduce a framework that divides up all our internet usage into two categories.</p><p><img src="https://landen.imgix.net/blog_uSsTzKptQlxlvUvQ/assets/xscGdbWOOPkGjdER.png" alt="Frame 1.png"></p><h3><strong>Unfamiliar problems</strong></h3><p>You have an unfamiliar problem and to solve it you either need to learn something new, or purchase goods or services to solve it</p><ul><li>e.g. taking out a mortgage, a health problem in the family, where to go to college, what skill to acquire next.</li><li>Unfamiliar problems are solved in large part with acquiring new knowledge, not just products or services.</li><li>These user journeys start with search engines — Google predominantly and **a lot of the time solving them is spent on web pages**.</li><li>When people are looking to solve unfamiliar problems, **revenue is typically higher-margin**, because users can't price the products and services as well.</li><li>These ultimately transition to being familiar problems.</li></ul><h3><strong>Familiar problems</strong></h3><ul><li>e.g. being entertained, keeping the dog food in stock,</li><li>These are best solved with apps like Email, Netflix, Twitter, DTC subscription boxes, etc.</li><li>Solving these needs has a very well defined user interaction journey. You open the app you're familiar with and follow its standard flow.</li><li>Revenue from people solving familiar problems is typically lower-margin and there's more competing products.
</li></ul><h3>How we're spending our time on familiar vs. unfamiliar problems</h3><p>Using time spent in apps vs mobile web on mobile is a way to proxy how we divide up our time.<strong> We spend most of our time on familiar problems but have a constant trickle of unfamiliar problems</strong>.</p><p><img src="https://landen.imgix.net/blog_uSsTzKptQlxlvUvQ/assets/cPuXkKFELALeIAkI.png" alt="Untitled (1).png"></p><h2>Unfamiliar problems are better solved with the open web</h2><p>Think about the last time you did some research, e.g. choosing a phone plan. You asked your friends, compared on forums, looked at the official sites, scribbled some notes and made a decision. Even if this journey was quick, you likely traversed a dozen services and products to do this.</p><p>Unfamiliar problems have less constraints, require creativity to solve, and thus are better suited to open solutions. Some other things that work for the open web here</p><ul><li>comparing alternatives is easier.</li><li>changing modalities (e.g. from reading to video) is easier.</li></ul><h2>Familiar problems stand to benefit more from tight vertical integration</h2><p>Take Spotify for example. It solves the very familiar problem of listening to music. Spotify just works better as an app because</p><ul><li>Controlling the user experience end to end makes for smoother flows.</li><li>Having all the user data kept with Spotify allows for better recommendation algorithms.</li><li>Spotify can easily hand off between devices.</li><li>It can run in the background</li></ul><p>Sure, the web can do a bunch of these things, but they're simply not first-class considerations in the open-read-close workflow that the browser was designed for.</p><h2>But the open web can be better for familiar problems too, especially for breaking monopolies</h2><p>Let's look at Amazon. Initially you start buying there because of their "always low prices" and the convenience of 2 day shipping. Over the years you keep shopping there, until you've forgotten that </p><ol><li>free 2 day shipping is now near universal</li><li>amazon isn't often the cheapest place</li></ol><p>On the Amazon app, you see the story around the product that best serves Amazon, not the buyer. Meanwhile, over on Insight you can use the web version and do all these things the app can't.</p><p><img src="https://landen.imgix.net/blog_uSsTzKptQlxlvUvQ/assets/ZEblynrLvBsutnlQ.png" alt="Screen Shot 2020-11-17 at 5.42.21 PM.png"></p><p>... and not just that

</p><p><img src="https://landen.imgix.net/blog_uSsTzKptQlxlvUvQ/assets/JVZoTRazmYPZXBQQ.png" alt="Screen Shot 2020-11-17 at 5.59.22 PM.png"></p><h2><strong>How solving unfamiliar problems gets harder too</strong></h2><p>Unfamiliar problems are solved in large part with acquiring new knowledge, not just products or services. The incentives to freely create knowledge that solves unfamiliar problems is lost as the web closes down.</p><ul><li>Google increasingly takes a larger percent of ad revenue as they <a href="https://sparktoro.com/blog/less-than-half-of-google-searches-now-result-in-a-click/">start extracting answers from pages and showing them on their search result pages.</a><a href="https://sparktoro.com/blog/less-than-half-of-google-searches-now-result-in-a-click/"></a></li><li><a href="https://sparktoro.com/blog/less-than-half-of-google-searches-now-result-in-a-click/"></a>Publishers have to either a) paywall their content (e.g. NYTimes) or b) subtly sell products (everyone standing a Wirecutter alternative), or c) ask for donations in order to survive.</li><li>Only a few big name publishers survive. Google and Facebook start sending them more of the traffic that's left, and since domain rank plays a big part in Google's ranking, those that survived assimilate more power and rank better.</li><li>and search engines seem more littered with SEO junk and less actually useful information year over year.</li></ul><h2>In conclusion, and where we fit in.</h2><p>And that's how your user experience slowly degrades, and that's why we stand to suffer as users if we give up the ability to remix software that the web brought us and closed apps are now taking away. </p><p>Our goal with Insight is to give the web (in particular on mobile) a fighting chance by exhibiting how it can be more powerful than a closed ecosystem and give more control to the end-user. We do this by showcasing the web's infinite extensibility and customizability for common use cases like <a href="http://insightbrowser.com/collections/search">search</a>, <a href="https://insightbrowser.com/collections/shopping">shopping</a>, <a href="https://insightbrowser.com/collections/reading">reading</a> and <a href="https://insightbrowser.com/collections/cooking">cooking</a>.</p><p>Insight's advanced features will soon only be available to Pro subscription users but for a limited time we're opening up <strong>lifetime free beta access if you download it via TestFlight below.</strong></p><h3>Coming up in part 2</h3><ul><li>What parts of the open web probably should die off?</li><li>A pragmatic path for what's left of the open web to thrive again.</li></ul><p>We'd love to hear from you, feel free to tweet at or DM us at @<a href="https://twitter.com/insightbrowser">insightbrowser</a>, and my personal Twitter is <a href="https://twitter.com/abhinavsharma">@abhinavsharma</a>.</p></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://insightbrowser.com/blog/open-web-dying-why-care</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25261132</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 01:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[H. G. Wells reviews "Metropolis" (1927)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 98 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25258616">thread link</a>) | @pmoriarty
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/H.G.Wells_on_Metropolis%201927.htm | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/H.G.Wells_on_Metropolis%201927.htm">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <blockquote>
    <blockquote>
      <blockquote>
              <p><i><span color="#00CCFF"> <img src="https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/metro200.jpg" width="286" height="208">H.G. 
                Wells wrote a review of the German film "Metropolis" 
                for the </span></i><span color="#00CCFF">New York Times</span><i><span color="#00CCFF"> 
                which was published on April 17, 1927. <p>
                
                Most people find the film (even in its surviving truncated versions) 
                rather brilliant, but Wells didn't like it much, perhaps because 
                he believes it was 'plagiarized' from his "When The Sleeper 
                Wakes."</p></span></i></p>
<p>I have recently seen the silliest film.  </p>
<p>I do not believe it
would be possible to make one sillier.  </p>
<p>And as this film sets out to display the
way the world is going,  </p>
<p>I think [my book] The Way the World is Going may very
well concern itself with this film.  </p>
<p>It is called Metropolis, it comes from the
great Ufa studios in Germany, and the public is given to understand that it has
been produced at enormous cost.  </p>
<p>It gives in one eddying concentration almost
every possible foolishness, cliché, platitude, and muddlement about mechanical
progress and progress in general served up with a sauce of sentimentality that
is all its own.</p>
<p><img src="https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/metro163.jpg" width="485" height="745"></p>
<p>It is a
German film and there have been some amazingly good German films, before they
began to cultivate bad work under cover of a protective quota. And this film has
been adapted to the Anglo-Saxon taste, and quite possibly it has suffered in the
process, but even when every allowance has been made for that, there remains
enough to convince the intelligent observer that most of its silliness must be
fundamental.  </p>
<p>Possibly I dislike this soupy whirlpool none the less because I
find decaying fragments of my own juvenile work of thirty years ago, The Sleeper
Awakes, floating about in it. </p>
<p>Capek's Robots have been lifted without apology,
and that soulless mechanical monster of Mary Shelley's, who has fathered so many
German inventions, breeds once more in this confusion.  </p>
<p>Originality there is
none. Independent thought, none.  </p>
<p>Where nobody has imagined for them the authors
have simply fallen back on contemporary things.  </p>
<p>The aeroplanes that wander about above the great city show no 
advance on contemporary types, though all that stuff could have been livened up 
immensely with a few helicopters and vertical or unexpected movements. </p>
<p>The motor cars are 1926 models or earlier. I do not think there 
is a single new idea, a single instance of artistic creation or even intelligent 
anticipation, from first to last in the whole pretentious stew; I may have 
missed some point of novelty, but I doubt it; and this, though it must bore the 
intelligent man in the audience, makes the film all the more convenient as a 
gauge of the circle of ideas, the mentality, from which it has proceeded.</p>
<p>The word Metropolis, says the advertisement in English, 'is
in itself symbolic of greatness'- which only shows us how wise it is to consult
a dictionary before making assertions about the meaning of words.  </p>
<p>Probably it
was the adapter who made that shot. The German 'Neubabelsburg' was better, and
could have been rendered 'New Babel'. It is a city, we are told, of 'about one
hundred years hence.' It is represented as being enormously high; and all the
air and happiness are above and the workers live, as the servile toilers in the
blue uniform in The Sleeper Awakes lived, down, down, down below.</p>
<p>Now far away in the dear old 1897 it may have been excusable
to symbolize social relations in this way, but that was thirty years ago, and a
lot of thinking and some experience intervene.  </p>
<p>That vertical city of the future
we know now is, to put it mildly, highly improbable. Even in New York and
Chicago, where the pressure on the central sites is exceptionally great, it is
only the central office and entertainment region that soars and excavates. And
the same centripetal pressure that leads to the utmost exploitation of site
values at the centre leads also to the driving out of industrialism and labour
from the population center to cheaper areas, and of residential life to more
open and airy surroundings. That was all discussed and written about before
1900. Somewhere about 1930 the geniuses of Ufa studios will come up to a book of
Anticipations which was written more than a quarter of a century ago. The
British census returns of 1901 proved clearly that city populations were
becoming centrifugal, and that every increase in horizontal traffic facilities
produced a further distribution. This vertical social stratification is stale
old stuff. So far from being 'a hundred years hence,' Metropolis, in its forms
and shapes, is already, as a possibility, a third of a century out of date.</p>
<p>But its form is the least part of its staleness. This great
city is supposed to be evoked by a single dominating personality. The English
version calls him John Masterman, so that there may be no mistake about his
quality. Very unwisely he has called his son Eric, instead of sticking to good
hard John, and so relaxed the strain. He works with an inventor, one Rotwang,
and they make machines. There are a certain number of other people, and the
'sons of the rich' are seen disporting themselves, with underclad ladies in a
sort of joy conservatory, rather like the 'winter garden' of an enterprising
1890 hotel during an orgy. The rest of the population is in a state of abject
slavery, working in 'shifts' of ten hours in some mysteriously divided
twenty-four hours, and with no money to spend or property or freedom. The
machines make wealth. How, is not stated. We are shown rows of motor cars all
exactly alike; but the workers cannot own these, and no 'sons of the rich'
would. Even the middle classes nowadays want a car with personality. Probably
Masterman makes these cars in endless series to amuse himself.</p>
              <p><span face="Times New Roman"><img src="https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/metro50.jpg" width="254" height="430"></span>One 
                is asked to believe that these machines are engaged quite furiously 
                in the mass production of nothing that is ever used, and that 
                Masterman grows richer and richer in the process. This is the 
                essential nonsense of it all. Unless the mass of the population 
                has the spending power there is no possibility of wealth in a 
                mechanical civilization. A vast, penniless slave population may 
                be necessary for wealth where there are no mass production machines, 
                but it is preposterous with mass production machines. You find 
                such a real proletariat in China still; it existed in the great 
                cities of the ancient world; but you do not find it in America, 
                which has gone furtherest in the direction of mechanical industry, 
                and there is no grain of reason in supposing it will exist in 
                the future. Masterman's watchword is 'Efficiency,' and you are 
                given to understand it is a very dreadful word, and the contrivers 
                of this idiotic spectacle are so hopelessly ignorant of all the 
                work that has been done upon industrial efficiency that they represent 
                him as working his machine-minders to the point of exhaustion, 
                so that they faint and machines explode and people are scalded 
                to death. You get machine-minders in torment turning levers in 
                response to signals - work that could be done far more effectively 
                by automata. Much stress is laid on the fact that the workers 
                are spiritless, hopeless drudges, working reluctantly and mechanically. 
                But a mechanical civilization has no use for mere drudges; the 
                more efficient its machinery the less need there is for the quasi-mechanical 
                minder. It is the inefficient factory that needs slaves; the ill-organized 
                mine that kills men. The hopeless drudge stage of human labour 
                lies behind us. With a sort of malignant stupidity this film contradicts 
                these facts.</p>
<p>The current tendency of economic life is to oust the mere
drudge altogether, to replace much highly skilled manual work by exquisite
machinery in skilled hands, and to increase the relative proportion of
semi-skilled, moderately versatile and fairly comfortable workers. It may indeed
create temporary masses of unemployed, and in The Sleeper Awakes there was a
mass of unemployed people under the hatches. That was written in 1897, when the
possibility of restraining the growth of large masses of population had scarcely
dawned on the world. It was reasonable then to anticipate an embarrassing
underworld of under-productive people. We did not know what to do with the
abyss. But there is no excuse for that today. And what this film anticipates is
not unemployment, but drudge employment, which is precisely what is passing
away. Its fabricators have not even realized that the machine ousts the drudge.</p>
<p>'Efficiency' means large-scale productions, machinery as
fully developed as possible, and <i>high</i> <i>wages</i>. The British
Government delegation sent to study success in America has reported unanimously
to that effect. The increasingly efficient industrialism of America has so
little need of drudges that it has set up the severest barriers against the
flooding of the United States by drudge immigration. 'Ufa' knows nothing of such
facts.</p>
<p>A young woman appears from nowhere in particular to 'help'
these drudges; she impinges upon Masterman's son Eric, and they go to the
'Catacombs,' which, in spite of the gas mains, steam mains, cables, and
drainage, have somehow contrived to get over from Rome, skeletons and all, and
burrow under this city of Metropolis. She conducts a sort of Christian worship
in these unaccountable caverns, and the drudges love and trust her. With a nice
sense of fitness she lights herself about the Catacombs with a torch instead of
the electric lamps that are now so common.</p>
<p>That reversion to torches is quite typical …</p></blockquote></blockquote></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/H.G.Wells_on_Metropolis%201927.htm">https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/H.G.Wells_on_Metropolis%201927.htm</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://erkelzaar.tsudao.com/reviews/H.G.Wells_on_Metropolis%201927.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25258616</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:34:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[DevRelOMeter]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25258465">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://leggetter.github.io/devrelometer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://leggetter.github.io/devrelometer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      <p>Are you practicing - or considering practicing - Developer <strong>Evangelism</strong> or <strong>Advocacy</strong>?</p>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://leggetter.github.io/devrelometer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25258465</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Stop Calling Us Frontline – We are your last resort]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 20 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25258390">thread link</a>) | @hispanic
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://jennifermilesky.com/2020/11/30/stop-calling-us-frontline-we-are-your-last-resort/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jennifermilesky.com/2020/11/30/stop-calling-us-frontline-we-are-your-last-resort/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-126">

	

	
			<figure>
				<img width="500" height="416" src="https://jennifermilesky.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/frontline-3.png?w=500" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://jennifermilesky.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/frontline-3.png 500w, https://jennifermilesky.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/frontline-3.png?w=150 150w, https://jennifermilesky.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/frontline-3.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="144" data-permalink="https://jennifermilesky.com/2020/11/30/stop-calling-us-frontline-we-are-your-last-resort/frontline/" data-orig-file="https://jennifermilesky.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/frontline-3.png" data-orig-size="500,416" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Frontline" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://jennifermilesky.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/frontline-3.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://jennifermilesky.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/frontline-3.png?w=500">			</figure><!-- .post-thumbnail -->

		
	<div>
		
<p>In the intensive care unit, patients receive treatment and therapies to prevent them from immediately dying. It’s not pleasant, but it’s true. You don’t want to come see us. </p>



<p>We see the signs and messages. “Thank you, Frontline Workers!” Honestly, it’s confusing. We aren’t your frontline. We are your last resort. And, after eight months, we are tired. Nurses are <a href="https://www.atsjournals.org/doi/full/10.1513/AnnalsATS.201804-269PS" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">burnt out</a>. Some organizations <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/2516043520957565" target="_blank">did not take care of their employees</a> well when COVID hit. Many nurses are leaving their jobs. Most units are experiencing staffing crises. There just simply aren’t enough nurses to take care of all of you. You don’t want to visit the ICU during normal circumstances. You certainly don’t want to be a patient in one now.</p>



<p>ICU beds usually run at about 70-80% capacity. It’s a sweet spot where the unit can function from an operational standpoint while still having bed availability for emergencies or cyclical unit flow. With the first wave of COVID, some ICUs were operating at 200-300% capacity. The bed crisis in itself wasn’t a huge one. A bed is a bed is a bed. Organizations simply <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://sccm.org/Blog/March-2020/United-States-Resource-Availability-for-COVID-19" target="_blank">opened more ICUs</a> in other areas of the hospital. It wasn’t pretty or comfortable, but it worked.</p>



<p>The real crisis came with <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.statnews.com/2020/11/19/covid19-hospitals-in-half-the-states-facing-massive-staffing-shortage/" target="_blank">staff</a>. Who was going to take care of all of these extra patients? Organizations employed many strategies. Nurses managed ICU patients <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://aacnjournals.org/ccnonline/article/40/4/25/31008/Answering-the-Call-Impact-of-Tele-ICU-Nurses" target="_blank">remotely,</a> sometimes from other states. Hospitals sought help from <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://khn.org/news/highly-paid-traveling-nurses-fill-staffing-shortages-during-covid-pandemic/" target="_blank">staffing agencies</a> and per diem staff. Non-ICU nurses were quickly “<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://rcni.com/nursing-standard/careers/career-advice/covid-19-what-to-expect-if-you-are-deployed-to-a-critical-care-setting-159646" target="_blank">upskilled</a>” to the critical care setting. In short, an already precarious situation just became even more dangerous.</p>



<p>Nurses new to the ICU setting usually go through an intense training program which includes classroom and clinical experience and ranges from three to six months in length. Upon completion of this program, they are still novice nurses and rely on their <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://healthresearchfunding.org/patricia-benner-novice-to-expert-nursing-theory-explained/" target="_blank">expert</a> colleagues for mentoring and guidance. As crucial as upskilled nurses are, they are still short on education, knowledge, and experience. In our current climate, nurses are working in unfamiliar environments, with a team they don’t know, with fewer resources, fewer experienced staff, and with higher staffing ratios. All of this can and will lead to <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://psnet.ahrq.gov/primer/nursing-and-patient-safety" target="_blank">unfavorable outcomes</a>.</p>



<p>COVID has now been around long enough that we are somewhat in a clinical routine. The patient H&amp;P’s (history and physical) are eerily similar. “Patient attended a family birthday party.” “Patient attended weekly bowling league.” “Masks were not worn.” “Attendees did not appropriately socially distance.” By the time the patient gets to us, they are in bad shape. </p>



<p>They can not breathe without the help of a ventilator. Breathing on a ventilator is very uncomfortable and unnatural. Lung injury in COVID is so profound that patients usually require the most extreme settings, which require heavy sedation and paralytics. If the patient still isn’t ventilating adequately, we will <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjKpvGr4KntAhUo2FkKHR_-DwoQFjAAegQIAhAC&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fjamanetwork.com%2Fjournals%2Fjama%2Ffullarticle%2F2769872&amp;usg=AOvVaw2mk45rzzxRWxBCOd7Thav5" target="_blank">prone</a> them. If their <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiypui74KntAhXwt1kKHWieAzAQFjAAegQIBhAC&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fannalsofintensivecare.springeropen.com%2Farticles%2F10.1186%2Fs13613-019-0552-5&amp;usg=AOvVaw16GntVT2DkGWTAypi9UjUC" target="_blank">kidneys shut down</a>, we will put them on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjT5ovF4KntAhXIjVkKHdweDu8QFjAEegQIBxAC&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.baxter.com%2Fperspectives%2Fhealthcare-insights%2Funderstanding-continuous-renal-replacement-therapy-crrt-covid-19&amp;usg=AOvVaw21OS75cAIaS1sC6qqNrR7H" target="_blank">dialysis</a>. If their blood pressure goes too low, we will put them on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwi-gJXp4KntAhUQjlkKHaSGCkcQFjABegQIBhAC&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov%2Fcritical-care%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw2cx171K92Nstkro2zgq9CE" target="_blank">continuous medication</a> to sustain life. If they spike an uncontrollable fever, we will put them on an ice blanket. We will bring iPads into the room and update families on the phone. The patient will be alone.</p>



<p>All of this will either work, or it won’t. The average ICU length of stay is <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://journals.lww.com/healthcaremanagerjournal/Abstract/2014/04000/Reduction_of_Intensive_Care_Unit_Length_of_Stay_.5.aspx#:~:text=The%20average%20ICU%20length%20of%20stay%20%28LOS%29%20is,an%20additional%201.5%20days%20in%20a%20non-ICU%20bed" target="_blank">3.3 days</a>. The average ICU length of stay with COVID is <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://bmcmedicine.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12916-020-01726-3" target="_blank">19 days</a>. Prior to COVID, over half of ICU patients experienced <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.posticu.org/" target="_blank">post intensive care syndrome (PICS)</a> after their discharge. This syndrome includes depression, anxiety, and cognitive deficits, sometimes limiting their ability to work or care for themselves. The after-effects of an ICU admission with COVID have not yet been studied. Those who don’t get better, will die. In high-surge states, their body will be moved to a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.webmd.com/lung/news/20201104/el-paso-gets-4th-mobile-morgue-as-deaths-surge" target="_blank">mobile morgue</a> because the hospital morgue has reached capacity. Families will be urged not to gather for a <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-rites-insight-idUSKBN2161ZM" target="_blank">funeral</a>. </p>



<p>This grim reality is not your frontline. Your frontline is:</p>



<p>Staying home<br>Social distancing<br>Mask wearing<br>Hand washing</p>



<p>If not for you, for your neighbor.</p>



<p>Stop calling us frontline. We are your last resort.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jennifermilesky.com/2020/11/30/stop-calling-us-frontline-we-are-your-last-resort/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25258390</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:15:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Objects in Functional Languages]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25258354">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/objects-in-functional-languages | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/objects-in-functional-languages">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Let's talk about objects in functional languages.</p>

<p>This could be a sticking point, so I'll get this out of the way up-front: I find arguments over whether such-and-such a thing is “really” functional or “really” imperative or “really” object-oriented to be for the most part frustrating and useless. A lot of these arguments boil down to value judgments in disguise (a thing I've touched on in the past when <a href="https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/proofs-and-programs-and-rhetoric" rel="nofollow">talking about the rhetorical emphasis placed on math in programming</a>) and many of the rest turn out to be based on informal definitions where 'functional' means 'like my favorite or first functional language'.<sup id="fnref:samp"><a href="#fn:samp" rel="nofollow">1</a></sup> I prefer to think about these concept less in terms of necessary criteria and hard lines, and more in terms of influence and approach and focus.</p>

<p>The paper <a href="http://www.cs.utexas.edu/~wcook/Drafts/2009/essay.pdf" rel="nofollow"><em>On Understanding Data Abstraction Revisited</em> by William Cook</a> (itself a paper that revisits <a href="http://lucacardelli.name/Papers/OnUnderstanding.A4.pdf" rel="nofollow"><em>On understanding data types, data abstraction, and polymorphism</em> by Luca Cardelli and Peter Wegner</a>) lays out simple definitions of the often-used concepts of “abstract data type” and “object”. His definition of “object” is, of course, not the only one, but I think it's a useful one. Importantly, Cook's definition is based on abstract criteria that can apply even when the language itself does not have an explicit concept of an “object”. To emphasize this, I'm going to use Haskell in this blog post to demonstrate a pure functional variation on “object-oriented programming”<sup id="fnref:lang"><a href="#fn:lang" rel="nofollow">2</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Beyond being a useful definition, Cook's formulation is also a valuable design pattern, one which has both advantages and disadvantages when designing programs. Consequently, the goal of this blog post is twofold: first, to show how “objects” can (under some definition) exist in a language like Haskell which has no built-in notion of “object-oriented programming”, and secondly, to show the advantages and disadvantages of code written in this style.</p>



<p>Cook's definition of an <em>abstract data type</em> is a type that</p>

<blockquote><p>[…] has a public name, a hidden representation, and operations to create, combine, and observe values of the abstraction.</p></blockquote>

<p>To use a simplified version of his example, here's a (not terribly efficient) way of defining a “set of integers” in Haskell as an abstract data type. In this case, we've got an <code>IntSet</code> type whose representation can be easily hidden, because the operations that a consumer of this library cares about about have been defined in terms of that abstract representation.</p>

<pre><code>-- we'll export `IntSet` but not the constructors
data IntSet
  = SetEmpty
  | SetInsert Int IntSet

empty :: IntSet
empty = SetEmpty

isEmpty :: IntSet -&gt; Bool
isEmpty SetEmpty = True
isEmpty _ = False

insert :: Int -&gt; IntSet -&gt; IntSet
insert x set
  | contains set x = set
  | otherwise = SetInsert x set

contains :: IntSet -&gt; Int -&gt; Bool
contains SetEmpty x = False
contains (SetInsert y rest) x
  | x == y = True
  | otherwise = contains rest x
</code></pre>

<p>This is probably not a terribly controversial definition or design: it's a pretty typical one for most functional languages! …well, it might be controversial to <em>use</em> since it's got awful algorithmic performance, but it's fairly unobjectionable as a teaching tool, at least.</p>

<p>What would a user see when looking at the documentation for this module? Since we're not exporting the constructors for <code>IntSet</code>, it'll look something like this:</p>

<pre><code>data IntSet
empty :: IntSet
isEmpty :: IntSet -&gt; Bool
insert :: Int -&gt; IntSet -&gt; IntSet
contains :: Int -&gt; IntSet -&gt; Bool
</code></pre>

<p>The ability to hide the definition of <code>IntSet</code> is the thing that makes this an abstract data type. A user of the library doesn't care—and ideally doesn't <em>need</em> to care—what constructors hide behind that <code>IntSet</code>.</p>



<p>Cook then goes on to describe “objects”. Here's another (equally inefficient) implementation of <code>IntSet</code>, which I'll define as <code>OIntSet</code> so I can easily refer to both:</p>

<pre><code>data OIntSet = OIntSet
  { oIsEmpty :: Bool
  , oContains :: Int -&gt; Bool
  }

oEmpty :: OIntSet
oEmpty = OIntSet
  { oIsEmpty = True
  , oContains = \_ -&gt; False
  }

oInsert :: Int -&gt; OIntSet -&gt; OIntSet
oInsert x set
  | oContains set x = set
  | otherwise = OIntSet
      { oIsEmpty = False
      , oContains = \i -&gt; i == x || oContains set i
      }
</code></pre>

<p>It's possible that we can choose our export list carefully so that this implementation of <code>OIntSet</code> reveals the exact same set of operations as the previous one. However, there's a major difference here: <code>OIntSet</code> is not actually hiding a specific type. Instead, it just bundles the relevant set of operations inside of a record of functions, which acts like an interface type. In both the ADT-based approach and the “object”-based approach, a user does not know about the internal representation of <code>OIntSet</code>, but in the ADT approach, this is because there exists a single representation which is non-public, while in the “object”-based approach, there may be multiple separate implementations that are indistinguishable.</p>



<p>An “object”-like representation allows for a vast amount of flexibility. Because a consumer of an <code>OIntSet</code> can use any value as long as the value has provided implementations of the relevant “methods”, we can easily and conveniently define new instances of <code>OIntSet</code> that have radically different internal representations. For example, we can define infinite sets that use simple numerical computations to define their <code>oContains</code> method, like this set of all even numbers:</p>

<pre><code>oEvenNumbers :: OIntSet
oEvenNumbers = OIntSet
  { oIsEmpty = False
  , oContains = \i -&gt; i `mod` 2 == 0
  }
</code></pre>

<p>Or we could construct <code>OIntSet</code> values that use a different data representation, such as a list, to store the members of the set:</p>

<pre><code>oFromList :: [Int] -&gt; OIntSet
oFromList list = OIntSet
  { oIsEmpty = null list
  , oContains = \i -&gt; i `elem` list
  }
</code></pre>

<p>But even though these <code>OIntSet</code> definitions use different underlying data representations, they expose the same interface, so we can use the same operations to manipulate them. For example, we can define an <code>oUnion</code> operation which computes the union of two <code>OIntSet</code> objects, since that operation is easily expressible in terms of <code>oIsEmpty</code> and <code>oContains</code>:</p>

<pre><code>oUnion :: OIntSet -&gt; OIntSet -&gt; OIntSet
oUnion set set' = OIntSet
  { oIsEmpty = oIsEmpty set &amp;&amp; oIsEmpty set'
  , oContains = \i -&gt; oContains set i || oContains set' i
  }
</code></pre>

<p>Our <code>oUnion</code> operation—indeed, any operation we define—can work on any two <code>OIntSet</code>s even if they have wildly different internal representations. We can even use this to combine all of our previously-defined <code>OIntSet</code> constructors into one expression, to create a set that uses a combination of Haskell lists, numeric predicates, and closures to represent a set:</p>

<pre><code>sample :: OIntSet
sample = oInsert 1 oEvenNumbers `oUnion` oFromList [10..20]
</code></pre>

<p>This is a very convenient way of building certain abstractions. By building around external interfaces, you can include varying data representations that easily work together.</p>

<p>This example is clearly a little bit contrived, so it's probably worth giving some other “real-world” examples where this design approach is useful. Object-oriented programming is generally cited as a good fit for a particular style of user interface programming, because it allows you to define classes of “widgets” that expose a common interface but have different internal representations. You could build a Haskell GUI library in this style by defining <code>Widgets</code> as “objects” with a common interface, something like this:</p>

<pre><code>data Widget = Widget
  { drawWidget :: Ctx -&gt; Position -&gt; IO ()
  , handleEvent :: Event -&gt; IO ()
  }
</code></pre>

<p>This is similar to the approach taken by the <a href="https://github.com/jtdaugherty/brick/" rel="nofollow">Brick TUI library</a>, which has <a href="http://hackage.haskell.org/package/brick-0.54/docs/Brick-Types.html#t:Widget" rel="nofollow">its own <code>Widget</code> record</a>.</p>



<p>One major concern with this style of data representation is performance and optimization. Consider our original ADT representation for <code>IntSet</code>: it's inefficient, yes, but we can make it more efficient in a number of ways. For example, we could modify it so that, instead of always inserting new elements “at the front”, we can instead insert them in such a way that the internal representation of the set is always sorted lowest-to-highest. This means that we may no longer have to traverse the entire list to check for element membership. Even better, we might swap out the list-like representation for a binary tree representation, maybe doing some rebalancing in certain cases.</p>

<p>There is no way <em>in general</em> to apply these optimizations to the <code>OIntSet</code>-style program. You could define an <code>OIntSet</code> that sits in front of a balanced tree and therefore has faster lookup and insertion, but once it's sitting behind the interface, you no longer have access to those internals. You cannot, for example, write an <code>oUnion</code> operation that rebalances the binary trees behind the two sets it's operating on: it doesn't even know if both sets <em>are</em> backed by trees!</p>

<p>In effect, the major selling point of the “object”-style design here is also a major downside: you don't have guarantees about the specific representation of data, which means your programs can easily mix-and-match different representations, but it also means that your program can't make use of representation-specific knowledge in ways that are advantageous.</p>

<p>There's another major concern as well, and that's that the specific choice of “object” representation can make a big difference in terms of what operations you can and cannot support. Look back at <code>OIntSet</code>—I was able to define <code>oUnion</code>, but what about <code>oIntersection</code>? It turns out that it's not actually possible using the specific representation I've chosen<sup id="fnref:perf"><a href="#fn:perf" rel="nofollow">3</a></sup>:</p>

<pre><code>oIntersection :: OIntSet -&gt; OIntSet -&gt; OIntSet
oIntersection set set' = OIntSet
  { oIsEmpty = {- ??? -}
  , oIntersection = \i -&gt; oContains set i &amp;&amp; oContains set' i
  }
</code></pre>

<p>How do I implement <code>oIsEmpty</code>? I might naïvely try to write the inverse of <code>oUnion</code> and define it as <code>oIsEmpty set || oIsEmpty set'</code>, but that's not at all what I want: the intersection of the set of even numbers and the set of odd numbers is an empty set, but neither the even nor the odd numbers are empty, so this would incorrectly compute their …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/objects-in-functional-languages">https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/objects-in-functional-languages</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/objects-in-functional-languages</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25258354</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 20:13:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Running a full desktop environment on a Kindle (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 173 | Comments 49 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25257772">thread link</a>) | @slondr
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://nns.ee/blog/2019/04/14/chroot-shenanigans-2.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nns.ee/blog/2019/04/14/chroot-shenanigans-2.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><a href="https://nns.ee/blog/2019/03/21/chroot-shenanigans.html">In my previous post</a>, I described running Arch on an OpenWRT router. Today, I’ll be taking it a step further and running Arch and a full LXDE installation natively on an Amazon Kindle, which can be interacted with directly using the touch screen. This is possible thanks to the Kindle’s operating system being Linux!
<!--description--></p>

<p>You can see the end result in action <a href="https://youtu.be/Bx386xpDqCY">here</a>. Apologies for the shaky video - it was shot using my phone and no tripod.</p>

<p>If you’re wanting to follow along, make sure you’ve <a href="https://wiki.mobileread.com/wiki/5_x_Jailbreak">rooted your Kindle</a> beforehand. This is essential – without it, it’s impossible to run custom scripts or binaries.</p>

<p>I’m testing this on an 8th generation Kindle (KT3) – it should, however, work for all recent Kindles given you’ve enough storage and are rooted. You also need to set up <a href="https://www.mobileread.com/forums/showthread.php?t=225030">USBnetwork</a> for SSH access and optionally <a href="https://www.mobileread.com/forums/showthread.php?t=203326">KUAL</a> if you want a simple way of launching the chroot.</p>

<p>First things first: We need to set up a filesystem and extract an Arch installation into it, which we can later chroot into. The filesystem will be a file which will be mounted as a loop device. The reason why we’re not extracting the Arch installation directly into a directory on the Kindle is because the Kindle’s storage filesystem is FAT32. FAT32 doesn’t support required features such as symbolic links, which would break the Arch installation. Please note that this also means that your chroot filesystem can be 4 gigabytes large, at maximum. This can be worked around by mounting the real root inside the chroot filesystem, which it’s still a hacky way to go about it. But I digress.</p>

<p>First, figure out how large your filesystem actually can be. SSH into your Kindle and see how much free space you have:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span>ssh root@192.168.15.244
<span>
</span><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>df</span> <span>-k</span> /mnt/base-us
<span>Filesystem   1K-blocks  Used    Available  Use%  Mounted on
/dev/loop/0  3188640    361856  2826784    11%   /mnt/base-us
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Seems like we have around 2800000K (around 2.8G) of space available. Let’s make our filesystem 2.6G – it’s enough to host our root filesystem and some extra applications, such as LXDE. Note that I’ll be running the following commands on my PC and transferring the filesystem over later. You can also do all of this on the Kindle, but it’s simply easier and faster this way.</p>

<p>Let’s create a blank file of the wanted size. I’m using <code>dd</code>, but you can also use <code>fallocate</code> for this:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span><span>dd </span><span>if</span><span>=</span>/dev/zero <span>of</span><span>=</span>arch.img <span>bs</span><span>=</span>1024 <span>count</span><span>=</span>2600000
<span>2600000+0 records in
2600000+0 records out
2662400000 bytes (2.7 GB, 2.5 GiB) copied, 6.92058 s, 385 MB/s
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Let’s create our filesystem on it. Since we’re doing this on the PC, we need make it 32bit and disable the <code>metadata_csum</code> and <code>huge_file</code> options on the filesystem, as the Kindle’s ext4 kernel doesn’t support them.</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span>mkfs.ext4 <span>-O</span> ^64bit,^metadata_csum,^huge_file arch.img
<span>mke2fs 1.45.0 (6-Mar-2019)
Discarding device blocks: done                            
Creating filesystem with 650000 4k blocks and 162560 inodes
Filesystem UUID: a4e72620-368a-44b4-81bb-9e66b2903523
Superblock backups stored on blocks: 
	32768, 98304, 163840, 229376, 294912

Allocating group tables: done                            
Writing inode tables: done                            
Creating journal (16384 blocks): done
Writing superblocks and filesystem accounting information: done 
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is optional, but I’ll also disable periodic filesystem checks on it:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span>tune2fs <span>-c</span> 0 <span>-i</span> 0 arch.img                               
<span>tune2fs 1.45.0 (6-Mar-2019)         
Setting maximal mount count to -1
Setting interval between checks to 0 seconds
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Next it’s time to mount the filesystem:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span><span>mkdir </span>rootfs
<span>$</span><span> </span><span>sudo </span>mount <span>-o</span> loop arch.img rootfs/
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The Kindle I’m using has a Cortex-A9-based processor, so let’s download the ARMv7 version of Arch Linux ARM from <a href="http://os.archlinuxarm.org/os/ArchLinuxARM-armv7-latest.tar.gz">here</a>. You can download it and extract then, or simply download and extract at the same time:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span>curl <span>-L</span> http://os.archlinuxarm.org/os/ArchLinuxARM-armv7-latest.tar.gz | <span>sudo tar </span>xz <span>-C</span> rootfs/
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><code>sudo</code> is required to extract as it sets up a lot of files with root permissions. You can ignore the errors about <code>SCHILY.fflags</code>. Verify that the files extracted successfully with <code>ls -l rootfs/</code>.</p>

<p>Let’s prepare our Kindle for the filesystem. I opted for hosting the filesystem in <code>extensions/karch</code> as I want to use KUAL for easy launching:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span>ssh root@192.168.15.244
<span>
</span><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>mkdir</span> <span>-p</span> /mnt/base-us/extensions/karch
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>While we’re here, it’s also a good idea to stop the power daemon to prevent the Kindle from going into sleep mode while transferring the filesystem and interrupting our transfer:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span>stop powerd
<span>powerd stop/waiting
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Let’s transfer our filesystem:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>exit</span>
<span>Connection to 192.168.15.244 closed.

</span><span>$</span><span> </span>scp arch.img root@192.168.15.244:/mnt/base-us/extensions/karch/
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This might take quite a bit of time, depending on your connection.</p>

<p>Once it’s done, let’s SSH in once again and set up our mountpoint:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$</span><span> </span>ssh root@192.168.15.244
<span>
</span><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>cd</span> /mnt/base-us/extensions/karch/
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>mkdir </span>system
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I decided to set up my own loop device, so I can have it named, but you can ignore this and opt to use <code>/dev/loop/12</code> or similar instead. Just make sure it’s already not in use with <code>mount</code>.</p>

<p>Setting up a loop point and mounting the filesystem:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>mknod</span> <span>-m0660</span> /dev/loop/karch b 7 250
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span>mount <span>-o</span> <span>loop</span><span>=</span>/dev/loop/karch <span>-t</span> ext4 arch.img system/
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We should also mount some system directories into it:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span>mount <span>-o</span> <span>bind</span> /dev system/dev
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span>mount <span>-o</span> <span>bind</span> /dev/pts system/dev/pts
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span>mount <span>-o</span> <span>bind</span> /proc system/proc
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span>mount <span>-o</span> <span>bind</span> /sys system/sys
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span>mount <span>-o</span> <span>bind</span> /tmp system/tmp
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>cp</span> /etc/hosts system/etc/
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It’s time to chroot into our new system and set it up for LXDE. You can also use this opportunity to set up whatever applications you need, such as an onscreen keyboard:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>chroot </span>system/ /bin/bash
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span><span>echo</span> <span>'en_US.UTF-8 UTF-8'</span> <span>&gt;</span> /etc/locale.gen 
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>locale-gen
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span><span>rm</span> /etc/resolv.conf 
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span><span>echo</span> <span>'nameserver 8.8.8.8'</span> <span>&gt;</span> /etc/resolv.conf
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>pacman-key <span>--init</span> <span># this will take a while</span>
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>pacman-key <span>--populate</span>
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>pacman <span>-Syu</span> <span>--noconfirm</span>
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>pacman <span>-S</span> lxde xorg-server-xephyr <span>--noconfirm</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We use Xephyr because it’s the easiest way to get our LXDE session up and running. Since the Kindle uses X11 natively, we can try using that. It’s possible to stop the native window manager using <code>stop lab126_gui</code> outside the chroot, but then the Kindle will stop updating the screen with new data, leaving it blank – forcing you to use something like <code>eips</code> to refresh the screen. The X server still works, however, and you can confirm this by using something like <code>x11vnc</code> after running your own WM in it. Xephyr spawns a new X server inside the preexisting X server, which is not as efficient but a lot easier.</p>

<p>We can however stop everything else related to the native GUI, as we need the extra memory and we can’t use it while LXDE is running anyways:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>chroot#</span><span> </span><span>exit</span>
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>SERVICES</span><span>=</span><span>"framework pillow webreader kb contentpackd"</span>
<span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>for </span>service <span>in</span> <span>${</span><span>SERVICES</span><span>}</span><span>;</span> <span>do </span>stop <span>${</span><span>service</span><span>}</span><span>;</span> <span>done</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>While we’re here, we need to get the screen size for later:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span>eips <span>-i</span> | <span>grep</span> <span>'xres:'</span> | <span>awk</span> <span>'{print $2"x"$4}'</span>
<span>600x800
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Let’s chroot back into the system and see if we can get LXDE to run. Be sure to replace the screen size parameter if needed:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>chroot </span>system/ /bin/bash
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span><span>export </span><span>DISPLAY</span><span>=</span>:0
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>Xephyr :1 <span>-title</span> <span>"L:A_N:application_ID:xephyr"</span> <span>-screen</span> 600x800 <span>-cc</span> 4 <span>-nocursor</span> &amp;
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span><span>export </span><span>DISPLAY</span><span>=</span>:1
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>lxsession &amp;
<span>chroot#</span><span> </span>xrandr <span>-o</span> right
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If everything goes well, you should have LXDE visible on your Kindle’s screen. Ta-da! Feel free to play around with it. I’ve found that the touch screen is suprisingly accurate, even though it is using an IR LED system to detect touches instead of a normal digitizer.</p>

<p>Once done in the chroot, Ctrl-C + Ctrl-D can be issued to exit the chroot. We can then restore the Kindle UI by doing:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>kindle#</span><span> </span><span>for </span>service <span>in</span> <span>${</span><span>SERVICES</span><span>}</span><span>;</span> <span>do </span>start <span>${</span><span>service</span><span>}</span><span>;</span> <span>done</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It might take a while for anything to display again.</p>

<p>I’ve mentioned setting up a KUAL extension to automate the entering and exiting of the chroot. You can find that <a href="https://github.com/neonsea/karch">here</a>. If you’re interested in using this, make sure you’ve set up your filesystem first and copied it over to the same directory as the extension, and that it’s named <code>arch.img</code>. Everything else is not mandatory - the extension will do it for you.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nns.ee/blog/2019/04/14/chroot-shenanigans-2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25257772</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:25:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Adopt your elePHPant now, the only original PHP elephant]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25257657">thread link</a>) | @waskip
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://www.elephpant.com/elephpant | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.elephpant.com/elephpant">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><div><div><p>00:02:03,010 --&gt; 00:02:06,333</p><p>(fr) Je suis le créateur de cet éléphant, c'est la mascotte du language PHP.</p><p>00:02:06,333 --&gt; 00:02:11,700</p><p>(fr) Je l'ai dessiné en 1998. Depuis, il a été adopté par la communauté PHP toute entière.</p><p>00:02:11,700 --&gt; 00:02:14,766</p><p>(fr) Il est le symbole de l'intelligence collective de PHP.</p><p>00:02:14,766 --&gt; 00:02:17,250</p><p>(en) Some of you known me, others do not.</p><p>00:02:17,250 --&gt; 00:02:21,000</p><p>(en) I am the creator of this elephant, it is the mascot of the PHP language.</p><p>00:02:21,000 --&gt; 00:02:26,690</p><p>(en) I drew it in 1998. Since then, it has been adopted by the PHP community.</p><p>00:02:26,690 --&gt; 00:02:30,500</p><p>(en) It is the symbol of the collective intelligence of PHP.</p><p>00:02:30,510 --&gt; 00:02:35,100</p><p>(fr) Il n'y a pas si longtemps, 90% des sites mondiaux sur le Web étaient développés en PHP.</p><p>00:02:35,110 --&gt; 00:02:39,900</p><p>(fr) Quel merveilleux succès ! Je pense à toi, Rasmus. À ta façon tu as changé le monde du digital !</p><p>00:02:40,133 --&gt; 00:02:44,600</p><p>(en) Not so long ago, 90% of the worldwide websites were built using PHP.</p><p>00:02:44,620 --&gt; 00:02:49,933</p><p>(en) What a wonderful success ! I think to you, Rasmus. In your way, you changed the digital world !</p><p>00:02:49,950 --&gt; 00:02:55,666</p><p>(fr) Au travers de cet éléphant, vous avez dès maintenant l'opportunité de vous offrir une partie de l'histoire d'internet.</p><p>00:02:56,200 --&gt; 00:03:01,200</p><p>(fr) L'histoire d'une communauté PHP qui a transformé et continuera à transformer le monde.</p><p>00:03:01,346 --&gt; 00:03:06,750</p><p>(en) Through this elephant, you have the opportunity to offer yourself a part of the internet history.</p><p>00:03:06,766 --&gt; 00:03:12,400</p><p>(en) The story of a PHP community that has transformed and will continue to transform the world.</p><p>00:03:12,372 --&gt; 00:03:16,500</p><p>(fr) Où que vous soyez dans ce monde, vous pouvez recevoir cet éléphant maintenant.</p><p>00:03:16,700 --&gt; 00:03:22,250</p><p>(fr) Cliquez juste sur le bouton qui vient juste de s'afficher en dessous et contactez-moi personnellement par Messenger.</p><p>00:03:22,250 --&gt; 00:03:27,750</p><p>(fr) Indiquez-moi juste votre pays, et je vous donnerais le prix exact pour une livraison à votre porte.</p><p>00:03:27,760 --&gt; 00:03:29,900</p><p>(fr) Cerise sur le gâteau, je ferais moi-même le colis.</p><p>00:03:30,000 --&gt; 00:03:33,566</p><p>(en) Wherever you are in this world, you can receive this elephant now.</p><p>00:03:33,575 --&gt; 00:03:37,800</p><p>(en) Just click on the button that just appeared below and contact me personally by Messenger.</p><p>00:03:37,850 --&gt; 00:03:43,300</p><p>(en) Just tell me your country, and I will give you the exact price to deliver your elephant to your door.</p><p>00:03:43,310 --&gt; 00:03:46,288</p><p>(en) Cherry on the cake, I will make the package myself.</p><p>00:03:46,300 --&gt; 00:03:51,500</p><p>(fr) N'oubliez pas, vous êtes 5 millions sur cette terre à être passionnés par le language PHP.</p><p>00:03:51,500 --&gt; 00:03:54,500</p><p>(fr) Continuez le merveilleux travail que vous faites depuis des années.</p><p>00:03:54,550 --&gt; 00:03:59,500</p><p>(fr) Je sais que vous donnez le meilleur chaque jour pour faire de ce monde, un monde meilleur.</p><p>00:03:59,600 --&gt; 00:04:04,404</p><p>(en) Do not forget, you are 5 million on this earth to be passionate about the PHP language.</p><p>00:04:04,410 --&gt; 00:04:07,800</p><p>(en) Continue the wonderful work you have been doing for years.</p><p>00:04:07,850 --&gt; 00:04:12,600</p><p>(en) I know you are giving your best every day to make this world a better world.</p><p>00:04:12,650 --&gt; 00:04:16,500</p><p>ResPHPect ! - ResPHPect à vous !</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.elephpant.com/elephpant</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25257657</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:16:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Grist, a Hacker Friendly Spreadsheet]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25257521">thread link</a>) | @paulfitz
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://www.getgrist.com/blog | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.getgrist.com/blog">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

<!-- Google Tag Manager (noscript) -->

<!-- End Google Tag Manager (noscript) -->

		

		<section>
  <div>

    <div>
      <div>
        <div>

          

<div>
<div><p><a href="https://www.pcjs.org/software/pcx86/app/other/visicalc/1981/"><img alt="VisiCalc" src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/blog/visicalc.jpg"></a></p>
</div>
<p>
Spreadsheets attract people with a hacker mindset, since they reward a
little technical curiosity with a big jump in capability. Despite
that, while there are some open source spreadsheet projects, most of
the action is closed source (Excel, Airtable, Honeycode, etc). Grist is a solid,
modern, powerful spreadsheet that fits well into the open-source
ecology, and is as friendly to hacker-developers as it is to
hacker-users. Here are some reasons why.
</p>
</div>

<div>
<p><img alt="Linked sections" src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/blog/links.webp"></p>
<p>
Grist borrows visually from classic spreadsheets and modern
dashboards, with every view backed by relational data, filtered and
linked with other views as needed. Grist takes care of the data, and keeping
it live, so custom views are easy to add if you need something new,
using <a href="https://support.getgrist.com/widget-custom/#minimal-example">standard HTML/JS/CSS</a>. For example, live-updating
<a href="https://support.getgrist.com/examples/2020-08-invoices/">invoices</a>,
<a href="https://support.getgrist.com/examples/2020-10-print-labels/">mailing labels</a>,
<a href="https://docs.getgrist.com/iqhzhQM66qg7/Pedigree-Example/m/fork/p/2#a1.s3.r11.c2">goat pedigrees</a>,
 <a href="https://public.getgrist.com/doc/exoplanets/m/fork">exoplanet birthday card</a>,
 or <a href="https://docs.getgrist.com/qctFijX9HUZu/Morse-Code/m/fork/p/2">morse code quizzer</a> that look just how you want them.
</p>
</div>

<div>
<p><img alt="datasette" src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/blog/datasette.png"></p>
<p>
Grist is a <a href="https://support.getgrist.com/exports/#backing-up-an-entire-document">self-contained format</a>, based on SQLite. Grist tables
are literally SQLite tables, which opens up all sorts of possibilities.
For example, I can take a Grist
<a href="https://docs.getgrist.com/doc/investment-research">example investment spreadsheet</a>
and publish it using Simon Willison’s <a href="https://github.com/simonw/datasette">datasette</a>
as a <a href="https://candy-tourmaline-efraasia.glitch.me/data/Investments">Glitch remix</a>
without any conversion steps needed. This is a step up from exporting CSV.
</p>
</div>

<div>
<p><img alt="python formulas" src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/blog/spots-left.png"></p>
<p>
Grist uses <a href="https://support.getgrist.com/functions/">python as its formula language</a>. Python has a good standard
library, nice syntax for working with lists, and is a favorite of data
scientists. Grist itself is written in TypeScript, with formula
evaluation isolated in a sandbox.
</p>
</div>

<div>
<p><img alt="data diff" src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/blog/diff.png"></p>

<p>
The Grist format makes it easy to find the most recent common ancestor
of two versions of a document, facilitating three-way comparisons and
git-style revision control. When working on a Grist spreadsheet with someone,
you can use real-time collaborative editing -
or you may sometimes prefer to
<a href="https://support.getgrist.com/copying-docs/#trying-out-changes">“fork” your spreadsheet</a>,
make a set of changes,
<a href="https://docs.getgrist.com/syx4YUwXdDyP/NYC-Bridges?compare=syx4YUwXdDyPELJUEqShA9~o4CKdSVuVQfGbyHCXctpqV~4">compare them with the original</a>
and then land them back.  We’re excited to flesh this workflow
out, and I think any programmer can see where we’re going with it.
</p>
</div>

<div>
<div>
  <p><a href="https://github.com/gristlabs/grist-core"><img alt="License" src="https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache%202.0-blue.svg"></a>
  </p>

  <!-- Place this tag where you want the button to render. -->
  
  
</div>

<p>
Grist code is available at <a href="https://github.com/gristlabs/grist-core">github.com/gristlabs/grist-core</a>
under a standard free and open source licence (Apache 2.0).
Grist software is developed by Grist Labs, which offers <a href="https://www.getgrist.com/pricing">free and paid
hosting plans</a>. Whether you choose us to host your spreadsheets,
or to run Grist yourself, you have the comfort of knowing the developers have revenue
(so they won’t one day vanish in the morning sun like an elusive gleam of dew on a flower),
and you have the code and your data (ditto).
</p>
</div>

<div>
<p><a href="https://jsfiddle.net/ondras/hYfN3/"><img alt="spreadsheet jsfiddle" src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/blog/fiddle.png"></a></p>
<p>
“Fiddle” sites are very handy for communicating and learning about a
technology. I know I learned a lot about javascript by playing
with this 30-line implemention of a spreadsheet:
<a href="https://jsfiddle.net/ondras/hYfN3/">https://jsfiddle.net/ondras/hYfN3/</a>. Grist supports fiddles almost by
accident, because you can <a href="https://docs.getgrist.com/">use Grist without logging in</a>,
and you can quickly edit a “fork” of a spreadsheet without changing your original.
Here, try <a href="https://docs.getgrist.com/doc/afterschool-program/m/fork">fiddling with one of our examples</a>. You won’t break it.
</p>
</div>

<p>Grist supports <a href="https://support.getgrist.com/col-types/#attachment-columns">attachments</a>, and those attachments can be downloaded as part of a
single Grist file format.
Grist has solid undo/redo support.
Hosted Grist makes <a href="https://support.getgrist.com/automatic-backups/">automatic backups</a> at hourly, daily, monthly, and yearly intervals.
Grist has <a href="https://support.getgrist.com/rest-api/">an API</a> and a <a href="https://zapier.com/apps/grist/integrations">Zapier integration</a>.
Grist supports real time collaboration.
Grist supports many <a href="https://support.getgrist.com/functions/">Excel functions</a>.
We publish a Grist docker image (see the <a href="https://github.com/gristlabs/grist-core#grist">README</a>),
and have an unreleased standalone app for Windows/Mac/Linux that we’ll be bringing
up to date.
</p>

<div>
<div><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plimpton_322"><img alt="Plimpton 322 tablet" src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/blog/Plimpton322.jpg"></a></p>
</div>

<p>
Spreadsheets have evolved a lot since <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plimpton_322">Babylonian times</a>.
In open-source, <a href="http://www.gnumeric.org/">Gnumeric</a> and <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/LibreOffice_Calc">Calc</a> are venerable standalone
Excel replacements.
<a href="https://github.com/mengshukeji/Luckysheet">LuckySheet</a> is a shot at a clone of that standalone experience in the browser.
<a href="https://github.com/audreyt/ethercalc/">Ethercalc</a> is a real-time collaborative spreadsheet, developed by
Audrey Tang, now Taiwan’s Digital Minister, extending work they did with Dan Bricklin on SocialCalc.
Evolving further, hybrid spreadsheet-database models are growing in usefulness and
popularity. That's what Grist is, and we are pleased to bring it now
to the open-source community.
</p>
</div>

<p>Spreadsheets have a long tail of features that are “must haves” for someone out there.
We think a quality, open code base is a big help for realizing those features, and having
peace of mind in relying on them.
Just as Babylonian clay tablets were, we hope that Grist will prove a
sturdy data storage and presentation infrastructure that
can survive for years (if not centuries!) to come.
</p>

<p>Come play with <a href="https://www.getgrist.com/">hosted Grist</a>, or
explore and build <a href="https://github.com/gristlabs/grist-core">Grist
source code</a>. In either case, we'd be grateful for your feedback at
<a href="https://twitter.com/getgrist">@getgrist</a> or
<a href="mailto:support@getgrist.com">support@getgrist.com</a>!
</p>



<p><img src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/team/paul.jpg">
Paul Fitzpatrick, CTO
</p>
<p><img src="https://www.getgrist.com/themes/grist/assets/images/team/dmitry.jpg">
Dmitry Sagalovskiy, CEO
</p>

        </div>
      </div>
    </div>


  </div>
</section>

<!-- Place this tag in your head or just before your close body tag. -->

				
		

		



		

	
</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.getgrist.com/blog</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25257521</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:05:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[M1 Mac mini overtakes entire Japanese desktop market in less than 2 weeks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 86 | Comments 63 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25257488">thread link</a>) | @gumby
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://appleterm.com/2020/11/30/m1-mac-mini-desktop-market-share-japan/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://appleterm.com/2020/11/30/m1-mac-mini-desktop-market-share-japan/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork">
<div data-sidebar="right" data-v-spacing="top:bottom" data-structure="default:boxed">
<section>
<article id="post-20363">
<section data-type="type-1">

</section>
<div> <figure><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" data-wpfc-original-src="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/m1-mac-mini-market-in-japan-overtake-rect-1-1024x576.jpg" alt="m1 mac mini market in japan overtake rect 1" data-wpfc-original-srcset="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/m1-mac-mini-market-in-japan-overtake-rect-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/m1-mac-mini-market-in-japan-overtake-rect-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/m1-mac-mini-market-in-japan-overtake-rect-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/m1-mac-mini-market-in-japan-overtake-rect-1.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" title="M1 Mac mini overtakes entire Japanese desktop market in less than 2 weeks 1"></figure> <p>In just under 2 weeks since launch, the <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/10/apple-announces-refreshed-mac-mini-at-one-more-thing-event/">M1 powered Mac mini</a> has catapulted <a href="https://apple.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple</a> to the top rank in the desktop market in Japan by a whopping 14.4%, according to market data by <em><a href="https://www.bcnretail.com/research/detail/20201129_201698.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BCN Retail</a>.</em></p> <p><a href="https://www.bcnretail.com/research/detail/20201129_201698.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data</a> between August and November 3rd, a little more than a week prior to the launch of the <a href="https://www.bcnretail.com/research/detail/20201129_201698.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">M1 Mac mini</a> shows <a href="https://apple.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple</a> at around 15% share in the desktop market, behind Lenovo Japan. However, following the launch of the new <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/10/apple-announces-refreshed-mac-mini-at-one-more-thing-event/">Mac mini on November 17th</a>, Apple charged forward to a whopping 27.1% market share, a 14.4% increase from just the start of the month.</p> <p>The <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/10/apple-announces-refreshed-mac-mini-at-one-more-thing-event/">new Mac mini</a> is the first desktop computer from Apple with the new <a href="https://apple.com/mac/m1" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple Silicon</a>. The new chip has gotten <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/17/apple-silicon-mac-reviews-exceeds-almost-every-expectation/">nothing but praise</a> for its <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/28/m1-intel-tiger-lake/">incredible performance</a> and outstanding battery life on the <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/10/apple-reveals-silicon-based-macbook-air/">MacBook Air</a> and <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/10/apple-announces-new-macbook-pros-at-one-more-thing-event/">MacBook Pro</a>. The <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/10/apple-announces-refreshed-mac-mini-at-one-more-thing-event/">Mac mini</a> is the smallest-form factor desktop that <a href="https://apple.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apple</a> offers alongside the iMac, iMac Pro, and Mac Pro.</p> <p>Apple will have fully moved its entire lineup to Apple Silicon away from Intel in 2 years <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/06/22/live-feed-wwdc2020/">according to CEO Tim Cook</a>. That transition is already underway and more devices are expected to join the Apple Silicon family early next year, including a <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/25/kuo-5g-ipad-macbook-apple-watch-redesign/">redesigned 16-inch MacBook Pro</a> and <a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/10/27/arm-based-imac-a14t-chip-in-q1-of-2021/">iMac</a>.</p></div><nav>
<a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/30/digitimes-periscope-lens/">
<figure><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" width="300" height="300" data-wpfc-original-src="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/persicope-lens-for-future-iphone-digitimes-squ-300x300.jpg" alt="blank" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-srcset="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/persicope-lens-for-future-iphone-digitimes-squ-300x300.jpg 300w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/persicope-lens-for-future-iphone-digitimes-squ-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/persicope-lens-for-future-iphone-digitimes-squ-150x150.jpg 150w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/persicope-lens-for-future-iphone-digitimes-squ-768x768.jpg 768w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/persicope-lens-for-future-iphone-digitimes-squ.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-object-fit="~" itemprop="image"><svg width="20px" height="15px" viewBox="0 0 20 15"><polygon points="0,7.5 5.5,13 6.4,12.1 2.4,8.1 20,8.1 20,6.9 2.4,6.9 6.4,2.9 5.5,2 "></polygon></svg><span></span></figure>
<p><span> Previous <span>Post</span> </span> <span> DigiTimes: Apple looking to use periscope lens for future iPhone model </span></p></a>
<a href="https://appleterm.com/2020/11/30/apple-ditches-initiative-in-france-set-to-ensure-big-tech-companies-pay-fair-taxes/">
<p><span> Next <span>Post</span> </span> <span> Apple ditches initiative in France set to ensure big-tech companies pay fair taxes </span></p><figure><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" width="300" height="300" data-wpfc-original-src="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/apple-program-in-france-ditch-squ-300x300.jpg" alt="blank" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-srcset="https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/apple-program-in-france-ditch-squ-300x300.jpg 300w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/apple-program-in-france-ditch-squ-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/apple-program-in-france-ditch-squ-150x150.jpg 150w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/apple-program-in-france-ditch-squ-768x768.jpg 768w, https://appleterm.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/apple-program-in-france-ditch-squ.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-object-fit="~" itemprop="image"><svg width="20px" height="15px" viewBox="0 0 20 15"><polygon points="14.5,2 13.6,2.9 17.6,6.9 0,6.9 0,8.1 17.6,8.1 13.6,12.1 14.5,13 20,7.5 "></polygon></svg><span></span></figure> </a>
</nav>
</article>
</section>
</div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://appleterm.com/2020/11/30/m1-mac-mini-desktop-market-share-japan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25257488</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 19:01:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Reimagine the File System]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25256046">thread link</a>) | @daenz
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://amoffat.github.io/supertag/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://amoffat.github.io/supertag/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

   
  <div>
    
    <nav data-toggle="wy-nav-shift">
      
    </nav>

    <section data-toggle="wy-nav-shift">

      
      <nav aria-label="top navigation">
        
          <i data-toggle="wy-nav-top"></i>
          <a href="#">Supertag</a>
        
      </nav>


      <div>
        
        <div>
        
          
















          <div role="main" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">
           <div itemprop="articleBody">
            
  
<div id="supertag">

<p><a href="https://travis-ci.org/amoffat/supertag"><img alt="Build Status" src="https://img.shields.io/travis/amoffat/supertag/master.svg?style=flat-square"></a>
<a href="https://amoffat.github.io/supertag/"><img alt="Docs" src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Documentation-v0.1.2-1a6cff?style=flat-square&amp;logo=read-the-docs&amp;logoColor=white"></a>
<a href="https://github.com/amoffat/supertag"><img alt="Docs" src="https://img.shields.io/badge/Github-v0.1.2-ff7204?style=flat-square&amp;logo=github&amp;logoColor=white"></a></p><p>Supertag is a tag-based file system, written in <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a>,
that provides a unique view of your files by removing the
hierarchy constraints typically imposed on files and folders. In other words, it allows you to think about your
files not as objects <em>stored</em> in folders, but as objects that can be <em>filtered</em> by folders.</p>
<p>Below, the file path <code><span>/A/B/C</span></code> yields the <a href="https://amoffat.github.io/supertag/glossary.html#term-intersection"><span>intersection</span></a> of all of the files that have been tagged with the
tags <code><span>A</span></code>, <code><span>B</span></code>, and <code><span>C</span></code>. Notice that the resulting files do not live <em>inside</em> of the full path,
they simply appear there because they’ve been tagged with each part of the file path.
Supertag takes care of rendering a dynamic directory
structure through which you can filter and navigate these files.</p>
<p><img alt="Supertag file intersection" src="https://amoffat.github.io/supertag/_images/intersection-opt.gif"></p><div>
<p>Note</p>
<p>You <code><span>/A/B/C</span></code> yields the same file intersection as <code><span>/C/B/A</span></code>, <code><span>/B/C/A</span></code>, etc. It doesn’t matter what
order that the path tags are in, because we’re simply dealing with the intersection of the tags.</p>
</div>
<p>Cool, right? See <a href="https://amoffat.github.io/supertag/usage/quickstart.html#quickstart"><span>Quickstart</span></a> for the crash course.</p>
</div>


           </div>
           
          </div>
          

        </div>
      </div>

    </section>

  </div>
  

  

  
  
    
   


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://amoffat.github.io/supertag/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25256046</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 17:07:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I choose therefore I am – SpaceHey, a blast from the past]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25255596">thread link</a>) | @indifferentalex
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://blog.spacehey.com/entry?id=1200 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.spacehey.com/entry?id=1200">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div><p>«Nel mezzo del cammin di nostra vita</p><p>mi ritrovai per una selva oscura,</p><p>ché la diritta via era smarrita.»</p><p>«Midway upon the journey of our life</p><p>I found myself within a forest dark,</p><p>For the straightforward pathway had been lost.»</p></div><p>-&nbsp;<span>Dante Alighieri</span></p><p><span id="docs-internal-guid-831a4fb5-7fff-d639-36d7-57d1a4f7bed9"><p><span>I've rediscovered some long forgotten joys since I signed up for SpaceHey yesterday, and even if my mind and thoughts are undoubtedly clouded by nostalgia and a longing for simpler times, certain ideas sprang up in my mind, and I think there is truth to them. I'd like to share these with you, hoping that together we can plant even more new seeds and promote healthier growth in our online communities.</span></p><p><span>One of the biggest takeaways is the difference when compared to the passive consumption on platforms such as Facebook, Twitter or Instagram (or basically any other social network out there at the moment). Here I am not presented with an infinite amount of content for me to scroll through, I actively have to seek it out. In doing that my relationship with the network and the content available throughout it changes from a <i>reactive</i> one to a <i>proactive</i> one. It becomes an experience more similar to browsing wikipedia for example, guided by curiosity and a genuine sense of exploration. I haven't been able to find the right words so far to explain it in writing, but experiencing it first-hand is a visceral feeling where the contrast between the two approaches is instantly felt, one feels empty and passive, the other engaging and exciting.</span></p><p><span>Adding the like button may have boosted engagement, MAUs (Monthly Active Users), profits and so much else. Algorithms that choose what content to show us did the same. Having tried SpaceHey which lacks these features, what's painfully obvious is that we didn't ask for them, they (and others) were imposed on us to promote the growth of these platforms while disregarding our real needs. They may have boosted some internal metrics and to some extent were justified as a "nice" thing for users, but because of their "success", these "features" were doubled-down on, optimized further and eventually led us to the AI-driven, mostly passive-consumerism, infinity pools that social networks are today.</span></p><p><span>Likewise, standardization (across the board) led to successes, many principally of business value, for the big companies dominating the space. It inevitably led to a loss of individuality however, a digital communism if you will. Users were forced to express themselves in pre-approved formats, that gradually got more and more standardized and limited to the point where today you can't even make the text in your Facebook posts bold (you can choose from a predefined set of stickers though!). To what end has it been? Moderation is as hot of a topic as it ever was, with no definitive solution in sight, in the meantime we jump on every new app that let us express ourselves more, only to fall victim to the all powerful algorithms that ultimately decide which content actually reaches people.</span></p><p><span>There's been a trend in the last few years of longing for the "old internet", places like Yahoo! GeoCities, personal blogs and yes, Myspace profiles, where individuals, rather than big organized groups, were the producers of content. Places where somebody with minimal technical knowledge could put pencil to paper and create something unique that reflected who they were, and where others were actually inclined to discover their creations. Nowadays everything is (or isn't) found through an algorithm (whether the almighty Google Search or a social network's own ranking algorithm) and the services that allowed this kind of content to be created in the first place have either shut down or followed the money and moved on.</span></p><p><span>SpaceHey seems to bring back what made those original services special, introducing both an instrument through which pages can be created and a vibrant platform that allows their discovery. My </span><span><a href="https://spacehey.com/alex">SpaceHey profile</a> requires almost no scrolling, yet I get to convey my own message to you, in the format that I choose. There is an incredible sense of empowerment and liberty in this approach. I can see this as a place where I can connect with people, a starting point when it comes to connecting with the world at large, a place I can call home knowing full well that I will have to leave in order to explore, since after all, there is no endless wall to scroll through.</span></p><p><span>A massive <b>thank you</b> to </span><span><a href="https://spacehey.com/an">An</a> who, by bringing us back to simpler roots showed in such a powerful way how far we have strayed. Wow, can you feel how fresh the air is here! I wish you all the best on this adventure, luck in facing the obstacles that you'll encounter and on filling up those "coming soon" pages (let me know if you need help!).</span></p><p><span>I don't know how long it'll last, but in a way, it doesn't matter.</span></p></span></p>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.spacehey.com/entry?id=1200</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25255596</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 16:35:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[That coworker who just wants to code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25254317">thread link</a>) | @mcrittenden
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://critter.blog/2020/11/29/that-coworker-who-just-wants-to-code/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://critter.blog/2020/11/29/that-coworker-who-just-wants-to-code/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-801">

	
<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>

		<div>

			
<p>(This is a sequel to “<em><a href="https://critter.blog/2020/08/11/that-coworker-who-never-stops-refactoring/">That coworker who never stops&nbsp;refactoring</a></em>“).</p>



<p>Steve is productive as hell. He writes solid code and gets crap done. He knows the codebase better than anyone. He’s even a <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/08/27/coaching-without-doing/">skilled teacher</a>, as long as the topic is the code.</p>



<p>But Steve doesn’t give a crap about <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/06/10/spotting-broken-processes/">improving process</a> or <a href="https://critter.blog/2016/10/27/the-whys-and-hows-of-jelling-teams/">jelling</a> or <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/08/20/plan-the-sprint-not-the-project/">planning</a> or anything else that isn’t writing code. He thinks <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/03/better-discussion-meetings-with-lean-coffee/">retros</a> and <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/08/17/zombie-standups-try-walking-the-board/">stand-ups</a> and <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/10/20/a-tiny-guide-to-sprint-planning-in-scrum/">sprint planning</a> are a waste of his time, and he multitasks during all of them. He wants to be left alone to do his job.</p>



<p>Steve is <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/10/28/the-all-powerful-bad-apple/">a bad apple</a>.</p>



<p>If you manage Steve, <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/24/intense-intervention-or-acceptance-pick-one/">fire him</a>. I don’t care how valuable you think he is. </p>



<p>If you work alongside Steve, give him and his manager <a href="https://critter.blog/2020/11/26/5-second-feedback/">lots and lots of feedback</a>.</p>



<p>If you are Steve, get your crap together. You’re killing your team. </p>





		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	<!-- .section-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://critter.blog/2020/11/29/that-coworker-who-just-wants-to-code/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25254317</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 14:54:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Big Match: matching open source code in binaries for fun and profit]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25253836">thread link</a>) | @znpy
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/post.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/post.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          

<blockquote>
<p>Do you do reverse engineering for a living?
Have you ever wasted several weeks reversing an open source library embedded in a target?
Do you crave for better tools than copy-pasting random strings into Google?</p>
<p>No?</p>
<p>Well, read anyway.</p>
<p>-- <em>babush</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Today we are proud of showing the world the first prototype of <strong>Big Match</strong>, our tool to find open-source libraries in binaries <strong>only using their strings</strong>.
How does it work?
Read this post to find out, or head to <a href="https://bigmatch.rev.ng/"><strong>our demo website</strong></a> to try it out.</p>
<p><a href="https://bigmatch.rev.ng/"><img src="https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/homepage.png"></a></p>
<p><strong>Spoiler:</strong> we are analyzing all the repositories on GitHub and building a search engine on top of that data.</p>

          
          
            <h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>There's a thing that every good reverser does when starting to work on a target: look for interesting strings and throw them into <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dQw4w9WgXcQ"><strong>Google</strong></a> hoping to find some open-source or leaked source.
This can save you anywhere from few hours of work to several days.
It's kind of a poor man's function (or library) matching.</p>
<p>In 2018, I decided to try out <strong><a href="https://line.me/en/">LINE</a>'s Bug Bounty</strong> program and so I started reversing a library bundled with the Android version of the App.
For those unfamiliar with LINE, it's the most used instant messaging App in Japan.
Anyway, there were many useful error strings sprinkled all around my target, so I did exactly that manual googling I've just mentioned.
Luckily, I was able to match some strings against Cisco's <a href="https://github.com/cisco/libsrtp"><code>libsrtp</code></a>.
But little did I know, my target included a modified version of <a href="https://github.com/pjsip/pjproject"><code>PJSIP</code></a>, a <strong>huge</strong> library that does indeed include <code>libsrtp</code>.
Unfortunately, I discovered this fact much later, so I wasted an entire week reversing an open-source library.</p>
<p>So, I thought: <em>"can we do better than manual googling? Why hasn't anyone built a huge database of all the strings in every public repository?"</em>.
And, just like that, the main idea for <strong>Big Match</strong> was born.</p>
<h2>Outline of our approach</h2>
<p>The way we, at rev.ng, decided to approach this problem is actually simple conceptually, but gets tricky due to the scale of the data we are dealing with.</p>
<p>In short, this is the outline of what we did:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Get the source code of the top C/C++ repositories on GitHub</strong>, where <em>"top"</em> means <em>"most starred"</em>. Ideally we would like to analyze all of them, and we will eventually, but we wanted to give priority to famous projects.</li>
<li>
<strong>Deduplicate the repositories:</strong> we don't want to have 70k+ slightly different versions of the Linux kernel in our database.</li>
<li>
<strong>Extract the strings</strong>: use <a href="https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep"><code>ripgrep</code></a> as a quick way to extract strings from source code.</li>
<li>
<strong>De-escape</strong> the strings. E.g.: turn <code>'\n'</code> into an actual newline character.</li>
<li>
<strong>Hash</strong> the strings.</li>
<li>
<strong>Store them</strong> in some kind of database.</li>
<li>
<strong>Query</strong> the database using the hashes of the strings from a target binary.</li>
<li>
<strong>Cluster</strong> the query results.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Where to start</h2>
<p>The first thing we did was figure out a way to <strong>get the list of all the repos on GitHub</strong>, sorted by stars.
It turns out, however, that this is more easily said than done.
GitHub has an official API but it is rate-limited and we wanted to avoid writing a multi-machine crawling system just for that.
So we looked around and, among many projects making available GitHub data, we found the amazing <a href="https://ghtorrent.org/"><strong>GHTorrent</strong></a>.</p>
<p>GHTorrent, short for <em>GitHub Torrent</em>, is a project created by Prof. Georgios Gousios of TU Delft.
What it does is periodically poll GitHub's <a href="https://developer.github.com/v3/activity/events/#list-public-events">public events API</a> and use the information on commits and new repositories to record the history of GitHub.
So, for example, if user <code>thebabush</code> pushes some changes to his repository <code>awesome-repo</code>, GHTorrent analyzes those changes and, if the repo is not present in its database, it creates a new entry.
It also saves its metadata, e.g. star count, and some of its commits.
By exploiting the GitHub REST API, GHTorrent is able to create a somewhat complete <a href="https://ghtorrent.org/relational.html">relational view</a> of all of GitHub (except for the actual source code):</p>
<p><a href="https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/ghtorrent-schema.svg"><img src="https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/ghtorrent-schema.svg"></a></p>
<p>GHTorrent's data is made available as either a MySQL dump of the relational database in the picture or as a series of daily MongoDB dumps.
GHTorrent uses Mongo as a caching layer for GitHub's API so that it can avoid making the same API call twice.</p>
<p>Once you import the GHTorrent MySQL dumps on your machine, you can quickly get useful information about GitHub using good ol' SQL (e.g.: information about the most popular C/C++ repos is a simple <code>SELECT ... WHERE ... ORDER BY ...</code>).
It also contains information about forks and commits, so you have some good data to exploit for the repo deduplication we want to do.</p>
<p>However, <strong>GHTorrent is best-effort by design</strong>, so you'll never have a complete and consistent snapshot of GitHub.
For example, some repos might be missing or have outdated metadata.
Another example is that commits information is partial: GHTorrent cannot possibly associate every commit to every repository containing it.
Think about the Linux kernel: one commit would need to be added to 70k+ forks and that kind of things doesn't scale very well.</p>
<p>Finally, there's another risk regarding the use of a project like GHTorrent: <strong>maintenance</strong>.
Keeping a crawler working costs money and time, and it seems like in the last couple of years <a href="http://ghtorrent-downloads.ewi.tudelft.nl/mysql/">they haven't been releasing MySQL dumps that often anymore</a>.
On the other hand, they still release their <a href="http://ghtorrent-downloads.ewi.tudelft.nl/mongo-daily/">incremental Mongo updates daily</a>.
Since they create the MySQL DB using REST API calls that are cached through MongoDB, those incremental updates should be everything you need to recreate their MySQL database.</p>
<p>A fun fact is that <strong>Microsoft used to sponsor GHTorrent</strong>, but I guess <a href="https://news.microsoft.com/announcement/microsoft-acquires-github/">they don't need to do it now</a> 🙃.
And yes, that's not a good thing for us.</p>
<p>In the end, since we don't actually need all the tables provided by the GHTorrent MySQL dump, we decided to write a script that directly consumes their Mongo dumps one by one and outputs the information we need into a bunch of text files.
In fact, <strong>most of our pipeline is implemented using bash scripts</strong> (you can read more in our future blogpost about what we like to call <strong><em>bashML</em></strong>).</p>
<h2>Repository deduplication</h2>
<p>We mentioned in the outline that we need to deduplicate the repositories.
We need to do that for several reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>As stated earlier, we don't want to download every single fork of every single famous project out there.</li>
<li>Duplicated data means that our database of repos grows very fast in size. The first ~100K repos we downloaded from GitHub amount to ~1.4TB of <code>gzip</code>'d source code (without <code>git</code> history), so you can see why this is an important point.</li>
<li>Duplicated data is bad for <strong>search results accuracy</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<p>GHTorrent has information about forks but, as for GitHub itself, that only counts forks created with the <em>"Fork"</em> button on the web UI.
The other option is to look for common commits between repositories.
If we had infinite computing resources, we would do this:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<strong>Clone every repository</strong> we care about.</li>
<li>Put every commit hash in a <strong>graph database</strong> of some kind.</li>
<li>Connect commit hashes using their <strong>parent/child relationship</strong>.</li>
<li>Find the <strong>root commits</strong>.</li>
<li>For every root commit, <strong>keep only the most-starred repo</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<p>However, we live in the real world, so this is simply impossible for us to do.
We would like to have a strategy to deduplicate repos <strong>before</strong> cloning them, as cloning would require a lot of time and bandwidth.
On top of that, when using git you can merge the history of totally-unrelated projects.
So, if you deduplicate repos based on the root commit alone, you end up removing a lot of projects you actually want to keep.</p>
<p>Case in point: <strong><a href="https://github.com/octocat/Spoon-Knife"><code>octocat/Spoon-Knife</code></a></strong>.</p>
<h2>Octocat</h2>
<p><code>octocat/Spoon-Knife</code> is the <strong>most forked project</strong> on GitHub, and there's a reason for that: it's the repo that is used in GitHub's <a href="https://guides.github.com/activities/forking/">tutorial on forking</a>.
This means that a lot of people learning to use GitHub have forked this repo at some point.</p>
<p>You might be wondering why <code>Spoon-Knife</code> causes troubles to our theoretical deduplication algorithm.
Well, take a look at this screenshot of <code>LibreCAD</code>'s git history:</p>
<p><img alt="LibreCAD history" src="https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/librecad.png"></p>
<p>At some point in the past some user by the name of <code>youarefunny</code> was learning to use GitHub and so he forked <code>Spoon-Knife</code>.
At some other point, he forked <code>LibreCAD</code> and made some commits.
Then, for whatever reason, he thought <em>"well, why not merge the history of these two nice repositories in a single one? So we can have a branch with the history of both projects!"</em>.
And finally, just to <del>fuck with us</del> contribute to a useful open-source project like <code>LibreCAD</code>, he decided to open a pull request using that exact branch.
And that pull request was accepted.</p>
<p><strong>TL;DR:</strong> the history of <code>Spoon-Knife</code> is included in <code>LibreCAD</code>'s repo.</p>
<p>If you want to check this out, visit <a href="https://github.com/LibreCAD/LibreCAD/commit/f08a37f282dd30ce7cb759d6cf8981c982290170">this link</a> or clone <code>LibreCAD/LibreCAD</code> and run <code>git diff f08a37f282dd30ce7cb759d6cf8981c982290170</code>.</p>
<p>Things like this present a serious issue for us because <code>Spoon-Knife</code> has 10.3k stars at the moment, while <code>LibreCAD</code> only has 2k.
Which means that if we were to remove the least starred project, we would actually remove <code>LibreCAD</code> and keep the utterly useless <code>Spoon-Knife</code> repo.</p>
<p>I hate you <code>yourefunny</code>.
And no, you are not actually funny.</p>
<p>But <code>yourefunny</code> is not alone in this: during our tests we've found that some people also like to merge the history of Linux and LLVM.
Go figure.</p>
<h2>Best-effort deduplication</h2>
<p>So we can't <code>git clone</code> every repo on GitHub and we can't do root-based deduplication.
What we can do is use GHTorrent once again and implement a different strategy.
In fact, <strong>GHTorrent has information about commits</strong>, too, albeit limited.
This is what it gives us:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<em>(partial)</em> <code>(parent commit, child commit)</code> relations.</li>
<li>
<em>(partial)</em> <code>(commit, repository)</code> relations.</li>
</ol>
<p>Exploiting this data we can't reconstruct the full git history of every repository, but we can recreate <strong>subgraphs</strong> of it.
We then apply this algorithm:</p>
<ol>
<li>Find a commit for which GHTorrent doesn't have a parent (we call them <em>parentless commits</em>) and consider it a root commit.</li>
<li>Explore the commit history graph starting at a root commit. We do this going <strong>upward</strong>, that is, only following <code>parent → child</code> edges.</li>
<li>We group all the repositories associated with the commits of a subgraph we obtain in step 2. We call such group a <em>repository group</em>.</li>
<li>For every repository group, we find the most starred repo it contains and consider it the <em>parent repo</em>, …</li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/post.html">https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/post.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rev.ng/blog/big-match/post.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25253836</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 14:11:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How many registers does an x86-64 CPU have?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 108 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25253797">thread link</a>) | @woodruffw
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/11/30/How-many-registers-does-an-x86-64-cpu-have | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/11/30/How-many-registers-does-an-x86-64-cpu-have">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">


<h2><em>Programming, philosophy, pedaling.</em></h2>

<ul>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/">Home</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags">Tags</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/favorites">Favorites</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/archive">Archive</a></li>
    
      <li><a href="https://yossarian.net/">Main Site</a></li>
    
</ul>

<hr>



<h2>
  <em>Nov 30, 2020</em>
</h2>

  <p>Tags:
  
    
    <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags#programming">programming</a>,
    
  
    
    <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags#x86">x86</a>
    
  
  </p>


<p>x86 is back in the general programmer discourse, in part thanks to Apple’s M1 and
<a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/apple_silicon/about_the_rosetta_translation_environment">Rosetta 2</a>.
As such, I figured I’d do <em>yet another</em> x86-64 post.</p>

<p>Just like <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/06/13/How-x86_64-addresses-memory">the last one</a>,
I’m going to cover a facet of the x86-64 ISA that sets it apart
as unusually complex among modern ISAs: the number and diversity of registers available.</p>

<p><a href="https://stefanheule.com/blog/how-many-x86-64-instructions-are-there-anyway/">Like instruction counting</a>,
register counting on x86-64 is subject to debates over methodology. In particular, for this blog
post, I’m going to lay the following ground rules:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>I <strong>will</strong> count sub-registers (e.g., <code>EAX</code> for <code>RAX</code>) as distinct registers. My justification:
they have different instruction encodings, and both Intel and AMD optimize/pessimize
particular sub-register use patterns in their microcode.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I <strong>will</strong> count registers that are present on x86-64 CPUs, but that can’t be used in long mode.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I <strong>won’t</strong> count registers that are <em>only</em> present on older x86 CPUs, like the 80386 and
80486 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_register">test registers</a>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I <strong>won’t</strong> count microarchitectural implementation details, like shadow registers.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I <strong>will</strong> count registers that aren’t directly addressable, like MSRs that can only be accessed
through <code>RDMSR</code>. However, I <strong>won’t</strong> (or will try not to) double-count registers that
have multiple access mechanisms (like <code>RDMSR</code> and <code>RDTSC</code>).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I <strong>won’t</strong> count model-specific registers that fall into these categories:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>MSRs that are only present on niche x86 vendors (Cyrix, Via)</li>
      <li>MSRs that aren’t widely available on recent-ish x86-64 CPUs
        <ul>
          <li><strong>Errata</strong>: I accidentally included AVX-512 in some of the original counts below,
  not realizing that it hadn’t been released on any AMD CPUs. The post has been updated.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>MSRs that are <em>completely</em> undocumented (both officially and unofficially)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>In addition to the rules above, I’m going to use the following considerations and methodology
for grouping registers together:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Many sources, both official and unofficial, use “model-specific register” as an umbrella term
for any non-core or non-feature-set register supplied by an x86-64 CPU. Whenever possible, I’ll
try to avoid this in favor of more specific categories.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Both Intel and AMD provide synonyms for registers (e.g. <code>CR8</code> as the “task priority register,” or
<code>TPR</code>). Whenever possible, I’ll try to use the more generic/category conforming name (like <code>CR8</code>
in the case above).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>In general, the individual cores of a multicore processor have independent register states.
Whenever this <strong>isn’t</strong> the case, I’ll make an effort to document it.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<hr>

<h2 id="general-purpose-registers">General-purpose registers</h2>

<p>The general-purpose registers (or GPRs) are <strong>the</strong> primary registers in the x86-64 register model.
As their name implies, they are the <strong>only</strong> registers that are <em>general purpose</em>: each has a set
of conventional uses<sup id="fnref:conventional" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:conventional">1</a></sup>, but programmers are generally free to ignore those conventions and use
them as they please<sup id="fnref:ignore" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:ignore">2</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Because x86-64 evolved from a 32-bit ISA which in turn evolved from a 16-bit ISA, each
GPR has a set of <em>subregisters</em> that hold the lower 8, 16 and 32 bits of the full 64-bit
register.</p>

<p>As a table:</p>

<table>
  <tbody><tr>
    
    <th>64-bit</th>
    
    <th>32-bit</th>
    
    <th>16-bit</th>
    
    <th>8-bit (low)</th>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RAX</td>
    
    <td>EAX</td>
    
    <td>AX</td>
    
    <td>AL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RBX</td>
    
    <td>EBX</td>
    
    <td>BX</td>
    
    <td>BL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RCX</td>
    
    <td>ECX</td>
    
    <td>CX</td>
    
    <td>CL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RDX</td>
    
    <td>EDX</td>
    
    <td>DX</td>
    
    <td>DL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RSI</td>
    
    <td>ESI</td>
    
    <td>SI</td>
    
    <td>SIL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RDI</td>
    
    <td>EDI</td>
    
    <td>DI</td>
    
    <td>DIL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RBP</td>
    
    <td>EBP</td>
    
    <td>BP</td>
    
    <td>BPL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>RSP</td>
    
    <td>ESP</td>
    
    <td>SP</td>
    
    <td>SPL</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R8</td>
    
    <td>R8D</td>
    
    <td>R8W</td>
    
    <td>R8B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R9</td>
    
    <td>R9D</td>
    
    <td>R9W</td>
    
    <td>R9B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R10</td>
    
    <td>R10D</td>
    
    <td>R10W</td>
    
    <td>R10B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R11</td>
    
    <td>R11D</td>
    
    <td>R11W</td>
    
    <td>R11B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R12</td>
    
    <td>R12D</td>
    
    <td>R12W</td>
    
    <td>R12B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R13</td>
    
    <td>R13D</td>
    
    <td>R13W</td>
    
    <td>R13B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R14</td>
    
    <td>R14D</td>
    
    <td>R14W</td>
    
    <td>R14B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>R15</td>
    
    <td>R15D</td>
    
    <td>R15W</td>
    
    <td>R15B</td>
    
  </tr>
  
</tbody></table>

<p>Some of the 16-bit subregisters are also special: the original 8086 allowed the <strong>high</strong> byte
of <code>AX</code>, <code>BX</code>, <code>CX</code>, and <code>DX</code> to be accessed indepenently, so x86-64 preserves this for some
encodings:</p>

<table>
  <tbody><tr>
    
    <th>16-bit</th>
    
    <th>8-bit (high)</th>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>AX</td>
    
    <td> AH</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>BX</td>
    
    <td> BH</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>CX</td>
    
    <td> CH</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>DX</td>
    
    <td> DH</td>
    
  </tr>
  
</tbody></table>

<p>So that’s 16 full-width GPRs, fanning out to another 52 subregisters.</p>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 68</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Running total: 68</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="special-registers">Special registers</h2>

<p>This is sort of an artificial category: like every ISA, x86-64 has a few “special” registers that
keep things moving along. In particular:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>The <em>instruction pointer</em>, or <code>RIP</code>.</p>

    <p>x86-64 has 32- and 16-bit variants of <code>RIP</code> (<code>EIP</code> and <code>IP</code>), but I’m <strong>not</strong> going to count
  them as separate registers: they have identical encodings and can’t be used in the same
  CPU mode<sup id="fnref:ip" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:ip">3</a></sup>.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The <em>status register</em>, or <code>RFLAGS</code>.</p>

    <p>Just like <code>RIP</code>, <code>RFLAGS</code> has 32- and 16-bit counterparts (<code>EFLAGS</code> and <code>FLAGS</code>). Unlike
  <code>RIP</code>, these counterparts can be partially mixed: <code>PUSHF</code> and <code>PUSHFQ</code> are both valid in
  long mode, and <code>LAHF</code>/<code>SAHF</code> can operate on the bits of <code>FLAGS</code> on some x86-64 CPUs
  outside of compatiblility mode<sup id="fnref:cpuid-lahf-sahf" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:cpuid-lahf-sahf">4</a></sup>. So I’m going to go ahead and count them.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 4</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Running total: 72</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="segment-registers">Segment registers</h2>

<p>x86-64 has a total of 6 segment registers: <code>CS</code>, <code>SS</code>, <code>DS</code>, <code>ES</code>, <code>FS</code>, and <code>GS</code>. The operation
varies with the CPU’s mode:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>In all modes except for long mode, each segment register holds a <em>selector</em>, which indexes into
either the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Descriptor_Table">GDT</a> or
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Descriptor_Table#Local_Descriptor_Table">LDT</a>. That yields
a segment <em>descriptor</em> which, among other things, supplies the base address and extent of the
segment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>In long mode all but <code>FS</code> and <code>GS</code> are treated as having a base address of zero and a 64-bit
extent, effectively producing a flat address space. <code>FS</code> and <code>GS</code> are retained as special cases,
but no longer use the segment descriptor tables: instead, they access base addresses that
are stored in the <code>FSBASE</code> and <code>GSBASE</code> model-specific registers<sup id="fnref:kernelgsbase" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:kernelgsbase">5</a></sup>.
More on those later.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 6</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Running total: 78</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="simd-and-fp-registers">SIMD and FP registers</h2>

<p>The x86 family has gone through <em>several</em> generations of SIMD and floating-point instruction
groups, each of which has introduced, extended, or re-contextualized various registers:</p>

<ul>
  <li>x87</li>
  <li>MMX</li>
  <li>SSE (SSE2, SSE3, SSE4, SSE4, …)</li>
  <li>AVX (AVX2, AVX512)</li>
</ul>

<p>Let’s do them in rough order.</p>

<h3 id="x87">x87</h3>

<p>Originally a discrete coprocessor with its own instruction set and register file, the x87
instructions have been regularly baked into x86 cores themselves since the 80486.</p>

<p>Because of its coprocessor history, x87 defines both normal registers<sup id="fnref:normal-ish" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:normal-ish">6</a></sup>
(akin to GPRs) and a variety of special registers needed to control the FPU state:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>ST0</code> through <code>ST7</code>: 8 80-bit floating-point registers</li>
  <li><code>FPSW</code>, <code>FPCW</code>, <code>FPTW</code> <sup id="fnref:mynames" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:mynames">7</a></sup>: Control, status, and tag-word registers</li>
  <li>“Data operand pointer”: I don’t know what this one does, but the Intel SDM specifies it<sup id="fnref:sdm" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:sdm">8</a></sup></li>
  <li>Instruction pointer: the x87 state machine apparently holds its own copy of the current
x87 instruction</li>
  <li>Last instruction opcode: this is apparently distinct from the x87 opcode, and has its
own register</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 14</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Running total: 92</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="mmx">MMX</h3>

<p>MMX was Intel’s first attempt at consumer SIMD in their x86 chips, released back in 1997.</p>

<p>For design reasons that are a complete mystery to me, the MMX registers are actually sub-registers
of the x87 <code>STn</code> registers: each 64-bit <code>MMn</code> occupies the mantissa component of its corresponding
<code>STn</code>. Consequently, x86 (and x86-64) CPUs cannot execute MMX and x87 instructions at the same time.</p>

<p>In addition to <code>MM0</code> through <code>MM7</code>, MMX also defines a new status register (<code>MXCSR</code>) as well as
a load/store instruction pair for manipulating it (<code>LDMXCSR</code> and <code>STMXCSR</code>).</p>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 9</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Running total: 101</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="sse-and-avx">SSE and AVX</h3>

<p>For simplicity’s sake, I’m going to wrap SSE and AVX into a single section: they use the same
sub-register pattern as the GPRs and x87/MMX do, so they fit well into a single table:</p>

<table>
  <tbody><tr>
    
    <th>AVX-512 (512-bit)</th>
    
    <th>AVX-2 (256-bit)</th>
    
    <th>SSE (128-bit)</th>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM0</td>
    
    <td>YMM0</td>
    
    <td>XMM0</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM1</td>
    
    <td>YMM1</td>
    
    <td>XMM1</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM2</td>
    
    <td>YMM2</td>
    
    <td>XMM2</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM3</td>
    
    <td>YMM3</td>
    
    <td>XMM3</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM4</td>
    
    <td>YMM4</td>
    
    <td>XMM4</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM5</td>
    
    <td>YMM5</td>
    
    <td>XMM5</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM6</td>
    
    <td>YMM6</td>
    
    <td>XMM6</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM7</td>
    
    <td>YMM7</td>
    
    <td>XMM7</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM8</td>
    
    <td>YMM8</td>
    
    <td>XMM8</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM9</td>
    
    <td>YMM9</td>
    
    <td>XMM9</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM10</td>
    
    <td>YMM10</td>
    
    <td>XMM10</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM11</td>
    
    <td>YMM11</td>
    
    <td>XMM11</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM12</td>
    
    <td>YMM12</td>
    
    <td>XMM12</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM13</td>
    
    <td>YMM13</td>
    
    <td>XMM13</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM14</td>
    
    <td>YMM14</td>
    
    <td>XMM14</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM15</td>
    
    <td>YMM15</td>
    
    <td>XMM15</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM16</td>
    
    <td>YMM16</td>
    
    <td>XMM16</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM17</td>
    
    <td>YMM17</td>
    
    <td>XMM17</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM18</td>
    
    <td>YMM18</td>
    
    <td>XMM18</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM19</td>
    
    <td>YMM19</td>
    
    <td>XMM19</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM20</td>
    
    <td>YMM20</td>
    
    <td>XMM20</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM21</td>
    
    <td>YMM21</td>
    
    <td>XMM21</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM22</td>
    
    <td>YMM22</td>
    
    <td>XMM22</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM23</td>
    
    <td>YMM23</td>
    
    <td>XMM23</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM24</td>
    
    <td>YMM24</td>
    
    <td>XMM24</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM25</td>
    
    <td>YMM25</td>
    
    <td>XMM25</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM26</td>
    
    <td>YMM26</td>
    
    <td>XMM26</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM27</td>
    
    <td>YMM27</td>
    
    <td>XMM27</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM28</td>
    
    <td>YMM28</td>
    
    <td>XMM28</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM29</td>
    
    <td>YMM29</td>
    
    <td>XMM29</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM30</td>
    
    <td>YMM30</td>
    
    <td>XMM30</td>
    
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    
    <td>ZMM31</td>
    
    <td>YMM31</td>
    
    <td>XMM31</td>
    
  </tr>
  
</tbody></table>

<p>In other words: the lower half of each <code>ZMMn</code> is <code>YMMn</code>, and the lower half of each <code>YMMn</code> is
<code>XMMn</code>. There’s no direct way register access for just the upper half of <code>YMMn</code>, nor does
<code>ZMMn</code> have direct 256- or 128-bit access for the thunks of its upper half.</p>

<p>SSE also defines a new status register, <code>MXCSR</code>, that contains flags roughly parallel
to the arithmetic flags in <code>RFLAGS</code> (along with floating-point flags in the x87 status word).</p>

<p>AVX-512 <strong>also</strong> introduces eight <em>opmask</em> registers, <code>k0</code> through <code>k7</code>. <code>k0</code> is a special case
that behaves much like the “zero” register on some RISC ISAs: it can’t be stored to, and
loads from it always produce a bitmask of all ones.</p>

<p><strong>Errata</strong>: The table above includes AVX-512, which isn’t available on any AMD CPUs as of 2020.
I’ve updated the counts below to only include SSE and AVX2-introduced registers.</p>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 33</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Running total: 134</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="bounds-registers">Bounds registers</h2>

<p>Intel added these with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intel_MPX">MPX</a>, which was intended to
offer hardware-accelerated bounds checking. Nobody uses it, since
<a href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Intel-MPX-Is-Dead">it doesn’t work very well</a>.
But x86 is eternal and slow to fix mistakes, so we’ll probably have these registers taking up space
for at least a while longer:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>BND0</code> — <code>BND3</code>: Individual 128-bit registers, each containing a pair of addresses
for a bound.</li>
  <li><code>BNDCFG</code>: Bound configuration, kernel mode.</li>
  <li><code>BNDCFU</code>: Bound configuration, user mode.</li>
  <li><code>BNDSTATUS</code>: Bound status, after a <code>#BR</code> is raised.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 7</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>Running total: 141</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="debug-registers">Debug registers</h2>

<p>These are what they sound like: registers that aid and accelerate software debuggers, like
<a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/gdb/">GDB</a>.</p>

<p>There are 6 debug registers of two types:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><code>DR0</code> through <code>DR3</code> contain linear addresses, each of which is associated with a breakpoint
condition.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><code>DR6</code> and <code>DR7</code> are the debug status and control registers. <code>DR6</code>’s lower bits indicate which
debug conditions were encountered (upon entering the debug exception handler), while <code>DR7</code> controls
which breakpoint addresses are enabled and their breakpoint conditions (e.g., when a particular
address is written to).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>What about <code>DR4</code> and <code>DR5</code>? For reasons that are unclear to me, they don’t (and have never)
existed<sup id="fnref:guess" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:guess">9</a></sup>. They <em>do</em> have encodings but are treated as <code>DR6</code> and <code>DR7</code>, respective, or produce
an <code>#UD</code> exception when <code>CR4.DE[bit 3] = 1</code>.</p>

<p><strong>Registers in this group: 6.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Running …</strong></p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/11/30/How-many-registers-does-an-x86-64-cpu-have">https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/11/30/How-many-registers-does-an-x86-64-cpu-have</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/11/30/How-many-registers-does-an-x86-64-cpu-have</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25253797</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 14:07:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Johns Hopkins: Heart Disease Deaths Dropped in 2020 [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25253486">thread link</a>) | @11thEarlOfMar
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://corona-transition.org/IMG/pdf/a_closer_look_at_u.s._deaths_due_to_covid-19_-_the_johns_hopkins_news-letter.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://corona-transition.org/IMG/pdf/a_closer_look_at_u.s._deaths_due_to_covid-19_-_the_johns_hopkins_news-letter.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div m="ÒqüRÇG§ß¿Øþñ�Î‹‰ƒ1‹¥cŠñ]óùöåÓ|†Û½S¥ñÊd¾­EëÔ€¦#gæ^twèµªÓ7«/Üë¾S3—3,mX0öÎ=s†îaUSõR¦ø+å'n4œOì½Ó¸R3«�Üµï(\8MB">"¡ÚMñ‘pÈ&amp;)È…lFXcbp(¢lÍ&lt;ÑºZ’3=™ÄÖ;…Ãy}½«†5�O­e»žÕyûxÓnù½±ØseïG´�­Ú½ß®/oR®¦‡¶\¸Z}6¶õfÁHÆàf»DX†qqp5˜i¸wBb•A'ípÔÁ‰E„ì˜˜Z˜Õ²i žR¸¶–„Ñ�½æÒ±Ì¤¶ˆÛ
W»oU,äÎ™FQmó»ŒŽF·&nbsp;àºAºA—Àôòyœ¦òýU¹_¦Í%Û¬¥ÔXp�,Ò‡,é±–ðpã©�yö‘LAÁï‚²
|å‚;�h†®ÈF«$z…WÎðãG
šŒ.Û\&gt;µà™Û64ÎŸŽ(|¦'óÛo�ý6%Ð†þCOÆaÀ^‰¼¿²ìÚ;¡?ûRÒûß¯¼ud¾1Ýº;":d¢,®Môxýz2Ìï’óyAö‹¦Ï¯›&gt;·$|n^ÿ?ŽÚþ÷!Ç›åß�_øÉ‰®ç_*þá?æ½üÝÚïÌå'¦:}Ú-Ñkô‰N‡:Q~8sò‰Ì�’èðŠp&lt;ª-;ÎÝaIwNÒ‰ü�¿—úê—_ýråÕWÇ‹b„ÅÑ¨ÝðÜtˆ’L°–Ë§…Ið»Ÿ$þiË–ß�O¨'£}ÜžÌ‡.ý'Ö“;MN—D/×“^?Üo~ä�êòXÂ¾‹x•&nbsp;øÂ®'0ûÝüÚÇÒƒz2:‹ojEúÌžÌ¾;ŸÕàÓ@{p
…bjj
Vb`RÖZ^{í5˜…�·ÜÕØ–�¶	T\^}õÕË—/4[ð.tljkk¡‘[4ßøÆ7`¦¿¿Ÿê+ËËË555p„Ã/0#óî»ïÂ¶Š…Ó¥ØØXèÛôõõA[�ÁUæ*»n‰¤§§çþýûÐlÁ'`L¯#‚zÂ•tu&nbsp;uŒw1$ƒ_ÇªG©TâW´Î•&nbsp;ØóÎ;ïÀÜÍÑ£G¯]»†ÊÃÝÔ{‚µkð:&gt;z %¸ÌuuCÉê‰MO|âÐ+P&gt;'5xrþîÓIÙ_�r£‡˜ƒ�9—‡y{dß&amp;Øò¹#˜ ’‚ q%û¯@Y	¼"âÄW�J-JÂå…"¥³‚]ôØE/'åðAYššn7XøËv8|.³|Ÿ^‚KÜÕû†–t•=[ñEãYCÙ£w‹çã‹çoeßÊL,ÆŽ0D0»vqBá)ÚŠ.Š(èO¨žo˜´vÌ{:æÜåÝÒ¤ÂÑÛY�‰ÅC…Ms³›ö-¥¸¡;fŒqEcëï÷×
o,îÁØ‚àF+]n¯Ë+ÚÝ¢`#=«GtxX«0Í�Ã–±Ó‹OyÜþà%æ
póxÐÝÔ4›èB{çF.¯íd:¤˜5[»¢K¯Qté¼ÊEÅhõØƒÐÒs/ÜýéÂ¿ý×7Ÿû?£~ø…ü“?íJ»¸Ò™g“N‰¥è2‹&gt;^‡š+àìòàsNsr›èWõa"¶y\6�Çâ¥=X€ÔÉ¯‰�úõA'˜E‹Ü'�7Ï¶Ì”Æ_zåîÛßÉ¼ðZSF„r¶W´«)¦t0Ž.ŸÕá5Y]Ø\7Û]tõ1@äsS{¹Er–àG�€n�NÐ�”Úº^šÜz«¸,±µoÁ]BLFóµÈ¢ðÛ¥wŠCoe…Þˆ�º}/2¶$.v©¶t&amp;/¥ëö…¢�_Š{ù+7~ð_¯üà?]þÉÉ¾òJ[AìüHßÊÊÎÔ’¦®g--¿=:µ,§¨ipbIª1C½L_´CtŒAiÖ!˜äQ]Gª¾@‚XÛ|¨-€€àb 8�Ñý”qŠ&lt;üâüÏÿx:Ïóø9|‚`†Ê`´8itQ0tZÚ½nàžÓg·‹&amp;«h‚‡ëa­O2žÙWy./î'WO|íý7`OæÅS¡·sšÛ'ÔÍŠ”œ¾÷Ï¤|õŸßûÅÛ—‹«æ×pÄÈÆy9¢À[Œ�h³‰¤
p=«†`3¡9*¬òbBWdÃZù¶eQO;œf'
¨dÓûè\QxÒ+ÓqQw¸1vèâm÷ƒìÿ	çI”ô8ü©v�¦ó&gt;©�Eú�ò%H´:�á°£Õ@F�ñ—¨	DÙð˜ê·¨÷ˆr§¸%¸–èÌ,ìèw
µ]‡³{íè&lt;¢`&nbsp;Tˆò®tƒ&gt;e¦ó4Ìñ›9ì404!7&nbsp;~aºàDÓà�%ÀàF1ˆ?«þb×†Õ‰U�ðÄÏä#²Y}¢Ñ-J�âÄ†µ¢g7¦`æ|âÀ¹¤ÑË)ca÷†c2ºKû¦Æ—vçú»ó
2c’Â/F]:ûzhjbzEcçØÜ†Lã$×¿Q\ÄÆIEJÅTÄ½þI]ço×^Ši¸–Ð‘Ö�ô`¨´n~ppsk~×´µ£›�\j¬ªˆ}÷õžÿÉ?ÿÅñ×ß»püâõ‹QIqy5Õ½SÓ»
��7ÄGÍ2ÓìrŸjÉ°Ø5Xú'~õ�øGzjÈVfÜF‡&lt;æ,€ˆ`a§
(·•œ×Ú}"vÉeVqxE]Ð0›Ý‘R�œ×Ù:¸¾®$7&amp;ZÄ{,&gt;›ÍmA¦	S¼—ˆâ~@Ü0D¶à©9€Q�6lÐÐ8ã×ŸR:AƒÍ]�±ä#Ø%‚ás‡y@‰ø•X’Ã®}ð°óAlÈ¶p;ì›”ö»þîªü`üÄ|‰…?&gt;„àô`¼Ål&nbsp;'�lì��€"f’óŽ¢ˆ�‚fbã}Ï)ŽI­Åý+7ó:ÎÄ�»““�ÛX×=7¹¢–êÀáD ¦Ñç±xD£KÔ8Ä=“sUm\ØS.ì*&nbsp;ÔE8Î99�np›@&amp;1|gƒ0ì¡—²gp¯)ìc–ú‘½´êñ›Y-ªÏF—]‰¯OmÈ¬©ì\êŸS-íYöŒ&gt;sR�wéëŒ9´ù D#ïèZ¯¸&nbsp;pÀ†ajéllÎl\Î|bþrbÁBbþtJÁxYãbïˆdK†
m¢Ÿ?@6ÝØ!‚ò3‘^bÎ¨V
“¸¸çkÒß«\»šÔ}òví™Øº[º*×g¥fC;#¿¬b»=€5°O‰óìÄ}ÛË�Ÿ¬Ñ•è&amp;°âœì	…ýt�Eö] &gt;(O&gt;�ø”tääWð¤Œ!éÿXP3x?&nbsp;nÄÒ0½u‡(½
¹{cÎ1Ú¡ª+˜N�k
½^ròÜƒ÷Oä¼õQî›æ½u$ïÍ£¹ïœ)8ßx»i¶jY1!7lXÝÌ]à^aã*n0Ñ˜ë&lt;Ä½ƒŒ€€€Èà‹J0-t²Ðßà@mŸD7xCöÁCñJ&nbsp;uÁéÁñ&nbsp;†õW€nðŸð§þ¥cn¸³à„&lt;@0é˜Â¨ÒÜ”…±±n~L£¼@
TrprÊ¨+Ëg°rlDížosÑ9Ù&amp;©Lî½uµì£˜æë5Eê!‰ssã)õ{�Õq@˜€ì´ãŽGb)Ø™2Þ|Ìžà§§À9L†'~(ù¦Ú�o€£@XIÈ
¶J
ºƒ¾q€ŠDÅhmË(^d«0ŸáÌ~¿þ&lt;&nbsp;7ø˜âwè­aµˆíCDK!	Øý2vÞGû ¥= [Œ£ŸÐYèfD¨dÀ_F�B&lt;ÐDÑ…smàASm.�ÑîÔ{| {&nbsp;4X¤Ûi}JÀÅõŒ’p‚Œ%´ÊC½5 ÚAµ`�àÍ¤ÕíBŸrÞ�h&amp;U“]¼+ƒÓéµÏâBñ¼pŽZ�"?azpõx	¸ã'/Ÿ@"QDÔ�àè@�l¢
+£=÷ê&nbsp;´¥r!'¹7
¾½É�‹5Ëú³(`YÄVÏû]Æ+ï8êTÖýòèWhøcq‰JA„ß¥£R¿ùüÉ—Þ
�L©né‡‘H+ÄÈ€WaêŸ¯^1Ð£��;‚?z�£§$¦ÉðŠpr=:·{¿¼ãthêÏß½øÆÉ°[©…-C³0á¼Aá`Ã8z@~…Ù‹a4œ‰³\ÐîÃÁNn\ŸUõzQµá�«ZÎ‰j:“2‰]·k+
�Ö*Ú9“b�*›×f3,Zí¢Ù(jv+“ÚþŒž»aeç®ä^v&amp;ªòB|}Hfç�Üž»Mó…½ë
³ªa+R{äzQgM&amp;/Ä4�sñª„õË&gt;îqü$wþÖŸÏýI0y€í�€ß½$¯Û$2rcéh£ÝLÐ.Œ‹Ö´8¸Û˜ÑöZÕ‘¯µ�üÎHÈÏ‡®½Òò«ºÓÏWœûEGâåÕ®rýæ¼Ç‚ýM.Ü €l"s�p¹˜ß
`²Ë
2…%– Ú¢Sá´ìZNóü‰‹v=	i#/4T¢E¢DãõÐðØ¬„²hå‹;T1.¤ò¸íT8”’Ø
ó”Ô˜‹ç&gt;äŽ/v=
çÀ*�z0$Ð±yLfŸ`
‚¨“‹{+îÙ6IUÂ@ôd"ÎÝ½t}àLøÐ…[ý!w£‹ç
‡¥C{V™ËI¶´7�U©M4êEå®¸
»pu›%±Ý7Ã/†UŸOn¿U=�;&amp;kÛµÏâ¶NÜÐŠë{¾ù	mgÉtÆ�æk¡õç£Z®U/”LiG`Í†¹&amp;Æø§Õ]5!ˆ# ½!¾Mp«�¢z2M+E™wb[nÜëº[;S5%�Ü³HÍŒ£P‹’-ï|¯ª1o.õBõÑm'ó×+¤Ù%›éiSÑ!õçÂê¯¤÷'4-U.k¡[ˆ€åãƒø4ç%@‘ˆÞRð`z‚à‚fAZ¢3&nbsp;W(˜DÅžsqN××°P˜ÕÓ×q­p&amp;cÖ4l5¨'UžÍh@dÈ@HT‹¢|¡�Ã´9E‚ƒ’ M‡Ï‚;Ž
!ðt1á‰Ù(<q½˜;dÃj`À�È�×ÿ$0 ÌÑ�”@äÀ<8ì=""  ;$ó*`w�Âr&¼¥m8p="" ö‰ñ1l,‰éŽ±oûc]Ú²x!²ÜžÙ“="" �ÿ÷‰!ÂnŒ•ödÔ•Õ7Þ½ýâ—"_úrÆñuf\Ý­rkd»bôbžï¦8ìÉ@o&wt="">¯—ÿÅ¼åókÖÏ-Z&gt;7güü¨õë5þ—Ê�¯F~óÍºï~¿à‡ß(zíGá'·jr-ËÃ¢QŠ¹ãÚŽÓ'Äè@.��¶ŸE´«AÌPö�®šfæ‹Ã®¿”ñÖ—c~ögûçÎ„ó»}UnÙšhÇ¤&amp;„ñáÅË†?üá·‹Š=ùíJý3~�F8‡M)`-ØzÌoOt\Ç1Ò“©Åß¨'lÖð%:Eiû�•I‹|ö)ú•bM`Ùþ&nbsp;7^GLÄ&lt;ðÇàŠÐt{!‰Q@`ëVjâ3=™?h&gt;ûø§†0™¿ƒ³°ý²²²ÒÛÛoD°âRYYYQQ=“ÒÒRDpç¤wtt,--!?–ZPSÏÊÊ‚ú
lÎ@µ&amp;%%enÄÁJÌÚÚ”p`X
3eìB!MMM£££°èzàyö³ü^/---(•Á»]]]³³³0ÖÇf&nbsp;!ÁïCŽŸ†‡‡ñ"o^‡Ö
š	«‰Á9yß:´œÇs~Ú^IÎÚ}Úw÷ùcì"Ÿ‚É&nbsp;ÿëœò„q’&lt;÷@fDð:ç9INË„·´€‚ØŠ2Ð�qY}N¤¯^²-Ã_ôÏ
™Œˆ¶úùÖ­Uôau¤vˆóR[Û”
n’&nbsp;s%©7äÞàõ´þ�ä.¸a*h]]ÓÊì¢Z—±}Y›Þ:=™ÈÂñû­Ò¢.ui—&amp;»fíîƒá»yýy�ó­£’]•KPìè†'¥röRRSÔƒžâÎ…±5ÎO¡Þ¨Œ¥˜¬¥Æµ¶#,®+Ö%Z©Æ
ý
lm`3"E¬–!•ÆìÇg=Va’0ÎŠÄ‰�+A…L«Äh1�6�š/*Y10ÕƒhÞ6nô.·¦5ÇÉ:úí„_|)á_.;÷‹‘œpÉH¥I:&amp;ºÈ‰¥â&gt;xy—á#ì;LÚ‰r99&gt;G‚Ìý®a=í-²íÅý}XÚ‡•BÈ¨4¢zÍ»9´ÓšÕpë½Ô£ß¿ýî¿ä†~´ÔQ.ê¶E—‰Éíh�
¯÷™zmS²±-•©£�ttðt.ºø^XýØ¶d¯&lt;`VøPà¯1‰ÓkúêÎå{Åw3šâ+SR*SÒªâîæGÜL¿›÷ öî@aþtÉƒ¹¢ÌÞ¤ðgßˆ|ã{¡¯?wëÈª’/ÍôVmo­Á¿úÀ‚®¸m%þA{lVmq}ïìÚž'.ÙWãðIÆÍ2ÀrŒÅ 
Ägº�™0›É�yÊÉ�è7êèl&amp;ßfm€dL¼=ö•l¢EçÓBO¦ww4¥»ôÔý;?¼ôÑWß{ýëoùõÅ¨ä²¾±UÇÐ¼-¯búøå¬¯|ÿÝ^=›SÖ5³�ið1ÊÀ÷P 6BÚ`UkÖ¹ÖÕšŒ¾øðªKQÍ7*òÖLsZ§Œmfá]°šþ÷Žt’h1&gt;Ñç?Xþ±V]Œáô?2ÀâÞùèt�#�&amp;,
¢Oër#èí&gt; <lÎ�<œ‰Ó‘™³ý�ðp9x¯ã'êcô§+ôƒÂldÚØiñ9¡Ë¡4ÿÜÃØˆíz>´V*«¸(u7�©ákéRÒÐ±[�'¢z.ÆuG¦µ—T
­,íê¥{»s“Cu
¥÷rï„Ä]&gt;wûòÕ„ØÄ¢ª¦þñÅ-¹Åãª˜¶g•®’ž�èüÑÈ¬ñ˜S‰%“‰¥£w‹F¢súîdt$gww·ÖöŒ5·÷UÆE'�=úîû!ï~xóäÕ˜«·£Cbn_‹¹{+-?»¼§ktk{g‹Øþ6ÌÙiE¯Z´myvFTÃåÝ÷.D¾ûÝoüÓƒø««#]è…Ù1À¨yh Ds8@¸ sa“ŠÐùÄ%¹µml­¸i&lt;§j÷‘E%ÌÛ˜¡UÈúˆ$rF›÷$"$fää�‘&gt;Öø¯ïß?›‹á#ÄY~m™àˆÍ{Y0ê£Ó˜Ôpe…8SÌãSäŸ
€þp
ÝÇ^ÂONP†àOŽcÑ^-#Kþñ€I
E�(�=Â¶®^$«2ý›êÂžÙ¤Ê®„‚ºòŽ¡Ñeé†Ò¢±Bq‚Ï"$ð$U¨¢1Å&lt;è¤éÜ&gt;µ¦iœF·ŸW!hùÇ–_'‡›ß¡rÅl¥C\Tx»ç5PÀ~Ð8u¯b0§f¬¼}¡wrîí&nbsp;™…7(±`,ƒÒBÚŽªr&nbsp;ÂHÁO&nbsp;k:_uß8Ï˜ìÙ›iÓ·2&amp;cîOÀS]çæØœJ¡§­kþ.£œØx´’²Ñ?×Â…“Zìœ0çÔmÞHé9w·!$­-¹j´yFº¦#MuÀ§Ùëô‡™÷Â'»sA�åS¯R&nbsp;¿¨\\�gö=žö;»ƒ=@xøQe-BCöÍlÈz$ûR�¢¥x)7¾ýVhÅùåç"ê.E¶^½Õq-¼ëZXÇõ›íañ]±•Óe“òQ¹yW°©Ý&gt;ôñx–è¤a(äèŒŠƒ�ûõdðUNÞMÞÿo)»s4E
ØÅÀè)ÿ&lt;�*ÊçlŽÈŒƒÅOdû÷_Ayü­à»ÿ3üÿ|8€¢b['*$âÊ¨±óÁdbXÍé;�!Å“Yý»í[ÖU«h|’ž�40÷lw’¤ÍTIö?öÇñ7hÂõÃœ�íšÆG ˜¦�&lt;ì-WPfzÝßF[&lt;=ºXf-¦&lt;@9ë½@ïb§=¸Ï~±¯p&gt;�2•IqJÀ°¹`&lt;6ÏÀ¾HåcÈË”¦&nbsp;ŽëÄî"Hñ{jIž` �Ê]PÏÀú›`mxcq‡þíc´@Ë‚íc±v@bÃ«PðrXat{ØÌ@Ò¿µšÀ·ê¯8Aš/í�	è(
Ø¢jÏ»Ö/m.Ÿ¿ŸÔy·ýÖýÁ{ík-Û¦
üzPO†ÐÁß¹Á`$H²gÜX«›ôdšwŽœO�žÌËï‡G¥Ö´,Á´=ä	X&nbsp;‰¤í^s^8¿!-½Kk‹›êòæá+w²_zÿò+\¹tû^m÷ìFîOR·é(ghÜxüçG°Ihaˆ‡jì8‘a‚f�¸Ò°YÓv&amp;eâ;"«Ê¡'£õÂ¥ùÀ÷¦ÙúÒNUh}òyíDûZMBëÍ‹GÎ=x7¼âä­ê3‘Õg¢k/ÆT_Êh»�ß“\?Y2¼Õ»®_Q{Õ&amp;ÚÅVÓhâ8‰ê!Â±÷C¯ÃûñYêáàØŒQê#
ì=6ecræK{Èð,:ïÎŒ½£ß¯ùàmÇ¿Ý{ö-'Ðxê'•ÇP~ö¥žÔk[ýuf	¶qôž¡:PŒ�D‰Ó@¬S�§&nbsp;M8fN{&nbsp;X]Ag)DÀþàEh"3QcâPjŠû§¸xñ]ñ¿	,z´Œ@¶@NžB‘×s¿„ýt�ÊyXê¡ÈIÓ«?Äc8â=
Ô³ˆ°´®ßqmÎÛ&amp;6JbºC&nbsp;'7q=m%êî\XôÔõÛÃ×búnåŽg÷m÷J,Rÿ(ÃX&nbsp;u“Í*T¢dÑ:Ñ¸^vo0.¢ñBJgTõÌƒ1YÇ¶yÆàÛuˆ›¨²‹*³(ÝõÌ÷ìÖeöÇ…×_¸Qs&gt;4cHÚµã\×R�/ÈÙ|á¯ª2&nbsp;ƒ¤¥":L^­ *VLã
K÷zoÇ4‡fõ¦´.5/©–Ô
J°Ò+¥\\Ñw/g^müørË±”éð´ÙÈ„‘›·{B®Ö��î¸Y2—7$ï–:6Í&gt;è°C	åƒÎp€£PþEšþwX] k…ò»“ìÉnoX'{·jŠÆÓâ;®ƒåŽ'M}[ÙÈú½‚É9X€Ž¶ G€9—ì�ÁèÑÃ~²ÁfœŽ›�RAPe:3P›Á$ûÄ.~ØÙŸ ö|@Ÿ]Ÿ0²0¦0*{h�é|1sÔñS£]\Ù³—4/&lt;Ó“ù@ÿÛA$�ÝKE´H­M}wOçù^äOÿ6îõ¯^{m¬ò®r¡Ã¡Y�::)Š¹»Að»”+ºŸ7@OÆúùÛçæmŸ›5ÿ‡óÿÚ©ùOEóÿýjÛÿ÷bù7¾Uô£oWyeøî5EW…k{Êg•cZÁ&nbsp;_ád;&amp;P&lt;¦�´e�
C1‚am2ÏVŸ¢=u$éHñÇßŽùÉ¯µ*ôÝùš,Ãò¸hÒ3ÈÈK&nbsp;õ|€sfò±ù%�ëSGžÑ�O
²§¿dcƒ±ôOÔ“ñÎÿVz2˜¶ðö)V¡G(å±„§×û÷ñ+¯jÎ®'°1€á3òEÄÎQ£žéÉü&gt;ºêÙ7&gt;;È5b Ž;tK`Œ…Ÿ5@î&nbsp;=‚Ÿ‡
<d@„•ì_ðyg0öƒ3ðjã-���r9¦›‡ ™ßqÿeábü€Èåáka±Àú…`ôá”(*�•Äyj8ˆðÁø="" ¥á="" <òò Õ?Ãgn4pÿÏ°ÌÏ¨(b1)ðÀår€n0õ£ÊÅÂþo<Ï”?��s£ÔÝÈ‰="" p&�þ?ÓÛ'Õ}þŠÿ3Èá="" ¼+$á¤4aõá˜¾ˆc³:oÿ²ð eívÎÈ©˜v„3ÑÍï¶$oÔkvupya+gøãÚ6ô¬ÜÌï»žÝ‘7[²˜t¾z·h&öÁ@zÅhýðÎÔ¶qiòaÑ…õö¬Ä—q;)¡1,£ã~ýtÇôÎ¦h÷akõÁÃÌŠ¦{x«¢y¼©w~x~o]jvãÄspâb<e�="" wÐyt~¶Ç@87Žøp;‰š�Âc¹="">m¬ò€lÀX³èR:”³’±ªÁ‚ˆŠð÷òÏÿ²ðÂkÑšÉF¯n	F}¢:€€¶_äü&amp;VÅ`´y½�Xà@§o\n+ã€ãßï ßa
ËäÿÔËø	/S98cíD£DT/êÇjÒ.^üå¥çÿþî±—†K’mÛÓä›	*šì7¶ÔÓ³[ýƒs}C³3ÛR%lÔsñ7GmZÁ*ûÃDY£O²ƒ¯Äz2µª
Ó–Áù†$"Ì¶ÏkJšfà»$1«9ÿAkEA{YakNfEìí{á×ã¢n@Uæîƒ˜¤ÎÜ¼Å¦†™ÚŠºÔèÔ«'®~�u¶³&amp;{}etW¡˜\W6ŽJî×ÏÅt§uVuŒ®H4°¹�þõKÿü(˜ðÞ	`l ‚Î¢‹C’�žòGtç•º#Š–Ù¶2�ñÁ.=äŠ‹ú•Îí¡„öÂ�3#pîØWßyã[ï|ðfHtvÝð‚Ô7½éÂQ÷Ó×sþá{ïüËË§2‹:&amp;æå¥�vô	—üãšI'fŸM¢zÛ¹Ô»Óœ7’^s)¼þRÁtÆœvNä-„±L†É&nbsp;G½ŒU 3~E}¶f

?À^N¥w`¬?pÒÿØ¤õÐë�¨§þuU	êYBDê
,ÂÐÃtaÕÏŽ%s½8é ;øK#JëÃ®1hh
�É
°G¤ÌGjŠn¼Š3k|“ÅñÑÀ×D™Ð¯&nbsp;Ù$N b…®Ç—ÉdÖ~/àè ¦(NêâlSŒN­÷8Ä›K¸ÓâÕ&amp;®¨¼]³†ôšÕ«©Ãï\mxÿzóé[-á‰­¥ÕÐ˜UYµ:ÕúÊtGWmnI\XüÕs‘—/ÆFÆäWu
L­íèíJ·(s‹Ã;–û�™}w²ÆÒÊšÆ•õ£»eÝ•ã1™m‘ñ•±‰%é)9‰™)7""�Ÿ¼þÞÑÈãçSoÄä'”fUeÅßOˆHˆ¾��T[R&gt;=6¤Ø[ÆEÑ%=RÑ»'
‹Ž¥¶Ý¶Ì†ÛG®¼ü÷7Ž¾P•+[žòáÌ«ÝEbQ+€ðÄR¸ì„3æ¬]ƒcbMÖ9¾ÒÐ;Û:´4·¥…¤éÈP`^Ã¬ÁÎ`Žb°�úÐã�÷ûŸÍ�ÀÂ'/¦Ù¼….ä“6˜W˜$ª•eéüªlyÏ°k€,hÀß$bsÏþ
CQŸn&lt;ç'Ïï§oû_{ø÷ñßXÆ˜É©Ç�ÄßøÈ¨†m‹�¥1¶ï‹^G�f·WpÁ)1�[FÇÐÚ^ËØBM÷ÐÈâú¶ZP™œ0^ŒÂ0U5Ò“Á#Hî(d‡ÇA…P™àd�(ËÀïx¯€=ÀqÓ=A\S;§·
#‹òÉ5ÍºÂ¾«vìþŒ…€’±Óí,Ø2‚!ºš½¨Ü©\âªÚÕ:¡ÎoÚ¹�=?v9v0$a *c$)¸±gcrQ	S|”�*àßHêŽt^
,ƒéÄ¾9K^Ózxz×•Ä†[ÙÙ�“½KŠm£¦«àö
ZŒìuj§ &nbsp;Eœ³:pGóùçp'ÞÇ1Ù™\Ôœú•gî5?ÄI
†åg°©„&amp;s´%P(ÉÀ%�EÔ[D� ÊäöåeÓhåJ^ÊpLXõÅk¥gãšÂòÇÓ«×
vÊë%µ;ÕëeM›µãÊQ©cLhƒ€0”Aé8šŒsã\O`Ç
²LÐÀ·]0ú9D&gt;Ëö=­¬}0ƒ]BµØDÍxštX&nbsp;TŠêŠŠkhŽfqb(™°@·ú¿½ÿžàGF$I_‡å“î&amp;eâÖ‚c¬l.;²þ"\&lt;Nm[«]2âºÖîÅŠÃFÇ¸qÐŽ×–‘_|›f´‡›õ¼’¬BOƒÁïû7ªäÁàïv7ðÀ™mö
Á/�‡A?±ƒ”1]û­¢`“¸èƒƒs¢û¼GÑÀWü¯?’iOX)ŠÒ�	@Ž	l6$Âá-¼þÄP„ñæþŠç`&lt;	´¿²ñJ¬�¬™AÕ‚�¿²0‘£Ã@%o:˜ÖµøGŒ
ÆYoð.wËàª,¾çVlGDîpF×F›Ä²ÅvW‰÷fXô‘aë#ôÑ=t©&nbsp;à�õÌÀ„JÓÀö{g“àw	z2·R*Z$Y0Ž”ÈÑÏçCÏ��A=Å‘(Ð¿ˆàtÐ¦Lhè™	K(€žÌOß&gt;ÿQHlEÛ&nbsp;Ô‹
|ž¢Þ
?¢0´à5¤ÚÒZÃi¥MpxÕÁ^oëNùÝÎ�[ÍçãZoVÎÏëf°…=`$¾ˆ¹‰4¯hï‰ì]`!	c2ýÛ­Åã™wÛo\(9r¹ä(d&lt;ñ­!Ñõ&nbsp;*s³ìThÑÉÈÒI
‘e£¹Ã;=[¶
™žµ˜¨ï&amp;"?T?VÇ‡,Ø#±ÃûñYêáx£Éò-B6&nbsp;ôd€‹l
jÖŠÊUëxýDÂ‰Ú¿ÕòÁ·:&gt;|®æ½¬xÿ¹²£ß+?ýboÚuÉ`£IºN~šEŽf1N¦`±Åù¬#;`é,´G`Ò–¸$2wL³9È,šb6‡¥#Öÿ�Ö”
áG’yn£ÿ`�íWÍOýØhÎLÒþ©š±àiA=î†Gñÿ¤¤¿b›ÿ»°´
_j0¸$Z0¦&nbsp;'³nY˜†*–Dµ]	k;“¯Å;	Yqñ37oÝˆî
ÏJéXoÝ6maGŒ-\«tP2Ñ‰²ÏÒ�º#o,•Kiî¶Ý,ÏÞkßµ,éÜR‹§
nÒ˜ƒz‰dRÛW4‘ÕxùjÅéÔÎ¸–õzÌõ
÷¤:ðXË‡ÄŸçDÃmŸG#+@è|z2K¦±šÅ¼äîHx�ËHk_k[Ñ¬hzy´ã]%nMú*Vïßh=}¡ùƒ¨Á‹½n´ž½Þt&amp;¤æ\rlÓzõ¬a:º&nbsp;0mhbœƒhìÏ&gt; ¡$ÒdPfÄ))&gt;ã,#VˆšLb›•·UÎÝOê‹j½˜9;¬ëP‹RÁ­¡rØÔŒŒdagÜB»ŸFï•Ã¥ªÊ½'wlíÙ7ö¬ëËµn¹Á£6út¦0ò08ÇŽùíš2U"àÌãÈøæ±zû3=†þ„G_xöô¯‡I!ƒ‡B7:ñÉ(h¨ûQöd–v­E�sgo&gt;³'ó¯‡øgñ&amp;õ
$¬Ïh£Ä½Ú3•ZwõWÑ?ÿ¢_úÓ�}¿3õÜFo‘e{B´(IO‹sèÉŒ‘žŒëÿgï=&nbsp;Í®3ÁöHKsfvf×&gt;Þõ®ÏÙ=ã™��½J¶dÙV–-©¥nu’ZÝêÜÕÕ•‹¬"YÌ9çœC1ç&amp;€™s`’ "ðßï¾€¨*V©ä®®îjá?�?~üxá¾ûî½ï¾ûîý‘ÍNÆðÔ¤ñ©	üÉüû6Åç�ÿ™{Í_üðößþCÑ¿Uwñ•áÔeoÃñÆô‰QÁHD:3x	–`|5
™,†iJ‰˜“=�qWØ&gt;(œ)ð¨÷ø1¹”yö/Ý~6P¡màÜÜðtú;f7£ÿŒ&lt;
àlîs=¢âûŠ±QmâøŒép;7X=‘�¨ÃŸÌ]v2–ß‘kgMù{s²ÿØ»øg}›/Ì’àB�y7‚,²©›3HÛÅñÚ`[½ŽÏëO?},r¼�h9Oü£sÃ�Œçˆiç×Œ=³.»ìd&gt;céjÄc�ffà(&amp;==ÝÝÝýå—_¾té¼ÅÀU¬k0YK+N+¹»À$&gt;ûúMß?»”OÜS¯ûBížþÞÿ}Ç’~ƒ×îM÷Æß!ö~n‚50Î�¬i…áuCI×zxÁðû¡õçü«®„ÕcŸ´°y¡oV­Àº‹½¦03»¦¦±�”º	ßÌ.¯Ì÷”N÷Äv¯ÔŽð‚®ì¦1ñôÎ‚Ê¸k0á$‚P.ïõ=[áÙ=&gt;	¢ÐÌŽ¦‘­Q¹aãH@šÝ±ÀIIó\\^w`jKHfKRiwmÏüä†.ý±D‡
TH´A{rÇÇvñÀI¡4"A
‰o{e[ü¼³v 8ÖÝà&nbsp;ˆÅqh&gt;XS-J{kÇó†*3+ÓÕó}ÆíiÁO20B�¨�~uÊw(Ï…ý{ïü5À“Ìu� ãñß²õ85B&nbsp;…</d@„•ì_ðyg0öƒ3ðjã-���r9¦›‡></lî�<œ‰ó‘™³ý�ðp9x¯ã'êcô§+ôƒâldúøiñ9¡ë¡4ÿüãøˆíz></q½˜;dãj`à�è�×ÿ$0></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://corona-transition.org/IMG/pdf/a_closer_look_at_u.s._deaths_due_to_covid-19_-_the_johns_hopkins_news-letter.pdf">https://corona-transition.org/IMG/pdf/a_closer_look_at_u.s._deaths_due_to_covid-19_-_the_johns_hopkins_news-letter.pdf</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://corona-transition.org/IMG/pdf/a_closer_look_at_u.s._deaths_due_to_covid-19_-_the_johns_hopkins_news-letter.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25253486</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 13:31:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: 25 Days of Vim, a Vim Advent calendar]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25253320">thread link</a>) | @colinbartlett
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://vimtricks.com/25-days-of-vim_2020/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vimtricks.com/25-days-of-vim_2020/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<h2>Enjoy 25 Vim Tips to Sharpen Your Skills</h2>
<p>With <strong>25 Days of Vim</strong>, we’re delivering one Vim tip from our archives every day for 25 days between December 1 and December 25. 🎄</p>
<p>🎁 Unwrap a small Vim gift every morning with one of our tips, tricks, or tutorials. Some you’ll know, some will be new. Either way, constant reinforcement is an excellent way to keep honing your Vim. You’ll also get all our brand-new Vim tips, published every Monday and Thursday!</p>





<p><a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/25-days-of-vim?utm_source=badge-featured&amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;utm_souce=badge-25-days-of-vim" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer external" data-wpel-link="external"><img loading="lazy" src="https://api.producthunt.com/widgets/embed-image/v1/featured.svg?post_id=276405&amp;theme=dark" alt="25 Days of Vim - A Vim Advent Calendar | Product Hunt" width="250" height="54"></a></p>
<div id="wp-advent-wrapper">
<ul id="wp-advent-calendar">
<li>
<a href="https://vimtricks.com/p/sheet/01-12-2020/" data-wpel-link="internal">
1 </a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="https://vimtricks.com/p/sheet/02-12-2020/" data-wpel-link="internal">
2 </a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="https://vimtricks.com/p/sheet/03-12-2020/" data-wpel-link="internal">
3 </a>
</li>
<li><span>4</span></li>
<li><span>5</span></li>
<li><span>6</span></li>
<li><span>7</span></li>
<li><span>8</span></li>
<li><span>9</span></li>
<li><span>10</span></li>
<li><span>11</span></li>
<li><span>12</span></li>
<li><span>13</span></li>
<li><span>14</span></li>
<li><span>15</span></li>
<li><span>16</span></li>
<li><span>17</span></li>
<li><span>18</span></li>
<li><span>19</span></li>
<li><span>20</span></li>
<li><span>21</span></li>
<li><span>22</span></li>
<li><span>23</span></li>
<li><span>24</span></li>
</ul>
</div>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vimtricks.com/25-days-of-vim_2020/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25253320</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 13:07:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Feel Like I Have No Real Interests; My Only Interest Is Making Money]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 185 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25253197">thread link</a>) | @_davebennett
<br/>
November 30, 2020 | https://www.bennettnotes.com/post/my-only-interest-is-making-money/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.bennettnotes.com/post/my-only-interest-is-making-money/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<article>
<p>I have no real interests or hobbies. If I was shopping for myself I’d probably just buy another book on “growing your side hustle” or one of the many “building a startup” books.</p>
<p>Revenue, monetization, and profit are always the primary driver for my activities. Whether or not I actually care about a particular topic is sorta irrelevant. And my frustration is that depending on who I talk to, I get entirely different perspectives on whether this going to facilitate my success in life or not. For example, people who are like my business/money focused family applaud my efforts. They don’t understand how this is bad.</p>
<p>“Dave, how is spending your free time trying to make more money a bad thing? You can use that money to pursue your hobbies or interests.”</p>
<p>“Yeah uncle, but I honestly don’t know what my hobbies and interests are besides things that make more money.”</p>
<p>“Great Dave, so your passion is making money!”</p>
<p>“But I don’t want that to be my passion!”</p>
<p>But if I talk to my more passion focused friends, I’m sorta self-judging in my head.</p>
<p>“Dave, I’m working on a youth charity. It’s soo many hours of long work and stressful, but really rewarding.”</p>
<p>“Oh umm…that’s great Pam. But that’s a lot of work, and no money? Like…is it really worth it? Imagine if you turned it into some type of education business. What’s the market like for that? You could charge at least $300 per student.”</p>
<p>Ugh, this is what gives me migraines. My 25 year old anxiety is telling me that if I pick the wrong strategy then my future is forever doomed. I also have no idea where this obsession began. I didn’t grow up poor, so I can’t use that as an excuse for my obsession. I think it might have to do with imposter syndrome and feeling like I have to prove myself. Basically, if I have lots of money rolling in then I can say “fuck the system” and not be criticized. I falsely feel like people can’t judge me if I have my own business that’s making Elon Musk level income.</p>
<p>Or maybe it’s simply because I live in the United States, and that’s just our culture here. Plus with all the uncertainty, you never know when debt can hit you. Poverty, streets, homeless shelter, etc.</p>
<p>But this just all feels wrong to me. It feels like I’m digging myself into a bad hole. What if my time was used toward genuine activities and interests? I could also have a chance at financial success with those. I just don’t know what those genuine interests are. All I know is that when I chase after these money quests, I always feel cheated in the end.</p>
<p>Let’s walk inside my mind for a second.</p>
<p>So I work on coding side projects outside of work. Do I love coding and problem solving? Eh, I’m not really sure. But, I do love the idea of one day rolling in cash from some tool or app I built. Therefore, I’m going to spend my time trying to find a niche market that I can penetrate with some basic app/program that I can at least charge $100 a month for. Then I just need to spend a couple of hours everyday scouring through Google trends, Reddit, or Exploding Topics to find something people are currently into. Then maybe set up a landing page, and see if people enter in their credit card info. Or how about I search the Apple App Store and find some shitty app that people pay big bucks for and copy it? Oh wait, hold up, snack boxes are trending! Okay, so I can just set up a service for $20 a month to send people almonds, right?</p>
<p>Trust me, it gets worst.</p>
<p>I make videos on YouTube. I have a little over 200k subscribers currently. Do I like making videos? Eh…I’m not really sure. Truthfully, most days I would rather not engage in the activity. But influencer sponsorships pay a lot! Also, adsense is a really nice passive income source. So what I need to do is spend my time studying the YouTube algorithm so I can produce videos that get more views. More views equals more money!! Oh and remember when I made videos on Android? Yeah nobody cares about that niche anymore. So I’m going to use tools like TubeBuddy or VidIQ to see trending topics that people are watching. Okay people are all talking about <em>Among Us</em> right now. So if I make a video that’s at least 10 minutes long I can stick a mid-roll ad into it too! Don’t forget all the long-tail keywords. Wait, my website hardly has any ads on it right now. I’m missing out on extra income! I need at least a sidebar ad and also a footer ad.</p>
<p>Guess what? After two days I lost motivation in the Snackbox idea. As for YouTube, I made videos on the “well researched SEO friendly topics” and they performed horribly. It was like another slap in the face saying “Dave, this is what happens when you chase money without regard for interests.” But….but…all the entrepreneurs say just having interest in building a business is enough!</p>
<p>Yeah, so I don’t know what to say or how to end this. I’m just hoping that by sharing my obstacles and fears I get some helpful incite; or at least connect people who also share this struggle. I feel like it’s one of the many problems that’s not addressed adequately and leaves us just desperate for answers.</p>

</article>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.bennettnotes.com/post/my-only-interest-is-making-money/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25253197</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:45:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I am an 80 column purist]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 71 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25251494">thread link</a>) | @Spiritus
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I write and prefer code that fits within 80 columns in <a href="https://curl.haxx.se/">curl</a> and other projects – and there are reasons for it. I’m a little bored by the people who respond and say that they have 400 inch monitors already and they can use them.</p>



<p>I too have multiple large high resolution screens – but writing wide code is still a bad idea! So I decided I’ll write down my reasoning once and for all!</p>



<h2>Narrower is easier to read</h2>



<p>There’s a reason newspapers and magazines have used narrow texts for centuries and in fact even books <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line_length">aren’t using long lines</a>. For most humans, it is simply easier on the eyes and brain to read texts that aren’t using really long lines. This has been known for a very long time.</p>



<p>Easy-to-read code is easier to follow and understand which leads to fewer bugs and faster debugging.</p>



<h2>Side-by-side works better</h2>



<p>I <em>never</em> run windows full sized on my screens for anything except watching movies. I frequently have two or more editor windows next to each other, sometimes also with one or two extra terminal/debugger windows next to those. To make this feasible and still have the code readable, it needs to fit “wrapless” in those windows.</p>



<p>Sometimes reading a code diff is easier side-by-side and then too it is important that the two can fit next to each other nicely.</p>



<h2>Better diffs</h2>



<p>Having code grow vertically rather than horizontally is beneficial for diff, git and other tools that work on changes to files. It reduces the risk of merge conflicts and it makes the merge conflicts that still happen easier to deal with.</p>



<h2>It encourages shorter names</h2>



<p>A side effect by strictly not allowing anything beyond column 80 is that it becomes really hard to use those terribly annoying 30+ letters java-style names on functions and identifiers. A function name, and especially local ones, should be short. Having long names make them really hard to read and makes it really hard to spot the difference between the other functions with similarly long names where just a sub-word within is changed.</p>



<p>I know especially Java people object to this as they’re trained in a different culture and say that a method name should rather include a lot of details of the functionality “to help the user”, but to me that’s a weak argument as all non-trivial functions will have more functionality than what can be expressed in the name and thus the user needs to know how the function works <em>anyway.</em></p>



<p>I don’t mean 2-letter names. I mean long enough to make sense but not be ridiculous lengths. Usually within 15 letters or so.</p>



<h2>Just a few spaces per indent level</h2>



<p>To make this work, and yet allow a few indent levels, the code basically have to have small indent-levels, so I prefer to have it set to two spaces per level.</p>



<h2>Many indent levels is wrong anyway</h2>



<p>If you do a lot of indent levels it gets really hard to write code that still fits within the 80 column limit. That’s a subtle way to suggest that you should not write functions that needs or uses that many indent levels. It should then rather be split out into multiple smaller functions, where then each function won’t need that many levels!</p>



<h2>Why exactly 80?</h2>



<p>Once upon the time it was of course because terminals had that limit and these days the exact number 80 is not a must. I just happen to think that the limit has worked fine in the past and I haven’t found any compelling reason to change it since.</p>



<p>It also has to be a hard and fixed limit as if we allow a few places to go beyond the limit we end up on a slippery slope and code slowly grow wider over time – I’ve seen it happen in many projects with “soft enforcement” on code column limits.</p>



<h2>Enforced by a tool</h2>



<p>In <a href="https://curl.se/">curl</a>, we have ‘checksrc’ which will yell errors at any user trying to build code with a too long line present. This is good because then we don’t have to “waste” human efforts to point this out to contributors who offer pull requests. The tool will point out such mistakes with ruthless accuracy.</p>



<h2>Credits</h2>



<p>Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/piotrarssale-15944391/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5016297">piotr kurpaska</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5016297">Pixabay</a></p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25251494</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:31:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Evolution of tree data structures for indexing: more than it sounds]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25251359">thread link</a>) | @MarkusWinand
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://erthalion.info/2020/11/28/evolution-of-btree-index-am/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://erthalion.info/2020/11/28/evolution-of-btree-index-am/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p><span>28 Nov 2020</span></p><h2 id="0-how-to-read-me">0. How to read me?</h2>
<p>I have to admit, my research blog posts are getting longer and longer. From one
side I find it genuinely encouraging, because if one gets so much information
just by scratching the topic, imagine what’s hidden beneath the surface! One
university professor once said “what could be interesting in databases?”, and
it turns out freaking a lot! On the other side it certainly poses problems for
potential readers. To overcome them I would suggest an interesting approach:
print this blog post out, or open it on your tablet/e-reader, where you can
make notes with a pencil or markers. Now while reading it try to spot ideas
particularly exciting for you and mark them. Along the way there would be
definitely some obscure parts or questions, write them on the sides as well.
You can experiment with the diagrams, changing or extending them, or just
drawing funny faces. But do not read everything at once, have no fear of
putting it aside for a while, and read in chunks that are convenient for you.
Some parts could be skipped as the text is build out of relatively independent
topics. The table of contents can help and guide you. Having said that we’re
ready to embark on the journey.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="#1-introduction">Introduction</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#2-rum-conjecture">RUM conjecture</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#3-b-tree-basics">B-tree basics</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#4-beyond-the-hard-leaves-of-basics">Beyond the hard leavers of
basics</a>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="#41-key-normalization">Key normalization</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#42-prefix-truncation">Prefix truncation</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#43-dynamic-prefix-truncation">Dynamic prefix truncation</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#44-suffix-truncation">Suffix truncation</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#45-indirection-vector">Indirection vector</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#46-sb-tree">SB-tree</a>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#5-why-is-it-not-enough">Why is it not enough?</a>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="#51-partitioned-b-tree">Partitioned B-tree</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#52-hybrid-indexes">Hybrid indexes</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#53-bw-tree">Bw-Tree</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#54-dptree">DPTree</a>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#6-trie">Trie</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#7-learned-indexes">Learned indexes</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#8-is-that-all">Is that all?</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="#references">References</a>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction</h2>
<p>Whenever we speak about indexes, especially in PostgreSQL context, there is a
lot to talk about: B-tree, Hash, GiST, SP-GiST, GIN, BRIN, RUM. But what if I
tell you that even the first item in this list alone hiding astonishing number
of interesting details and years of research? In this blog post I’ll try to
prove this statement, and we will be concerned mostly with B-tree as a data
structure.</p>
<p><img src="https://erthalion.info/public/img/btree-joke.png" width="80%"></p>

<p>Let’s start systematically and take a look at the definition first:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>B-tree is a self-balancing tree data structure that maintains sorted data and
allows searches, sequential access, insertions, and deletions in logarithmic
time.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What is your first association with the concept of B-tree? Mine is “old and
well researched, or in other words boring”. And indeed apparently it was first
introduced in <a href="https://infolab.usc.edu/csci585/Spring2010/den_ar/indexing.pdf">1970</a>! Not only that, already in 1979 they
were <a href="http://cgi.di.uoa.gr/~ad/M149/ubiquitous_btree.pdf">ubiquitous</a>. Does it mean there is nothing exciting left any
more? Once upon a time I came across a remarkable read called
<a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1561/1900000028">Modern B-Tree techniques</a> which inspired me to dig
deeper into the topic and read bunch of shiny new whitepapers. Afterwards
totally by chance I’ve stumbled upon a book “Database Internals: A Deep Dive
into How Distributed Data Systems Work”, which contains great sections on
B-tree design. Both works were the triggers to write this blog post. What was I
saying about nothing exciting left? At the end I couldn’t be more wrong.</p>
<p>It turns out that there are multitude of interesting ideas and techniques
around B-Trees. They’re all coming from the desire to satisfy different (often
incompatible) needs, as well as adapt to emerging hardware. To demonstrate how
many of those exist, lets play a game. Below you can find a table of names I’ve
found in various science papers, together with a couple of silly names I’ve
come up myself. Can you find out the fake ones?</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>B-tree</td>
<td>B<sup>+</sup>-tree</td>
<td>B<sub>link</sub>-tree</td>
<td>DPTree</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>wB<sup>+</sup>-tree</td>
<td>NV Tree</td>
<td>FPTree</td>
<td>FASTFAIR</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>HiKV</td>
<td>Masstree</td>
<td>Skip List</td>
<td>ART</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>WORT</td>
<td>CDDS Tree</td>
<td>Bw Tree</td>
<td>HOT</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>KISS Tree</td>
<td>VAST Tree</td>
<td>FAST</td>
<td>HV Tree</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>UB Tree</td>
<td>LHAM</td>
<td>MDAM</td>
<td>Hybrid B<sup>+</sup> Tree</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p>Any ideas? Well, I have a confession to make – all of them are real, I just
don’t have enough imagination to come up with such names. Having this in mind
hopefully you understand that if we want to make a survey, the first step would
be to establish some classification. Not only this will help us to structure
the material, but also will explain why on earth anyone would need to invent so
many variations of what we though was so simple!</p>
<h2 id="2-rum-conjecture">2. RUM conjecture</h2>
<p>To classify different index access methods we need to think about the following
ambitious question – is there anything common between almost any index access
method? The authors of <a href="https://stratos.seas.harvard.edu/files/stratos/files/rum.pdf">RUM conjecture</a> provide an interesting
insight about this topic:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The fundamental challenges that every researcher, systems architect, or
designer faces when designing a new access method are how to minimize, i)
read times, ii) update cost , and iii) memory (or storage) overhead.</p>
<p>In this paper, we conjecture that when optimizing the read-update-memory
overheads, optimizing in any two areas negatively impacts the third</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This essentially states that if an index access method could be specified as a
point inside “Read”, “Update” (on the Fig. 1 it’s called “Write” for
convenience of drawing), “Memory” space we can observe an interesting
invariant. Every time we modify one index access method to have less overhead
for reading or memory footprint (i.e. shift the corresponding point closer to
“Read”/”Memory” corners), we inevitably loose on the updating workload (i.e.
getting further away from “Write” corner).</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://erthalion.info/public/img/rum.png" width="50%">
<br>
<figcaption>
Fig 1. RUM space
</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>In fact as a non-scientist I would even speculate that there should be another
dimension called “Complexity”, but the idea is still clear. I will try to show
this invariant at work via examples in this blog post, but it already gives us
some ground under the feet and opportunity to visually represent different
versions of B-tree by moving point on the triangle back and forth. But first
let’s recall the basics.</p>
<h2 id="3-b-tree-basics">3. B-tree basics</h2>
<p>So what is B-tree? Well, it’s a tree data structure: a root node, some number
of branch nodes (marked grey) and a bunch of leaf nodes (marked green):</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://erthalion.info/public/img/btree.png" width="100%">
<br>
<figcaption>
Fig 2. B-tree nodes arrangement
</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Every node of this tree is usually a page of some certain size and contains
keys (shaded slices of a node) and pointers to other nodes (empty slices with
arrows). Keys on page are kept in sorted order to facilitate fast search within
a page.</p>
<p>The original B-tree design assumed to have user data in all nodes,
branch and leaf. But nowadays the standard approach is a variation called
B<sup>+</sup>-tree, where user data is present only in leaf nodes and branch
nodes contains separator keys (pivot tuples in PostgreSQL terminology). In this
way separation between branch and leave nodes become more strict, allowing
better flexibility for choosing format of former and making deletion operations
can affect only latter. In fact the original B-tree design is barely worth
mentioning these days and I’m doing this just to be precise. Since
B<sup>+</sup>-tree is sort of default design, we’ll use B-tree and
B<sup>+</sup>-tree interchangeably in this text from now on. An interesting
thing to mention here is that the only requirements for separator keys is to
guide search algorithm to a correct leaf node. As long as they fulfil this
condition they can contain anything, no other requirements exist.</p>
<p>Strictly speaking, only child pointers are truly necessary in this design, but
quite often databases also maintain additional neighbour pointers, e.g. what you
can see on the Fig. 2 between the leaf nodes. It could be helpful for some
operations like index scan, but need to be taken into account for node
split/merge operations. PostgreSQL uses <a href="https://www.csd.uoc.gr/~hy460/pdf/p650-lehman.pdf">Lehman-Yao</a> version,
called B<sub>link</sub>-tree, with links to both left and right sibling nodes
(the left link one is actually not presented in the original
B<sub>link</sub>-tree design, and it makes backward scan somewhat interesting),
and there are even implementations like WiredTiger with
<a href="https://github.com/wiredtiger/wiredtiger/blob/f08bc4b18612ef95a39b12166abcccf207f91596/src/include/btmem.h#L550">parent pointers</a>.</p>
<p>Having all this in place one can perform a search query by following the path
marked red on the Fig. 2, first hitting the root, finding a proper separator
key, following a downlink and landing on a correct page where we deploy binary
search to find the resulting key.</p>
<p>Until now, we were talking only about static parts of B-tree design, but of
course there is more to it. For example there is one dynamic aspect of much
importance (quite often it even scares developers like a nightmare), namely
page splits. What do we need to do when there is a new value to insert, but the
target page does not have enough space like on the following diagram?</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://erthalion.info/public/img/page-split-1.png" width="60%">
<br>
<figcaption>
Fig 3. B-tree page split (a)
</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>What happens here is we’re trying to insert the new value (shaded box) into the
page with not enough space for it. To maintain the three balanced we need to
allocate another leaf page, distribute keys between old and new leaf, promote a
new separator key into the parent page and update all required links
(left/right siblings if present):</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://erthalion.info/public/img/page-split-2.png" width="60%">
<br>
<figcaption>
Fig 4. B-tree page split (b)
</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Curiously enough the new separator key could be chosen freely, it could be any
value as long as it separates both pages. We can see what does it change in the
optimization section.</p>
<p>Locking is obviously an important part of a page split. No one wants to end up
with concurrency issues when pages get updated while in the middle of a split,
so a page to be split is write-locked as well as e.g. right sibling to update
left-link if present.</p>
<p>As you can see, page splits are introducing performance overhead. We need to
bring in a new page, move elements around and everything should be consistent
and correctly locked. And already at this pretty much basic point we already
can see some interesting trade-offs. For example B*-tree modification tries to
rebalance data between neighbouring nodes to postpone page split as long as
possible. In terms of trade-offs it looks like a balance between complexity and
insert overhead.</p>
<p>I didn’t tell you everything about B<sub>link</sub>-tree and it’s going to be our next
topic example in this section. Not only Lehman-Yao version adds a link to the
neighbour, it also introduces a “high key” to each page, which is an upper bound
on the keys that are allowed on page. While obviously introducing a bit memory
overhead those two changes make it possible to detect a concurrent page split
by checking the page high key, which allows the tree to be searched …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://erthalion.info/2020/11/28/evolution-of-btree-index-am/">https://erthalion.info/2020/11/28/evolution-of-btree-index-am/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://erthalion.info/2020/11/28/evolution-of-btree-index-am/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25251359</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:01:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Am Not Fat]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 134 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25251082">thread link</a>) | @snow_mac
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content" role="main">
      <p> <em>Published: </em> 11/28/2020</p>

      <p>I’m not fat. There I said it, I should feel better about myself, right? Size is just a number. Right? Come on you know it’s true, size, weight and all that jazz is just a BS figure on the scale. That’s what we tell ourselves to make us feel better.</p>

<p>I’m obese, my medical BMI is 42.0. I’m 335 pounds. As Penn Jillette would say, I’m a “fat fuck”. I’m tired of being a “fat fuck” or as my wife prefers a “big guy”.</p>



<p>I’m an audiobook guy. I’m in love with Audible, she is very wonderful service to have, she reads to me every day, all day. About two weeks ago, I was bored, and she suggested Presto, a book by Penn Jillette about how he lost 100 pounds. I was bored, lazy and waiting for someone so I bought the book. Oh my gosh, the language is obscene, but the author is hilarious and entertaining. I could not put the book down. It made me want to toss the skinny white peppermint mocha and bananas in the trash…</p>

<p>Basically, Penn is a obese guy like me, well he was, he was 330 pounds at his highest. He went to the hospital for heart issues and nearly died. On a fist full of pills to keep his blood pressure less than the voltage of an outlet in Europe he embarked on a crazy, all in diet consisting of potatoes for two weeks. I like his style, he’s an all or nothing guy like me. Either give me the steak, the ice cream and the sides or give me nothing. I want to eat big; I want to live big. Moderation is bullshit as Penn would say, I would agree! I don’t do anything in moderation. If I’m going to do something, it’s all-in baby. When in Vegas last summer, I was the dipshit who went all in with a pair of kings in my hand and straight on the table; that’s me baby, not the smartest guy but hey I like to live it big.</p>

<p>I don’t do keto, I don’t do paleo, but when I do diet, I go really big, I go to Costco and literally buy everything I need to be successful on that plan, I research, I plan. It’s just like thanksgiving this year; I researched, I planned, I went to Costco and planned out each and every ingredient. I was diligent. Every doctor, health coach and fitness instructor has told me that my relationship with food is fucked up. Well, not fucked up, but bad; unhealthy. As Penn would say your life sucks if you’re taking diet advice from a Las Vegas Magician, well, Penn, my life does suck. I can’t breathe outside very well, hell, I get windy walking to the park. I’m an obese guy, I have a CPAP machine, I’m 335 pounds, I can barely do the things I want to do, basic stuff; sleep and wake rested, eat and not feel sick, go for a walk and not get winded. I’m half Penn’s age and his same weight… It’s time for a change.</p>



<p>The plan according to Penn’s buddy, Cray Ray, aka “Ray Cronise” is to do the following:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Eat nothing but potatoes for two weeks. Boiled, baked, steamed, roasted; does not matter, just no salt, oil, or sugar. Plain, nothing added, no salt, no butter, no pepper, no olive oil, just a plain, boring potato. Sweet, red, yellow, gold, purple, do not be a racist pig about potatoes, eat the potato rainbow, but just potatoes. Feel free to pig out on potatoes; just no fries or chips, that’s the beautiful potato ruined by Americans</li>
  <li>Contrast showers: Humans have conquered winter &amp; cold. Therefore, in order to get back to the biologically true lifestyle we’ve grown as a species as, we need to bring back the cold. Turn down the thermostat and cycle 10 seconds hot; 30 seconds cold showers for 5 minutes. It’s brutal but the time goes by shockingly fast</li>
  <li>After two weeks on potatoes, you go to a plant based, vegan lifestyle until you hit your target weight</li>
</ol>



<p>One big thing with CrayRay and Penn is the need for a scale, the smartass of scales. On an impluse I plopped down $100 for the <a href="https://www.withings.com/us/en/body-plus">Withings Body + scale</a>. It’s been 10 days! 10 DAYS!!! I’m 326.4, on day 2 of the plan. In 10 days, 1 of which involving nothing but potatoes, I’ve lost 9 pounds. This is AMAZING.</p>

<p>On day 1, it’s black Friday, or sucker day of the year. Everyone piles in their car after a Thanksgiving Day hang over consisting of pie and turkey, to go buy more stuff to stuff into their garage in six months. It’s all American in style and glory. What am I do? Well, shopping for TVs on Amazon like every other fat guy scared out of his mind of COVID-19. I’m sitting on my couch waiting for the oven, 350 degrees for 45 minutes, to produce 9 potatoes. That’s right 9 potatoes, or about 1000 ish calories. Once done cooking, I scarf down one single sweet potato. It’s sweet (no shit sherlock), delicious and surprisingly moist. I like it, I chase it with 4 tiny petite potatoes and some black coffee. This diet is sure boring.</p>

<p>Lunch time rolls around and I make some food for the kiddo and thanksgiving dinner for lunch for the wife. What do I have? If you guessed potatoes, you’d win the prize! I had 2 potatoes, a red and white. It was bland, boring and good.</p>

<p>A car ride nap, so more black coffee and about 2 liters of water later, we’re sitting down to dinner. I made peanut noodles for the wife, mac and cheese with some TG leftovers for the baby. I have 3 more potatoes, a gold, a red and a sweet potato. 2 potatoes into the meal, I’m stuffed. STUFFED ON TWO POTATOES?!?!??! Yeah, I save the sweet potato for dessert and decide to count my potatoes.</p>

<p>A few days ago, while prepping for thanksgiving, I bought 10 pounds of potatoes. I thought that was a LOT of potatoes, but when I counted it out I had around 20 potatoes left. That’s enough to feed a family a four a potato a night for a week, but for a guy living on potatoes? It’s more like two days if I’m lucky, so I head to Costco.</p>

<p>I love Costco. Everything there is a deal, no matter what the idiots on Life Hacker tell you. I love their steak, their fruit and yes, I love their clothes and bedding. But potatoes, that’s where you really make off like bandits. The potatoes were on sale today too.</p>

<p>I knew to continue the diet I needed to account for 14 days of potatoes, less today and the 1.5 I had in revere; thus, I knew I need about 12 (rounding up) days of potatoes. I’m supposed to be on a calorie restricted diet of 1800 or less per day, which is helping, but to get 1800 calories a day eating just potatoes, I’d need to consume 5 POUNDS of potatoes. That’s right, every day on this thing to hit target calorie intake I’d need 5 POUNDS!?!?!? So, with 12 days needed to be shopped, a total of 60 pounds of potatoes, I headed to Costco.</p>



<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Potato Type</td>
      <td>Per Unit Cost</td>
      <td>Units</td>
      <td>Total Cost</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Creamer Potatoes</td>
      <td>$3.99 / 5 lb</td>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>$16</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Organic Sweet Potatos</td>
      <td>$6.99 / 6.5 lbs</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>$14</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Russet Potatoes</td>
      <td>$7 / 15 lbs</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>$7</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Gold Potatoes</td>
      <td>$6 / 10 lbs</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>$12</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>68 pounds of potatoes for a whopping $49!</p>

<p>Here’s what my shopping chart looked like:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/costco-potatoes.png" alt="Costco cart"></p>

<p>That’s a lot of potatoes! The berries are for my son, Luke, for him to eat with yogurt and breakfast for the next two weeks. Not pictured is the bottles of the sparkling water I got to enhance my diet this week.</p>



<p>If you don’t want to see me shirtless, it’s time to close the page. My starting stats on 11/20/2020 are: 335 LBS, but the offical, diet starting stats are: 333.4 lbs, BMI of 41.7. I’ll be updating this blog with progress, but here’s to my weightloss and success.</p>

<p>I’m off to eat more potatoes!</p>

<p><img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/11272020-front.png" alt="front"> 
<img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/11272020-side.png" alt="side"></p>



      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25251082</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:49:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[And this world’s a fickle measure]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 70 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25250968">thread link</a>) | @jseliger
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-12060">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>They told me, “You have to watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rhThso-PE_o">this interview where Mike Tyson talks about medieval history</a>,” and so I did, and there he was at the New York Public Library in 2013 being interviewed by curator Paul Holdengräber, whose German accent strikes the American ear as both effortlessly intellectual and lightly amusing, and who would seem to have nothing in common with the face-tattooed boxer.</p>



<p><img data-attachment-id="12067" data-permalink="https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11-57-11-pm-copy/" data-orig-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" data-orig-size="1816,934" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2020-11-28 at 11.57.11 PM copy" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=863" src="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" alt=""></p>



<p>The two men do, in fact, find much to talk about. Their discussion is mesmerizing, because to most of us Mike Tyson is nothing but a face and fists, not a man who reflects aloud and at length about his inner life. Holdengräber prompts a reticent Tyson to narrate clips of his greatest moments in the ring, and newcomers to boxing will easily see why Tyson was such a sensation, but Iron Mike grows more animated when other matters arise.</p>



<p>Half an hour into the interview, Holdengräber says that their mutual friend, eccentric German filmmaker Werner Herzog, urged him to ask Tyson why he’s so fascinated by Clovis, the founder of the Merovingian Frankish dynasty, and Pepin the Short, the first Carolingian king of the Franks. Tyson’s answer, however halting, makes him come alive: </p>



<blockquote><p>I don’t know—it all comes from my insecurity from being poor, and not having enough—to be insecure, and being—yeah, that’s what it is: obscure. I never wanted to be obscure. I was born in obscurity and I never wanted to deal with that again, never wanted to be that. And they came from obscurity.</p></blockquote>



<p>Tyson then narrates a capsule history of the Frankish kings. He rambles, he doesn’t get all the details right, and his mispronunciation of names marks him as an autodidact, but it’s a shame to hear the audience laugh when Holdengräber asks, “Mike, how do you know all this shit?” Whether Tyson is mapping his own experiences onto medieval history or hearing echoes of the Franks in his troubled life, the credentialed, status-conscious audience is uncomfortable with his sincere interest in a past they find trivial.</p>



<p>Yet Tyson is the real deal, a book lover not because his peer group yaks about whichever author the <em>New York Times</em> has dubbed fame’s latest love child, but because he’s hungry for ideas, for meaning, for connections across time. He speaks with undisguised emotion about Cus D’Amato, the trainer and manager who turned him into a lethal boxer. Obsessed with Nietzsche and Clausewitz, D’Amato taught Tyson to see boxing as war and war as the key to decoding the world. “That is just what I do,” Tyson explains, an attentive pupil and dutiful son. “I love war. I love the act of war. I love the players in war, the philosophy of war.”</p>



<p>Tyson is searching for more than war on the pages of the past. Having grown up amid crime and chaos and founded his life on violence, he now relies on books to make moral and ethical sense of the world:</p>



<blockquote><p>Yeah—they’re our most priceless possessions, because if you think about it, you know, a room without a book is like a body without a soul. It’s the only way that we can connect the future with the past. Without that, there’s no way that we can know about the future, and know about particularly the past, or the present, you know, that when you think about history, the value of history is not necessarily scientific but moral. By liberating our minds and deepening our sympathies and fortifying our will, we can control—pretty much history allows us to control not society but ourselves, which is a much more important thing to do, you know what I mean? And it would allow us to pretty much meet the future more so than foretell it, and for that reason alone, in order to predict the future we always have to look through the past, because very rarely does time not repeat itself, and it always will repeat itself. </p><p>I’ve heard a quote before in a book that we would be fools to think historically that the past is us in funny clothes, but the past <em><span>is</span></em> us in funny clothes, and that’s truly what it is. That’s from somebody who really said a really profound statement but he misquoted what he was saying, he must have been saying it backwards, because that’s really what the past was, it’s just us in funny clothes, in different times, that’s really what it is.</p></blockquote>



<p>Of course, to hear Tyson cite <a href="http://thecampvs.com/2011/08/03/cicero-on-books-and-the-soul/">a quip inaccurately attributed to Cicero</a>, “a room without books is like a body without a soul,” is to wonder if he’s putting us on. Late in the interview, he jokes that if you quote books, you fool people into thinking you’re smart—but Tyson, for all his malapropisms and mispronunciations and odd mannerisms, <em>is</em> intelligent. He’s going round after round with big questions that  many of the ostensibly educated attendees at his book-talk don’t bother to ask.</p>



<p>When Holdengräber suggests that Tyson’s knowledge of history didn’t improve his behavior, Tyson calmly disagrees. He compares himself to the fictional Ben-Hur, a fellow athlete and celebrity who achieved glory but was doomed to be unfree until he set his priorities in order: “He may not have been famous again,” Tyson points out, “but he got his family, and that was his success.” </p>



<p>After listening to Mike Tyson—childhood criminal, devastating fighter, struggling alcoholic and recovering drug addict, convicted rapist, pop-culture eidolon—speak for an hour and a half, I still don’t quite know who he is. He may be the closest thing 21st-century America has to <a href="https://quidplura.com/2011/11/03/but-the-answers-you-seek-will-never-be-found-at-home/">a Robert E. Howard character</a>, a born barbarian who’s ignorant of social niceties but possesses earned wisdom that the civilization around him disdains. I don’t know whether he’s all in on his bookish pursuits or one slight away from again gnawing off someone’s ear. Whether he’s a good man or a bad man feels foolish to ask about a professional punch-thrower who reads Nietzsche, but Tyson looks like a <em>better</em> man, one who has perhaps searched harder for his humanity than the onlookers snickering from the safety of their library seats. What has their pride gained them? Tyson’s, by contrast, has brought him perspective, and with it the humility to admit that his story is still being written—and has been before.</p>




			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25250968</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Victoria to fine drivers blocking EV chargers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25250936">thread link</a>) | @oxplot
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-to-fine-drivers-blocking-ev-chargers | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-to-fine-drivers-blocking-ev-chargers">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>Drivers who block electric vehicle chargers in Victoria will be fined under new road rules. </p>
<p>Non-electric vehicles, or electric cars that aren’t plugged in to the charger, face fines of $330.44 for “stopping in a parking area for electric-powered vehicles”. </p>
<p>The rules are designed to stop electric vehicle chargers, which are sparse in some parts of Australia, from being blocked by drivers looking for a convenient spot to park their internal-combustion vehicle. </p>
<p>Similar rules have been implemented in American states such as Colorado to prevent what’s known as ICEing. </p>
<div><figure><ul><li><div><figure><a data-fancybox="gallery" href="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/3000/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg" data-thumb="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/180/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg"><img alt="Victoria to fine drivers blocking EV chargers" srcset="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/1600/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg 2x, https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/800/-/app/uploads/2020/03/electric-charging-ev-charge-electric-3.jpg 1x" loading="lazy"></a></figure></div></li></ul></figure></div>
<p>Although it has brought in new rules to protect electric vehicle drivers, Victoria has also made news for <a href="https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-aiming-to-raise-30-million-per-year-from-ev-road-tax">trying to tax them</a>. </p>
<p>The state has followed <a href="https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/south-australia-plans-ev-road-user-levy-but-also-pledges-to-buy-more-electric-cars-for-its-own-fleet">South Australia</a> in committing to a&nbsp;<strong>road tax for electric vehicle</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>plug-in hybrid vehicle</strong>&nbsp;owners.</p>
<p>The tax of&nbsp;<strong>2.5 cents per kilometre</strong>&nbsp;for pure electric vehicles and&nbsp;<strong>2.0 cents per kilometre</strong>&nbsp;for plug-in hybrid vehicles was announced by the Victorian Treasurer ahead of this week’s state budget, and will come into force in July 2021.</p>
<p>An electric vehicle owner who travels&nbsp;<strong>15,000km</strong>&nbsp;per year will be charged&nbsp;<strong>$375</strong>&nbsp;on top of their annual registration fee, while plug-in hybrid owners will pay an extra&nbsp;<strong>$300</strong>&nbsp;per year.</p>
<p>Although the estimated $30 million the tax will raise annually won’t be funnelled directly into electric vehicle infrastructure, the Treasurer said $45 million will be set aside in the budget to boost take-up of hybrid, plug-in hybrid, and electric vehicles.</p>
<div><figure><ul><li><div><figure><a data-fancybox="gallery" href="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/3000/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg" data-thumb="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/180/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg"><img alt="Victoria to fine drivers blocking EV chargers" srcset="https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/1600/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg 2x, https://images.carexpert.com.au/resize/800/-/app/uploads/2020/10/mercedes-benz-EQC-charging-electric.jpg 1x" loading="lazy"></a></figure></div></li></ul></figure></div>
<p>Chairman of the Electric Vehicle Council of Australia, Behyad Jafari, described Victoria’s tax as a “shameful abdication of Victoria’s intention to reduce emissions”.</p>
<p>South Australia’s proposed charge will include a fixed component, similar to current registration charging, and a variable charge based on distance travelled.</p>
<p>The proposal has been widely criticised, with chief executive of the peak body for carmakers in Australia, Tony Weber, describing it as “beyond belief”.</p>
<p>“We believe this charge will make South Australia the only jurisdiction in the world that actually opposes the uptake of low and zero emission vehicles,” Mr Weber added.</p>
<p>As state governments in Victoria, South Australia, and New South Wales have moved to tax electric vehicle owners, the Australian Capital Territory (ACT) has positioned itself as the friendliest jurisdiction in the nation for EV buyers.</p>
<p>It recently announced an ambitious target to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/all-act-new-car-sales-to-be-zero-emissions-by-2030-under-ambitious-plan">sell only zero-emissions new vehicles</a>&nbsp;by 2030.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.carexpert.com.au/car-news/victoria-to-fine-drivers-blocking-ev-chargers</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25250936</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:15:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Recruiters and Human Traffickers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249818">thread link</a>) | @Danieru
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<p>Japan's <a href="http://www.japaneselawtranslation.go.jp/law/detail_main?id=10&amp;vm=2&amp;re=">Employment Security Act</a> requires a recruitment business to obtain a license. Failure to do so can result in imprisonment of up to a year. While I've met sleazy recruiters, sending them to prison seems a tad excessive to me. Curious about why the industry is so harshly regulated, I started digging. This took me into the seemingly dry but surprisingly interesting topic of the history of recruitment in Japan. As virtually nothing about this is written in English, I'm sharing what I found.</p>

<h2 id="japans-first-employment-agency">Japan’s first employment agency</h2>

<p>The earliest account of an employment agency in Japan comes from the mid-Seventeenth century. <a href="http://shokugyo-kyokai.or.jp/shiryou/gyouseishi/01-1.html">Keian Yamato</a> was a doctor who was sometimes asked by his patients to introduce servants or help arrange marriages. He was compensated for these introductions, and eventually this side business grew so successful that it overtook his medical practice. In 1652, he quit his job as a doctor to focus on his introduction business instead. So much so was his early fame, that early employment agencies were called “Keian” after him.</p>

<p>Keian’s agency and others got started at that point in Japanese history because the economic conditions were right for them. For an employment agency to be a viable business, there needs to be both a large supply of people seeking employment, and employers seeking labor. By mid-Seventeenth century Japan, such a market for labor was flourishing in response to a shift in Japanese society that had started with the dawn of the Edo Period, fifty years earlier.</p>

<h2 id="the-labour-market-in-the-edo-period">The labour market in the Edo Period</h2>

<p>The Edo period started in 1603 when <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tokugawa_Ieyasu">Ieyasu Tokugawa</a> officially assumed control of Japan. Before he came to power, for the last century and a half, Japan had been in a state of near-constant civil war, leading to much of the country struggling to recover from the ongoing conflict.</p>

<p>Ieyasu chose Edo, modern day Tokyo, to be the center of his government and country. Previous to this, the political and cultural center was located in western Japan, and Edo and the surrounding region had been economically underdeveloped. But Ieyasu enacted policies that encouraged the urbanization of Edo, transforming it from a small castle town with only one hundred houses to a bustling metropolis of over 250,000 people by 1650.</p>

<p>Not only did Ieyasu pursue urbanization of Edo, but his policies encouraged it throughout Japan. The government divided all of Japan into specific regions, granting each to a local Daimyo, a powerful feudal lord, who built their own castles surrounded by Samurai residences. This lead to a growth in the number of artisans and merchants, who in turn needed staff, creating new employment opportunities.</p>

<p>Further driving demand for labour was the government policy of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sankin-k%C5%8Dtai">Sankin-kōtai</a>, which required Daimyo to alternate living between their holdings and Edo on a yearly basis, in an attempt to prevent them from gaining too much power. As it was infeasible for Daimyos to relocate their entire household to Edo, this led to a demand for temporary staff.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, Edo saw a large influx of job seekers. Traditionally in Japan, the eldest son inherited everything: the family name, business, and any assets. Other children were seen as a burden, particularly for poor families. Struggling families practiced “Kuchi-berashi”, literally translated as reducing the number of mouths, where they would place their children to work elsewhere. As Edo flourished, many second sons and daughters of poor rural families journeyed there in search of employment.</p>

<p>Not only did children seek employment in Edo, but so did adults. Often these were people from farming villages who were cast out by their family, or samurai who became masterless after their leader fell in battle.</p>

<p>As these job seekers didn’t have local connections, they sought out someone who could make introductions. With the burgeoning employment market, recruiting as a profession was born in Japan.</p>

<h2 id="employment-in-the-edo-period">Employment in the Edo period</h2>

<p>Employment is a relationship where an employer pays an employee for work. While this has been one type of relationship, there are others where people perform work without receiving compensation, such as slavery or indentured servitude. In the Edo Period, the division between compensated and forced labor was ambiguous, with the term <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A5%89%E5%85%AC">Hōkō</a>, roughly translated as “service” or “apprenticeship”, used to refer to a wide range of employment-like relationships.</p>

<p>The most straightforward kind of Hōkō was temporary labor, where a person tended to be paid daily. Another form was a long term contract of a year or more to work for a samurai house. With this contract, they were usually paid on a monthly or yearly basis, however the salary itself was low as they were also provided room and board while working for the family.</p>

<p>Unpaid apprenticeships also fall under the term Hōkō, whereby a person would work for an artisan or merchant to learn the business. While they usually wouldn’t be directly paid for their work, the expectation was that their previous employer would sponsor their new business.</p>

<p>Children could also be placed out to work under a Hōkō agreement, where they would often learn a craft while being given food, clothes, and a place to live, but not be directly financially compensated. The parents of the children would be given what was effectively an interest free loan: they’d get a lump sum payment when the child started the apprenticeship, which they’d need to pay back when it ended.</p>

<p>While Hōkō tended to refer to agreements of fixed duration, it also encompasses a slavery-like relationship, whereby a whole family was born to serve a wealthy family for their entire life. Near the beginning of the Edo period, this form of permanent Hōkō was banned, and restricted to a fixed period instead (a maximum of 3 years in 1616, but extended it to 10 years in 1625).</p>

<h2 id="recruiter-or-human-trafficker">Recruiter or human trafficker?</h2>

<p>In modern parlance, just like there is a clear divide between employment and forced labour, there is also a clear divide between recruiters who perform employment matchmaking, and human traffickers who provide uncompensated labourers to employers. In the Edo period, the difference between these two professions was murkier than it is today.</p>

<p>For instance, when children ventured into Edo in search of employment and didn’t have any local connections, they would sometimes make use of a local recruiter. These recruiters would sign a contract on behalf of the parents with an employer. While some of these were benevolent, it was easy for them to be exploitative, and force the children to take jobs with poor working conditions.</p>

<p>During this period, the government also established special regions called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Y%C5%ABkaku">Yukaku</a>, which became the only legal area to practice prostitution. The government saw Yukaku as a way of maintaining public order and collecting taxes. To ensure a steady stream of new prostitutes, the government allowed the “apprenticing” of young girls into prostitution. Unlike normal apprenticeships though, where the parents needed to pay back the “loan” that they received, the girl herself became responsible for paying it back. The amount the parents received was so much though, that even if the girl worked her entire life as a prostitute, she could never pay off the debt. The only way out was to have a wealthy man buy out her remaining debt, and become his mistress. Some recruiters took advantage of Yukaku, and effectively bought young girls from poor families in rural areas and sold them to brothels.</p>

<h2 id="first-steps-towards-regulation-of-recruitment">First steps towards regulation of recruitment</h2>

<p>In 1867, the Tokugawa shogunate was finally toppled, ushering in a new era in Japanese history, referred to as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meiji_(era)">the Meiji period</a>. Whereas the previous government had maintained an isolationist stance, the new government embraced western technology and culture, seeking to modernize the country before it was subjugated by western powers.</p>

<p>As part of this modernization, the government abolished the strict class system that divided Japanese into Samurai, peasants, artisans, and merchants, declaring that everyone who had been peasants, artisans, and merchants to be equal. People who were formerly Samurai and Daimyo however were still granted a status as nobles.</p>

<p>With this move modernity, the government sought to regulate the recruiting industry. In 1872, they introduced a requirement that recruiters be licensed and have a guarantor. They also limited the fee a recruiter could receive to be a maximum of 5% of the salary of the introduced employee. This fee was paid by both the employee and employer.</p>

<h2 id="international-attempts-to-ban-private-employment-agencies">International attempts to ban private employment agencies</h2>

<p>As part of the Treaty of Versailles that ended World War I, <a href="https://www.ilo.org/global/about-the-ilo/history/lang--en/index.htm">the International Labour Organization (ILO)</a> was founded to advance social and economic justice through setting international labour standards.</p>

<p>At their very first meeting in 1919, the ILO called on its members to establish free public employment agencies and move towards banning fee charging agencies. As a member of the ILO, Japan created a new law, which required municipal governments to establish public employment agencies and introduced stricter requirements for private employment agencies. While there had been 9,712 private agencies in 1926, the number dwindled to 2,541 by 1934.</p>

<p>The new regulation of the industry also saw stronger controls against unethical recruitment, such as using exaggerated or false claims to recruit people, forcing applications, recruiting women to be prostitutes, blocking applicants’ freedom, and so on.</p>

<p>In April 1938, the public employment agencies that had been operated at a local level were nationalized with a new law. This law also banned private agencies, except for some of the existing agencies, which were allowed to continue while facing even stricter regulations. Many of the private agencies who were banned merged into the national agency. The driving factor for this nationalization was not human rights though, but rather a response to a rapid increase in …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/">https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249818</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 01:19:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[It’s time to remove news from Facebook and Google]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249414">thread link</a>) | @anaxana
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <p>Pay up -- or we’re pulling the plug. </p><p>That’s the approach the news industry should take when it comes to Google and Facebook: Pay for our journalism or we’re banning it from your platforms. </p><p>For too long, journalists have given away their stories for free in exchange for distribution by the duopoly. At best, a story may go viral (rare) or hit the SEO lottery and experience a one-off traffic surge (unsustainable). </p><p>And for that, newsrooms have willingly handed over <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/09/business/media/google-news-industry-antitrust.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share">billions of dollars</a> in ad revenue to the tech giants that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/03/facebooks-siren-call/">threaten</a> their very existence. (Google and Facebook are No. 1 and No. 2 <a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/technology/facebook-ad-revenue-2019-2020">ad platforms</a> in the U.S., respectively).</p><p>The news industry as a whole needs to come together and demand to be fairly compensated for their contributions. Until Facebook and Google agree to pay up, they are simply exploiting journalism under the pretext of democratizing information. </p><p>News drives habit. Habit drives frequency. And frequency drives time spent. In the attention economy (read: ad-driven), news content entices people to come back and stay in platforms’ carefully crafted ecosystems. </p><p>In short, platforms need news. </p><p>Mark Zuckerberg said it himself when Facebook launched its news tab in 2019 (its most recent olive branch to publishers). In a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/25/opinion/sunday/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-news.html">piece for the<em> New York Times</em></a>, the Facebook founder pledged to “support the news industry” and said that journalism today is “more important than ever.” But only <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/10/23/facebook-offer-news-tab-users-pay-some-publishers-their-work/">some of the 200+ publishers</a> involved in the news tab were actually paid for their contributions. &nbsp;</p><p>These platforms are simply using their high-minded mission statements (e.g. Facebook: To “give people the power to build community and bring the world closer together” and Google: To “organize the world’s information”) as a thuggish pretext for exploiting journalism. </p><p>Instead, they should pay a licencing fee or provide a sizable cut of ad revenue to newsrooms that are populating the platforms (Murdoch analogized this to a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/jan/22/rupert-murdoch-facebook-should-pay-news-publishers">carriage fee</a>). &nbsp;</p><p>It’s not enough for them to attempt damage control by <a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/google-paying-publishers-is-more-about-pr-than-the-needs-of-the-news-industry/">spinning up funds</a> claiming to help journalism or offering some – but not all – publishers fees for their contributions. (If you want to know how Google really feels about paying for news, see <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/google-news/google-to-shut-down-news-site-in-spain-over-copyright-fees-idUSL1N0TV0S520141211">how they treated publishers</a> in Spain).</p><p>That’s why we’re building <a href="https://www.forthapp.com/?utm_source=nillium&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_campaign=frontpage">Forth</a>, a news-first platform that pays journalists for their work and offers the audience concise updates with context -- from the reporters they trust. All revenue generated on Forth is shared with our news partners. </p><p>We only allow trusted and credible journalists (vetted by our editorial team) to publish to the platform. It's a one-stop shop for accurate information about what's happening right now. &nbsp;</p><p>It’s one thing for Facebook and Google to out-innovate a slow-to-adapt industry -- it’s another to profit off of the same industry's work with impunity. </p><p>Newsrooms should be mad as hell -- and they don’t have to take it anymore. </p><p>Let’s Go Forth, </p><p>-- Xana</p><p><br><em>Xana O'Neill is the Co-Founder of Forth, a platform for concise updates with context from the reporters you trust.</em></p>
                </div>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249414</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Coup-Proofing the Startup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249332">thread link</a>) | @harporoeder
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>In the middle of an actual, like, actual workplace coup with secret meetings, purges, puppetmasters, frame-ups, leak investigations, and (rumored) slack DM surveillance, I was listening to the bombshell podcast and heard about this book about coup-proofing, and how it ruins teams.
I picked up a copy, and this year I read it.</p>

<p>The book (Caitlin Talmadge / <a href="https://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu/book/9781501700293/the-dictators-army">The Dictator’s Army</a>) is about how coup fears hamstrung management in two wars:
Saddam Hussein’s 8-year failed invasion of Iran, and South Vietnam’s final defense against the North.
This article is about private sector leadership lessons I took from the book.</p>

<p>Writing about private sector leadership on the eve of a plausible military coup seems like peeing into the ocean, but it’s this or doomscrolling and holding in your pee can kill you.</p>

<p>Most management books are aspirational and map out success.
This one is about repeated failure, despite great funding, first-mover advantage and better equipment, through repeated mistakes, and in the public eye.
Nothing that I would know anything about cough.</p>

<p>Startups sub 30 people have a hard time accessing experienced hires who combine domain skill and the ability to work on a team.
There are real reasons for this, and some boil down to something like Saddam’s coup fears.
But if our society plans to continue airlifting cash into small companies, onboarding good middle managers earlier can make more of these bets pay off.</p>

<p>If you prefer a soundtrack, play this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=thbICk05yPk">masterclass on management</a> (from GI Joe’s Cobra Commander) in the background.
It sometimes gets me through the week.</p>

<ol id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#despots-meddle" id="markdown-toc-despots-meddle">Despots meddle</a></li>
  <li><a href="#managing-up" id="markdown-toc-managing-up">Managing up</a></li>
  <li><a href="#demotions-temporary-and-permanent" id="markdown-toc-demotions-temporary-and-permanent">Demotions, temporary and permanent</a></li>
  <li><a href="#combined-arms" id="markdown-toc-combined-arms">Combined arms</a></li>
  <li><a href="#some-people-out-there-dont-have-maps" id="markdown-toc-some-people-out-there-dont-have-maps">Some people out there don’t <em>have</em> maps</a></li>
  <li><a href="#the-butchers-bill" id="markdown-toc-the-butchers-bill">The butcher’s bill</a></li>
  <li><a href="#professional-silence" id="markdown-toc-professional-silence">Professional silence</a></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="despots-meddle">Despots meddle</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>Despotism is a legitimate mode of government in dealing with barbarians, provided the end be their improvement, and the means justified by actually effecting that end.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Liberty, as a principle, has no application to any state of things anterior to the time when mankind have become capable of being improved by free and equal discussion.
– JS Mill</p>
</blockquote>

<p>By inference, if you’re not hiring barbarians and / or they don’t need improvement, or your team is capable of discussion, consider a lighter-weight leadership style.</p>

<p>‘Despot’ also means bronze age feudal landowners or the heir apparent of Byzantium, but we haven’t had those for a while.
Adaptive reuse of the term in revolutionary France gave the term its modern meaning:
an absolute ruler who governs without restraint by the law.
See also ‘frondeur’.</p>

<p>When growing teams take on more complex goals but don’t update their management, they encounter pathologies of delegation –
senior leadership who isn’t sure how to solve problems using middle managers, who give them the wrong length leash.
This is the 10 person to 30 person growth spurt.
Good companies outgrow it this <em>if</em> they survive.</p>

<p>Here’s what that looked like in Iraq:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>decision-making at the senior levels of the Iraqi military revolved more around the fear of what Saddam might do than what the Iranians might do.<sup id="fnref:senior-fear" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:senior-fear">1</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>by the middle of the war, Saddam was making a serious effort to inform himself about military matters in order to understand what was happening. However, Saddam was the only decision maker,<sup id="fnref:educate" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:educate">2</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Technocratic middle managers were spending most of their energy undoing their leader’s bad decisions, rather than fighting and winning.
There’s a spectrum between ‘own worst enemy’ and ‘annoying bandwidth bottleneck’, but new managers generally are on it somewhere.</p>

<p>Over-centralization of authority sends a message that people shouldn’t act on their own, which paralyzes your org.
Note that I’m not arguing against hierarchical authority or a clear chain of command, but rather against authority all concentrating at the top, making it impossible for middle managers to do their jobs.
In Vietnam:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>few officers who had come up in the Diem system were willing to do anything “in the absence of detailed orders.”<sup id="fnref:detailed" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:detailed">3</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Centralization also hamstrings the flexibility of a large team to adapt to new information.
Top leaders, often lacking domain skill or up-to-date information, are best at ‘do nothing without asking me’ orders that trap middle managers in bad positions.
In one case:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Because Saddam had decreed that units were not allowed to cede any ground, the Iraqi defense was poorly coordinated and ineffective, eventually inducing panic.<sup id="fnref:panic" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:panic">4</a></sup> …
Iraqi officers in the field lacked the authority to redeploy forward troops or to call on reserves.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>And because the dictators aren’t an expert in any part of the organization, lack the attention to focus on everything at once, and aren’t accountable to anyone, they have zero memory.
In one case in Vietnam, President Thieu’s personal intervention not only disrupted the existing strategy, but he had forgotten by the next day that he’d given the order.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>sudden change in orders from an uninformed Thieu was a disaster, resulting in neither a robust defense of the city nor a clean withdrawal.<sup id="fnref:sudden-change" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:sudden-change">6</a></sup> … Amazingly … Hue’s abandonment apparently came as a surprise to President Thieu<sup id="fnref:abandonment" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:abandonment">7</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unaccountable, illogical plans from inexpert leaders create hills to die on, in some cases literally.
They also come through unusual channels (because hands-on leaders prioritize fast action).
Unusual channels = coordination and preparation impossible for middle managers.
In one case in South Vietnam, a general:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>personally interceded at all levels, sometimes going so far as to personally issue orders by radio to individual brigade commanders without notifying the division operations center. Both Giai and his division advisers often learned of new orders only as they were being carried out.<sup id="fnref:all-levels" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:all-levels">8</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>By comparison, the North Vietnamese had good delegation and sane command structures in place.
From an internal document, they valued:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“unanimity of thought from the top to the bottom regarding the opportunity we faced and the tactics to be employed” but significant room for commanders to execute their plans<sup id="fnref:unanimity" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:unanimity">9</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>After the American revolution, George III was having a conversation with his American portraitist Benjamin West; he heard Washington was going to resign his commission and ‘return to his farm’.
The King was like ‘ha pull the other one’, recognizing that giving up power is very hard, and said something like ‘<em>if</em> he does it I take back everything I said about the guy.’
The point is that accepting the limits to authority is hard, but also critical for good leaders.</p>

<h2 id="managing-up">Managing up</h2>

<p>One of the lessons of 2020 is probably that sometimes the only person in the room who can stop a bad outcome is a middle manager,
and often they can only do it by managing up, not through direct action.</p>

<p>Middle managers are frequently in situations where their domain skills are better than senior leadership –
either because they’re technocrats with domain skills,
or because they’re dealing with the problem day-to-day and have better information, or both.</p>

<p>We still get shouted down a lot, resulting in waste:
of money, of time, of resources, of opportunities, of morale.
In a war it can be lives.</p>

<p>We speak out a few times but eventually converge to inaction as your <a href="https://danluu.com/wat/">wtfs trail off</a>.
We give up because we’re tired, but that’s not all of it:
We stop arguing because when a leader experiences argument as dissent, their reactions are unpredictable and poison the team.</p>

<p>The way around this way of thinking is to
(1) make very sure that you’re very right when you pick a fight with your boss,
(2) fight for better delegation, not just a correct decision this one time.
And (3) remember that if you succeed, things get permanently better; these are hard fights but companies need them to grow.</p>

<p>Middle managers are the only people who have the authority and connections to fight these fights.
That’s why they leak, that’s why they manage up.
The organization will fail if we don’t.
Employees depend on companies to put food on the table; you do have a moral obligation to help your employer not fail (if you can) (barring circumstances like if <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hn1VxaMEjRU">you’ve looked at these caps recently</a>).</p>

<p>I saw a <a href="https://twitter.com/FutureDocs/status/938173926953443328">JAMA article</a> about ‘professional silence’ by doctors.
Silence is not golden when an important argument is being suppressed.</p>

<p>Senior technocrats have a surprising amount of power when they align their story and band together. For Saddam, years into the war:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Iraqi generals blamed Saddam’s military organizational practices for both sets of losses, raising a serious danger of overthrow from within<sup id="fnref:blame" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:blame">10</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Because his leadership style was in conflict with their technical skills.
He punished losses in ways that deterred ground commanders from requesting backup, creating a losing cycle:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Saddam put great pressure on Iraqi commanders on the ground to avoid losses, which led them not to report failures. Withholding losses from reports and thus not receiving reinforcements or other support left commanders in impossible combat conditions. However, this was better than reporting their failures and suffering execution.<sup id="fnref:pressure" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:pressure">11</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The command-and-control system was incapable of transmitting the true tactical situation. Senior Iraqi officers later noted that they often got more timely information from the media than they did from their own commanders at the front.<sup id="fnref:media" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:media">12</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>In Vietnam, General Phu, a technocrat middle manager who had been brought in to fix the South Vietnamese army’s problems, tried to use his authority to salvage a bad campaign and was talked down.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Phu, who previously had enjoyed an excellent reputation as commander of the 1st Division, expressed grave reservations about the operation to those around him, complaining that he had done it only because of Thieu’s order<sup id="fnref:reservations" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:reservations">13</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>President Thieu’s realtime intervention, leading to a bad loss, demoralized him and he was never able to lead again:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Thieu’s absurd order to withdraw immediately from the Central Highlands essentially caused another corps commander, General Phu, …</p></blockquote></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html">https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249332</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
