<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 12:37:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 12:37:48 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I accidentally built a spying app]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25310316">thread link</a>) | @akeck
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://withblue.ink/2020/09/24/that-time-i-accidentally-built-a-spying-app.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://withblue.ink/2020/09/24/that-time-i-accidentally-built-a-spying-app.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>In the fall of 2007, my parents gave me an unforgettable gift for my sixteenth birthday: a first-generation iPhone.</p><p>I still clearly remember watching the keynote in which Steve Jobs announced the first Apple-branded phone a few months earlier. As a teenager attending high school in my hometown of Vicenza, Italy, I tuned into the livestream just before dinner, carefully listening to every word he said. That evening, Jobs started announcing a “widescreen iPod with touch controls”, a “revolutionary mobile phone” and a “breakthrough Internet communications device”–theatrically pausing before confessing that he was actually talking about one single device: the iPhone. Thousands of miles away from me, you could hear attendees exploding cheerfully through the live feed. Jobs went on demoing this amazing invention that, a decade later, would end up changing much more than the mobile phones market: it directly or indirectly impacted our society through mobile web, app stores, changing work-life balance, and social media.</p><p>October came, and so did the day I finally got my iPhone. I was really excited as I was the first one in my social circle with one. Every other teenager (and adult!) that saw my phone reacted in awe and with lots of curiosity. More than a few were also secretly envious, something I secretly did not mind. To add to the novelty, at the time the iPhone was only available for sale in the US.</p><p>To get an iPhone for me, my father had to ask a friend traveling to New York on a business trip to bring one back on the plane with her. That was not the end of it, however, as all phones were locked to the AT&amp;T network. In order for me to be able to use my iPhone in Italy, I had to unlock it.</p><p>That process required learning a variety of tools and techniques developed by hackers in the community, then documented in various blogs and forums. The first step was to <em>jailbreak</em> the phone, which gave you full access to the system and allowed you to run third-party apps. Then you’d have add one of those “hacking” apps to your phone, which patched the bootloader to remove the lock the US carrier had put on it. Despite sounding like a mouthful, the iPhone hacking community had worked hard on the User Experience (UX), making this entire process relatively easy for most people with basic tech skills.</p><hr><p>I really loved my shiny, new iPhone, and I was so excited about it that I was willing to accept many of its original limitations. It only supported slow 2G networks, didn’t have copy/paste, couldn’t transfer files via Bluetooth to my friends, and <a href="https://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughts-on-flash/">famously</a> didn’t support Adobe Flash, which was ubiquitous on the web at the time.</p><p>However, there was one thing I really couldn’t stand: the Messages application could only store 1,000 texts (SMS).</p><p>That was 2007 — before the days of WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Telegram, etc. Instant messaging was something people did on their PCs only, with things like Windows Live Messenger (née MSN Messenger) or AIM.</p><p>For a high schooler like me, text messaging was the main way I kept in touch with my friends daily (<em>what was I supposed to do, call them?</em>). With my carrier giving me a whopping 100 free texts per day (seriously, we had to pay for them), between sent and received texts it would take less than a week to reach the storage limit of 1,000.</p><p>That’s when it all started.</p><p>Because my iPhone was already “hacked” (jailbroken), as a requirement for unlocking it and use it in Italy, I had full system access already. That allowed me to c extract any document I wanted, including my phone’s text message database.</p><p>It wasn’t even a month since I got my iPhone that I had already built a small “app” running on my laptop to archive my text messages forever. I would manually extract the SMS database from my iPhone, copy it to my laptop, then use a set of scripts written in PHP (the only programming language I knew at the time) to store the messages in a local database, and finally display them using a web-based interface.</p><p>This thing I put together worked just fine for me, but I immediately realized the “business potential” of what I had just created. Just like myself, I assumed many others had the same annoyance. I could have used what I learned to help them too, and maybe make some pocket change in the process. As a matter of fact, I did consider myself an enterprising teenager.</p><p>The idea had potential, and the “app” I built for myself already provided solid foundations, so I just needed to do a bit more work to turn it into a commercially-viable project.</p><p>The biggest challenge was making the solution more accessible to others, including those who were not particularly tech-savvy. That’s when I started learning about app development for iPhone.</p><p>Famously, Apple did not want the iPhone to support third-party apps at the beginning, saying developers should build web apps instead. That policy didn’t last long, and with the iPhone OS 2 update, launched in mid-2008, the official App Store came to life: the rest, as they say, is history.</p><p>However, the hacking community had already found a way to sideload apps and had even developed an “app store” called Cydia where you could find games, apps, and even mods to enhance the capabilities of the operating system itself. Cydia came preinstalled on every <em>jailbroken</em> iPhone, which meant potentially hundreds of thousands of people had access to it.</p><p>Everyone could build apps that would be published on Cydia, as long as you knew how to–something that was not remotely as easy to do as it is with today’s tools. As an enterprising teenager with quite a bit of free time on my hand during those winter afternoons and evenings, I took on that challenge.</p><hr><p>The first version of YouArchive.It came out in January 2008.</p><p>Today, you would describe YouArchive.It as a cloud service to store iPhone text messages. You could store all your messages in there, then read and search them using a web-based application.</p><p>There’s still a video left on YouTube showing the application in action (this was the third, and last, version):</p><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/ps5ohEhO3S4" allowfullscreen="" title="YouTube Video"></iframe></p><p>With YouArchive.It came an iPhone application too. Published on the Cydia app store, it allowed importing messages into the “cloud service” directly from the phone.</p><p>YouArchive.It was free to use with a limit of 80,000 text messages. Because personal communications can be sensitive, all messages were stored encrypted. With a one-time payment of just €5 (about $6), you could become a VIP, remove any limit and enjoy unlimited storage.</p><p><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*vTxYRljXFl3IBXGRsXOVag.png" alt="A screenshot of iTextUploader running on a first-generation iPhone"></p><figcaption>A screenshot of iTextUploader running on a first-generation iPhone</figcaption><p>For the next year and a half, YouArchive.It continued to grow organically. A few blogs and websites dedicated to iPhone “hacking” and to the underground app stores wrote about the app. Even a small radio program in the US featured it</p><p>I continued developing the app as a side project while in high school. I was also providing tech support and maintaining the infrastructure.</p><p>Listening to users' feedback, I would periodically add new features. YouArchive.It started displaying emojis as soon as the iPhone supported that (outside of Japan, it required downloading an app to enable them). Users asked for and got the ability to restore texts in another iPhone, before iCloud was available. I also implemented other privacy features such as requiring a password to open the mobile app.</p><blockquote><h3 id="what-i-didnt-realize-at-the-time-however-is-that-i-had-unknowingly-and-unwillingly-built-a-spying-tool-and-a-really-convenient-and-efficient-one">What I didn’t realize at the time, however, is that I had, unknowingly and unwillingly, built a spying tool, and a really convenient and efficient one.</h3></blockquote><p>Enough users were paying the fee to become VIP that I could cover the costs of running the service–this was before everyone was using Amazon Web Services or Microsoft Azure, so I was renting a co-located physical server which wasn’t cheap–and keep some pocket cash. Not much, but enough to pay for some hobbies and outings with friends.</p><p>Most importantly, building YouArchive.It gave me a lot of satisfaction and the opportunity to learn a lot of things about software development, business, dealing with customers and listening to their feedback.</p><hr><p>When I finally shut the service down, in June 2010, YouArchive.It had about 32,000 registered users who stored over 76 million messages.</p><p>The first, and stated, reason for the deprecation was a technical one: YouArchive.It’s iPhone app required using private APIs, which meant it could not be published on the App Store (and it still couldn’t to this day), limiting it to <em>jailbroken</em> phones only.</p><p>The second reason however was the most important to me, even though I have not revealed it until now.</p><p>About a year before the app closed, in April 2009 I implemented a new feature that was requested by many users: the ability to upload texts automatically, in background, without user intervention. For paying “VIP” users only, the mobile app could automatically send all new text messages to YouArchive.It, as often as every 15 minutes.</p><p>Automatic upload was an incredible convenience for many users that wanted to hoard their texts like me, to keep them forever, search within them, print or export them, or just liked having a backup.</p><p>What I didn’t realize at the time, however, is that I had, unknowingly and unwillingly, built a spying tool, and a really convenient and efficient one.</p><p>Thanks to background uploads, people could install the YouArchive.It app on another person’s iPhone, set it up, maybe even hide it (something possible on a <em>jailbroken</em> iPhone), and then watch as the text messages come in, almost real-time. Jealous partners, stalkers and the likes could install this tool on an unknowing victim’s phone with relative ease.</p><p>I can’t remember how I discovered that — it might have been a support request from a user or a post in a bulletin board. I also can’t know how many people were using YouArchive.It for their own archiving rather than to spy on others. Realizing what my users were doing, however, made me feel really uncomfortable and I did not want any part of that anymore.</p><p>As a senior in high school, barely eighteen years-old, I realized for the first time how technology can have a …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://withblue.ink/2020/09/24/that-time-i-accidentally-built-a-spying-app.html">https://withblue.ink/2020/09/24/that-time-i-accidentally-built-a-spying-app.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://withblue.ink/2020/09/24/that-time-i-accidentally-built-a-spying-app.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25310316</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:32:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Down Here, They Sometimes Call It 'Boy']]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 61 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25308101">thread link</a>) | @pelt
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://www.realclearbooks.com/articles/2020/11/17/down_here_they_sometimes_call_it_boy_585675.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.realclearbooks.com/articles/2020/11/17/down_here_they_sometimes_call_it_boy_585675.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

                            

                                                        <!-- sphereit start -->
                            <!-- startprint -->

                            <!-- end article source sponsored -->

                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    
                                                                                        
                            
                            
                            
                            
                                
                                
                                                                                        
                                                            <div>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/60E52DB6-B5F7-48D8-8FC5-73A5CE8F8AF4"> <img src="https://assets.realclear.com/images/52/527328_5_.jpg"> </a></p>

<p>Regnery Publishing</p>


</div>
<p><em>The following is an excerpt from "<a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/60E52DB6-B5F7-48D8-8FC5-73A5CE8F8AF4">Big White Ghetto: Dead Broke, Stone-Cold Stupid, and High on Rage in the Dank Woolly Wilds of the "Real America"</a>" by Kevin D. Williamson.</em></p>
<p>"Dogfood—yeah, <em>d</em><em>o</em><em>g</em><em>f</em><em>o</em><em>o</em><em>d</em>—because it looks like ground-up dog food.” He’s embarrassed to be talking about this. “Or sand, because it’s brown. Or diesel. Or killa or 9-1-1. That’s the influence of rap culture down here.” He is a young, clean-cut, Eagle Scout–ish white kid, hesitant about using the words “rap culture,” like he’s not sure if he’s allowed to say that. But he goes on, matter-of-factly. He’s been off heroin for only a few months, so the details are fresh in his mind, even if he remains a little hazy on parts of his autobiographical timeline. “The 9-1-1, they call it that because they want you to know it’s potent, that you’ll have to go to the emergency room.”</p>
<p>That’s a weird and perverse and nasty kind of advertising, but then dope-buying psychology isn’t very much like Volvo-buying psychology: Crashing is just another part of the ride. One spiteful dealer boasts about spiking his product with excessive amounts of fentanyl—a pharmaceutical analgesic used for burn victims and cancer patients—his plan being to intentionally send overdosed users to the hospital or the morgue . . . for <em>m</em><em>a</em><em>r</em><em>k</em><em>e</em><em>t</em><em>i</em><em>n</em><em>g</em> <em>p</em><em>u</em><em>r</em><em>p</em><em>os</em><em>e</em><em>s</em>. Once the word got out about the hideous strength of his product, that killa went right out the door ricky-tick.</p>
<p>The young man explaining the current vocabulary of opiate addiction in Birmingham is barely old enough to buy a beer, and his face and voice are soft. He describes the past several years of his life: “dope-sick and stealing,” going from job to job—eight jobs in six months—robbing his employers of everything not physically nailed to the floor, alienating his family, descending. He was an addict on a mission: “You’re always chasing that first shot of dope, that first high—and the first one for me almost killed me. I was seventeen or eighteen years old, and I met a guy who had just got out of prison, doing a thirteen-year sentence for heroin possession and distribution. He was staying at the Oak Mountain Lodge, which is a nice little classic place.” (In 2013, four police officers and a drug dog had to be treated for exposure to dangerous chemicals after raiding a suspected meth lab in that hotel; the customer reviews online are decidedly mixed.) “I was <em>snorting </em>heroin when I met up with him, and set him up with my connect. He offered to shoot me up, and I wanted to do it. And I remember him looking me in the eyes and telling me, ‘If you do this, you’ll never stop, and you’ll never go back.’ And I said, ‘Let’s do it.’”</p>
<p>He doesn’t know what happened for the next several hours. When he regained consciousness, his junkie buddy’s girlfriend was worriedly ministering to him.</p>
<p>“That was first thing in the morning,” he says. “That night, I did another one.”</p>
<p>Same results. “I’d nodded out from snorting it, but there’s nothing like shooting it.”</p>
<p>He was, he says, a “pretty good junkie” for a time.</p>
<p>This particular opiate odyssey starts off in a Walgreens, something that turns out to be absolutely appropriate. I’m headed up the south coast and then inland on the heroin highway up to Atlanta, starting from the Port of Houston, which connects that city with 1,053 ports in nearly 200 countries and which in December alone welcomed the equivalent of 63,658 20-foot cargo containers of goods into the United States. There was, the feds are pretty sure, some dope squirreled away in there. In fact, all sorts of interesting stuff comes in and out of Houston. In May, U.S. Customs seized a Fast Attack Vehicle with gun mounts headed to the Netherlands. It hadn’t been ordered by the Dutch military. (Organized crime in the Netherlands is bananas: A raid in the summer of 2020 found Dutch police opening up a shipping container expecting to find it loaded with narcotics or stolen goods, but what they found instead was a dentist’s chair bolted to the floor and handcuffs hanging overhead—it was set up as a mobile torture chamber, God knows why.) I’m at Walgreens because I’ve got a long drive ahead and I’m going to be out of pocket for a bit, and I have a prescription to fill: an honest-to-goodness Schedule II Controlled Substance, in the official nomenclature, a term that covers some pretty interesting stuff, including the oxycodone and fentanyl I’ll be hearing so much about in the next few days. Some of us are going to heaven, some of us are going to hell, but all of us have to stop at Walgreens first.</p>
<p>The clerk is on the phone with a doctor’s office: “What’s your DEA number?”</p>
<p>For working-class white guys who haven’t found their way into the good jobs in the energy economy or the related manufacturing and construction booms that have reverberated throughout the oil patch, who aren’t college-bound or in possession of the skills to pay the bills, things aren’t looking so great: While much of the rest of the world gets healthier and longer-lived, the average life expectancy for white American men without college educations is declining. Angus Deaton, the Princeton economist who won the Nobel Prize in 2015, ran the numbers and found (in a study co-authored by his Princeton colleague Anne Case) that what’s killing what used to be the white working class isn’t diabetes or heart disease or the consumption of fatty foods and Big Gulps that so terrifies Michael Bloomberg, but alcohol-induced liver failure, along with overdoses of opioid prescription painkillers and heroin: Wild Turkey and hillbilly heroin, and regular old heroin, too, the use of which has increased dramatically in recent years as medical and law-enforcement authorities crack down on the wanton overprescription of oxy and related painkillers.</p>
<p>Which is to say: While we were <em>ignoring </em>criminally negligent painkiller prescriptions, we helped create a gigantic population of opioid addicts, and then, when we started paying attention, the first thing we did was take away the legal (and quasi-legal) stuff produced to exacting clinical standards by Purdue Pharma (maker of OxyContin) and others. So: lots of opiate addicts, fewer prescription opiates.</p>
<p>What was left was diesel, sand—<em>d</em><em>o</em><em>g</em><em>f</em><em>o</em><em>o</em><em>d</em>.</p>
<p>The clerks at this Walgreens are super friendly, but the place is set up security-wise like a bank, and that’s to be expected. This particular location was knocked over by a young white man with a gun the summer before last, an addict who had been seen earlier lurking around the CVS down the road. This is how you know you’re a pretty good junkie: The robber walked in and pointed his automatic at the clerk and demanded oxy first, then a bottle of Tusinex cough syrup, and then, almost as an afterthought, the $90 in the till. Walgreens gets robbed a lot: In January, armed men stormed the Walgreens in Edina, Minnesota, and stole $8,000 worth of drugs, mainly oxy. In October, a sneaky young white kid in an Iowa State sweatshirt made off with more than $100,000 worth of drugs—again, mainly oxy and related opioid painkillers, from a Walgreens in St. Petersburg, Florida. Other Walgreens locations—in Liberty, Kansas; East Bradford, Pennsylvania; Elk Grove, California; Kaysville, Utah; Virginia Beach; New Orleans—all have been hit by armed robbers or sneak thieves over the past year or so, and there have been many more oxy thefts.</p>
<p>It won’t make the terrified clerks feel any better, but there’s poetic justice in that: In 2013, Walgreens paid the second-largest fine ever imposed under the Controlled Substances Act for being so loosey-goosey in handling oxy at its distribution center in Jupiter, Florida, that it enabled untold quantities of the stuff to reach the black market. The typical pharmacy sells 73,000 oxycodone pills a year; six Walgreens in Florida were going through more than 1 million pills a year—each. A few years before that, Purdue was fined $634.5 million for misleading the public about the addictiveness of oxycodone. Kentucky, which has been absolutely ravaged by opiate addiction, is still pursuing litigation against Purdue, and it has threatened to take its case all the way to the Supreme Court, if it comes to that.</p>
<p>Ground Zero in the opiate epidemic isn’t some exotic Taliban-managed poppy field or some cartel boss’s fortified compound: It’s right there at Walgreens, in the middle of every city and town in the country.</p>
<p>I pick up my prescription and get on my way.</p>
<p>The next afternoon, having driven past billboards advertising boudin and strip joints with early-bird lunch specials and casino after casino after sad little casino; help-wanted signs for drilling-fluid businesses and the Tiger Truck Stop (which has a twenty-four-hour Cajun café and an actual no-kidding <em>live tiger </em>in a cage out front); past Whiskey Bay and Contraband Bayou, where the pirate Jean Lafitte once stashed his booty; around the Port of New Orleans, another <em>entrepôt </em>for heroin and cocaine—it is almost as close to Cartagena as it is to New York—I arrive at a reasonably infamous New Orleans drug corner, where I inquire as discreetly as I can about the availability of prescription …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.realclearbooks.com/articles/2020/11/17/down_here_they_sometimes_call_it_boy_585675.html">https://www.realclearbooks.com/articles/2020/11/17/down_here_they_sometimes_call_it_boy_585675.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.realclearbooks.com/articles/2020/11/17/down_here_they_sometimes_call_it_boy_585675.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25308101</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 21:15:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Myth of Code Coverage]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 98 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25306071">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://preslav.me/2020/12/03/the-myth-of-code-coverage/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://preslav.me/2020/12/03/the-myth-of-code-coverage/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div id="post-body"><p>One question I often ask potential software engineering candidates is to pinpoint the percentage of code coverage in an ideal project. Interestingly enough, many of them jump to the sky with numbers beyond 90%. They would start preaching how well-tested code is more reliable and brings more value to all stakeholders. When I ask about the current projects they work on, the reality looks a bit more down to earth.</p><p>Want to know my answer? I'd say it's <strong>around 66.7%</strong>.</p><p>The reasons for that vary, but allow me to be blunt and say that <strong>1/3 of the code every software project is irrelevant, buggy, overly complicated, or simply sucks.</strong> It has a reason to be where it is, but chances are, one year down the road, it will become a liability. Being dogmatic about tests and covering every line will only make it more difficult to get rid of it.</p><p>See, no two lines of code are equal in value and importance. Adding a new feature to an existing application affects its capabilities only marginally. However, it takes a proportionally large amount of time to develop and integrate due to the existing complexity. The bigger the complexity, the longer it takes to introduce new functionality. By the time the feature finds itself in production, it may as well be already irrelevant.</p><blockquote>The only sure-fire way to improve code coverage (and by that keep software relevant) is to identify and remove the unnecessary code.</blockquote><p>How do you identify irrelevant code? Don't search for it. Instead, let it reveal itself to you. One dimension of software that few teams make good use of, is its history. Git is a great analysis tool. Start using it not only to prevent future problems but also, to understand where and how often certain parts of the code change over time.</p><p>Chances are, you will find pieces of code that have undergone fewer changes than the rest in long periods. Those are the pillars of your application - the 2/3s that <strong>must be well-tested</strong>.</p><p>You will also find others where changes occur more or less every week. Ask yourselves whether those are still relevant, both from a technical and business perspective. Adding tests for the sake of coverage would have the opposite effect of increasing the code quality. In a perfectly-design software project, the part that is allowed to change most often is the configuration. A simple analysis of the code change frequency would show whether that is the case. If it isn't, try separating the moving parts from the core logic. If this is not feasible either, most probably those portions of the code don't belong to the codebase anyway. Turning them into interchangeable scripts (even stored in a separate repository) is one way of tackling them in their own right.</p><p>Let's not get too much into technical details. I have already alluded to the work of <a href="https://twitter.com/AdamTornhill">Adam Tornhill</a> on code analysis in a previous post of mine:</p><figure><a href="https://preslav.me/2020/03/01/use-the-git-history/"><div><p>Use the Git History to Identify Pain Points in Any Project</p><p>Have you heard of Adam Tornhill [https://twitter.com/AdamTornhill]’s work? If
not, I highly recommend that you set some time aside and check out Your Code as
a Crime Scene [https://amzn.to/32DM1G9] or Software DEsign X-Rays
[https://amzn.to/2vtbjdR…</p><p><img src="https://preslav.me/favicon.png"><span>Preslav Rachev</span></p></div><p><img src="https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/fd47e6bba1f42ecacf2e7af9e4c5fb52?s=250&amp;d=mm&amp;r=x"></p></a></figure><p>In a future post, I will discuss some of the new ideas I applied to the simple git one-liner I presented there.</p></div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://preslav.me/2020/12/03/the-myth-of-code-coverage/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25306071</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 18:46:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fable 3: F# to JavaScript compiler]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 227 | Comments 99 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25305650">thread link</a>) | @adamnemecek
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://fable.io/blog/Announcing-Nagareyama-4.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fable.io/blog/Announcing-Nagareyama-4.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Today is the day, Fable 3 Nagareyama is officially released! Does this mean the latest version is bug-free? Probably not, but at least the install command is shorter. We have also tested the release candidates in many projects and managed to fix all the outstanding issues so if you find a problem when upgrading your Fable 2 project you may even consider yourself lucky (also, please report).</p>
<p>First things first, I have to acknowledge all the people that have contributed to this release: from Don Syme himself to ncave, our mysterious contributor, and all the early-users that have helped polish this release. Very importantly, the teachers too that take care of my children in difficult times so I can focus on programming. The fact that so many people can collaborate together to put a project like Fable forward still feels like magic to me and I can only say a big THANK YOU to you all. I'm also very happy this is coincidental with the release of F# 5, as incredibly smart people are putting a lot of effort to make the development experience with the language really pleasant. Quoting Krzysztof Cieślak, what a great time to be an F# developer!</p>
<p>How can you try Fable 3, you say? This is it:</p>
<pre><code>dotnet tool install fable
dotnet fable src</code></pre><p>(Change "src" with the path to your project.) It's that easy, type <code>dotnet fable --help</code> to see more options. Of course you still need extra tooling to bundle the JS code, spin off a development server, etc. If you're upgrading an app using Webpack, please <a href="https://github.com/MangelMaxime/fulma-demo/pull/43">check this PR for reference</a>.</p>
<p>Let's quickly go through the highlights of Nagareyama:</p>
<ul>
<li>It's Fable v3. Three is bigger than two, that's already a win.</li>
<li>There are no breaking changes, your Fable 2 project should compile as is with Nagareyama (you may need to update some libraries).</li>
<li>It's a dotnet tool, following suit with most F# project. Remember when Fable, Paket and Fake had each their own way to be downloaded and version-managed? Those days are happily gone!</li>
<li>It removes the inter-process communication with JS, greatly simplifying Fable usage and development.</li>
<li>The previous point together with other fixes have improved the compilation speed by a big deal. Expect it to be at least cut in half in most cases!</li>
<li>Fable is not tightly coupled with a specific bundler anymore like Webpack so you can use any tool you like! (Webpack is still a great choice.)</li>
<li>A lot of effort has been also put to prettify the generated code, making it more readable and easier to debug if needed.</li>
<li>Nagareyama can accept plugins by library authors. Zaid is already using this feature to make it much simpler to <a href="https://youtu.be/a6Ct3CM_lj4?t=860">write React components compatible with JS tooling</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can check the <a href="https://fable.io/blog/Announcing-Nagareyama-3.html">previous posts</a> for more details.</p>


<p>So what are you waiting for? Give Nagareyama a try and let the world know if it goes well... and let us know (privately) if it doesn't 😅 Have fun!</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fable.io/blog/Announcing-Nagareyama-4.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25305650</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 18:08:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Porting a 100% local app to the web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 152 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25304100">thread link</a>) | @jlongster
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://actualbudget.com/blog/porting-local-app-web | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://actualbudget.com/blog/porting-local-app-web">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>While researching <a href="https://actualbudget.com/blog/cursed-caching-curious">a curious caching bug</a>, I got inspired to take another look at how Actual stores data locally on the web. There's some history I need to explain. Years ago, Actual was only going to be a desktop app. That means <em>all</em> of your data is stored locally. No server.</p><p>Then I realized how important mobile is, and that most people don't want to worry about losing their data if they drop their computer in the ocean. A syncing engine was born, and desktop and mobile apps have happily synced their data ever since. A copy is kept on a server so users can login and easily view their data, and if they worry about privacy they can enable <a href="https://actualbudget.com/docs/overview/syncing-across-devices/#end-to-end-encryption">end-to-end encryption</a>.</p><p>In the last year I grew jealous of web apps. Look at how easily they can deploy… how quickly they can drop users right into the app. No install required. Here I am asking users to download an 80MB file just to run the app. That download absolutely kills conversion rates, and makes the login flow, support, a/b testing and <em>everything</em> much harder.</p><p>I love desktop apps because you have access to much better tech (like native sqlite3), the app is super fast (no network calls), and the user owns their data. However, I can't ignore that the benefits of the web <a href="https://www.kalzumeus.com/2009/09/05/desktop-aps-versus-web-apps/">dwarfs these advantages</a>.</p><p>I started thinking about a web version of Actual. After some hacking, <a href="https://app.actualbudget.com/">I got it working</a> without changing the architecture. That means all your data is still stored locally in the browser, and there are no network calls. It's a completely 100% "local" app in the browser [0].</p><p>I haven't marketed the web version much because it hasn't been tested enough, and it needs improvements like lazy loading code to make it load faster. The biggest thing I'm worried about is the data storage layer. Since <strong>all your data is local</strong>, if something goes wrong there you could potentially lose data. And we're really stressing the browser's persistant db by storing everything in it.</p><p>To be clear: <strong>we are not deprecating the desktop version</strong>. However in the future the web version will be the primary platform, with the choice to download the desktop version if desired.</p><p>The way it works a bit unusual. Here's a high-level overview:</p><ul><li>Actual uses <a href="https://www.sqlite.org/index.html">sqlite3</a>. This is a hard requirement. The app runs tons of complex SQL queries to aggregate financial data and it's so good at doing it. Queries are easy to express and run super fast.</li><li>On desktop and mobile, native sqlite3 is used. The web does not support sqlite3, however. To get around this, Actual uses a <a href="https://github.com/sql-js/sql.js">wasm version</a> of sqlite3 and creates an in-memory db.</li><li>The obvious problem is persistence. When you make changes, we need to persist them somewhere so when the user reloads they don't lose their data. Luckily we are using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conflict-free_replicated_data_type#State-based_CRDTs">state-based CRDT's</a> and all updates come through as a list of "messages". If you are online, these messages get synced to our server so when you reload, all your data should sync up.</li><li>It's not ideal to require a big sync every time you open the app though. Also, if you are offline there shouldn't be any chance of losing data. To solve this, Actual persists each message into IndexedDB. When the app opens, it applies all messages from the local IndexedDB to get up-to-date.</li><li>It's <em>still</em> not ideal to require applying any messages on load. It won't scale - if you use the app for months you'll accumulate tens of thousands of messages. IndexedDB would grow indefinitely and loading the app would get slower. To solve this, when the stored messages crosses a threshold it flushes the entire sqlite3 db to IndexedDB and clears all the messages.</li><li>That means both a binary representation of the sqlite3 db and a list of messages is persisted in IndexedDB. On load, the app creates the in-memory sqlite3 db from the snapshot and applies any remaining messages from IDB.</li></ul><p>Turns out this is similar to how a <a href="https://sqlite.org/wal.html">write-ahead log</a> works.</p><p>I was worried about the reliability of IndexedDB. Reading the docs it seems like browsers might delete databases as needed, but in practice this doesn't seem to happen [1]. It's probably a much bigger problem on mobile where memory is scarce, but I don't mess with the mobile web (use a native app instead). I was also worried about hitting the limit of IDB storage, but as explained next that hasn't been a problem.</p><p>This technique started as an experiment, but it has worked surprisingly well. I have 5 years worth of data in Actual, and the size of the sqlite3 db is 9.7MB. The threshold of the messages table is around 50KB, so in total I'm storing ~10MB in IndexedDB for a user who's been around for 5 years. It's not even close to hitting the IndexedDB max storage limit, which these days is at least 500MB.</p><p>While it has worked so far, I want to be 100% confident in this approach. I've been digging deep into how each browser stores IndexedDB data on disk and discovered a couple improvements I can make. I was going to write about them in this post, but I ended up writing more about the overall approach. In the next post I'll dig deep into how IndexedDB works across browsers.</p><p>[0] While I didn't talk about it in this post, this also means that the entire app runs in the browser. The "backend" runs in a background worker thread and everything happens locally.</p><p>[1] If the local data does somehow get corrupted or deleted, it's not a <em>huge</em> deal. All changes are still sent off and stored on a server (which is how all other devices get synced). If something goes wrong, the app can re-download your data from the server. The only case where you'd lose data is if you were offline and lost your local data, which is to be expected.</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://actualbudget.com/blog/porting-local-app-web</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25304100</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 16:23:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mannequin.js: An Articulated Mannequin Figure Library]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 146 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25302602">thread link</a>) | @petercooper
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<ul>
  <li><a href="#About">About</a></li>
  <li><a href="#Initialization">Initialization</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#Minimal-program">Minimal program</a></li>
      <li><a href="#Figure-types">Figure types</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#Body-parts">Body parts</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#Central-body-parts">Central body parts</a></li>
      <li><a href="#Upper-limbs">Upper limbs</a></li>
      <li><a href="#Lower-limbs">Lower limbs</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#Body-posture">Body posture</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#Static-posture">Static posture</a></li>
      <li><a href="#Dynamic-posture">Dynamic posture</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#Other-functions">Other functions</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#Custom-colors">Custom colors</a></li>
      <li><a href="#Hiding-body-parts">Hiding body parts</a></li>
      <li><a href="#Custom-body-parts">Custom body parts</a></li>
      <li><a href="#Global-position">Global position</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#Future-plans">Future plans</a></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Mannequin.js</strong> is a simple library of an articulated mannequin figure. The shape of the figure
and its movements are done purely in JavaScript. The graphics is implemented in
<a href="https://threejs.org/">Three.js</a>. Click on an image to open a live demo.</p>

<p><a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-posture.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-posture.jpg" width="150"></a>
<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-figure-types.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-figure-types.jpg" width="150"></a>
<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-custom-body-parts.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-custom-body-parts.jpg" width="150"></a>
<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-point.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-point.jpg" width="150"></a>
<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-scene.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-scene.jpg" width="150"></a></p>

<p>This is the fourth incarnation of the mannequin figure. The first one was implemented
in Elica. The second one was implemented in C/C++ and OpenGL. The third one
was implemented in JS/Three.js and is a direct predecessor of the current mannequin.js.
Since its first incarnation, mannequin.js is used in the course <em>Fundamentals of Computer Graphics</em> for Computer Sciences undergraduate students from the
<a href="https://www.fmi.uni-sofia.bg/en">Faculty of Mathematics and Informatics</a>
at <a href="https://www.uni-sofia.bg/index.php/eng">Sofia University</a>.</p>

<p>Mannequin.js is licensed under <strong>GPL-3.0</strong>.</p>

<p>Three.js is included in this repository to safeguard against incompatibilities with future versions. Three.js is not a part of mannequin.js.</p>



<p>The <strong>mannequin.js</strong> library is provided as a JavaScript file that has to
be include along with three.js.</p>

<h3 id="minimal-program">Minimal program</h3>

<p>Here is a minimal program that creates a male figure in the browser (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-minimal.html">live example</a>):</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;html&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;head&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;script</span> <span>src=</span><span>"three.min.js"</span><span>&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;script</span> <span>src=</span><span>"mannequin.min.js"</span><span>&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;/head&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;body&gt;</span>
    <span>&lt;script&gt;</span>
      createScene();
      var man = new Male();
    <span>&lt;/script&gt;</span>
  <span>&lt;/body&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;/html&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The helper function <code>createScene()</code> provides a default set-up of the scene and its elements, like lighting, camera, ground, etc. Another helper function, <code>animate(t)</code> is responsible for defining figures’ postures at moment <em>t</em>. If the set-up is done with a custom function, then it should also manage the animation loop by itself.</p>

<h3 id="figure-types">Figure types</h3>

<p>Mannequin figures are created as instances of classes <code>Male()</code>, <code>Female()</code> or <code>Child()</code> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-figure-types.html">live example</a>):</p>

<p><a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-figure-types.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-figure-types.jpg"></a></p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>var</span> <span>man</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>Male</span><span>();</span>
    <span>man</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>set</span><span>(</span><span>20</span><span>,</span><span>3.5</span><span>,</span><span>0</span><span>);</span>
    <span>man</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>120</span><span>);</span>
    <span>:</span>
<span>var</span> <span>woman</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>Female</span><span>();</span>
    <span>woman</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>set</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>20</span><span>,</span><span>2</span><span>,</span><span>0</span><span>);</span>
    <span>woman</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>60</span><span>);</span>
    <span>:</span>
<span>var</span> <span>kid</span> <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>Child</span><span>();</span>
    <span>kid</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>y</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>8</span><span>;</span>
    <span>kid</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>90</span><span>);</span>
    <span>:</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>These three classes have a common predecessor – the class <code>Mannequin(feminine,height)</code>, where <em>feminine</em> is boolean and defines whether the shape is feminine or masculine, and the second parameter is a number for relative height (adults have height 1).</p>



<p>All types of figures have the same structure of joints. For example, the right arm of a figure is accessed by <code>r_arm</code>. Left and right body parts are in respect to the figure, not to the viewer (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-body-parts.html">live example</a>):</p>

<p><a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-body-parts.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-body-parts.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Each body part has rotation methods that turn it around a pivot point.
The first parameter <em>angle</em> of the methods is the angle of rotation in degrees,
so 180 is half turn and 360 is full turn. Negative angles are allowed and
they represent turning in the opposite direction. Some methods have an optional
second parameter for <em>direction</em> of motion, which could be the constant <code>LEFT</code> or
<code>RIGHT</code>.</p>

<h3 id="central-body-parts">Central body parts</h3>

<p>The central body parts are the ones which have single instances - <em>head</em>, <em>neck</em>, <em>torso</em>, <em>pelvis</em> and the body as a whole. To move the whole <strong>body</strong> use methods <em>bend</em>, <em>turn</em> and <em>tilt</em> of the figure (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-body.html">live example</a>):</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.bend ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.turn ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.turn ( angle, direction )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.tilt ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.tilt ( angle, direction )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>The <strong>head</strong> supports similar methods: <em>nod</em>, <em>turn</em> and <em>tilt</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-head.html">live example</a>):</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.head.nod ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.head.turn ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.head.turn ( angle, dir )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.head.tilt ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.head.tilt ( angle, dir )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>The <strong>torso</strong> has the same methods as the whole body: <em>bend</em>, <em>turn</em> and <em>tilt</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-torso.html">live example</a>):</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.torso.bend ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.torso.turn ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.torso.turn ( angle, direction )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.torso.tilt ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.torso.tilt ( angle, direction )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>Although the <strong>neck</strong> is a separate part of the body, it is not controlled individually. Instead, a part of the head motion is distributed over the neck. Similarly, the <strong>pelvis</strong> is not controlled individually. Instead, the whole body is controlled by bending, turning and tilting.</p>

<h3 id="upper-limbs">Upper limbs</h3>

<p>The upper limbs are symmetrical body parts: <em>arm</em>, <em>elbow</em>, <em>wrist</em> and <em>fingers</em>.</p>

<p>Both <strong>arms</strong> support methods <em>raise</em>, <em>straddle</em> and <em>turn</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-arm1.html">live example</a>). The following list refers to the right arm, however, the same methods are available for the right hand:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.r_arm.raise ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_arm.straddle ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_arm.straddle ( angle, direction )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_arm.turn ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_arm.turn ( angle, direction )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>If the <em>direction</em> parameter is omitted, then the default motions of <em>straddle</em> and <em>turn</em> are symmetrical. For example, the left arm is straddled to the left, while the right arm is straddled to the right (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-arm2.html">live example</a>).</p>

<p>The motion of the <strong>elbow</strong> is only <em>bend</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-elbow.html">live example</a>). Negative values for <em>angle</em> result in unnatural elbow position.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.r_elbow.bend ( angle )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>The <strong>wrists</strong> have the same methods as the torso: <em>bend</em>, <em>turn</em> and <em>tilt</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-wrist.html">live example</a>), but similar to the arms, the directions are symmetrical, if <em>direction</em> is not set:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.r_wrist.bend ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_wrist.turn ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_wrist.turn ( angle, direction )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_wrist.tilt ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_wrist.tilt ( angle, direction )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>The last body parts of the upper limbs are the <strong>fingers</strong>. They can only <em>bend</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-fingers.html">live example</a>), however, they are composed of two segments and the bending angle is distributed over both of them.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.r_fingers.bend ( angle )</code></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="lower-limbs">Lower limbs</h3>

<p>The lower limbs are symmetrical body parts: <em>leg</em>, <em>knee</em> and <em>ankle</em>.</p>

<p>Both <strong>legs</strong> support methods <em>raise</em>, <em>straddle</em> and <em>turn</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-leg.html">live example</a>). Straddling and turning are symmetrical if <em>direction</em> is not set.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.r_leg.raise ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_leg.straddle ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_leg.straddle ( angle, direction )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_leg.turn ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_leg.turn ( angle, direction )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>The motion of the <strong>knee</strong> is only <em>bend</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-knee.html">live example</a>). Negative values for <em>angle</em> result in unnatural knee position.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.r_knee.bend ( angle )</code></li>
</ul>

<p>The <strong>ankles</strong> have the same methods as the wrists: <em>bend</em>, <em>turn</em> and <em>tilt</em> (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-ankle.html">live example</a>), but similar to the legs, the directions are symmetrical, if <em>direction</em> is not set:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>figure.r_ankle.bend ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_ankle.turn ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_ankle.turn ( angle, direction )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_ankle.tilt ( angle )</code></li>
  <li><code>figure.r_ankle.tilt ( angle, direction )</code></li>
</ul>



<p>The posture of a figure is defined by a setting the rotations of body parts. The order of rotations is fixed independent on the order of rotations in the user program (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-order.html">live example</a>). For example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>figure</span><span>.</span><span>head</span><span>.</span><span>nod</span><span>(</span><span>30</span><span>);</span>
<span>figure</span><span>.</span><span>head</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>45</span><span>);</span>
<span>figure</span><span>.</span><span>head</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>20</span><span>,</span><span>RIGHT</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>produces the same posture as:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>figure</span><span>.</span><span>head</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>20</span><span>,</span><span>RIGHT</span><span>);</span>
<span>figure</span><span>.</span><span>head</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>45</span><span>);</span>
<span>figure</span><span>.</span><span>head</span><span>.</span><span>nod</span><span>(</span><span>30</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Sometimes this might lead to unexpected results, especially if the user assumes an order of rotations that is different from what mannequin.js uses. This might happen when a body part is rotated around 3 or 2 axes.</p>

<h3 id="static-posture">Static posture</h3>

<p>The static posture defines the position of body part that do not change. By default, when a figure is created, its body parts are set to the default posture. This version of mannequin.js does not provide posture editor, so all rotations has to be defined programmatically.</p>

<p><a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-posture.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-posture.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Sometimes it is better to define the figure step by step. Tai Chi Chuan posture (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-posture.html">live example</a>) could start by defining the whole body position:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// overall body position</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>y</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>7.7</span><span>;</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>5</span><span>,</span><span>LEFT</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>15</span><span>);</span>

<span>// torso and head</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>torso</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>30</span><span>,</span><span>RIGHT</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>torso</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>15</span><span>,</span><span>RIGHT</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>torso</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>15</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>head</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>70</span><span>,</span><span>RIGHT</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then the orientation of the legs can be set:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// right leg</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_leg</span><span>.</span><span>raise</span><span>(</span><span>85</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_leg</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>20</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_leg</span><span>.</span><span>straddle</span><span>(</span><span>40</span><span>,</span><span>LEFT</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_knee</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>90</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_ankle</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>35</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_ankle</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>20</span><span>,</span><span>RIGHT</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_ankle</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>15</span><span>);</span>

<span>// left leg</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_leg</span><span>.</span><span>raise</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>30</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_knee</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>25</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_ankle</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>42</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Finally, the arms are fixed:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>// left arm</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_arm</span><span>.</span><span>raise</span><span>(</span><span>10</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_arm</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>40</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_arm</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>60</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_elbow</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>155</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_wrist</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>50</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>l_fingers</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>10</span><span>);</span>

<span>// right arm</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_arm</span><span>.</span><span>raise</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>10</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_arm</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>70</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_arm</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>20</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_elbow</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>40</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_wrist</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>30</span><span>);</span>
<span>man</span><span>.</span><span>r_fingers</span><span>.</span><span>bend</span><span>(</span><span>90</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="dynamic-posture">Dynamic posture</h3>

<p>The dynamic posture – i.e. a posture that changes over time – is set with the same methods that are used for static posture. Mannequin.js defines an empty function <code>animate(t)</code>, which is called in the animation loop once for each frame. All changes of a posture should be defined inside this function (<a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-dynamic.html">live example</a>). The parameter <em>t</em> is the time, measured in tenths of seconds. This function is set up in <code>createScene()</code>. If <em>createScene</em> and <em>animate</em> are not used, then the animation loop should be managed manually.</p>

<p><a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/example-dynamic.html"><img src="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/examples/snapshots/example-dynamic.jpg"></a></p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>function</span> <span>animate</span><span>(</span><span>t</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>var</span> <span>time1</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>sin</span><span>(</span><span>2</span><span>*</span><span>t</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>cos</span><span>(</span><span>3</span><span>*</span><span>t</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>cos</span><span>(</span><span>5</span><span>*</span><span>t</span><span>))</span><span>/</span><span>3</span><span>,</span>
        <span>time2</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>sin</span><span>(</span><span>2</span><span>*</span><span>t</span><span>-</span><span>60</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>cos</span><span>(</span><span>3</span><span>*</span><span>t</span><span>-</span><span>90</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>cos</span><span>(</span><span>5</span><span>*</span><span>t</span><span>-</span><span>120</span><span>))</span><span>/</span><span>3</span><span>;</span>

    <span>ball</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>3</span><span>*</span><span>time1</span><span>;</span>

    <span>child</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>3</span><span>*</span><span>time1</span><span>;</span>
    <span>child</span><span>.</span><span>position</span><span>.</span><span>y</span> <span>=</span> <span>4</span><span>+</span><span>cos</span><span>(</span><span>90</span><span>*</span><span>time1</span><span>);</span>

    <span>child</span><span>.</span><span>turn</span><span>(</span><span>-</span><span>90</span><span>-</span><span>20</span><span>*</span><span>time1</span><span>+</span><span>20</span><span>*</span><span>time2</span><span>);</span>
    <span>child</span><span>.</span><span>tilt</span><span>(</span><span>10</span><span>*</span><span>time1</span><span>);</span>
    <span>:</span>
	
    <span>scene</span><span>.</span><span>rotation</span><span>.</span><span>y</span> <span>=</span> <span>rad</span><span>(</span><span>30</span><span>*</span><span>time1</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>To make the animation loop faster, all constant rotations should be defined outside <em>animate</em>. Also, if a rotation changing in the loop, there is no need to set it up outside the loop.</p>



<p>Apart for moving body parts, the current version of mannequin.js provides basic functionality for additional modification or accessing the figure.</p>

<h3 id="custom-colors">Custom colors</h3>

<p>By default, all figures use a predefined set of global colors for body parts. Global colors are stored in <code>Mannequin.colors</code> array as six <a href="https://threejs.org/docs/#api/en/math/Color">Three.js colors</a> or lowercase <a href="https://www.w3schools.com/colors/colors_names.asp">HTML/CSS color names</a> in specific order – head, shoes, pelvis, joints, limbs and torso:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>Mannequin</span><span>.</span><span>colors</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>'</span><span>antiquewhite</span><span>'</span><span>,</span>	<span>// head</span>
    <span>'</span><span>gray</span><span>'</span><span>,</span>		<span>// shoes</span>
    <span>'</span><span>antiquewhite</span><span>'</span><span>,</span>	<span>// pelvis</span>
    <span>'</span><span>burlywood</span><span>'</span><span>,</span>	<span>// joints</span>
    <span>'</span><span>antiquewhite</span><span>'</span><span>,</span>	<span>// limbs</span>
    <span>'</span><span>bisque</span><span>'</span>		<span>// torso</span>
<span>];</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The global color of …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/">https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://boytchev.github.io/mannequin.js/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25302602</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 14:35:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Guide to Effective Reading]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 186 | Comments 20 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25302132">thread link</a>) | @accountLost
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://maartenvandoorn.nl/reading-guide/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://maartenvandoorn.nl/reading-guide/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1454">

	<!-- .entry-header -->



	<div>

		
<figure><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2600/1*0tmBPKA1YGo82VNeMS3KhA.jpeg" alt=""><figcaption> <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://unsplash.com/photos/9pw4TKvT3po?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText" target="_blank">Let’s make that magic&nbsp;happen</a> </figcaption></figure>



<p>Learning is a heavily misunderstood&nbsp;concept.</p>



<p>As a&nbsp;paradigm&nbsp;example of&nbsp;deep work,&nbsp;we understand that, when reading, directing your full attention to the material at hand is essential.&nbsp;Graspingcomplex information is hard.</p>



<p>But this is only half the battle.</p>



<p>After some string of words hits your retina and has made its way to your brain, you’re&nbsp;not done.</p>



<p>In a&nbsp;cruel&nbsp;irony,&nbsp;these hours of&nbsp;deep work&nbsp;often cause&nbsp;flow&nbsp;states&nbsp;and the feeling that ‘you’ve had a good day’ and learned a&nbsp;shitload&nbsp;of new stuff.</p>



<p>But for many reading&nbsp;episodes&nbsp;this feeling is&nbsp;deceptive.&nbsp;There is anineliminable&nbsp;aspect to learning that takes place&nbsp;<em>after&nbsp;</em>the&nbsp;glorious&nbsp;flow state.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;other half of the battle is&nbsp;to&nbsp;transfer the newly acquired intelligence from your working memory to your&nbsp;long-term&nbsp;understanding and&nbsp;integrate&nbsp;it into your standing stack of mental models.</p>



<p>If you don’t&nbsp;facilitate&nbsp;this, your learning&nbsp;gains&nbsp;are only a&nbsp;fraction&nbsp;of what they could have been.</p>



<p>In this article,&nbsp;I’m going to breakdown how to win the battle and the war — how to&nbsp;avoid&nbsp;these traps and organize your reading habit for a maximalReturn On Investment (ROI)&nbsp;on reading hours.</p>



<p>This is what we’ll cover:</p>



<pre><strong>Table of Contents</strong></pre>



<pre>1. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#1b1d">Meta-Learning</a><br>2. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#1d70">Learning is a two-step process</a><br>3. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#9181">Remembering the right things</a><br>4. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#7b89">Enter: Mental models</a><br>5. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#a837">Learning = upgrading your mental models</a></pre>



<pre>6. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#f0d0">How to ‘get it in there’ (macro-level)</a><br>7. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#8823">How to ‘get it in there’ (micro level)</a><br>7.1 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#19fe">Know your why</a></pre>



<pre>8. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#d988">Active reading</a><br>8.1 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#414f">How to make a mind map</a><br>8.2 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#ad79">Which Returns are you aiming for?</a><br>8.3 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#d61e">Written active recall with bullet points</a><br>8.4 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#a187">How to actively read a book</a><br>8.5 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#8ead">Remember your why (yes, again)</a></pre>



<pre>9. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#4e04">Advanced active reading</a><br>9.1 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#9782">The QEC method</a><br>9.2 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#8dac">Keep a running tally</a><br>9.3 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#dc6b">Put your unconsciousness to work</a><br>9.4 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#7a10">Pulling it all together</a><br>9.5 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#6b84">How to actively read a book (advanced)</a></pre>



<pre>10. <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#926b">Organizing repetition and reflection</a><br>10.1 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#f934">Setting up and using your review cycle</a><br>10.2 <a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#5182">Improved learning: engage in active recall</a></pre>



<pre><a href="https://medium.com/@maartenvandoorn/the-complete-guide-to-effective-reading-fc1835937757/#fc24">Conclusion: The cycle of learning</a></pre>



<p>Warning: this is a very&nbsp;nerdy&nbsp;post.</p>



<h3 id="1b1d">Meta-Learning</h3>



<p>Meta-learning&nbsp;is knowing how to learn.&nbsp;It is one of the most important skills to learn, yet few people know how to do to it.</p>



<p>Reading and writing is what I do for a living, and, interestingly, a lot of non-imaginary&nbsp;friends have been asking me how I learn.&nbsp;This is special, becausemost of the times when people don’t know how to do something, they go&nbsp;togreat&nbsp;lengths&nbsp;<em>not&nbsp;</em>to notice their&nbsp;deficiency.</p>



<p>Could it be that many students turned ‘knowledge workers’ have the&nbsp;naggingfeeling that something is missing in their skillset because they were never taught&nbsp;meta-learning?</p>



<p>This is not their fault, but a&nbsp;<a href="https://medium.com/the-understanding-project/schools-dont-support-personal-development-they-distort-it-7e1c227eb01d" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lack in our education system</a>.</p>



<p>As Adam Robinson observed on the&nbsp;<a href="https://fs.blog/adam-robinson-pt2/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank"><em>Farnam Street&nbsp;</em>podcast</a>:</p>



<blockquote><p>“<strong>No one ever shows us how to learn, ever</strong>.&nbsp;Nowhere in school.&nbsp;For example, imagine, Shane, [Shane is the host of the FS podcast] in French class, French 101, your first French class, your teacher said,&nbsp;“Everyone, you’re going to have to learn a lot of vocabulary in this class so before I teach you any words I’m going to teach you a way to remember vocabulary.”&nbsp;They never do that.&nbsp;They just go, “We’re going to have a quiz on these 30 words on Monday.&nbsp;Good luck.”&nbsp;But they don’t teach us how to learn actually, or remember things.”</p></blockquote>



<p>This is&nbsp;weird, because,&nbsp;in today’s high-information world,&nbsp;people need the ability to&nbsp;<em>make sense of</em>&nbsp;complexity and to&nbsp;<em>combine</em>&nbsp;many bits of data into a broad picture of the world.</p>



<p>Merely&nbsp;<em>acquiring</em>information is&nbsp;<em>not&nbsp;</em>(yet) learning.</p>



<p>Learning itself is a skill, and knowing how to do it well is an incredibly valuable advantage.</p>



<p>We take this is for granted, but how to do this is&nbsp;far from&nbsp;obvious&nbsp;and doesn’t get taught in the curriculum.</p>



<hr>



<h3 id="1d70">Learning is a&nbsp;two-step&nbsp;process</h3>



<p>So, how do we learn?</p>



<p>Before we attempt to answer the question,&nbsp;let’s get clear&nbsp;on what a&nbsp;satisfactoryanswer needs to get us.&nbsp;What does it&nbsp;<em>mean&nbsp;</em>to learn?&nbsp;When have you learned something?</p>



<p>In the introduction, I stated that&nbsp;just studying the information isn’t enough(no matter how intense your focus was).&nbsp;Learning has&nbsp;two phases — not one.</p>



<ol><li>Read/listen&nbsp;the damn thing</li><li>Process and&nbsp;recall&nbsp;what you’ve just ‘learned’</li></ol>



<p>A lot has been said about the first phase — about deep work, concentration, blocking out&nbsp;distractions, and so&nbsp;forth.&nbsp;This makes sense:&nbsp;if you’re checking Facebook all the time,&nbsp;your mind is not ‘there’, and you might as well not have spent your afternoon ’reading’ this book.</p>



<p>This is all great and I‘m a big fan, but in the&nbsp;meantime, we’re ignoring step two.</p>



<p>If you don’t spend time revisiting and grappling with the book either,&nbsp;<em>the same applies</em> — you might as well not have read it.&nbsp;In the long run, there is no difference between skipping the first or the second stage (except whether you passed that French test in high school back in 2019…).</p>



<p>After you’ve killed Cersei, you’ve still got the&nbsp;White Walkers to deal with.&nbsp;If you don’t, you lose either way.</p>



<p>That is why students who&nbsp;binge-study&nbsp;the night before the exam quite literally forget everything two days later:&nbsp;while all these&nbsp;lame&nbsp;French words were still in their short-term memory,&nbsp;allowing them to pass the test,&nbsp;the information never&nbsp;transitioned&nbsp;to their long-term understanding — and so, sooner or later, it&nbsp;evaporated.</p>



<p>To learn,&nbsp;you need to transfer the newly acquired intelligence from&nbsp;your working memory to your long-term understanding.</p>



<p><strong>The jump from short-term memory to long-term understanding doesn’t happen automatically.</strong><strong>The default mode, after you close your books for the day, is not&nbsp;</strong><strong>retainment</strong><strong>&nbsp;but&nbsp;<em>forgetting</em></strong><strong>.</strong></p>



<p>This learning guide&nbsp;is not about&nbsp;<a href="https://medium.com/the-understanding-project/why-you-dont-need-to-read-those-productivity-guides-347fe02cc196" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">how to do generic deep work</a>.&nbsp;It explains how to maximize the ROI on hours spent reading,&nbsp;<em>assuming</em>&nbsp;you did them ‘deep work style’.</p>



<h3 id="9181">Remembering the right&nbsp;things</h3>



<p>First, I need to discuss a common&nbsp;objection&nbsp;that denies phase two of learning matters.&nbsp;If you have no&nbsp;quibble&nbsp;with memorization, and doing the required effort, you can skip this section.</p>



<p>“But Mr. Maarten,” the protest goes, “you mention ‘processing’ and ‘remembering’ into my ‘long-term understanding’, but isn’t memorizing pointless?&nbsp;My Google Assistant can look everything up and also is smarter than me, says my Google Assistant.”</p>



<p>Indeed,&nbsp;Albert Einstein is&nbsp;<a href="https://medium.com/the-polymath-project/studying-history-is-more-important-than-ever-in-todays-economy-c99fde4be7d0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">supposed</a>&nbsp;to have said:&nbsp;“Never&nbsp;memorize&nbsp;what you can look up in a book”.&nbsp;In Einstein’s days, books were&nbsp;unequaled&nbsp;as a source of information.&nbsp;We, on the other hand, live in an age where nearly everything can be accessed through the magic vehicle of internet.&nbsp;Following Einstein’s logic, then,&nbsp;<em>nothing&nbsp;</em>is worth memorizing anymore, because&nbsp;<em>everything</em>&nbsp;can be looked up.</p>



<p>But, of course, that is probably not what old Albert was getting at.</p>



<p>Most likely,&nbsp;the advice he wanted to&nbsp;dispense&nbsp;was that&nbsp;you should not waste your time by committing unimportant details to memory.&nbsp;Rather,&nbsp;your&nbsp;focus should be on understanding the bigger picture — on&nbsp;how things relate to each other.</p>



<p>This reminds me of Elon Musk’s&nbsp;approach to learning.&nbsp;He&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/2rgsan/i_am_elon_musk_ceocto_of_a_rocket_company_ama/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">recommends</a>viewing knowledge as a tree:</p>



<blockquote><p>Make sure you understand the fundamental principles, the trunk and big branches, before you get into the leaves/details or there is nothing for them to hang on to.</p></blockquote>



<p>To ‘learn’, we need to do more than merely feeding ourselves new information.&nbsp;Expanding our intelligence requires&nbsp;<em>connecting</em>&nbsp;new materials to what we already knew&nbsp;(the second phase of learning).&nbsp;That, in turn, requires something to connect&nbsp;<em>to.</em></p>



<p>There’s no adding branches without a solid trunk.</p>



<p>The very possibility of genuine insight requires a memorized base.&nbsp;Without it, data you consume will not be added to your tree of knowledge.&nbsp;Instead, they will float in the air for a couple of weeks or so, before being taken away by the wind.</p>



<p>Knowledge, gone.&nbsp;Time, wasted.</p>



<p>What I’m saying is&nbsp;<em>not&nbsp;</em>that we should&nbsp;devise&nbsp;techniques which enable us torecite&nbsp;everything we’ve learned.&nbsp;That’s why we’re not talking about, for example,&nbsp;retaining&nbsp;the date of the French revolution.</p>



<p>However,&nbsp;you&nbsp;<em>should&nbsp;</em>learn by heart the lessons it tells you about how the world works&nbsp;and update your representation of reality&nbsp;accordingly.</p>



<p>In&nbsp;other words,&nbsp;you should use it to&nbsp;inform&nbsp;your&nbsp;unconscious — the&nbsp;sum&nbsp;of your mental models.</p>



<h3 id="7b89">Enter: Mental&nbsp;models</h3>



<p>I’ve long been skeptical about mental models since (1) they’re all the rage now and (2) no one seems to be able to explain in concrete terms what they are. A dangerous combination.</p>



<p>It turned out my doubt was due to ignorance on my part.</p>



<p>A mental model,&nbsp;as&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mental_model" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a>&nbsp;tells us, is</p>



<blockquote><p>An explanation of someone’s thought process about how something works in the real world.&nbsp;<strong>It is a representation of the surrounding world</strong>, the relationships between its various parts and a person’s intuitive perception about his or her own acts and their consequences.</p></blockquote>



<p>Every problem and situation is just another ‘one of those’ — another one of a certain type.&nbsp;Figuring out what type it is and reflecting on principles for handling that type of issue will help you do a better job.</p>



<p>On the conscious level, mental models allow us to ‘fit’ different possible interpretations onto reality to see if it is ‘one of those’.</p>



<p>For example,&nbsp;according to&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Hanlon’s Razor</a>&nbsp;one should&nbsp;“never attribute tomalice&nbsp;that which is adequately explained by carelessness”.&nbsp;When your coworker hands you crappy slides for the presentation you have to give in five minutes — what’s going on here?</p>



<p>Which ‘one of those’ do we have here?</p>



<p>You can see&nbsp;how different mental models in our heads will cause us to reach different conclusions about the correct interpretation of the situation.</p>



<p>A mental model is a mental, simplified&nbsp;depiction&nbsp;of how something works.They are how we order complexity, why we consider some things more relevant than others, and how we reason.&nbsp;They help us filter, organize and understand.</p>



<p>For instance, according to&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_distribution" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">Pareto distribution</a>,&nbsp;“for many events,&nbsp;roughly 80% of the …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://maartenvandoorn.nl/reading-guide/">https://maartenvandoorn.nl/reading-guide/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://maartenvandoorn.nl/reading-guide/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25302132</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 13:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using Google Analytics without GDPR consent]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 107 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25301500">thread link</a>) | @evrimfeyyaz
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://evrim.io/using-google-analytics-without-gdpr-consent/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://evrim.io/using-google-analytics-without-gdpr-consent/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://evrim.io/using-google-analytics-without-gdpr-consent/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25301500</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 12:23:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Wikipedia's in Trouble (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 83 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25300942">thread link</a>) | @sanqui
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>
I got involved in wikipedia <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=User%3ASpencerk&amp;action=history&amp;year=2006&amp;month=-1&amp;tagfilter=">very early</a>.

It was one of the most revealing things in my life, watching it being laughed at, to become the center of, and authority of, human knowledge.

It was obvious that it was working. The lag of this was 5 years or more.

Wikipedia was an experiment that proved itself, when every graph was going up and to the right.

Some of the graphs are now going down.

</p><p>Wikipedia's Markup language:</p><p>
One of the central design decisions in wikipedia is that <span>all information</span> is stored in an editable document.
This poses a huge amount of challenges for caching and scaling wikipedia. It's not a database, that you can run a script on.

Worse though, is that all of it's content is buried in this ad-hoc, impenetrable, opaque, and mostly <i>un-parsable</i> format.

If wikipedia had used <i>markdown</i>, <i>html</i>, or some <i>standardised format</i>, any parser would flip-it into other future formats.

Wikipedia's custom language is just <a href="https://github.com/spencermountain/wtf_wikipedia/blob/master/README.md">clearly insane</a>, undocumented, hopeless.
There's a team <span>(of great people!)</span> at wikimedia <a href="https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/tag/parsoid/">constantly working on it</a>, and unable to make any backwards-incompatible changes. I imagine their lives are hard.
People are creating weird new syntax concepts all the time.

Here's the markup for the <b>first sentence</b> of the Albert Einstein wikipedia article:
<img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/albert-einstein.jpg">

The first wikimedia parser was called <a href="https://github.com/earwig/mwparserfromhell/">mwparserfromhell</a>. DBPedia, <a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a9/LOD_Cloud_2014-08.svg">the center of the semantic web</a>, after years of work, has only ever offered limited parsing from categories and infoboxes.
Much of the early-years at <b>Freebase</b> were spent trying, with limited-success, at parsing wikipedia.
I've spent <a href="https://github.com/spencermountain/wtf_wikipedia/graphs/commit-activity">years</a> trying to parse it myself.
I'm a shitty programmer. <i>WolframAlpha</i>, and many other serious companies are using my parser,
       which is <span>down right hilarious</span>.

<img id="rtl" src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/rtl.jpg"></p><p>yes, arabic editors must write it in right-to-left, <a href="https://youtu.be/OCQd02hORJQ">somehow</a>.</p><p>

It's hard to describe how much of a serious problem this is.
Wikipedia's content is never going to go anywhere, or be used by anything.

Wikipedia may slowly die-off - like myspace, or geocities - but it's information will not go on.

Play-around in the official wikipedia android app. Many pages are unreadable.
There is a good-deal of <i>clearfix</i>, and <span>table-span</span> logic, mushed right into the syntax.
Most developers will not touch this kind of stuff.

There will be no move to a wikipedia 2.

</p><p>Static copies of dynamic content</p><p>
The contents of the english wikipedia dump are as follows, (as of Jan 2019):
</p><p>
of the <b>14m</b> records in the wikipedia dump, only <b>5.5m</b> (40%) are public-facing articles.

   <span>Yup.</span>
This does not include deleted pages, or old versions, either.


<b>Redirects:</b>
A computer-science 101 problem is to implement a fuzzy string matching. There's usually a section in the textbook about it:
</p><div>
<p><img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/clr.jpg"></p><p>oh yes, right here in chapter 34.</p><p>
there are <b>8,550,441</b> redirects in wikipedia.
They are mostly typos, or case-changes, and are mostly created by hand, every day.

<span>and what happens to a redirect when a page gets deleted, or merged, or spli - <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Link_rot">Yup</a>.</span>
</p></div>

<p><b>Talk pages:</b>
Wikipedia has 35m registered users. When a user joins, a bot will often send them a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:Welcome">{{welcome}}</a> template.
Sometimes nice users will do it themselves. It looks <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_talk:Kj_aviator">like this</a>.

   - when this happens, this creates a new user page, with <b>a copy of this text</b> each time.

There are millions of examples of this in the dump. The same text, verbatim over and over.

The same process happens with <b>'Wikiprojects'</b>. Bots go around adding templates, by creating a talk page, and adding a template to it.

The same process happens with <i>deleted pages, fair-use warnings, and some bot edits</i>. Each time an edit happens, a new page is created, and boilerplate text gets thrown into it.
Resulting in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:XTC_discography">this</a>:
<img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/boilerplate.png"></p><hr><p>
So let's get things straight:
in <b>1993</b>, a small japanese game company created <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A-Rank_Thunder_Tanjouhen">this videogame</a>:
</p><p><img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/thunder.jpg">
</p><p>
• In <b>2008</b>, a wikipedia user created the article with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=A-Rank_Thunder_Tanjouhen&amp;oldid=205879125">two sentences and a link</a>.

• In the past 10 years since, the page has been edited <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=A-Rank_Thunder_Tanjouhen&amp;oldid=205879125">26 times by bots</a>.

• this created a Talk page filled with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:A-Rank_Thunder_Tanjouhen">11 automated sentences</a>.

A huge bulk of the wikipedia database is this boilerplate text. See <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:764_Gedania">this asteroid</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:NS3_(HCV)">this virus</a>, or this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:Oceania_Judo_Union">judo club</a>.

... and remember, if we wanted to change this text, we'd have to go and edit each of these pages - and because this syntax is so nuts, <b>bots have a hard time</b> making even simple stylistic changes, without ruining a whole page.

oh, so what happens to these auto-generated talk pages when a page is deleted, merged, or spli- <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:578_Happelia">yup</a>

<b id="automation">Automated articles:</b>
There is a lot of disagreement about how much of wikipedia is generated by bots, and if this matters.
There's no way of knowing. Any boring-themed article with a few sentences, a reference, and an infobox probably won't get deleted.
So nothing's stopping you from spitting-out articles from a <b>database of enzymes</b>, or <b>college rugby players</b>, or season statistics for defunct sports teams.
</p><p><img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/enzymes.jpg">
  <img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/subgiants.png">
</p><p>
I have nothing against bots, I have nothing against the long-tail, but I think automated article-creation is responsible for a good amount of the wikipedia's claimed growth, over the past few years.
We need to be up-front about this, if we're talking about the health of the project.

Here's the distribution of words in english wikipedia, by the size of articles:
</p>

<div>
<p><span>ok hey,</span> I don't mind that the wm developers didn't develop a fancy search index, in 2001.
That's fine.
Nobody could have predicted the success and scale of wikipedia early on.
</p><p>
What angers me though
         - <i>and it should anger you</i> -
is that these problems has not been fixed in the <b>18 years</b> since.

God damn them.

Well-meaning people are wasting their time on this <span>everyday</span>.

Any <i>startup job-interview</i> asks questions about implementing a system like this.
Any CS grad can create a lucene index, to handle typos.
Some of it is complicated. Some of it is basic competence.

<span>It's annoying to whine</span>,
     but at some point, we're right to be angry at wikipedia.

            that it cannot find 2nd gear,
     when the rest of the world is zipping-along.
</p>
</div>

<p>Wikidata</p><p>
In 2007 Danny Hillis raised $57 million dollars,<a href="https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/metawebtechnologies#section-overview">[1]</a> bought-out the <b>entire</b> MIT semantic-web group,
hired 50~ employees, (including <a href="https://www.apple.com/leadership/john-giannandrea/">this person</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Toby-Segaran/e/B001I9RQVS">this person</a>, <a href="http://davidhuynh.net/">this person</a>) and got an office in the mission.

They reconciled all of wikipedia, the entire musicbrainz database, the entire open-library database, the tvdb database, and all of wordnet.
They signed a (massive) deal to import <b>all collections of the stanford library</b>.<a href="https://www.clir.org/pubs/reports/pub152/stanford-linked-data-workshop/">[2]</a>

They hit <b>high-90%</b> classification of all <a href="https://research.google.com/pubs/archive/44818.pdf"><b>50 million</b></a> entities (wikipedia has 5m)
They were evaluated at very-high 90's accuracy by several third-parties.

Facebook, Bing, Amazon, and Google all began using its data in nearly real-time in their search products.

This was one of the largest and most ambitious software projects in history.

In 2010 freebase was bought for a whack of money, and then killed-off by google.
When google announced they would be shutting down the API, they offered to import all of this data to a new wikimedia project called <span>wikidata</span>.

Wikidata was 4-or-5 Lua developers, in Germany, on a few research grants.

</p><p>and they said no. 😐</p><p>

so they said this data didn't meet it's guidelines regarding sourced data.

    <i>... aren't you pulling information <b>from wikipedia</b> blindly?</i>

    <i>... what about your (~60%) unreferenced facts?</i>

    <i>... aren't you <b>multiplying vandalism</b> from multi-lingual wikipedias?</i>

    <i>... how do you use, or verify references?</i>

They built a tool to <b>hand-transfer each freebase fact</b>, which if you have a calculator, may seem funny.
<span>(at 10 people clicking full-time, would have taken 10 million years)</span>

8 years later, <a href="https://www.wikidata.org/wiki/Wikidata:Main_Page">Wikidata</a> remains tiny, buggy, unused, and worse - <i>majority unreferenced</i>.
I mean, they're pulling their data from wikipedia, which gets vandalized almost every minute!

It's accomplished very-little from its 5-year plan. They write academic papers.
They still don't really offer a rest api.
       ...creating new types or properties is I think, possible? or it's supposed to be...

It's got few of the safeguards, momentum, features, and ambition that Freebase had a full decade ago.
If wikidata was a company, it would not exist anymore, and you wouldn't have heard of it.

But Wikimedia places <b>banner-ads</b> on <span>hours of eye-blistering user-created content</span>,
begging children, students, and poor-people for money.
and they choose to be this petty, pithy and behind-the-times.

</p><p>Category-system</p><p>
It's a beautiful idea, to classify information with category-scheme, <a href="https://humane.computer/review-the-science-of-managing-our-digital-stuff/">until it falls-apart</a>.

<a href="http://www.shirky.com/writings/ontology_overrated.html"><img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/shirky-category.jpg"></a>
Wikipedia has many-thousands of categories. They <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Dump_reports/Category_cycles">loop-around</a> all-over the place.

</p><p>
People:
    → Musicians
        → Singers
              → American_Idol
                  → Books_about_American_Idol
</p><p>
or worse:
</p><p><span>Albanian language</span>:
    → Albanian-speaking countries and territories
      → Kosovo (region)
        → Kosovo
          → Kosovar society
            → Languages of Kosovo
              → <span>Albanian language</span>
</p><p>
if you're ever too-cheerful, and wanting to feel depressed, have a visit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Categories_for_discussion/Log/Today">Categories for deletion/Today</a>,
where you'll see precious human-life spent debating whether <b>'Category:Goth'</b> should exist, if it is a genre of music, if it's is a fashion-style, etc.

Work is being ravenously deleted all the time. You'll get sad thinking about it.

</p><p>Templates</p>
<div>
  <p>what about all this stuff →</p>
  <p><img src="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/assets/infobox.png">
</p></div><p>
You're right.

Wikipedia has good structured-data in <b>infoboxes, lists, tables, citations, etc</b>.

The issue is, as of Feb 2019, Wikipedia has <b>634,755 different kinds of templates</b> (see this <a href="https://s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/spencer-scratch/allTemplates-2018-10-26.tsv">21mb download</a>).

Yes, there are all different.

Yes, there are <span>templates-within-templates-with-escaping-with-escaping</span>.

Even if you parse them perfectly, how do you know that for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:HorseDeathYear">Template:HorseDeathYear</a>, the third parameter is the <b>birth date of the horse</b>, and the fourth is the birth-month?

see, for example:

• <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:16-Team_bracket_templates">Tennis Brackets vs Table Tennis Brackets</a>

• '<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:Birth_date_and_age">Birth_date_and_age</a>' vs '<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:Birth-date_and_age">Birth-date_and_age</a>'.

• <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Template:Trapezoidnotation">a template for a Trapezoid unicode symbol</a>
It's just a straight-up mess.

If you're thinking, <i>gee wikipedia editors must feel exhausted and stupid</i> - you're right.

<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Special:WhatLinksHere/Template:Retired&amp;limit=500">Many</a>…</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/index.html">http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/index.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://blog.spencermounta.in/2019/wikipedias-in-trouble/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25300942</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 10:41:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I made 24 high-quality Covid illustrations. Free for commercial and personal use]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 307 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25300594">thread link</a>) | @andyydao
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://www.pixeltrue.com/frontliner-heroes | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.pixeltrue.com/frontliner-heroes">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
  
<div data-collapse="small" data-animation="default" data-duration="400" role="banner"><div data-w-id="829bd4f8-a52c-9bed-f351-1f1c429ebfb2"><p><a href="#" id="w-node-1f1c429ebfb3-a3ea6df0"><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50a7fc8b859794cc27d27_COVID%20Logo.svg" loading="lazy" alt=""></a></p><div id="w-node-1f1c429ebfb6-a3ea6df0"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50a7fc8b859446ec27d28_Logo%20no%20background.png" loading="lazy" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 100vw, (max-width: 1439px) 20px, (max-width: 1919px) 25px, 30px" srcset="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50a7fc8b859446ec27d28_Logo%2520no%2520background-p-500.png 500w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50a7fc8b859446ec27d28_Logo%2520no%2520background-p-800.png 800w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50a7fc8b859446ec27d28_Logo%2520no%2520background-p-1080.png 1080w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50a7fc8b859446ec27d28_Logo%20no%20background.png 1214w" alt=""></p></div></div></div><div><div data-w-id="f1207815-d48c-2550-8aa6-2af2cd0d2c1b"><p data-w-id="f1207815-d48c-2550-8aa6-2af2cd0d2c1c">Frontliner Heroes</p><p>24 high-quality Covid illustrations. Free for commercial and personal use.</p></div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50b2c6728188179a7570d_Hero%20Illustration.svg" loading="eager" width="462" data-w-id="f1207815-d48c-2550-8aa6-2af2cd0d2c20" alt=""><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50b2c672818d125a7570c_Background.svg" loading="lazy" data-w-id="f1207815-d48c-2550-8aa6-2af2cd0d2c21" alt=""></p></div><div><div><div><div><p>Frontliner Heroes comes with exciting scenes that are commonly used to stop the spread of COVID. In addition, we'll be continually adding new illustration to this pack!</p></div></div></div></div><div><p><h2>24 Illustrations to fight against COVID!</h2></p></div><div><div><h2>Sample Applications</h2><p>These illustrations are perfect for any type of project. Simply Drag and drop them in and you're ready to go!</p></div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50b4456b3fd49b0f42063_Sample%20Applications.svg" loading="eager" alt=""></p></div><div><p><h2>Awesome Features</h2></p><div id="benefits"><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50b54fe9410cacea1ebe4_Group%2084.png" alt=""></p><div><h3>Fully Vector<br></h3><p>All illustrations are fully vector meaning you can enlarge illustrations without quality loss<br></p></div></div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50b54fe94105ee6a1ebe8_Group%20174.svg" alt=""></p><div><h3>Customizable<br></h3><p>Easily change illustration scenes to match your brand using common programs like Sketch and Figma.<br></p></div></div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5dd3495558fd7f3d1fcb52bc/5fc50b54fe9410876ca1ebe6_Group%20148.png" alt=""></p><div><h3>Different File Formats<br></h3><p>With our Frontliners pack you'll get access to all source files - this includes SVG, PNG&nbsp;and AI&nbsp;files.<br></p></div></div></div></div></div><!--[if lte IE 9]><script src="//cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/placeholders/3.0.2/placeholders.min.js"></script><![endif]-->





<!-- Memberstack --> 
 








<meta name="p:domain_verify" content="efd5329f8b1be336c6381d60a312999c">



<!-- Facebook Pixel Code -->


<!-- End Facebook Pixel Code -->


<!-- Global site tag (gtag.js) - Google Analytics -->














</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.pixeltrue.com/frontliner-heroes</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25300594</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 09:40:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Self-host your fonts for better performance]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 577 | Comments 386 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25300396">thread link</a>) | @zwacky
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://wicki.io/posts/2020-11-goodbye-google-fonts/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wicki.io/posts/2020-11-goodbye-google-fonts/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<div>
  <div>
    <div>
      
      <p>
        
          November 30, 2020
        
      </p>

      <figure>
    <img src="https://wicki.io/posts/2020-11-goodbye-google-fonts/goodbye-google-fonts.jpg" alt="Google Fonts"> 
</figure>

<p>I’ve used Google Fonts in prototypes and in 10M+ MAU products. It’s incredibly easy to get started with and provides an amazing font discovery. That’s also why it’s currently still used on over <a href="https://trends.builtwith.com/websitelist/Google-Font-API">42M websites</a>!</p>
<p>This convenience has its price: Performance. Many <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/fast-google-fonts-with-cloudflare-workers/">have</a> <a href="https://medium.com/clio-calliope/making-google-fonts-faster-aadf3c02a36d">already</a> <a href="https://www.keycdn.com/blog/web-font-performance#disadvantages-of-web-fonts">pointed</a> <a href="https://blog.logrocket.com/self-hosted-fonts-vs-google-fonts-api/">out</a> the cost of multiple requests. If you want the remaining speed boost, then you’re best off downloading your used Google Fonts and self-host them.</p>
<p>This is nothing new. In fact it’s been advocated already for years. Even Google themselves <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mv-l3-tJgGk&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=24m58s">advised others to self-host fonts</a> in their Google I/O ‘18 talk about web performance.</p>
<h2 id="self-hosting-fonts-vs-google-fonts">Self-hosting fonts vs Google Fonts</h2>
<p>By nature Google Fonts, even with all its font and CSS optimisations, can’t be faster than self-hosted fonts.</p>
<p>Sia wrote <a href="https://medium.com/clio-calliope/making-google-fonts-faster-aadf3c02a36d">a great post</a> where she compared the performance between Google Fonts and self-hosted fonts without the impact of a CDN.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://wicki.io/posts/2020-11-goodbye-google-fonts/with-google-fonts.png" alt="Network flow with Google Fonts"> <figcaption>
            <p>Optimised Google Fonts loading with preconnect</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
    <img src="https://wicki.io/posts/2020-11-goodbye-google-fonts/without-google-fonts.png" alt="Network flow with self-hosting fonts"> <figcaption>
            <p>Optimised self-hosting fonts with preload</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<hr>
<h2 id="the-old-performance-argument">The old performance argument</h2>
<p>So if the bottom-line performance is in self-hosting fonts’ favour: What was the argument that convinced us developers that Google Fonts is at least as performing as the self-host approach?</p>
<p>Google Fonts was designed to be distributed on a global CDN and reap the caching benefits from it. Users request fonts via said CDN. Chances are that they have downloaded the font resources at an earlier point already from a different site.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“[…] Our cross-site caching is designed so that you only need to load a font once, with any website, and we’ll use that same cached font on any other website that uses Google Fonts.”</p>
<p>— <a href="https://fonts.google.com/about">https://fonts.google.com/about</a></p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="invalidating-the-old-performance-argument">Invalidating the old performance argument</h2>
<p>Since Chrome v86, released October 2020, cross-site resources like fonts can’t be shared on the same CDN anymore. This is due to the partitioned browser cache (Safari has had this for years already).</p>
<p>In <a href="https://developers.google.com/web/updates/2020/10/http-cache-partitioning">this Google post</a> they explain what the partitioned browser cache is. It got only introduced to prevent a possible cross-site tracking mechanism.</p>
<h2 id="cache-partitioning-in-other-browsers">Cache partitioning in other browsers</h2>
<p>Safari really cares about privacy. It circumvented this very cross-site tracking attack for years already. Then finally comes Chrome. Other browsers that are based off Chromium, still need to signal or implement the feature.</p>
<ul>
<li>✅ <strong>Chrome</strong>: since v86 (October 2020)</li>
<li>✅ <strong>Safari</strong>: since 2013</li>
<li>🚫 <strong>Firefox</strong>: planning to implement</li>
<li>🚫 <strong>Edge</strong>: most likely soon</li>
<li>🚫 <strong>Opera</strong>: most likely soon</li>
<li>🚫 <strong>Brave</strong>: most likely soon</li>
<li>🚫 <strong>Vivaldi</strong>: most likely soon</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Google Fonts resources will be redownloaded for every website, regardless it being cached on the CDN. Self-host your fonts for better performance. The old performance argument is not valid anymore.</p>
<p>Thanks for checking this post out!</p>


      
      <hr><div>
  <p><img src="https://wicki.io/images/me_huc890d15b6e9f2ce8978e9aa27127dd5e_67203_350x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" alt="Simon Wicki">
    
  </p>

  <div>
    <div>
      <p>
        <strong>Simon Wicki</strong> is a Freelance Frontend Developer in
				Berlin. Passionate and fluent in Vue, Angular, React and Ionic. Interested in 
				Tech, frontend &amp; non-fiction books
      </p>
      <p>
        <a href="https://twitter.com/zwacky" onclick="ga('send', 'event', 'clickout', 'bottom_cta', '\/posts\/2020-11-goodbye-google-fonts\/')" target="_blank">
          <img src="https://wicki.io/images/svg/twitter.svg" alt="Twitter" title="Twitter">
          Follow @zwacky
        </a>
      </p>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

    </div>
  </div>
</div>


        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wicki.io/posts/2020-11-goodbye-google-fonts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25300396</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 09:01:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Project Loom and Structured Concurrency]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 166 | Comments 97 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25300233">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
December 4, 2020 | https://www.javaadvent.com/2020/12/project-loom-and-structured-concurrency.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.javaadvent.com/2020/12/project-loom-and-structured-concurrency.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
							
<h2>Why Loom?</h2>
<p>In 1998, it was amazing that the Sun Java Web Server (the precursor of Tomcat) ran each request in a separate thread, and not an OS process. It was able to serve thousands of concurrent requests this way! Nowadays, that’s not so amazing. Each thread takes up a significant amount of memory, and you can’t have millions of threads on a typical server.</p>
<p>That’s why the modern mantra of server-side programming is: “Never block!” Instead, you specify what should happen once the data is available.</p>
<p>This asynchronous programming style is great for servers, allowing them to handily support millions of concurrent requests. It isn’t so great for programmers.</p>
<p>Here is an asynchronous request with the <code>HttpClient</code> API:</p>
<pre>HttpClient.newBuilder()
   .build()
   .sendAsync(request, HttpResponse.BodyHandlers.ofString())
   .thenAccept(response -&gt; . . .);
   .thenApply(. . .);
   .exceptionally(. . .);
</pre>
<p>What we would normally achieve with statements is now encoded as method calls. If we loved this style of programming, we would not have statements in our programming language and merrily code in Lisp.</p>
<p>In JavaScript, code tagged as “async” is rewritten into method calls like the ones that you’ve just seen. But that means you can only call async methods from other async methods, and your API splits into a sync and an async part, forcing you to duplicate functionality.</p>

<p>Project Loom takes its guidance from languages such as Erlang and Go, attacking the root of the problem by making blocking very cheap. You run tasks in “virtual threads”, a nearly unlimited resource that is mapped into actual “carrier” threads. When a virtual thread blocks, it is “parked” and another virtual thread runs on the carrier thread. The name is supposed to remind you of virtual memory that is mapped to actual RAM.</p>
<p>Before you complain about the name, remember that naming is hard. The Loom team previously tried “fiber”, but it is already used elsewhere with a slightly different meaning. And “lightweight” or “new” thread might look foolish when something lighter-weight or newer comes along.</p>
<p>After experimenting with separate classes for OS threads and virtual threads, they ended up deciding to use a single class for both—the familiar <code>java.lang.Thread</code>—in order to ease migration.</p>
<p>Of course, good old <code>java.lang.Thread</code>, which has been around for 25 years, ever since Java 1.0, has its share of cruft. Awkward cancellation, thread groups, priorities, depreceated methods <code>stop</code>,<code>suspend</code>, <code>resume</code>. The Loom team felt that these liabilities were minor since most programmers never explicitly use the <code>Thread</code> API but launch tasks with an <code>ExecutorService</code>. (Of course, the same argument would support coming up with a cleaner virtual thread API instead.)</p>
<p>If you have been around for a very long time, you may remember that early versions of Java had “green threads” that were mapped to an OS thread. However, there is a crucial difference. When a green thread blocked, its carrier thread was also blocked, preventing all other green threads from making progress.</p>

<p>You can download binaries of Project Loom at <a href="http://jdk.java.net/loom/">http://jdk.java.net/loom/</a>. They are updated regularly.</p>
<p>As already mentioned, a virtual thread is an object of the <code>Thread</code> class. Here are three ways of producing fibers. First, there is a new factory method that constructs and starts a virtual thread:</p>
<pre>Thread thread = Thread.startVirtualThread(runnable);
  // <cite>Note that the thread is already started</cite></pre>
<p>This is good for demos, tutorials or quick-and-dirty experiments in JShell.</p>
<p>For more customization, there is a builder API:</p>
<pre>Thread thread = Thread.builder()
   .virtual()
   .name(taskname)
   .task(runnable)
   .build();</pre>
<p>However, as you have been told for many years now, it is better to use an executor service than to manually construct <code>Thread</code> instances. The static method <code>Executors.newVirtualThreadExecutor()</code> provides one. (The existing executor services are not useful for virtual threads. It would be counterproductive to pool them!)</p>
<p>For example,</p>
<pre>ExecutorService exec = Executors.newVirtualThreadExecutor();
exec.submit(runnable1);
exec.submit(runnable2);
</pre>
<p>As with the other factory methods in the <code>Executors</code> class, you can optionally supply a <code>ThreadFactory</code>. And the new <code>Thread.Builder</code> class has an easy way to provide a factory, instead of a single instance:</p>
<pre>ThreadFactory factory = Thread.builder()
   .virtual()
   .name(taskname)
   .task(runnable)
   .<b>factory()</b>;

ExecutorService exec = Executors.newThreadExecutor(factory);
</pre>
<p>Let’s try this out. As a first test, we just sleep in each task.</p>
<pre>import java.util.concurrent.*;

public class Test {
   public static int DELAY = 10_000;
   public static int NTASKS = 1_000_000;

   public static void run(Object obj) {
      try {
         Thread.sleep((int) (DELAY * Math.random()));
      } catch (InterruptedException ex) {
         ex.printStackTrace();
      }
      System.out.println(obj);
   }

   public static void main(String[] args) {
      ExecutorService exec = Executors.newVirtualThreadExecutor();
      for (int i = 1; i &lt;= NTASKS; i++) {
         String taskname = "task-" + i;
         exec.submit(() -&gt; run(taskname));
      }
      exec.close();
   }
}
</pre>
<p>Run the program and it just works. Then try using OS threads—change to <code>Executors.newCachedThreadPool()</code> or <code>Executors.newFixedThreadPool(NTASKS)</code>. The program will run out of memory; on my laptop, after about 25,000 threads.</p>
<p>Ok, but in practice, you don’t want to sleep, but do useful work. Consider a program adapted from one of <a href="https://www.javaspecialists.eu/about/heinz/">Heinz Kabutz</a>‘ puzzlers, The program fetches a daily image, from Dilbert or Wikimedia. It consists of classes <a href="http://horstmann.com/unblog/2019-07-27/dailyImages/ImageProcessor.java"><code>ImageProcessor</code></a> and <a href="http://horstmann.com/unblog/2019-07-27/dailyImages/ImageInfo.java"><code>ImageInfo</code></a>. The code is an impenetrable maze of twisty passages, all alike (i.e. helper functions yielding completable futures).</p>
<p>With virtual threads, simply read web contents synchronously. It blocks, but we don’t care. All the complexity goes away. The control flow is simple and comprehensible.</p>
<pre>exec.submit(() -&gt; {
    String pageURL = info.getUrlForDate(date);
    String page = getSync(pageURL, HttpResponse.BodyHandlers.ofString());
    String imageURL = info.findImage(page).getImagePath();
    byte[] image = getSync(imageURL, HttpResponse.BodyHandlers.ofByteArray());
    info.setImageData(image);
    process(info);
    return null;
});</pre>
<p>Here is the simplified <a href="http://horstmann.com/unblog/2020-12-05/dailyImages/ImageProcessor.java"><code>ImageProcessor</code></a> code.</p>
<p><b>Pro tip: </b>The statement <code>return null;</code> makes the lambda into a <code>Callable</code> instead of a <code>Runnable</code>, so that you don’t have to catch checked exceptions 😜</p>
<p>Try this out with something you care about. Call web services and make database connections, without worrying about callbacks. When blocking is cheap, a whole lot of accidental complexity goes away. Of course, to use this in a web app framework, you’ll have to wait for your framework provider to run your code in virtual threads.</p>
<h2>Structured Concurrency</h2>
<p>In <a href="https://vorpus.org/blog/notes-on-structured-concurrency-or-go-statement-considered-harmful/">this highly recommended article</a> (from which the images below are taken), Nathaniel Smith proposes structured forms of concurrency. Here is his central argument. Launching a task in a new thread is really no better than programming with GOTO, i.e. harmful:</p>
<pre>new Thread(runnable).start();</pre>
<p><img src="http://horstmann.com/unblog/2019-12-05/sequential-and-go-to-schematic.svg" alt=".svg" width="38%"></p>
<p>When multiple threads run without coordination, it’s spaghetti code all over again. In the 1960s, structured programming replaced <code>goto</code> with branches, loops, and functions:</p>
<p><img src="http://horstmann.com/unblog/2019-12-05/control-schematics.svg" alt=".svg" width="42%"></p>
<p>When you look at a line of code, you know how the program got there.</p>
<p>Structured concurrency does the same for concurrent tasks. We should know, from reading the program text, when they all finish.</p>
<p><img src="http://horstmann.com/unblog/2019-12-05/nursery-schematic-unlabeled.svg" alt=".svg" width="30%"></p>
<p>That way we can control the resources that the tasks use, and we know when it is time to move on.</p>
<p>In Loom, the <code>ExecutorService</code> implements this basic construct. <code>ExecutorService</code> has a <code>close</code> method that blocks until all of its virtual threads have completed. (I used this method in the first sample program to keep <code>main</code> alive until all virtual threads are done. In the past, you had to call the <code>awaitTermination</code> method instead.)</p>
<p>Conveniently, <code>ExecutorService</code> implements the <code>AutoCloseable</code> interface, so that you can just use a <code>try</code>-with-resources statement:</p>
<pre>try (ExecutorService exec = Executor.newVirtualThreadExecutor()) {
   for (int i = 0; i &lt; NTASKS; i++) {
      exec.schedule(() -&gt; run(i));
   }
} // <cite>Blocks until all threads completed</cite>
</pre>
<p>I wrote a simple web crawler as a demonstration of virtual threads—here is the <a href="http://horstmann.com/unblog/2020-12-05/Crawler.java"><code>Crawler</code></a> class. In my first attempt, I fired off a new virtual thread for each URL in a page. If I had wanted to become Google, I could have let my crawler run forever. But I wanted to go no more than 3 hops from the starting point. With “fire and forget”, there is no way of knowing when the recursion is done.</p>
<p>Instead, for each page, I make a new executor service and wait for completion. That way, the whole program completes when all pages have been crawled.</p>
<p>This seems a lot of blocking. But in Loom, blocking is cheap, so we shouldn’t worry about that.</p>
<p>We are used to having one executor service as thread pool for all our tasks. But in Loom, you are encouraged to use a separate executor service for each task set.</p>
<h2>Deadlines</h2>
<p>When crawling the web, you are likely to encounter dead links. Reading from one should time out eventually, but it can take surprisingly long.</p>
<p>The standard remedy is, of course, to provide a timeout. Loom prefers deadlines to timeouts, so you specify</p>
<pre>ExecutorService exec = Executors.newVirtualThreadExecutor().withDeadline(
   Instant.now().plus(30, ChronoUnit.SECONDS))
</pre>
<p>Why deadlines? In general, timeouts compose poorly. Suppose you have to accomplish two sequential tasks with an overall timeout of 10 seconds. You don’t want to give each of the tasks a timeout of 5 seconds. After all, if one takes 6 seconds and the other 3 seconds, you still come in under the finish line. To get the timeout of the second task, you’d have to measure the duration of the first task and subtract that from the overall timeout. With deadlines, it is much simpler. Each task gets the same deadline.</p>
<p>The call <code>exec.close()</code> blocks until all virtual threads have completed or the …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.javaadvent.com/2020/12/project-loom-and-structured-concurrency.html">https://www.javaadvent.com/2020/12/project-loom-and-structured-concurrency.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.javaadvent.com/2020/12/project-loom-and-structured-concurrency.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25300233</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 08:24:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Monoliths as a Service]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 111 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25299598">thread link</a>) | @gdeglin
<br/>
December 3, 2020 | https://www.themostfamousartist.com/maas | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.themostfamousartist.com/maas">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-nc-base="header" data-controller="AncillaryLayout">
      

      

      <div>

        

        <div>
          
            
              
                
                  
                
              
            
          

          <main>
            
              <section data-content-field="main-content">
                <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1607097261878" id="page-5fc97f1d887b444c614b8d8c"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_3851"><div><h2>Monoliths</h2><h2>-as-a-</h2><h2>Service</h2><p>We are the global <a href="https://community.themostfamousartist.com/">creative community</a> behind the most headline-worthy art stunts in the world…</p></div></div><div><div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_9210"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607041819948-XGLKS00TJZNS7Q9Y5B2A/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKgzHX-v50OZTetcbLmgWuUUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcUecxn97ackQPp7vN6eXy76HeX13iayLWBPrh_wlieguDDFqElwGSvRuYqUGd2Qj9/En4H_GdVQAEbxof.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607041819948-XGLKS00TJZNS7Q9Y5B2A/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKgzHX-v50OZTetcbLmgWuUUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8N_N4V1vUb5AoIIIbLZhVYxCRW4BPu10St3TBAUQYVKcUecxn97ackQPp7vN6eXy76HeX13iayLWBPrh_wlieguDDFqElwGSvRuYqUGd2Qj9/En4H_GdVQAEbxof.jpg" data-image-dimensions="1100x619" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="En4H_GdVQAEbxof.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc9831ae262c01594584f4a" data-type="image" src="https://www.themostfamousartist.com/En4H_GdVQAEbxof.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="56.47279549718574" data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_11756"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607042187227-P8AU33UQURGTAANT1YC8/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kM8bRIq_Jlpy-TzDnLsZvCFZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpza1AxxNfjW7BkJnaaYjyko9vKUJGGjt8ug7pUBGdtLuGURcg7iOHM7Nr4qX47O0bg/Screen+Shot+2020-12-03+at+5.32.18+PM.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607042187227-P8AU33UQURGTAANT1YC8/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kM8bRIq_Jlpy-TzDnLsZvCFZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpza1AxxNfjW7BkJnaaYjyko9vKUJGGjt8ug7pUBGdtLuGURcg7iOHM7Nr4qX47O0bg/Screen+Shot+2020-12-03+at+5.32.18+PM.png" data-image-dimensions="710x663" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Screen Shot 2020-12-03 at 5.32.18 PM.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc98488be6684539de0aaf9" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607042187227-P8AU33UQURGTAANT1YC8/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kM8bRIq_Jlpy-TzDnLsZvCFZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpza1AxxNfjW7BkJnaaYjyko9vKUJGGjt8ug7pUBGdtLuGURcg7iOHM7Nr4qX47O0bg/Screen+Shot+2020-12-03+at+5.32.18+PM.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_27247"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607042450189-ITWLCGYG711MYOL884GL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kB4r0hTEGhin2obdF0zE7a5Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzms-7abpVor2v0Z_jpb6HxwUXnH_MpeGSWjCARzTWV2WkfmJhGMIgLexgogVlDfN4/image002.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607042450189-ITWLCGYG711MYOL884GL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kB4r0hTEGhin2obdF0zE7a5Zw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzms-7abpVor2v0Z_jpb6HxwUXnH_MpeGSWjCARzTWV2WkfmJhGMIgLexgogVlDfN4/image002.png" data-image-dimensions="600x319" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="image002.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc9858f8562787517514285" data-type="image" src="https://www.themostfamousartist.com/image002.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="111.9186046511628" data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_37744"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607042839081-56GDULGPEO49ENLEB75H/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEJc2EGurRIpVfMw4geeYwYUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdLkWgqQttFkESsR54W-Vo-DqQFSZr6WbDVTBl4dDuN6FCj7ScNggbDYsBK08KsWg4Y/unnamed.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607042839081-56GDULGPEO49ENLEB75H/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kEJc2EGurRIpVfMw4geeYwYUqsxRUqqbr1mOJYKfIPR7LoDQ9mXPOjoJoqy81S2I8GRo6ASst2s6pLvNAu_PZdLkWgqQttFkESsR54W-Vo-DqQFSZr6WbDVTBl4dDuN6FCj7ScNggbDYsBK08KsWg4Y/unnamed.png" data-image-dimensions="685x1069" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="unnamed.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc98713fedaa13a4859642c" data-type="image" src="https://www.themostfamousartist.com/unnamed.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="74.10881801125704" data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_100133"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043738456-SDNZQKP2DZ10HUJD0CNW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kK60W-ob1oA2Fm-j4E_9NQB7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0kD6Ec8Uq9YczfrzwR7e2Mh5VMMOxnTbph8FXiclivDQnof69TlCeE0rAhj6HUpXkw/image-asset.jpeg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043738456-SDNZQKP2DZ10HUJD0CNW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kK60W-ob1oA2Fm-j4E_9NQB7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0kD6Ec8Uq9YczfrzwR7e2Mh5VMMOxnTbph8FXiclivDQnof69TlCeE0rAhj6HUpXkw/image-asset.jpeg" data-image-dimensions="2500x3333" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc98a93be6684539de1ae1c" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043738456-SDNZQKP2DZ10HUJD0CNW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kK60W-ob1oA2Fm-j4E_9NQB7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0kD6Ec8Uq9YczfrzwR7e2Mh5VMMOxnTbph8FXiclivDQnof69TlCeE0rAhj6HUpXkw/image-asset.jpeg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div><div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_102695"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043772160-6AJ9ZOMWE3ANBTUQ6L7B/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLB_yMpT-58X960ldGXfhF97gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UfUt7F94jAuNcGuXWqaIgpmYtJRtNO6b9ISO5qSF_BivoRwB-dUGsSquCnVTFQcaRg/Screen+Shot+2020-12-03+at+6.02.34+PM.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043772160-6AJ9ZOMWE3ANBTUQ6L7B/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLB_yMpT-58X960ldGXfhF97gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UfUt7F94jAuNcGuXWqaIgpmYtJRtNO6b9ISO5qSF_BivoRwB-dUGsSquCnVTFQcaRg/Screen+Shot+2020-12-03+at+6.02.34+PM.png" data-image-dimensions="2242x1656" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Screen Shot 2020-12-03 at 6.02.34 PM.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc98ab281b71b40858d52d6" data-type="image" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043772160-6AJ9ZOMWE3ANBTUQ6L7B/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kLB_yMpT-58X960ldGXfhF97gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UfUt7F94jAuNcGuXWqaIgpmYtJRtNO6b9ISO5qSF_BivoRwB-dUGsSquCnVTFQcaRg/Screen+Shot+2020-12-03+at+6.02.34+PM.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="86.11632270168855" data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_113021"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043820963-AXDZ2HUID2Q5XIXG8OFN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKmibDOp36EpI-R8w230T2h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmFrKkuyfqIWRdt3lCufLMAX0Qfwyuk7RFPSxNYhV3IXAEkgv7Qmv4u2TS9vWgjv5P/EoWgkDoU8AEHjxE.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043820963-AXDZ2HUID2Q5XIXG8OFN/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKmibDOp36EpI-R8w230T2h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmFrKkuyfqIWRdt3lCufLMAX0Qfwyuk7RFPSxNYhV3IXAEkgv7Qmv4u2TS9vWgjv5P/EoWgkDoU8AEHjxE.jpg" data-image-dimensions="1241x1598" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="EoWgkDoU8AEHjxE.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc98aeae262c0159459c0cc" data-type="image" src="https://www.themostfamousartist.com/EoWgkDoU8AEHjxE.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="86.67917448405254" data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607040806507_124725"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043851605-G5OT65D8N3HOWGDX05U5/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kB80eW4KK5wgMfkTp6SjTNtZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxkEDnlqEYEiGVDb0kl5jpOJsm5iyfgdjNZyk67t96-U_4JMfIDDY8RGcVnRlrKExA/En86BBMXYAE9bUh.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/545815c3e4b0c42e0d7a6235/1607043851605-G5OT65D8N3HOWGDX05U5/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kB80eW4KK5wgMfkTp6SjTNtZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpxkEDnlqEYEiGVDb0kl5jpOJsm5iyfgdjNZyk67t96-U_4JMfIDDY8RGcVnRlrKExA/En86BBMXYAE9bUh.jpg" data-image-dimensions="600x800" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="En86BBMXYAE9bUh.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5fc98b0b2ae1264a0389776a" data-type="image" src="https://www.themostfamousartist.com/En86BBMXYAE9bUh.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607045462369_157150"><p><h2>Now that we have your attention…</h2></p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1607045462369_69251"><div><p>We are pleased to offer a small group of collectors </p><p>the opportunity to purchase an authentic alien monolith </p><p>from the studio of </p><p>“The Most Famous Artist”</p></div></div></div></div></div>
              </section>
            
          </main>

        </div>
      </div>

      


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.themostfamousartist.com/maas</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25299598</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 06:22:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Faroe Island roundabout under the Atlantic Ocean]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 93 | Comments 61 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25299574">thread link</a>) | @sohkamyung
<br/>
December 3, 2020 | https://nordfra.dk/faroe-island-first-roundabout-in-the-world-under-the-atlantic-ocean/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nordfra.dk/faroe-island-first-roundabout-in-the-world-under-the-atlantic-ocean/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<div id="content">

<div>
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main" role="main">

			
<article id="post-1224" class="page">
	<!-- .entry-header -->
	<div>
		<p><img src="http://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o.jpg" alt="" width="2000" height="829" srcset="https://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o.jpg 2000w, https://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o-300x124.jpg 300w, https://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o-1024x424.jpg 1024w, https://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o-768x318.jpg 768w, https://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o-1536x637.jpg 1536w, https://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o-250x104.jpg 250w, https://nordfra.dk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/128669834_3552788624799306_5681539663523713154_o-350x145.jpg 350w" sizes="(max-width: 767px) 89vw, (max-width: 1000px) 54vw, (max-width: 1071px) 543px, 580px"></p>
<p>The Eysturoyartunnilin (or Eysturoy Tunnel, earlier known as Skálafjarðartunnilin) is a large infrastructure project which connects the island of Streymoy to the island of Eysturoy through a sub-sea road tunnel under the Tangafjørður sound in the Faroe Islands. It also crosses the southern part of Skálafjørður and connects the towns of Runavík on the eastern side and Strendur on the western side of the fjord. Altogether, the three-branch sub-sea tunnel measures 11.24 kilometres (6.8 miles) long, including an underwater roundabout. Construction costs are estimated to be around a billion DKK. It will open for traffic in December 2020.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->
</article><!-- #post-1224 -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</div><!-- #primary -->
</div><!-- .wrap -->


		</div><!-- #content -->

		<!-- #colophon -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nordfra.dk/faroe-island-first-roundabout-in-the-world-under-the-atlantic-ocean/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25299574</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 06:18:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How I Manage My Random Daily Notes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 204 | Comments 173 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25299442">thread link</a>) | @hachibu
<br/>
December 3, 2020 | https://hachibu.net/posts/2020/how-i-manage-my-random-daily-notes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hachibu.net/posts/2020/how-i-manage-my-random-daily-notes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><img src="https://hachibu.net/posts/2020/how-i-manage-my-random-daily-notes/images/featured.png"><figcaption><p>Illustration: Hachibu</p></figcaption></figure><p>For years, I kept track of random notes by creating a text or Markdown
file on my desktop. And at the end of the day, I would delete that file and
start over again the next day. Inspired by the minimalism of <a href="https://github.com/todotxt/todo.txt-cli">todo-txt-cli</a>,
I created a similar system to manage my own notes.</p><p>Keep reading for more details or skip to the code: <a href="https://github.com/hachibu/note.sh">github.com/hachibu/note.sh</a>.</p><h4 id="introduction">Introduction</h4><p>As I mentioned before, I used to keep a single notes file on my desktop, and I
would delete it everyday. I would use this notes file to keep track of random
thoughts and details related to my work and personal life. My notes file might
contain code snippets from work, inspirational quotes, or it might have my
latest and greatest open-source software idea, or maybe even the beginning of a
new blog post. Anyway, I loved the simplicity of it, and I didn’t want any more
apps, databases or logins in my life.</p><p>But it wasn’t until I started using <a href="https://github.com/todotxt/todo.txt-cli">todo-txt-cli</a>
that I considered writing a script to manage my own notes. The brilliant part
about <code>todo-txt-cli</code> is that it’s just text files stored in my Dropbox and a
small shell script to interface with those files.</p><p>Inspired by the minimalism of <code>todo-txt-cli</code>, I built <a href="https://github.com/hachibu/note.sh">note.sh</a>.
In total, the entire project consists of 1 Bash script, 1 environment variable
to configure the notes directory and 1 symlink to install it to your
<code>/usr/local/bin</code> directory.</p><h4 id="how-it-works">How It Works</h4><p>The way it works is that every time I run the script, it opens the note for that
day in my editor of choice. For example, if today was December 2, 2020 then the
script would open a file named <code>2020-12-02.md</code> in the notes directory.</p><p>I use Vim as my editor, and I have my notes stored on Dropbox so I can access
them on all of my computers. So, my shell RC file looks like this.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="shell"><span>export</span> <span>EDITOR</span><span>=</span><span>"vim"</span>
<span>export</span> <span>NOTE_DIR</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>$HOME</span><span>/Dropbox/Notes"</span>
</code></pre></div><p>And my Dropbox directory looks like this.</p><p><img src="https://hachibu.net/posts/2020/how-i-manage-my-random-daily-notes/images/dropbox-screenshot.png" alt="Dropbox Screenshot"></p><p>For searching, the script accepts a pattern and runs a recursive grep over the
notes directory. I chose grep because I use this script on both Mac and Linux,
and I wanted the script to be as portable as possible.</p><h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4><p>I’ve been using this script for several months across several computers, and I
still love it. I don’t search as often as I thought I would, but it’s comforting
to know it’s all there if I need it. I also ended up creating an alias for my
script so all I need to type is the letter <code>n</code> to run the script.</p><p>In the future, I’d like to add a test suite to the code base, figure out how
to create a Homebrew formula, and add archiving for older notes.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hachibu.net/posts/2020/how-i-manage-my-random-daily-notes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25299442</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 05:51:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[That Dothraki Horde, Part I: Barbarian Couture]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 117 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25299176">thread link</a>) | @parsecs
<br/>
December 3, 2020 | https://acoup.blog/2020/12/04/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-i-barbarian-couture/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2020/12/04/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-i-barbarian-couture/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>This is the first part of a three part (II, III) look at the Dothraki, the fictional horse-borne nomads of the <em>Game of Thrones</em> / <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> series and the degree to which George R.R. Martin’s claim that they are “an amalgam of a number of steppe and plains cultures” holds up to scrutiny.  This is something that I have been suggesting I would get to since (checks notes),<a href="https://acoup.blog/2019/05/04/new-acquisitions-that-dothraki-charge/"> May.  Of Last Year.</a>  So it is about time we actually get to it.</p>



<p>The plan is for this series to run in three parts.  Part I (this part) will discuss how the Dothraki <em>look</em> in the setting.  Part II will look at broader questions of social organization and culture (I am nearly certain this is one of those cases where there will be a IIa and a IIb, but my hope for brevity springs eternal).  Part III will look at military culture.  In all three parts I am going to use both the books and the show – noting where they diverge – in part because the heaviest characterization the Dothraki got in the show was when Martin was still significantly involved with it (meaning that large parts of it likely still reflect his vision), but also because the show is how the vast majority of people experience this particular fiction.  Both the original text and the show derived from it deserve to have their vision discussed.</p>



<p>As always, if you like what you are reading here, please share it; if you really like it, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreon</a>. And if you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or military history musings.</p>






<p>First, a <strong>content warning for this series</strong>: this is discussing <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> and <em>Game of Thrones</em> which features a lot of content which is not G-rated.  More to the point, it is a discussion of what – I will argue – Martin presents as one of, if not the most brutal and sexually violent society in that setting.  And that means those themes are going to come up here (less in this essay, but more in the other parts); we are going to remain serious and adult about those things of course, but they will be a part of this analysis nonetheless.  If that is not for you, by all means feel free to check out for a few weeks.</p>



<p>Before we get into the main point, <strong>I want to note that I am going to reference my series on the <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/01/17/collections-the-fremen-mirage-part-i-war-at-the-dawn-of-civilization/">Fremen Mirage</a> <em>a lot</em> here</strong>, because there is a lot of Fremen stuff going on with how Dothraki society is depicted.  As a result, it may be useful to go back and read those, but just to recap, we may define the Fremen Mirage this way:</p>



<p><a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/02/21/collections-the-fremen-mirage-interlude-ways-of-the-fremen/"><strong>The Fremen Mirage is a literary trope, <em>unconnected to historical reality</em>, which presents societies as a contrast between unsophisticated, but morally pure, hyper-masculine and militarily effective ‘strong men’ societies honed by ‘hard times’ (that is, the Fremen of the term) and a sophisticated but effeminate and decadent ‘weak men’ societies weakened by ‘good times,’ frequently with an implicit assertion of the superior worth of the former.</strong></a></p>



<p>Next, a note on citation here from the books.  My understanding is that different printings of the books have different pagination, which seems to be why the Wiki of Ice and Fire cites by chapter numbers (except that the chapters of the books, as printed, <em>aren’t numbered</em> in the print editions I’ve seen, making this classical-style citation extremely cumbersome and inexact).  I am going to cite by the page numbers of my edition, which is the 2011 Bantam Books Trade Paperback Edition (the box set).  Hopefully that will be enough.</p>



<p>Finally, a note on my expertise here.  <strong>I am not a scholar of either the peoples of the Eurasian Steppe or the American Great Plains</strong>.  The former group does intrude into my period and study, as steppe nomads, in the form of Scythians, Sarmatians and Huns did interact (sometimes peacefully, sometimes violently) with the broader Mediterranean world.  Consequently, my knowledge of steppe peoples tend to be better that my knowledge of the Native American peoples of the Great Plains, but I have tried, within the limits of time and availability, to do my research. <strong> I actually think, in a strange sense, this is useful, because my own initial unfamiliarity with the topic has demonstrated to me just how <em>basic</em> the level of research and reading necessary to avoid the failures of this depiction are</strong>.  You do not, in turns out, need to be an experienced scholar on the topic; just a few books and a couple of emails is enough to already radically improve on what we see and read in <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em>, much less the absolute <em>mess </em>of what we see in <em>A Game of Thrones</em>.</p>



<p>Writing this has been tricky.  I am well aware that both of these broad cultural groups (that is, Steppe peoples and Plains Native Americans) are often represented in popular culture only in the form of inaccurate and demeaning stereotypes.  I do not want to be just another link in that chain of poor understanding.  I have thus tried to root my argument here, wherever possible, in either the writings of specialist scholars (there will be more of that next week as we get into subsistence patterns, warfare, etc.) or primary evidence, particularly in terms of <em>period photographs</em>, when it comes to clothing and dress.  With luck I have not erred overmuch.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="5355" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg" data-orig-size="1024,991" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/1024px-skythian_archer_plate_bm_e135_by_epiktetos.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scythians#/media/File:Skythian_archer_plate_BM_E135_by_Epiktetos.jpg">Via Wikipedia</a>, an Attic vase-painting of a Scythian archer (c. 500 BCE).  The Scythians, like the Huns and Mongols, were a Eurasian Steppe people, many of them horse-borne nomads of the same sort.  Far from being drab, their clothing was colorful and distinctive, including their particular hats, which show up not only in Greek but also in Persian artwork.</figcaption></figure>



<h2>…But, Why?</h2>



<p>But before we get into the issue proper, it is important to clear away the standard objections, both why subject <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> (and its spin-off properties) to critical analysis at all and also why, if we are going to do that, we are going to focus squarely in on the Dothraki.  The answer to the first is something that we’ve rehearsed a number of times, but bears restating: for most of its readers (and the watchers of <em>A Game of Thrones</em>), <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> will be their primary exposure to the idea of the Middle Ages.  This is particularly true because of the reputation that the series has for being ‘<a href="https://acoup.blog/2019/05/28/new-acquisitions-not-how-it-was-game-of-thrones-and-the-middle-ages-part-i/">how it really was</a>,’ a reputation that George R.R. Martin has consciously cultivated (as with his classic complaint of <a href="https://youtu.be/p-VxvKoDFIw">‘what was Aragorn’s tax policy’</a> – there is a rich irony that, had Martin understood rulership in the Middle Ages better, he would have understood why Aragorn’s tax policy was less important).  Martin has been quite open that he “<a href="https://www.westeros.org/Citadel/SSM/Entry/6040/">draw[s] inspiration from history</a>” and that fact has long been a selling point of the series over more obviously fantastical kinds of medieval-themed high fantasy as well as a <a href="https://ew.com/article/2015/06/03/george-rr-martin-thrones-violence-women/">response to some of the series’ more controversial moments</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Naturally, that cloak of verisimilitude has tended to intensify the degree to which elements of <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> is taken by its readers and viewers as representative of the Middle Ages more generally.</strong>  And of course as I have noted in the (quite recent) past,<strong> <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/11/20/miscellanea-my-thoughts-on-assassins-creed-valhalla/">fiction is often how the public conceptualizes the past and that concept of the past shapes the decisions we make in the present</a></strong>.  In the case of <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> in particular, this vision of the past is <a href="https://acoup.blog/2019/06/12/new-acquisitions-how-it-wasnt-game-of-thrones-and-the-middle-ages-part-iii/">particularly worth interrogating</a> because it serves as the basis for a<a href="https://youtu.be/ek2O6bVAIQQ"> parable on power and violence</a>.</p>



<p>But <em>even if it didn’t</em>, it would still be worth discussing these aspects of the universe of <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em>, because that is what we are supposed to do with cultural products, with <em>literature</em>.  <strong>I am sometimes baffled that the very fans who insist that their particular loves be treated seriously, as <em>art</em> are the same fans who react with frustration if one then sets out to interrogate those same genres the way one would interrogate serious art or literature</strong>.  This is it, after all!  This is what you (we, really) wanted!  A (quite unimpressive, I’ll grant you) ivory tower academic is taking this genre seriously and subjecting it to serious criticism!  Isn’t that what emerging genres often hope for, to be taken seriously as ‘high’ literature?</p>



<p><strong>And of course we should take it seriously.</strong>  And here I want to speak briefly to the purpose of these sorts of endeavors, <strong>because the goal here is not to force anyone to dislike <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em></strong>.   We’re not here to ‘cancel’ <em>ASOIF</em> any more than we were going to ‘cancel’ <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/11/20/miscellanea-my-thoughts-on-assassins-creed-valhalla/"><em>AC:Valhalla</em> two weeks ago</a> (a game I continue to play, I might add).  Instead, discussing cultural products like this is a form of inoculation against their potentially negative aspects, because once a reader knows that, for instance, the depiction of a given culture in a work of fiction has relatively little to do with any real world culture, they can compartmentalize that to the fiction itself; <strong>it loses its power to mislead</strong> <strong>and so may be enjoyed in safety, as it were</strong>.  And there are good things in <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> and in the first six or so seasons of <em>Game of Thrones</em>; but we also need to be honest about the failings.</p>



<p>(Of course, more broadly, doing this as a practice exercise is a key part of building up that skill – what we may term ‘critical reading’ – more generally, rendering the alert reader more resistant to this sort of thing, both in its unintended form (as, I suspect, in this case) or  in its more dangerous<em> intended form</em>.  Put another way, developing critical reading skills is one important way to make one’s self a harder target for misinformation, including historical misinformation.)</p>



<h2>A Dash of Pure Fantasy</h2>



<p>Alright, so <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> is worth looking at closely.  So why <em>this</em> part of the fiction?  It comes down to something <a href="https://www.westeros.org/Citadel/SSM/Entry/6040/">George R.R. Martin wrote</a>:</p>



<blockquote><p>The Dothraki were actually fashioned as an amalgam of a number of steppe and plains cultures… Mongols and Huns, certainly, but also …</p></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/12/04/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-i-barbarian-couture/">https://acoup.blog/2020/12/04/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-i-barbarian-couture/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2020/12/04/collections-that-dothraki-horde-part-i-barbarian-couture/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25299176</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 05:05:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PixelNeRF Neural Radiance Fields from One or Few Images]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 207 | Comments 55 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25298426">thread link</a>) | @choppaface
<br/>
December 3, 2020 | https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <p id="paper-title">
            
            <h3>
                Neural Radiance Fields from One or Few Images
            </h3>
            <h3>
                <small title="Note: This is a joke">IEEE International Conference on Neural Radiance Fields (ICNeRF)</small>
            </h3>
        </p>

        
        
        <div>
            <div>
                <div id="dynamic-teaser">
                     <!-- row -->

                     <!-- row -->
                    <div id="teaser-dtu">
                        <div>
                            <p>3 Input Views</p>
                            
                            <p><strong>pixelNeRF</strong></p>
                            <p>3-view NeRF</p>
                        </div>
                        <div>
                            <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/teaser/dtu_inputs.jpg">
                            </p>
                            
                            <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/teaser/dtu_outputs_sm.gif">
                            </p>
                        </div> <!-- row -->
                    </div>
                </div> <!-- dynamic-teaser -->
                <!-- <img id="teaser" src="img/teaser.png" class="img-responsive" alt="teaser figure"> -->
                <p>
                    We propose pixelNeRF, a learning framework that predicts a continuous neural scene representation conditioned on
                    one or few input images.
                    The existing approach for
                    constructing neural radiance fields&nbsp;<a href="https://www.matthewtancik.com/nerf">[Mildenhall et al. 2020]</a>
                    involves optimizing the representation to every scene independently, requiring many calibrated views and significant compute time.
                    We take a step towards resolving these shortcomings
                    by introducing an architecture that conditions a NeRF on image inputs in a fully convolutional manner. This allows the network to be trained across multiple scenes to learn a scene prior, enabling it to perform novel view synthesis in a feed-forward manner from a sparse set of views (as few as one).
                </p>

            </div>
        </div>
        <div id="overview-video">
            <div>
                <h4>Narrated Overview</h4>
                <p>
                    <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/voebZx7f32g" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
                </p>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <p>
                    Leveraging the volume rendering approach of NeRF, our model can be trained directly from images with no explicit 3D supervision.
                    We conduct extensive experiments on ShapeNet benchmarks for single image novel view synthesis tasks with held-out objects as well as entire unseen categories.
                    We further demonstrate the flexibility of pixelNeRF by demonstrating it on multi-object ShapeNet scenes and real scenes from the DTU dataset. In all cases, pixelNeRF outperforms current state-of-the-art baselines for novel view synthesis and single image 3D reconstruction.
                </p>
                <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/pipeline.png" alt="pipeline">
            </p></div>
        </div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <h4>Feed-forward NeRF from One View</h4>
                <p>
                    Using multiview image supervision, we train a single pixelNeRF to 13 largest object categories
                    in ShapeNet in order to perform novel-view synthesis on unseen objects.
                    Our approach operates in <strong>view-space</strong>—as opposed to canonical—and requires <strong>no test-time optimization</strong>.
                    Nevertheless, in terms of image metrics, we significantly outperform existing methods quantitatively, as shown in the paper.
                </p>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p>Input</p>
                            <p>SoftRas</p>
                            <p>DVR</p>
                            <p>SRN</p>
                            <p><strong>pixelNeRF</strong></p>
                            <p>GT</p>
                        </div>
                        <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/shapenet_000.gif" alt="shapenet results animated">
                    </p></div>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p>Input</p>
                            <p>SoftRas</p>
                            <p>DVR</p>
                            <p>SRN</p>
                            <p><strong>pixelNeRF</strong></p>
                            <p>GT</p>
                        </div>
                        <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/shapenet_001.gif" alt="shapenet results animated">
                    </p></div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <h4>Scene-level Representation</h4>
                <p>
                    Since our method requires <strong>neither canonical space nor object-level information such as masks</strong>,
                    it can represent scenes with multiple objects, where a canonical space is unavailable,
                    without modification.
                    Our method can also <strong>seemlessly integrate multiple views</strong> at test-time to obtain better results.
                    SRN performs extremely poorly here due to the lack of a consistent canonical space.
                </p>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p>2 Input Views</p>
                            <p>SRN</p>
                            <p><strong>pixelNeRF</strong></p>
                        </div>
                        <div>
                            <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/two_000_input.jpg" alt="two object input">
                            </p>
                            <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/two_000_sm.gif" alt="two object results animated">
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            
                            <p>1 Input View</p>
                            <p>SRN</p>
                            <p><strong>pixelNeRF</strong></p>
                        </div>
                        <div>
                            <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/two_001_input.jpg" alt="two object input">
                            </p>
                            <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/two_001_sm.gif" alt="two object results animated">
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <h4>Real-world Scenes</h4>
                <p>
                    We show that our method can also conduct wide-baseline view synthesis on more complex real scenes from the <a href="http://roboimagedata.compute.dtu.dk/?page_id=36">DTU MVS</a> dataset,
                    producing reasonable results when given only 1-3 views at inference time.
                    Moreover, it is feed-forward without requiring test-time optimization for each scene.
                </p>
                <div>
                    
                    <div>
                        <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/dtu_inputs.jpg" alt="DTU 3 input images">
                        </p>
                        <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/dtu.gif" alt="DTU results animated">
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <h4>Generalization</h4>
                <p>
                    To demonstrate generalization capabilities,
                    we apply a model trained on ShapeNet planes, cars, and chairs to unseen ShapeNet categories.
                </p>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p>Input</p>
                            <p>DVR</p>
                            <p>SRN</p>
                            <p><strong>pixelNeRF</strong></p>
                            <p>GT</p>
                        </div>
                        <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/gen_000.gif" alt="shapenet unseen category results animated">
                    </p></div>
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p>Input</p>
                            <p>DVR</p>
                            <p>SRN</p>
                            <p><strong>pixelNeRF</strong></p>
                            <p>GT</p>
                        </div>
                        <p><img src="https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/img/gif/gen_001.gif" alt="shapenet unseen category results animated">
                    </p></div>
                </div>
                <p>
                    Separately, we apply a pretrained model on real car images after background removal.
                </p>
                
                
            </div>
        </div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <h4>Related Links</h4>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        NeRF was introduced in <a href="https://www.matthewtancik.com/nerf">Mildenhall et al. (2020)</a>
                    </li><li>
                        Local image features were used in the related regime of implicit surfaces in
                        <a href="https://shunsukesaito.github.io/PIFu/">Saito et al. (2019)</a>
                        and
                        <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.10711">Xu et al. (2019)</a>
                    </li><li>
                        Our MLP architecture is
                        inspired by
                        <a href="https://avg.is.tuebingen.mpg.de/publications/niemeyer2020cvpr">DVR</a>
                    </li><li>
                        Parts of our
                        PyTorch NeRF implementation are taken from
                        <a href="https://github.com/kwea123/nerf_pl">kwea123</a>
                    </li><li>
                        Also see the concurrent work
                        <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2010.04595">GRF</a>
                        which also introduces image features for NeRF, showing image features can even improve NeRF when a large number of views are available.
                </li></ul>
            </div>
        </div>
        
        <div>
            <div>
                <h4>Acknowledgements</h4>
                <p>
                    We thank Shubham Goel and Hang Gao for comments on the text. We also thank
                    Emilien Dupont and Vincent Sitzmann for helpful discussions.
                    This website is inspired by the template of <a href="http://mgharbi.com/">Michaël Gharbi</a>.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Please send any questions or comments to <a href="https://alexyu.net/">Alex Yu</a>.
                </p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alexyu.net/pixelnerf/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25298426</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 03:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A terminal-based workflow for research, writing, and programming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 263 | Comments 120 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25297268">thread link</a>) | @jerodsanto
<br/>
December 3, 2020 | http://jacobzelko.com/workflow/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://jacobzelko.com/workflow/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <p><em>My personal workflow for terminal-based coding, writing, research, and more!</em></p>

<p>Hello everyone!
It has been quite sometime since I last posted!
Suffice it to say, I have been immensely busy the past year but I am happy to say I am able to resurrect this blog! <img title=":tada:" alt=":tada:" src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f389.png" height="20" width="20"></p>

<p>I have thoroughly grown into my own workflow for programming, research, and writing.
Today, I am happy to be able to share it with you!</p>

<p>If you prefer to watch a video describing most of this entire process, here is an overview of my workflow from one of my <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/thecedarprince">live streams</a>.
It does not go as in-depth as this document but should serve as a strong complement to this post. <img title=":smile:" alt=":smile:" src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f604.png" height="20" width="20"></p>

<p><a href="https://youtu.be/2SLZQQfMF8E"><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/workflow_youtube_vid.jpg" alt=""></a></p>



<p>I use <a href="https://github.com/alacritty/alacritty">Alacritty</a> as my terminal, <a href="https://www.zsh.org/">zsh</a> and <a href="https://ohmyz.sh/">oh-my-zsh</a> as my shell and plugin manager respectively, <a href="https://github.com/tmux/tmux">tmux</a> as my multiplexer, <a href="https://github.com/Peltoche/lsd">lsd</a> as my list command with fun icons, <a href="https://github.com/belluzj/fantasque-sans">Fantasque Sans Mono</a> as my typeface font, <a href="https://github.com/neovim/neovim">neovim</a> for my editor, <a href="https://github.com/junegunn/fzf">fzf</a> paired with <a href="https://github.com/BurntSushi/ripgrep">ripgrep</a> for speedy and interactive file finding, <a href="https://github.com/sharkdp/bat">bat</a> an enhanced <code>cat</code> with a git diff gutter, <a href="https://github.com/jgm/pandoc">pandoc</a> for writing in markdown and LaTeX and outputting the piece to whatever file type I want, <a href="http://jacobzelko.com/setting-up-zotero/">Zotero</a> for managing my collection on scientific literature, <a href="https://github.com/ranger/ranger">ranger</a> as a terminal-based file explorer, and <a href="https://github.com/morhetz/gruvbox-contrib">gruvbox-dark</a> as my general color palette.</p>

<p>Here are gists to the relevant config files I use to modify my interface and user experience:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
<strong>neovim</strong>: <a href="https://gist.github.com/TheCedarPrince/7b9b51af4c146880f17c39407815b594">init.vim</a>
</li>
  <li>
<strong>Alacritty</strong>: <a href="https://gist.github.com/TheCedarPrince/7743091bd8743a7568b718f30bf707c2">.alacritty.yml</a>
</li>
  <li>
<strong>tmux</strong>: <a href="https://gist.github.com/TheCedarPrince/07f6f8f79b1451ec436ff8dee236ccdd">.tmux.conf</a>
</li>
  <li>
<strong>zsh</strong>: <a href="https://gist.github.com/TheCedarPrince/77afe2674803d965a0f5abd108337040">.zshrc</a>
</li>
</ul>

<p>Here is a picture of what that looks like altogether:</p>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/workflow_layout.png" alt=""></p>

<h2 id="my-workflow-in-action-boom">My Workflow in Action <img title=":boom:" alt=":boom:" src="https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/unicode/1f4a5.png" height="20" width="20">
</h2>

<p>The following sections describe in broad strokes my workflow.
I mention some plugins that I use and are provided in my config files.
If you want to learn more about them, I encourage you to read through my config files or search for them.</p>

<h3 id="floating-terminals">Floating Terminals</h3>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/float_term.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>Floating terminals are immensely powerful and I love them!
This enables me to quickly pull up a terminal and do some changes without having to split tmux panes or get out of vim.
Furthermore, what is awesome is that you can use it as a sort of <code>vim-slime</code> tool to send lines of code to the floating terminal.
This is a great feature as it uses your last used floating terminal for its target - therefore, if you switch between projects a lot, just switch your floating terminal accordingly.
No need to keep opening and closing REPL sessions and such!</p>

<h3 id="persistent-working-sessions-via-tmux">Persistent Working Sessions via tmux</h3>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/tmux_restore.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>Though it is a little hard to see, I closed my terminal completely.
Oh no!
All my paneling and windows have disappeared! 
I’ll have to spend valuable time getting my workflow set back up… Or do I?</p>

<p>tmux can actually remember all these layouts with the plugins, <code>resurrect</code> and <code>continuum</code>. 
This is great for when your computer unexpectedly dies or crashes as everything is backed up at regular intervals you define!
Furthermore, pairing the (neo)vim plugin, <code>obsession</code>, allows tmux to also automatically recover vim layouts and sessions as well.
You will never have to worry about losing your terminal workflow again!</p>

<h3 id="mouse-mode">Mouse Mode</h3>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/mouse_mode.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>tmux and (neo)vim also support mouse mode and interactivity!
I can quickly jump all over the place with my mouse or easily resize any opened pane.</p>

<h3 id="interactive-file-finding">Interactive File Finding</h3>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/vim_fzf.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>I integrated the powerful file finding tool, <code>fzf</code>, with <code>ripgrep</code> to quickly find files I am looking to use. 
Then, in my (neo)vim configuration file, I merged these two together into one function that I can easily call while editing files in (neo)vim. 
find files I search for and pandoc to enable citations in pandoc, markdown, or TeX files.</p>

<h3 id="terminal-based-file-explorer">Terminal-Based File Explorer</h3>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/ranger_mode.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>Furthermore, I also use the great tool, <code>ranger</code>, which allows me to have a terminal based file explorer.
It’s nice as it pops up in its own window and does not actually directly interfere with any of the background files being edited. 
It even has image preview capabilities!</p>

<h3 id="citation-engine--live-preview">Citation Engine &amp; Live Preview</h3>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/citation_mode.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>As a researcher, this part gets me immensely excited!
While I am writing, I can actively insert citation keys into whatever I am working on via <code>vim-pandoc</code>.
With my config file, you will have to specify where your own .bib file exists.
Furthermore, <code>markdown-preview</code> allows me to preview my markdown in a web browser and <code>vim-latex-live-preview</code> allows me to view my current TeX files in a pdf viewer – works for subfiles too! 
This works for whenever I write TeX files or markdown files which makes writing a breeze!</p>

<p>If any of this section is confusing, I strongly encourage you to read my article on <a href="http://jacobzelko.com/personal-research-management/">Knowledge Management</a>.</p>



<p>These are parts of my workflow that I used to use.
They have been retired for a variety of reasons but all in an effort to improve my workflow.
I have kept these around in case anyone finds it useful!</p>

<h3 id="vim-slime-for-rapid-evaluation">Vim-Slime for Rapid Evaluation</h3>

<p><strong>Rationale for deprecation:</strong> I used to use <code>vim-slime</code> but deprecated it from my workflow because of the flexibility of floating terminals.
Not only could I use floating terminals to send code, I could also quickly flip through terminals in one button press.</p>

<p><img src="http://jacobzelko.com/assets/vim_slime.gif" alt=""></p>

<p>Here, I target my Julia REPL in a tmux panel and use the <code>vim-slime</code> plugin to send code from my Julia script opened in neovim to the Julia REPL for rapid evaluation. 
This config works for any time you want to target a window.
This also works for code chunks such as functions or loops!</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>I hope you found my workflow and toolchain interesting!
My dream would be for this workflow to serve as inspiration for your own workflow.
Make it your own and all the best!</p>

<p><em>If you spot any errors or have any questions, feel free to <a href="http://jacobzelko.com/contact/">contact me</a> about them!</em></p>

<hr>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://jacobzelko.com/workflow/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25297268</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
