<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 08:39:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 08:39:36 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Indian Government Breached, Massive Amount of Critical Vulnerabilities]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26221607">thread link</a>) | @astroanax
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A writeup detailing the vulnerability reporting process that took place after Sakura Samurai had breached the Indian Government</p><p>Reading time: 6 minutes.</p><div>
      

<p>Sakura Samurai knew that the Indian Government operated an RVDP (Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure Program). <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> put a list together of initial assets in scope for Sakura Samurai to legally test. <a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a> reported that he had found sensitive data and was able to breach police assets. <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> was working in the enumeration processes with his friend, <a href="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001" title="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001">Zultan Holder</a> [not an active Sakura Samurai member] and identified a slew of various attack vectors, immediately resulting in the exposure of many pairs of credentials for databases and other pertinent applications.</p>
<p>The team was informed of the initial enumeration results as they continued to work on the list of assets within scope, while also further jumping into the research and began performing analysis on the sensitive data, identifying additional vectors of attack, exposed PII, and even more credentials.</p>
<p>Sakura Samurai team members included <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner">Aubrey Cottle</a>, and<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking"> John Jackson</a></p>
<p>In total, the following vulnerabilities were identified, in no specific order:</p>
<ul>
<li>35 Separate Instances of Exposed Credential Pairs (Servers, Important Applications, etc)</li>
<li>3 Instances of Sensitive File Disclosure</li>
<li>5 Exposed private-key pairs for servers</li>
<li>13K+ PII Records [and those are only the records that we were inadvertently exposed to]</li>
<li>Dozens of Exposed Sensitive Police Reports</li>
<li>Session Hijacking Chained via Multiple Vulnerabilities, resulting in the compromise of extremely sensitive government systems</li>
<li>Remote Code Execution on a sensitive financial server; a server that contained large backups of Financial Records</li>
</ul>

<p>First and foremost, it is important to note that so many Critical findings had been identified during our testing that we cannot possibly include all of the vulnerabilities without making this writeup unnecessarily heavy. Therefore, we have opted to include small snippets of repetitive findings in this section. Many variations of application and server credentials also were obtained but the point has already been made.</p>
<p><strong>Exposed Database Credentials</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/db-creds.png" alt=""><br>
<strong>Private SSH Keys</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/priv-ssh.png" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Sensitive File Exposure</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/sens-file-exp.png" alt=""><br>
<strong>Exposed PHP Mailer Credentials</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/mailer.png" alt=""></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a> identified an application that resulted in a vulnerability that allowed him to access Sensitive Police Records, containing PII of individuals listed on the report. In addition, sample forensic reports and forensic tooling that is used by the police department was identified by Willis. The exposure of citizen’s sensitive information, some being victims, is a sensitive subject within itself and highly alarming.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/police.png" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/police2.png" alt=""><br>
Shortly after, <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> found a vulnerability that resulted in the exposure of 14,000+ user records. The records included a wide range of sensitive information, including full name, contact info, employee’s department, date of birth, etc. These exposed records along with other various SQL server dumps and Rob’s Police Record Exposure is enough to constitute a data breach without even logging into any of the servers.</p>
<p>Henry identified many credential pairs which could have resulted in even more exploitation of many other people. The PII identified is a small sample of a much larger issue.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/14k-records.png" alt=""><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">John Jackson</a> was able to identify a relevant Remote Code Execution Vulnerability, affecting an out-of-date application residing on one of the government servers. The remote code execution vulnerability allowed for complete access to sensitive files on the server, including the ability to exfiltrate complete backups of financial records [although data exfiltration wasn’t performed to avoid unnecessary action]</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/rce1.png" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/rce2.png" alt=""><br>
Finally, <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://www.twitter.com/Kirtaner">Aubrey Cottle</a> identified the presence of what appeared to be an extremely important application being hosted by the same server that John had achieved successful Remote Code Execution on. Cottle then chained together multiple vulnerabilities in conjunction with the Remote Code Execution vulnerability, resulting in the ability to hijack any user’s session on the web application. The application contained troves of sensitive government data and could have given a threat actor the ability to perform highly-critical, admin-based government actions.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/session-chained.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Even though the Indian Government has a RVDP in place, we didn’t feel comfortable disclosing the vulnerabilities right away. The hacking process was far from the standard situation of business-as-usual security research. In total, our report compounded to a massive 34 page report worth of vulnerabilities. We knew that our intent was good, but we wanted to ensure that the US Government had eyes on the situation. Sakura Samurai coordinated with the <a href="https://twitter.com/DC3VDP" title="https://twitter.com/DC3VDP">U.S. DoD Vulnerability Disclosure Program (VDP)</a> to assist in facilitating initial conversations of disclosure. <a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">John Jackson</a> spoke with DC3’s Program Manager via email and coordinated on a plan of action.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-1.png" alt=""><br>
Roughly 4 days later, after further communication with the DC3, we felt safe to begin our initial reveal of research on the NCIIPC’s RVDP program.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-2.png" alt=""></p>
<p>In addition, the DC3 also commended the hacking that we did in support of making the cyberspace a better place for everyone.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-3.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Unfortunately, what seemed like a done deal turned out to be quite the unprofessional ride. Any organization knows that fixing breach-worthy vulnerabilities is extremely time sensitive. Once threat actors catch wind of major vulnerabilities against an organization they begin poking on their own, looking for more vectors of attack. Immediately upon revealing that Sakura Samurai was the group responsible for hacking the Indian Government, we followed up with them via Email.</p>
<p><strong>Timeline</strong></p>
<p><strong>2021/02/04</strong> - DC3 begins initial contact with the Indian Government.<br>
<strong>2021/02/08</strong> - Sakura Samurai informs the public that they breached the Government.<br>
<strong>2021/02/08</strong> - Sakura Samurai makes contact with the NCIIPC, noting that the report that they received was a result of their research.<br>
<strong>2021/02/09</strong> - The NCIIPC responds, with a basic acknowledgement and thank you for the research.<br>
<strong>2021/02/09</strong> - Sakura Samurai asks for clarification on patching and the responsibility of breach disclosure to the public.<br>
<strong>2021/02/10</strong> - Sakura Samurai, having received no response, asks for an update on the involved remediation and breach notification processes.<br>
<strong>2021/02/16</strong> - Sakura Samurai once again asks for NCIIPC’s plans for remediation and disclosure.<br>
<strong>2021/02/17</strong> - The NCIIPC makes contact, 7-days later, stating that they will follow up in a short time. Again, we ask about plans of anticipated patching and breach notification to the affected citizens.<br>
<strong>2021/02/19</strong> - In the morning, we ask again about patching and disclosure, 8-hours later and still no response on the matter.<br>
<strong>2021/02/19</strong> - Sakura Samurai reviews the submitted vulnerability report and notes that only about an eighth or less of the submitted Critical Vulnerabilities have been resolved within a two-week period. No notification of breach has occurred even though Government Employees and Indian Citizens are at risk of exploitation from threat actors.</p>

<p>Governments have an obligation to protect the private data of its employees and citizens. In addition, the exposure of proprietary government data can be used for great means of manipulation and for other destructive purposes. While the NCIIPC operates a Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure Program, the recklessness and avoidance of communication represents the complete opposite of a responsible program. A failure to release notification of breach to affected citizens and to patch highly-critical vulnerabilities in a timely manner reflects poorly on the state of their Information Security posture. The clock to patch vulnerabilities began immediately when the DC3 contacted the NCIIPC via Twitter, as it is a highly visible space - one which threat actors avidly monitor.</p>
<p>Sakura Samurai urge the NCIIPC to patch the remainder of the vulnerabilities. The criticality of some of the issues cannot wait weeks or months for adequate resolution.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Check out our website</strong><br>
<a href="https://sakurasamurai.org/" title="https://sakurasamurai.org">https://sakurasamurai.org</a></p>
<p><strong><em>Twitter Links:</em></strong><br>
Main Page<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii" title="https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii">https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii</a><br>
Founders<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">https://twitter.com/johnjhacking</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/nicksahler" title="https://twitter.com/nicksahler">https://twitter.com/nicksahler</a><br>
Members<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner">https://twitter.com/Kirtaner</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">https://twitter.com/rej_ex</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/endingwithali" title="https://twitter.com/endingwithali">https://twitter.com/endingwithali</a><br>
Collaborator<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001" title="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001">https://twitter.com/orpheus9001</a></p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26221607</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 06:57:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Data Immutability, Verifiability and Integrity Without the Blockchain Overhead]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26221324">thread link</a>) | @sidcool
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://techtake.info/2021/02/16/data-immutability-verifiability-and-integrity-without-the-blockchain-overhead/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://techtake.info/2021/02/16/data-immutability-verifiability-and-integrity-without-the-blockchain-overhead/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Whenever a software project needs to implement immutable records, people often start thinking of Blockchain or <strong>D</strong>istributed <strong>L</strong>edger <strong>T</strong>echnology like Hyperledger. Blockchain and DLT make use of cryptographic techniques that enable immutability, verifiability and integrity checks. However, Blockchain and DLT need much more than just these checks. It needs to prevent all the attempts of a double-spend by potential malicious users. In a trust-less environment it needs implementation of complex protocols which leads to consumption of huge amount of electricity. This makes writing data on Blockchain costly. DLTs like Hyperledger make use of simpler consensus algorithms between a “set of trusted nodes”, which reduces the cost. However, it still incurs significant costs if nothing more than immutability, verifiability and integrity were the concern.</p>



<p>This post is about how to implement data immutability, verifiability and integrity without using a Blockchain or a DLT in industrial strength software applications.</p>



<ul><li><a href="#foundation">Foundational technique</a><ul><li><a href="#hash-function">Cryptographic hash function</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#verifiability">Verifiability</a><ul><li><a href="#verify-id">Deterministic and Verifiable IDs</a></li><li><a href="#data-format">Data format and ID Generation</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#immutability">Immutability and Verifiability</a><ul><li><a href="#merkel-dag">Merkel DAG and immutable data structures</a></li><li><a href="#mutation">Mutation</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#integrity">Immutability, Verifiability and Integrity</a><ul><li><a href="#application">More applications</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#future-proof">Future-proofing</a><ul><li><a href="#multi-hash">Multihash</a></li></ul></li></ul>



<h2 id="foundation">Foundational technique – Cryptographic Hashing</h2>



<p>To understand the solution, some foundational techniques must be understood. This section describes what is cryptographic hashing. Those who are already aware of cryptographic hashing, they may skip to the next section.</p>



<h4 id="hash-function">Cryptographic hash function</h4>



<p>If you provide a stream of bytes to a cryptographic hash function, it generates a number called hash (also referred to as digest). The following properties make it a very useful tool:</p>



<ol><li>It is impossible to guess the generated hash value for a stream of bytes. To get the hash value, one has to run the algorithm, there is no shortcut.</li><li>For a given input it always generates the same hash value.</li><li>It is infeasible to deduce the input based on the hash value. That means it is an irreversible mathematical function.</li><li>No two different stream of bytes result in the same hash value. Even a small change in the input stream generates a totally different number.&nbsp;<em>(When two different stream of bytes produce the same hash value, we say the cryptographic hash function is broken. It is also referred to as there is a collision in the cryptographic hash function.)</em></li><li>Any size of input stream will always result in the same size of hash value. Some hash functions generate hash values that are 256 bits long. If those functions are used, the result will always be 256 bits long.</li></ol>



<p>Examples of commonly used cryptographic hash functions include:</p>



<ul><li>SHA-256 (returns 256 bit&nbsp;unsigned integers)</li><li>RIPEMD-160 (returns 160 bit unsigned integers)</li></ul>



<p>Sample hash values:</p>



<figure><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Input</strong></td><td><strong>SHA-256</strong></td><td><strong>RIPEMD-160</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Hello world</td><td>0x64ec88ca00b268e5ba1a35678a1b5316d212f4f366b2477232534a8aeca37f3c</td><td>0xdbea7bd24eef40a2e79387542e36dd408b77b21a</td></tr><tr><td>Hello world.</td><td>0xaa3ec16e6acc809d8b2818662276256abfd2f1b441cb51574933f3d4bd115d11</td><td>0x6ad34a17d22d67a7ab02710ae9eb6f282cb1d787</td></tr><tr><td>Unrelated, totally.</td><td>0x2bd72f5c4300444890325b3363ef2027f30ed38797c3133dbc62a90564976458</td><td>0x51cb1844d22a00d5f659795e0b1c339c6fa1a8bc</td></tr></tbody></table><figcaption>Hex representation of SHA-256 and RIPEMD-160 hash values for different inputs</figcaption></figure>



<p>There are two things we observe from the table above:</p>



<ol><li>With a slight change in input, the hash values change dramatically and by looking only at the hash values, one cannot conclude&nbsp;that&nbsp;the first and second are&nbsp;even closely related. This is also referred to as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avalanche_effect" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">avalanche effect</a>. It is one of requirements of a cryptographic algorithms to have the avalanche effect.</li><li>The values mentioned are actually text strings and do not look like numbers, although we expected them to be numbers.</li></ol>



<p>They are actually numbers, represented this way to reduce the size of the presented text. For example, binary representation of the number 255&nbsp;is ‘11111111’. Decimal representation is ‘255’. Hexadecimal representation is ‘ff’ or ‘FF’. The representations in the table above are hexadecimal representations of 32 byte and 20 byte numbers. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base64" target="_blank">base64encoding</a> is commonly used to represent the hash values in cryptographic applications.</p>



<h2 id="verifiability">Verifiability</h2>



<p>For quite some time, open source software has been distributed through various mirror sites so that downloads are sped up. Any user could download the software package quickly from a nearby mirror site. These nearby sites could be malicious and could provide compromised open source software packages. In order to overcome this problem, open source software builds would publish a checksum file on their website. This checksum file is used to verify that the downloaded package from a nearby mirror site is authentic. The checksum file actually contains a cryptographic hash of the software package.</p>



<p>For example: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.openoffice.org/download/checksums/3.4.1_checksums.html" target="_blank">Apache OpenOffice – Download checksum files</a>.</p>



<pre>e08f9c8acecba1ee0046f820b0abed97dfe90511bd733a65936fdf0ea9c22540  Apache_OpenOffice_incubating-SDK_3.4.1_Linux_x86-64_install-rpm_en-US.tar.gz</pre>



<p>This is the content from SHA256 checksum file for <a href="http://archive.apache.org/dist/incubator/ooo/files/stable/3.4.1/Apache_OpenOffice_incubating-SDK_3.4.1_Linux_x86-64_install-rpm_en-US.tar.gz.sha256" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Apache Open Office SDK for Linux x86-64</a> build.</p>



<p>It would not matter which mirror site the SDK is downloaded from. A user can easily verify the authenticity of the download using a simple command like:</p>



<pre><code>$ sha256sum Apache_OpenOffice_incubating-SDK_3.4.1_Linux_x86-64_install-rpm_en-US.tar.gz
e08f9c8acecba1ee0046f820b0abed97dfe90511bd733a65936fdf0ea9c22540  Apache_OpenOffice_incubating-SDK_3.4.1_Linux_x86-64_install-rpm_en-US.tar.gz</code></pre>



<p>If the generated SHA256 does not match with the checksum file, the user knows that the software package has been tampered.</p>



<p>We will use the same technique to verify data objects. The data object we are interested in would have an ID. Any application or service asks for objects using IDs. If the data that the application gets does not generate the same hash value as the ID, then the application can easily conclude that the data is not what was asked for or the data has mutated. On a typical hardware the cryptographic hash function would take a few microseconds to generate the hash value. So, this is not costly and offers good verifiability.</p>



<p>In the context of this post, the verifiability that we are seeking is not because we operate in a trust-less or adversarial environment like Blockchains, but mainly because data can become corrupt or can be deliberately changed by hackers / attackers. This is for companies to verify that the data they hold has not been modified undesirably.</p>



<h4 id="verify-id">Application: Deterministic and Verifiable IDs</h4>



<p>In a typical RESTful request, a client posts a request to a service, and the service returns back an ID. The service uses the ID to index the object that got created due to the request. However, with a predetermined ID generation technique, it is possible for the client to know the ID even before the service receives the request. This is done even in blockchains. The transactionID (also referred as <a href="https://wiki.bitcoinsv.io/index.php/TXID" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TXID</a>) is a hash computed from certain fields of a transaction request.</p>



<p>To be able to know the ID of an object that will be returned by a service even before the object is created in a service has significant benefits. </p>



<ol><li>Just by computing the ID from the fields of an object, and comparing it with the ID provided in the object, one can determine if the object is the right object. Housekeeping processes can easily determine data corruption or software bugs or potential attacks.</li><li>Request need not be processed synchronously.</li><li>The client can fire a batch of requests in just one call. Each individual request can easily be identified by the request id which will be deterministic for both the client and the service. This eliminates the need to create IDs on the client side, and map them to the server side IDs.</li><li>Non-idempotent requests such as HTTP POST requests can achieve deterministic behaviour. Multiple POST requests (which could be because of software bug or infrastructural replays) will not cause harm, as the request ID is predetermined. The server can easily identify a duplicate request.</li></ol>



<p>Example: To generate an OrderID, one could take the sha256 of a series of bytes of the quantity, price, dateTime of the order, clientID, and the assetID or assetSymbol.</p>



<pre><code>OrderID = sha256(bytes(qty)||bytes(price)||bytes(dateTime)||bytes(clientID)||bytes(assetID))</code></pre>



<h4 id="data-format">Data format and ID Generation</h4>



<p>While the scheme above for ID generation works, it has a certain drawback. For every type of objects, a developer would have to write an ID generator. This is not desirable. For a majority of the types of objects, the id generator should just be available easily. For this, the object itself can be serialised and the serialised stream of bytes can be hashed.</p>



<p>It is important to note that text based data structures like JSON, XML are not very well suited for this. The main reason behind this is that adding a space or TAB within the document will not alter the data for JSON or XML, however will yield a totally different hash value and therefore a totally different object ID. Hence, it is better to use serialisation formats designed for cross platform, multiple language environments and are deterministic. Compact data serialisation like <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers" target="_blank">protocol buffers</a>, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://google.github.io/flatbuffers/" target="_blank">FlatBuffers</a>, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://avro.apache.org/" target="_blank">Apache Avro</a> and even <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7049" target="_blank">CBOR</a> are much better suited for this.</p>



<h2 id="immutability">Immutability and Verifiability</h2>



<p>Software professionals often jump to Blockchain to achieve immutability even in a non-adversarial environment like most business applications. Any party explicitly trying to cheat would face the court, and fraudulent transactions can be reverted in the most common business applications seen throughout the world. Therefore, there is no need for all the complexity and consensus algorithms like proof-of-work or proof-of-stake. Even on DLTs there are algorithms like Raft which are used to achieve consensus. Although much lesser in the power consumption, raft could still be an overkill for some …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://techtake.info/2021/02/16/data-immutability-verifiability-and-integrity-without-the-blockchain-overhead/">https://techtake.info/2021/02/16/data-immutability-verifiability-and-integrity-without-the-blockchain-overhead/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://techtake.info/2021/02/16/data-immutability-verifiability-and-integrity-without-the-blockchain-overhead/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26221324</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 05:55:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Frustrated with Parler deplatforming, I am building a service no one can silence]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 168 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218900">thread link</a>) | @anon20190221
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<p>This is the first post in this blog, it was published on February 19, 2021.</p>

<h2 id="motivation">Motivation</h2>

<h3 id="censorship">Censorship</h3>

<p>The year of 2020 will be remembered for the pandemic, the BLM movement, and the U.S. elections among other billion of things around the globe. It is funny I even mention the third one considering how little I give a damn about U.S. politics, yet this whole story begins with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parler">Parler</a> deplatforming that happened about a month ago. Let me remind you: Apple, Google, Amazon, and a few other companies terminated their service to the free speech social network for insufficient moderation effectively destroying the platform in a matter of just a couple of days. What the fuck?</p>

<p>OK, let me be clear with my position: I believe every private company has a right to refuse service to anyone, whether an individual or a business, but I also have my own right to despise them for exercising that. What they did was probably legal, but screw them anyway, they failed us. Regardless what these psychopathic corporations like to tell the public, they are only concerned with maximizing shareholder value, and if there is anything  even remotely resembling an image liability (through pressure by political radicals, cancel culture SJWs, you name it), they will not think twice. What disgusts me the most here is neither greed nor hypocrisy but their unwillingness to grow a pair of balls and stand up for freedom of speech.</p>

<p>You see, freedom of speech and expression must be absolute. You cannot have censorship-resistance with exceptions; otherwise, these exceptions could be used to remove or block anything unwanted, not only offensive. This way, the Chinese cannot access Wikipedia because of what originally started as a counter-terrorism measure, and the Russians cannot access LinkedIn because of what originally started as a children protection measure. We cannot deprive humanity of their freedom just because some small fraction of users might, unfortunately, use that freedom to spread offensive content. In the same way, you do not ban electricity because people get electrocuted.</p>

<p>Let us now switch from corporates to governments. Ooh, wee! Do not even get me started on that. And I am not even talking about cases like Google happily not letting people disable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SafeSearch">SafeSearch</a> in Indonesia because its government knows best, that is just the tip of the iceberg. I am talking about political censorship which includes silencing people with torture, gulags, and bullets. Here is the world map of the freedom of the press status:</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/press-freedom.png" alt="2020 Press Freedom Index"></p>

<p>Just look at this mess. Blue tones mean OK-ish, others not so much. This map is <a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/User:NordNordWest">NordNordWest</a>’s work based on the <a href="https://rsf.org/en/ranking">2020 Press Freedom Index</a> and is distributed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/de/legalcode">CC BY-SA 3.0 de</a>. Keep in mind population densities, e.g. there are about 90 times more people per unit area living in Vietnam than Australia. I am actually surprised the U.S. did so well in 2020 considering how badly they wanted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julian_Assange">Mr. Assange</a> to be extradited and executed.</p>

<p>What would you answer your children if they asked you how in the world North Korea still exists in its current form with 25 million Koreans suffering for over 70 years and no one is doing anything about that? Or how about 28 million people in Venezuela? Or 82 million people in Iran? Giving voice to all whistleblowers and activists, especially the ones risking their lives and freedom in hostile environments is the fundamental goal of Pepe.</p>

<h3 id="darknets">Darknets</h3>

<p>There is already <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tor_(anonymity_network)">Tor</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I2P">I2P</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freenet">Freenet</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNUnet">GNUnet</a> etc. We can run emails, message boards, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent">BitTorrent</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kad_network">Kad</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System">IPFS</a> on top of them, maybe even use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethereum">Ethereum</a> smart contracts for decentralized computing. All the technology is there, why bother with something new? Well, first of all, these are all amazing projects, there is nothing wrong with them. The peculiar thing, however, is none of them except BitTorrent (and perhaps Tor) gained much popularity, neither do we see any readily available censorship-resistant communication platforms. Why is that?</p>

<p>I claim there are 2 main reasons for that:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>They are hard to use. The “Unix is user-friendly, it is just picky about who its friends are.” aphorism still lives in most them: you may need to install a bunch of additional software (such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_virtual_machine">JVM</a> or shared libraries) potentially dealing with a dependency hell on some platforms; read through sparse documentation and dead forums on optimal network, security, and sharing settings; carefully configure your router, computer, and client; install, study, and configure applications running on top of the darknet, i.e. repeat the steps. The reason why Tor became popular outside of research was not because it was first, but because of the hacky all-in-one Tor Browser Bundle with sane defaults.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>They prefer purity to practicality. Instead of concentrating manpower on few specific use cases, most existing tools try to conquer the world: a new internet, interplanetary, infrastructure, an application framework, APIs, a Turing-complete language on the blockchain etc. This is great and all, it is general, conceptual, modular, extensible, and stackable—everything we like—but sometimes overengineering is just overengineering given the goal. And our goal here is not to make a technical revolution, but to help as many people as we can communicate without fear of retribution.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>BitTorrent evolved into something that is used by 150 million people worldwide, it seamlessly adopted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_hash_table">DHT</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer_exchange">PEX</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micro_Transport_Protocol">µTP</a>, trackerless <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnet_URI_scheme">magnet links</a>, and people do not even know what the hell it all means. Even though proprietary, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skype">Skype</a> thrived very similarly (at least before it was crippled by Microsoft), millions of its users did not even know what peer-to-peer meant, not to mention how it worked under the hood, it just did. These two systems succeeded not because of luck but rather as a result of some excellent product decisions. We need to learn from that and reiterate.</p>

<h2 id="pepe-overview">Pepe overview</h2>

<h3 id="user-level">User level</h3>

<p>For the messaging platform, I chose to use an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imageboard">imageboard</a> similar to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4chan">4chan</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futaba_Channel">Futaba Channel</a>. While not the most popular type of forum, imageboards are extremely flexible and free of junk like authentication or karma, they promote anonymity in a very practical way, and over 30 million people are already familiar with them. Perhaps, I am not a big fan of their crowded old-school design, but the initial user traction is more important than my sense of beauty, we will refine the looks through time.</p>

<p>That is, the Pepe imageboard is going to be the only application running on top the Pepe darknet, they are in fact inseparable. This way, we can design the network specifically for this one use case. This brings both security and performance benefits. Joining the darknet can be as simple as double clicking the application, and users do not need to install or configure any third-party browsers or proxy servers, they can just go to <a href="http://localhost:8666/">localhost:8666</a> using Chrome, Safari, or whatever they like, and it is going to be safe without any third-party extensions.</p>

<p>Once online, users may browse existing or create new message boards about various topics in any language such as <code>/en/food/</code> or <code>/ja/math/</code>. A board is a collection of threads about something more specific, would it be an idea or a question. A thread has a collection of posts that people send replying to each other. Each post may have one or multiple attachments such as photos, videos, you name it. So that you have an idea of what it looks like, here is a screenshot of a random thread on the 4chan DIY board:</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/4chan-thread.png" alt="4chan thread"></p>

<p>What is fundamentally different with Pepe is moderation. Instead of relying on a centralized entity with a banhammer, each board and thread owner may anonymously moderate their spaces on their own. However, nothing can actually be deleted, it can only be shadowed, and each user decides whether they want to see the light or the full version of the page at any moment in time. People can still reply to shadowed posts inside their own shadowed posts, so no one cannot silence anyone, only maintain order on the light side.</p>

<p>If people are no longer interested in particular threads, they will eventually become forgotten by the network and naturally disappear from their board. But if there is at least one person who is subscribed to or has archived some thread, no one in the world (even Pepe creators) can censor or somehow shut it down without hurting most of the network Pepe is running on top of.</p>

<h3 id="network-level">Network level</h3>

<p>The three biggest problems with 4chan and similar communication platforms are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>They use closed source software so no one can tell how secure everything is and what is really going on there.</li>
  <li>They are centralized, i.e. some individual or business owns the servers and fully controls the whole infrastructure.</li>
  <li>They collect lots of metadata including but not limited to “someone with this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address">IP address</a> posted this at this moment in time”.</li>
</ul>

<p>Mitigating the first problem is the easiest: just use open-source software whenever possible. Regarding the centralization issue, we could switch to a decentralized solution like BitTorrent (imagine each torrent containing a thread with its posts and attachments), but that itself does not help with privacy, people can still see what others are doing. Similarly, we could tackle the privacy issue with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network">VPN</a> or a darknet like Tor or I2P, but that, contrary to popular belief, does not solve the centralization issue in any way. Clearly, we need the best of the two worlds. Let us fuse them together!</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/pepe-routing.png" alt="Pepe routing"></p>

<p>Here is an very simplified walk through how the network works. Imagine Bob is an undercover journalist who wants to anonymously share his report and Alice is a political activist who is interested in the investigation Bob had been doing. It all starts with Bob announcing he has the report:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Bob joins the network and gathers information about random peers on it through the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_hash_table">DHT</a>. This way, Bob discovers hundreds of participants including X and Y. Similarly, Bob registers himself on the network through the DHT so that others …</p></li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/">https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218900</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:28:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TransferWise changes name to Wise]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 193 | Comments 156 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218693">thread link</a>) | @watbe
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<div>
<p>Today, we’re changing our name from TransferWise to Wise.</p>
<p>Our customers now need us for more than money transfers. Sending, spending, and receiving money internationally is too expensive, slow, and inconvenient. We’re fixing that for people and businesses.</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://transferwise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise#transferwise-is-now-wise">skip ahead to see what changes for you</a> (spoiler: not much, right away), but first, let’s go back a bit.</p>
<h2><a href="#a-decade-into-our-mission" id="a-decade-into-our-mission"></a>A decade into our mission</h2>
<p>Ten years ago, Taavet and I set out to fix international money transfers for all of us who’d been overcharged and underserved by banks. We named our idea ‘TransferWise’ — because our early customers were ‘wise’ to know their banks were charging hidden fees in exchange rate markups.</p>
<p>We set ourselves a mission to make money work without borders — to make money move instantly, transparently, conveniently, and — eventually — for free.</p>
<p>Now, we’re a community of 10 million like-minded people and businesses managing money all over the world, saving billions and fighting as hard as ever against hidden fees.</p>
<p>Our multi-currency account and the clever debit card is replacing international banking for many of you. By building this infrastructure for you, we’ve created a platform that more than a dozen banks use today.</p>
<p>You’ve told us for years the problem is bigger than money transfers. Any time money moves into another currency, it’s still a maze of hidden exchange rate markups, high fees, delays, and small print.</p>
<h2><a href="#well-fix-international-banking-together" id="well-fix-international-banking-together"></a>We’ll fix international banking together</h2>
<p>Sending, spending, receiving, and holding money internationally doesn’t work like it should, because the international banking system was built for the past.</p>
<p>For generations, banks have been defined by borders. Traditional bank accounts trap our money in one country, making international lives more difficult and expensive than they need to be. We shouldn’t have to accept this status quo.</p>
<p>Today, we don’t. We’ll fix it with Wise — the world’s most international account. It makes your money borderless — with instant, super-cheap money transfers, a debit card to spend in any currency, account details to get paid in 30+ countries, balances to hold your money safely in 50+ different currencies, multi-currency direct debits, and other revolutionary features.</p>
<h2><a href="#transferwise-is-now-wise" id="transferwise-is-now-wise"></a>TransferWise is now Wise</h2>
<p>Today our name catches up with who we’re already building for — a community of people and businesses with multi-currency lives. Wise is for all of us who live, work, travel, or support family around the world. It’s for those of us who want to cut out the middlemen that hold us back from being truly borderless.</p>
<p>For customers, not too much will change right away. We become “Wise” or “Wise Business” — depending how you use us. You can access your exact same account via <a href="http://wise.com/">wise.com</a>, using your current email and password. You won't need a new account. In a few weeks we will start to redirect transferwise.com to wise.com.</p>
<p>Our logo has changed, and our apps will be renamed. But our icon — the fast flag — remains as a symbol for money without borders. Beyond that, you’ll notice some new colours, words, and designs.</p>
<p>The core experience of using Wise will remain faster, cheaper, and more convenient than anything else. Our mission remains the same. We’re still making — and always will be making — money work without borders.</p>
<p>We’re humbled that 10 million of you already rely on us to help you lead your international lives. We can’t wait to bring the next 100 million of you with us as we continue to build a new, fair, and transparent world of money.</p>
<p>Onwards.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218693</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tap your phone at Gold Coast bus stops to access my website]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 69 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218432">thread link</a>) | @joshuawithers
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://joshwithers.blog/2021/02/22/tap-your-phone.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joshwithers.blog/2021/02/22/tap-your-phone.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
      <p>My February 2021 Apple Fitness challenge is to walk 227km in the month. So I was out late last night closing in on the target when I stopped and looked at the bus timetable sign at a local bus stop.</p>

<p><img src="https://joshwithers.blog/uploads/2021/7f4522c3f4.jpg"></p>

<p>That NFC tag piqued my curiosity. I wondered if it worked on iPhone?</p>

<p>So I tapped my iPhone 12 Pro up against the NFC logo and a website hyperlink notification popped up like when you scan a QR code.</p>

<p><img src="https://joshwithers.blog/uploads/2021/0c4028d20c.jpg"></p>

<p>And TransLink, the local public transport provider, had neglected to renew the domain name used in the NFC tag.</p>

<p>I now own the <a href="http://transl.in/">transl.in</a> domain name and the people of the Gold Coast now have easy access to my website. 🤷‍♂️</p>

<p>As an example, a local bus stop links to <a href="http://transl.in/k_300428">http://transl.in/k_300428</a></p>

  </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joshwithers.blog/2021/02/22/tap-your-phone.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218432</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 23:29:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Data Pipeline Is a Materialized View]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 94 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26217911">thread link</a>) | @nchammas
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Say you run an online book store and want to build a data pipeline that figures out who the top-selling authors are. Logically, the input to the pipeline is a log of every individual book purchase on the store for all time, along with details about each book like who authored it. And the output is a list of the top-selling authors per month.</p>

<!-- [image: book purchases + authorship info -> top-selling authors of the month] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/top-selling-authors.png" width="1000">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>The output of this data pipeline is a function of the input. In other words, the output is derived from the input by running the input through the pipeline.</p>

<!-- [image: f(input) -> output] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/f-input-output.png" width="400">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>This is an important characteristic of the output. As long as the input data and pipeline transformations (i.e. the pipeline code) are preserved, the output can always be recreated. The input data is <em>primary</em>; if lost, it cannot be replaced. The output data, along with any intermediate stages in the pipeline, are <em>derivative</em>; they can always be recreated from the primary data using the pipeline.</p>

<h2 id="the-logical-view">The Logical View</h2>

<p>Let’s represent our hypothetical “Top-Selling Authors” pipeline as a directed graph, where the nodes represent datasets and the edges represent transformations of those datasets. Furthermore, let’s color each dataset in the graph based on whether it’s primary or derivative.</p>

<!-- [image: colored graph of transformations] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/pipeline-graph.png" width="500">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>Most data pipelines, if you zoom out far enough, look something like this. You have some source data; it gets sliced, diced, and combined in various ways to produce some outputs. If someone were to wipe out all the derived data in this pipeline, you’d be able to regenerate it without any data loss. The pipeline could include any number of arbitrary steps, like copying files from an FTP share, or scraping data from a web page. It doesn’t matter as long as the pipeline produces the same output when given the same input.</p>

<p>Any time someone queries the output of the pipeline, it’s logically equivalent to them running the entire pipeline on the source data to get the output they’re looking for. In this way, a pipeline is a <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/relational-databases/views/views?view=sql-server-ver15">view</a> into the source data.</p>

<h2 id="materializing-the-view">Materializing the View</h2>

<p>Of course, data pipelines don’t work this way in practice. It would be a waste of resources and a long wait for users if every query triggered a series of computations stretching all the way back to the primary data. When you ask for this month’s top-selling authors, you expect a quick response.</p>

<p>Hence, the typical real-world pipeline <em>materializes</em> its output, and often also several of the intermediate datasets required to produce that final output. Materializing a dataset simply means saving it to persistent storage, as opposed to repeatedly computing it on the fly. So when you ask for that list of authors, whatever system answering your query can start from the closest materialized dataset, as opposed to starting at the source or primary data.</p>

<!-- [image: cached nodes in graph colored; key explaining colors; caption] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/pipeline-with-cached-nodes.png" width="500">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    A query against dataset B only needs to recompute the pipeline starting from A, since A is materialized.
    All derivative datasets, whether materialized or not, can be thrown away and recreated from the primary data.
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>So we’ve turned our view into a <em>materialized view</em>. “View” represents the logical transformations expressed in the pipeline. “Materialized” represents the fact that we cache the output of the pipeline, and perhaps also some of the intermediate steps. A complex set of interdependent data pipelines can be conceptualized in this way, as a graph of materialized views.</p>

<p>Note that this concept can be applied very broadly, and not just to what we think of as “normal” data pipelines:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A traditional web cache alleviates read traffic from the primary database, which is the source of truth. The cache is derivative and can be regenerated from the database at any time. The data in the cache is materialized so that incoming queries do not need to go all the way back to the database to get an answer.</li>
  <li>A build system compiles or assembles source code into artifacts like executables or test reports. The artifacts are derivative, whereas the source code is primary. When you run a program over and over, you reuse the artifacts output by your build system, as opposed to recompiling them from source every time.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="updating-a-materialized-view">Updating a Materialized View</h2>

<p>Materializing the output, though a practical necessity for most pipelines, adds an administrative cost. When the source data changes, the materialized views need to be updated. Otherwise, the data you get from the view will be <em>stale</em>.</p>

<!-- [image: highlighted new source row; out-of-date output aggregation] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/update-materialized-view.png" width="600">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    The sales total of 101 for Eric Carle is stale. The correct value is now 103.
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>To update a materialized view, there are two high-level properties you typically care about: the update <em>trigger</em>, and the update <em>granularity</em>. The former affects the freshness of your output, which impacts end-users of the data, and the latter affects the performance of your update process, which impacts the engineers or operators responsible for that process.</p>

<h3 id="update-trigger">Update Trigger</h3>

<p>The update trigger is the event that prompts a refresh of the materialized view—e.g. by running your pipeline against the latest source data.</p>

<p>That event may be a file landing in a shared drive, or some data arriving on an event stream, or another pipeline completing. For some pipelines, the update trigger may just be a certain time of day, in which case it might be more useful to talk about the update <em>frequency</em> rather than trigger.</p>

<p>A typical batch pipeline, for example, might run on a daily or hourly cadence, whereas a streaming pipeline may run every few seconds or minutes, or whenever a new event is delivered via some sort of event stream. Whenever the pipeline runs, it updates its output, and the whole process can be viewed as a <em>refresh</em> of the materialized view.</p>

<h3 id="update-granularity">Update Granularity</h3>

<p>The update granularity refers to how much of the materialized view needs to be modified to account for the latest changes to the source data.</p>

<p>A common update granularity is the full refresh. No matter how small or large the change to the source data, when the pipeline runs it throws away the entire output table and rebuilds it from scratch.</p>

<p>A more sophisticated pipeline might rebuild only a subset of the table, like a date partition. And an extremely precise pipeline may know how to update exactly the output rows that are impacted by the latest changes to the source data.</p>

<p>The update trigger and granularity are independent. You can have a pipeline that runs every second and does a full refresh of its output, and you can have a pipeline that runs once a day but carefully updates only the rows that it needs to.</p>

<h3 id="typical-examples">Typical Examples</h3>

<p>Let’s explore these two properties a bit using our example pipeline that computes the top-selling authors of the month.</p>

<h4 id="the-daily-batch-update">The Daily Batch Update</h4>

<p>Every night at 1 a.m., an automated process looks for a dump of the latest purchases from the previous day. The dump is a compressed CSV file.</p>

<p>The update process uses this dump to recompute the month’s sales numbers for all authors. It replaces the entire output table with all-new calculations for all authors. Many of the authors’ numbers may not have changed since the last update (because they had no new sales in that time period), but they all get recomputed nonetheless.</p>

<p>This is a very typical example of a batch pipeline. It has a scheduled update trigger at 1 a.m. every night, and an update granularity of the entire output.</p>

<h4 id="the-live-updating-table">The Live-Updating Table</h4>

<p>In this version of our top-selling authors pipeline, individual purchases are streamed in as they happen, via a stream processor like Apache Kafka. Every purchase on this stream triggers an update to the calculation of top-selling authors.</p>

<p>The update process uses each individual purchase to incrementally recompute the sales total for the relevant author. If an author has no new sales over a given span of updates, their sales total is not recomputed (though their rank in the top-selling authors may need to be updated).</p>

<p>This is an example of a precise streaming pipeline. The update trigger is the purchase event that is streamed in, and the update granularity is the sales total for a single author.</p>

<h2 id="the-declarative-data-lake">The Declarative Data Lake</h2>

<p>We previously discussed the idea of conceptualizing your <a href="https://nchammas.com/writing/modern-data-lake-database">data lake as a database</a>. And here we’ve shown how you can conceptualize your data pipelines as materialized views.</p>

<p>But what if we could take this idea further than just as a conceptual tool? What if you could actually implement your data pipelines as a graph of materialized views?</p>

<p>Taken far enough, the promise of such an idea would be to build a <em>declarative data lake</em>, where the code that manages the lake focuses more on defining <em>what</em> the datasets are and less on <em>how</em> to mechanically build or update them.</p>

<p>Two relatively new projects express aspects of this vision in clear but different ways, and they merit some discussion here: <a href="https://www.getdbt.com/">dbt</a> and <a href="https://materialize.com/">Materialize</a>.</p>

<h3 id="dbt-pipelines-as-batch-updated-sql-queries">dbt: Pipelines as Batch-Updated SQL Queries</h3>

<p>The core of <a href="https://www.getdbt.com/">dbt</a> is an engine for building <a href="https://docs.getdbt.com/docs/introduction#what-makes-dbt-so-powerful">a graph of SQL queries</a>. Parts of any given query can be generated dynamically using a templating language (<a href="https://docs.getdbt.com/tutorial/using-jinja/">Jinja</a>), and queries can reference other queries.</p>

<p>Every query has a configured materialization strategy, which defines whether the results of the query are generated ahead of time, and if so, how they are stored and updated.</p>

<p>If the results are materialized, they can be updated with a full refresh or <a href="https://docs.getdbt.com/docs/building-a-dbt-project/building-models/configuring-incremental-models/#understanding-incremental-models">incrementally</a>, though there are some restrictions on what kinds of updates can be done incrementally. Updates are typically triggered on a schedule.</p>

<h3 id="materialize-pipelines-as-live-updated-materialized-views">Materialize: Pipelines as Live-Updated Materialized Views</h3>

<p><a href="https://materialize.com/">Materialize</a> is an engine for building live, incrementally updated materialized views from streaming sources like Apache Kafka. A view can reference other live-updated views, as well as fixed tables.</p>

<p>The primary interface for creating these views is plain and elegant: A <a href="https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-materialized-view/"><code>CREATE MATERIALIZED VIEW</code></a> SQL statement.</p>

<p>Conceptually, this is roughly the same statement that is available in 
<a href="https://docs.oracle.com/en/database/oracle/oracle-database/21/sqlrf/CREATE-MATERIALIZED-VIEW.html">tradition…</a></p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view">https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26217911</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 22:26:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Trussed – a new Rust framework for security chips that could replace JavaCard]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26217528">thread link</a>) | @conorpp
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://trussed.dev/blog/trussed-announcement/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://trussed.dev/blog/trussed-announcement/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><article><p>Today’s the day: We’re very proud to announce <a href="https://trussed.dev/">Trussed</a>®, an open source framework for modern cryptographic applications, which powers the FIDO and PIV authenticators of the Bee firmware on the new Solo V2 security key by SoloKeys.</p><p>It’s written in Rust.</p><p><img src="https://trussed.dev/images/uploads/trussed-square-200.png" alt=""></p><h3 id="summary">Summary</h3><p>This announcement will give a high-level overview of the motivation for and design of Trussed. It will be followed soon by a “tutorial” of sorts, walking through an <a href="https://github.com/trussed-dev/trussed-totp-pc-tutorial">implementation of TOTP</a> (time-based one-time password, a commonly used second factor authentication method) in minimal form on PC.</p><p>We’re not just announcing, we’re also releasing the source code, dual-licensed under the Apache and MIT licenses, on GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/trussed-dev/trussed/">https://github.com/trussed-dev/trussed/</a>. This code is still very much a work in progress, and does not yet come with stable functionality or API promises. However, we think the time has come to continue further work in public, so we may learn from the open source community.</p><p>“We” here are not just SoloKeys, but also <a href="https://www.nitrokey.com/" title="Nitrokey">Nitrokey</a>, our competitor-slash-collaborator from Germany that has always used SoloKeys firmware in their web authentication products, and will continue to do so. <a href="https://www.nitrokey.com/" title="Nitrokey">Nitrokey</a> will have their own announcement on this topic and their further plans for security keys here.</p><p>Together, we loosely build the current “Trussed Alliance” of Trussed implementers, users, and evangelists. We are reachable by several means, for instance via email at <a href="mailto:alliance@trussed.dev">alliance@trussed.dev</a>, by Matrix chat in <a href="https://matrix.to/#/#trussed:matrix.org">#trussed:matrix.org</a>, or async at <a href="https://github.com/trussed-dev/trussed/discussions">github.com/trussed-dev/trussed/discussions</a>. We are very interested in and open to additional allies. Particularly, at this stage, those with strong (correct) opinions, and the drive to contribute to the implementation :)</p><h3 id="but-what-is-trussed">But what is Trussed?</h3><p>You may be aware of PKCS #11 (<a href="http://docs.oasis-open.org/pkcs11/pkcs11-ug/v2.40/pkcs11-ug-v2.40.html">usage guide</a>), which – despite all of its warts – is a standardized, high-level, platform-independent API, enabling software to make use of hardware-backed cryptography. There are other APIs in a similar spirit, such as <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/WebCryptoAPI/">WebCrypto</a> by the W3C (with its own warts, and notably relaying JavaScript applications to software implementations of cryptography), or <a href="https://github.com/parallaxsecond/parsec">PARSEC</a> (backed by Arm and Docker, which has a rather more grand scope).</p><p>All of these have in common that applications can outsource their cryptographic needs to a trusted third party implementation through a common API. Secret keys can be generated for various algorithms or mechanisms (symmetric cryptography such as AES, asymmetric cryptography such as P256, Ed25519, X25519, RSA, etc.). The application obtains not the sensitive key material, but instead a handle object, with which it can then perform further operations: sign data, verify signatures, encrypt or decrypt data, etc.</p><p>The core idea of Trussed is this: What if there were similar facilities – without the warts – right inside the firmware of embedded devices?</p><p>Thinking further: What if these were provided by idiomatic, misuse-resistant, best cryptographic practice-following APIs? What if the list of available cryptographic mechanisms, together with their software or hardware implementations, were flexibly configurable at compile time, but came with “batteries included”? What if this “crypto-in-a-box” would be easy to plug into whatever setup one is already using? What if applications, then, could focus on implementing their domain-specific logic and interfaces with the outside world, while taking advantage of <a href="https://www.imperialviolet.org/2016/05/16/agility.html">one cryptographic joint, kept well oiled.</a></p><p>And that is exactly what Trussed is!</p><h3 id="portable-trussed-apps">Portable Trussed apps</h3><p>You may see the term “Trussed app”. By this we mean any unit of firmware that uses the Trussed APIs, and otherwise is completely cross-platform (meanwhile, it will be called externally by the runtime/scheduler). To repeat, a Trussed app is called externally, but internally only calls Trussed APIs – this makes it portable to all platforms on which Trussed itself runs on.</p><p>Two prime examples would be the FIDO and PIV authenticator apps by SoloKeys. In the past (with the existing Solo V1 key C firmware), when others wanted to “somehow reuse” app code it didn’t really work – forks happened, or even simple copy-pastes. Similarly, Google’s FIDO2 implementation in <a href="https://github.com/google/OpenSK">OpenSK</a> is tightly coupled to the Tock OS around it, and limited to devices which have Tock OS support.</p><p>By decoupling from runtimes, and making minimal requirements on Trussed platforms, we envision that “Trussed apps” will be shareable between vendors (each adding their own runtime and physical product). That bug fixes and functionality additions can be shared. That alternative implementations of existing applications are possible (e.g., a <a href="https://github.com/dicekeys/seeding-webauthn">DiceKeys</a>-backed FIDO2 app).</p><p>Generally, we would like to open up an ecosystem of “Trussed apps” (WireGuard, password managers, GPG for those that like it, pocket HSMs, etc.), eventually replacing JavaCard and bringing embedded cryptographic firmware to the modern age.</p><h3 id="trussed-components">Trussed Components</h3><p>There are two major components in Trussed, the service, and the clients.</p><p>The service depends on platform resources (storage, entropy, UI facilities), bundles up cryptographic algorithm implementations at compile time, and is then just a beefy component with a “process” method. This method needs to be called by the runtime/scheduler, either regularly, or on-demand via a provided syscall abstraction.</p><p>The service’s storage is partitioned by client, and further by type of object the service is responsible for managing on a client’s behalf: A key store for cryptographic keys, a file store for binary metadata (exposed as a POSIX-ish filesystem interface), and a certificate store.</p><p>The clients correspondingly have APIs (for crypto, file and other needs) to send requests with, for instance a “CryptoClient + P256 + HmacSha256”. Client and service communicate via <a href="https://docs.rs/interchange">interchanges</a>, shared memory areas in which requests and replies are placed. Both the requests and replies are modeled as Rust types, so there is no low-level memory copying and length calculations. Additionally, interchanges serve as a strong demarcation between different privileged executions (such as the secure and nonsecure worlds in ARM TrustZone).</p><h3 id="what-is-trussed-not">What is Trussed not?</h3><p>Trussed intends to be a configurable box you can use with ease in your firmware, but it does not intend to take over your entire platform. It is not an embedded operating system. Trussed does not use the heap, all variables are allocated on the stack. Trussed does not internally use threads in any way, control flow is linear and predictable.</p><p>To create a functional product, besides a Trussed platform, you need to supply:</p><ul><li>runtime/scheduler: with SoloKeys, we use <a href="https://rtic.rs/">RTIC</a> (Real-Time Interrupt-driven Concurrency), which is a thin software wrapper around the Arm Cortex-M NVIC hardware scheduler. Conceivably, something like <a href="https://www.tockos.org/">Tock</a> should work, or threaded scheduling on PC</li><li>interfaces: with SoloKeys, we use <a href="https://docs.rs/usb-device">usb-device</a> as a framework to implement USB classes (CTAPHID, CCID) on top of our <a href="https://github.com/lpc55/lpc55-hal">LPC55 HAL</a> (hardware abstraction layer), and our own NFC device framework</li><li>dispatch: depending on the richness of the runtime, there may be separate need to dispatch between multiple interfaces and multiple applications</li><li>secure manufacturing: Trussed has the concept of “device attestation”, binding a unique identifier for the chip it runs on to private device attestation keys (Ed255 + P256), via a vendor certificate authority. Further it has a concept of “key attestation”, attesting keys on the device as being generated on the device and not being extractable, via the device attestation keys and certificates. While Trussed exposes methods to do this, they rely on preparations that depend on the platform and need to be done in the manufacturing process.</li><li>optionally, a secure signed firmware update procedure: conceivably, Trussed might be used in a custom bootloader, but the compile-time security of Trussed comes from firmware “bundles” being verified by a vendor. There needs to be a way to ensure any changes to the firmware are “atomic” and authorized, replacing the entire bundle of runner + apps + Trussed with a new non-compromised setup (operating on the existing data).</li></ul><h3 id="first-implementation">First Implementation</h3><p>SoloKeys <a href="https://solokeys.com/blogs/news/our-solo-v2-campaign-launches-on-january-26th">will be releasing the first products built with Trussed</a>. Their Solo v2 authenticators are fully open source and designed for enterprise use for FIDO2 and PIV. More applications are to follow, all based on Trussed.</p><p><img src="https://trussed.dev/images/uploads/solov2.png" alt="Solo V2" title="Solo V2"></p><h3 id="what-about-the-trademark">What about the trademark?</h3><p>To conclude, we would like to explain why Trussed sometimes has a registered trademark symbol next to it. First off, as mentioned, the source code itself is permissively dual-licensed. There is no intent for any “open core” kind of license/monetization scheme (some reasoning that resonates is <a href="https://250bpm.com/blog:15/">here</a>). We consider the ideas expressed in Trussed to be public domain, and really just an (ongoing) distillation of best practices.</p><p>However, when a vendor wishes to sell a product, and advertise that it is “Built on Trussed”, has “Trussed® Inside”, or similar (in effect, profit from the trust we will build in Trussed!), we would like to be able to ensure that basic requirements are fulfilled for the platform, applications and product manufacturing chain – this is needed to make a secure product.</p><p>As an example, Trussed ensures keys are kept secret by storing them encrypted-at-rest at all times. It can do so either by using a backing storage that is encrypted by hardware, or adding a software encryption layer itself – one or the other, but it needs to be ensured.</p><p>As another example, Trussed needs a source of entropy. Ideally, a platform has a hardware source, alternatively, the manufacturing process can inject an entropic seed – again, one or the other (or both) need to be ensured.</p><p>To sum up, we hope that you find use for Trussed in your products. The more eyes, the better! If you do use Trussed, we’d like you to advertise that you do. In this case, please contact <a href="mailto:alliance@trussed.dev">alliance@trussed.dev</a> so we can discuss. There is no formal certification process at this point.</p><h3 id="some-more-details-about-portability">Some more details about portability</h3><p>Cryptographic implementations …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://trussed.dev/blog/trussed-announcement/">https://trussed.dev/blog/trussed-announcement/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://trussed.dev/blog/trussed-announcement/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26217528</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 21:42:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Porting a React library 1:1 to Svelte – It might be easier than you think]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26217119">thread link</a>) | @micha-lmxt
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://gradientdescent.de/porting-react | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gradientdescent.de/porting-react">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Svelte lures developers with the promise of better performance and smaller bundle size than competitors like React. But, since it is new, its eco-system is small. Let's change that!
    </p>
<p>There are many differences between Svelte and React. Svelte is a compiler, while React lives in the browser. Svelte components are written into '.svelte' files, while React uses <code><code>jsx</code></code>/<code><code>tsx</code></code>. React has the virtual DOM while, Svelte doesn't. So, are these frameworks so different, that we have to write every library from scratch?
    </p>
<p>No.
    </p>
<p>I took a React library, which I like, and translated it to Svelte. It is a good excercise to see what the real differences between React and Svelte are, and to see which concepts are related. The library I chose is <a href="https://github.com/bvaughn/react-virtualized-auto-sizer"><code><code>react-virtualized-auto-sizer</code></code></a>. It has unimpressive 295 stars as a standalone library at github, but it belongs to the <code><code>react-virtualized</code></code> library, which is currently at 21 thousand stars. For comparison, the highest rated Svelte specific library besides Svelte and Sapper is <code><code>svelte-material-ui</code></code> with 1.5k stars. The <code><code>auto-sizer</code></code> allows your component to grow or shrink to the available space on your page.
    </p>
<img alt="An image of a port, with a ship and a crane." title="Port" src="https://gradientdescent.de/images/port.jpg">
<h2 id="PortingAuto-Sizer">Porting Auto-Sizer
    </h2>

<blockquote>
      
    </blockquote>
<p>The library <code><code>react-virtualized-auto-sizer</code></code> has only one exported component, so it is quite a low-hanging fruit to port. It is older, so it is implemented as a React class component. React component have more lifecycle methods than in Svelte, so it may be hard or impossible to reproduce the same behavior. In this case it will be no problem.
    </p>

<h3 id="AutoSizercomponent">AutoSizer component
    </h3>

<p>There are only two files of interest in the library. The first file is <code><code>src/vendor/detectElementResize.js</code></code> and it contains only code, that is independent of React. So, I could simply copy it into my project. The other file is <code><code>src/index.js</code></code>. The author used <a href="https://flow.org/">Flow</a> for static type checking, so it starts with a lot of type definitions. Other than that, the file just holds the component source code.
    </p>
<p>In the root of my new project <a href="https://github.com/micha-lmxt/svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer"><code><code>svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer</code></code></a> I create a file <code><code>AutoSizer.svelte</code></code>.
    </p>
<h4 id="Props">Props
    </h4>

<p>First, in the scripts part I've put all props of the React component, except children and style. Both of these are handled a bit differently in Svelte. Some of the props have a default, so I copied that over:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// react-virtualized-auto-sizer/src/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>export</span><span> </span><span>default</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>AutoSizer</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> React</span><span>.</span><span>PureComponent</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Props</span><span>,</span><span> State</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>static</span><span> defaultProps </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>onResize</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{},</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>disableHeight</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>false</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>disableWidth</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>false</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>style</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>{},</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>}</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>This becomes the following:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;script&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    export let onResize = () =&gt; </span><span>{}</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>    export let disableHeight = false;</span></span>
<span><span>    export let disableWidth = false;</span></span>
<span><span>    export let className = "";</span></span>
<span><span>    export let defaultHeight = undefined;</span></span>
<span><span>    export let defaultWidth = undefined;</span></span>
<span><span>    export let nonce = undefined;</span></span>
<span><span>    ...</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;/script&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<h4 id="State">State
    </h4>

<p>The React component defines a state variable and a few class member:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// react-virtualized-auto-sizer/src/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>state</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>height</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>props</span><span>.</span><span>defaultHeight</span><span> </span><span>||</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>width</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>props</span><span>.</span><span>defaultWidth</span><span> </span><span>||</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>}</span><span>;</span></span>

<span><span>  _parentNode</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>?</span><span>HTMLElement</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>_autoSizer</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>?</span><span>HTMLElement</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>_detectElementResize</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>DetectElementResize</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>which both become simple state variables in Svelte:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>defaultHeight</span><span> </span><span>||</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>defaultWidth</span><span> </span><span>||</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>_parentNode</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>_autoSizer</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>_detectElementResize</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>

<h4 id="componentDidMountandcomponentWillUnmount">componentDidMount and componentWillUnmount
    </h4>

<p>The code from the <code><code>componentDidMount</code></code> and <code><code>componentWillUnmount</code></code> member functions is put into Sveltes <code><code>onMount</code></code> and <code><code>onDestroy</code></code> callbacks respecitvely.
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// react-virtualized-auto-sizer/src/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>componentDidMount</span><span>() </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>nonce</span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>props</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>if</span><span> (</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>_autoSizer</span><span> </span><span>&amp;&amp;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>The variable unloading (<code><code>const {nonce}...</code></code>) is deleted and also all <code><code>this</code></code>-s are also removed (thank you vs-code find-and-replace function :) ):
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>onMount</span><span>(</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>if</span><span> (</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>_autoSizer</span><span> </span><span>&amp;&amp;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<h4 id="_onResize">_onResize
    </h4>

<p>The "<code><code>_onResize = () =&gt; {...</code></code>" member becomes a const function "<code><code>const _onResize = () =&gt; {...</code></code>". Again, props unloading is deleted. The React component uses <code><code>width</code></code> and <code><code>height</code></code> again, so I had to rename the new consts to <code><code>width_</code></code> and <code><code>height_</code></code>. And the <code><code>setState</code></code> part is changed:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// react-virtualized-auto-sizer/src/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>if</span><span> (</span></span>
<span><span>        (</span><span>!</span><span>disableHeight</span><span> </span><span>&amp;&amp;</span><span> </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>state</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>!==</span><span> </span><span>newHeight</span><span>) </span><span>||</span></span>
<span><span>        (</span><span>!</span><span>disableWidth</span><span> </span><span>&amp;&amp;</span><span> </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>state</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>!==</span><span> </span><span>newWidth</span><span>)</span></span>
<span><span>      ) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>setState</span><span>(</span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>          </span><span>height</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingTop</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingBottom</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>          </span><span>width</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingLeft</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingRight</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>to simple assignment:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>if</span><span> (</span></span>
<span><span>        (</span><span>!</span><span>disableHeight</span><span> </span><span>&amp;&amp;</span><span> </span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>!==</span><span> </span><span>newHeight</span><span>) </span><span>||</span></span>
<span><span>        (</span><span>!</span><span>disableWidth</span><span> </span><span>&amp;&amp;</span><span> </span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>!==</span><span> </span><span>newWidth</span><span>)</span></span>
<span><span>    ) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>height_</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingTop</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingBottom</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>width_</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingLeft</span><span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>paddingRight</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<h4 id="render">render
    </h4>

<p>So far, there have been no significant changes. Syntax is a little bit different, but not much. For the <code><code>render</code></code> function we got a little more to do. Let's break this down to four steps.
    </p>
<p>Step 1 - Styling: The React code defines a <code><code>outerStyle</code></code> object
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>  </span><span>render</span><span>() </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>   </span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>outerStyle</span><span>:</span><span> Object </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>overflow</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>'</span><span>visible</span><span>'</span><span>}</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>and in the code the height and the width of this style object can be set to 0. In Svelte, inline styling is not supplied as an object, but as a string. An equivalent implementation is straight forward, but I take a different route here, since Svelte makes it easier to avoid inline styling. I create two boolean variables <code><code>let outerstylewidth = false, outerstyleheight = false</code></code>, which are set to true, when the <code><code>width</code></code> or <code><code>height</code></code> style would have been set to 0 by the React component. Then I add the following style element to the <code><code>.svelte</code></code> file and make the two classes conditional with the <a href="https://svelte.dev/tutorial/classes"><code><code>class:</code></code> directive</a>:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;style&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    div {</span></span>
<span><span>        overflow: visible;</span></span>
<span><span>    }</span></span>
<span><span>    .outerstylewidth {</span></span>
<span><span>        width:0;</span></span>
<span><span>    }</span></span>
<span><span>    .outerstyleheight{</span></span>
<span><span>        height:0;</span></span>
<span><span>    }</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;/style&gt;</span></span>

<span><span>&lt;div class={className} class:outerstylewidth class:outerstyleheight bind:this={_autoSizer}&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>Step 2 - ref -&gt; bind: I use the The <a href="https://svelte.dev/tutorial/bind-this"><code><code>bind:this</code></code> directive</a> as an exchange for the <code><code>ref</code></code>-logic. Note that this makes the <code><code>_setRef</code></code> member function unecessary.
    </p>

<p>Step 3 - make render code reactive: The logic part of the <code><code>render</code></code> function is marked as reactive, since it is called each time something changes:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>childParams</span><span>:</span><span> Object </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{}</span><span>;</span></span>

<span><span>    </span><span>// Avoid rendering children before the initial measurements have been collected.</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>// At best this would just be wasting cycles.</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>false;</span></span>

<span><span>    </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>!</span><span>disableHeight</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>===</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>true;</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>outerStyle</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>childParams</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>height</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>}</span></span>

<span><span>    </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>!</span><span>disableWidth</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>===</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>true;</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>outerStyle</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>childParams</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>width</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>To:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>childParams</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{}</span><span>;</span></span>

<span><span>    </span><span>// Avoid rendering children before the initial measurements have been collected.</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>// At best this would just be wasting cycles.</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>false</span><span>,</span><span>  </span><span>outerstylewidth</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>false</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>outerstyleheight</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>false;</span></span>

<span><span>    $</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>false;</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>!</span><span>disableHeight</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>===</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>                </span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>true;</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>outerstyleheight</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>true;</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>childParams</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>height</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>}</span></span>

<span><span>        </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>!</span><span>disableWidth</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>if</span><span> (</span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>===</span><span> </span><span>0</span><span>) </span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>                </span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>true;</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>outerstylewidth</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>true;</span></span>
<span><span>            </span><span>childParams</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>width</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;/</span><span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>Step 4 return -&gt; html: Finally, the return statement
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>return</span><span> (</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>&lt;div</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>className</span><span>={</span><span>className</span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>ref</span><span>={this</span><span>.</span><span>_setRef</span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>style</span><span>={</span><span>{</span></span>
<span><span>          </span><span>...</span><span>outerStyle</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>          </span><span>...</span><span>style</span><span>,</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>}</span><span>}&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>{!</span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span> </span><span>&amp;&amp;</span><span> </span><span>children</span><span>(</span><span>childParams</span><span>)</span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>      </span><span>&lt;/div&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    )</span><span>;</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>is straight forward translated to this code. The <code><code>{#if}</code></code> statement replaces the <code><code>{...&amp;&amp;...}</code></code> part and children translate to slot:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.js</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;div</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span>={</span><span>className</span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span>:</span><span>outerstylewidth</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span>:</span><span>outerstyleheight</span><span> </span><span>bind</span><span>:</span><span>this</span><span>={</span><span>_autoSizer</span><span>}&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>{</span><span>#</span><span>if</span><span> </span><span>!</span><span>bailoutOnChildren</span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>        </span><span>&lt;slot</span><span> </span><span>width</span><span>={</span><span>childParams</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>height</span><span>={</span><span>childParams</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>/&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    </span><span>{/</span><span>if</span><span>}</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;/div&gt;</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<h4 id="Types">Types
    </h4>

<p>Typescript declarations make the life of the consumer of the library easier. The types of the React library are stored within the definitelyTyped project <code><code>@types/react-virtualized-auto-sizer</code></code>.
    </p>
<p>The React component is changed into a Svelte component:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// @types/react-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.d.ts</span></span>
<span><span>import</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>React</span><span> </span><span>from</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>react</span><span>"</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>export</span><span> </span><span>default</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>React</span><span>.</span><span>Component</span><span>&lt;</span><span>AutoSizerProps</span><span>&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{}</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>To:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>/// svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer/index.d.ts</span></span>
<span><span>import</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span>SvelteComponentTyped</span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>from</span><span> </span><span>'</span><span>svelte</span><span>'</span><span>;</span></span>
<span><span>...</span></span>
<span><span>export</span><span> </span><span>default</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span> </span><span>extends</span><span> </span><span>SvelteComponentTyped</span><span>&lt;</span><span>AutoSizerProps</span><span>,{},{</span><span>default</span><span>:</span><span>{</span><span>width</span><span>?:</span><span>number</span><span>,</span><span>height</span><span>?:</span><span>number</span><span>}}&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{}</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<h4 id="Howtouseit">How to use it
    </h4>

<p>That's it, the library is ported. You can load the library with
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>npm install --save-dev svelte-virtualized-auto-sizer</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>This is how you would use the original in React:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>&lt;AutoSizer&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    {(height,width)=&gt;(</span></span>
<span><span>    &lt;div style={{!width!}}&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>      Test</span></span>
<span><span>    &lt;/div&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    )}</span></span>
<span><span>&lt;/AutoSizer&gt;</span></span></code></p>
      
    </pre>
<p>and here is the equivalent in Svelte, using the <a href="https://svelte.dev/tutorial/slot-props"><code><code>let:</code></code> directive</a>:
    </p>
<pre><p><code><span><span>&lt;AutoSizer let:width={childWidth} let:height={childHeight}&gt;</span></span>
<span><span>    &lt;div style={"width:"+childWidth+"px;height:"…</span></span></code></p></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://gradientdescent.de/porting-react">https://gradientdescent.de/porting-react</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gradientdescent.de/porting-react</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26217119</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 20:57:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Introduction to Crystal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26217013">thread link</a>) | @thejokersthief
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://blog.oisinaylward.me/blog/crystal/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.oisinaylward.me/blog/crystal/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>February 21, 2021</p><p><span>
      <a href="https://blog.oisinaylward.me/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/3684f/crystal.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Crystal logo" title="Crystal logo" src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/8a901d72da53e5eb6edcf11dce08acb6818f1731/a9b08/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/3684f/crystal.png" srcset="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/9076bceecd20a42a2fcc6f79b977cd7842af0266/e2060/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/12f09/crystal.png 148w,https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/8a901d72da53e5eb6edcf11dce08acb6818f1731/a9b08/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/3684f/crystal.png 225w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p><p>One of my favourite programming languages in the last few years has been <a href="https://crystal-lang.org/">Crystal</a>. While the language has not yet reached its 1.0 version, it has been widely used in production and has a growing ecosystem. Crystal provides an easy setup and allows you to jump straight into developing your own Crystal programs. I’m going to walk you through getting it setup and how you can get started!</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">puts "Hello World"</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>Crystal is a general purpose, Ruby-inspired compiled programming language, making it extremely fast and easy to program with. The syntax is strongly inspired by Ruby, but also provides static typechecking. Crystal sits somewhere in the top 100 programming languages according to <a href="https://www.tiobe.com/tiobe-index/">TIOBE</a>, not widely used but don’t let that put you off!</p><p>I was originally interested in Crystal due to its expressive syntax and the claims on its speed. I am likely in the minority in that I came into Crystal with no prior Ruby experience. Crystal soon became my go-to language for personal programming projects. My project <a href="https://github.com/azula-lang/azula">Azula</a> (WIP programming language) was built entirely in Crystal - a choice a made due to Crystal’s nice macro system and built-in LLVM bindings. Crystal was an excellent choice, allowing rapid development and producing a small binary (1.9mb in Crystal vs 3mb in Go).</p><h3>Shards</h3><p>The Crystal ecosystem is powered by its Shard system. Shards is Crystal’s dependency manager that is usually installed along with Crystal. It aims to allow reproducible installs across platforms by declaring dependencies and their versions. You can read more about Shards <a href="https://crystal-lang.org/reference/the_shards_command/index.html">here</a>.</p><h2>Installing Crystal</h2><p>On Ubuntu, installing Crystal is as easy as running:</p><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ curl -fsSL https://crystal-lang.org/install.sh | sudo bash</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>For other platforms, have a look at the <a href="https://crystal-lang.org/install/">Crystal install guide</a>!</p><h2>First Crystal Program</h2><p>Crystal provides a nice scaffolding tool to setup a new project, including a README template, license and gitignore.</p><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ crystal init app myproject</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>If we open up <code>myproject/src/myproject.cr</code>, we can start writing our Crystal program!</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">def say(message : String)
    puts message
end

say "Hello!"</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>In this example, we create a function called <code>say</code> that accepts a string and passes it to <code>puts</code>. As you can see, almost identical to Ruby except for the typing of the parameter in the function.</p><h2>Project Structure</h2><h3>src</h3><p>Inside the <code>src/</code> directory is where all the Crystal files will go. It can contain subdirectories, allowing you to divide up your code. You can include separate files by using the <code>require</code> keyword.</p><h3>spec</h3><p>The <code>spec/</code> directory is the home for your tests. Using the <code>crystal spec</code> subcommand, we can run all our tests.</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">it "works" do
    i = 5 + 10
    i.should eq 15
end</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><h3>shard.yml</h3><p><code>shard.yml</code> is used to define our project. In here, we define the name, version, authors, Crystal version, licence &amp; dependencies.</p><deckgo-highlight-code yaml="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">name: myproject
version: 0.1.0

authors:
  - OisinA

targets:
  myproject:
    main: src/myproject.cr

crystal: 0.36.1

license: MIT</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><h2>Building &amp; Running</h2><h3>Running</h3><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ crystal run src/myproject.cr
Hello!</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>Running your Crystal project is as simple as running <code>crystal run [file]</code>.</p><h3>Building</h3><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ crystal build src/myproject.cr
$ ./myproject
Hello!</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>To build your project, you use <code>crystal build [file]</code> producing an executable. You can optionally use the <code>--release</code> optimising the executable. This flag will significantly increase the build time but the produced binary should be smaller and faster.</p><p>Crystal’s build times are reasonable. Compiling my project <a href="https://github.com/azula-lang/azula">Azula</a> takes ~16s with the release flag. Compiling our barebones project above takes ~8s.</p><h2>Example</h2><h3>Simple Web Server</h3><p>In this example, I am using <a href="https://github.com/kemalcr/kemal">Kemal</a>, a HTTP framework for Crystal, to set up a really simple web server to return some JSON on a request. Kemal makes it really easy to quickly write a web application and has built-in JSON support, static file serving and templating. Kemal is installed using Crystal Shards, adding it to the <code>shards.yml</code>.</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">require "kemal"
require "json"

get "/" do |env|
    env.response.content_type = "application/json"
    {name: "Oisin", time: Time.local}.to_json
end

Kemal.run</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>Running this will start up a HTTP server on port 3000, returning JSON containing name and the current time.</p><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ curl http://localhost:3000
{"name":"Oisin","time":"2021-02-21T18:07:46+00:00"}</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>It’s as simple as that!</p><h2>The Future of Crystal</h2><p>With Crystal being in a nice place at the moment - what are the next steps? The next step for Crystal is to reach a 1.0 release. This version of Crystal will be completely stable and fully ready for production. The Crystal team are currently working towards this goal currently. While there is no timeline in place, its an exciting prospect! I am excited for the future of Crystal and hope to see it more widely used.</p><h2>Resources</h2><p>If you’ve enjoyed this blog post, you might be interested in reading more about Crystal and its ecosystem. I’ll list some links here and feel free to reach out to me on <a href="https://twitter.com/oisinaylward">Twitter</a> if you have any questions!</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/veelenga/awesome-crystal">Awesome Crystal List</a> A big list of Crystal code and resources</li><li><a href="https://crystal-lang.org/reference/index.html">Crystal Reference</a> The Crystal Team’s own language reference</li><li><a href="https://crystal-lang.org/api/">Crystal API Docs</a> Crystal’s API docs for working with the standard library</li></ul><h3>Footnotes:</h3><ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/osslate">@osslate</a>
For proof-reading and giving nice criticism &lt;3</li><li><a href="https://crystal-lang.org/2020/03/03/towards-crystal-1.0.html">Towards 1.0</a>
Information about Crystal’s upcoming 1.0 release</li></ul><hr><ul><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.oisinaylward.me/blog/crystal/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26217013</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 20:47:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to design a motherboard for your electronics project]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 53 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26215270">thread link</a>) | @frenchie4111
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content_area">
    <div>
        
            
        

        
             <h2>-1. Overview</h2>
<p> After the prototyping phase of any electronics project, I like to make a "Motherboard" PCB. For this phase I will continue to use breakout boards for all of the individual components, but link them together using a PCB. This allows the PCB design to stay simple and flexible, and makes them easy to hand manufacture them in my workshop. This is a great setup if you want to do a small (10ish) beta run of your project before designing a full product. I have shipped many hardware products using this stage, it's a great way to validate your MVP before putting money into tooling and CM bring up. </p> <p> This tutorial will walk through the process that I follow to create a motherboard. The intended audience is someone who has already wired up a prototype on a breadboard, and wants to get started bundling them together into a motherboard. This will be the guide I wish existed when I got started doing this. </p>
 <p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/4018eef6e0333515d064a35fe2336c2858a216c3/83757/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/thermostat-motherboard.jpeg"></p><p>Here is an example of the motherboard I designed for my <a href="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/caffstat_beta">Thermostat</a> project </p>
<p> This is just the process I figured out for myself, it's by no means perfect. If you have any feedback or questions about any of this stuff, want a PCB design for your project, or just want to chat, feel free to reach out to me: mdl0394@gmail.com </p>
<p> This is Part 1 of the guide. In this guide we will go through initial setup, component model sourcing and schematic design. In Part 2 we will go through board layout and ordering PCBs. If you want to be notified when Part 2 comes out, sign up for email notifications, or subscribe to the RSS feed. </p> 
            <div>
    <p>

    Thanks for reading! If you want to stay updated feel free to follow the <a href="https://staycaffeinated.com/feed.xml">RSS feed</a>, if you have any suggestions feel free to email me at <a href="mailto:mdl0394@gmail.com">mdl0394@gmail.com</a></p><p>
    

    You could also submit your email here, and I will personally email you whenever I post new things:

    </p>
</div>

        

        <h2>Table of Contents</h2>
        <ul><li><a href="#0-before-you-build-a-pcb">0. Before you build a PCB</a><ul><li><a href="#01-installing-eagle">0.1 Installing Eagle</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#1-anatomy-of-a-pcb-design">1. Anatomy of a PCB Design</a></li><li><a href="#2-finding-or-creating-component-models">2. Finding or Creating Component Models</a><ul><li><a href="#21-octopart">2.1. Octopart</a></li><li><a href="#22-desparate-googling">2.2. Desparate Googling</a></li><li><a href="#23-installing-a-library">2.3. Installing a library</a></li><li><a href="#24-creating-your-own-library">2.4. Creating your own Library</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#3-creating-your-schematic">3. Creating your Schematic</a><ul><li><a href="#31-basic-project-setup">3.1. Basic Project Setup</a></li><li><a href="#32-place-your-components">3.2. Place your components</a></li><li><a href="#33-placing-the-ground-label">3.3. Placing the Ground Label</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#34-wiring-using-labels">3.4. Wiring using Labels</a><ul><li><a href="#35-reviewing-your-schematic">3.5. Reviewing your Schematic</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#40-part-2-board-layout---coming-soon">4.0 Part 2 (Board Layout) - Coming Soon</a></li></ul>


        <h2 id="0-before-you-build-a-pcb">0. Before you build a PCB</h2>

<p>Before you build a PCB you should already have all of the breakout boards &amp; devkits you want to use for the project. When designing the motherboard you should already have a good understanding of how the electronics components are wired together, if you donâ€™t itâ€™s easy to make costly mistakes.</p>

<p>For this project I will be using my Caffstat (Hackable Smart Home Thermostat) project. If you are interested in a smart home thermostat feel free to check out that <a href="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/caffstat_beta">project here</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7eacc185287abd48aa4bca8d5f02bff250b987d9/def8e/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/untitled.png" alt="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7eacc185287abd48aa4bca8d5f02bff250b987d9/def8e/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/untitled.png">
<img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%201.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%201.png">
<img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%202.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%202.png"></p>

<p>These 3 images represent the stages of any electronics project: Breadboard -&gt; Project Board -&gt; PCB</p>

<p>This project contains 3 different breakout boards and a few through hole components. The brains of the operation are an ESP32 Devkit, there are breakouts for the Thermostat and Screen, and through hold components for the buttons, resistors, and relays.</p>

<h3 id="01-installing-eagle">0.1 Installing Eagle</h3>

<p>For this tutorial I will we be using Eagle. Itâ€™s got a free tier tool that, and it integrates well into the Autodesk suite. Eagle is free for up to two layer boards, which should be all you need for most electronics projects. The information here will be pretty generally applicable to any tool, although the screenshots will be of eagle specifically.</p>

<p>You can download eagle for free <a href="https://www.autodesk.com/products/eagle/overview">here</a></p>

<h2 id="1-anatomy-of-a-pcb-design">1. Anatomy of a PCB Design</h2>

<p>A PCB Design contains two main parts, the schematic and the layout. The schematic is an abstract diagram of the connections between components in your project, and the layout is the actual physical layout of those components, and the electrical traces that connect them. The great thing about PCB design software, is that the schematic will be enforced when you are creating the layout, this makes it very straight forward to create the layout after youâ€™ve created the schematic.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%203.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%203.png"></p>

<p>This is the completed schematic for the caffstat project. You can see all of the breakout boards as individual components (red). The connections between them are mostly being managed by net labels to simplify the schematic (more on this later).</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%204.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%204.png"></p>

<p>Here is an image of the completed layout. Every component has found a space on the board, and all of the electrical traces have been drawn. Donâ€™t worry if it looks complicated/messy now, when we go step by step it will be very easy to create.</p>

<h2 id="2-finding-or-creating-component-models">2. Finding or Creating Component Models</h2>

<p>Before you can begin drawing a schematic and layout, you need to find or create models for each and every one of your components. A device model contains both a <strong>symbol</strong> for part (goes in the schematic) and a <strong>footprint</strong> of the part (for the layout). I will list out some great resources for finding or creating these here. I can create a full tutorial for creating your own component models if you are interested, let me know at mdl0394@gmail.com</p>

<p>One thing to note is that Eagle comes pre-packaged with a bunch of common components. These are mostly things like standard resistors/capacitors. Itâ€™s worth checking the pre-installed library before spending too much time scouring the internet. The easiest way to check the library is to use the â€œAdd Partâ€� button discussed in section 3.2 of this tutorial.</p>

<h3 id="21-octopart">2.1. Octopart</h3>

<p>The best tool I have found for looking up components and downloading models is <a href="https://octopart.com/">Octopart</a>. Their mission is to provide the best search engine for electronics components. Almost every part can be found in the search engine, I always check here first.</p>

<p>If octopart has the CAD Model for your part, it will appear like this, you want to download the Eagle format, this will download the library that you can install later.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%205.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%205.png"></p>

<h3 id="22-desparate-googling">2.2. Desparate Googling</h3>

<p>I have also found quite a few schematics by just googling the part. It can often be helpful to try different variations on the name, and include the term â€œEagleâ€� or â€œ.lbrâ€� (Eagle library file extension) in your query. If you do find a schematic, make sure you do some measurements (you can do this on the layout of your design) to ensure it matches well with your part (sometimes people upload bad designs, or are modeling something slightly different than yours, you donâ€™t want to order a PCB with bad footprints)</p>

<h3 id="23-installing-a-library">2.3. Installing a library</h3>

<p>Once you have a library itâ€™s easy to install, drag the Library (.lbr) file into the <code>libraries</code> section of the Eagle Control Panel. <strong>Important:</strong> after dragging the lbr file, make sure you right click and hit â€œUseâ€� otherwise you wonâ€™t actually be able to add it to your project. Libraries in use will have a green dot next to them</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%206.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%206.png"></p>

<h3 id="24-creating-your-own-library">2.4. Creating your own Library</h3>

<p>If you fail to find any schematics online (often the case with cheap breakout boards, or with chinese knockoffs) you might have to make your own. Itâ€™s not too hard to make your own models, mostly just a little bit tedious. Creating your own models &amp; libraries is a full tutorial in itself, if I get interest I can put that together, for now I will refer you to the resources I used to learn the process.</p>

<p>A good tutorial on how to make custom eagle components can be found here: <a href="https://www.build-electronic-circuits.com/eagle-components/">https://www.build-electronic-circuits.com/eagle-components/</a></p>

<h2 id="3-creating-your-schematic">3. Creating your Schematic</h2>

<p>Once you have your components, you can start creating your schematic.</p>

<h3 id="31-basic-project-setup">3.1. Basic Project Setup</h3>

<p>First thing is to make a new Project and new Schematic in eagle. Go into the projects section, right click and hit â€œNew Projectâ€�. Then right click and hit â€œNew Schematicâ€�. Once the schematic opens, you also want to create a layout (Weâ€™ll use this in Step 4). Do this by hitting the â€œGenerate/Switch to Boardâ€� button on the top bar.</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/6647e677a7889893fc65d08499400076efd2adee/d3801/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/screen_shot_2021-01-18_at_9.26.13_am.png" alt="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/6647e677a7889893fc65d08499400076efd2adee/d3801/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/screen_shot_2021-01-18_at_9.26.13_am.png"></p>

<h3 id="32-place-your-components">3.2. Place your components</h3>

<p>Once you have a schematic you need to put all of your part symbols on. The add part button is on the left bar, clicking this will bring up a dialogue that lets you choose a component. If you donâ€™t see a component you installed here, go back to the control panel and make sure you selected â€œUseâ€� on the right click menu.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%207.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%207.png"></p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%208.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%208.png"></p>

<p>Add all of your components to your schematic. Make sure you give yourself a bunch of room around components to create connections. You should also try to sort the parts in logical groupings, the simpler your schematic, the less likely-hood of bugs.</p>

<p>While placing components there are a few useful tools at your disposal. The Move, Rotate and Copy tools at the top of the left panel are all useful for organizing your schematic. When you want to select an object, the easiest thing to do is to click the + symbol (probably either at the center, or the origin of the part).</p>

<p>Here is what my schematic looks like after I have placed all of my parts.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%209.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%209.png"></p>

<h3 id="33-placing-the-ground-label">3.3. Placing the Ground Label</h3>

<p>The standard for schematics is to use a specialty component to label the shared ground. You can find this by searching â€œgndâ€� in the Add Part menu.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2010.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2010.png"></p>

<p>I will usually place one of these per component, just off the bottom of the component, and wire them to the ground pin.</p>

<h2 id="34-wiring-using-labels">3.4. Wiring using Labels</h2>

<p>You can directly connect parts together using the â€œNetâ€� tool (Green line) however with more than a few parts, this will very quickly become unmanageable. Instead of doing that, I will show you how to use labels to cleanly connect parts together. Note that for some components I will not use labels for connections, this makes sense for analog circuits, or things like pull down resistors because they can be logically grouped together.</p>

<p>For every node that I want to connect, I will first draw a one or two unit Net. Like so:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2011.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2011.png"></p>

<p>Then using the â€œNameâ€� tool I will name all of the new nets something that makes them easier to keep track of. To name a net, select the tool, then select the green line for the net, a text dialogue should …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1">https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26215270</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 17:23:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Please do not put IP addresses into DNS MX records]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 205 | Comments 161 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26215112">thread link</a>) | @hannob
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://blog.hboeck.de/archives/904-Please-do-not-put-IP-addresses-into-DNS-MX-records.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.hboeck.de/archives/904-Please-do-not-put-IP-addresses-into-DNS-MX-records.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
            <div>
                <!-- s9ymdb:498 --><p><img width="225" height="300" src="https://blog.hboeck.de/uploads/postbox.jpg" alt="Postbox">I want to highlight a common misconfiguration in the DNS records for e-mail servers.<img src="https://ssl-vg03.met.vgwort.de/na/a108fe84457f4d03abf3877bee3dad9f" width="1" height="1" alt=""></p><p>

When a domain is configured to receive mails usually a DNS record of the type MX is configured pointing to the host name of the mail server.</p><p>

Notably, according to the respective <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1035">RFC 1035</a> the MX record must contain a domain name and may not directly point to an IP address. However some mail servers do configure an IP address. Many mail servers are lenient when it comes to this misconfiguration and will deliver mails nevertheless, so this may stay undetected.</p><p>

I happen to use a mail server that is less forgiving (Courier), and every now and then I cannot send a mail due to this. It’s rare, but it does happen. If your mail server has such a configuration you may not receive some legitimate e-mails.</p><p>

So I’m hoping to raise some awareness and get some of those servers fixed.</p><ul><li>Obviously if you run a mail and DNS server please don’t do this and correctly set your MX records.</li><li>If you do any kind of IT service or consulting that is related to mail and DNS servers this is a good thing to add to your list of things to check regularly (here's a <a href="https://github.com/hannob/ipmx">very simple python script you can use</a>).</li><li>If you run any form of service or tool that checks DNS and mail servers for misconfigurations, please add a check for IP addresses in MX records and warn your users. Unfortunately only few services do this currently (thanks to <a href="https://www.hardenize.com/">Hardenize</a> and <a href="https://intodns.com/">IntoDNS</a> who will warn users about this), and some popular services don’t.</li></ul><p>

I did a quick scan of the Alexa Top 1 Million list. Currently <a href="https://github.com/hannob/ipmx/blob/main/scans/ipmx-2021-02-20.txt">around 0,06 % are affected</a> (if you happen to know someone responsible for a host on this list please consider pointing them to this blogpost). I hope by writing this I can reduce that number, I may later try to contact them via their postmaster alias.</p><p>

(<a href="https://nohat.cc/f/post-box-mailbox-letterbox-mail-box-postage/4671034800209920-201811091927.html">Image source: nohat.cc / CC0</a>)
            </p></div>

            
            
            
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.hboeck.de/archives/904-Please-do-not-put-IP-addresses-into-DNS-MX-records.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26215112</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 17:07:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Alice 4 FPGA Rasterizer (Open Hardware Video Card Related)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26214600">thread link</a>) | @peter_d_sherman
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            

            <h2>Overview</h2>

            <p>The Alice 4 rasterizer is broken into two main parts:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>A <a href="https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/libgl.html">software library</a> linked with the C application program. The library
                    implements the IrisGL API. It performs transformations, lighting, clipping,
                    and retained mode (display lists). Its output is a list of commands
                    (clear screen, draw triangle, swap buffers, etc.) that it writes to
                    memory outside Linux's range.</li>
                <li>An FPGA configuration that reads these commands from SDRAM and
                    executes them. For triangles it interpolates color (RGB) and depth
                    (Z). The FPGA also scans out the image buffer to the
                    LCD and performs other minor tasks.</li>
            </ul>

            <h2>Buffers</h2>

            <p>There are three image buffers in shared memory:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>A front color buffer, which is displayed to the user via the LCD.
                The scanning is continuous because the LCD has no memory of its own.
                The timing and wire format is similar to VGA.</li>
                <li>A back color buffer, which is being rasterized into.</li>
                <li>A depth buffer, used along with the back buffer during rasterization.</li>
            </ul>

            <p>The first two buffers are only virtually “front” and “back”. Those two
            labels switch every frame as the back buffer becomes the new front
            buffer and is shown to the user.</p>

            <h2>Modules</h2>

            <p>The Verilog code is broken into about a dozen modules:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>Main: Integrates all the other modules.
                    <ul>
                        <li>soc_instance: Module generated by Qsys to interface with
                            SDRAM and I<sup>2</sup>C.</li>
                        <li>LCD_control: Generates LCD control signals (H-Sync, V-Sync,
                            pixel enable, next frame signal, X coordinate, Y coordinate).
                            This runs at 25&nbsp;MHz (about 50&nbsp;FPS). It could run faster (up to 40&nbsp;MHz)
                            but the board clock is 50&nbsp;MHz, so it was convenient to
                            divide that by two and avoid having asynchronous clocks.</li>
                        <li>LCD_text: Given screen pixel X and Y, returns character X and Y
                            (text column and row) and sub-character X and Y.</li>
                        <li>LCD_debug: Given character X and Y and three 32-bit debug values,
                            returns which character to draw.
                            <ul>
                                <li>Binary_to_hex: Converts a nybble to a hex
                                    ASCII value. Used for each nybble of the
                                    debug values to generate hex output.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>Frame_buffer: Sends the front frame buffer to the LCD.</li>
                        <li>LCD_font: Given ASCII character and sub-character X and Y,
                            returns whether the pixel is on or off.
                            <ul>
                                <li>Font_ROM: The font pixels.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>Command_reader: Pre-fetches drawing commands from
                            SDRAM into a FIFO.</li>
                        <li>Rasterizer: Reads drawing commands and executes them.
                            <ul>
                                <li>Read_FIFO: Queues rasterized pixels,
                                    waiting for Z read to complete.</li>
                                <li>Write_FIFO: Queues rasterized and Z-compared
                                    pixels, waiting for pixel writes to complete.
                                    See the “Write FIFO” section below for more details.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>Prescaler: Generates a tick every N clocks.</li>
                        <li>PWM: Generates a PWM signal for LCD backlight brightness.</li>
                        <li>Debouncer: Debounces the Home button.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <h2>Memory controller</h2>

            <p>The Altera Cyclone V SoC has a wonderful memory controller for accessing
            the synchronous dynamic RAM (SDRAM). It has a port for the ARM and six ports
            for the FPGA. Each FPGA port can be configured for input or output, and their
            relative priorities (including the ARM port) can be set. The priorities were
            critical for making sure the front-buffer scan-out was never starved of
            pixels. The SDRAM itself ran so fast (400&nbsp;MHz DDR) that all the ports could
            be active and not stall too often. The ports were set up as follows:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>Reading the front-buffer for LCD scan-out. This was configured
                to be the highest priority.</li>
                <li>Reading the graphics command buffer.</li>
                <li>Reading the depth buffer for the pixel being rasterized.</li>
                <li>Writing the color of the pixel just rasterized.</li>
                <li>Writing the depth of the pixel just rasterized.</li>
            </ul>

            <p>All five ports were hooked up to FIFOs to minimize the effects of
            memory latency.</p>

            <h2>Rasterization</h2>

            <p>Rasterization uses the edge-equation technique. The idea is to test every
            pixel to see whether it's inside the triangle. “Inside” is defined as “on the
            same side of every edge”. Only pixels in the bounding box of the triangle are
            tested. This technique wastes at least 50% of its time on pixels outside the
            triangle, but it's simpler to implement than edge-walkers.</p>

            <p>The state machine in <tt>Rasterizer.v</tt> reads commands from SDRAM
            (indirectly through the FIFO) and executes them. Because the SDRAM interface
            is (logically) 64 bits wide, and each pixel takes 32 bits (8 bits each of
            red, green, and blue, with 8 bits wasted), we always rasterize two pixels
            at a time. At 50&nbsp;MHz, that's 100 million pixels per second, but with (at least)
            half of them wasted, that's at most 50 million drawn pixels per second.</p>

            <p>To minimize SDRAM latency stalls, we use three FIFOs in the rasterization
            process:</p>
            
            <ul>
                <li>The Command FIFO queues the drawing commands so that the
                    state machine need not block too long.</li>
                <li>The Read FIFO queues drawn pixels while we wait for the
                    depth read to return. After determining that a pixel is
                    inside the triangle, we initiate a read of its
                    corresponding depth value (if depth-comparison is enabled
                    for this triangle). This can take some time (tens of clocks) and we don't
                    want to block the rasterizer. Instead, we queue up all the
                    information we have about this pixel (depth memory address,
                    depth value, color memory address, and color) and move on to the
                    next pixel.
                    Another module (<tt>Read_FIFO.v</tt>) waits for the SDRAM read
                    to return. Since SDRAM reads return in the order they were
                    made, the module then gets the next item in our FIFO,
                    compares the depth values, and if the new pixel is closer to
                    the camera than the existing pixel, enqueues the same pixel
                    information into the Write FIFO. (All of this is done two
                    pixels at a time.)</li>
                <li>The Write FIFO queues pixels that must be written back to SDRAM.
                    The pixel's color must be written, and optionally the depth value
                    must be written (if enabled for this triangle). This is a complicated
                    module because we must take into account whether there are pixels
                    in the FIFO to write, whether the depth memory controller is ready
                    to accept another write, and whether the color memory controller is
                    ready to accept another write. See the section “Write FIFO” below
                    for details.</li>
            </ul>

            <p>There's very little stalling in this pipeline, so we end up with a
            rasterization rate of about 50 million Gouraud (color-interpolated)
            Z-buffered pixels per second. The triangle overhead lets us do
            almost 2 million (empty) triangles per second. It's hard to compare
            these numbers to
            <a href="http://www.sgidepot.co.uk/gfxtables.html">real SGI machines</a>, 
            but we seem to be matching the performance of machines built in the
            early 1990s.</p>

            <h2>Reciprocal</h2>

            <p>For each triangle, the rasterizer computes its on-screen area, then takes
            the reciprocal of the area. This is necessary for the normalization of
            the barycentric coordinates used to interpolate color and depth.
            <a href="https://www.scratchapixel.com/lessons/3d-basic-rendering/rasterization-practical-implementation/rasterization-stage">Scratchapixel</a> has a great explanation
            of how this works; scroll down to the “Barycentric Coordinates” section.</p>

            <p>To compute the reciprocal we use the built-in
            <a href="https://www.altera.com/en_US/pdfs/literature/ug/ug_lpm_alt_mfug.pdf"><tt>lpm_divide</tt></a> module:</p>

            <pre>lpm_divide
    #(.LPM_WIDTHN(32),
      .LPM_WIDTHD(32),
      .LPM_NREPRESENTATION("UNSIGNED"),
      .LPM_DREPRESENTATION("SIGNED"),
      .LPM_PIPELINE(6)) area_divider(
        .clock(clock),
        .clken(area_reciprocal_enabled),
        .numer(32'h7FFF_FFFF),
        .denom(tri_area),
        .quotient(tri_area_recip_result)
    );
            </pre>

            <p>The module is configured to have six pipeline stages, which means that
            the result will come out six clocks after the denominator was put in.
            We don't pipeline (overlap) our reciprocals (we only need one per triangle), but our
            state machine must wait six clocks for this result. We found the
            number 6 by trying various values until the compiler stopped complaining
            about timing violations.</p>

            <h2>Write FIFO</h2>

            <p>The Write FIFO, which writes pixel data to the back color buffer and
            to the depth buffer, was one of the most difficult modules to write in
            this project. Conceptually the state machine should perform these
            steps in a loop:</p>

            <ol>
                <li>Wait for a new pixel to be available in the Write FIFO.</li>
                <li>Write it to the back color buffer and to the depth buffer.</li>
                <li>Wait for both SDRAM controller ports to acknowledge that they had
                    accepted the writes.</li>
            </ol>

            <p>Remember that wherever we talk about “a pixel” here, we mean two
  …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html">https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26214600</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 16:19:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Efficient blockchain architecture based on FIDO keys]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 55 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26214175">thread link</a>) | @dandanua
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://dandanua.github.io/posts/super-efficient-blockchain-architecture-based-on-fido-keys/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dandanua.github.io/posts/super-efficient-blockchain-architecture-based-on-fido-keys/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction</h2><p>Reaching decentralized consensus is hard. Really, there must be a reason why Bitcoin network is such an energy-inefficient monster with its Proof-of-Work algorithm. Of course, many other consensus algorithms exist that are not that power-hungry, for example, Proof-of-Stake variations. But they require some sort of centralization, usually hidden under details and complexity. And they still have limits, a boundary on the total number of transactions per second that a network can process.</p><p>I don’t believe it’s possible to find an efficient consensus algorithm, which would be truly decentralized. But why restrict ourselves to just software solutions? Here I want to explain that a super-efficient hardware solution exists. And it’s already within the reach of our current technologies.</p><h2 id="2-the-main-problem">2. The Main Problem</h2><p>What is the root cause of why it’s so hard to achieve a decentralized consensus?</p><p>Well, in the case of cryptocurrencies it’s called <em>double spending</em>. If Clara has 100 coins at some point in time then she can’t spend 200 coins – the network will just ignore such transaction as incorrect. But transferring 100 coins to Alice or 100 coins to Bob are both correct transactions. Yet they are conflicting. If Clara simultaneously commits both these transactions then the network has to decide what to choose as the right one and what to discard.</p><p>Making a decision based on time is not a deterministic way, because some participants can receive one of the conflicting transactions earlier in time, while the others will see a different order.</p><p>Somehow the whole network, i.e. every participant of it, has to decide what to pick as the correct transaction in a way, that will be in agreement with the decisions of every other participant.</p><p>This decision can’t be based on some mathematical function of a transaction (if Clara has enough freedom of composing it). For example, we can’t have a rule where we pick the transaction of 100 coins to Alice as correct because <em>A &lt; B</em>. Because if Clara commits another conflicting transaction of 100 coins to Aaron later in time, then the whole network would have to change its decisions.</p><p>Note that the same problem exists in a broader context, not related to currencies. For example, you can have a blockchain network where users can play chess games. At any moment in time a player has a set of allowable moves. But a player is allowed to choose only one move. If he commits two moves simultaneously, then, again, the network has to decide what to pick as the right one.</p><p>There are many consensus algorithms invented, but they are just ways to centralize a network, where these conflict resolution decisions are made by some selected (or elected) set of participants. In fact, Bitcoin PoW consensus algorithm is a form of election of a participant (miner), whose decision will be set as correct for the whole network.</p><hr><p>So, how can we use hardware to solve this problem?</p><p>Imagine hypothetical hardware that additionally signs Clara’s transactions (via some cryptographic microchips). Moreover, this hardware keeps a counter of Clara’s transactions and <em>attaches</em> this number to a signed transaction. So, the network will see a transaction with its number that has two signatures – the one by Clara’s private key and another one by hardware private key.</p><p>Conflict resolution is trivial in this case. The network will accept a transaction that has a lower counter (it has to be +1 of the previous transaction number).</p><p>The main assumption that we need for network security is that Clara can’t tamper hardware or simulate it in some way. Of course, making tamper-proof hardware is also a hard task, but the technology is almost there. There are a lot of tamper-resistant USB keys that are already on the market.</p><p>Actually, FIDO keys are already satisfying our blockchain needs!</p><h2 id="3-fido-keys">3. FIDO keys</h2><p>FIDO (Fast IDentity Online) is an alliance of the world’s major IT companies. They developed U2F (Universal 2nd Factor) – an open standard of two-factor authentification that uses USB or NFC keys. Luckily, this standard is indeed universal. Even though it was developed as an addition to password authentification in centralized services, we can use it in a blockchain network instead!</p><p>A nice overview of U2F protocol you can see <a href="https://developers.yubico.com/U2F/Protocol_details/Overview.html">here</a>.</p><p>In particular, look at this diagram</p><p><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://developers.yubico.com/U2F/Protocol_details/auth_flow4.svg" alt="Mobile View"><em>https://developers.yubico.com/U2F/Protocol_details/Overview.html</em></p><p>It is supposed that a Relying Party (server) starts second-factor authentification by sending a <em>challenge</em> to a client. But blockchain network has no servers. Instead of a challenge, Clara uses the hash of her transaction, where <em>app_id</em> is just a name of the blockchain network and <em>handle</em> is Clara’s personal public key. Then the U2F device will update the counter and return the signed transaction with the attached counter. This is exactly what we need! Clara then sends this information along with the actual transaction and her own signature to the network.</p><p>To ensure that Clara can’t simulate the device, U2F protocol additionally includes the attestation certificate of the device manufacturer, as explained <a href="https://fidoalliance.org/fido-technotes-the-truth-about-attestation/">here</a>.</p><h2 id="4-typical-usage-scenario">4. Typical usage scenario</h2><p>First of all, a user has to register in the network. To do this, he needs to have FIDO hardware key and to generate his personal private/public keys. The registration is essentially linking personal keys with device keys. For this, an empty challenge can be used in the device signing flow.</p><p>Making transactions was described in the previous section.</p><p>If the device is lost/broken/stolen then the user can register another device with its personal key. Though, in this case, the network should wait for some time, for example, 24 hours, to be sure that the previous device (in a couple with the personal key) is not used anymore.</p><h2 id="5-threats">5. Threats</h2><p>Since every transaction must have two signatures – by device and user, the device alone can’t be used to harm its user.</p><p>But an incorrect or tampered device can be used to submit conflicting transactions to the network (for example, with the same counter). This will split the network if no other consensus algorithm is involved.</p><p>But we can assume that manufacturer has no incentives to make incorrect devices to harm the network.</p><p>So, the only threat is device tampering. Even though modern FIDO keys are tamper-resistant, their security is probably not enough to be used in blockchain networks, because there were no reasons to make them fully tamper-proof in usage with centralized servers. But nearly tamper-proof technology is certainly possible.</p><h2 id="6-super-efficiency">6. (Super) Efficiency</h2><p>As for this blockchain efficiency, it’s certainly unreachable for ordinary blockchains. Because in this architecture, no additional communication to resolve possible conflicts is needed <strong><em>AT ALL</em></strong>. Every possible conflict is resolved immediately in an independent and coherent fashion.</p><h2 id="7-final-words">7. Final Words</h2><p>This is, of course, only a high-level overview of blockchain architecture. A lot of details are skipped. But I hope it can be seen that this architecture is a real solution to a lot of blockchain problems.</p><hr><p><em><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26214175">Discussion</a> on HackerNews.</em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dandanua.github.io/posts/super-efficient-blockchain-architecture-based-on-fido-keys/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26214175</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 15:36:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build an SMS Forwarder with Raspberry Pi Zero W and Waveshare SIM7000E Hat]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 51 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26213956">thread link</a>) | @mtrcn
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://mete.dev/2021/02/21/build-an-sms-forwarder-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w-and-waveshare-sim7000e-hat/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mete.dev/2021/02/21/build-an-sms-forwarder-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w-and-waveshare-sim7000e-hat/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
						
<p>In this guide, I will explain how to receive SMS messages and forward them to your Telegram account using Raspberry PI Zero W and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.waveshare.com/SIM7000E-NB-IoT-HAT.htm" target="_blank">Wireshare GSM hat</a>. </p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard.png" alt="" width="473" height="380" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard.png 945w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard-300x241.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard-768x618.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 473px) 100vw, 473px"></figure></div>



<p>Python will be used to read SMS messages and forward them to <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://core.telegram.org/bots/api" target="_blank">Telegram Bot API</a>. Messages will be listened to by <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://wammu.eu/smsd/" target="_blank">Gammu</a> SMS service and it will trigger the Python script when an SMS message received.  </p>



<h2>Setup</h2>



<p>First of all, we have to enable communication between GSM hat and Raspberry PI Zero, run Raspberry Pi Software Configuration Tool (raspi-config);</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo raspi-config</code></pre>



<p>Then, follow following actions;</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png" alt="" width="743" height="458" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png 990w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1-300x185.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1-768x474.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 743px) 100vw, 743px"><figcaption>Go to Interface Options</figcaption></figure></div>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2.png" alt="" width="745" height="457" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2.png 993w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2-300x184.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2-768x471.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 745px) 100vw, 745px"><figcaption>Select and enter P6 Serial Port</figcaption></figure>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3.png" alt="" width="740" height="458" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3.png 987w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3-300x185.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3-768x475.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"><figcaption>Select No at this screen.</figcaption></figure></div>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4.png" alt="" width="740" height="459" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4.png 986w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4-300x186.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4-768x477.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"><figcaption>Lastly, select Yes at this screen.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Exit configuration tool. Now we need to enable UART on raspberry pi. Shutdown and eject SD card to open in another computer. Open /boot/config.txt file, find the below statement and uncomment it to enable the UART. You can directly append it at the end of the file as well.</p>



<pre><code>enable_uart=1</code></pre>



<p>Now, reboot raspberry pi device and open the console to install Gammu SMS Deamon and Python PiP package installer. </p>



<pre><code>$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install python-pip gammu-smsd</code></pre>



<p>Install Telegram Bot API python library.</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo pip install python-telegram-bot==12.3.0</code></pre>



<p><em>Note: Version 12.3.0 is the latest version that is compatible with Python 2.7, if you want to use it with Python 3+ version, you can install the latest available version.</em></p>



<p>Now you need to create a bot in Telegram and obtain a token. Afterwards, start a chat with that bot in your Telegram account and send a test message to your bot. This will help us to identify your chat ID. </p>



<p>Open following URL with you Telegram Bot token and copy the chat ID in the response; </p>



<pre><code>https://api.telegram.org/bot[YOUR-BOT-TOKEN]/getUpdates</code></pre>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="269" height="29" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image.png" alt=""><figcaption>This is your chat ID.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Save following script in /home/pi/forward-telegram.py;</p>



<pre><code>#!/usr/bin/env python
from __future__ import print_function
import os
import sys
import telegram

numparts = int(os.environ['DECODED_PARTS'])

text = ''
# Are there any decoded parts?
if numparts == 0:
    text = os.environ['SMS_1_TEXT']
# Get all text parts
else:
    for i in range(1, numparts + 1):
        varname = 'DECODED_%d_TEXT' % i
        if varname in os.environ:
            text = text + os.environ[varname]

# Log
print('Number %s have sent text: %s' % (os.environ['SMS_1_NUMBER'], text))

#Send by Telegram
bot = telegram.Bot(token='[YOUR-BOT-TOKEN]')
bot.send_message(chat_id=[YOUR CHAT ID], text=os.environ['SMS_1_NUMBER'].strip() + " | "+ text)
</code></pre>



<p>Make python file executable</p>



<pre><code>$ chmod +x /home/pi/forward-telegram.py</code></pre>



<p>Update Gammu SMS Deamon’s configuration to use GSM hat. Waveshare uses /dev/ttyS0 for communication. </p>



<pre><code>$ sudo nano /etc/gammu-smsdrc</code></pre>



<p>Find following lines in the configuration file and update with correct values, for me these values are following;</p>



<pre><code>port = /dev/ttyS0
connection = at115200</code></pre>



<p>Also, we need to specify the script path to be ran by Gammu so add following line below [smsd] section;</p>



<pre><code>RunOnReceive = /home/pi/forward-telegram.py</code></pre>



<p>You can find my complete configuration file <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://gist.github.com/mtrcn/045d7eeef1e38c092939d5ee87f96fb0" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



<p>Restart Gammu SMS service.</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo systemctl restart gammu-smsd.service</code></pre>



<p>That’s all! You should now able to get your SMS messages to your Telegram account. </p>



<p>You can monitor Gammu SMS service for any problem with the following command;</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo systemctl status gammu-smsd.service</code></pre>




						
											</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mete.dev/2021/02/21/build-an-sms-forwarder-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w-and-waveshare-sim7000e-hat/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26213956</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 15:07:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When Bitcoin miners take over a town (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 193 | Comments 447 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26213693">thread link</a>) | @edward
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
									<p><span>EAST WENATCHEE,&nbsp;Washington — Hands on the&nbsp;</span>wheel, eyes squinting against the winter sun, Lauren Miehe eases his Land Rover down the main drag and tells me how he used to spot promising sites to build a bitcoin mine, back in 2013, when he was a freshly arrived techie from Seattle and had just discovered this sleepy rural community.</p>
<p>The attraction then, as now, was the Columbia River, which we can glimpse a few blocks to our left. Bitcoin mining — the complex process in which computers solve a complicated math puzzle to win a stack of virtual currency — uses an inordinate amount of electricity, and thanks to five hydroelectric dams that straddle this stretch of the river, about three hours east of Seattle, miners could buy that power more cheaply here than anywhere else in the nation. Long before locals had even heard the words “cryptocurrency” or “blockchain,” Miehe and his peers realized that this semi-arid agricultural region known as the Mid-Columbia Basin was the best place to mine bitcoin in America — and maybe the world.</p>
<p>The trick, though, was finding a location where you could put all that cheap power to work. You needed an existing building, because in those days, when bitcoin was trading for just a few dollars, no one could afford to build something new. You needed space for a few hundred high-speed computer servers, and also for the heavy-duty cooling system to keep them from melting down as they churned out the trillions of calculations necessary to mine bitcoin. Above all, you needed a location that could handle a lot of electricity — a quarter of a megawatt, maybe, or even a half a megawatt, enough to light up a couple hundred homes.</p>
<p>The best mining sites were the old fruit warehouses — the basin is as famous for its apples as for its megawatts — but those got snapped up early. So Miehe, a tall, gregarious 38-year-old who would go on to set up a string of mines here, learned to look for less obvious solutions. He would roam the side streets and back roads, scanning for defunct businesses that might have once used a lot of power. An old machine shop, say. A closed-down convenience store. Or this: Miehe slows the Land Rover and points to a shuttered carwash sitting forlornly next to a Taco Bell. It has the space, he says. And with the water pumps and heaters, “there’s probably a ton of power distributed not very far from here,” Miehe tells me. “That could be a bitcoin mine.”</p>
<blockquote><p>Over the past two years, the region has taken on the vibe of a boomtown.</p></blockquote>
<p>These days, Miehe says, a serious miner wouldn’t even look at a site like that. As bitcoin’s soaring price has drawn in <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2018/03/09/how-bitcoin-works-illustration-infographic-217333" target="_blank">thousands of new players worldwide</a>, the strange math at the heart of this cryptocurrency has grown steadily more complicated. Generating a single bitcoin takes a lot more servers than it used to — and a lot more power. Today, a half-megawatt mine, Miehe says, “is nothing.” The commercial miners now pouring into the valley are building sites with tens of thousands of servers and electrical loads of as much as 30 megawatts, or enough to power a neighborhood of 13,000 homes. And in the arms race that cryptocurrency mining has become, even these operations will soon be considered small-scale. Miehe knows of substantially larger mining projects in the basin backed by out-of-state investors from Wall Street, Europe and Asia whose prospecting strategy, as he puts it, amounts to “running around with a checkbook just trying to get in there and establish scale.”</p>
<p>For years, few residents really grasped how appealing their region was to miners, who mainly did their esoteric calculations quietly tucked away in warehouses and basements. But those days are gone. Over the past two years, and especially during 2017, when the price of a single bitcoin&nbsp;<a href="https://99bitcoins.com/price-chart-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jumped</a>&nbsp;from $1,000 to more than $19,000, the region has taken on the vibe of a boomtown. Across the three rural counties of the Mid-Columbia Basin — Chelan, Douglas and Grant — orchards and farm fields now share the rolling landscape with mines of every size, from industrial-scale facilities to repurposed warehouses to cargo containers and even backyard sheds. Outsiders are so eager to turn the basin’s power into cryptocurrency that this winter, several would-be miners from Asia flew their private jet into the local airport, took a rental car to one of the local dams, and, according to a utility official, politely informed staff at the dam visitors center, “We want to see the dam master because we want to buy some electricity.”</p>
<p>The Mid-Columbia Basin isn’t the only location where the virtual realm of cryptocurrency is colliding with the real world of megawatts and real estate. In places like China, Venezuela and Iceland, cheap land and even cheaper electricity have resulted in bustling mining hubs. But the basin, by dint of its early start, has emerged as one of the biggest boomtowns. By the end of 2018, according to some estimates, miners here could account for anywhere from 15 to 30 percent of all bitcoin mining in the world, and impressive shares of other cryptocurrencies, such as Ethereum and Ripple. And as with any boomtown, that success has created tensions. There have been disputes between miners and locals, bankruptcies and bribery attempts, lawsuits, even a kind of intensifying guerrilla warfare between local utility crews and a shadowy army of bootleg miners who set up their servers in basements and garages and max out the local electrical grids.</p>
<div id="attachment_846110"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-846110" loading="lazy" src="https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-714x476.jpg" alt="" width="714" height="476" srcset="https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-714x476.jpg 714w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-1160x773.jpg 1160w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-380x253.jpg 380w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-171x114.jpg 171w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-90x60.jpg 90w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-104x69.jpg 104w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-200x133.jpg 200w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-390x260.jpg 390w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-54x36.jpg 54w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-1080x720.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px"></p><p id="caption-attachment-846110">The Datacenter Mjoelnir in Iceland, a cryptocurrency mine run by Genesis-Mining | Hanna Andresdottir/EPA</p></div>
<p>More broadly, the region is watching uneasily as one of its biggest natural resources — a gigantic surplus of hydroelectric power — is inhaled by a sector that barely existed five years ago and which is routinely derided as the next dot-com bust, or this century’s version of the Dutch tulip craze, or, as&nbsp;New York Times&nbsp;columnist Paul Krugman&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/paulkrugman/status/955107120671797248?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">put it in January</a>, a Ponzi scheme. Indeed, even as Miehe was demonstrating his prospecting chops, bitcoin’s price was already in a swoon that would touch $5,900 and rekindle widespread doubts about the future of virtual currencies.</p>
<p>For local cryptocurrency enthusiasts, these slings and arrows are all very much worth enduring. They believe not only that cryptocurrency will make them personally very wealthy, but also that this formerly out-of-the-way region has a real shot at becoming a center — and maybe&nbsp;<i>the&nbsp;</i>center — of a coming technology revolution, with the well-paid jobs and tech-fueled prosperity that usually flow only to gilded “knowledge” hubs like Seattle and San Francisco. Malachi Salcido, a Wenatchee building contractor who jumped into bitcoin in 2014 and is now one of the basin’s biggest players, puts it in sweeping terms. The basin, he tells me, is “building a platform that the entire world is going to use.”</p>
<p>And squarely between these two competing narratives are the communities of the Mid-Columbia Basin, which find themselves anxiously trying to answer a question that for most of the rest of us is merely an amusing abstraction: Is bitcoin for real?</p>
<p>***</p>
<p><b>A few miles from the shuttered carwash</b>, David Carlson stands at the edge of a sprawling construction site and watches workers set the roof on a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CfrjhflKGzQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Giga Pod</a>, a self-contained crypto mine that Carlson designed to be assembled in a matter of weeks. When finished, the prefabricated wood-frame structure, roughly 12 by 48 feet, will be equipped with hundreds of high-speed servers that collectively draw a little over a megawatt of power and, in theory, will be capable of producing around 80 bitcoins a month. Carlson himself won’t be the miner; his company, Giga-Watt, will run the pod as a hosting site for other miners. By summer, Giga-Watt expects to have 24 pods here churning out bitcoins and other cryptocurrencies, most of which use the same computing-intensive, cryptographically secured protocol called the blockchain. “We’re right where the rubber hits the road with blockchain,” Carlson shouts as we step inside the project’s first completed pod and stand between the tall rack of toaster-size servers and a bank of roaring cooling fans. The main use of blockchain technology now is to keep a growing electronic ledger of every single bitcoin transaction ever made. But many miners see it as the record-keeping mechanism of the future. “We’re where the blockchain goes from that virtual concept to something that’s real in the world,” says Carlson, “something that somebody had to build and is actually running.”</p>
<p>Granted, all that real-worlding and road-hitting is a little hard to visualize just now. The winter storms that have turned the Cascade Mountains a dazzling white have also turned the construction site into a reddish quagmire that drags at workers and equipment. There have also been permitting snafus, delayed utility hookups, and a lawsuit, recently settled, by impatient investors. But Carlson seems unperturbed. “They are actually making it work,” he told me earlier, referring to the mud-caked workers. “In a normal project, they might just say, ‘Let’s just wait till spring,’” Carlson adds. “But in bitcoin and blockchain, there is no stopping.” Indeed, demand for hosting services in the basin is so high that a desperate miner offered Carlson a Lamborghini if Carlson would bump him to the head of the pod waiting list. “I didn’t take the offer,” Carlson assures me. “And I like Lamborghinis!”</p>
<blockquote><p>Across the expanding bitcoin universe, lots of miners are turning their basements and spare bedrooms into jury-rigged data centers.</p></blockquote>
<p>Carlson has become the face of the Mid-Columbia Basin crypto boom. Articulate, infectiously optimistic, with graying hair and a trim beard, the Microsoft software developer-turned-serial entrepreneur has built a series of mines, made (and lost) several bitcoin fortunes and endured countless setbacks to become one of the region’s largest players. Other local miners credit Carlson for launching the basin’s boom, back in 2012, when he showed …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/">https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26213693</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 14:35:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Designing for Voice User Interfaces]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26213122">thread link</a>) | @allending
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://blog.snappymob.com/designing-for-voice-user-interfaces-principles-and-best-practices | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.snappymob.com/designing-for-voice-user-interfaces-principles-and-best-practices">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
		<div id="primary">
			<main id="main" role="main">
<article id="post-12">
	<!-- HEADER: .header-content -->
	<!-- .header-content -->

	<!-- BODY: .entry-content -->
	<div>
		<p>Most of the digital products we use today are designed for our eyes, simply because as highly visual beings, we rely on our sight a lot.</p>

<p>Whether we’re reading microcopy to understand what a button does, or scanning through textual instructions to familiarize with a new machine, interacting with devices using visual cues is what we’re very used to.</p>
<p>But what happens when visual feedback is secondary? How does that change the way we interact with interfaces, and the way they’re designed for us?</p>
<p>Voice User Interfaces (VUI) like Amazon Alexa and Google Assistant are designed differently from screen-first interfaces for many reasons — the main one being that the principles of spoken communication differ from those of written communication. Because of that, UX designers cannot approach voice-first interfaces the same way they do screen-first interfaces.</p>
<p>How and why should they be done differently? Let’s dive into some of the best practices in voice design.</p>
<h2><strong>Best Practices in Voice Design</strong></h2>
<p>According to <a href="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/docs/alexa/alexa-design/get-started.html">Amazon’s Alexa Design Guide</a>, voice interfaces should be four things — adaptable, personal, relatable, and available. Both Amazon’s guide and <a href="https://developers.google.com/assistant/conversational/df-asdk/design">Google Assistant’s Conversation design guide</a> stress that voice-first skills should be natural and user-centric for a seamless experience.</p>
<p>Here’s a breakdown of the best practices in designing user experiences for voice user interfaces.</p>
<h3>1. Be Flexible and Receptive</h3>
<p>Language is dynamic. Let’s say a user wants to make a call, they can say <em>“Call X”</em>, <em>“Ring X”</em>, <em>“Get X on the phone”</em>, or a thousand more other variations that can be matched to the same “Call” intent. Your skill must be able to pick up on key details in varied utterances, even if there are multiple embedded in a single answer.</p>
<p>Sometimes, to save time, users may string multiple pieces of information in a single command or response to a question. For example, if one says…</p>
<p><em>“Set a reminder for my interview with Snappymob at 3pm tomorrow.”&nbsp;</em></p>
<p>…they likely don’t want to repeat any of the information they’ve already mentioned. It’d show a lack of receptiveness to follow the exchange with <em>“What time would you like to set your reminder for?”</em> or <em>“What’s the reminder for?”</em>, because then the user would have to repeat <em>“3pm”</em> or <em>“Interview with Snappymob”</em>.</p>
<p>When your interface is able to pick up on additional information that wasn’t asked for, and fill in the gaps unprompted, you create a more intuitive experience for your users.</p>
<h3>2. Ask Questions, One at a Time</h3>
<p>Simply speaking, users need to know when their cue is. With voice-activated devices, asking questions lets them know when they need to respond.</p>
<p>Phrasing in statements rather than questions, like <em>“Let me know where you would like to go.”</em> instead of <em>“Where would you like to go?”</em> makes it unclear if the user needs to prompt the next activity with an answer.</p>
<p>To avoid confusion on both sides, it’s also standard to ask for one piece of information at a time. For instance, asking a user <em>“What is your new contact’s name, mobile number, and email address?”</em> might cause information overload and make forming an answer difficult. Instead, ask single-answer questions to fill in the blanks one by one.</p>
<h3>3. Present Clear Options</h3>
<p>Unlike visual interfaces, with voice-first, users aren’t choosing from navigation menus they can visually scan through. Hence, it’s important to relay their options in a clear and concise manner. This is where you need to pay attention to language.</p>
<p>Syntax matters especially with distinguishing between either/or questions and yes/no questions. For example, <em>“Would you like twister fries or french fries to go with your meal?”</em> could sound like a yes or no question. Instead, to make the option prompt clearer, it could be phrased like <em>“Which side would you like: Twister fries or french fries?”</em>.</p>
<h3>4. Narrow Down to Only the Necessary</h3>
<p>This applies to both questions and choices. Text can be scanned through, but spoken words take time to relay — so be succinct.</p>
<p>Only ask for confirmation for actions with high importance, like making calls, sending text messages, and any action that involves recipients or monetary transactions.</p>
<p>Asking for unnecessary confirmation or making users reiterate information can easily frustrate them. For example, an <em>“Are you sure” </em>confirmation might not be necessary for simple commands like <em>“Turn off the lights”</em> or <em>“Tell me the current price for Bitcoin”</em>, but necessary for <em>“Send email” </em>and <em>“Call Cindy”</em>.</p>
<p>As for choices, make sure your users aren’t bombarded with ten choices at a time. Remember that unlike text, users can’t scan back and forth to digest a message with speech. Giving them too much information to process at a time will lead to more errors in comprehension and exchange.</p>
<h3>5. Restate Questions</h3>
<p>As mentioned before, on voice-first interfaces, users aren’t relying primarily on a visual navigation menu. So to make sure they know where they are, it’s always helpful to reinstate the questions they answer.</p>
<p>For example, when a user asks for the recipe for spaghetti bolognese, it’s clearer to respond with <em>“To make spaghetti bolognese, the ingredients are…”</em> instead of jumping straight into <em>“The ingredients are…”</em>. A simple restatement reassures the user that they’re getting the answer they’re looking for.</p>
<h3>6. Be Prepared for Blockers</h3>
<p>Being well-prepared includes being prepared for scenarios where things don’t go as planned. Here are some of the most common blockers to think ahead for when designing for voice user interfaces:</p>
<h3><strong>Corrections</strong></h3>
<p>When a VUI gets a piece of information wrong, users will naturally correct it with common phrases like <em>“No, I said-”</em> or a simply a reiteration of their command.</p>
<p>Your interface must be able to pick up on corrections, accept them instantaneously, and restate the command for confirmation.</p>
<h3><strong>Comprehension Failures</strong></h3>
<p>When the VUI fails to understand the user’s command, it’s important to handle the error with grace.</p>
<p>The standard way to approach this is with a statement followed by a repetition of the question, like <em>“Sorry, I didn’t catch that. Who would you like to share this link with?”</em>. This is to make it clear to the user that they should reiterate their answer following the cue.</p>
<h3><strong>Unavailable Functions</strong></h3>
<p>When a user asks for a function that doesn’t exist, instead of using the standard <em>“Sorry, I didn’t get that”</em> response repeatedly, let them know what can be done for them instead to move the conversation forward.</p>
<p>Here’s a scenario — a user says <em>“Cook me spaghetti”</em>. Instead of ending the exchange with “Sorry, I couldn’t understand that”, respond with <em>“I can only help you find recipes for spaghetti. Would you like me to look for the best ones?”.</em></p>
<h3><strong>Non-Responses</strong></h3>
<p>Sometimes users forget to answer, or abandon ship halfway through a conversation. Some other times, the VUI doesn’t pick up on the sound input. In situations like these, re-prompts are necessary to give the user another go at answering a question, in case the non-response wasn’t intended.</p>
<p>In the re-prompts, it’s important to restate where they left off, so they know where to pick up. For example, a user doesn’t respond after saying <em>“Set a reminder”</em>. The re-prompt should restate what the user’s intent was, and what they should do next, something like this — <em>“I can help you set a reminder. What would you like to be reminded for?”</em>.</p>
<h2><strong>Let Us Help You</strong></h2>
<p>Thinking of jumping on the voice-first bandwagon? Snappymob might be the agency you’re looking for.</p>
<p>Our team of expert designers and engineers are passionate about user experience and making products that delight. Talk to us and let us give you a boost in your next project!</p>
		<!-- Contact us CTA -->
		
		<!-- Post category tags-->
		<p><label>
				App Design			</label>
		</p>
		<!-- Social share -->
		
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- Disable meta footer --> 
	<!-- 	<footer class="entry-footer default-max-width">
</footer> -->
	<!-- .entry-footer -->

	<!-- Disable author detail -->
	<!-- -->
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->
			</main><!-- #main -->
		</div><!-- #primary -->
	</div><div>
	  <div>
		
		<p>
			We understand that every project is unique. Contact us and we will get
			back to you with the next steps.
		  </p>
		
	  </div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.snappymob.com/designing-for-voice-user-interfaces-principles-and-best-practices</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26213122</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 12:55:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Viking Invasion of Leicestershire (2012)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26212092">thread link</a>) | @zeristor
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-8898898974994971235" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p><span>We know exactly when the Viking Age
began in England – it was more than 1,200 years ago – on June 8, 793. That was
the day when invading Norsemen destroyed the Abbey church on the island of
Lindisfarne, off the north-east coast of England. Lindisfarne was a centre of
learning famous across the continent – but that meant nothing to these fierce
invaders.</span></p>
<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-n4m_7H0fvSE/UKSycIixbvI/AAAAAAAAAfo/DAUUpjbSAwM/s1600/Viking+Leicester.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="212" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-n4m_7H0fvSE/UKSycIixbvI/AAAAAAAAAfo/DAUUpjbSAwM/s320/Viking+Leicester.jpg" width="320"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>The Vikings arrived in England in 793 AD</td></tr>
</tbody></table>
<p><span>Monks were either killed in the abbey,
thrown into the sea to drown or carried away as slaves – along with the church’s
treasures. The devastation of Northumbria’s Holy Island shocked Europe. “Never
before has such an atrocity been seen”, declared the Northumbrian scholar,
Alcuin of York. The Vikings had announced themselves in a devastating way. This
was just a warning of what was to come.</span></p>

<p><span>Over the next 300 years, more and more
invaders would flood into England, and Leicestershire would be full of Vikings.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Divided country</span></b></p>
<p><span>At the
time, England was not one united country – it was divided up into Anglo-Saxon
kingdoms.</span><b> </b><span>Leicester was
included within Mercia, and was known as Legreceastre. It was the principal
city in that kingdom. Even a thousand years ago and more, Legreceastre was a
bit of a melting pot.</span><b> </b><span>It
was a meeting point of several different cultures – the Angles from the Wash
and the Humber, Saxons from Warwickshire, Mercians from the Trent, and Celts
from the hills of Charnwood. In Leicester, they met, traded and eventually
settled.</span><b> </b><span>What increasingly
united these peoples was Christianity.</span><b>
</b><span>Mercia was Christian – the “new” religion reached Leicester in the
year 658. A church was said to have stood from the 7th century on the current
St Margaret’s site.</span><b> </b><span>Leicestershire,
as we know it, was in the heart of the Mercian kingdom and is thought to have
been the capital for political and ecclesiastical affairs. It was far enough
away from the frontiers to avoid changing hands as the unstable boundaries of
the mini-kingdom advanced and receded.</span><b>
</b><span>But what the Anglo-Saxons had worked so hard to build in
Leicestershire, was about to come to an end. The Scandinavian enemy was at the
gates and Mercia would never be the same again.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Ruthlessly pillaged</span></b></p>
<p><span>In 10 short years, between 865 and 874,
the whole structure of life in Mercia collapsed. A huge Scandinavian army
marched and pillaged up and down England. The Anglo-Saxon Chronicle has
preserved a glimpse of these years of chaos in its records of “a great heathen
army” that pillaged East Anglia in the year 865. Between 865 and 868 the
Northmen widened their field for plunder and tribute to East Mercia. Leicester
was attacked in 868, partly destroying the ancient Roman city walls.</span></p>

<p><span>Thousands of Danes swarmed down the
River Soar in their small, easily-managed boats, penetrating the very heart of
the country, carrying fire and sword among the simple and terrified population,
whom they ruthlessly pillaged and massacred. In the winter of 874 to 5, after
defeating Burhed, King of Mercia in battle, the raiders established their
quarters at Repton on the River Trent. Monasteries, the repositories of rich
and beautiful objects in gold, silver and jewellery, formed particular targets
for the pagan invaders. The monastery that had been founded at Breedon in
Leicestershire was reputedly sacked. But these Danes didn’t just hit and run,
like the early invaders on Lindisfarne.</span></p>

<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-RAtAWAWsTdU/UKSybtWvK9I/AAAAAAAAAfc/l0Lz_w86CgM/s1600/Viking+Boat.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="243" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-RAtAWAWsTdU/UKSybtWvK9I/AAAAAAAAAfc/l0Lz_w86CgM/s320/Viking+Boat.jpg" width="320"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>The Vikings swarmed down the River Soar</td></tr>
</tbody></table>
<p><span>In its records of the year 877, the
Anglo-Saxon Chronicle suggests a permanent settlement of the land. The Danish
army it says “went into the land of the Mercians, and shared out some of it,
and gave some to Ceolwulf”. Ceolwulf was the puppet king whom the Danes placed
on the Mercian throne. It seems Mercia was now divided in half.</span></p>

<p><span>Large parts of its eastern territories
had passed into the hands of the Scandinavian invaders and were open to
settlement. Within the next decade, in 886, the losses of Anglo-Saxon territory
in Mercia were clearly defined by a treaty that King Alfred the Great concluded
with Guthrum, the leader of the Danes, after his Wessex Saxons had recaptured
London.</span></p>

<p><span>A permanent “country of Danes” was now
established within England, known as the Danelaw. This Danish part of England
comprised the greater part of eastern England from East Anglia to North
Yorkshire, incorporating most of Leicestershire. You could say that Leicester
was part of Denmark.</span></p>

<p><span>Leicestershire was close to the Danelaw
boundary though, and it is believed that some of the wealthier inhabitants
migrated with as many possessions as they could carry. As the churches were
destroyed and Christian rites trampled, the Bishop of Leicester retired to
safety at Dorchester-on-Thames. It would be more than a thousand years before
there would again be a Diocese of Leicester. Leicester, with Derby, Nottingham,
Lincoln and Stamford, became one of the “Five Boroughs” of the Danelaw. Leicester,
as a former Anglo-Saxon royal city, continued its importance under Danish rule.
Danish forms of taxation and local government took root in Leicester.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Danish Leicester</span></b></p>
<p><span>Although the Danelaw’s existence was
relatively short-lived, it left an everlasting mark on the history of
Leicestershire. The Scandinavians left an indelible impression on the language
of the East Midlands. </span><span>&nbsp;</span><span>Vocabulary,
grammatical structures and the very tones of local dialect were deeply affected
by the contact with Scandinavia. Despite this, there aren’t many archeological
finds to be seen; visible remains of the Norsemen are hard to come by. Leicestershire’s
archaeological record lacks burials, pottery and everyday implements.</span></p>

<p><span>Finds that we do have are generally
personal ornaments such as brooches, horse accessories, coinage and weaponry. There
are also some distinctly Irish objects found in Leicestershire that were
probably plundered by Vikings during raids, and transported back to the Danelaw
lands. Such finds include a “shrine mount” from Breedon and belt buckles from
Melton.</span></p>

<p><span>Our understanding of Danish settlement
and the geography of the Danelaw depends largely on the evidence of
Scandinavian place-names. The place-name ending of by, which means a farm or
more usually a settlement, is seen throughout Denmark. That same ending is
common in England too. In Leicestershire alone, 56 villages end in by (such as Oadby)
and of these, half the number contain a Danish personal name as their other
element. But towards Leicester, on the broad gravel spreads where the River
Wreake empties into the Soar, the character of place-names changes. The sounds
of the Scandinavian invaders gives way to names of an older Mercian origin with
names ending in -ton. Thrussington, Syston and Cossington all speak of an
earlier period in Leicestershire’s settlement history. Even though the ton
element suggests the presence of a settlement that survived the impact of the
Danish army, the first element in these names is frequently a Scandinavian
personal name. Many Leicestershire villages were named after powerful Danes.
Ingarsby is named after the Danish Prince Ingar and it is now believed that
Humberstone may be named after Ingar’s brother, Hubba. </span><span>&nbsp;</span><span>Both Princes entered Leicester during the
Danish invasion and could have settled in the villages named after themselves.</span></p>

<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ij1MO4XWLvQ/UKS0APCvwSI/AAAAAAAAAgE/HVsFvpOADvw/s1600/Viking+Princes.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="320" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ij1MO4XWLvQ/UKS0APCvwSI/AAAAAAAAAgE/HVsFvpOADvw/s320/Viking+Princes.jpg" width="295"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Some think the Viking princes are on the tower of Humberstone church</td></tr>
</tbody></table>
<p><span>But as well as being named after actual
people, many villages were named after the gods. Thurmaston, Thurcaston,
Thurlaston and Thurnby all owe their name to one of the principal pagan gods of
the Scandinavian culture – Thor, who together with Odin, were the most commonly
worshipped gods. An archaeological find from Leicestershire of a miniature
“Thor’s Hammer”, the god’s famous magical weapon, is on display in the Jewry
Wall Museum.</span></p>

<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1ehV6iV7B9k/UKSyduMs2kI/AAAAAAAAAfs/-kxLGS5K0VU/s1600/thor+hammer.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="210" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1ehV6iV7B9k/UKSyduMs2kI/AAAAAAAAAfs/-kxLGS5K0VU/s320/thor+hammer.jpg" width="320"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Miniature Thor's Hammer&nbsp; found in Leicestershire</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p><b><span>Names are clues</span></b></p>
<p><span>With invading forces, you may assume
that they would settle on the broad and fertile river terraces of the Soar. But
settlements already existed here and new areas of land were needed to house the
large band of men who came to dwell in Leicestershire. By the study of
place-names, it appears that they turned towards the emptier and perhaps less
rewarding river terraces that flank the narrow valley of the Wreake. Along that
river we find Frisby, Hoby, Rotherby, Brooksby and Rearsby. The word “Wreake”
is also derived from Scandinavia, being the Old Norse word for “twisted”. So,
Wreake is both a description and the new name for the river once known as the
River Eye. Historian Sir Frank Stenton said the Wreake settlement was occupied
by a large body of the Danish army who took permanent occupation of the land
some time around 877.</span></p>

<p><span>The army would have been stationed here
so it could spring to the defence of Leicester if the town was ever threatened
by invaders from the west. Another Danish encampment is thought to have stood
on the area of Leicester known as Dane Hills. The creation of the Danelaw made
as great an impression on Leicester as in the surrounding countryside. The
colonising Danes, soldiers and farmers, turned the Mercian cathedral city into
a garrison town. The term “gate,” descended from the Old Norse, “gata,” meaning
a street, occurs in a handful of streets in the heart of Leicester. All in the
same part of town we find Gallowtree Gate, Humberstone Gate, Church Gate,
Belgrave Gate and Sanvey Gate. They lie outside the line of the former Roman
and medieval wall, beyond the bounds of the Anglo-Saxon town. As we all know,
the first four streets converge at the Clock Tower where High Street passed
through the former East Gate out of the walled enclosure of the medieval town. Thus,
the presence of the “gata” element in modern street names of Leicester suggests
that the Danes, when they made Leicester one of their strongholds, established
a new town outside the wall of the Mercian city. By the early years of the 10th
century, Leicester may have been like a town of two halves, sharply divided
into Anglo-Saxon and Danish quarters.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Fresh …</span></b></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html">http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26212092</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 09:25:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How my school gamed the stats]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 155 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26211921">thread link</a>) | @optimalsolver
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://www.greaterwrong.com/posts/Yv9aj9bWD5H7aaDdy/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.greaterwrong.com/posts/Yv9aj9bWD5H7aaDdy/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I was reading the Slate Star Codex <a href="https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/book-review-the-cult-of-smart">review</a> of The Cult of Smart. Part of it discusses charter vs state schools and the allegations of fraud of various kinds undermining charter schools record of better achievement. Reading it, I realized that I took for granted that public schools engage in systematic fraud in a variety of ways. I donâ€™t think this is something everyone understands, hence this post.</p>
<p>I went to a state school in the UK. State schools are rated on a 1 âˆ’ 4 scale from unsatisfactory to outstanding. My school was rated good, meaning a 3. A few memories which stand out. During my first week I saw one of the boys in my class who was 11 at the time held up against the wall in a corridor while a 16 year old put a shiv to his throat and robbed him. He handed over his wallet and keys. A year or two later and I remember seeing a small boy who struggled with depression held up by the throat against a locker and slapped in the face by a troublemaker from the same class in front of everyone just before we went in to the classroom. I remember classes which were filled start to finish with people shouting and talking. Neither of the first two events were common but they also werenâ€™t uncommon. No one was surprised to witness them. Itâ€™s worth emphasizing again that my school was above average, in fact quite far above average, and in a middle class area. Itâ€™s also worth noting that I was mostly in top ability streamed classes, meaning my classroom experience was likely far better than average.</p>
<p>There were many ways in which the school and teachers gamed the system to boost their measured performance. One way was to do exams for students. I was on a bottom set language class for French. After two years I literally couldnâ€™t speak a single sentence in french and maybe knew 20 words in total. I still passed my exams. How? We did the tests in class. Often the teacher would go through them with us. Literally giving us the test and then going through each question on the whiteboard and telling us what to write. A different year and a different teacher, this time the teacher would sit next to us and write the answers down. Why sit next to us? It was the bottom set so people often wouldnâ€™t even bother to write down the answer if they were told it. This kind of thing was normal, so much so that I, and I think most people there, didnâ€™t realize anything unusual was happening.</p>
<p>Another way schools game metrics is to cheat inspections. A major component of how schools are judged in the UK is through independent inspections carried out by an independent quasi-governmental organization called Ofsted. Now, you may imagine that these inspections would be unannounced, so as to best get a real image of how a school works. Not the case. Theyâ€™re scheduled well in advance. Before every inspection, a few things would happen in my school:</p>
<ul><li><p>The worst troublemaker kids would be taken aside and put in a special room where inspectors wouldnâ€™t see them. Either that or they would just be told not to come into school at all on that day.</p></li><li><p>All of us were told in assembly that an inspection was coming and to be on our best behavior on that day. Often teachers would have conversations with less serious troublemakers and impress on them that they would behave on that day or face consequences afterwards.</p></li><li><p>Teachers would put a great deal more effort into their lesson plans than was normal. Classroom behavior management would also be far stricter.
Because of these and other measures my school during an inspection was utterly different than my school on a normal day. On some level this isnâ€™t surprising. If teachersâ€™ promotions and managementâ€™s jobs depend on good inspection results and inspections are easy to game, people will game them. Incentives drive behavior. But itâ€™s still sad.</p></li></ul>
<p>Another way the stats were gamed was by not recording bad behavior. When a school gives a detention or suspends/â€‹expels a student, thereâ€™s a record of it. This is especially true of suspensions, students being sent home or expulsions. The more of these you have, the worse you look as a school. The solution then is obvious, donâ€™t punish people or punish them in non-recorded ways. Again, in my school it was completely normal for students in lower sets to swear at the teacher, talk over them or disrupt the class for everyone else. It was normal for someone to be aggressive and abusive towards others and to face at most a 40 minute detention, but even getting a detention would be unusual.</p>
<p>I realize that one data point is not enough to draw solid general conclusions. My own perception is that this kind of fraud wasnâ€™t specific to my school. My cousin went to a state school fairly nearby. Heâ€™s 4 years younger than me. During one of my winters back from undergrad we discussed his school and his experiences mirrored mine. His exact words regarding inspections were â€œI learned 4 times more that day than any other day that year. It was amazingâ€�. I talked to a few British students at university, although specifically the not middle/â€‹upper class ones who would have gone to public schools. They had gone to schools similar to mine in different parts of the country and their stories were similar and often worse. Two particularly funny examples from my friendsâ€™ experiences stand out. A teacher in year 9 walked up to a student who was talking, picked them up and threw them out of an (open) first floor window. My friend sitting in class noticed two boys making fun of him and then proceeded to get up in the middle of class while the teacher was talking, walk to their table, flip the table upwards to hit them in the face before going to sit down again when the teacher told him to. (Remember, my friend was a studious, sporty Asian kid and not a troublemaker. This kind of thing is normal in that environment). Comedic stories aside, my experiences in school, while not universal, seem fairly common in the UK and from what Iâ€™ve read of the statistics, bad US schools are far, far worse.</p>
<p>Iâ€™m unsure what my point here is. I think I have two:</p>
<ul><li><p>Charters may cook their books in various ways. In the UK, State schools do too. I would be surprised if it wasnâ€™t also the case in the US.</p></li><li><p>I think that I feel like a lot of commentators on places like SSC have fairly middle class experiences of fairly good schools and that bleeds into how their comparison between state vs charter schools. Itâ€™s just good to remember that itâ€™s not those nice middle class schools that charters typically replace.</p></li></ul>
<p>Crossposted to my blog at <a href="https://dissent.blog/2021/02/20/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats/">https://â€‹â€‹dissent.blog/â€‹â€‹2021/â€‹â€‹02/â€‹â€‹20/â€‹â€‹how-my-school-gamed-the-stats/â€‹â€‹</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.greaterwrong.com/posts/Yv9aj9bWD5H7aaDdy/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26211921</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 08:44:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Optimized bubble sort in JavaScript. Cocktail sort]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26211514">thread link</a>) | @chovybizzass
<br/>
February 20, 2021 | https://learn.coderslang.com/0037-javascript-optimized-bubble-sort.-coctail-sort/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://learn.coderslang.com/0037-javascript-optimized-bubble-sort.-coctail-sort/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://learn.coderslang.com/0036-javascript-bubble-sort/" target="_blank">Bubble sort algorithm</a>
doesn’t track the current state of the array.</p><p>Even if it gets the fully sorted array as an input, the runtime will remain of the same <strong>O(n^2^)</strong> complexity. By design this algorithm analyses all the adjacent pairs of elements of the original array <strong>n</strong> times where <strong>n</strong> is the length of an array.</p><h2 id="optimized-bubble-sort">Optimized bubble sort</h2><p>The bubble sort algorithm doesn’t keep track of the current state of the array in any way.</p><p>Even if we send an already sorted array as input, we will need the same number of loop iterations as for an unsorted array to get the result.</p><p>Performance can be improved by adding a flag (boolean variable) that will monitor whether there was at least one exchange at the current iteration.</p><p>If not, then the array is sorted and the task is complete.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="js"><span>const</span> <span>optimizedBubbleSort</span> <span>=</span> (<span>arr</span>) =&gt; {
  <span>let</span> <span>hasSwapped</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span>;
  <span>let</span> <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span>;
  
  <span>for</span> (<span>let</span> <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span>; <span>i</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>arr</span>.<span>length</span>; <span>i</span><span>++</span>) {
    <span>for</span> (<span>let</span> <span>j</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span>; <span>j</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>arr</span>.<span>length</span> <span>-</span> <span>i</span>; <span>j</span><span>++</span>) {
      <span>if</span> (<span>arr</span>[<span>j</span>] <span>&gt;</span> <span>arr</span>[<span>j</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span>]) {
        <span>hasSwapped</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span>;
        <span>let</span> <span>tmp</span> <span>=</span> <span>arr</span>[<span>j</span>];
        <span>arr</span>[<span>j</span>] <span>=</span> <span>arr</span>[<span>j</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span>];
        <span>arr</span>[<span>j</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span>] <span>=</span> <span>tmp</span>;
      }
    }
    <span>if</span> (<span>!</span><span>hasSwapped</span>) {
      <span>return</span> <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span>;
    } <span>else</span> {
      <span>hasSwapped</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span>;
    }
    <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span><span>++</span>;
  }
  <span>return</span> <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span>;
}
</code></pre></div><p>Let’s take two arrays to check the implementation. The second one is twice as long as the first one, but it has only one element out of place.</p><ul><li>display the initial state of the arrays</li><li>we sort them and save the number of iterations that the <code>optimizedBubbleSort</code> sort function will return</li><li>display the arrays again to make sure that they are sorted and check the number of iterations it took to sort</li></ul><div><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>const</span> <span>testData</span> <span>=</span> [ <span>0</span>, <span>-</span><span>1</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>-</span><span>3</span> ];
<span>const</span> <span>almostSortedTestData</span> <span>=</span> [ <span>12</span>, <span>-</span><span>3</span>, <span>-</span><span>1</span>, <span>0</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span>, <span>7</span>, <span>8</span>, <span>9</span>, <span>10</span> ];

<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>testData</span>, <span>`Initial testData state`</span>);
<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>almostSortedTestData</span>, <span>`Initial almostSortedTestData state`</span>);

<span>const</span> <span>iterationsTestData</span> <span>=</span> <span>optimizedBubbleSort</span>(<span>testData</span>);
<span>const</span> <span>iterationsAlmostSortedTestData</span> <span>=</span> <span>optimizedBubbleSort</span>(<span>almostSortedTestData</span>);

<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>testData</span>, <span>`Total iterations: </span><span>${</span><span>iterationsTestData</span><span>}</span><span>`</span>);
<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>almostSortedTestData</span>, <span>`Total iterations: </span><span>${</span><span>iterationsAlmostSortedTestData</span><span>}</span><span>`</span>);
</code></pre></div><p>The console output is:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span> 0, -1, 4, 5, 2, -3 <span>]</span> Initial testData state
<span>[</span> 12, -3, -1, 0, 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, <span>10</span> <span>]</span> Initial almostSortedTestData state

<span>[</span> -3, -1, 0, 2, 4, <span>5</span> <span>]</span> Total iterations: <span>6</span>
<span>[</span> -3, -1, 0, 2,  4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10, <span>12</span> <span>]</span> Total iterations: <span>2</span>

</code></pre></div><p>Although the second array turned out to be 2 times longer than the first one, we only needed two iterations of the outer loop to sort it.</p><p>On the second pass, the <code>hasSwapped</code> flag has not changed. This means that there were no exchanges and the array has already been sorted. We completed the optimized bubble sort algorithm right away and wasted no extra time.</p><p>By the way, if we try to sort an array in which all elements are already arranged in ascending order using the <code>optimizedBubbleSort</code> function, then we will need only one iteration of the outer loop. So at best we get <strong>O(n)</strong> runtime complexity.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>const</span> <span>testData</span> <span>=</span> [ <span>0</span>, <span>1</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>3</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span>, <span>6</span> ];

<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>testData</span>, <span>`Initial testData state`</span>);

<span>const</span> <span>iterationsTestData</span> <span>=</span> <span>optimizedBubbleSort</span>(<span>testData</span>);

<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>testData</span>, <span>`Total iterations: </span><span>${</span><span>iterationsTestData</span><span>}</span><span>`</span>);
</code></pre></div><p>Вывод на экран:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="javascript">[ <span>0</span>, <span>1</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>3</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span>, <span>6</span> ] <span>Initial</span> <span>testData</span> <span>state</span>
[ <span>0</span>, <span>1</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>3</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span>, <span>6</span> ] <span>Total</span> <span>iterations</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span>
</code></pre></div><h2 id="cocktail-sort">Cocktail sort</h2><p>Cocktail sort is another enhancement of the bubble sort. Alternative names for this sorting algorithm are shaker sort or bidirectional sort.</p><p>We start in exactly the same way as in the bubble sort, and “push up” the maximum element. After that, we unfold and “push down” the minimum of the remaining elements.</p><p>Once we get to the beginning of the array, there will already be 2 elements in their places - the first and the last one. Thus, we will make 2 times less iterations of the outer loop. Due to this, the speed of the cocktail sort will be slightly higher than that of the bubble sort.</p><p>We’ll start with the small refactoring and extract the exchange function from our algorithm. We’ll call it <code>swap</code> :</p><div><pre><code data-lang="js"><span>function</span> <span>swap</span>(<span>arr</span>, <span>i</span>, <span>j</span>) {
  <span>let</span> <span>tmp</span> <span>=</span> <span>arr</span>[<span>i</span>];
  <span>arr</span>[<span>i</span>] <span>=</span> <span>arr</span>[<span>j</span>];
  <span>arr</span>[<span>j</span>] <span>=</span> <span>tmp</span>;
}
</code></pre></div><p>Then, we implement the cocktail sort in JavaScript:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="js"><span>function</span> <span>cocktailSort</span>(<span>arr</span>) {
  <span>let</span> <span>left</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span>;
  <span>let</span> <span>right</span> <span>=</span> <span>arr</span>.<span>length</span> <span>-</span> <span>1</span>;
  <span>let</span> <span>hasSwapped</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span>;
  <span>let</span> <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span>;

  <span>while</span> (<span>left</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>right</span>) {
    <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span><span>++</span>;
    <span>for</span> (<span>let</span> <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>left</span>; <span>i</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>right</span>; <span>i</span><span>++</span>) {
      <span>if</span> (<span>arr</span>[<span>i</span>] <span>&gt;</span> <span>arr</span>[<span>i</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span>]) {
        <span>swap</span>(<span>arr</span>, <span>i</span>, <span>i</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span>);
        <span>hasSwapped</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span>;
      }
    }
    <span>right</span><span>--</span>;
    <span>for</span> (<span>let</span> <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>right</span>; <span>i</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>left</span>; <span>i</span><span>--</span>) {
      <span>if</span> (<span>arr</span>[<span>i</span>] <span>&lt;</span> <span>arr</span>[<span>i</span> <span>-</span> <span>1</span>]) {
        <span>swap</span>(<span>arr</span>, <span>i</span>, <span>i</span> <span>-</span> <span>1</span>);
        <span>hasSwapped</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span>;
      }
    }
    <span>left</span><span>++</span>;
    <span>if</span> (<span>!</span><span>hasSwapped</span>) {
      <span>return</span> <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span>;
    } <span>else</span> {
      <span>hasSwapped</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span>;
    }
  }
  <span>return</span> <span>outerLoopIterationCount</span>;
}
</code></pre></div><p>And, using the same array, let’s make sure that there are indeed 2x less iterations of the outer loop:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="javascript"><span>const</span> <span>testData</span> <span>=</span> [ <span>0</span>, <span>-</span><span>1</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>-</span><span>3</span> ];

<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>testData</span>, <span>`Initial testData state`</span>);
<span>const</span> <span>iterationsTestData</span> <span>=</span> <span>cocktailSort</span>(<span>testData</span>);
<span>console</span>.<span>log</span>(<span>testData</span>, <span>`Total iterations: </span><span>${</span><span>iterationsTestData</span><span>}</span><span>`</span>);
</code></pre></div><p>As you see, the array is sorted and total iterations is <code>3</code> instead of <code>6</code> for the <code>optimizedBubbleSort</code>:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="js">[ <span>0</span>, <span>-</span><span>1</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>-</span><span>3</span> ] <span>Initial</span> <span>testData</span> <span>state</span>
[ <span>-</span><span>3</span>, <span>-</span><span>1</span>, <span>0</span>, <span>2</span>, <span>4</span>, <span>5</span> ] <span>Total</span> <span>iterations</span><span>:</span> <span>3</span>
</code></pre></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://learn.coderslang.com/0037-javascript-optimized-bubble-sort.-coctail-sort/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26211514</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 07:11:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[“555” and related telephone prefixes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 38 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26211060">thread link</a>) | @miles
<br/>
February 20, 2021 | https://computer.rip/2021-02-20%20555%20500%20710%20etc.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://computer.rip/2021-02-20%20555%20500%20710%20etc.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>


<p>We are probably all familiar with "555" telephone numbers. The basic idea is
that the 555 exchange code (or NXX in a NANP NXX-XXXX number) is reserved for
use in fiction. Of course, this isn't actually true at all, but that hasn't
stopped basically every work of fiction putting their imaginary telephone
numbers in the 555 exchange.</p>
<p>In reality, the 555 exchange has a somewhat bumpy history, as is the case with
most "special purpose" telephone ranges. Seemingly from the genesis of NANP as
a formal numbering standard, the 555 exchange was reserved for special use by
telcos, and was not to be used for normal subscriber lines. The 555 exchange
accumulated various and sundry uses, but most prominently, starting in the
early '60s it was used for directory service at 555-1212 in nearly all NPAs
(area codes). This was nearly the only successful use of the 555 exchange,
leaving it mostly empty.</p>
<p>Because the 555 exchange was conveniently largely out of use, it became common
for the entertainment industry to use 555 numbers in fiction. Wikipedia makes
the claim that the telephone industry had specifically recommended 555 numbers
for this use in the '60s, and while this is rather thinly sourced, it's not
hard to believe as any odd person in a technical role at a telephone company
might have suggested 555 as an exchange with extremely few assigned numbers.</p>
<p>In any case, the use of 555 numbers for fiction was somewhat informal. This
changed in 1994, when the telephone industry regretted leaving an entire
exchange out of use and formed a working group which allowed 555 numbers to
be assigned to nationwide communications services. The idea was that 555
numbers would have the unusual property of working nationwide when dialed as
only seven digits, somewhat like an early version of SMS short codes.</p>
<p>Because the use of 555 numbers in fiction was longstanding, the working group
explicitly reserved numbers starting 555-01 for use in fiction. This, in 1994,
is when this practice became formalized---but only for those 100 numbers.</p>
<p>In practice the 555 service as imagined was unsuccessful, and in the 2010s the
use was eliminated more or less by handshake agreement. Much like the pre-1994
state, the only valid phone numbers in the 555 exchange are 555-1212 for
directory assistance, and 555-4334. This latter number is apparently still
assigned for a nationwide use but no one specifies <em>what</em> use.</p>
<p>I did a bit of digging, and... came up empty. 555-4334 in a number of area
codes turns up nothing from the CNAM service I use. Similar attempts with
a couple of validation/carrier lookup vendors returned different types of
useless results. I haven't found any mention of the number in old newspapers,
with the interesting exception of some newspapers listing their classified
ads with exclusively 555 numbers, including 4334.</p>
<p>It was not an unusual practice at the time for newspapers to provide special
"voice mail box" numbers for classified ads, but to my knowledge the use of 555
was not typical.  The first newspapers to do so were almost all in Utah, which
hints that it may have originated as a choice by a local telco, potentially
Mountain Bell but maybe more likely an independent. I will do some more digging
into this over time. It's interesting in that it suggests a major use of 555
numbers which no document I've seen on the history of the exchange mentions.
This practice doesn't seem to have been eliminated until the 1994 reallocation.</p>
<p>I also learned that in 2009 you could get a rebate of $7,555 or $4,334 on a new
Dodge Nitro. Isn't OCR fun?</p>
<p>Finally, I located an older FCC report (dated 1997) that lists 555-4334 as
allocated to MCI mail, an early e-mail service. MCI mail access was initially
by modem, and so it's possible that 555-4334 was used as an access number,
although an 800 number was also provided for this purpose and 4334 is not
mentioned anywhere I can find as an access number. An interesting feature of
MCI Mail was its ability to forwarded email to postal addresses (by printing and
mailing it) or by fax or teletype, so I speculate that 555-4334 may have been
used as a return number for TTY messages, since the TTY integration was
apparently bidirectional. In any case, another document noted that 555-4334 was
permitted to remain in service until that service ended, which may have been an
allowance due to the fact that MCI was a telephone carrier (and thus had
greater sway over the working group) and that replacing the number may have
been technically difficult.</p>
<p>Today, it remains the case that only 555-01xx is properly allocated for
fictional use. However, the 555 exchange as a whole is as dead (or considering
the use by newspapers, much  more dead) than ever before, so it remains common
to use the entire 555 exchange in fiction.</p>
<p>Oddly, the 555 NPA (rather than exchange) is allocated for similar
applications, but as far as I can tell it is not in use.</p>
<p>The failure of the post-1994 use of 555 for a "short dialing service" reflects
a larger series of telco failures that has left some other special prefixes.
In the '90s, a great deal of attention was directed towards "non-geographic"
dialing. Because the telephone system connected the nation together, why not
have a method of telephone dialing which is independent of geography? Well, as
it turns out, there are several reasons, but this didn't stop anyone from
trying.</p>
<p>Although there were a hodgepodge of other attempts, the first major
non-geographic dialing scheme is contained in the special 700 NPA (area code).
This NPA was allocated as a direct result of the breakup of the Bell system for
use directly by interexchange (long-distance) carriers, since all existing
numbering ranges were allocated to the exchange (local) carriers. The primary
service offered in this range was "EasyReach 700" from AT&amp;T, which was
basically carrier-managed "follow-me."</p>
<p>Follow-me is a common feature of business telephone systems that allows a call
to a given number (extension or DID) to be directed to one or more real
extensions depending on the location of the intended recipient. For example, a
call to a professional might go to their desk or to an assistant depending on
whether they are in the office, while an auto mechanic might have a call to a
general contact number ring at the front desk or in the shop depending on where
they are.</p>
<p>EasyReach 700 moved this same concept from the PABX to the telephone network,
making it possible for follow-me to span the nation and making it accessible to
businesses without an (expensive) PABX. For example, a consumer with two
different homes could get a 700 number and set it to forward to whichever house
they were staying in, while a traveling salesman could set their 700 number
to forward to whichever hotel they were staying in.</p>
<p>EasyReach was a failure. There were several reasons, but the most significant
relates to the billing climate of the time. Today, unlimited long-distance is
so ubiquitous that the issue may not be obvious, or you might naively assume
that AT&amp;T had found a way to resolve the long distance cost issue. They did
not---in fact, they came up with something worse. The owner of a 700 number
could set it up to either bill forward (to the caller) or reverse (to the
callee). This meant that the caller of a 700 number had virtually no way to
determine whether the call would be free or charged at long-distance rate, and
this was a huge deterrent to use of these numbers.</p>
<p>Today, this and other uses of the 700 NPA have all died out, leaving 700
a nearly empty NPA. Like other empty NPAs, 700 is sometimes hijacked for
special uses by non-mainstream carriers and corporate phone systems. If my
hazy memory is correct, the 700 NPA was used by GE's interoffice leased-line
long distance network when I briefly worked for a GE business. Wikipedia
says that WalMart still uses it this way.</p>
<p>Since the 700 NPA was such a success, AT&amp;T naturally decided to do it again.
In 1993, NANP allocated the 500 NPA to Personal Communications Service (PCS),
not to be confused with Personal Communications Service (PCS). In fact, the
same term was allocated to two completely different purposes by two different
telecom organizations within a few years. The latter refers to a set of
services offered by a wireless network, e.g. Sprint PCS, while the former
refers to...  EasyReach 700 all over again, except for now it's called True
Connections.</p>
<p>True Connections failed for the exact same reasons as EasyReach 700, and was
officially eliminated in 2000, but by this point AT&amp;T had already largely
replaced it with a service using 800 numbers which were of course always
reverse billed...  which you and I might think is obviously what they should
have done in the first place, but back in the '90s toll-free and non-geographic
were viewed as being different animals. It seems to have taken AT&amp;T a long time
to catch on to the fact that the realities of long-distance billing required
that they be closely linked.</p>
<p>The concept of PCS (the non-geographic dialing one) did not die out with True
Connections, and additional NPAs were allocated to the same purpose,
generally in the format of 5 followed by the same digit twice, much like 800.
500 numbers continue to be non-geographic and the billing situation remains
odd, but that hasn't stopped the use of 500 for certain uses like modem banks
for ISPs and some calling cards. Very few 500 numbers remain in use today
despite the multiple allocated 500 codes, and due to the billing issues it's
common for outbound calls to 500 numbers to be blocked. Similar to 700, it's
not unusual for 500 to be used for internal purposes, although this is probably
less of a good idea since PCS services in the 500 NPA have not officially been
ended.</p>
<p>500 and related PCS area codes (500 has a surprising number of overlays
considering how obscure its usage is) also see use for other miscellaneous
telco applications. For example, the 588 area code, also assigned to PCS, was
(and may still be) …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://computer.rip/2021-02-20%20555%20500%20710%20etc.html">https://computer.rip/2021-02-20%20555%20500%20710%20etc.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://computer.rip/2021-02-20%20555%20500%20710%20etc.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26211060</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 05:27:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Modern software controls dependencies because it helps software authors]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 109 | Comments 106 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26210576">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 20, 2021 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/BundlingHelpsSoftwareAuthors | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/BundlingHelpsSoftwareAuthors">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Modern software controls dependencies because it helps software authors</h2>

	<p><small>February 20, 2021</small></p>
</div><div><p>Over on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/thatcks/status/1363196953065099265">I had a hot take</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Hot take: Every distribution packager who's saying "you shouldn't
bundle dependencies" is implicitly telling software authors "you
should do more work for us and limit the features (and reliability) of
your software".</p>
</blockquote>

<p>(This was sparked by reading <a href="https://blogs.gentoo.org/mgorny/2021/02/19/the-modern-packagers-security-nightmare/">The modern packagerâ€™s security
nightmare</a>,
<a href="https://lobste.rs/s/zb1c4k/modern_packager_s_security_nightmare">via</a>.
I'm not exactly on one side or the other, but <a href="https://twitter.com/thatcks/status/1363263921960980485">I do think distributions
should be honest about what they're asking for</a> and I
don't think they're going to get it.)</p>

<p>This hot take is a bit too narrow. What really matters is software
authors and modern software systems restricting the versions of
dependencies (for both maximum and minimum versions). Explicit or
implicit bundling on top of that just makes the problem slightly worse
for distributions.</p>

<p>For software authors, restricting the versions of dependencies that
they work with reduces the amount of work that they have to do,
both to test against a range of versions and to either forever chase
after whatever changes those dependencies like to make or to forever
limit what features of dependencies they use to ones available in
old versions (and sometimes both at once). In theory, both testing
and chasing after changes would be dealt with by <a href="http://semver.org/">Semantic Versioning</a> (if everyone followed it), at least for a
single program. In practice, not only are people fallible but also
<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/SemverHasLimits">people have a different understanding of what semantic versioning
means</a> because semantic versioning is ultimately
a social thing, not a technical one. Our field's history has shown
(sometimes vividly) that if software authors allow versions of
dependencies to move on them, soon or later things break and the
software author has to fix it.</p>

<p>(There's also the practical issue that not all dependencies even
claim or agree to follow semantic versioning in the first place.)</p>

<p>For distributors, once software authors start restricting versions
the distributor has both an upgrade problem and a distribution
problem. On the upgrade side, dealing with an issue in a program may now
require persuading it to accept a new version of a dependency. On the
distribution side, it's now likely that you'll have multiple programs
that have different version requirements for the same dependency. At the
very least this multiplies the packages involved.</p>

<p>(Many distributions also have package system design problems that
restricts the range of versions of things that they can have installed
at the same time. Even under <a href="http://semver.org/">Semantic Versioning</a>, this is a
problem for the distribution the moment that you have two programs
with conflicting version requirements that can't both be packaged and
installed at the same time.)</p>

<p>However, there's no free lunch here. What distributors want when
they ask for unbundled dependencies without version restrictions is
for software authors to do the work to accept any version of their
dependencies, or at least any version that falls within <a href="http://semver.org/">Semantic
Versioning</a>, and for dependencies to faithfully follow semver and
also make it possible to package and install different major versions
(at least) at the same time. <strong>Accepting a broad version range of your
dependencies is actual work</strong>, even apart from the limitations it may
impose on what your code and your software can do. Software authors and
the creators of software package ecosystems (like Go and Rust) are not
refusing to do this because they don't like distributions; they are
refusing to do this because they have found, over and over again, that
this doesn't really work and does cause problems for software authors
(and often users of programs) in the long run.</p>

<p>(The software community that's gone through this experience the
most visibly is Go, which started out with intrinsically unversioned
dependencies that were used universally across all your programs
by default and wound up switching to strongly versioned dependencies
after many people had many problems with that initial state. Go
experienced so many problems that <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/FallibleSemverAndMVS">they adopted an unusually strict
and software author friendly versioning scheme</a>.)</p>

<p>It's popular for people to argue that software authors should be doing
this work anyway even if the distributions weren't asking for it,
so them actually doing it is no big deal. This is quite convenient
for the people making the argument, but it doesn't make the argument
valid. Software authors don't owe anyone any work what so ever; they
do whatever work serves their needs and is interesting to them. With
limited time and interest, it's both rational and proper for software
authors to optimize for their own development.</p>

<p>PS: Generally distributions also want some combination of all software
to update to the latest version of their dependencies and for
dependencies to explicitly support older versions. This is also extra
work for software authors, especially when the distribution also wants
it to happen for older versions of programs.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/BundlingHelpsSoftwareAuthors</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26210576</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 03:36:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Boeing 747 loses parts after take-off from Maastricht – 2 injuries]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26209611">thread link</a>) | @UncleOxidant
<br/>
February 20, 2021 | https://www.aviation24.be/airlines/longtail-aviation/boeing-747-loses-parts-after-take-off-from-maastricht-diverts-to-liege-two-people-injured/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.aviation24.be/airlines/longtail-aviation/boeing-747-loses-parts-after-take-off-from-maastricht-diverts-to-liege-two-people-injured/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident.jpg 1920w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-300x169.jpg 300w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-768x432.jpg 768w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-696x392.jpg 696w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-1068x601.jpg 1068w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-747x420.jpg 747w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-600x338.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px">A Boeing 747-400BCF freighter registered VQ-BWT (MSN 24975) flying for Bermuda-based Longtail Aviation took off from runway 21 at Maastricht Aachen Airport this Saturday afternoon at 16:11 (UTC+1). The aeroplane operating flight LGT5504 to New York JFK experienced heavy damage on an engine shortly after take-off. Engine parts (turbine blades) fell in the nearby village of Meerssen resulting in 2 people slightly injured and damage to cars.</strong></p>
<p>According to a spokesman for the South Limburg Safety Region, an explosion has probably occurred in engine number one of the aircraft. Metal parts such as turbine blades have come down around the Limburg town of Meerssen.</p>
<p>Debris hit an elderly woman, who was slightly injured as a result. A child also burned his fingers on a piece of metal.</p>
<p>In Meerssen several houses and cars got damaged by falling debris.</p>
<p>The thirty-year-old plane immediately diverted on three engines to Liège airport, where it landed safely after making a number of laps over the Ardennes to burn fuel and lose weight.</p>
<p><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1.jpg" alt="blank" width="1001" height="610" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1.jpg 1001w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-300x183.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-768x468.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-696x424.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-689x420.jpg 689w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-600x366.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1001px) 100vw, 1001px"></p>
<p>According to aviation expert Joris Melkert, it is a special incident: “<em>I cannot remember a recent case in the Netherlands where parts of an engine fell down.</em>”</p>
<p>The cause of the incident is unknown. The engine may have sucked up something causing the turbine blades to break. This is what the debris looks like, says the airport spokesman.</p>
<p>The police are calling on people to leave the debris behind, in connection with recording the damage.</p>
<p>The Onderzoeksraad voor Veiligheid (Dutch Safety Board) has started an exploratory investigation.</p>
<p>Spotter Aubrey Verbaere was present at Liège Airport when the Longtail Boeing 747 landed and provided <em>Aviation24.be</em> with the following pictures:</p>
<figure id="attachment_107911" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107911"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-scaled.jpg" alt="blank" width="2048" height="1365" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-scaled.jpg 2048w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-300x200.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1024x683.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-768x512.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-696x464.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1068x712.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1920x1280.jpg 1920w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-630x420.jpg 630w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107911">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107912" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107912"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643.jpg" alt="blank" width="1280" height="1280" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643.jpg 1280w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-300x300.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-150x150.jpg 150w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-768x768.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-696x696.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-1068x1068.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-420x420.jpg 420w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-600x600.jpg 600w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107912">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107914" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107914"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364.jpg" alt="blank" width="1280" height="1280" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364.jpg 1280w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-300x300.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-150x150.jpg 150w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-768x768.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-696x696.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-1068x1068.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-420x420.jpg 420w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-600x600.jpg 600w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107914">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107906" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107906"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231.jpg" alt="blank" width="1280" height="1280" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231.jpg 1280w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-300x300.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-150x150.jpg 150w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-768x768.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-696x696.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-1068x1068.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-420x420.jpg 420w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-600x600.jpg 600w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107906">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107909" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107909"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-scaled.jpg" alt="blank" width="2048" height="1365" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-scaled.jpg 2048w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-300x200.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1024x683.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-768x512.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-696x464.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1068x712.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1920x1280.jpg 1920w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-630x420.jpg 630w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107909">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Longtail Aviation</b> is a charter airline based in St. George’s, Bermuda and was formed in August 1999.</p>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Longtail Aviation cargo 747 loses engine parts over Meerssen after failure on departure from Maastricht Airport in The Netherlands. Aircraft landed safely in Liege. <a href="https://t.co/b22hB9QgKF">https://t.co/b22hB9QgKF</a> <a href="https://t.co/NYps5GoBzT">pic.twitter.com/NYps5GoBzT</a></p>
<p>— Breaking Aviation News &amp; Videos (@breakingavnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/breakingavnews/status/1363175798438510603?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.aviation24.be/airlines/longtail-aviation/boeing-747-loses-parts-after-take-off-from-maastricht-diverts-to-liege-two-people-injured/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26209611</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:35:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
