<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 20:21:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 20:21:34 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pieter Levels Makes $600k a Year from Nomad List and Remote OK]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24259201">thread link</a>) | @Pete-Codes
<br/>
August 24, 2020 | https://www.nocsdegree.com/pieter-levels-learn-coding/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.nocsdegree.com/pieter-levels-learn-coding/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                    <div>
                        <p><a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio">Pieter Levels </a>makes about $600,000 a year. He taught himself to code and has an unconventional philosophy. This is not an interview but an analysis piece. Pieter defied the critics and built Nomad List and Remote OK into successful businesses without cutting edge tools like React or other modern frameworks. I send articles like this twice a week - <a href="https://nocsdegree.carrd.co/">join 2,000 developers that get the newsletter</a>.</p><h2 id="who-is-pieter-levels">Who is Pieter Levels</h2><p>Pieter is a self-taught developer from The Netherlands. He has an MBA but no coding qualifications. As we will see in today's article he has a rough and ready approach to coding but it pays off handsomely. </p><p>His <a href="https://www.nomadlist.com/">Nomad List</a> directory and community for digital nomads draws in over $300k a year and that's despite a recent fall in revenue due to people not travelling during the Corona virus crisis. </p><figure><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/05/Screenshot-2020-05-14-at-23.30.06.png" alt=""></figure><p>His Remote Ok job board for remote workers made <a href="https://remoteok.io/open">$300,000 over the last 12 months</a></p><figure><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/05/Screenshot-2020-05-14-at-23.23.51.png" alt="Revenue chart for Remote OK job board"></figure><p>So that's a total of $600,00 from the last 12 months! Not bad for a self-taught developer! Pieter is active on Twitter and has a very stong following there. </p><p>As he works for himself he is able to travel extensively and live where he choses. Although, rather than the common misconception of digital nomads being constantly on the move, Pieter recommends spending a few months in each place. This way you avoid travel burnout. </p><h2 id="how-did-pieter-levels-learn-to-code">How did Pieter Levels learn to code?</h2><p>Not a lot is known about his very earlies forays into coding apart from the fact that as a teenager he played around programming. His first attempt at a web business was an analytics service for Youtube which would let you see how all your videos/channels were performing in one place. Unfortunately, he worked on it for a year without making any money from it. </p><p>From that point Pieter adopted his now familar approach to coding and business - build websites quickly and monetize from the beginning. He only adds more features if there is money coming in and the idea is validated by the market.</p><p>Pieter takes the "search on Google" approach to Google. So when he wanted to connect a database to a website or make a button do something on his website he would just search the terms on Google and find solutions in places like Stackoverflow. Pieter is a strong critic of the approach of doing courses as he believes people learn best by doing and building. </p><p>One analogy would be different approaches to learning Spanish. One person might study a course, learn the correct grammar and then go to Spain. Whereas Pieter would go to Spain, ask for the words he needs to use and go from there. </p><p>When asked in the past why he didn't use modern frameworks like React he made the point that as he was a solo founder he couldn't afford to spend time re-building his websites as this would mean his project would stall. </p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><a href="https://gum.co/GGofo"><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/08/monetize.png" alt="monetize"></a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h2 id="what-technologies-does-pieter-levels-use">What technologies does Pieter Levels use?</h2><p>Pieter is famous (or infamous) for having a rather eccentric choice of stack by modern standards. It's essentially the easiest, least glamorous tools you could imagine. But that's ok because Pieter makes $600k a year! </p><p>Here is his stack:</p><ul><li>HTML (hand coded so no template to make life easier)</li><li>CSS (He has used pre-processors like LESS and SASS in the past)</li><li>Javascript (No frameworks - this is sometimes referred to jokingly as Vanilla Javascript. There is no such thing as Vanilla JS though. It's just plain-old Javascript without a framework such as React, Vue or Angular) </li><li>jQuery (An unfashionable choice nowadays but it does the job)</li><li>PHP (He doesn't use any frameworks like Laravel)</li><li>SQLite - Pieter says it's super quick and swears by it. SQLite is a database written in a single file so Pieter doesn't need to set up a server for it. &nbsp;</li><li>his sites are hosted on a single VPS running Ubuntu with NGINX.</li></ul><p>Here are some modern options Pieter doesn't use </p><ul><li>React - he jokes a lot about how he never wants to learn it due to it's (perceived) complexity. </li><li>Node - for a time he considered using it but he's never used it in production</li><li>Angular/ Vue - he doesn't use any Javascript frameworks </li><li>SQL/ Postgres - he doesn't use any of the conventional databases </li></ul><h2 id="get-a-job-without-a-cs-degree-">Get a job without a CS degree 👇</h2><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><a href="http://nocsok.com/"><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/08/Screenshot-2020-08-07-at-17.35.28-2.png" alt="No-CS-OK-screenshot-1"></a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h2 id="what-results-has-pieter-had-with-this-approach-to-coding">What results has Pieter had with this approach to coding?</h2><p>Despite the technical critics, Pieter has been consistently making six figures since 2014. He currently makes approximately $600,000 a year which is far more than most developers. He has been able to live in countries with a low cost of living so he will likely be able to have financial independence and not need to work relatively soon. </p><figure><blockquote data-width="550"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">📈 Record sales yesterday of $2,342.04 on <a href="https://t.co/S9Qv34rpbP">https://t.co/S9Qv34rpbP</a> for no apparent reason (maybe companies are spending their EOY HR budgets?). Normal sales is like $299 or 1 post per day. <a href="https://t.co/8HukglDuiv">pic.twitter.com/8HukglDuiv</a></p>— ؜ (@levelsio) <a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio/status/938699122445451265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2017</a></blockquote>

</figure><figure><blockquote data-width="550"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/rORz8xdCQp">https://t.co/rORz8xdCQp</a> is a single PHP file called "index.php" generating $2,342.04 in a day. No frameworks. No libraries. 💖</p>— ؜ (@levelsio) <a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio/status/938707166508154880?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2017</a></blockquote>

</figure><h2 id="what-is-pieter-levels-working-on-now">What is Pieter Levels working on now?</h2><p>He just released a new project, <a href="https://remoteworkers.dev/">Remote Workers</a>, where people can post their resumé. He "built in public" - that is to say he gave daily updates of his code on Twitter. This is also a great way for developers to build an audience! You can check out what people are saying about Remote Workers on <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/remote-workers">Product Hunt</a>. </p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>Pieter is like a bare knuckle boxer so don't compare him to a Judo practioner going to the Olympics. One is going to win no matter what and one is going to follow the rules they have trained under and have finer technique. Neither is better or worse. It depends on the situation. </p><p>Pieter's approach would not be good if you were trying to get a job in a lot of companies. But Pieter isn't looking for a job and the proof for him is in his bank balance. So Pieter's scrappy technique is better suited if you are attracted to coding for entrepreneurship and being a solo founder who doesn't have to share their code with others to work on. He doesn't use Github to save his code, for instance and this is an industry standard that most employers expect. If you want to be an indie hacker/entrepreneur though then Pieter is a fine act to follow. </p><h3 id="if-you-enjoyed-this-article-please-send-it-to-a-friend">If you enjoyed this article please send it to a friend </h3><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><h3 id="and-you-should-totally-sign-up-for-the-newsletter">And you should totally <a href="https://nocsdegree.carrd.co/">sign up for the newsletter</a> </h3>
                    </div>
                </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.nocsdegree.com/pieter-levels-learn-coding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24259201</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A tale of webpage speed, or throwing away React]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24258855">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 24, 2020 | https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section itemprop="articleBody">
  <p>Back in 2011, I happened to get a job writing <a href="https://backbonejs.org/">Backbone.js</a> app. If you never did that, don’t. I was complaining about difficulties with composition left and right to whoever would listen. As I started digging into alternatives for the front-end, I discovered <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_reactive_programming">FRP</a> and <a href="https://www.flapjax-lang.org/">Flapjax</a>, and <a href="https://clojurescript.org/">ClojureScript</a>. The last one got me hooked on <a href="https://clojure.org/">Clojure</a>. I even did a <a href="https://fwdays.com/event/js-frameworks-day-2013/review/Functional-Reactive-Programming-&amp;-ClojureScript">successful talk</a> on FRP and ClojureScript (and precursor to <a href="https://hoplon.io/">Hoplon</a>, called hlisp).</p>
<h2 id="react">React</h2>
<p>Then in May 2013 React was released. I championed it on my new job and discovered during Clojure-themed hackaton (<a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2013/clojurecup/">Clojure Cup 2013</a>) that CLJS and React are a great match. What’s so good about React though? To me, the main selling point is that it composes well.</p>
<p>When you use predecessors like jQuery or Backbone or Angular or whatever after just a year of development your code is a mess of event listeners and triggers. Don’t get me started on unobtrusive JS, code locality is non-existent with jQuery. Which handler is bound where and what it does? It’s too hard to discover to be a good base for a good codebase!</p>
<p>Then I started working at <a href="https://kasta.ua/">Kasta</a>, where web frontend was exactly that jQuery-ish mess. Nobody ever wanted to touch checkout, since you could spend hours, if not days, making the smallest change. Then QA would find more invalid states than you can dream of. And then users would report more bugs to our call center. It was just as awful as you can imagine.</p>
<p>So after some experiments, tests, and checks, I decided that we’re going React + ClojureScript way with server-side rendering done in Clojure.</p>
<h2 id="demise">Demise</h2>
<p>And for a while, things were looking good. We had this <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2017/server-side-rendering/">architecture</a> where our components are executed as Clojure on the backend, so no Node.js on the server, hurray! And developer UX is through the roof with the excellent live reload (thanks CLJS), ability to connect from your editor to browser REPL, and experiment there. It is just great!</p>
<p>To make a long story short, our frontend grew bigger and bigger. Incremental compilation started to become slower — it now routinely takes more than a second or two. And while there were few attempts on keeping the whole app performant, ultimately we failed. It’s a death by a thousand cuts. The application became too big and its boot time became too long. Server side rendering helps partially, but then hydration freezes the browser. On the older hardware or Androids it became unacceptable!</p>
<p>One of the main reasonings back in 2016 was that we take a hit on startup time, but in turn, get no page loads and have a rich web application with a lot of interactions. And for a while that worked! But startup time became longer and longer, leading to a shameful rating of 5/100 from Google’s PageSpeed (okay, it was sometimes up to ~25/100, whatever).</p>
<p>More than that, while doing what is described below, we’ve discovered that React also leads to some questionable practices. Like hovers in JS (rather than in CSS), drop-down menus in JS, not rendering hidden (under a hover) text (Google won’t be happy), weird complex logic (since it’s possible!), etc. You can have a React app without those problems, but apparently, you have to have better self-control than we had (nobody’s perfect!).</p>
<p>Also since then, the vast majority of our users switched to mobile apps. This made the web app the main entry point for new users. This means its main goal is rendering fast for a newcomer, because old-timers, which want more functionality, are on mobile app now. And <a href="https://web.dev/tti/">TTI</a> (time to interactive) is so much more important here.</p>
<h2 id="time-for-a-change">Time For A Change</h2>
<p>So given that circumstances have changed, what do we do? I read articles “how I survive on vanilla JS” since before React appeared and they usually don’t make sense — it’s either a pink-glassed rant about how great it is, disregarding all the problems (separation of concerns, cohesion, composability, code locality) or a project by one (or few) persons, who just keep everything in their head.</p>
<p>Somewhere back in February I stumbled upon <a href="https://intercoolerjs.org/">Intercooler.js</a>. I’m not sure if I ever saw it before — maybe I did but skimmed over — it does not matter. This time it captured my attention.</p>
<p>The idea is that all HTML is rendered on the server. And client updates parts of HTML, controlled by element’s attributes. Basically like HTML+XHR on steroids. You can’t do anything you want, but that’s partially the point: some limits are good so you won’t do crazy stuff. And you need some support from the server, so you can render partial results — just an optimization, but quite an important one.</p>
<p>There is an alternative library — <a href="https://unpoly.com/">Unpoly</a>. It has more features around layout and styling but has a little bit less thought out XHR stuff (hard to do a POST request with parameters without having a form, for example). And the library size is much bigger. And it’s written in CoffeeScript with lots of classes, <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/inheritance/">ugh</a>.</p>
<p>So I made a proof-of-concept implementation of our catalogue page in Intercooler and it worked! Except there was a dependency on jQuery and some other irritating stuff… As I was struggling to make a batch request for HTML fragments I understood one thing: when I wrote down a roadmap for catalogue the last point was “small intercooler-like thing for analytics”.</p>
<p>So why wait?</p>
<h2 id="twinspark">TwinSpark</h2>
<p>I liked Intercooler’s coherent approach to working around AJAX, so I decided to name the library after some automotive stuff as well, and TwinSpark seems like an appropriate name. So what’s the deal?</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/kasta-ua/twinspark-js">TwinSpark</a> is a framework for declarative HTML enhancement: you put additional attributes on your element and TwinSpark does something with them. Like makes an AJAX call and replaces target with a response, or adds a class, or… well, see <a href="https://kasta-ua.github.io/twinspark-js/">examples</a>, shall you?</p>
<p>There are some differences with Intercooler, of course, because why would it exist? The most noticeable one is that there is no dependency on jQuery. It supports only modern browsers (not IE or Opera Mini) but drops that 88kb monster.</p>
<p>It also has:</p>
<ul>
<li>no inheritance — can’t stress that enough!</li>
<li>clear extension points for your directives</li>
<li>support for batching requests to a server</li>
<li>tighter attribute name convention (my own opinion, but <code>ic-get</code> and <code>ic-post</code> irritate me: do not make me change keys!)</li>
<li>much smaller payload (thanks to no jQuery!)</li>
<li>should be faster (thanks to no jQuery again)</li>
</ul>
<p>Honestly speaking, the main reasons are <a href="https://kasta-ua.github.io/twinspark-js/#batch">batching</a> and <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/inheritance/">no inheritance</a>. Inheritance is particularly painful here. In Intercooler, if you declared <code>ic-target</code> on the body, all tags inside will think it’s their target too. So you include a component somewhere in HTML tree and an attribute higher on tree changes this component behavior. I mean this is a freaking dynamic scope, I want none of that! :)</p>
<p>Funnily enough, after about a month of dabbling with TwinSpark, Intercooler’s author announced that he’s doing a jQuery-less modern version: <a href="https://htmx.org/">htmx</a>. :) It has really good extensions points, so maybe it’s possible to add batching… but inheritance is still there. :-(</p>
<h2 id="why-is-that-a-good-idea">Why is that a good idea</h2>
<p>We need to look at it from two sides: if it’s good for developers and if it’s good for users. React was great at former and terrible at later.</p>
<p>TwinSpark approach is much better in most cases for the user: less JavaScript, less jitter, more common HTML-like behavior. In the worst case, we would serve you 2.5MB of minified (non-gzipped) JS and 700KB of HTML (half of it were initial data for React) for catalogue. JS bundle is not that big because of embedded images or css or some other obscure stuff, it’s big because it’s the whole app, with a lot of views and logic.</p>
<p>Now it’s 40KB of minified non-gzipped JS (TwinSpark, analytics, some behavior, IntersectionObserver polyfill) and 350KB of HTML. Two orders of magnitude difference and even HTML is smaller! This is just like Christmas in childhood!</p>
<p>On the developer side, I think React is better still, but code locality is great, composability is much better (since you are forced in a limited world of working in a simplistic model) than with jQuery. Plus there are a lot of ways to improve it.</p>
<p>The good news is that the development process did not change that much! We’re still writing components that query necessary data from site-wide memory store (and make a call to API when needed), but they are executed only on the server. We effectively piggy-backend on our previous architecture, and this gives us the perfect ability to render “partial” HTML - since components do not wait for some “controller” to give them all necessary data. This is what allowed us to have both React and non-React versions to co-exist and make an A/B test without writing the markup twice.</p>
<h2 id="results">Results</h2>
<p>It took us four months since the first experiments to release. Not exactly the amount of time I imagined when we started (“should take two to three weeks at most!"), heh, but we were not exclusively doing that. It still took a lot of time and energy to remove React-isms from the code and wrangle our app to be a server-side citizen. It still could use some polishing, but we decided to release it despite that just to cut it short. And A/B test showed that we were right — especially for Android phones.</p>
<p>Google gives our catalogue 75/100 now instead of 5/100. Hurray, I guess? :)</p>

  </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24258855</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 09:25:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Principal Component Analysis]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24257468">thread link</a>) | @keyboardman
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>

<p>Principal components analysis (PCA) is one of a family of techniques for taking high-dimensional data, and using the dependencies between the variables to represent it in a more tractable, lower-dimensional form, without losing too much information. It has been widely used for data compression and de-noising. However, its entire mathematical process is sometimes ambiguous to the user.</p>



<p>In this article, I would like to discuss the entire process of PCA mathematically, including PCA projection and reconstruction, with most of the derivations and proofs provided. At the end of the article, I implemented PCA projection and reconstruction from scratch. After reading this article, there should be no more black box in PCA anymore.</p>

<h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites</h3>

<h4 id="orthogonal-matrix">Orthogonal Matrix</h4>

<p>In linear algebra, an orthogonal matrix is a real square matrix whose columns and rows are orthogonal unit vectors (orthonormal vectors).</p>



<p>Equivalently, the mathematical expression is</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\top}A = AA^{\top} = I
\end{align}\]

</p><p>By <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invertible_matrix">the definition of invertible matrix</a>, this means matrix $A$ is invertible and $A^{-1} = A^{\top}$.</p>



<p>We could also view this from the perspective of determinant.</p>



<p>Because $A$ and $A^{\top}$ are square matrices and using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Determinant#Properties_of_the_determinant">the properties of determinant</a></p><p>

\[\begin{align}
\det(I) &amp;= \det(A^{\top}A) \\
&amp;= \det(AA^{\top}) \\
&amp;= \det(A) \det(A^{\top}) \\
&amp;= \det(A) \det(A) \\
&amp;= \det(A)^2 \\
&amp;= \det(A^{\top})^2 \\
&amp;= 1 \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Since $\det(A) \neq 0$, matrix $A$ is invertible. We multiply $A^{-1}$ on both side of the orthogonal matrix definition.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\top}A A^{-1} &amp;= I A^{-1}\\
A^{\top} I &amp;= A^{-1} \\
A^{\top} &amp;= A^{-1} \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We have also derived the conclusion that $A^{-1} = A^{\top}$.</p>



<p>Similarly, a complex square matrix $A$ is unitary if its transpose conjugate $A^{\dagger}$ is also its inverse.</p>



<p>Equivalently, the mathematical expression is</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\dagger}A = AA^{\dagger} = I
\end{align}\]

</p><h4 id="symmetric-matrix">Symmetric Matrix</h4>

<p>Real symmetric matrix has the following useful properties:</p>



<p>If $A$ is a real symmetric matrix, all of its eigenvalues are real numbers.</p>



<p>Because of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complex_conjugate#Generalizations">the conjugate properties</a> and $\overline{A} = A$ since $A$ is a real value matrix,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
\overline{Av} &amp;= \overline{\lambda v} \\
&amp;= \overline{A} \overline{v} \\
&amp;= A \overline{v} \\
&amp;= \overline{\lambda} \overline{v} \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We got $A \overline{v} = \overline{\lambda} \overline{v}$.</p>



<p>Let $\lambda \in \mathbb{C}$ be an eigenvalue of the symmetric matrix $A$. $Av = \lambda v$ and $v \neq 0$. We multiply $v^{\dagger}$ ($v^{\dagger} = \overline{v}^{\top}$) to the both sides, and because of $A^{\top} = A$ and the property we have just derived $A \overline{v} = \overline{\lambda} \overline{v}$,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
v^{\dagger} A v &amp;= \lambda v^{\dagger} v \\
&amp;= v^{\dagger} A^{\top} v \\
&amp;= \overline{v}^{\top} A^{\top} v \\
&amp;= (A\overline{v})^{\top} v \\
&amp;= (\overline{\lambda} \overline{v})^{\top} v \\
&amp;= \overline{\lambda}^{\top} \overline{v}^{\top} v \\
&amp;= \overline{\lambda} v^{\dagger} v \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We have $\lambda v^{\dagger} v = \overline{\lambda} v^{\dagger} v$, thus $\lambda$ is real.</p>



<p>This concludes the proof.</p>

<h4 id="positive-semi-definite-matrix">Positive Semi-Definite Matrix</h4>

<p>The $n \times n$ symmetric matrix $A$ is defined to be positive semi-definite, if $x^{\dagger} A x \geq 0$ for $x \in \mathbb{C}^n$.</p>



<p>The positive semi-definite matrix has the following important property:</p>



<p>The eigenvalues of positive semi-definite matrix are non-negative.</p>



<p>Because $x^{\dagger} A x \geq$ for $x \in \mathbb{C}^n$, suppose $x$ is an eigenvector of $A$ and $Ax = \lambda x$ where $x \neq 0$,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
x^{\dagger} A x &amp;= x^{\dagger} \lambda x \\
&amp;= \lambda x^{\dagger} x \\
&amp;\geq 0 \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Because $x^{\dagger} x$ must be real number and $x^{\dagger} x &gt; 0$, we have $\lambda \geq 0$.</p>



<p>This concludes the proof.</p>

<h4 id="covariance-matrix">Covariance Matrix</h4>

<p>The covariance matrix has the following important property:</p>



<p>Covariance matrix is positive semi-definite. This means that the eigenvalues of covariance matrix is non-negative.</p>



<p>The proof of that covariance must be positive semi-definite could be found in my previous post on <a href="https://leimao.github.io/blog/Multivariate-Gaussian-Covariance-Matrix/">Multivariate Gaussian and Covariance Matrix</a>.</p>

<h4 id="singular-values">Singular Values</h4>

<p>The singular values, $\sigma_1$, $\sigma_2$, $\cdots$, $\sigma_r$, of an $m \times n$ matrix $A$ are the square roots, $\sigma_i = \sqrt{\lambda_i}$, of non-negative eigenvalues of the associated Gram matrix $K = A^{\dagger}A$. The corresponding eigenvectors of $K$ are known as singular vectors of $A$.</p>



<p>Note that the associated Gram matrix $K = A^{\dagger}A$ is real and symmetric, so the eigenvalues of $K$ are all real.</p>



<p>$K = A^{\dagger}A$ is also positive semi-definite.</p>



<p>For any vector $x$</p><p>

\[x^{\dagger} (A^{\dagger} A) x = (Ax)^{\dagger} Ax\]

</p><p>Because $Ax$ is also a vector,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
x^{\dagger} (A^{\dagger} A) x \geq 0
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Therefore, all the eigenvalues of $K = A^{\dagger}A$ are non-negative and they all have a corresponded singular value of $A$.</p>

<h4 id="singular-value-decomposition">Singular Value Decomposition</h4>

<p>In linear algebra, the singular value decomposition (SVD) is a factorization of a real or complex matrix that generalizes the eigendecomposition of a square normal matrix to any $ m\times n$ matrix via an extension of the polar decomposition.</p>



<p>Specifically, the singular value decomposition of an $m \times n$ real or complex matrix $M$ is a factorization of the form $U \Sigma V^{\dagger}$, where $U$ is an $m \times m$ real or complex unitary matrix, $\Sigma$ is a $m \times n$ rectangular diagonal matrix with non-negative real numbers on the diagonal, and $V$ is an $n \times n$ real or complex unitary matrix.</p>



<p>The diagonal entries $\sigma_{i}=\Sigma_{ii}$ of $\Sigma$ are known as the singular values of $M$. The number of non-zero singular values is equal to the rank of $M$.</p>



<p>In particular, for any matrix $A \in \mathbb{C}$,</p><p>

\[A_{m \times n} = U_{m\times m} \Sigma_{m \times n} V_{n \times n}^{\dagger}\]

</p><p>We will skip the proof for why every matrix has SVD and the algorithm for SVD.</p>

<h4 id="singular-value-decomposition-for-norm-matrix">Singular Value Decomposition for Norm Matrix</h4>

<p>For any matrix $A \in \mathbb{C}$, $A^{\dagger} A$ could be expressed as</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\dagger} A &amp;= (U \Sigma V^{\dagger})^{\dagger} U \Sigma V^{\dagger} \\
&amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} U^{\dagger}  U \Sigma V^{\dagger} \\
&amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} I \Sigma V^{\dagger} \\
&amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma V^{\dagger}
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We multiply $V$ at both side of the equation.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\dagger} A V &amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma V^{\dagger} V \\
&amp;=  V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma I \\
&amp;=  V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma \\
&amp;= \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma V \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Note that $\Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma$ is a square diagonal matrix. Based on the definition of eigenvalue and eigenvectors, the diagonal values of $\Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma$, including the zeros, are the eigenvalues of $A^{\dagger} A$. All the columns of $V$ are the corresponding eigenvectors of $A^{\dagger} A$.</p>



<p>Similarly, $A A^{\dagger}$ could be expressed as</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A A^{\dagger} U &amp;= \Sigma \Sigma^{\dagger} U \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Note that $\Sigma \Sigma^{\dagger}$ is a square diagonal matrix. Based on the definition of eigenvalue and eigenvectors, the diagonal values of $\Sigma \Sigma^{\dagger}$, including the zeros, are the eigenvalues of $A A^{\dagger}$. All the columns of $U$ are the corresponding eigenvectors of $A A^{\dagger}$.</p>

<h3 id="mathematics-of-principal-components-analysis">Mathematics of Principal Components Analysis</h3>

<p>We start with $p$-dimensional vectors, and want to summarize them by projecting down into a $q$-dimensional subspace, where $q \leq p$. Our summary will be the projection of the original vectors on to $q$ directions, the principal axes, which span the subspace.</p>

<h4 id="minimizing-projection-residuals">Minimizing Projection Residuals</h4>

<p>Given a dataset $X \in \mathbb{R}^{n \times p}$ whose row is the centered data vectors $x_i \in \mathbb{R}^p$ for $0 \leq i \leq n-1$ ($\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} x_{i} = 0$), if we have a unit vector $w \in \mathbb{R}^p$ ($|w| = 1$) and we project the all the data vectors to this unit vector $w$.</p>



<p>The length of projection for data vector $x_i$ on $w$, by definition, is</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
|x_i| \cos \theta &amp;= \frac{\langle x_i, w \rangle}{|w|} \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, w \rangle \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>where $\langle x_i, w \rangle$ is the inner product of $x_i$ and $w$.</p>



<p>The projection vector for data vector $x_i$ on $w$ is $\langle x_i, w \rangle w$.</p>



<p>The residual, which is the distance from data vector $x_i$ to $w$, is the length of vector $x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w$.</p>



<p>Let’s check what the residual square $| x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w | ^2$ is.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
| x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w |^2 &amp;= \langle x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w, x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w \rangle \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - \langle x_i, \langle x_i, w \rangle w \rangle - \langle \langle x_i, w \rangle w, x_i \rangle + \langle \langle x_i, w \rangle w, \langle x_i, w \rangle w \rangle \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - \langle x_i, w \rangle \langle x_i, w \rangle - \langle x_i, w \rangle \langle w, x_i \rangle + \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \langle w,  w \rangle \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - 2 \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 + \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 |w| ^2 \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - 2 \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 + \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle -  \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>The optimization goal of projection is to minimize mean squared error $\text{MSE}(w)$, which is the mean of the residual sum of squares.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
\text{MSE}(w) &amp;= \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1} | x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w |^2 \\
&amp;= \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1} \big( \langle x_i, x_i \rangle -  \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \big)\\
&amp;= \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1} \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1}  \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2\\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Remember the relationship between variance and expected value, $\mathbb{V}(X) = \mathbb{E}(X^2) - \mathbb{E}(X)^2$, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/">https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24257468</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 04:12:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Clean Start for the Web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24255541">thread link</a>) | @tannhaeuser
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The web is in need of some reinvention right now.</p><p>The web’s evolution over the last decade has mirrored the American economy. All of the essential indicators are going “up and to the right,” a steady stream of fundamental advances reassure use that there “is progress,” but the actual experience and effects for individuals stagnates or regresses.</p><p>The crisis affects platforms, creators, and consumers alike.</p><p><em>I’m going to try and dissect and diagnose this situation, a bit. You can skip forward if you just want to read my casual, unprofessional pitch for a reboot of the web. The idea is that we could choose a new lightweight markdown format to replace HTML &amp; CSS, split the web into documents and applications, and find performance, accessibility, and fun again.</em></p><details><summary>This post uses the pedantic definition of "the web"</summary>I've discussed attempts to reinvent the "Internet" a few times. Things like dat, IPFS, and arweave are all projects to reinvent an Internet, or a transport and data-sharing layer. The web is what lies on top of that, the HTML, CSS, URLs, JavaScript, browsing experience.</details><h3 id="the-platform-collapse">The platform collapse</h3><p>The platform side is what changed last week, when <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/08/firefox-maker-mozilla-lays-off-250-workers-says-covid-19-lowered-revenue/">Mozilla laid off 250 employees</a> and indicated that it would affect Firefox development. Firefox wasn’t the #2 browser - that’s Safari, mainly because of the captive audience of iPhone and iPad users. But it was the most popular browser that people <em>chose</em> to use.</p><p><img alt="Chart of browser market share, with Chrome becoming the monopoly" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-chart-of-browser-market-share-with-chrome-becoming-the-monopoly.png"></p><p><em>Chart from <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share#monthly-200901-202007">statcounter</a></em></p><p>The real winner is not just Chrome, but Chrome’s engine. One codebase, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KHTML">KHTML</a>, split into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebKit">WebKit</a> (Safari), and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blink_(browser_engine)">Blink</a> (Chrome, Microsoft Edge, Opera, etc.)</p><p>This a textbook monoculture. In one sense, it’s a victory for collaboration because nobody’s ‘wasting time’ on competing implementations and web developers can expect the same features and bugs across different browsers. But in a deeper way, it threatens one of the basic principles of how the web has evolved.</p><h3 id="specs--implementations">Specs &amp; implementations</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-decline.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Decline" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-decline.jpg"></picture></p><p>The web has evolved through a combination of <em>specifications</em> and <em>implementations</em>. Organizations like the <a href="https://whatwg.org/">WHATWG</a>, <a href="https://www.w3.org/">W3C</a>, and <a href="https://www.ietf.org/">IETF</a> have been collaboration spaces for independent developers, corporations, and academics to discuss potential new features of the web. Then, browsers would test those ideas out in a variety of implementations.</p><p>This was an interesting structural piece: it reassured us all that it was <em>possible</em> to follow along, and that a multi-participant web was one of our goals. It was frustrating to pull up <a href="https://caniuse.com/">caniuse</a> and see blank spots, but the idea was that different browsers may take the lead in some areas, but everyone catches up eventually. Chrome was not always the first to jump on features, or the first to optimize.</p><p>It’s slower to collaborate than to work alone, but it was beneficial in some ways that we’ve lost now. Chrome has been moving extremely fast, adding new specifications and ideas at a startling rate, and it’s becoming one of the hardest pieces of software to replicate.</p><p>Mike Healy I think <a href="https://twitter.com/mike_hasarms/status/1296575224599556097">said it best</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Do you think the web has almost ‘priced itself out of the market’ in terms of complexity if only 1-2 organisations are capable of building rendering engines for it?</p></blockquote><p>Not only is it nearly impossible to build a new browser from scratch, once you have one the ongoing cost of keeping up with standards requires a full team of experts. Read Drew DeVault’s <a href="https://drewdevault.com/2020/08/13/Web-browsers-need-to-stop.html">Web browsers need to stop</a> for that point, and keep reading all of Drew’s stuff.</p><details><summary>What about Flow?</summary>Yep, there’s a <a href="https://www.ekioh.com/flow-browser/">browser called Flow</a>, which may exist and may support a full range of web standards. If it does exist, I’ll be very excited about it, but it has been teased for almost a year now without any concrete evidence, so it could equally be vaporware.</details><h3 id="the-problem-for-creators">The problem for creators</h3><p>The web has gotten much harder to develop for.</p><p>The web has had about 25 years to grow, few opportunities to shrink, and is now surrounded by an extremely short-sighted culture that is an outgrowth of economic and career short-termism. There are lots of <a href="https://frankchimero.com/blog/2018/everything-easy/">ways to do anything</a>, and some of the most popular ways of building applications on the web are - in my opinion - <a href="https://macwright.com/2020/05/10/spa-fatigue.html">usually ghoulish overkill</a>.</p><p>The best way for folks to enter <em>web development</em> in 2020 is to choose a niche, like <a href="https://vuejs.org/">Vue.js</a> or <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a>, and hope that there’s a CSS and accessibility expert on their team.</p><p>For folks who just want to create a web page, who don’t want to enter an industry, there’s a baffling array of techniques, but all the simplest, probably-best ones are stigmatized. It’s easier to stumble into building your resume in React with GraphQL than it is to type some HTML in Notepad.</p><h3 id="the-problem-for-consumers">The problem for consumers</h3><p>We hope that all this innovation is <em>for the user</em>, but often it isn’t. Modern websites seem to be as large, slow, and buggy as they’ve ever been. Our computers are <a href="https://macwright.com/2019/11/15/something-is-wrong-with-computers.html">barely getting faster</a> and our internet connection speeds are stagnating (don’t even <em>try</em> to mention 5G). Webpage <a href="https://www.pingdom.com/blog/webpages-are-getting-larger-every-year-and-heres-why-it-matters/">size growth</a> is outpacing it all.</p><p>The end result is that I no longer expect pages to be fast, even with <a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock">uBlock</a> installed in Firefox and a good local <a href="https://sonic.net/">fiber internet provider</a>.</p><p>I don’t want to lay all of the blame at <em>those web developers</em>, though. Here’s a story from an old job that I find kind of funny. We were collecting some data from user interactions to answer simple questions like “do people click to upload or do they drag &amp; drop?” So we enabled <a href="https://segment.com/">Segment</a>, a tool that lets you add data-collection pipelines by including a single script. The problem, though, is that Segment offered a big page of on/off switches with hundreds of data providers &amp; ad-tech companies on it. And, sure, enough, some folks closer to the business side started <em>clicking all those buttons</em>.</p><p>See, the problem with ads and data tracking is that <em>you can</em>, and who is going to say no? (In that instance, I said no, and added a <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP">CSP</a> that would block new advertiser access at the page level.)</p><h2 id="recreating-simplicity">Recreating simplicity</h2><blockquote><p>You cannot get a simple system by adding simplicity to a complex system. - <a href="http://erlang.org/pipermail/erlang-questions/2012-March/065087.html">Richard O’Keefe</a></p></blockquote><p>Where do we go from here? Some of the smartest folks out there have been <a href="https://twitter.com/_developit/status/1296628134406692865">advocating for a major version revision</a> of the web.</p><p><em>I am in no way qualified to speculate on a whole new web from scratch, but the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/21/us/california-wildfires.html">air quality</a> is scary so I’m skipping my run and it’s Saturday morning so here we are.</em></p><p>How do we make the web fun, participatory, and good?</p><p>My first thought is that there are two webs:</p><h3 id="the-document-web">The document web</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-web-pages.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Illustration of web pages" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-web-pages.jpg"></picture></p><p>There is the “document web”, like blogs, news, Wikipedia, Twitter, Facebook. This is basically the original vision of the web, as far as I can understand it (I was 2). Basically CSS, which we now think of as a way for designers to add brand identity and tweak pixel-perfect details, was instead mostly a way of making plain documents readable and letting the <em>readers</em> of those documents customize how they looked. This attribute actually <a href="https://twitter.com/autiomaa/status/1296755641164468224">survived for a while in Chrome, in the form of user stylesheets</a>, and <a href="https://davidwalsh.name/firefox-user-stylesheet">still works in Firefox</a>. Though it’s going to be a rough ride in the current web which has basically thrown away <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_HTML">semantic HTML</a> as an idea.</p><h3 id="the-application-web">The “application” web</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-machines.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Illustration of machines" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-machines.jpg"></picture></p><p>Then there’s the “application web”. This started as <em>server</em> applications, built with things like <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a> and <a href="https://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> and before them a variety of technologies that will live forever in corporations, like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jakarta_Servlet">Java Servlets</a>.</p><p><a href="https://backbonejs.org/">Backbone.js</a> demonstrated that a lot of these applications could be moved into the browser, and then <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a> and its many SPA-style competitors established a new order for the web – highly-interactive, quite complex, client-side applications.</p><h3 id="the-war-between-the-parts-of-the-web">The war between the parts of the web</h3><p>I posit that this dual-nature is part of what gives the web its magic. But it’s also a destructive force.</p><p>The magic is that a simple blog can be creative expression, can be beautifully interactive. This one isn’t, but I’m just saying - <a href="https://www.typewolf.com/site-of-the-day">it’s possible</a>.</p><p>The problem is that the “document web” is often plagued by application characteristics - it’s the JavaScript and animations and complexity that makes your average newspaper website an unmitigated disaster. Where document websites adopt application patterns they often accidentally sacrifice <a href="https://www.a11yproject.com/">accessibility</a>, performance, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_scraping">machine readability</a>.</p><p>And the “application web” is plagued by the document characteristics - interactive applications are going to great lengths to avoid most of the essential characteristics of HTML &amp; CSS and just use them as raw materials - avoiding writing any HTML directly at all, avoiding <a href="https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/css-in-js">writing any CSS directly at all</a>, avoiding <a href="https://www.react-spring.io/">default animation features</a>, replacing <a href="https://reactrouter.com/">page-based navigation with something that looks like it but works completely differently</a>. The application web uses <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/introducing-jsx.html">JSX</a>, not HTML, and would like that in the browser itself, or <a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a>, instead of JavaScript, and would like that too.</p><p>When I read blog posts from ‘traditional web developers’ who are mad that HTML &amp; CSS aren’t enough anymore and that everything is complicated –&nbsp;I think this is largely that the application stack for building websites has replaced the document stack in a lot of places. Where we would use Jekyll or server-side rendering, we now use React or Vue.js. There are advantages to that, but for a lot of minimally-interactive websites, it’s throwing away decades worth of knowledge in exchange for certain performance perks that might not even matter.</p><p>The appeal of social networks is partly because they let us create <em>documents</em> without thinking about web technology, and they provide guarantees around performance, accessibility, and polish that otherwise would take up our time. You don’t have to think about whether your last Facebook post will load quickly on your friend’s phone or whether your Instagram post will be correctly cropped and resized in the timeline - those things are taken care of.</p><p>To some extent, this doesn’t <em>need</em> to be something that only social networks provide, though: standards like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS">RSS</a> and services like <a href="https://www.instapaper.com/">Instapaper</a> show that pleasing formatting and distribution can be done at the <em>platform level</em> and be provided on top of existing vanilla websites.</p><details><summary>These are not absolutes.</summary>Yeah, I can hear it now: but these categories are not …</details></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html">https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24255541</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 21:47:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Loot boxes in online games and their effect on consumers [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24254712">thread link</a>) | @infodocket
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/ATAG/2020/652732/IPOL_ATA(2020)652732_EN.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/ATAG/2020/652732/IPOL_ATA(2020)652732_EN.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/ATAG/2020/652732/IPOL_ATA(2020)652732_EN.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24254712</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 19:47:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bare Metal Rust Generics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 195 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24254048">thread link</a>) | @cube00
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>I've had the pleasure to work with very experienced firmware developers; the
kind of people who know the size of their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_zone_(computing)">red
zones</a> and routinely
transform coffee into linker scripts and pointer dereferences. In other words,
the <a href="http://www.catb.org/%7Eesr/jargon/html/story-of-mel.html">Mels</a> and <a href="https://www.usenix.org/system/files/1311_05-08_mickens.pdf">Zeus
Hammers</a> of the
world.</p>
<p>When it comes to the tools of our trade, many of them are curious and
experimental. Some of them—very much myself included—explore far enough to leave
pragmatism behind and veer into idealism, stubbornly forcing beautiful round
pegs into industrial square holes. Hey, maybe they're square for a reason, but
it doesn't hurt to try.</p>
<p>The majority of them aren't like that. Your average battle-tested firmware
developer has accrued a healthy distrust of the abstract, probably born of
watching shiny platonic constructs crash and burn with painfully <em>real</em> and
<em>concrete</em> error traces. It is sobering, having to chase a hardfault on a tiny
MCU across enough vtables and templated code to make Herb Sutter puke angle
brackets. No wonder modern approaches are met with some resistance unless the
LOADs and the STOREs are in clear view.</p>
<p>I felt this way too when someone suggested to me, back in 2014, that an
up-and-coming language called <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> showed promise
in the embedded field. <em>Surely not</em>, I thought, <em>too high level.</em> Even though I
had been playing with it already, my profoundly ingrained bit-twiddling
instincts told me not to trust a language that supported functional programming,
or one that dared to have an <em>opinion</em> on how I managed my memory. Bah! That's
how you get philosophers to run out of forks, and your forks to turn into
SIGSEGVs.</p>
<p>I was wrong.</p>
<p>Through the past five years of experimentation, I've gone from intrigued, to
optimistic, to <em>convinced</em> that Rust is an ideal language to build industrial
grade, bulletproof bare metal software. Beyond that, I've come to realize that
even the highest level constructs that the base language offers are applicable
to firmware development, very much unlike other languages that span a wide range
of paradigms (I'm looking at you, C++). There are a few reasons I felt this way:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rust's safety guarantees and general strictness bring the debug time down
significantly, so there's less need to spend time developing mental maps of
how high level constructs correspond to hardware primitives.</li>
<li>The type system is <em>great</em> at enforcing local reasoning and preventing leaky
abstractions. Building decoupled systems with no runtime cost is easy.</li>
<li>The compiler error messages are worthy of an AI assistant with <em>concerning</em>
mind-reading abilities.</li>
</ul>
<p>Lately, I've had the chance to work on a Rust
<a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f412.html">STM32F412</a>
project in a professional setting, with one of the goals being to foster a Rust
knowledge pool at my company. The project, <code>Loadstone</code>, is a 32kb secure
bootloader targeting bare metal devices for the medical industry.</p>
<p>While it would've been easier—and much less of a headache to my colleagues—to
stick to a subset of Rust more familiar to C developers, with your <code>for</code>s, your
<code>*mut u8</code>s and your <code>unsafe</code>s, I instead decided not to pull any punches and
make liberal use of generics, iterator adapters, typestate programming and other
stuff that would've made 2010's cuervo cry blood and hug the closest copy of
Kernighan and Ritchie.</p>
<p>The pressures of a real collaborative project have taught me a lot, and many
assumptions have been refined thanks to the criticism of several skilled
outsiders who, as outsiders often do, had a privileged view on things I took for
granted.</p>
<p>A topic that came up frequently in code review is
<a href="https://thume.ca/2019/07/14/a-tour-of-metaprogramming-models-for-generics/">generics</a>.
Perhaps still recovering from a SFINAE nightmare, some colleagues were
unsure about the use of generics to group behaviour that we'd normally write
separate implementations for. The concerns tended to fall in one of three
categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Runtime performance.</li>
<li>Binary size bloat.</li>
<li>Habitability and readability.</li>
</ul>
<p>The first is easy to dispel, as it often comes from unfamiliarity with static
dispatch. No vtables or heap allocations in anything we're doing, promise! The
second concern is valid but I've found it to be negligible in practice; I have
plans for another blog post giving some concrete benchmarks.</p>
<p>The last concern is the most subjective and thus the hardest to argue, so I
decided to focus on it in this blog series. I'll go over the design process of
two similar flash memory drivers, and hopefully show how generic programming can
make the job easier and the result more habitable, even in the barren, heapless,
rugged world of bare metal firmware.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Compile times are another common—and very valid—argument against liberal use
of generics. However, it is not a big problem for low footprint embedded
projects like this one.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_memory">Flash memory</a> is electronic
non-volatile storage. It's ubiquitous in consumer electronics; any time you
switch a small device off and it <em>remembers something</em>—whether it's settings,
songs, documents, even its own program—chances are you have flash memory to
thank. We'll be looking at two different <em>NOR</em> flash chips, since the first demo
port of <code>Loadstone</code> requires us to operate both:</p>
<ul>
<li>The embedded
<a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f412.html">STM32F412</a>
1MB MCU flash.</li>
<li>The external 128MB <a href="https://www.micron.com/-/media/client/global/documents/products/data-sheet/nor-flash/serial-nor/n25q/n25q_128mb_1_8v_65nm.pdf">Micron
N25Q128</a>
flash chip present in the <a href="https://www.st.com/en/evaluation-tools/32f412gdiscovery.html">STM32F412ZGT6 Discovery
Kit</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You probably knew what flash memory is used for already, but what non-firmware
developers may not know is that flash memory is <em>quirky</em>. You cannot simply
write a byte to a NOR flash address, sir, that would be rude. While a blob of
flash memory will happily turn a <code>1</code> into a <code>0</code>, the opposite operation will
fail silently.</p>
<p>You can think of every <code>1</code> bit (NOR flash's <em>erased</em> state) as a lit candle you
can blow out. However, in this metaphor you don't get a lighter
to light them back up; you get a flamethrower. Without getting into the hardware
principles involved, the design of NOR flash memory requires that you erase
(i.e. set to <code>1</code>) memory <em>in bulk</em>, in chunks often orders of magnitude bigger
than the minimum addressable memory. On most chips you even have a three way
mismatch: your read, write and erase sizes aren't equal. Ugh.</p>
<p>As you can imagine, this makes writing flash drivers a bit of a pain,
particularly because even the smallest write operations turn into <em>read/write
cycles</em>. Writing a single byte requires reading the minimum erasable block
surrounding the targeted address (which may itself require multiple reads),
potentially erasing the entire block, then writing back the original data merged
with the desired byte.</p>
<p>As you can also imagine, nobody but the person writing this driver <em>wants to
care about this</em>. Even in the minimalistic world of bare metal software,
productive collaboration depends on developers filing away these sharp edges,
presenting interfaces that uniformize or hide any aspects of hardware irrelevant
to the bigger design. As such, a first stab at a flash memory interface should
simply offer a way to read and write ranges of memory.</p>
<p>Let's look at some code:</p>
<pre><code><span>pub trait </span><span>ReadWrite {
   </span><span>type </span><span>Error;
   </span><span>type </span><span>Address;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>address</span><span>: </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>bytes</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> [</span><span>u8</span><span>]) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>write</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>address</span><span>: </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>bytes</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>[</span><span>u8</span><span>]) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>range</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>) -&gt; (</span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address);
   </span><span>fn </span><span>erase</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>The above is what I converged on as a generic interface to a flash
driver. If you're unfamiliar with Rust generics, the above isn't a type, or a
parent class to inherit from. It's more like a Haskell typeclass; a set of
requirements for a concrete type to implement, described in this case in the
form of associated types (<code>Error</code> and <code>Address</code>) and method signatures (<code>read</code>,
<code>write</code>, <code>range</code> and <code>erase</code>).</p>
<p>Even at this early step, some tradeoffs have to be made. The keen,
hardfault-traumatized reader will notice that this interface doesn't lend itself
well to timing sensitive problems. All methods are blocking, and abstracting the
read/write cycle away will naturally lead to non-deterministic write times; a
write may take very little if it only requires toggling bits off, or it might
take very long if it straddles two big sectors requiring erase operations. The
<code>bytes</code> output parameter in <code>read</code> might also strike you as not too rusty, where
returning a <code>Vec&lt;u8&gt;</code> is often idiomatic. Unfortunately we have no heap to work
with, so if you want to take your bytes home you'll have to bring your own bag.</p>
<p>Indeed, it's hard to write the universal interface. This one made sense for the
problems we're solving, but make sure to keep in mind the requirements of your
project!</p>
<h3 id="why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type">Why not simply write a concrete type?<a href="#why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type" aria-label="Anchor link for: why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type">🔗</a></h3>
<p>Ah, the word "simply" is tricky. Datasheet in hand, it may have been easier to
write. It might even save us a few bytes down the line. But altogether I think
the benefits of starting here are well worth the drawbacks:</p>
<ul>
<li>Makes it easy to write test doubles and leverage static dispatch for unit
testing. This kind of approach is what I miss the most when writing C, where
I'm forced to resort to link time substitution or to do things with the
preprocessor too vile to even mention here.</li>
<li>Decouples your design from the get go and makes collaboration easy. Another
developer can immediately start working against this interface, and it's
abstract enough to give you confidence it won't need to be changed as more
knowledge of the hardware emerges.</li>
<li>Going abstract first forces you to think long and hard about what behaviour is
common to each implementation and what behaviour isn't, which helps to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_repeat_yourself">not
repeat yourself</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>But the biggest reason, and one where C++ and Rust diverge, is the fact that
<em>you can reason about this interface locally</em>. This stems from a non-obvious
difference between the C++ template system and Rust traits. Where C++ templates
type check at the point of instantiation, Rust traits type check at the point of
definition.</p>
<p>What does this mean? It means that the inscrutable, seven-feet-deep-in-a-library
C++ template errors are impossible in Rust, because the compiler doesn't need to
go beyond the interface to prove it is used correctly.</p>
<p>A similar interface using C++ …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/">https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24254048</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 18:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Covid-19 fatality rate “worst miscalculation in the history of humanity”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24253636">thread link</a>) | @mrfusion
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/worst-miscalculation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/worst-miscalculation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
		<!-- #masthead .site-header -->

	<div id="main">

		<div id="primary">
			<div id="content" role="main">

			
				

				
<article id="post-1262">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
		
<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ron-Brown-PhD-.jpg" alt="Ron Brown Phd" width="167" height="171" srcset="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ron-Brown-PhD-.jpg 333w, https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ron-Brown-PhD--292x300.jpg 292w" sizes="(max-width: 167px) 100vw, 167px"><figcaption><sup>Ronald B. Brown PhD</sup></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>This month, Dr. Ronald B. Brown had a daring paper published in <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/disaster-medicine-and-public-health-preparedness/article/public-health-lessons-learned-from-biases-in-coronavirus-mortality-overestimation/7ACD87D8FD2237285EB667BB28DCC6E9#" target="_blank">Disaster Medicine and Public Health Preparedness</a>, conservatively entitled <em>Public health lessons learned from biases in coronavirus mortality overestimation</em>. </p>



<p>“The subject of this article is disruptive, to say the least, although it is not as obvious from the title,” Dr. Brown told me in an email. “The manuscript cites the smoking-gun, documented&nbsp;evidence showing that the public’s overreaction to the coronavirus pandemic was based on the worst miscalculation in the history&nbsp;of humanity,&nbsp;in my opinion. My manuscript underwent an intensive&nbsp;peer-review process. You are the first media guy who has responded to my invitation.”</p>



<p>It’s sadly no surprise the media has not kept Dr. Brown’s phone ringing with interview requests. The abstract, in itself, contains a firecracker where he says: </p>



<p>“Results of this critical appraisal reveal information bias and selection bias in coronavirus mortality overestimation, most likely caused by misclassifying an influenza infection fatality rate (IFR) as a case fatality rate (CFR).”</p>



<p>Is that not what we’ve seen? The number of people they said would be buried in mass COVID-19 graves better reflects how many people simply ended up with a cough and fever.</p>



<p>Dr. Brown added that CDC and WHO documents show that the case fatality rate for influenza was similar to the coronavirus, implying that the lockdowns were pointless. His paper questions why the 2017-2018 influenza season in the United States did not “receive the same intensive media coverage as COVID-19.”</p>



<p>He points out that “the accuracy of coronavirus tests rushed into production during the pandemic were unknown.” And he explores how the  media began focusing on an increase in coronavirus cases while ignoring the decrease in  death rates.</p>



<p>Much of the article looks at how lockdowns and anti-social distancing probably had little or no effect on reducing COVID-19 deaths. He says that “the public’s belief that mitigation measures were responsible for reducing coronavirus mortality may be a post hoc fallacy if lower mortality was actually due to the overestimation of coronavirus deaths.”</p>



<p>Speaking on the damage done by the counter-measures, Brown writes: “The ethics of implementing fear-based public health campaigns needs to be reevaluated for the potential harm these strategies can cause.”</p>



<p>His report includes this mind-map on how we were all mind-warped:</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="447" height="447" src="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image.png" alt="" srcset="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image.png 447w, https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image-300x300.png 300w, https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 447px) 100vw, 447px"></figure></div>



<p>You can read Brown’s full paper at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/7ACD87D8FD2237285EB667BB28DCC6E9/S1935789320002980a.pdf/public_health_lessons_learned_from_biases_in_coronavirus_mortality_overestimation.pdf" target="_blank">Cambridge University Press</a>. It succinctly dismisses the notion that the <a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/resist-the-corona-craze/" data-type="post" data-id="405">corona craze</a> has anything to do with welfare of the people. As Albert Camus warned: “The welfare of the people in particular has always been the alibi of tyrants, and it provides the further advantage of giving the servants of tyranny a good conscience.”</p>
 	



</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
</article><!-- #post-1262 -->
	
<p><span>				
<hr>
<p><a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/face-mask-flyer/" rel="prev">previous</a> | 
<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/subscribe">subscribe</a> | 
<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/sanity-and-her-son/" rel="next">next</a></p>

<p colspan="3">
<img src="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/john-manley-outside-aug-2020-e1598311423971.jpeg" width="100" alt="John C. A. Manley">
	
	
	
	
	<strong>John C. A. Manley</strong>&nbsp;has spent over a  decade ghostwriting for medical doctors, as well as naturopaths, chiropractors  and Ayurvedic physicians. He publishes the&nbsp;<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/subscribe">COVID-19(84) Red Pill Posts</a>&nbsp;–  an email-based newsletter dedicated to preventing the governments of the world  from using an exaggerated pandemic as an excuse to violate our freedom, health,  privacy, livelihood and humanity. He is also writing a novel,&nbsp;<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/covid-27">COVID-27: A Dystopian Love Story</a>. You can visit his website at:&nbsp;<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/">MuchAdoAboutCorona.ca</a>
	
	
	
	</p></span>
			
			</p></div><!-- #content .site-content -->
		</div><!-- #primary .content-area -->


<!-- #masthead .site-header -->

	</div><!-- #main .site-main -->


	<!-- #colophon .site-footer -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/worst-miscalculation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24253636</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 17:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Finding vulnerable Twitter accounts with expired domains]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 183 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252524">thread link</a>) | @zainamro
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <p><a href="https://zainamro.com/hacks">← hacks</a></p>
    <h3>Finding vulnerable Twitter accounts with expired domains</h3>
    <p>August 23, 2020</p>
    <p>Recently, I discovered a simple yet suprisingly effective attack vector against Twitter accounts (and which likely applies to other platforms as well). This attack vector makes it easy to find and hack vulnerable accounts with login emails that are using expired domains. If a user creates a Twitter account with an email on their own domain, then forgets to renew their domain at some point, that account can be hijacked by registering the domain, forwarding all emails to your email, then submitting a password reset on that account. By itself, this is hardly an attack vector since finding such vulnerable accounts is the more important part, and we already know that owning someone's email is essentially a "game over" situation. This attack becomes more dangerous when you can combine it with an efficient method to find these vulnerable accounts quickly and at scale. As it turns out, this is trivial on Twitter for several reasons attributable to their platform design.</p>
    <p>If you're familiar with Twitter, you know that users are given the option to add a public website url. With a simple script and proxy, an attacker can quickly iterate over millions of accounts and check if the domain in that url is not registered; this usually indicates some likelihood that the Twitter account was created with an email address on a now-expired domain. To verify this, they can submit a password reset which will show them a censored version of the account email address for confirmation; however, even though it's censored, it still provides enough information to check if the email domain matches the expired domain listed on their account profile. If it does, the attacker now knows this is an account that can be hacked. Once this entire process is automated, it makes finding these accounts very easy. This method of account hijacking is very likely being used right now by malicious hackers, and I believe it accounts for a large portion of stolen accounts/handles on the platform.</p>
    <img src="https://zainamro.com/assets/img/twitter-emails.png">
    <p>This attack can potentially be executed on other platforms besides Twitter, assuming one can find a similar discovery method. In Twitter's case, they could make it harder to discover these accounts by not showing any email confirmation upon requesting a password reset. This would make the process more costly for attackers who would no longer be able to verify whether an account can be hacked prior to registering the domain. Or perhaps, Twitter should monitor and unlist domains that are no longer registered and notify users when this happens so that they're aware. As for most users, in addition to turning on 2FA, it's important to be very cautious when using an email on your own domain to create accounts; it makes it much easier to lose access if you forget to renew or can't under certain extreme circumstances like incarceration or death.</p>
    <p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252524">Comments</a></p>
    <!-- Global site tag (gtag.js) - Google Analytics -->
    
    
  

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24252524</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:25:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Writing a simple Python to C compiler: hello, fibonacci]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252233">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <p>In this post we'll write a Python to C compiler in Python. This is
especially easy to do since Python has a <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/ast.html">builtin parser
library</a> and because a
number of <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/">CPython internals are exposed for extension
writers</a>.</p>
<p>By the end of this post, in a few hundred lines of Python, we'll be able to
compile and run the following program:</p>
<pre><code>$ cat tests/recursive_fib.py
def fib(n):
    if n == 0 or n == 1:
        return n

    return fib(n - 1) + fib(n - 2)


def main():
    print(fib(40))
$ python3 pyc tests/recursive_fib.py
$ ./bin/a.out
102334155
</code></pre>
<p>This post implements an extremely small subset of Python and
<strong>completely gives up on even trying to manage memory</strong> because I
cannot fathom manual reference counting. Maybe some day I'll find a
way to swap in an easy GC like Boehm.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/eatonphil/pyc">Source code for this project is available on Github.</a></p>
<h3 id="dependencies">Dependencies</h3><p>We'll need Python3, GCC, libpython3, and clang-format.</p>
<p>On Fedora-based systems:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo dnf install gcc python3-devel clang-format python3
</code></pre>
<p>And on Debian-based systems:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo apt install gcc python3-dev clang-format python3
</code></pre>
<p>
  This program will likely work as well on Windows, Mac, FreeBSD,
  etc. but I haven't gone through the trouble of testing this (or
  providing custom compiler directives). Pull requests welcome!
</p><h3 id="a-hand-written-first-pass">A hand-written first-pass</h3><p>Before we get into the compiler, let's write the fibonacci program by
hand in C using libpython.</p>
<p>As described in the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/extending/embedding.html#very-high-level-embedding">Python embedding
guide</a>
we'll need to include libpython and initialize it in
our <code>main.c</code>:</p>
<pre><code>#define PY_SSIZE_T_CLEAN
#include &lt;Python.h&gt;

int main(int argc, char *argv[]) {
  Py_Initialize();

  return 0;
}
</code></pre>
<p>To compile against libpython, we'll use
<a href="https://helpmanual.io/man1/python3-config/">python3-config</a> installed
as part of <code>python3-devel</code> to tell us what should be linked
at each step during compilation.</p>
<pre><code>$ gcc -c -o main.o $(python3-config --cflags) main.c
$ gcc $(python3-config --ldflags) main.o
$ ./a.out; echo $?
0
</code></pre>
<p>Cool! Now as we think about translating the fibonacci implementation,
we want to keep everything as Python objects for as long as
possible. This means passing and receiving
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/object.html">PyObject*</a> to and from
all functions, and converting all C integers to
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html">PyLong*</a>, a "subtype" of
<code>PyObject*</code>. You can imagine that everything in Python is
an <code>object</code> until you operate on it.</p>
<p>
  For more information on objects in Python, check out
  the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/reference/datamodel.html">Data
  model</a> page in Python docs.
</p><p>To map a C integer to a <code>PyLong*</code> we use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html#c.PyLong_FromLong">PyLong_FromLong</a>. To
map in reverse, we use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html#c.PyLong_AsLong">PyLong_AsLong</a>.</p>
<p>To compare two <code>PyObject*</code>s we can use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/object.html#c.PyObject_RichCompareBool">PyObject_RichCompareBool</a>
which will handle the comparison regardless of the type of the two
parameters. Without this helper we'd have to write complex checks to
make sure that the two sides are the same and if they are, unwrap them
into their underlying C value and compare the C value.</p>
<p>We can use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/number.html#c.PyNumber_Add">PyNumber_Add</a>
and
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/number.html#c.PyNumber_Subtract">PyNumber_Subtract</a>
for basic arithmetic, and there are many similar helpers available to
us for operations down the line.</p>
<p>Now we can write a translation:</p>
<pre><code>#define PY_SSIZE_T_CLEAN
#include &lt;Python.h&gt;

PyObject* fib(PyObject* n) {
  PyObject* zero = PyLong_FromLong(0);
  PyObject* one = PyLong_FromLong(1);
  if (PyObject_RichCompareBool(n, zero, Py_EQ) || PyObject_RichCompareBool(n, one, Py_EQ)) {
    return n;
  }

  PyObject* left = fib(PyNumber_Subtract(n, one));

  PyObject* two = PyLong_FromLong(2);
  PyObject* right = fib(PyNumber_Subtract(n, two));

  return PyNumber_Add(left, right);
}

int main(int argc, char *argv[]) {
  Py_Initialize();

  PyObject* res = fib(PyLong_FromLong(7)); // Should be 13

  return PyLong_AsLong(res);
}
</code></pre>
<p>Compile and run it:</p>
<pre><code>$ gcc -c -o main.o $(python3-config --cflags) main.c
$ gcc $(python3-config --ldflags) main.o
$ ./a.out; echo $?
13
</code></pre>
<p>That's great! But we cheated in one place. We assumed that the input
to the <code>fib</code> function was an integer, and we propagated
that assumption everywhere we wrote <code>PyNumber_*</code>
operations. When we write the compiler, we'll need to check that both
arguments are an integer before we call a numeric helper, otherwise we
may need to call a string concatenation helper or something else
entirely.</p>
<h3 id="compiler-architecture">Compiler Architecture</h3><p>We'll break the code into four major parts:</p>
<ol>
<li><code>libpyc.c</code>: helper functions for generated code</li>
<li><code>pyc/context.py</code>: utilities for scope and writing code in memory</li>
<li><code>pyc/codegen.py</code>: for generating C code from a Python AST</li>
<li><code>pyc/__main__.py</code>: the entrypoint</li>
</ol>
<p>
  When I'm writing a new compiler using an existing parser I almost
  always start with the entrypoint and code generator so I can explore
  the AST. However, it's easiest to explain the code if we start with
  the utilities first.
</p><p>We'll also want an empty <code>pyc/__init__.py</code>.</p>
<h3 id="libpyc.c">libpyc.c</h3><p>This C file will contain three helper functions for safely adding,
subtracting, and printing. It will be concatenated to the top of the
generated C file. We'll only support integers for now but this
structure sets us up for supporting more types later on.</p>
<p>We'll use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html#c.PyLong_Check">PyLong_Check</a>
before calling number-specific methods.</p>
<pre><code>#define PY_SSIZE_T_CLEAN
#include &lt;Python.h&gt;

inline PyObject* PYC_Add(PyObject* l, PyObject* r) {
  // TODO: allow __add__ override

  // Includes ints and bools
  if (PyLong_Check(l) &amp;&amp; PyLong_Check(r)) {
    return PyNumber_Add(l, r);
  }

  // TODO: handle str, etc.

  // TODO: throw exception
  return NULL;
}

inline PyObject* PYC_Sub(PyObject* l, PyObject* r) {
  // TODO: allow __add__ override

  // Includes ints and bools
  if (PyLong_Check(l) &amp;&amp; PyLong_Check(r)) {
    return PyNumber_Subtract(l, r);
  }

  // TODO: handle str, etc.

  // TODO: throw exception
  return NULL;
}

inline PyObject* PYC_Print(PyObject* o) {
  PyObject_Print(o, stdout, Py_PRINT_RAW);
  printf("\n");
  return Py_None;
}
</code></pre>
<p>That's it! We could generate these as strings in Python but it gets
hairy to do so. By using a dedicated C file, we can take advantage of
syntax highlighting since this file is only C code. And since we've
marked all functions as <code>inline</code>, there's no runtime cost
to using not embedding these as strings in Python.</p>
<h3 id="pyc/context.py">pyc/context.py</h3><p>This file will contain a <code>Context</code> class for managing
identifiers in scope and for proxying to a <code>Writer</code> class
that contains helpers for writing lines of C code.</p>
<p>We'll have two instances of the <code>Writer</code> class in
<code>Context</code> so that we can write to a body (or
current/primary) region and an initialization region.</p>
<p>The initialization region is necessary in case there are any variables
declared at the top-level. We can't initialize these variables in C
outside of a function since every <code>PyObject*</code> must be
created after calling <code>Py_Initialize</code>. This section will be
written into our C <code>main</code> function before we enter a
compiled Python <code>main</code> function.</p>
<pre><code>import copy


class Writer():
    content = ""

    def write(self, exp: str, indent: int = 0):
        self.content += ("  " * indent) + exp

    def writeln(self, stmt: str, indent: int = 0):
        self.write(stmt + "\n", indent)

    def write_statement(self, stmt: str, indent: int = 0):
        self.writeln(stmt + ";", indent)


class Context():
    initializations = Writer()
    body = Writer()
    indentation = 0

    scope = 0
    ret = None
    namings = {}
    counter = -1

    def __getattr__(self, name: str) -&gt; object:
        # Helpers to avoid passing in self.indentation every time
        outputs = [initializations", "body"]
        for output in outputs:
            if name.startswith(output):
                return lambda s, i=None: getattr(getattr(self, output), name[len(output)+1:])(s, i if i is not None else self.indentation)

        return object.__getattr__(self, name)

    def get_local(self, source_name: str) -&gt; dict:
        return self.namings[source_name]

    def register_global(self, name: str, loc: str):
        self.namings[name] = {
            "name": loc,
            "scope": 0,
        }

    def register_local(self, local: str = "tmp") -&gt; str:
        self.counter += 1
        self.namings[local] = {
            "name": f"{local}_{self.counter}",
            # naming dictionary is copied, so we need to capture scope
            # at declaration
            "scope": self.scope,
        }
        return self.namings[local]["name"]

    def copy(self):
        new = copy.copy(self)
        # For some reason copy.deepcopy doesn't do this
        new.namings = dict(new.namings)
        return new

    def at_toplevel(self):
        return self.scope == 0
</code></pre>
<p>This is all pretty boring boilerplate. Let's move on.</p>
<h3 id="pyc/<strong>main</strong>.py">pyc/<strong>main</strong>.py</h3><p>The entrypoint is responsible for reading source code, parsing it,
calling the code generator, writing the source code to a C file, and
compiling it.</p>
<p>First, we read and parse the source code:</p>
<pre><code>import ast
import os
import subprocess
import shutil
import sys

from context import Context
from codegen import generate

BUILTINS = {
    "print": "PYC_Print",
}


def main():
    target = sys.argv[1]
    with open(target) as f:
        source = f.read()
    tree = ast.parse(source, target)
</code></pre>
<p>Then we write <code>libpyc.c</code> into the body, register builtins,
and run code generation:</p>
<pre><code>
...

def main()
    ...

    ctx = Context()
    with open("libpyc.c") as f:
        ctx.body_write(f.read() + "\n")

    for builtin, fn in BUILTINS.items():
        ctx.register_global(builtin, fn)

    generate(ctx, tree)
</code></pre>
<p>Next, we create a clean output directory and write
<code>main.c</code> with the generated code and a <code>main</code>
function to initialization Python and any global variables:</p>
<pre><code>...

def main():
   ...

    # Create and move to working directory
    outdir = "bin"
    shutil.rmtree(outdir, ignore_errors=True)
    os.mkdir(outdir)
    os.chdir(outdir)

    with open("main.c", "w") as f:
        f.write(ctx.body.content)

        main = ctx.namings.get("main")["name"]
        f.write(f"""int main(int argc, char *argv[]) {{
  Py_Initialize();

  // Initialize globals, if any.
{ctx.initializations.content}
  PyObject* r = {main}();
  return PyLong_AsLong(r);
}}""")
</code></pre>
<p>Finally, we run <code>clang-format</code> and <code>gcc</code> against
the generated C code:</p>
<pre><code>...

def main():
    ...

    subprocess.run(["clang-format", "-i", "main.c"])

    cflags_raw = …</code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html">https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24252233</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 14:35:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Microsoft .NET SDK is violating the GDPR, object now]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251579">thread link</a>) | @dgl
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-sdk-gdpr | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-sdk-gdpr">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p><b>Skip to the end if you just want a template for a "Right to object"
letter.</b></p>

<p>The .NET Core software development kit (SDK) is a set of command line tools
that allow development against Microsoft's .NET. When the command line tool is
run it sends some telemetry back to Microsoft.</p>

<p>This telemetry is <a href="https://aka.ms/dotnet-cli-telemetry">documented</a>, however the way it is implemented appears
against the <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/">GDPR</a> in multiple ways.</p>

<h3>Collection by default</h3>

<p>Running <code>dotnet help</code> on a clean install, will print a message about telemetry,
but will send the details on that run.</p>

<p><a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-help.png"><img src="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-help.png"></a></p>

<p>Therefore the GDPR requriements under <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/recitals/no-42/">"Burden of proof and requirements for
consent"</a> cannot be met -- even if we
give Microsoft the benefit of doubt and consider a command line application
somewhat special, it does not give us a chance to opt-out, yet alone opt-in.</p>

<p><a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-installer.png"><img src="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-installer.png"></a></p>

<p>During the installation process, there is a link to Microsoft's <a href="https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/privacystatement">Privacy
statement</a>, however this
does not mention the environment variable needed to opt-out, so there is no way
to opt out before the first piece of data is sent.</p>

<h3>Collecting personal data</h3>

<p>The linked information page, as well as the text printed  in the CLI both say "The data is
anonymous.", it clearly isn't. They collect MAC addresses and the current
working directory, which are sent to their servers hashed.</p>

<p>A key thing to understand: <b>Hashing without a salt does not make the data
anonymous or even pseudonymous.</b></p>

<p>See for example <a href="https://medium.com/@alexewerlof/gdpr-pseudonymization-techniques-62f7b3b46a56">GDPR pseudonymisation
techniques</a>.
Given this, it is a clear violation as <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-6-gdpr/">Article
6</a> requires specific purposes for processing,
but the data was claimed to be anonymous, which it isn't.</p>

<p>A common place to run "dotnet help" might be a home directory, which can often
include a username, e.g. <code>/home/dgl</code>. So while it's hashed it is easily
possible to find the hash that relates to a particular user:</p>

<pre><code>$ pwd
/home/dgl
$ echo -n $PWD | sha256sum
67acfe0ddd44867e1e5da5ddaf25a5b90e928f523cecf614e201c683b7533cf6  -
</code>
</pre>

<p>This matches the relevant part of the JSON sent:</p>

<pre><code>  "Current Path Hash": "67acfe0ddd44867e1e5da5ddaf25a5b90e928f523cecf614e201c683b7533cf6",
</code></pre>

<p>There are some discussions about the collection of MAC addresses in
<a href="https://github.com/dotnet/sdk/issues/6145">issue #6145</a> but no
particular reply from Microsoft; people suspect it's a GDPR violation. Note
that under the GDPR there are time limits for replying, so that's another
potential GDPR issue.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/ms-report.txt">report</a> I sent to Microsoft detailed how a
MAC address is likely not even 48-bits of search space, as we know what ones
are assigned, so brute-forcing is quite possible, particularly when combined
with the fact the search space can be reduced by filtering on the path
hash.</p>

<p>One principle of the GDPR is you need to explain why you're collecting
information, Microsoft do in a round about way, rather than on the link
printed by the command (<a href="https://aka.ms/dotnet-cli-telemetry">https://aka.ms/dotnet-cli-telemetry</a>) which explains what they are collecting, the "why" is hidden on a <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/what-weve-learned-from-net-core-sdk-telemetry/">blog post</a>.</p><p>

It says:
</p><blockquote>
Hashed MAC address â€” Determine a cryptographically (SHA256) anonymous and unique ID for a machine. Useful to determine the aggregate number of machines that use .NET Core. This data will not be shared in the public data releases.
<p>

Hashed current working directory â€” Determine build machines from dev machines using the heuristic of a large number of working directories. This distinction helps explain large #s of builds from a machine.
</p></blockquote>


<p>This shows a clear intention to join the data, for some purposes. The "Hashed
MAC address" is obviously understood to be somewhat sensitive as it mentions
they won't share it. Interestingly the same is not said for the current working
directory, which is also sensitive.</p>

<h3>Privacy policy</h3>

<p>As mentioned Microsoft has a <a href="https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/privacystatement">general privacy policy</a>.</p>

<p>This could allow some collection, however:</p>

<blockquote>
You have choices when it comes to the technology you use and the data you
share. When we ask you to provide personal data, you can decline.
</blockquote>

<p>This behaviour would be GDPR compliant, but the key point is due to the first
collection behaviour of e.g. running <code>dotnet help</code> there is no chance to
decline. So the behaviour of the dotnet tool is inconsistent with their own
privacy policy.</p>

<h3>How to respond?</h3>

<p>I sent a report to Microsoft's security team, because arguably incorrect use of
a cryptographic hashing function (SHA256 of the items, without a salt) is a
"Security Design Flaw" which qualifies under the <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/bounty-dot-net-core">dotnet 
bug bounty</a>. This was
obviously fishing a bit, and Microsoft denied me. More surpsingly they don't
seem to consider this a problem at all, their final reply was:</p>

<blockquote>
We have updates scheduled for the first run experience and related documentation to make it more accurate. Personal data is handled consistently with GDPR requirements.
</blockquote>

<p>You'll notice that they don't talk about any actual collection changes. Also
interestingly if the data is anonymous as they claim, what "Personal data" are
they referring to in this reply?</p>

<h4>What's the route the GDPR gives us here?</h4>

<p>This is an interesting one, partly <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-11-gdpr/">Article 11 Processing which does not
  require identification</a> could apply, in that they can exclude themselves
from right of access, etc. With the exception of "Right to object".</p>

<p>There are two routes, either we give enough information for Microsoft to be
happy we identify ourselves (and use the right to erasure), or we use the right
to object, which while it doesn't require Microsoft to delete the data
entirely does require them to limit their use of it.</p>

<p>So I can object to any processing of my data, and as I've proved we can use
the MAC address to find my machine in their data. I believe given this has gone
on for several years that even if they make the data collection GDPR compliant,
there is a huge historical collection of data that may need clearing as it has
been collected unlawfully.</p>

<p>In my original <a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/ms-report.txt">report</a> to Microsoft I made some recommendations:</p>

<pre><code>
Recommendations:
<ul><li>Remove the telemetry, it avoids any potential GDPR issues;</li>
<li>Delete the historical data (I am not a lawyer, but I suspect this has GDPR
implications);
</li></ul></code></pre>

<p>It appears they do not intend to follow these so I suggest that any user of
.NET Core SDK in the European Union takes matters into their own hands and use
their right to object:</p>

<div>
<p>
[Your full address]
[The date]</p>

<p>To Data Controller, Microsoft Corporation</p>

<p>I am exercising my right to object under the General Data Protection
Regulation (Article 21).</p>

<p>It has come to my attention that Microsoft .NET Core SDK collects telemetry,
and the opt-out process for this data is flawed.</p>

<p>In particular setting the <code>DOTNET_CLI_TELEMETRY_OPTOUT</code> variable
is only suggested the first time the tool is run, so some data may have been
collected against my will.</p>

<p>In light of Microsoft not deleting this telemetry data for everyone (per the
report of David Leadbeater on 3 August 2020). I wish that my telemetry data is
restricted from further processing, as I have set the opt-out environment
variable, but I cannot be sure that some data has not reached Microsoft
already.</p>

<p>The MAC addresses of my machine(s) is/are:</p>

<p>XX:XX:XX:XX:XX:XX</p>

<p>I believe this is enough to identify my records, as they are stored as a
SHA256 hash of this MAC address.</p>

<p>Please send a full response within one calendar month confirming if you will
comply with my request. If you cannot respond within that timescale, please
tell me when you will be able to respond.</p>

<p>If there is anything you would like to discuss, please contact me.</p>

<p>Thank you,
</p></div>

<p>Obviously the somewhat strange thing about this is you reveal your MAC
address to Microsoft in the process, but I'm fairly sure the data protection
around GDPR requests is something that is well scrutinized.</p>

<p>If you do want to send this to Microsoft go to
<a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-GB/concern/privacy">https://www.microsoft.com/en-GB/concern/privacy</a> and select "I want to contact
Microsoftâ€™s Data Protection Officer".</p>

<p>It's strange this is still an issue as this was previously discussed over
two years ago (see this <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17177241">Hacker News
thread</a>). Let's use our right to object!</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-sdk-gdpr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24251579</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:57:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Persisting as a solo founder]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 622 | Comments 232 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251403">thread link</a>) | @vishnumohandas
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><img src="https://sa.vishnu.tech/noscript.gif" alt="">




    



  



    
    <p><time itemprop="datePublished">August 19, 2020</time>
    </p>
    

<p>I quit my job in January 2020 to build a privacy friendly photo organizer.</p>

<p>As a 30 year old whose friends are either getting married or planning
off-springs, what I had underestimated was the difficulty involved in finding a co-founder and how that would compound the difficulty involved in
finding an investor.</p>

<p>Once I accepted the loneliness and the lack of a financial cushion I had to figure out a way to keep building without burning myself out.</p>

<p>It took me a while, but I have found a rhythm that works, and with it, a steady
source of endorphins. Here are some changes that helped me to keep things
moving.</p>

<h2 id="being-patient">Being patient</h2>

<p>Life is no longer as comfortable as it used to be and things are not always
going the way I want them to. Preseverance has been key and indirectly patience
too. Naval’s <a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/1261481752448524289" target="_blank">take on
meditation</a> (60 minutes x
60 days), was an eye opener. I’ve stuck with it since, and I now have an easier
time identifying negative thought patterns and sitting out situations that would
otherwise overwhelm me.</p>

<p>On some level, spending the last few months locked indoors with my parents, who
are not the most rational people in the world has also helped. But I wouldn’t
recommend it.</p>

<h2 id="reducing-procrastination">Reducing procrastination</h2>

<p>Over time I’ve realized that action precedes motivation and procrastination precedes guilt.</p>

<p>Breaking down tasks into chunks that seem trivial to accomplish has helped reduce the friction in getting started on unexciting grunt work.</p>

<p>Then there are tasks which I loathe from my core, like writing out applications
to VCs explaining why what I’m doing will matter. To those I attach reinforcing
personal reasons, like, “I need the $50k to hire that college junior who I love
working with, and that will give me spare bandwidth to focus on traction channels”.</p>

<h2 id="thinking-clearer">Thinking clearer</h2>

<p>It is sub-optimal to not have a coworker to bounce ideas off and rant about problems to. A lot of times it’s these conversations that help you gain clarity.</p>

<p>It’s a luxury I do not have so every time I feel stuck, I type/scribble my thoughts out, and then question everything that was written, and then document my realizations.</p>

<p>Task tracking has also helped in clearing the path. I write down unstructured
thoughts into a diary, and once I’ve clarity, I promote them to a Notion board
(that’s divided into <em>Thinking</em>, <em>Building</em>, <em>Reading</em>, <em>Writing</em> and
<em>Adulting</em>) and every Monday within an Excel sheet I track what was done, and
what is left to be done.</p>

<h2 id="reducing-distractions">Reducing distractions</h2>

<p>I’ve reduced my information consumption to free up brain cycles. I’ve disabled all notifications on my phone barring a few contacts, and I’ve more or less stopped browsing on it. As an added bonus, this has reduced the negativity with which I perceived the world.</p>

<p>To minimize the overhead of context switches, I split tasks into a tree of checkpoints. Before taking a break I note down the next simplest checkpoint so that when I get back to work there’s little friction to resume.</p>

<p>To help me zone out I keep <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5qap5aO4i9A" target="_blank">lofi
beats</a> or
<a href="http://github.audio/" target="_blank">github.audio</a> playing in the background. Listening to the
latter gives me a strange sense of motivation and makes me feel less alone.</p>

<h2 id="staying-grounded">Staying grounded</h2>

<p>I’m lucky to have some friends who call/text every other week. I look at them as my accountability partners and I talk to them about what I’m doing on a high level. While not all of them genuinely care, some do, and these conversations force me to reflect on how well I’m doing what I’m doing.</p>

<p>While Silicon Valley wisdom suggests that if I’m not sleeping I should be
working, failing because of a burn out would be stupid. An advantage of not
having a VC onboard so far has been the freedom to dictate my pace. So I spend
days thinking, reading, fiddling with my violin or just doing nothing when I
feel like writing code is not what I want to do.</p>

<hr>

<p>It’s been 7 months of building alone, and while this is not how I pictured things to be on my last day at work, this is the happiest I have ever been. There’s a long way to go, and the grind seems inviting.</p>

<p>This list is by no means exhaustive, for I’m still learning. If you’ve
anything to share, please join <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251403" target="_blank">the discussion on HackerNews</a>.</p>

<hr>

<p>If you are curious about what I’ve been building, check out
<a href="https://ente.io/" target="_blank">ente.io</a>.</p>

    <br>
    


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24251403</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:27:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[2020: An Isolation Odyssey]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24250068">thread link</a>) | @unhammer
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | http://lydiacambron.com/index.php/project/2020-an-isolation-odyssey/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://lydiacambron.com/index.php/project/2020-an-isolation-odyssey/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>2020: an isolation odyssey</em> is a reenactment of the iconic finale of <em>2001: A Space Odyssey</em> (Stanley Kubrick, 1968). Restaged in the context of home quarantine, the journey through time adapts to the mundane dramas of self-isolation–poking fun at the navel-gazing saga of life alone and indoors.</p>

<p>This project began in late March and was completed in late May, spanning the height of the pandemic in New York City. Staged in a one bedroom Brooklyn apartment, <em>2020</em> presents an obvious similarity to the domestic setting of <em>2001</em>. The stacked videos and synced movements also reveal parallels in emotion. The narrowness of daily life in a single space, transitioning from confusion to acceptance, a distorted sense of time, and ‘returning’ after a transformational event–all experiences analogous to quarantine. </p>

<p>The adapted version delineates the passing of time through wardrobe rather than age, identifying each phase of the character’s journey with a product of self care or PPE. Tools of private entertainment or self betterment are also used as props, questioning our confidence in products and productivity as anchors during times of uncertainty. Multitasking while #wfh, conjuring guilt or longing with unused exercise equipment, your entire being reduced to a measure of time–these scenes all illustrate the absurd comedy of trying to maintain control during this unprecedented and unpredictable time.<br>
</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://lydiacambron.com/index.php/project/2020-an-isolation-odyssey/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24250068</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 06:37:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Problem-Solving Techniques That Work for All Types of Challenges (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24249449">thread link</a>) | @wyclif
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A lot of people don’t realize that there are general purpose problem solving techniques that cut across domains. They can help you deal with thorny challenges in work, your personal life, startups, or even if you’re trying to prove a new theorem in math.</p>



<p>Below are the 26 general purpose problem solving techniques that I like best, along with a one-word name I picked for each, and hypothetical examples to illustrate what sort of strategy I’m referring to.</p>



<p>Consider opening up this list whenever you’re stuck solving a challenging problem. It’s likely that one or more of these techniques can help!</p>



<h4>General Purpose Techniques for Solving Challenging Problems of All Kinds</h4>



<p>1. <strong>Clarifying</strong> – try to define the problem you are facing as precisely as you can, maybe by writing down a detailed description of exactly what the problem is and what constraints exist for a solution, or by describing it in detail to another person, which may lead to you realizing the problem is not quite what you had thought, or that it has a more obvious solution than you thought.</p>



<p>Life Example: <em>“I thought that I needed to find a new job, but when I thought really carefully about what I don’t like about my current job, I realized that I could likely fix those things by talking to my boss or even, potentially, just by thinking about them differently.”</em></p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“we thought we had a problem with users not wanting to sign up for the product, but when we carefully investigated what the problem really was, we discovered it was actually more of a problem of users wanting the product but then growing frustrated because of bad interface design.”</em></p>



<p>2. <strong>Subdividing</strong> – break the problem down into smaller problems in such a way that if you solve each of the small problems, you will have solved the entire problem.</p>



<p>Startup Example:<em> “My goal is to get company Z to become a partner with my company, and that seems hard, so let me break that goal into the steps of (a) listing the ways that company Z would benefit from becoming a partner with us, (b) finding an employee at company Z who would be responsive to hearing about these benefits, and (c) tracking down someone who can introduce me to that employee.”</em></p>



<p>Math Example:<em> “I want to prove that a certain property applies to all functions of a specific type, so I start by (a) showing that every function of that type can be written as a sum of a more specific type of function, then I show that (b) the property applies to each function of the more specific type, and finally I show that (c) if the property applies to each function in a set of functions then it applies to arbitrary sums of those functions as well.”</em></p>



<p>3. <strong>Simplifying </strong>– think of the simplest variation of the problem that you expect you can solve that shares important features in common with your problem, and see if solving this simpler problem gives you ideas for how to solve the more difficult version.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I don’t know how to hire a CTO, but I do know how to hire a software engineer because I’ve done it many times, and good CTOs will often themselves be good software engineers, so how can I tweak my software engineer hiring to make it appropriate for hiring a CTO?”</em></p>



<p>Math Example: <em>“I don’t know how to calculate this integral as it is, but if I remove one of the free parameters, I actually do know how to calculate it, and maybe doing that calculation will give me insight into the solution of the more complex integral.”</em></p>



<p>4. <strong>Crowd-sourcing</strong> – use suggestions from multiple people to gain insight into how to solve the problem, for instance by posting on Facebook or Twitter requesting people’s help, or by posting to a Q&amp;A site like Quora, or by sending emails to 10 people you know explaining the problem and requesting assistance.</p>



<p>Business Example: <em>“Do you have experience outsourcing manufacturing to China? If so, I’d appreciate hearing your thoughts about how to approach choosing a vendor.”</em></p>



<p>Health Example: <em>“I have trouble getting myself to stick to doing exercise daily. If you also used to have trouble getting yourself to exercise but don’t anymore, I’d love to know what worked to make it easier for you.”</em></p>



<p>5. <strong>Splintering</strong> – if the problem you are trying to solve has special cases that a solution to the general problem would also apply to, consider just one or two of these special cases as examples and solve the problem just for those cases first. Then see if a solution to one of those special cases helps you solve the problem in general.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I want to figure out how to improve employee retention in general, let me examine how I could have improved retention in the case of the last three people that quit.”</em></p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I want to figure out how to convince a large number of people to become customers, let me first figure out how to convince just Bill and John to become customers since they seem like the sort of customer I want to attract, and see what general lessons I learn from doing that.”</em></p>



<p>6. <strong>Reading</strong> – read the books or textbooks that seems most related to the topic, and see whether they provide a solution to the problem, or teach you enough related information that you can now solve it yourself. </p>



<p>Economics Example: <em>“Economists probably have already figured out reasonable ways to estimate demand elasticity, let’s see what an econometrics textbook says rather than trying to invent a technique from scratch.”</em></p>



<p>Mental Health Example: <em>“I’ve been feeling depressed for a long time, maybe I should read some well-liked books about depression, such as ‘Feeling Good.'”</em></p>



<p>7. <strong>Searching </strong>– think of a similar problem that you think practitioners, bloggers or academics might have already solved and search online (e.g., via google, Q&amp;A sites, or google scholar academic paper search) to see if anyone has done a write-up about how they solved it.</p>



<p>Advertising Example: <em>“I’m having trouble figuring out the right advertising keywords to bid on for my specific product, I bet someone has a blog post describing how to approach choosing keywords for other related products.”</em></p>



<p>Machine Learning Example:<em> “I can’t get this neural network to train properly in my specific case, I wonder if someone has written a tutorial about how to apply neural networks to related problems.”</em></p>



<p>8. <strong>Unconstraining</strong> – list all the constraints of the problem, then temporarily ignore one or more of the constraints that make the problem especially hard, and try to solve it without those constraints. If you can, then see if you can modify that unconstrained solution until it becomes a solution for the fully constrained problem.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I need to hire someone who can do work at the intersection of machine learning and cryptography, let me drop the constraint of having cryptography experience and recruit machine learning people, then pick from among them a person that seems both generally capable and well positioned to learn the necessary cryptography.”</em></p>



<p>Computer Science Example: <em>“I need to implement a certain algorithm, and it needs to be efficient, but that seems very difficult, so let me first figure out how to implement an inefficient version of the algorithm (i.e., drop the efficiency constraint), then at the end I will try to figure out how to optimize that algorithm for efficiency.”</em></p>



<p>9. <strong>Distracting</strong> – fill your mind with everything you know about the problem, including facts, constraints, challenges, considerations, etc. and then stop thinking about the problem, and go and do a relaxing activity that requires little focus, such as walking, swimming, cooking, napping or taking a bath to see if new ideas or potential solutions pop into your mind unexpectedly as your subconscious continues to work on the problem without your attention.</p>



<p>Example: <em>“For three days, I’ve been trying to solve this problem at work, but the solution only came to me when I was strolling in the woods and not even thinking about it.”</em></p>



<p>Example from mathematician Henri Poincaré: <em>“The incidents of the travel made me forget my mathematical work. Having reached Coutances, we entered an omnibus to go someplace or other. At the moment when I put my foot on the step, the idea came to me, without anything in my former thoughts seeming to have paved the way for it, that the transformations I had used to define the Fuchsian functions were identical with those of non-Euclidean geometry.”</em></p>



<p>10. <strong>Reexamining</strong> – write down all the assumptions you’ve been making about the problem or about what a solution should look like (yes – make an actual list). Then start challenging them one by one to see if they are actually needed or whether some may be unnecessary or mistaken.</p>



<p>Psychology Example: <em>“We were assuming in our lab experiments that when people get angry they have some underlying reason behind it, but there may be some anger that is better modeled as a chemical fluctuation that is only loosely related to what happens in the lab, such as when people are quick to anger because they are hungry.”</em></p>



<p>Math Example: <em>“I need to construct a function that has this strange property, and so far I’ve assumed that the function must be smooth, but if it doesn’t actually need to be then perhaps I can construct just such a function out of simple linear pieces that are glued together.”</em></p>



<p>11.<strong> Reframing</strong> – try to see the problem differently. For instance, by flipping the default, analyzing the inverse of the problem instead, thinking about how you would achieve the opposite of what you want, or shifting to an opposing perspective.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“If we were building this company over again completely from scratch, what would we do differently in the design of our product, and can we pivot the product in that direction right now?”</em></p>



<p>Life Example: <em>“Should move to New York to take a job that pays $20,000 more per year? Well, if I already lived in New York, the decision to stay there rather than taking a $20,000 pay cut to move here would be an easy one. …</em></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/">https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24249449</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 04:10:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to update U-Boot for PostmarketOS on the Pine Phone]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 73 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24244407">thread link</a>) | @dustfinger
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://bloggerbust.ca/post/how-to-update-uboot-for-postmarketos-on-the-pinephone/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bloggerbust.ca/post/how-to-update-uboot-for-postmarketos-on-the-pinephone/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> 


<!--endtoc-->

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>If you are in a hurry to update U-Boot and the SPL on your PinePhone, then please proceed directly to <a href="#write-u-boot-plus-spl-to-bootable-storage">Write U-Boot+SPL to bootable storage</a>.</p>

<p>In this article, I am going to explain what U-Boot, SoC and the SPL are. After that, I will describe the sunxi bootable storage layout as well as the PinePhone boot procedure, so you will understand what you will be updating and why. Then, I will teach you how to determine if an upgrade is required, and I will explain two different ways of upgrading U-Boot. As a special treat for the curious, I will show you the first steps to reverse engineer the U-Boot+SPL firmware blob. I hope this article peeks your curiosity and encourages you to learn more.</p>

<p>Discussed on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24244407">Hacker News</a> and <a href="https://forum.pine64.org/showthread.php?tid=11099">Pine64</a>.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-u-boot">What is U-Boot?</h2>

<p>U-Boot, or rather <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Das%5FU-Boot">Das U-Boot</a> a.k.a <em>the Universal Boot Loader</em>, is a small program that is loaded into <em>read-only memory</em> (ROM) and is ultimately responsible for loading the Linux kernel. Designed with flexibility in mind, U-Boot now supports <a href="https://gitlab.denx.de/u-boot/u-boot/-/tree/master/arch">a wide variety of architectures</a> for <a href="https://gitlab.denx.de/u-boot/u-boot/-/tree/master/board">embedded boards</a>, each of which may support multiple boot methods. This article is only concerned with U-Boot as it is configured for the <a href="https://gitlab.denx.de/u-boot/u-boot/-/blob/master/board/sunxi/README.sunxi64">Allwinner 64-bit boards</a>, specifically the <a href="https://linux-sunxi.org/A64">Allwinner A64 SoC</a>.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-a-soc">What is a SoC?</h2>

<p>No, it does not refer to the stinky fabric covering your feet. <em>SoC</em> stands for <em>System on a Chip</em>. The PinePhone contains the <a href="https://linux-sunxi.org/A64">Allwinner A64 SoC</a>, featuring a Quad-Core <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARM%5FCortex-A53">ARM Cortex-A53 ARMv8-A CPU</a> and an <a href="https://linux-sunxi.org/Mali400">ARM Mali400 MP2 GPU</a>. See the <a href="https://linux-sunxi.org/A64#Documentation">Allwinner A64 documentation</a> for more details.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-the-spl">What is the SPL?</h2>

<p>The <em>Secondary Program Loader’s</em> (SPL) primary function is to load U-Boot proper, the <em>flattened device tree</em> (<a href="https://devicetree-specification.readthedocs.io/en/latest/flattened-format.html">FDT</a>) and the <em>Arm Trusted Firmware</em> (<a href="https://www.trustedfirmware.org/about/">ATF</a>), ultimately passing execution to the ATF. In particular, execution is passed to <em>Trusted Firmware-A</em> (<a href="https://trustedfirmware-a.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html">TF-A</a>), which is <a href="https://github.com/ARM-software/arm-trusted-firmware">the official reference implementation</a> used by SoCs with armv8- cores, such as <a href="https://trustedfirmware-a.readthedocs.io/en/latest/plat/allwinner.html">Allwinner Armv8-A SoCs</a>.</p>

<h2 id="what-installs-the-spl">What installs the SPL?</h2>

<p>The SPL is installed via the <code>u-boot-pinephone</code> package from the <a href="http://postmarketos1.brixit.nl/postmarketos/master/aarch64/">postmarketOS aarch64 APK repository</a>. The package is built from the <a href="https://gitlab.com/pine64-org/u-boot/">pine64 u-boot fork</a> in which they added a <a href="https://gitlab.com/pine64-org/u-boot/-/blob/master/.gitlab-ci-pine64.yml">pine64 specific GitLab CI/CD pipeline configuration</a>. By listing the contents of the package using the <a href="https://wiki.alpinelinux.org/wiki/Alpine%5FLinux%5Fpackage%5Fmanagement#apk%5Finfo">apk info</a> command we can see where the SPL binary is actually installed to the root file system.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">second-chance:~$ apk info -L u-boot-pinephone</code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="text">u-boot-pinephone-2020.04_git20200421-r1 contains:
usr/share/u-boot/pine64-pinephone/u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code></pre></div>
<p>However, this is just a convenient location to deliver the binary. The SPL must be deployed to a specific location on disk so that the BootROM can load it.</p>

<h2 id="a-bit-about-bytes">A bit about bytes</h2>

<p>I suspect that not all of those reading this article are familiar with the various standards when it comes to measuring information. Allow me to digress with a brief introduction to these standards with respect to how they both measure and represent a <em>kilobyte</em>. Many of the articles that I have linked herein use the <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JEDEC%5Fmemory%5Fstandards#Unit%5Fprefixes%5Ffor%5Fsemiconductor%5Fstorage%5Fcapacity">Joint Electron Device Engineering Council</a></em> (JEDEC) memory standards in which the unit for <em>kilobyte</em> is denoted by (<code>KB</code>), in upper case letters and represents <code>1024B</code>. This is not to be confused with the kilobyte from the <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metric%5Fprefix/">International System of Quantities</a></em> (SI) in which <em>kilo</em> is denoted with a lower case <code>k</code>, such that <code>kB</code> means <code>1000B</code>. My preference is to use the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kibibyte">kibibyte</a> (pron. KI-BEE-BYTE), which was established by the <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International%5FElectrotechnical%5FCommission">International Electrotechnical commission</a></em> (IEC) and is recognized by all major standards organizations, including those aforementioned.</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Decimal</th>
<th></th>
<th>Binary</th>
<th></th>
<th></th>
</tr>
</thead>

<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Value</td>
<td>Metric</td>
<td>Value</td>
<td>IEC</td>
<td>JEDEC</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>B byte</td>
<td>1</td>
<td>B byte</td>
<td>B byte</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>1000</td>
<td>kB kilobyte</td>
<td>1024</td>
<td>KiB kibibyte</td>
<td>KB kilobyte</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>1000^2</td>
<td>MB megabyte</td>
<td>1024^2</td>
<td>MiB mebibyte</td>
<td>MB megabyte</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>1000^3</td>
<td>GB gigabyte</td>
<td>1024^3</td>
<td>GiB gibibyte</td>
<td>GB gigabyte</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>1000^4</td>
<td>TB terabyte</td>
<td>1024^4</td>
<td>TiB tebibyte</td>
<td>-</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p>The reasoning behind my preference is two fold:</p>

<ol>
<li>The JEDEC <a href="https://www.jedec.org/document%5Fsearch?search%5Fapi%5Fviews%5Ffulltext=JESD100B01">Terms, Definitions, and Letter Symbols for Microcomputers, Microprocessors, and Memory Integrated Circuits</a> only defines the first three higher order prefixes: <em>kilo</em> (K), <em>mega</em> (M), <em>giga</em> (G), referring to them for common usage. The prefix <em>tera</em> was later added to the JEDEC terms dictionary to reflect <a href="https://www.jedec.org/standards-documents/dictionary/terms/mega-m-prefix-units-semiconductor-storage-capacity">common prefix usage for modern semiconductor storage capacity</a>.</li>
<li>IEC prefixes cannot be confused with Metric prefixes.</li>
</ol>

<p>To make matters more confusing, sometimes lowercase <code>k</code> is used to mean 1024, e.g. see <a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man1/tar.1.html#OPTIONS">tar(1) OPTIONS</a> sub section <code>Size Suffixes</code> located <a href="https://man7.org/linux/man-pages/man1/tar.1.html#RETURN%5FVALUE">above the RETURN VALUE section</a>. Understanding which system of measurement is being used is essential when calculating offsets.</p>

<h2 id="layout-of-sunxi-bootable-storage">Layout of sunxi bootable storage</h2>

<p>The first 40 plus <code>KiB</code> of bootable storage for an Allwinner based board has the <a href="https://linux-sunxi.org/Bootable%5FSD%5Fcard#SD%5FCard%5FLayout">following default layout</a>:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Start</th>
<th>Size</th>
<th>Usage</th>
</tr>
</thead>

<tbody>
<tr>
<td>0KiB</td>
<td>8KiB</td>
<td>Reserved for optional MBR or GPT</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>8KiB</td>
<td>32KiB</td>
<td>Initial SPL</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>40KiB</td>
<td>-</td>
<td>U-Boot Proper</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p>From the layout, one can conclude that upgrading the SPL and U-Boot for the PinePhone must involve writing the <code>u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code> to bootable storage starting at <code>8192B</code>.</p>

<h2 id="pinephone-boot-procedure">PinePhone boot procedure</h2>

<p>Bootstrapping is complicated by initial memory address space limitations. The <a href="https://linux-sunxi.org/BROM#U-Boot%5FSPL%5Flimitations">SPL is limited to 32 KiB</a>, most likely because the BootROM, or BROM, loads the SPL into <a href="https://linux-sunxi.org/A64/Memory%5Fmap">SRAM A1</a>, which is a <code>32 KiB</code> subsection. If the SPL is larger than <code>32 KiB</code> the BROM will refuse to load it. After the SPL loads U-Boot proper and passes execution to the ATF, U-Boot proper in turn runs <a href="https://gitlab.com/postmarketOS/pmaports/-/blob/master/device/community/device-pine64-pinephone/uboot-script.cmd">the Pine Phone’s u-boot command script</a>. The command script sets the default bootargs for init and calls the <a href="https://gitlab.denx.de/u-boot/u-boot/-/blob/master/cmd/booti.c">booti command</a>, which boots the Linux Kernel Image from memory given the <em>flattend device tree</em> (<a href="https://devicetree-specification.readthedocs.io/en/latest/flattened-format.html">FDT</a>) and the <em>initial ramdisk</em> (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Initrd">initrd</a>), ultimately passing execution to Linux init.</p>



<div>
  
<div><pre><code data-lang="text">+-----------------------+
|        BootROM        |
+-----------.-----------+
|
|
+-----------V-----------+
|     u-boot.itb+SPL    |
+-----------.-----------+
|
|
+-----------V-----------+
|       TF-A BL31       |
+-----------.-----------+
|
|
+-----------V-----------+
| U-Boot Proper (=BL33) |
+-----------.-----------+
|
|
+-----------V-----------+
|        Linux          |
+-----------------------+</code></pre></div>
</div>

<p>You might have noticed that <code>/usr/share/u-boot/pine64-pinephone/u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code> is much larger than <code>32KiB</code>.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="text">second-chance:~$ ls -lh /usr/share/u-boot/pine64-pinephone/u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin
-rw-r--r--    1 root     root      486.0K Jun 20 12:41 /usr/share/u-boot/pine64-pinephone/u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code></pre></div>
<p>That is because the SPL binary image includes a <em>Flattened uImage Tree</em> (<a href="https://gitlab.com/pine64-org/u-boot/-/blob/master/doc/uImage.FIT/source%5Ffile%5Fformat.txt">FIT image</a>) named <code>u-boot.itb</code> that contains the rest of the firmware.</p>

<h2 id="determine-which-bootable-storage-device-is-relevant">Determine which bootable storage device is relevant</h2>

<p>Before you can <a href="#how-to-determine-if-u-boot-needs-to-be-upgraded">determine if U-Boot needs to be upgraded</a>, you need to know which storage device your PinePhone is booting from. This can be easily determined by using the <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/8/lsblk">lsblk(8)</a> command to list the running operating system’s current mount points. Below is the output of <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/8/lsblk">lsblk(8)</a> run on my PinePhone booted from an <code>SD</code> card:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">second-chance:~$ lsblk --output NAME,TYPE,MOUNTPOINT</code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="text">NAME         TYPE MOUNTPOINT
mmcblk0      disk
├─mmcblk0p1  part /boot
└─mmcblk0p2  part
mmcblk2      disk
├─mmcblk2p1  part
├─mmcblk2p2  part
├─mmcblk2p1  part
└─mmcblk2p2  part
mmcblk2boot0 disk
mmcblk2boot1 disk</code></pre></div>
<p>The disk corresponding to the <code>/boot</code> mountpoint is the name of the block special device that postmarketOS is currently running form. The device path to the relevant boot storage device is therefore <code>/dev/mmcblk0</code>. We will be using this device name in the next two sections to determine if an upgrade is needed and again to perform the actual upgrade if warranted. You must be careful to use the device name that is relevant to your own running environment if you are following along.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-determine-if-u-boot-needs-to-be-upgraded">How to determine if U-Boot needs to be upgraded?</h2>

<p>You can determine if an upgrade is necessary simply by comparing the version of U-Boot installed by the <code>u-boot-pinephone</code> package with the version of U-Boot that is written to <a href="#determine-which-bootable-storage-device-is-relevant">the bootable storage device which is relevant to your running environment</a>.</p>

<p>To see which version of <code>U-Boot</code> was installed by the <code>u-boot-pinephone</code> package, simply run the <code>apk policy</code> sub command as shown below:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">second-chance:~/$ apk policy u-boot-pinephone</code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="text">u-boot-pinephone policy:
  2020.04_git20200421-r1:
    lib/apk/db/installed
    etc/apk/cache
    http://postmarketos1.brixit.nl/postmarketos/master</code></pre></div>
<p>Alternatively, you can use the <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/1/busybox">busybox(1)</a> <code>strings</code> command to search the binary’s printable strings for the regex pattern <code>U-Boot [[:digit:]]</code> by piping the output through a <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/1/busybox">busybox(1)</a> <code>grep</code> filter. As a side note, the PinePhone uses busybox, so when you find yourself looking up command line documentation with the intention of running the command from a PinePhone shell, always check the <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/1/busybox">busybox(1)</a> man pages first.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">second-chance:~/packages$ strings /usr/share/u-boot/pine64-pinephone/u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin | grep -E <span>'U-Boot [[:digit:]]'</span></code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="text">U-Boot 2020.04 (Jun 20 2020 - 12:41:48 +0000)</code></pre></div>
<p>Similarly, to determine the version of U-Boot that is currently written to bootable storage, you can search for the same regex pattern in the printable strings of the boot disk after the first <code>8 KiB</code>. However, since the bootable storage is significantly larger than <code>u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code>, it would not be efficient to use the <code>strings</code> command as we did previously. Instead, we will use the <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/1/busybox">busybox(1)</a> <code>dd</code> command, which will allow us to control where to begin and end the search. Since we can’t easily know the exact offset of the version string, which can very from build to build, my strategy has been to simply skip the first <code>8 KiB</code> and then read the same number of <code>KiB</code> as the size of the currently installed <code>u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code>. If my search turns up nothing, then that means that the previously installed version was larger, and I can simply increase the <code>count</code> to some reasonable number of <code>KiB</code> until I find what I am looking for.</p>

<p>First, let’s determine the size of <code>u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code>.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="sh">ls -lh /usr/share/u-boot/pine64-pinephone/u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code></pre></div><div><pre><code data-lang="text">-rw-r--r--    1 root     root      543.3K Jul 18  2020 /usr/share/u-boot/pine64-pinephone/u-boot-sunxi-with-spl.bin</code></pre></div>
<p>The binary installed to disk is about <code>5…</code></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bloggerbust.ca/post/how-to-update-uboot-for-postmarketos-on-the-pinephone/">https://bloggerbust.ca/post/how-to-update-uboot-for-postmarketos-on-the-pinephone/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bloggerbust.ca/post/how-to-update-uboot-for-postmarketos-on-the-pinephone/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24244407</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 14:35:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build tools around workflows, not workflows around tools]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 483 | Comments 144 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24244329">thread link</a>) | @thesephist
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://thesephist.com/posts/tools/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thesephist.com/posts/tools/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <p><em>This March, I spent a couple of days traveling through western Iceland.</em></p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/iceland.jpg" alt="Iceland, part 1"></p>
<p>While I was there, I thought a lot about tools – mechanical tools, software tools, tools that last, and tools that are fragile. The somber snow-covered scenery made me think about how quickly most of the tools we use today get outdated or replaced, and I thought about the kinds of tools that I’ve been building for myself for the last few years to help organize my life.</p>
<p>I took a walk around <em>Smábátahöfnin í Keflavík</em> (a small marina nearby) that night, unraveled myself into my hotel room, and started writing this post.</p>
<p>I want to share why I build my own tools and how I think we should think about building tools for life. It’s long, so here’s a roadmap. Feel free to jump around.</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#my-tools-today">My tools, today</a></li>
<li><a href="#workflows--tools">Workflows &gt; tools</a>
<ol>
<li><a href="#tasks-and-notes-a-false-dichotomy">Tasks and notes, a false dichotomy</a></li>
<li><a href="#tools-that-grow-with-your-workflows">Tools that grow with your workflows</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><a href="#own-your-load-bearing-tools-of-life">Own your load-bearing tools of life</a></li>
<li><a href="#cost-and-other-smaller-benefits">Cost and other smaller benefits</a></li>
<li><a href="#your-tools-are-an-extension-of-you">Your tools are an extension of you</a></li>
<li><a href="#appendix-the-technical-nitty-gritty">Appendix: the technical nitty-gritty</a></li>
</ol>
<hr>

<p>For the last few years, I’ve been on a journey to replace all of the essential digital tools I use for organizing my life with tools I develop, maintain, and deploy myself.</p>
<p>What started with a single-page notes app I made in high school has grown into a constellation of home-grown productivity tools I now rely on for my day-to-day work and learning. Here’s a sample.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesephist/polyx#ligature">Ligature</a>, for long-term notes and tasks, goals, brainstorming, project planning, and other important writing.</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/ligature.jpg" alt="Ligature"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesephist/pico">Pico</a>, for more ephemeral notes and tasks that change on a daily basis. I split up my notes into two apps (Ligature and Pico) because it works better for my workflow. (More on this later.)</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/pico.jpg" alt="Pico"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesephist/mira">Mira</a> for keeping track of people I know, why they’re interesting, and what we’ve talked about.</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/mira.png" alt="Mira"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesephist/lovecroft">Lovecroft</a> for managing and sending emails to my <a href="https://thesephist.com/#newsletter">mailing lists</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/lovecroft.jpg" alt="Lovecroft"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesephist/polyx#noct">Noct</a> for backing up and syncing all my files across computers and the cloud. Noct doesn’t have a graphical UI, just a command-line tool.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/frieden/">Frieden</a> as a public availability calendar, showing when I’m free or busy.</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/frieden.png" alt="Frieden"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesephist/thingboard">Thingboard</a> for more free-form Post-its-on-the-wall style brainstorming.</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/thingboard.jpg" alt="Thingboard"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://codeframe.co/">Codeframe</a> for spinning off simple JavaScript experiments like <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/word-experiments/#word-plotter">the word plotter</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/codeframe.jpg" alt="Codeframe"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://github.com/thesephist/draw">draw</a>, a collaborative whiteboard, best used with my iPad Pro and Apple Pencil.</p>
<p><img src="https://thesephist.com/img/draw.jpg" alt="Draw"></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Taken together, these apps do almost everything I need to do on my computer to keep myself organized. I don’t use any third-party notes, task management, or contacts apps, though I used to be a big fan of Simplenote and Todoist. I’ve used Notion, Dropbox Paper, Google Docs, and Airtable, but only for working in teams that centralized on them. These days, besides email and calendar, I live within a system of my own tools, and it works well for me.</p>
<p>I don’t want to imply that my tools are objectively better than the professional tools on the market like Notion and Dropbox. Those latter services have more features, and might even be more reliable today. But I think my tools fit me better for a different reason.</p>

<p>Each person’s mind works a little differently, and each person remembers and processes information a little differently. I think we all work at our best when we work with tools that fit how our minds work.</p>
<p>The Eureka moment that some of us feel when we finally find a notes app or todo system that fits our brains – that epiphany happens when the tools we use mirror the way our minds work, and how we want to move information through our lives. Good tools fit perfectly around our workflows, bad tools don’t.</p>
<p>When we resort to having other people build tools for us, the tools they build might never quite perfectly fit our workflows, because they’re not built for our individual minds. When other people build tools for us to use, they either design tools after their own workflows and mental models, or worse, they design it for a mass market of millions of people who all sort-of-but-not-really work and think in similar ways. The result is that mass-market productivity tools don’t fit the way our individual minds are predisposed to work. Instead, to use these tools, we need to bend our workflows to fit around the tools.</p>
<p>My biggest benefit from writing my own tool set is that <strong>I can build the tools that exactly conform to my workflows, rather than constructing my workflows around the tools available to me.</strong> This means the tools can truly be an extension of the way my brain thinks and organizes information about the world around me. My tools aren’t perfect yet, but as they grow and evolve, they’ll only become better reflections of my personal mental models.</p>
<p>For example, one place where my mind works differently than the tools on the market is the task/notes distinction.</p>
<h3 id="tasks-and-notes-a-false-dichotomy">Tasks and notes, a false dichotomy</h3>
<p>My workflow used to differentiate between tasks and notes. Tasks were action items that I could reference, take action on, and complete, and then erase from my list. Notes were things that were indefinitely relevant. I would take notes and then come back to reference them many times. A note by itself isn’t actionable.</p>
<p>But once I started building my own tools, I realized this distinction isn’t really the way my brain worked. For me, a huge grey area exists between actionable, completable tasks and purely encyclopedic notes. Here are some things that fall in the grey area for me, pulled from my real, actual notes I took this week.</p>
<ol>
<li>I recently learned some really useful tips about how to grow leaders within a community from the book <em><a href="https://gettogetherbook.com/">Get Together</a></em>. I definitely want to act on these learnings at some point in the communities I lead, but I don’t want them cluttering up my todo list because they’re not things I can just complete and check off quickly. I also want to remember these tips forever, even after the first time I act on them.</li>
<li>I’ve been brainstorming an idea for a side project related to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_algebra">symbolic mathematics</a>. I’ve been writing down my inspirations related to this project. I don’t want to tuck it away in my notes, because this is something I want to build soon, but I also don’t want to shove paragraphs of notes into a todo list item.</li>
<li>I keep a running list of ideas I have for future blog posts, but I don’t really have a “write the next blog post” task item under which I’d normally put these ideas, because I don’t write on schedule – I just write when I can. Where should these ideas go? They’re sort-of notes and sort-of tasks.</li>
</ol>
<p>You might think that these are either very clearly todo items or very clearly notes, and that’s ok. But I certainly felt differently, and I realized I was only separating things into these two buckets because my tools forced me to. Before I wrote my own tools, I had a todo app (Todoist) and I had a notes app (Simplenote), and there was nothing in between.</p>
<p>Eventually, I discovered a better mental model for my working style: I ask myself <em>how immediately</em> I need to take action on something.</p>
<p>The way that I see it, everything I learn and jot down is something for me to act on at some point in my life. If I read something that I never thought would influence the way I lived, it wouldn’t have value to me, and I simply wouldn’t write it down. Armed with this insight, these days, I have two different notes apps, and I don’t use a todo list app. These two apps are Ligature and Pico, mentioned above.</p>
<p>One is for notes that are changing often. Day-to-day tasks, things to remember for the next week, even long notes and links related to what I’m working on <em>now</em>. The other app is for notes that grow over time, like notes I take while reading books or watching talks, my annual goals, financial planning, reading list, and project outlines. <strong>My two notes apps mirror the way my brain works best – one is my short-term, working memory, the other is my long-term memory.</strong></p>
<p>I’ve had this system for a few months now, and haven’t felt any need for something better. It doesn’t have the crazy features of some notes services on the market today, but it just works the way my brain does.</p>
<p>But what if I need something different later on in life?</p>
<h3 id="tools-that-grow-with-your-workflows">Tools that grow with your workflows</h3>
<p>The other benefit of building homebrew tools is that <strong>tools you build yourself can grow and change as your workflow changes over time</strong>. So if my needs do change over time, my tools can grow to accommodate exactly what I need.</p>
<p>When I first started keeping more organized notes on the interesting people I met, I started with a document in my notes app. Over time, I noticed that these notes followed a pattern: I wrote down their name and primary contact info, how I first met them, what school they went to, and what we talked about the last time we spoke.</p>
<p>So when I built Mira, my own people-manager app, I designed it around that exact workflow I had developed. When I later realized I was also recording people’s Twitter usernames in the description field, I just added a Twitter username field to each contact.</p>
<p>This is typical of the way I <em>discover</em> my workflows. <strong>I start with a minimal, bare-bones solution, and try to pick up on patterns and tricks I create for myself. And then I encode those patterns and tricks into the tools over time.</strong></p>
<p>This way, my tools can grow organically as my workflows evolve. Neither of them gets in the way of each other most of the time, and I think that was hard to appreciate before I started relying wholly on my own tools.</p>

<p>My productivity tools, especially my notes and contacts, are the load-bearing tools of my life. If they break or disappear, it’ll take a long time and a lot of effort for me to rebuild those same workflows and tools, so it’s important that they’re reliable, and that I can depend on them working for me for a long time (measured in years and decades, not quarters).</p>
<p>I’ve written at length about <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/ownership/">the importance of ownership</a> before. I want to own the pieces of my life that are most critical, and I want agency over how these tools change over time.</p>
<p>I want these notes and ideas and workflows to stick with me as I grow as a person through the next decades. If I had to …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thesephist.com/posts/tools/">https://thesephist.com/posts/tools/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thesephist.com/posts/tools/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24244329</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 14:23:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Writing better Code (extension to Joel's 12 steps to better Code)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24243656">thread link</a>) | @gerlacdt
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://gerlacdt.github.io/posts/writing-better-software/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gerlacdt.github.io/posts/writing-better-software/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span>I</span>n Joel Spolsky’s blog post <a href="https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2000/08/09/the-joel-test-12-steps-to-better-code/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“The Joel Test: 12 Steps to better
Code”</a>,
he describes a test composed of twelve simple yes-no questions. For a
<strong>yes</strong> you get one point. 10 points are acceptable and 12 are
perfect. If you have less than 10 points, you will get in trouble with
your software – sooner or later.</p>
<p>For a quick self-check, these are the original questions:</p>
<ol>
<li>Do you use source control?</li>
<li>Can you make a build in one step?</li>
<li>Do you make daily builds?</li>
<li>Do you have a bug database?</li>
<li>Do you fix bugs before writing new code?</li>
<li>Do you have an up-to-date schedule?</li>
<li>Do you have a spec?</li>
<li>Do programmers have quiet working conditions?</li>
<li>Do you use the best tools money can buy?</li>
<li>Do you have testers?</li>
<li>Do new candidates write code during their interview?</li>
<li>Do you do hallway usability testing?</li>
</ol>
<p>Although Joel’s Test is still an excellent indicator for good software
development and engineering, 20 years have past and many game changing
technologies have emerged like mobile apps, the public cloud and in
general better tooling is available. The success of
<a href="https://git-scm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">git</a> and <a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">github</a> changed
how we develop software. In this article i want to extend Joel’s test
with contemporary questions:</p>
<ol start="13">
<li>Do you enforce a common code styleguide?</li>
<li>Do you write tests?</li>
<li>Do you conduct code reviews?</li>
<li>Do your developers write documentation?</li>
<li>Do you focus on code health?</li>
<li>Do you practice continuous integration?</li>
<li>Do you have a mentoring program?</li>
<li>Is your infrastructure reproducible?</li>
<li>Are you doing your best to keep your engineers?</li>
<li>Do you provide the best technology for your developers?</li>
<li>Do you focus on the four key metrics?</li>
<li>Do you empower your developers?</li>
</ol>
<p>The extended test consists of 24 yes-no questions. As with Joel’s
Test, for a <strong>yes</strong> you get one point. The ranking is:</p>
<ul>
<li>&lt;= 20 points, you must improve</li>
<li>21 points, you are ok</li>
<li>22 points, you are a high-performer</li>
<li>23 points, you are a high-performer</li>
<li>24 points, you are best-in-class</li>
</ul>
<p>Further I want to emphasis that <strong>sustainablity</strong> is my main intention
for the test. Many questions contribute directly or indirectly to a
sustainable and healthy codebase which is crucial for a successful
long-term software project and in general for a successful software
company. <a href="https://youtu.be/zW-i9eVGU_k?t=197" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Titus Winters</a> defines a
sustainable codebase as:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your organization’s codebase is sustainable when you are able to
change all of the things that you ought to change, safety, and can do
so for the lifetime of your codebase.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4 id="13-do-you-enforce-a-common-code-styleguide"><a href="#13-do-you-enforce-a-common-code-styleguide"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M326.612 185.391c59.747 59.809 58.927 155.698.36 214.59-.11.12-.24.25-.36.37l-67.2 67.2c-59.27 59.27-155.699 59.262-214.96 0-59.27-59.26-59.27-155.7 0-214.96l37.106-37.106c9.84-9.84 26.786-3.3 27.294 10.606.648 17.722 3.826 35.527 9.69 52.721 1.986 5.822.567 12.262-3.783 16.612l-13.087 13.087c-28.026 28.026-28.905 73.66-1.155 101.96 28.024 28.579 74.086 28.749 102.325.51l67.2-67.19c28.191-28.191 28.073-73.757 0-101.83-3.701-3.694-7.429-6.564-10.341-8.569a16.037 16.037 0 0 1-6.947-12.606c-.396-10.567 3.348-21.456 11.698-29.806l21.054-21.055c5.521-5.521 14.182-6.199 20.584-1.731a152.482 152.482 0 0 1 20.522 17.197zM467.547 44.449c-59.261-59.262-155.69-59.27-214.96 0l-67.2 67.2c-.12.12-.25.25-.36.37-58.566 58.892-59.387 154.781.36 214.59a152.454 152.454 0 0 0 20.521 17.196c6.402 4.468 15.064 3.789 20.584-1.731l21.054-21.055c8.35-8.35 12.094-19.239 11.698-29.806a16.037 16.037 0 0 0-6.947-12.606c-2.912-2.005-6.64-4.875-10.341-8.569-28.073-28.073-28.191-73.639 0-101.83l67.2-67.19c28.239-28.239 74.3-28.069 102.325.51 27.75 28.3 26.872 73.934-1.155 101.96l-13.087 13.087c-4.35 4.35-5.769 10.79-3.783 16.612 5.864 17.194 9.042 34.999 9.69 52.721.509 13.906 17.454 20.446 27.294 10.606l37.106-37.106c59.271-59.259 59.271-155.699.001-214.959z"></path></svg></a>13. Do you enforce a common code styleguide?</h4>
<p><strong>Consistency</strong> is one of the most important properties of a codebase.
It bolsters readability and maintainability which are essential for
sustainable code. A consistent codebase is easier to grasp and makes
onboarding new developers faster. New programmers are guided by the
prevailing style and can adapt quickly to it. Consistency is also an
indicator for coder’s discipline, clearly you don’t want to have dead
code, unused imports, wrong indentations, and other intricacies in
your codebase. The desired consistency can be achieved by a code
styleguide.</p>
<p>At best you enforce the rules of the styleguide via tooling like
static code analyzers, linters and autoformatting tools. Often these
tools are integrated into the build or are executed before a
commit. Further there are also manually measures like <a href="#codereview">code
reviews</a> to enforce a common code style.</p>
<p>A consistent code style increases productivity, e.g. linters prevent
sloppy programming errors, autoformatters leave no room for useless
(sometimes religious) discussions about indentation and formatting
rules. All code looks the same. Developer’s taste and ego take a back
seat.</p>
<h4 id="14-do-you-write-tests"><a href="#14-do-you-write-tests"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M326.612 185.391c59.747 59.809 58.927 155.698.36 214.59-.11.12-.24.25-.36.37l-67.2 67.2c-59.27 59.27-155.699 59.262-214.96 0-59.27-59.26-59.27-155.7 0-214.96l37.106-37.106c9.84-9.84 26.786-3.3 27.294 10.606.648 17.722 3.826 35.527 9.69 52.721 1.986 5.822.567 12.262-3.783 16.612l-13.087 13.087c-28.026 28.026-28.905 73.66-1.155 101.96 28.024 28.579 74.086 28.749 102.325.51l67.2-67.19c28.191-28.191 28.073-73.757 0-101.83-3.701-3.694-7.429-6.564-10.341-8.569a16.037 16.037 0 0 1-6.947-12.606c-.396-10.567 3.348-21.456 11.698-29.806l21.054-21.055c5.521-5.521 14.182-6.199 20.584-1.731a152.482 152.482 0 0 1 20.522 17.197zM467.547 44.449c-59.261-59.262-155.69-59.27-214.96 0l-67.2 67.2c-.12.12-.25.25-.36.37-58.566 58.892-59.387 154.781.36 214.59a152.454 152.454 0 0 0 20.521 17.196c6.402 4.468 15.064 3.789 20.584-1.731l21.054-21.055c8.35-8.35 12.094-19.239 11.698-29.806a16.037 16.037 0 0 0-6.947-12.606c-2.912-2.005-6.64-4.875-10.341-8.569-28.073-28.073-28.191-73.639 0-101.83l67.2-67.19c28.239-28.239 74.3-28.069 102.325.51 27.75 28.3 26.872 73.934-1.155 101.96l-13.087 13.087c-4.35 4.35-5.769 10.79-3.783 16.612 5.864 17.194 9.042 34.999 9.69 52.721.509 13.906 17.454 20.446 27.294 10.606l37.106-37.106c59.271-59.259 59.271-155.699.001-214.959z"></path></svg></a>14. Do you write tests?</h4>
<p>Writing automatic test is a major trait of a sustainable
codebase. There are many kind of tests but the best known
classification comes with the <a href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/practical-test-pyramid.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Test
Pyramid</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Unit Tests</li>
<li>Service Tests</li>
<li>User Interface Tests</li>
</ul>
<p>Particularly <strong>unit tests</strong> build the foundation and give developers
confidence to move fast and not to break existing functionality. Unit
testing is a major pillar of a fast feedback loop. This keeps
developers happy and the quality high. In general, tests act as a
safety net, prevent new bugs from being introduced and old bugs from
reoccurrence.</p>
<p>Without automatic tests your codebase will erode and only long-term
developers will be capable to make changes. Onboarding new developers
will take months or will never succeed at all. Over time developer
speed will slow down and finally come to a complete halt. Heavily
relying on manual testing before a release is a clear indicator of
missing automatic tests and extends the release cycle by days or
weeks. High performers deploy on a daily basis which is not possible
with manual testing phases. Therefore manual testing should be reduced
to a minimum or completely avoided.</p>
<p>Establishing a good testing culture is especially important. E.g.</p>
<ul>
<li>no code changes without a corresponding test</li>
<li>no bugfix without a test demonstrating the bug is indeed fixed</li>
<li>unit test should be fast, so developers run them continuously</li>
<li>unit test code coverage should be at a reasonable level like ~70%</li>
</ul>
<p>At Google, they practice the <a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/software-engineering-at/9781492082781/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Beyonce Rule “If you liked it, you
shoulda put a test on
it!"</a>
This rule inverts responsibility, e.g. if someone breaks a feature and
there was no test, the original author of the broken feature “shoulda
put a test on it!”.</p>
<h4 id="codereview"><a href="#codereview"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M326.612 185.391c59.747 59.809 58.927 155.698.36 214.59-.11.12-.24.25-.36.37l-67.2 67.2c-59.27 59.27-155.699 59.262-214.96 0-59.27-59.26-59.27-155.7 0-214.96l37.106-37.106c9.84-9.84 26.786-3.3 27.294 10.606.648 17.722 3.826 35.527 9.69 52.721 1.986 5.822.567 12.262-3.783 16.612l-13.087 13.087c-28.026 28.026-28.905 73.66-1.155 101.96 28.024 28.579 74.086 28.749 102.325.51l67.2-67.19c28.191-28.191 28.073-73.757 0-101.83-3.701-3.694-7.429-6.564-10.341-8.569a16.037 16.037 0 0 1-6.947-12.606c-.396-10.567 3.348-21.456 11.698-29.806l21.054-21.055c5.521-5.521 14.182-6.199 20.584-1.731a152.482 152.482 0 0 1 20.522 17.197zM467.547 44.449c-59.261-59.262-155.69-59.27-214.96 0l-67.2 67.2c-.12.12-.25.25-.36.37-58.566 58.892-59.387 154.781.36 214.59a152.454 152.454 0 0 0 20.521 17.196c6.402 4.468 15.064 3.789 20.584-1.731l21.054-21.055c8.35-8.35 12.094-19.239 11.698-29.806a16.037 16.037 0 0 0-6.947-12.606c-2.912-2.005-6.64-4.875-10.341-8.569-28.073-28.073-28.191-73.639 0-101.83l67.2-67.19c28.239-28.239 74.3-28.069 102.325.51 27.75 28.3 26.872 73.934-1.155 101.96l-13.087 13.087c-4.35 4.35-5.769 10.79-3.783 16.612 5.864 17.194 9.042 34.999 9.69 52.721.509 13.906 17.454 20.446 27.294 10.606l37.106-37.106c59.271-59.259 59.271-155.699.001-214.959z"></path></svg></a>15. Do you conduct code reviews?</h4>
<p>Code reviews are a critical step in your software engineering
process. Not only they prevent entering bugs into your mainline but
they are a major tool for knowledge transfer, learning and mentoring.
The code review process fosters a common understanding between
reviewers and author and offers a platform for discussions about
trade-offs and design decisions. Reviews are not only focused on
correctness but also on readability, performance and other
non-functional properties.</p>
<p>All of that will lead to better solutions. Further reviewers practice
their code reading skill which is as important as code
writing. Besides compiling, linting and running tests, code reviews
form a major step in a developers feedback loop. Code should never be
committed into mainline without a proper code review.</p>
<p>Because code reviews can conjure up heated discussions, reviewers
should comply to some <a href="https://google.github.io/eng-practices/review/reviewer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">code review
guidelines</a>
in order to guarantee a flawless experience.</p>
<h4 id="16-do-developers-write-documentation"><a href="#16-do-developers-write-documentation"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M326.612 185.391c59.747 59.809 58.927 155.698.36 214.59-.11.12-.24.25-.36.37l-67.2 67.2c-59.27 59.27-155.699 59.262-214.96 0-59.27-59.26-59.27-155.7 0-214.96l37.106-37.106c9.84-9.84 26.786-3.3 27.294 10.606.648 17.722 3.826 35.527 9.69 52.721 1.986 5.822.567 12.262-3.783 16.612l-13.087 13.087c-28.026 28.026-28.905 73.66-1.155 101.96 28.024 28.579 74.086 28.749 102.325.51l67.2-67.19c28.191-28.191 28.073-73.757 0-101.83-3.701-3.694-7.429-6.564-10.341-8.569a16.037 16.037 0 0 1-6.947-12.606c-.396-10.567 3.348-21.456 11.698-29.806l21.054-21.055c5.521-5.521 14.182-6.199 20.584-1.731a152.482 152.482 0 0 1 20.522 17.197zM467.547 44.449c-59.261-59.262-155.69-59.27-214.96 0l-67.2 67.2c-.12.12-.25.25-.36.37-58.566 58.892-59.387 154.781.36 214.59a152.454 152.454 0 0 0 20.521 17.196c6.402 4.468 15.064 3.789 20.584-1.731l21.054-21.055c8.35-8.35 12.094-19.239 11.698-29.806a16.037 16.037 0 0 0-6.947-12.606c-2.912-2.005-6.64-4.875-10.341-8.569-28.073-28.073-28.191-73.639 0-101.83l67.2-67.19c28.239-28.239 74.3-28.069 102.325.51 27.75 28.3 26.872 73.934-1.155 101.96l-13.087 13.087c-4.35 4.35-5.769 10.79-3.783 16.612 5.864 17.194 9.042 34.999 9.69 52.721.509 13.906 17.454 20.446 27.294 10.606l37.106-37.106c59.271-59.259 59.271-155.699.001-214.959z"></path></svg></a>16. Do developers write documentation?</h4>
<p>Documentation starts with the code. Code comments or a good
description of a pull request are good examples. Thereby good
documentation focuses on <strong>why</strong> something was done. An extensive
<code>README.md</code> acts as the “front-page” of a project and should contain
its purpose and instructions for developers to set up their local
environment for development, e.g installing prerequisites, building
the project, running the tests.</p>
<p>Additionally a variety of documents with different purposes exist:</p>
<ul>
<li>Design Docs (showing alternative solutions, why was one approach
chosen over the others?)</li>
<li>Architecture Diagrams (System overview, showing coherence between
components)</li>
<li>Operational Playbooks for <a href="https://landing.google.com/sre/workbook/chapters/on-call/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Software Reliability Engineers
(SREs)</a>
(operational instructions for fighting outages)</li>
</ul>
<p>All these documents should be written by developers, operators or
other technical people. Living, up-to-date documentation makes a
project more understandable and long-term project members are capable
of answering questions why things were done in the past – in the
majority of projects, the top answer is “this is historically grown”.
The only way to get real insights is conducting time consuming
face-to-face interviews. Documentation helps to keep an overview over
an ever-growing project, to facilitate the start for new developers
and to build a searchable knowledge base. Past decisions should be
transparent through good documentation and not hidden in people’s
heads.</p>
<h3 id="17-do-you-focus-on-code-health"><a href="#17-do-you-focus-on-code-health"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M326.612 185.391c59.747 59.809 58.927 155.698.36 214.59-.11.12-.24.25-.36.37l-67.2 67.2c-59.27 59.27-155.699 59.262-214.96 0-59.27-59.26-59.27-155.7 0-214.96l37.106-37.106c9.84-9.84 26.786-3.3 27.294 10.606.648 17.722 3.826 35.527 9.69 52.721 1.986 5.822.567 12.262-3.783 16.612l-13.087 13.087c-28.026 28.026-28.905 73.66-1.155 101.96 28.024 28.579 74.086 28.749 102.325.51l67.2-67.19c28.191-28.191 28.073-73.757 0-101.83-3.701-3.694-7.429-6.564-10.341-8.569a16.037 16.037 0 0 1-6.947-12.606c-.396-10.567 3.348-21.456 11.698-29.806l21.054-21.055c5.521-5.521 14.182-6.199 20.584-1.731a152.482 152.482 0 0 1 20.522 17.197zM467.547 44.449c-59.261-59.262-155.69-59.27-214.96 0l-67.2 67.2c-.12.12-.25.25-.36.37-58.566 58.892-59.387 154.781.36 214.59a152.454 152.454 0 0 0 20.521 17.196c6.402 4.468 15.064 3.789 20.584-1.731l21.054-21.055c8.35-8.35 12.094-19.239 11.698-29.806a16.037 16.037 0 0 0-6.947-12.606c-2.912-2.005-6.64-4.875-10.341-8.569-28.073-28.073-28.191-73.639 0-101.83l67.2-67.19c28.239-28.239 74.3-28.069 102.325.51 27.75 28.3 26.872 73.934-1.155 101.96l-13.087 13.087c-4.35 4.35-5.769 10.79-3.783 16.612 5.864 17.194 9.042 34.999 9.69 52.721.509 13.906 17.454 20.446 27.294 10.606l37.106-37.106c59.271-59.259 59.271-155.699.001-214.959z"></path></svg></a>17. Do you focus on code health?</h3>
<p>A healthy codebase is a major criteria for developer happiness. If
your developers working on a shitty codebase, they adapt to the poor
quality or leave. The existing codebase act as a <strong>role model</strong>. For
the purpose of high quality code, it is important to continuously
focus on code health. The best coders are repelled by bad code and
attracted by healthy code. But what is a healthy codebase?</p>
<p>A codebase is healthy when:</p>
<ul>
<li>you have fast builds</li>
<li>you have an easy development setup</li>
<li>you have fast and maintainable tests</li>
<li>you have clean, readable, loosely coupled and consistent code</li>
<li>you can easily debug the system</li>
<li>you continuously tackle technical debt</li>
</ul>
<p>You can find a much more exhaustive explanation of code health in
<a href="https://testing.googleblog.com/2016/08/hackable-projects.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google’s Testing Blog about Code
Health</a>.</p>
<p>Signs of bad code are:</p>
<ul>
<li>complicated developer setup</li>
<li>hard to debug, missing monitoring, noisy garbage logs</li>
<li>long build times</li>
<li>inconsistent code (dead code, unused imports, different formatting
styles, no code styleguide)</li>
<li>large merge conflicts due to long running feature branches, broken mainline</li>
<li>no tests, flaky tests, hard-maintainable tests because of mocking overuse</li>
</ul>
<p>Never trade dirty code or workarounds due to time or release pressure
for code health. You will end up very badly in the long run. Worse
yet, you get in a vicious cycle because bad code slows you down and in
order to fulfil the next release you add more dirty workarounds. So
always prioritize code health, even when it looks counterintuitive at
first sight.</p>
<h3 id="18-do-you-practice-continuous-integration"><a href="#18-do-you-practice-continuous-integration"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M326.612 185.391c59.747 59.809 58.927 155.698.36 214.59-.11.12-.24.25-.36.37l-67.2 67.2c-59.27 59.27-155.699 59.262-214.96 0-59.27-59.26-59.27-155.7 0-214.96l37.106-37.106c9.84-9.84 26.786-3.3 27.294 10.606.648 17.722 3.826 35.527 9.69 52.721 1.986 5.822.567 12.262-3.783 16.612l-13.087 13.087c-28.026 28.026-28.905 73.66-1.155 101.96 28.024 28.579 74.086 28.749 102.325.51l67.2-67.19c28.191-28.191 28.073-73.757 0-101.83-3.701-3.694-7.429-6.564-10.341-8.569a16.037 16.037 0 0 1-6.947-12.606c-.396-10.567 3.348-21.456 11.698-29.806l21.054-21.055c5.521-5.521 14.182-6.199 20.584-1.731a152.482 152.482 0 0 1 20.522 17.197zM467.547 44.449c-59.261-59.262-155.69-59.27-214.96 0l-67.2 67.2c-.12.12-.25.25-.36.37-58.566 58.892-59.387 154.781.36 214.59a152.454 152.454 0 0 0 20.521 17.196c6.402 4.468 15.064 3.789 20.584-1.731l21.054-21.055c8.35-8.35 12.094-19.239 11.698-29.806a16.037 16.037 0 0 0-6.947-12.606c-2.912-2.005-6.64-4.875-10.341-8.569-28.073-28.073-28.191-73.639 0-101.83l67.2-67.19c28.239-28.239 74.3-28.069 102.325.51 27.75 28.3 26.872 73.934-1.155 101.96l-13.087 13.087c-4.35 4.35-5.769 10.79-3.783 16.612 5.864 17.194 9.042 34.999 9.69 52.721.509 13.906 17.454 20.446 27.294 10.606l37.106-37.106c59.271-59.259 59.271-155.699.001-214.959z"></path></svg></a>18. Do you practice continuous integration?</h3>
<p>Nowadays Continuous Integration is hopefully commonplace. At best, you
work with trunk-based development and your mainline is always
releasable, preferably with feature toggles. Highest priority is to
keep the mainline green and a broken build should be fixed
immediately. Small and frequent releases prevent bugs or even outages
which happen when large releases are done only intermittently.</p>
<p>CI helps to prevent tedious merge conflict resolutions because your
developers regularly commit into mainline. Additionally you will get
rid of time consuming integration problems at the end of your
implementation phases.</p>
<p>“Agile”’s main goal is to identify risks as early as possible and not
to postpone them till the end of a project. CI supports exactly</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://gerlacdt.github.io/posts/writing-better-software/">https://gerlacdt.github.io/posts/writing-better-software/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gerlacdt.github.io/posts/writing-better-software/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24243656</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 12:27:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Teletext Bad Apple]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 104 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24243360">thread link</a>) | @bemmu
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://bitshifters.github.io/posts/prods/bs-badapple.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bitshifters.github.io/posts/prods/bs-badapple.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

                <!-- has to be portfolio-item for the caption overlay to work -->
                <div>
                    <div>

                        
                        <a href="#videoModal" data-toggle="modal">
                            
                            
                            <img src="https://bitshifters.github.io/content/bs-badappl.png" width="640" alt="image-alt">                            
                        </a>
                        


                        <p><strong>“Bad Apple” - The definitive BBC Micro/Teletext Version</strong></p>

<p>The Tou Hou Bad Apple <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G3C-VevI36s">video</a> has become a benchmark for pushing retro computing power to the limits. While it has been ported to many other 8-bit platforms, we are now pleased to present the definitive BBC Micro version in glorious Teletext pixel graphics.</p>

<p>Our version is a full 3m18s of video playback, played back at 25 frames per second in Teletext / MODE 7.</p>

<p>MODE 7 on the BBC Micro used a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mullard_SAA5050">Mullard SAA5050</a> Teletext display/decoder chip which (apart from from subtle implementation differences) is the same <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Teletext">Teletext</a> chip used in analogue TVs. It is 40x25 characters, supporting 8 primary colours, with support for text characters and basic graphical effects using control codes embedded into each character row. Support for teletext on the BBC Micro was an original requirement of the BBC’s specification for the machine due to their own use of broadcast teletext (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ceefax">Ceefax</a>).</p>

<p>The music is a custom VGM chiptune, hand designed by <a href="http://www.inversephase.com/">Inverse Phase</a> for the BBC Micro’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Texas_Instruments_SN76489">SN76489</a>. You can support IP’s excellent work by <a href="https://www.patreon.com/inversephase">becoming a patron here</a>.</p>

<p>Intro art by <a href="http://www.horsenburger.com/">Horsenburger</a>, and you can buy awesome stuff from <a href="https://www.tshirtstudio.com/marketplace/horsenburger's-textworks">Horsenburger’s store</a>.</p>

<p>The code, music &amp; screens are crammed into a standard 8-bit 2MHz 6502 based BBC Micro’s 32Kb RAM, and the video is streamed into memory track by track, after being heavily compressed to fit on one single 400Kb double sided floppy disk image.</p>

<p>You can watch the demo in your browser, using the brilliant JSBeeb Javascript BBC Micro emulator by clicking the Emulate button below.</p>

<p>Full source is on Github.</p>

<p>For more information on teletext, take a look at the following sites:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://teletextart.co.uk/">TeletextR</a> - News &amp; Happenings in the world of Teletext</li>
  <li><a href="http://edit.tf/">Edit.TF</a> - A Web Based Teletext Editor</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/TeletextGroup/">Facebook Teletext Group</a> - Teletext Community Group</li>
  <li><a href="http://danfarrimond.co.uk/">Dan Farrimond’s Art</a> - Awesome teletext art</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.horsenburger.com/">Horsenburger’s Art</a> - Addtional Awesome teletext art</li>
</ul>


                        <hr>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Team:
                                <strong>Bitshifters
                            </strong>
                            </li>
                            
                            <li>Authors:
                                <strong>Kieran, Simon, Inverse Phase &amp; Horsenburger
                            </strong>
                            </li>
                            
                            <li>Released:
                                <strong>2017
                            </strong>
                            </li>
                            <li>Type:
                                <strong>Demo
                            </strong>
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                Platform:
                                <strong>
                                BBC Micro Model B
                            </strong>
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                        <!--
                        <ul class="list-inline item-details">
                            
                            <a href="http://www.pouet.net/prod.php?which=69110" target="_blank">Pouet</a>  
                            <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=22y_aiOx9CY" target="_blank">Video</a> 
                        </ul>
-->

                    </div>
                </div>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bitshifters.github.io/posts/prods/bs-badapple.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24243360</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 11:16:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why is it ok to divide by 0.0?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24243277">thread link</a>) | @okaleniuk
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://wordsandbuttons.online/why_is_it_ok_to_divide_by_0_0.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wordsandbuttons.online/why_is_it_ok_to_divide_by_0_0.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	
	<p>
This is the speed of light in meters per second.
	</p>
	<p>
299 792 458
	</p>
	<p>
It is a relatively small number. It has nine digits and one can easily write it down on a small sheet of paper.
	</p>
	<p>
But what if we only have about half of that sheet?
	</p>
	<p>
If we're ok with some small error, let's say 0.1%, then we can say that the speed of light is approximately this:
	</p>
	<p>
300 000 000
	</p>
	<p>
It's still nine digits but we can also write it as:
	</p>
	<p>
3×10<sup>8</sup>
	</p>
	<p>
Or, using engineering notation,
	</p>
	<p>
3e8
	</p>
	<p>
It's the same number, the same power of ten, it just takes fewer symbols to write it down.
	</p>
	<p>
Now 3e8 represents the speed of light. With some small error, of course.
	</p>
	<p>
But 3e8 with the 0.1% error also represents a lot of other numbers. In fact, it represents every number in the range of [3e8 - 3e5, 3e8 + 3e5]. That's 600 001 integer numbers. And an infinite number of real ones.
	</p>
	<p>
Digital computers mostly keep numbers in a similar way. They store a small amount of binary digits for the number and even a smaller amount of binary digits to indicate the <i>e-something</i> analog which is the multiplying power of two. In this way, they can operate both very large and very small numbers. But of course, the number of digits is finite so there are numbers so large they can not be written at all. We just don't have enough digits to write them down.
	</p>
	<p>
3728084...many more digits...901359572e1
	</p>
	<p>
And the same goes for the small numbers. There are numbers so small that we can't write them down in engineering notation.
	</p>
	<p>
1e-82883617...even more digits...46221667
	</p>
	<p>
With digital computers, we have to represent all those tiny numbers with:
	</p>
	<p>
0.0
	</p>
	<p>
Not the integer zero but the floating-point zero. That's two different animals. Actually, these are three different animals since there is also -0.0 that represents all the tiny negative numbers.
	</p>
	<p>
Anyway, just like 3e8 represents a range of numbers, a 0 represents not a single number but every number that is so small you don't have enough digits to write down how small it is.
	</p>
	<p>
So the number representing zero might be an actual zero but it might very well not be one. So when we ask a computer to divide a number by zero we're actually telling it to divide a number by some arbitrary real small number. And it does. And the result is the arbitrary very large number.
	</p>
	<p>
In floating-point numbers, there is a special number to represent all the arbitrary large numbers. It's called “infinity” but just as the 0.0 doesn't only represent zero but all the ultra-small numbers, “infinity” doesn't represent infinity but rather all the numbers that are so large you don't have enough digits to write down how large they are.
	</p>
	<p>
But why do we have to keep our numbers small? Why is it important to fit things into some relatively small amount of digits? Cant, we just have all the digits we want?
	</p>
	<p>
And the answer is — the speed of light.
	</p>
	<p>
In computing, especially in high-performant computing when you measure latencies in nanoseconds, the light suddenly doesn't seem to go travel all that fast.
	</p>
	<p>
How far do you think light travels in one nanosecond given the optimal conditions?
	</p>

	
	


	
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wordsandbuttons.online/why_is_it_ok_to_divide_by_0_0.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24243277</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 11:00:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AngelCAD: Script-based 3D solid modeller]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 67 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24243077">thread link</a>) | @app4soft
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://arnholm.github.io/angelcad-docs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://arnholm.github.io/angelcad-docs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <header>
        
        
        

        <p>AngelCAD - user documentation</p>

        
        <p><a href="https://github.com/arnholm/angelcad-docs">View the Project on GitHub <small>arnholm/angelcad-docs</small></a></p>
        

        

        
      </header>
      <section>

      <p><strong>AngelCAD - script based 3D solid modeller</strong></p>

<p>AngelCAD is a powerful open source 3D solid modeller based on the Constructive Solid Geometry (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constructive_solid_geometry">CSG</a>) modelling technique, expressed in the <a href="http://www.angelcode.com/angelscript/sdk/docs/manual/doc_script.html">AngelScript</a> language. The software creates 3D models in STL or other file formats.</p>



<p>The csg_wikipedia.as sample</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>AngelCAD resources</th>
      <th>&nbsp;</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="http://www.angelcode.com/angelscript/sdk/docs/manual/doc_script.html" target="_blank">AngelScript language</a></td>
      <td>AngelScript language reference</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://arnholm.github.io/angelcad-docs/docs/annotated.html" target="_blank">AngelCAD language extension</a></td>
      <td>Language extension for 3d modelling</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://forum.abmesh.com/" target="_blank">AngelCAD user forum</a></td>
      <td>Discuss AngelCAD topics</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://github.com/arnholm/angelcad-samples" target="_blank">angelcad-samples</a></td>
      <td>Examples repository - GitHub</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://youtu.be/h-qDzG9bwnQ" target="_blank">Video</a></td>
      <td>script based 3D solid modeller</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><a href="https://github.com/arnholm/angelcad/releases" target="_blank">Downloads</a></td>
      <td>Prebuilt binaries - Windows and Linux</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>(links above open in new tabs)</p>

<p><strong>AngelCAD IDE and Viewer</strong> - With the desktop IDE you edit/run the scripts and launch the 3d Viewer</p>

<p><img src="https://arnholm.github.io/angelcad-docs/images/angelcad_ide.png" alt="AngelCAD modeller"></p>

<p><strong>Technology</strong> - AngelCAD uses <a href="https://github.com/arnholm/xcsg" target="_blank">xcsg</a> for 3d computations. xcsg is based on the <a href="https://github.com/arnholm/carve" target="_blank">carve library</a> by Tobias Sargeant. Also used is <a href="http://angusj.com/delphi/clipper.php">Clipper</a> by Angus Johnson, qhull by C.B. Barber and libtess2 by Mikko Mononen.</p>

<p>The AngelCAD language interpreter - as_csg - is based on the <a href="http://www.angelcode.com/angelscript/" target="_blank">AngelScript language</a> by Andreas Jönsson, as_csg extends the language with 3d modelling primitives and operations for constructive solid geometry.</p>

<p>The AngelCAD IDE and Viewer applications use the <a href="https://wxwidgets.org/" target="_blank">wxWidgets cross-platform GUI library</a> to create native GUI for Windows and Linux.</p>


      </section>
      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://arnholm.github.io/angelcad-docs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24243077</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 10:07:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Don't Name Classes After Patterns. Mostly]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24241886">thread link</a>) | @allending
<br/>
August 21, 2020 | https://sender.cloudy.email/campaigns/paxjhchaiasjoifsiw/webversion/jdnapfbdgjegdqmdeduwc | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sender.cloudy.email/campaigns/paxjhchaiasjoifsiw/webversion/jdnapfbdgjegdqmdeduwc">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div width="100%">
													<tbody>
														<tr>
															<td><!--[if mso]>
				<table align="left" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%" style="width:100%;">
				<tr>
				<![endif]--><!--[if mso]>
				<td valign="top" width="600" style="width:600px;">
				<![endif]-->
															<div>
																		<p>Good Morning/Afternoon/Evening as the case may be.</p>

																		<p>I've been hoping you are well, and thinking about naming.</p>

																		<p><em>Estimated reading time: 7 minutes, 37 seconds.</em></p>

																		<h2>A Small Digression</h2>

																		<p>You may have heard <a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/postal/click?link=92413&amp;sid=wqqbdfbdgjegdnzqbuftx&amp;ck=77-9PyZs77-906QTfXUr77-977-977-9c--_ve-_vUoJ77-9Plfvv71IeTjvv70K77-9Hu-_vWA=" target="_blank">Phil Karlton's famous saying</a>:</p>

																		<blockquote>
																		<p>There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation and naming things.</p>
																		</blockquote>

																		<p>I first heard this as 'There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation, naming things, and off-by-one errors.'</p>

																		<p>I passed this phrase on for many years before realizing that the 'off-by-one errors' bit was a joke.</p>

																		<p>Truth.</p>

																		<p>I am so literal that it pains me. I confess this in case it's paining you too. Puns, for example, fly right over my head, and any that I make are most likely inadvertent. I don't believe that there are any puns in the text that follows—but how would I know?</p>

																		<h2>Thoughts on Using Pattern Names in Class Names</h2>

																		<p>I've always heard that it's best to avoid using pattern names in class names. As one so often does, I've cargo-culted this rule without truly examining it. I habitually obey it myself, and teach it to folks in my OOD classes, but until recently I couldn't have articulated a convincing defense.</p>

																		<p>But then, while writing the 2nd Edition of 99 Bottles of OOP, I broke it. I created a new class whose name included the name of a pattern. I did this because it just felt right.</p>

																		<p>This put me in a pickle.</p>

																		<p>I very much believe in being guided by feelings about code, but when writing a book one can't just say, 'Okay, now do this because I, the author, <em>feel</em> like you should'. Respect for the reader requires investing sincere effort into dragging feelings about code into the light of day, and at least <em>trying</em> to justify them with convincing words.</p>

																		<p>Below I've included the excerpt from the book where I attempt just such convincing. The excerpt explains the purpose of the no-pattern-names-in-class-names rule and defends its utility.</p>

																		<p>I've built a newsletter around this rule not only because I believe that it's useful, but also because my initial attempts to explain it exposed deep holes in my understanding. This was a revelation. Had I not been writing a book, I might have hand-waved around these gaps in my knowledge forever.</p>

																		<h3>Some Context</h3>

																		<p>Before moving on to the excerpt, here's a bit of context to orient you. At this point in the book:</p>

																		<ul>
																			<li>
																			<p>The code contains a <code>CountdownSong</code> class that gets injected with a player of the <code>verse template</code> role.</p>
																			</li>
																			<li>
																			<p><code>BottleVerse</code> is the only class that plays this role. It's used as the default <code>verse template</code> in <code>CountdownSong</code>.</p>
																			</li>
																		</ul>

																		<p>So, <code>CountdownSong</code> has-a <code>verse template</code>, whose concrete implementation is supplied by <code>BottleVerse</code>.</p>

																		<ul>
																			<li>
																			<p>I'm writing tests for <code>CountdownSong</code>, and have just decided to create a new player of the <code>verse template</code> role to inject for use during these tests.</p>
																			</li>
																			<li>
																			<p>I've named this new class <code>VerseFake</code>.</p>
																			</li>
																		</ul>

																		<p>The excerpt below also mentions a <code>BottleNumber</code> class. This class wraps a number to add bottle-ish behavior.</p>

																		<h3>The Excerpt</h3>

																		<p>With that, here's a bit of chapter 9:</p>

																		<blockquote>
																		<p><em>The <code>VerseFake</code> class above is perfect for your needs, though it must be acknowledged that it unrepentantly breaks several common programming rules.</em></p>

																		<p><em>First, Chapter 8 suggested that you put domain behavior on instances. This class violates that rule; its behavior is on the class/static side.</em></p>

																		<p><em>Next, there's an as-yet-unmentioned object-oriented programming rule that prohibits the use of pattern names in class names. The word "Fake" above refers to a testing pattern, so naming this class <code>VerseFake</code> violates that rule.</em></p>

																		<p><em>Fake things first. You're probably familiar with the idea of design patterns, which are named, re-usable solutions to common software problems. Pattern names act as shortcuts to big ideas and allow programmers to communicate with speed and precision. Pattern thinking has so influenced software design that most programmers are familiar with a number of patterns. For example, you've likely heard of Decorator, Adapter, Enumerator, and so on, even if you're a bit fuzzy on the specifics of some of their definitions.</em></p>

																		<p><em>Since pattern names are so meaningful, it can be tempting to stick them in class names. For example, you might use the Decorator pattern to enclose a <code>number</code> in a new class that adds additional responsibility. Initially, <code>NumberDecorator</code> might seem like a good name for the result. The problem with including the name of a pattern in the name of a class is that this permits you the feeling of having created a useful name without actually having done so. Pattern names don't generally reflect concepts in your application. Appending them to class names pollutes your domain with programmer-y words and circumvents the search for names that add semantic meaning. Class names that include patterns are a signal that you've given up too soon on the hard problem of naming.</em></p>

																		<p><em>Class names should reflect concepts in your domain, not the patterns used to create them. Compared to <code>BottleNumber</code>, the much-richer name you gave this class in Chapter 4, <code>NumberDecorator</code> is so abstract as to be meaningless. Future readers won't care that the class was created using Decoration but they'll be grateful to know that it's a bottle-ish kind of number.</em></p>

																		<p><em>The <a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/postal/click?link=92414&amp;sid=wqqbdfbdgjegdnzqbuftx&amp;ck=77-977-977-977-9eSwVZ2JBZ--_ve-_ve-_ve-_vV9x77-9BQjvv73vv701a0gd77-9Qu-_ve-_ve-_ve-_vQ==" target="_blank">xUnit Test Patterns</a> book by <a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/postal/click?link=92415&amp;sid=wqqbdfbdgjegdnzqbuftx&amp;ck=77-9HgHvv70tK1MW77-977-977-9FO-_ve-_vcm-77-977-977-9M--_ve-_vXYhN2tdTu-_ve-_ve-_vQ==" target="_blank">Gerard Meszaros</a> standardizes the <a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/postal/click?link=92416&amp;sid=wqqbdfbdgjegdnzqbuftx&amp;ck=77-9fXp-JDEw77-977-9VO-_vdSyfnnvv71n77-977-9TO-_ve-_vSrvv70xKO-_vSTvv70=" target="_blank">pattern names</a> of a set of objects that are used to simplify testing. <code>TestDouble</code> is his generic name for all of the patterns. Within <code>TestDouble</code> he further delineates the <code>Dummy</code>, <code>Stub</code>, <code>Spy</code>, <code>Mock</code>, <code>Fake</code>, and <code>Temporary Test Stub</code> patterns.</em></p>

																		<p><em>Meszaros defines <code>Fake</code> as a <code>TestDouble</code> that provides a lightweight implementation of a collaborator that is needed by the class you are actually unit testing. A <code>Fake</code> is a regular old object; no testing magic is involved. In this case the new <code>VerseFake</code> class is a real player of the verse template role; it's called a <code>Fake</code> because it's only used during testing. <code>BottleVerse</code> plays the role of verse template in production. <code>VerseFake</code> was created to play this role during <code>Bottles</code>' unit tests.</em></p>

																		<p><em>The upshot is that <code>Fake</code> is the name of a pattern, so <code>VerseFake</code> violates the don't-include-pattern-names-in-class-names rule.</em></p>

																		<p><em>Rules exist to save money, and the two rules that <code>VerseFake</code> breaks are primarily meant to save money in production code; they might not be so applicable in code created to simplify tests. For example, the purpose of <code>VerseFake</code> is to fake the role of verse template. In this case, <code>VerseFake</code> might be the most intention-revealing name possible. If you end up needing a number of different kinds of fakes, you might need additional qualifiers in their names (<code>SimpleVerseFake</code>, <code>ComplicatedVerseFake</code>) but the word "fake" still adds meaning in the domain of your tests.</em></p>

																		<p><em>Similarly, it's important that the shape of production code not interfere with your ability to change it. The put-domain-behavior-on-instances rule serves this goal. In tests, however, you're less concerned with preserving the fake's changeability and more interested in directly communicating its responsibilities. Putting the behavior in a class or static method simplifies the code in <code>VerseFake</code> at the expense of making it less adaptable. This is a trade-off you'll happily make in code used only by the tests.</em></p>
																		</blockquote>

																		<p>I am convinced by that explanation, and I hope you are too. Now that I comprehend it, the no-pattern-names-in-class-names rule seems both simple and inevitable.</p>

																		<p>The deeper point is that I didn't really understand this rule until I had to write an explanation—believe me, my early attempts were neither brief nor convincing. The above is the result of a few days of walking around in my office, muttering, groping for insight.</p>

																		<p>It's not necessarily bad to cargo-cult a rule. Most rules that have risen to the level of cargo-cult-ability are actually pretty reasonable, and even if you don't completely understand their subtleties, following them might improve your code.</p>

																		<p>However, you'll get more value from a rule if you comprehend its underlying purpose. And even better, understanding its true purpose allows you to justify yourself when you decide to break it.</p>

																		<p>Thanks for reading. I very much hope you are safe and well.</p>

																		<p>Best,</p>

																		<p>Sandi</p>

																		<hr>
																		<h2><a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/postal/click?link=92417&amp;sid=wqqbdfbdgjegdnzqbuftx&amp;ck=ae-_vSYK77-9Uu-_ve-_vUvvv73vv71vJ--_ve-_vRJzBmjvv71DODzvv73vv73vv715y6Hvv71v77-9" target="_blank">99 Bottles of OOP, 2nd Edition</a> is complete!</h2>

																		<h3>Use coupon code <strong><a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/postal/click?link=92418&amp;sid=wqqbdfbdgjegdnzqbuftx&amp;ck=77-9cO-_vSDvv70WXw4wE3w-77-9Z--_ve-_vTzvv73vv73vv73vv73bre-_vTXvv73KkO-_vQ7vv70=" target="_blank">2ND-IS-DONE!</a></strong> through Sept 7</h3>

																		<h3>for a <a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/postal/click?link=92418&amp;sid=wqqbdfbdgjegdnzqbuftx&amp;ck=77-9cO-_vSDvv70WXw4wE3w-77-9Z--_ve-_vTzvv73vv73vv73vv73bre-_vTXvv73KkO-_vQ7vv70=" target="_blank">25% discount</a> on the book.</h3>

																		<p>The new edition:</p>

																		<ul>
																			<li>has three new chapters (it's almost 50% longer).</li>
																			<li>comes in separate books for two programming languages (Ruby and JavaScript) and two beverages (beer and milk), with a free PHP upgrade coming this fall.</li>
																			<li>is available as an ebook only, in epub, kepub, kobi, and pdf formats.</li>
																			<li>bundles every book variant. A single purchase gets you all of the books.</li>
																		</ul>

																		<p>I am so <em>glad</em> to be done with this edition that I'm passing that good cheer on to you.</p>

																		<p><strong><em>Note:</em></strong><br>
																		<span><em>Those of you who already own the book should have recently received</em></span><span><em>your own personal upgrade coupon.</em></span></p>

							…</div></td></tr></tbody></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://sender.cloudy.email/campaigns/paxjhchaiasjoifsiw/webversion/jdnapfbdgjegdqmdeduwc">https://sender.cloudy.email/campaigns/paxjhchaiasjoifsiw/webversion/jdnapfbdgjegdqmdeduwc</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sender.cloudy.email/campaigns/paxjhchaiasjoifsiw/webversion/jdnapfbdgjegdqmdeduwc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24241886</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 05:40:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Stef's Free Online Smalltalk Books]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 86 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24241561">thread link</a>) | @triyambakam
<br/>
August 21, 2020 | http://stephane.ducasse.free.fr/FreeBooks.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://stephane.ducasse.free.fr/FreeBooks.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
	   I started to be fed up to see all the books I like to be out of print, so I started to contact authors and 
	   collect their old books. I would like to thanks them all and their publishers as well. If you
       know an author that is willing to give to the community a book, please give
       him my email. You can support me. </p><p> Thanks in advance. 




</p><p>
You can find a lot more recent and free books at <a href="http://books.pharo.org/">http://books.pharo.org</a>: Spec, Pharo by Example Updated, Pharo with Style, Learning OOD with TDD, and many more. 
In addition most the new books around Pharo are hosted at <a href="http://github.com/SquareBracketAssociates">http://github.com/SquareBracketAssociates</a> and each project has an automatic build with the latest PDF version.


</p><p>
If you have more books and you want to get them archived and listed here please contact me.

</p><div width="95%" height="174">

	<tbody><tr>
	    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/DynamicWebDevInSeaside/DynWebDevInSeaside.png" width="100"></td>
	    <td>
	      <p><a href="http://book.seaside.st/">[ Dynamic Web Development with Seaside ]</a> Stephane Ducasse, Lukas Renggli, David C. Shaffer and Rick Zaccone. Square Bracket Associates, 2009.</p>
	     
	This book is made available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 license. You will be able to  buy a softcover copy from <a href="http://www.lulu.com/">lulu.com</a>. 
	    </td>
	  </tr>
	

	<tr>
	    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/PBE/PharoByExample.png" width="100"></td>
	    <td>
	      <p><a href="http://books.pharo.org/">[ Pharo by Example (original version and translation) ]</a> Andrew P. Black, Stéphane Ducasse, Oscar Nierstrasz, Damien Pollet with Damien Cassou and Marcus Denker. Square Bracket Associates, 2009.</p> Pay attention there is also Pharo by Example Updated (for Pharo 50) and we are working on Pharo by Example for Pharo 80.
	     
	This book is made available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 license. You will be able to  buy a softcover copy from <a href="http://www.lulu.com/">lulu.com</a>. 
	    </td>
	  </tr>

	<tr>
	    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Gnu/GNU.png" width="100"></td>
	    <td>
	     <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Gnu/computer_programming_using_gnu_smalltalk.pdf">[ Computer Programming using GNU Smalltalk ]</a> Canol Gokel, free e-book. 2009. 
	   <a href="http://www.canol.info/books/computer_programming_using_gnu_smalltalk">home page of the book to have an up to date version</a>.
		</p> 
	    </td>
	  </tr> 


  	<tr>
	    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/SBE/sbe.png" width="100"></td>
	    <td>
	      <p><a href="https://hal.inria.fr/inria-00441576/document">[ Squeak by Example ]</a> Andrew P. Black, Stéphane Ducasse, Oscar Nierstrasz and Damien Pollet. Square Bracket Associates, 2007.</p> Watch out this book is old. Better read <a href="http://books.pharo.org/">Pharo by Example book</a>.
	    </td>
	  </tr>
	
	<tr>
	    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/SmalltalkDesignPatternCompanion/coversm.gif" width="100"></td>
	    <td>
	      <p> <a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/SmalltalkDesignPatternCompanion">[ Smalltalk design pattern companion book drafts ]</a> Sherman Alpert, Kyle Brown, and Bobby Woolf. Addison-Wesley,  978-02011846241998.</p>
		The chapters listed here are not in their final form but more in draft form. Buy the book it is really excellent. 
	    </td>
	  </tr>
	
	
   <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/ByExample/byExample.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td> 
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/ByExample/">[ Smalltalk by
      Example: the Developer's Guide ]</a> Alex Sharp, McGraw Hill Text; ISBN:
      0079130364, 1997.</p>
      This book covers all kinds of issues basic level, design, testing... I
      liked it a lot. The code and the book as a single file containing everything are available. Thank again
      Lukas Renggli for his effort for converting everything from Word.
       Thanks a lot Alec and thanks McGraw-Hill <a href="http://books.mcgraw-hill.com/">http://books.mcgraw-hill.com/</a>
  They were really nice with us so think about it if you hesitate to buy
  one of their books. Not all the publishers are that open-minded. 
  </td>
  </tr>
  
<tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/WithStyle/WithStyle.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/WithStyle/SmalltalkWithStyle.pdf">[ Smalltalk With Style ]</a> by Edward Klimas, Suzanne Skublics and David A. Thomas. 
		ISBN: 0-13-165549-3, Publisher: Prentice Hall, Copyright: 1996. A great and 
		small book that everybody should read. Thanks Ed, Suzanne and Dave to give it for free. 
		Thanks Don for the OCR!
	   </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  
<tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/InsideST/InsideSmalltalkV1.png" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/InsideST/InsideSmalltalk.pdf">[ Inside Smalltalk 
       (Volume One) ]</a>  by LaLonde, Wilf R. and Pugh, John R., Prentice-Hall, 1990, ISBN 0-13-468414-1.
       Thanks Don for the OCR! 
	   </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  
  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/InsideST/InsideSmalltalkV2.png" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/InsideST/InsideSmalltalkII.pdf">[ Inside Smalltalk (Volume Two)],</a>  by LaLonde, Wilf R. and Pugh, John R., Prentice-Hall, 1990, ISBN 0-13-468414-1. Thanks Don for the OCR! </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
<tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/LittleSmalltalk/littleST.jpeg" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/LittleSmalltalk/ALittleSmalltalk.pdf">[ A Little Smalltalk ] </a> by Tim Budd, Addison-Wesley 1987.  
      <br>Many thanks to Tim Budd and his  publisher. Please have a look at <a href="http://www.aw.com/catalog/academic/discipline/1,4094,69948,00.html">http://www.aw.com/catalog/academic/discipline/1,4094,69948,00.html</a>. Thanks Don for the OCR!.
		</p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
<tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Art/Art.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Art/artAdded174186187Final.pdf">[ The Art and Science of Smalltalk ]</a>  by Simon Lewis, Prentice-Hall 1995-1999.  
      <br>Many thanks to the original publishers of this book Prentice-Hall, the responsible of the HP series and Simon Lewis.</p>
    </td>
  </tr>
<tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/PracticalSmalltalk/practical.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/PracticalSmalltalk/PracticalSmalltalk.pdf">[ Practical Smalltalk: Using Smalltalk/V ]</a>  by Dan Shafer and Dean A. Ritz, Springer Verlag; (July 1991).  
      <br>Many thanks to the original publishers of this book Springer Verlag,  and Dan. Thanks</p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  
<tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/HopkinsHoran/HopkinsHoran.jpg" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/HopkinsHoran/HopkinsHoran.pdf">[ Smalltalk An Introduction to Application Development using VisualWorks ]</a> Trevor Hopkins and Bernard Horan,  Pearson Education, 1995. The answers of the exercises are at ftp://st.cs.uiuc.edu/pub/Smalltalk/books/Book_Answers.tar.gz
      <br>Many thanks to the original publishers of this book,  Pearson Education,  for permission to distribute this work, and of course the authors! </p>
    </td>
  </tr>

<tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/STandOO/st-and-oo.jpg" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/STandOO/Smalltalk-and-OO.pdf"> [ Smalltalk and Object Orientation: an Introduction ] </a> Springer-Verlag, ISBN 3-540-76115-2, 1997.
</p>
      <br>This book provides a good survey of Smalltalk. Some information are now obsolete 
      but it is still worth reading. Enjoy it. Thanks John to support our request. We want to thank Springer Verlag Publishing
    for allowing us to give you this book for free.
    </td>
  </tr>
  
 <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/SmalltalkVTutorial/emptyCover.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/SmalltalkVTutorial/SmalltalkVTutorial.pdf"> [ Smalltalk V Tutorial ]</a>
	   </p>
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Taste/taste.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Taste/"> [ The Taste of Smalltalk ] </a> Ted Kaehler and Dave Patterson, W W Norton Co.; ISBN: 0393955052; (May 1986).</p>
      This book is for collectors. The quotes are really excellent. 
      <br>All the chapters are ready (except chap.2 for now)
    Enjoy it. (Scanned ... by Stef, Alex, Gabriela, and Lukas).
    Thanks Ted.
    </td>
  </tr>

 <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/emptyCover.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
     <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Joy/">[ The Joy Of Smalltalk ]</a> Ivan
    Tomek (September 2000). 700 pages</p>
    Ivan wrote this book and he gave it to the community. It contains a lot of useful material. 
    Thanks again ivan and continue to write good books. 
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  
  
   <!--<tr>
    <td width="45%"><img src="FreeBooks/SmalltalkObjectAndDesign/SmalltalkObjectAndDesign.jpg" width=100></td>
    <td width="55%">
      <p><a href="http://books.iuniverse.com/viewbooks.asp?isbn=1583484906&page=fm1">Smalltalk,objects and design</a>
	  Liu, iUniverse books</p>
      
	  </font>
    </td>
  </tr>-->
  
  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/BitsOfHistory/BitsOfHistory.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/BitsOfHistory/"> [ Smalltalk-80, Bits of History, Words of Advice] </a> By Glen Krasner, Editor
ISBN 0-201-11669-3. 344 pp. 1983</p>
      This book is for collectors. Thanks Glenn.
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/BlueBook/blueBook.jpg" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/BlueBook/">[ Smalltalk-80: The Language and its Implementation ]</a>
	By Adele Goldberg and DavidRobson; 		Xerox Palo Alto Research Center
	ISBN 0-201-11371-6. 344 pp. 1983</p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/TheInteractiveProgrammingEnv/TheInteractiveProgrammingEnv.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/TheInteractiveProgrammingEnv/TheInteractiveProgrammingEnv.pdf">[ Smalltalk-80, The Interactive Programming Environment ]</a> By Adele Goldberg 
ISBN  0201113724. 560 pp. 1983</p> This book is for collectors. Thanks Adele. Thanks Don for the OCR!
    </td>
  </tr>
  
 <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/CollectiveNBlueBook/small-bluebook-cover.jpg" width="100"></td>
    <td>
    <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/CollectiveNBlueBook/">[ DRAFTS of Squeak, Open Personal Computing and Multimedia ]</a> Mirror of <a href="http://coweb.cc.gatech.edu/squeakbook/">http://coweb.cc.gatech.edu/squeakbook/</a> Edited by Mark Guzdial and Kim Rose. Prentice-Hall 2000.  It's available from Prentice-Hall.  </p>
    <br>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  
   <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/GuzdialBookDrafts/mark1.jpg" width="100"></td>
    <td>
     <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/GuzdialBookDrafts/">[ DRAFS of Squeak: Open Personal Computing for Multimedia ]</a>
	 taken from <a href="http://www.cc.gatech.edu/~mark.guzdial/drafts/">http://www.cc.gatech.edu/~mark.guzdial/drafts/</a> 
	 Mark Guzdial, Prentice-Hall 2000. It's available from Prentice-Hall. </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Syntax/BuchLogo.png" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p> <a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Syntax/Syntax.zip">[ (In German) Syntaxbasierte
      Programmierwerkzeuge ]</a> L. Schmitz, B.G. Teubner Stuttgart 1995.  
        1996.</p>
      <p>This book presents compilation techniques in german.
	 Lothar Schmitz is still developing a free visual compiler-compiler
	 (SIC and JACCIE).  <!-- <a
	 href="http://ist.unibw-muenchen.de/Research/Tools/SIC">http://ist.unibw-muenchen.de/Research/Tools/SIC</a> 
<a href="http://ist.unibw-muenchen.de/Research/Tools/JACCIE">http://ist.unibw-muenchen.de/Research/Tools/JACCIE</a> 
-->

</p>
    </td>
  </tr>

  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/SmalltalkDE/emptyCover.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p> <a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/SmalltalkDE/smalltalkBuch.pdf">[ (In German) Smalltalk
      Einfuehrung in die objekt-orientierte Programmierung ]</a> Peter P. Bothner, Wolf-Michael Kaehler 1999.  
        1996.</p>
      <p>This book presents object-oriented programming in german with VisualWorks.  
<!-- <a href="http://e-books.zfn.uni-bremen.de/e-book-SMALLTALK.html</a>  
-->

</p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/emptyCover.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Swedish/">[  (In Swedish) Objektorienterad programmering i Smalltalk ]</a>
	  Bjoern Eiderbaeck, Per Haegglund, and Olle Baelter</p>
      <br>Thanks Bjoern Eiderbaeck.
	  
    </td>
  </tr>
  
  <tr>
    <td><img src="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Programando/Programando.gif" width="100"></td>
    <td>
      <p><a href="http://sdmeta.gforge.inria.fr/FreeBooks/Programando/ProgramandoConSmalltalk-BORRADORFINAL07-Febrero-2006.pdf">[ (In Spanish) Programando con Smalltalk ]</a>
	  Diego Gomez Deck</p>
      <br>Thanks Diego. This book is distributed under the Creative Commons license.
	  
    </td>
  </tr>
  
</tbody></div><p>
 I added some other material because they illustrate the philosophy behind Smalltalk.

 </p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://stephane.ducasse.free.fr/FreeBooks.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24241561</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 04:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Debian Janitor: 60k Lintian Issues Automatically Fixed]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 145 | Comments 20 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24241549">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
August 21, 2020 | https://www.jelmer.uk/janitor-update-3.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jelmer.uk/janitor-update-3.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="layout">
    <div>
        <div>
            <section>
                
            </section>
            <p>The <a href="https://jelmer.uk/debian-janitor.html">Debian Janitor</a> is an automated
system that commits fixes for (minor) issues in Debian packages that can be
fixed by software. It gradually started proposing merges in early
December. The first set of changes sent out ran <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/jelmer/lintian-brush">lintian-brush</a> on sid packages maintained in
Git. This post is part of <a href="https://jelmer.uk/tag/janitor-update.html">a series</a> about the progress of the
Janitor.</p>
<div id="scheduling-lintian-fixes">
<h2>Scheduling Lintian Fixes</h2>
<p>To determine which packages to process, the  <a href="https://janitor.debian.net/">Janitor</a>  looks at the import of  <a href="https://lintian.debian.org/">lintian</a>  output across the archive that is available
in  <a href="https://wiki.debian.org/UltimateDebianDatabase/">UDD</a> <a href="#f1" id="id1">[1]</a>. It
will prioritize those packages with the most and more severe issues that it has
fixers for.</p>
<p>Once a package is selected, it will clone the packaging repository and run
<a href="https://manpages.debian.org/testing/lintian-brush/lintian-brush.1.en.html">lintian-brush</a>
on it.  Lintian-brush provides a framework for applying a set of “fixers” to a
package. It will run each of a set of “fixers” in a pristine version of the
repository, and handles most of the heavy lifting.</p>
</div>
<div id="the-inner-workings-of-a-fixer">
<h2>The Inner Workings of a Fixer</h2>
<p>Each fixer is just an executable which gets run in a clean
checkout of the package, and can make changes there. Most
of the fixers are written in Python or shell, but they
can be in any language.</p>
<p>The contract for fixers is pretty simple:</p>
<ul>
<li>If the fixer exits with non-zero, the changes are reverted and fixer is
considered to have failed</li>
<li>If exits with zero and made changes, then it should write a summary of its
changes to standard out</li>
</ul>
<p>If a fixer is uncertain about the changes it has made, it should report so on
standard output using a pseudo-header.  By default, lintian-brush will discard
any changes with uncertainty but if you are running it locally you can still
apply them by specifying <tt><span>--uncertain</span></tt>.</p>
<p>The summary message on standard out will be used for the commit message and
(possibly) the changelog message, if the package doesn’t use gbp dch.</p>
</div>
<div id="example-fixer">
<h2>Example Fixer</h2>
<p>Let’s look at an example. The package priority “extra” is deprecated since
Debian Policy 4.0.1 (released August 2 017) – see
<a href="https://www.debian.org/doc/debian-policy/ch-archive.html#priorities">Policy 2.5 "Priorities"</a>.
Instead, most packages should use the “optional” priority.</p>
<p>Lintian will warn when a package uses the deprecated “extra” value for the
“Priority”  - the associated tag is
<a href="https://lintian.debian.org/tags/priority-extra-is-replaced-by-priority-optional.html">priority-extra-is-replaced-by-priority-optional</a>.
Lintian-brush has a fixer script that can automatically replace “extra” with
“optional”.</p>
<p>On systems that have lintian-brush installed, the source for the fixer lives in
<a href="https://salsa.debian.org/jelmer/lintian-brush/-/blob/master/fixers/priority-extra-is-replaced-by-priority-optional.py">/usr/share/lintian-brush/fixers/priority-extra-is-replaced-by-priority-optional.py</a>,
but here is a copy of it for reference:</p>
<table><tbody><tr><td><div><pre> 1
 2
 3
 4
 5
 6
 7
 8
 9
10
11
12
13</pre></div></td><td><div><pre><span></span><span>#!/usr/bin/python3</span>

<span>from</span> <span>debmutate.control</span> <span>import</span> <span>ControlEditor</span>
<span>from</span> <span>lintian_brush.fixer</span> <span>import</span> <span>report_result</span><span>,</span> <span>fixed_lintian_tag</span>

<span>with</span> <span>ControlEditor</span><span>()</span> <span>as</span> <span>updater</span><span>:</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>para</span> <span>in</span> <span>updater</span><span>.</span><span>paragraphs</span><span>:</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>para</span><span>.</span><span>get</span><span>(</span><span>"Priority"</span><span>)</span> <span>==</span> <span>"extra"</span><span>:</span>
            <span>para</span><span>[</span><span>"Priority"</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>"optional"</span>
            <span>fixed_lintian_tag</span><span>(</span>
                <span>para</span><span>,</span> <span>'priority-extra-is-replaced-by-priority-optional'</span><span>)</span>

<span>report_result</span><span>(</span><span>"Change priority extra to priority optional."</span><span>)</span>
</pre></div>
</td></tr></tbody></table><p>This fixer is written in Python and uses the  <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/jelmer/debmutate">debmutate</a>  library to easily modify
control files while preserving formatting — or back out if it is not possible
to preserve formatting.</p>
<p>All the current fixers come with tests, e.g. for this particular fixer the
tests can be found here:
<a href="https://salsa.debian.org/jelmer/lintian-brush/-/tree/master/tests/priority-extra-is-replaced-by-priority-optional">https://salsa.debian.org/jelmer/lintian-brush/-/tree/master/tests/priority-extra-is-replaced-by-priority-optional</a>.</p>
<p>For more details on writing new fixers, see the  <a href="https://salsa.debian.org/jelmer/lintian-brush#writing-new-fixers">README</a>  for
lintian-brush.</p>
<p>For more details on debugging them, see the  <a href="https://manpages.debian.org/unstable/lintian-brush/lintian-brush.1.en.html">manual page</a>.</p>
</div>


            

            

            
            <p><a href="#">Go Top</a></p>        </div>
    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jelmer.uk/janitor-update-3.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24241549</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 04:30:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How NAT Traversal Works]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 148 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24241105">thread link</a>) | @signa11
<br/>
August 21, 2020 | https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
<p>We covered a lot of ground in our post about <a href="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-tailscale-works/"><em>How Tailscale
Works</em></a>.  However, we glossed over how we can get through NATs
(Network Address Translators) and connect your devices directly to
each other, no matter what’s standing between them. Let’s talk about
that now!</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-intro.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>Let’s start with a simple problem: establishing a peer-to-peer
connection between two machines. In Tailscale’s case, we want to set
up a WireGuard® tunnel, but that doesn’t really matter. The
techniques we use are widely applicable and the work of many people
over decades. For example, <a href="https://webrtc.org/">WebRTC</a> uses this bag of tricks to
send peer-to-peer audio, video and data between web browsers. VoIP
phones and some video games use similar techniques, though not always
successfully.</p>
<p>We’ll be discussing these techniques generically, using Tailscale and
others for examples where appropriate. Let’s say you’re making your
own protocol and that you want NAT traversal. You need two things.</p>
<p>First, the protocol should be based on UDP. You <em>can</em> do NAT traversal
with TCP, but it adds another layer of complexity to an already quite
complex problem, and may even require kernel customizations depending
on how deep you want to go. We’re going to focus on UDP for the rest
of this article.</p>
<p>If you’re reaching for TCP because you want a stream-oriented
connection when the NAT traversal is done, consider using QUIC
instead. It builds on top of UDP, so we can focus on UDP for NAT
traversal and still have a nice stream protocol at the end.</p>
<p>Second, you need direct control over the network socket that’s sending
and receiving network packets. As a rule, you can’t take an existing
network library and make it traverse NATs, because you have to send
and receive extra packets that aren’t part of the “main” protocol
you’re trying to speak. Some protocols tightly integrate the NAT
traversal with the rest (e.g. WebRTC). But if you’re building your
own, it’s helpful to think of NAT traversal as a separate entity that
shares a socket with your main protocol. Both run in parallel, one
enabling the other.</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-deep-integration.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>Direct socket access may be tough depending on your situation. One
workaround is to run a local proxy. Your protocol speaks to this
proxy, and the proxy does both NAT traversal and relaying of your
packets to the peer. This layer of indirection lets you benefit from
NAT traversal without altering your original program.</p>
<p>With prerequisites out of the way, let’s go through NAT traversal from
first principles. Our goal is to get UDP packets flowing
bidirectionally between two devices, so that our other protocol
(WireGuard, QUIC, WebRTC, …) can do something cool. There are two
obstacles to having this Just Work: stateful firewalls and NAT
devices.</p>
<h3 id="figuring-out-firewalls">Figuring out firewalls</h3>
<p>Stateful firewalls are the simpler of our two problems. In fact, most
NAT devices include a stateful firewall, so we need to solve this
subset before we can tackle NATs.</p>
<p>There are many incarnations to consider. Some you might recognize are
the Windows Defender firewall, Ubuntu’s ufw (using iptables/nftables),
BSD’s pf (also used by macOS) and AWS’s Security Groups. They’re all
very configurable, but the most common configuration allows all
“outbound” connections and blocks all “inbound” connections. There
might be a few handpicked exceptions, such as allowing inbound SSH.</p>
<p>But connections and “direction” are a figment of the protocol
designer’s imagination. On the wire, every connection ends up being
bidirectional; it’s all individual packets flying back and forth. How
does the firewall know what’s inbound and what’s outbound?</p>
<p>That’s where the stateful part comes in. Stateful firewalls remember
what packets they’ve seen in the past and can use that knowledge when
deciding what to do with new packets that show up.</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-firewalls-1a.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>For UDP, the rule is very simple: the firewall allows an inbound UDP
packet if it previously saw a matching outbound packet. For example,
if our laptop firewall sees a UDP packet leaving the laptop from
<code>2.2.2.2:1234</code> to <code>7.7.7.7:5678</code>, it’ll make a note that incoming
packets from <code>7.7.7.7:5678</code> to <code>2.2.2.2:1234</code> are also fine. The
trusted side of the world clearly intended to communicate with
<code>7.7.7.7:5678</code>, so we should let them talk back.</p>
<p>(As an aside, some <em>very</em> relaxed firewalls might allow traffic from
anywhere back to <code>2.2.2.2:1234</code> once <code>2.2.2.2:1234</code> has communicated
with anyone. Such firewalls make our traversal job easier, but are
increasingly rare.)</p>
<h4 id="firewall-face-off">Firewall face-off</h4>
<p>This rule for UDP traffic is only a minor problem for us, as long as
all the firewalls on the path are “facing” the same way. That’s
usually the case when you’re communicating with a server on the
internet. Our only constraint is that the machine that’s <em>behind</em> the
firewall(s) must be the one initiating all connections. Nothing can
talk to it, unless it talks first.</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-firewalls-2.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>This is fine, but not very interesting: we’ve reinvented client/server
communication, where the server makes itself easily reachable to
clients. In the VPN world, this leads to a hub-and-spoke topology: the
hub has no firewalls blocking access to it and the firewalled spokes
connect to the hub.</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-firewalls-3.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>The problems start when two of our “clients” want to talk
directly. Now the firewalls are facing each other. According to the
rule we established above, this means both sides must go first, but
also that neither can go first, because the other side has to go
first!</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-firewalls-4.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>How do we get around this? One way would be to require users to
reconfigure one or both of the firewalls to “open a port” and allow
the other machine’s traffic. This is not very user friendly. It also
doesn’t scale to mesh networks like Tailscale, in which we expect the
peers to be moving around the internet with some regularity. And, of
course, in many cases you don’t have control over the firewalls: you
can’t reconfigure the router in your favorite coffee shop, or at the
airport. (At least, hopefully not!)</p>
<p>We need another option. One that doesn’t involve reconfiguring
firewalls.</p>
<h4 id="finessing-finicky-firewalls">Finessing finicky firewalls</h4>
<p>The trick is to carefully read the rule we established for our
stateful firewalls. For UDP, the rule is: <strong>packets must flow out
before packets can flow back in.</strong></p>
<p>However, nothing says the packets must be <em>related</em> to each other
beyond the IPs and ports lining up correctly. As long as <em>some</em> packet
flowed outwards with the right source and destination, any packet that
<em>looks like</em> a response will be allowed back in, even if the other
side never received your packet!</p>
<p>So, to traverse these multiple stateful firewalls, we need to share
some information to get underway: the peers have to know in advance
the <code>ip:port</code> their counterpart is using. One approach is to
statically configure each peer by hand, but this approach doesn’t
scale very far. To move beyond that, we built a <a href="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-tailscale-works/#the-control-plane-key-exchange-and-coordination">coordination
server</a> to keep the <code>ip:port</code> information synchronized in a
flexible, secure manner.</p>
<p>Then, the peers start sending UDP packets to each other. They must
expect some of these packets to get lost, so they can’t carry any
precious information unless you’re prepared to retransmit them. This
is generally true of UDP, but especially true here. We’re <em>going</em> to
lose some packets in this process.</p>
<p>Our laptop and workstation are now listening on fixed ports, so that
they both know exactly what <code>ip:port</code> to talk to. Let’s take a look at
what happens.</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-firewalls-5a.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>The laptop’s first packet, from <code>2.2.2.2:1234</code> to <code>7.7.7.7:5678</code>, goes
through the Windows Defender firewall and out to the internet. The
corporate firewall on the other end blocks the packet, since it has no
record of <code>7.7.7.7:5678</code> ever talking to <code>2.2.2.2:1234</code>. However,
Windows Defender now remembers that it should expect and allow
responses from <code>7.7.7.7:5678</code> to <code>2.2.2.2:1234</code>.</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-firewalls-5b.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>Next, the workstation’s first packet from <code>7.7.7.7:5678</code> to
<code>2.2.2.2:1234</code> goes through the corporate firewall and across the
internet. When it arrives at the laptop, Windows Defender thinks “ah,
a response to that outbound request I saw”, and lets the packet
through! Additionally, the corporate firewall now remembers that it
should expect responses from <code>2.2.2.2:1234</code> to <code>7.7.7.7:5678</code>, and
that those packets are also okay.</p>
<p>Encouraged by the receipt of a packet from the workstation, the laptop
sends another packet back. It goes through the Windows Defender
firewall, through the corporate firewall (because it’s a “response” to
a previously sent packet), and arrives at the workstation.</p>
<figure>
    
        <img src="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/nat-firewalls-5c.png">
    
    
</figure>

<p>Success! We’ve established two-way communication through a pair of
firewalls that, at first glance, would have prevented it.</p>
<h4 id="creative-connectivity-caveats">Creative connectivity caveats</h4>
<p>It’s not always so easy. We’re relying on some indirect influence over
third-party systems, which requires careful handling. What do we need
to keep in mind when managing firewall-traversing connections?</p>
<p>Both endpoints must attempt communication at roughly the same time, so
that all the intermediate firewalls open up while both peers are still
around. One approach is to have the peers retry continuously, but this
is wasteful. Wouldn’t it be better if both peers knew to start
establishing a connection at the same time?</p>
<p>This may sound a little recursive: to communicate, first you need to
be able to communicate. However, this preexisting “side channel”
doesn’t need to be very fancy: it can have a few seconds of latency,
and only needs to deliver a few thousand bytes in total, so a tiny VM
can easily be a matchmaker for thousands of machines.</p>
<p>In the distant past, I used XMPP chat messages as the side channel,
with great results. As another example, WebRTC requires you to come up
with your own “signalling channel” (a name that reveals WebRTC’s IP
telephony ancestry), and plug it into the WebRTC APIs. In Tailscale,
our coordination server and fleet of DERP (Detour Encrypted Routing
Protocol) servers act as …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/">https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24241105</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 02:36:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Gentle Introduction to Zero-Knowledge Proofs with Hands-On Examples]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 28 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24240915">thread link</a>) | @mariorz
<br/>
August 21, 2020 | https://dochdoch.gitlab.io/snark_intro/snark_intro_front/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dochdoch.gitlab.io/snark_intro/snark_intro_front/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dochdoch.gitlab.io/snark_intro/snark_intro_front/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24240915</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 01:53:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bread, How Did They Make It? Part IV: Markets, Merchants and the Tax Man]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 110 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24240677">thread link</a>) | @Kednicma
<br/>
August 21, 2020 | https://acoup.blog/2020/08/21/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iv-markets-and-non-farmers/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://acoup.blog/2020/08/21/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iv-markets-and-non-farmers/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>As the fourth and final part (<a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/24/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-farmers/">I</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/31/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-ii-big-farms/">II</a>, <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/08/06/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iii-actually-farming/">III</a>) of our look at the basic structure of food production in the pre-modern world (particularly farming grain to make bread), this week we’re going to look at how at least some of the delicious food we made in the last post might make its way into the hands of people who are <em>not</em> <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/24/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-i-farmers/">farmers </a>or even<a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/07/31/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-ii-big-farms/"> farm owners</a>.</p>



<p>In the previous three posts, I have mostly just used the magic word ‘markets’ to describe how the food produced in the countryside gets to the cities and people who are not farmers.  As we’ll see in this post, that is a bit of an oversimplifying fib, both in that the phrase ‘markets’ covers a <em>lot </em>of complexity, but also (as we’ll see) some of the major drivers of moving that food from the countryside into towns doesn’t involve money <em>or</em> market interactions.  That said, we’re going to <em>start</em> with market transactions, because while they are actually the minority-type in many of these societies, they are more readily familiar and understandable, I suspect, to modern readers.  Then we’ll move to <em>extraction</em> as the other category.</p>



<p>Speaking of extraction, as always, if you like what you are reading here, you can support me on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/user?u=20122096">Patreo</a>n. And if you want updates whenever a new post appears, you can click the button below for email updates or follow me on twitter (@BretDevereaux) for updates as to new posts, as well as my occasional ancient history, foreign policy or pop-culture thoughts.</p>






<h2>Point of Sale</h2>



<p>I want to start by leaning on (with small modifications for clarity) Paul Erdkamp’s taxonomy of the various options by which food might get into the stream of commerce.  A small farmer might sell their grain (I) directly to city-dwellers, (II) indirectly, via urban middlemen and grain merchants, either in the market or (III) ‘at the gate’ (meaning selling to merchants who come out to the farm in order to buy; the difference being who transports the food to the city), (IV) to itinerant traders at periodic rural markets or (V) to other local small farmers.  As we’ll see, <em>large </em>landholders have a <em>somewhat</em> larger range of options within this taxonomy, but the fundamentals are the same.</p>



<p>While all of these sale methods certainly happened, in every society I have looked at, Option I – selling directly to city-dwellers – is fairly rare for grains and other bulk agricultural goods.  Market <em>gardeners</em>, selling fruits, vegetables (and sometimes flowers) often do sell this way, maintaining a high-intensity garden near town and a shop or stall in the town market.  Likewise, while Option V – small-scale trade between farmers – absolutely happens, it is typically non-monetary: the banqueting of neighbors discussed in the first post.  Where it is monetary, it is typically quite small scale and very short distance.  By and large, small and mid-sized farmers hadn’t the time, expertise or infrastructure to sell their goods directly.  They needed to be farming, not manning a market stall or trying to figure out how to store their goods close to the point of sale.  And of course large landowners, being rich, aren’t going to stand in the market square either (and in many cases don’t want their obvious representative doing so either,  see below).  So while I and V happen, they’re not too common or too large a portion of total trade and we may lay them aside for this discussion.</p>



<p>That leaves Options II, III and IV, all of which involve selling grain to a middle-man merchant of some sort.  The main difference is the location of sale (in town, at the gate, or at periodic rural markets).  Outside of large cities and major ports, markets were likely to be <em>periodic</em>, occurring only on certain days (typically around once per week).  In Roman Italy, these were the <em>nundinae</em> (‘ninth days,’ although it was an 8-day cycle as the Romans count inclusively); the <em>nundinae</em> were minor festivals, days of rest and merrymaking, but they were also the days when the rural markets would be open – the rest-day from agricultural labor enabled farmers to head into local towns to buy or sell whatever they needed (interestingly, at Rome, the <em>nundinae</em> were <em>dies nefasti</em> – state business couldn’t generally be conducted on them – so poor farmers hoping to use their day off to participate politically were out of luck).  Similar periodic markets are common in the Middle Ages (and even today; most ‘farmer’s markets’ in the United States are periodic, <a href="http://www.carrborofarmersmarket.com/">including my town’s</a>).  The periodic nature of these markets is an adaptation to agricultural rhythms; for a market to function there need to be a lot of people together all at once and the small towns that dotted the countryside simply didn’t have the density to do that all of the time.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="4249" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg" data-orig-size="2325,663" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=2048 2048w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/fresco_from_the_house_of_julia_felix_pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_forum_market.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merchant#/media/File:Fresco_from_the_House_of_Julia_Felix,_Pompeii_depicting_scenes_from_the_Forum_market.JPG">Via Wikipedia</a>, a fresco showing market activity, with merchants showing off wares of fabric (left) and goods in pots (center) from the House of Julia Felix at Pompeii, first century CE.  Please note: the importance of pottery in modern archaeology has given many students and the general public the idea that the ancients were always shipping pots around for sale, as if there was a vast market in pottery.  <strong>Generally, people were buying what was in the pot, not the pot itself</strong>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>But as noted, our farmers are unlikely to be selling their grain directly to customers.  Instead, they are likely to be using some sort of middle-man merchant, which brings us to:</p>



<h2>Merchants!</h2>



<p>Merchants are a bit of a break from the people we have so far discussed in that they, by definition, live in the realm of the <em>market</em> (in the economic sense, although often also in a physical sense).  As we’ve seen so much of the world of our farmers and even our millers and bakers was governed by <em>non-market</em> interactions: horizontal and vertical social ties that carried expectations that weren’t quite transactional and certainly not monetized.  By contrast, merchants work with transactions and tend to be the <em>first</em> group in any society to attempt to monetize their operations once money becomes available.  I find students are often quick to feel identity with the merchant class, because these folks are more likely to travel, more likely to use money, more likely to employ or be employed in wage-labor; they feel more like modern people.</p>



<p>It thus tends to come as something of a surprise that with <em>stunning</em> consistency, <strong>the merchant class tended to be at best cordially disliked and at worst <em>despised</em> by the broader community</strong> (although not typically to the point of suffering legal disability, as did some other jobs; see S. Bond, <em>Trade and Taboo: Disreputable Professions in the Roman Mediterranean</em> (2016) for this in Rome).  This often strikes students as strange, both because we tend to think rather better of our own modern merchants but also because the image they have of the merchant class certainly looks elite.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="4257" data-permalink="https://acoup.blog/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse/" data-orig-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg" data-orig-size="1134,766" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg?w=1024" src="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg?w=150 150w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg?w=300 300w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg?w=768 768w, https://acoupdotblog.files.wordpress.com/2020/08/britlibaddms35166apocalypseunkfolio3sealblackhorse.jpg 1134w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merchant#/media/File:BritLibAddMS35166ApocalypseUnkFolio3SealBlackHorse.jpg">Via Wikipedia</a>, a manuscript illustration showing the Horseman of Famine depicted as a grain merchant (from Revalations 6:5-6), holding the scales he would use to measure out grain.</figcaption></figure>



<p>For the farmers who need to sell their crops (for reasons we will get to in a moment) and purchase the things they need that they cannot produce, the merchant feels like an adversary: always pushing his prices to his best advantage.  We expect this, but remember that our pre-modern farmers are just <em>not that exposed to market interactions</em>; most of their relationships are reciprocal, not transactional – the horizontal relationships we discussed before.  The merchant’s ‘money-grubbing’ feels like a betrayal of trust in a society where you banquet your neighbors in the good years so they’ll help you in the bad years.  <strong>The necessary function of a merchant is to transgress the ‘rules’ of village interactions which – and this <em>resounds</em> from the sources – the farmers tend to understand as being ‘cheated.’</strong></p>



<p>At the same time, <strong>while most merchant types are humble, the high-risk and potentially high-reward involved in trade meant that <em>some</em> merchants </strong>(again, a small number) <strong>could become <em>very</em> rich</strong>.  That, as you might imagine, <strong>did not go over well for the traditionally wealthy in these societies</strong>, the large landholders.  Again, the values here often strike modern readers as topsy-turvy compared to our own, but to the elite large landholders (who dominate the literary and political culture of their societies), the <em>morally correct</em> way to earn great wealth is to inherit it (or capture it in war).  The <em>morally correct</em> way to hold that wealth is with large landed estates.  Anything else is <em>morally</em> suspect, and so the idea that a successful merchant could – by a process that again, strikes the large landholder, just like the small farmer, as ‘cheating’ – leap-frog the social pyramid and skip to the top, without putting in the work at either having distinguished wealthy ancestors <em>or</em> tremendous military success was an open insult to elite values.  Often laws were put in place to limit the ability of wealthy non-aristocrats (likely merchants or successful artisans) from displaying their wealth (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sumptuary_law">sumptuary laws</a>) so as to keep them from competing with the aristocrats; at Rome, senators were forbidden from owning ships with much the same logic (Roman senators being clever, they still invested in trade through proxies while at the same time disapproving of the activity in public politics).</p>



<p>Such disdain appears, with varying justification, in the sources of every pre-modern agrarian society I’ve studied, to one degree or another.  One commonplace of Greek and Roman thinking – despite these being very active, maritime societies – was that the first production of ships and the first sailing was in some essential way a profanation of the divine realm of the sea, a space humans ought not have ever ventured into – and certainly not for anything as mean as profit (e.g. Euripides, <em>Medea</em> 1-6; Catullus. 64.1-20; Valerius Flaccus, <em>Argonautica</em> 627-632; Seneca, <em>Medea</em> 1-12; 301-379, <em>inter alia</em> – thanks to my old grad school pals <a href="https://www.usf.edu/arts-sciences/departments/world-languages/about-us/hedrick.aspx">Buddy Hedrick</a> and <a href="http://gdrsd.org/gdrhs/faculty/michael-hoffman/">Michael Hoffman </a>for …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://acoup.blog/2020/08/21/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iv-markets-and-non-farmers/">https://acoup.blog/2020/08/21/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iv-markets-and-non-farmers/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://acoup.blog/2020/08/21/collections-bread-how-did-they-make-it-part-iv-markets-and-non-farmers/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24240677</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 01:04:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
