<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 12:20:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 12:20:18 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: I built a desktop radiation monitor with Raspberry Pi, brass and wood]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 98 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23756964">thread link</a>) | @chrisys
<br/>
July 7, 2020 | https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
            <p>I was always a fan of the steampunk style, and having also had experience building steam engines in the past, there was only one real direction this project could go. Once I had my radiation detector kit hooked up to my Raspberry Pi running InfluxDB and Grafana, I found myself woodworking, machining, and fabricobbling an enclosure out of mahogany, brass, copper, toggle switches and, because it just had to be done, nixie tubes.</p>

<p>Read the story of the almost year-long journey (<em>cough</em> some other stuff cropped up…) I went on to make my steampunk vision a reality below, and if you want to get up and running quickly, find out how to <a href="https://www.balena.io/blog/build-a-simple-radiation-monitor-using-a-raspberry-pi-influxdb-and-grafana/">build your own simple version right here</a>!</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/geiger-main.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(56)">  
</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="500" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lEL_XkN69n8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<hr>

<h2 id="contents">Contents</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="#intro">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#inspiration">Inspiration &amp; Design</a></li>
<li><a href="#build">The build</a>
<ul><li><a href="#panel">The front panel</a></li>
<li><a href="#wood">Working with wood</a></li>
<li><a href="#brass">Top brass</a></li>
<li><a href="#dekatrons">Imitation Dekatrons</a></li>
<li><a href="#fasteners">Fussy about fasteners</a></li>
<li><a href="#pi">Plumbing in a Pi project</a></li>
<li><a href="#nixie">Nixie tubes</a></li>
<li><a href="#counter">Electrifying a mechanical counter</a></li>
<li><a href="#electronics">Electronics</a></li>
<li><a href="#geiger">Relocating the Geiger tube</a></li></ul></li>
<li><a href="#final">Final assembly</a></li>
<li><a href="#software">Programming and software</a></li>
<li><a href="#end">You have come to the end of your journey</a></li>
</ul>

<hr>

<h2 id="introductionspanidintrospan">Introduction <span id="intro"></span></h2>

<p>Low cost radiation monitors and Geiger counter kits have been available online for around $30-50US/£25-45 for a while, but standing alone they don’t do much other than make the recognizable “clicking” sound we all know from movies and TV. I decided to up the ante by connecting one to a Raspberry Pi, storing the data with InfluxDB, and showing the readings with a Grafana dashboard.</p>



<p>I updated the tech, gave it a web interface, added remote management, and built a custom mahogany housing with brass and copper fittings to show everything off, because it’s important to look suitably <em>hip</em> when sitting on the desk next to your <a href="https://www.balena.io/blog/build-a-raspberry-pi-powered-train-station-oled-sign-for-your-desk/">train sign</a>… right?</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/header.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(58)">  
</p>

<p>Anyway, I’m gonna show what I built to hopefully provide some inspiration, then show you how to get up and running with a simpler version of the project that anyone can build at home without any special tools. Let’s hit this.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="inspirationdesignspanidinspirationspan">Inspiration &amp; design <span id="inspiration"></span></h2>

<p>I’ve always found the idea of radiation fascinating; how there are invisible particles moving around at incredibly high speeds, crashing into things and flipping bits all around us. Due to my fascination, it doesn’t take a lot to capture my interest when it comes to this field.</p>

<p>One day last year I was reminiscing over the <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-44606771">now defunct</a> UK-based electronics retailer Maplin, and how they sold all sorts of interesting kits for the aspiring engineer. This led me to <a href="https://www.richardmudhar.com/blog/2019/09/maplin-geiger-counter/">Richard Mudhar’s blog</a> where he tells the story of the <em>Maplin Geiger Counter</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/mudhar-example.png" alt="An excerpt and image from Richard Mudhar's post"></p>

<figure>  
The original Maplin Geiger Counter. Perhaps some of the design cues are visible here?! (Credit: <a href="https://www.richardmudhar.com/blog/2019/09/maplin-geiger-counter/">Richard Mudhar</a>)  
</figure>

<p>The kit that Richard has built above features both an electromechanical counter on the left, and two rings of LEDs reminiscent of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dekatron">dekatron tubes</a> on the right. This display has the neat design feature that as the rate of count increases, the display becomes more noticeable.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/dekatron.gif" alt=""></p>

<figure>  
The spinning light effect of the Dekatron is something I wanted to replicate. By Hellbus - Own work, CC BY-SA 3.0, <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=4741470">https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=4741470</a>.  
</figure>

<p>I liked the idea of combining the modern technology on the inside (Raspberry Pi, Grafana, etc.) with the timeless look of brass, copper, toggle switches, dark hardwood, and glass on the outside. The idea was now to build something that looked old and had that distinctive steampunk style, but was up to date and Internet-connected.</p>

<p>In addition to the total absolute count like the old Maplin counter, I wanted to offer a live display of the counts per minute (CPM) reading, and what better way to do this than with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nixie_tube">Nixie tubes</a>, to get that nice warm orange glow and keep things looking cosy.</p>

<p>I started scribbling down ideas and thoughts of materials I wanted to use alongside shopping lists for parts, and possible designs for the case.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/notes.jpg" alt="Original shop notes!"></p>

<figure>  
Notes don’t survive well in a machine shop, but these are what’s left of my original sketches.  
</figure>

<p>This process was very much led by an image I had in my mind about how the thing should look and feel and so I just had to make it real… somehow.</p>

<hr>

<h2 id="thebuildspanidbuildspan">The build <span id="build"></span></h2>

<p>With some thoughts and ideas scribbled down it was time to get started. As this is for the most part going to be a bespoke, hand-built item, and made up as I go along, it’s not necessary to put everything in CAD. There are of course some core items that exist already and cannot change size; the Raspberry Pi and radiation detector board, for example. These are off-the-shelf parts that have to fit in the box no matter what, and start to dictate the size of the final unit.</p>

<p>Almost all other parts are completely hand made, machined and fabricated. This was necessitated by the desire to make everything authentic; I didn’t want to build things just for looks, I wanted any design choices made for aesthetic reasons to also be functional; by this I mean when I put 18 screws in something to make it look good, they are going to be 18 <em>real</em> screws that you have to take out to gain access!</p>

<p><strong>NOTE:</strong> Each of the build log images link to a separate gallery when clicked. You can look through the images that way if you prefer, or read on in full detail.</p>

<h3 id="thefrontpanelspanidpanelspan">The front panel <span id="panel"></span></h3>

<p>I started with the front panel of the housing, I knew I wanted two toggle switches; one for power and one for sound (to disable the clicking noise), along with 3 nixie tubes to display the CPM up to 999. Normal background radiation is in the range of about 25-75 CPM, so I figured if background radiation is above 999 CPM, we have bigger problems than worrying about enough digits on the counter.</p>



<p>The two front panel pieces are made from 6mm thick mild steel plate, cut to size with an angle grinder and then milled to dimension with the help of Bridget, the Bridgeport. Holes are then cut for the nixies and the toggle switches.</p>



<p>I manufactured labels for each by hand-punching lettering into 0.5mm thick brass sheet, polishing and fixing with M2 screws. The steel pieces are coated with a clear lacquer to prevent corrosion.</p>

<h3 id="workingwithwoodspanidwoodspan">Working with wood <span id="wood"></span></h3>

<p>Wood isn’t my favourite material to work with, I mean it just changes shape of its own accord! Who can work with that?! Anyhow, it’s very pretty, and so it was decided that the outer box should be made of hardwood. I started with a scrap piece of mahogany, cut it to halve the thickness on the bandsaw, and then set about planing and shaping the sides of the box to fit the dimensions of the Raspberry Pi (3A+) and the radiation detector.</p>



<p>The dimensions of the front panel along with the steel faceplates were planned out in Fusion 360 so that I could print a cutting and drilling template. This was taped onto the planed piece of mahogany, the holes for screws were drilled, and the openings for components cut out.</p>



<p>The pieces were cut at 45 degree angles to enable a mitre joint in each corner. The joints were reinforced with biscuits (mmm biscuits), and then the 4 sides were glued and clamped and allowed to cure overnight.</p>



<p>The top and bottom of the case are made from the same scrap mahogany, but planed a lot thinner - approximately 6mm, the same as the steel plate.</p>

<h3 id="topbrassspanidbrassspan">Top brass <span id="brass"></span></h3>

<p>I had the idea that it would look good to hold the box together with a totally unnecessary amount of screws, 36 to be exact; 18 on top and 18 on the bottom. To prevent the screws damaging the wood surface and to add some extra detail to the top of the case I decided to make a brass plate that the screws all go through to clamp the top cover down.</p>



<p>Some pieces of 2mm brass strip were cut, mitred on the corners and soldered together. Once soldered, sanded and polished, the joints are barely visible.</p>



<p>Holes for screws were then drilled, and the brass plate used to secure the oversize lid to the box whilst it was sanded to size on a drum sander. I later learned that using a drum sander for this was a mistake as it marked the sides of the box, but you live and learn!</p>

<div>  
    <p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/top-brass-7.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(22)"></p><figure>  
Finished case and lid woodwork with brass frame temporarily fitted  
</figure>

</div>

<h3 id="imitationdekatronsspaniddekatronsspan">Imitation Dekatrons <span id="dekatrons"></span></h3>

<p>My attempt at imitating the Dekatron tube effect starts with a piece of 50mm stainless steel (or aluminium) bar. The bar is turned on a lathe down to 40mm, and to have a cavity for the electronics. The work is removed from the lathe and parted off on a bandsaw before being returned to the lathe to have a hole drilled in the rear for cabling to drive the LEDs.</p>



<p>The part is then put on the milling machine to have 10 holes drilled and M2 <del>taps snapped off in the holes</del> threaded ready to fasten the faceplate.</p>



<p>The brass faceplate is made from the same 0.5mm thick brass sheet as the labels from the faceplates. Each piece is drilled with 20 holes (10 for LEDs, 10 for fasteners), and then hand stamped with the numbering for each LED.</p>

<div>  
    <p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/dekatrons-7.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(29)"></p><figure>  
The wired LED faceplate ready to be screwed into the housing.  
</figure>  
</div>

<p>The LEDs are wired with a common ground and connected using a piece of recycled floppy disk drive ribbon cable. All the work is then carried out a second time for the ‘X10’ display. The eagle-eyed readers will notice that the second display is made from a different material than the first - this is due to the fact I snapped both a drill bit and a tap off in the M2 holes - working with stainless steel with these small tools is very difficult! I ended up making the second from aluminium, which machines like butter, in comparison.</p>



<p>Throughout the development of this project I found myself continually swapping fasteners and trying different combinations to see what looks best. The end result is a mix of M2 and M3 metric machine screws in both brass and stainless steel, cheese head and countersunk head, all slotted. You may notice that in earlier photos some of the parts were assembled with Allen-head cap screws but these were later swapped out. Ebay is usually a great place to get small quantities of fasteners of all different shapes and sizes.</p>

<div>  
    <p><img src="https://www.balena.io/blog/content/images/2020/07/screws.jpg" onclick="openModal();currentSlide(30)"></p><figure>  
A mix of fastener types used for this project - various M3 and M2 machine screws.  
</figure>  
</div>

<p>The wood screws used for the top and …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/">https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.balena.io/blog/show-tell-a-steampunk-desktop-background-radiation-monitor/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23756964</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 08:33:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Google offers free fabbing for 130nm open-source chips]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 298 | Comments 104 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23755693">thread link</a>) | @tomcam
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://fossi-foundation.org/2020/06/30/skywater-pdk | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fossi-foundation.org/2020/06/30/skywater-pdk">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Did you ever dream about creating your own chip?
I mean, a physical chip.
One which you can hold in your hand, and which does exactly what you’ve designed it to do?</p>

<p>Until today, there were two major road blocks: you had to get access to a process design kit (PDK) from a chip manufacturing house (a foundry), and you had to have enough money to actually pay for the manufacturing.
These times are over.
Today.</p>

<p>Today, in a FOSSi Dial-Up talk, Tim Ansell of Google announced <a href="https://github.com/google/skywater-pdk">SkyWater PDK</a>, the first manufacturable, open source <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Process_design_kit">process design kit</a>.
What differentiates this PDK from previous attempts is the fact that it is manufacturable: with this PDK, you can actually produce chips with the <a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/">SkyWater foundry</a> in the 130nm node.</p>

<p>That leaves you as chip designer only with one road block: money.
Manufacturing chips is expensive – even for more than a decade old nodes like the 130nm node, you need to spend at least a couple thousand dollars.</p>

<p>You know what?
Don’t worry – Google and efabless have got you covered!
They are providing <strong>completely free of cost</strong> chip manufacturing runs: one in November this year, and multiple more in 2021.
All open source chip designs qualify, no further strings attached!</p>

<p>Learn more about all of that by re-watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EczW2IWdnOM">Tim’s Dial-Up talk</a> or click through the <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vRtwZPc8ykkkgtUkHkoJZrP9jKOo3FYdKqbg-So0ic6_kx7ha1vHnxrWmuxWkTc9GfC8xl0TfEpMLwK/pub?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000">slides</a>.</p>

<p>This is certainly a dream come true for us at the FOSSi Foundation.
We helped the Free and Open Source Silicon community, our community, grow and tackle huge challenges over the years.
An open, manufacturable PDK was the main blocker in a fully open flow between RTL and a physical chip, and we’re extremely excited to see that blocker removed.</p>

<p>As always, removing one roadblock only highlights more challenges:
RAM, ROM and flash compilers, analog blocks, optimizations to various tools, and much, much more.
Now is the perfect time to get involved in the Free and Open Source Silicon ecosystem – or learn more about the accomplishments and challenges ahead of us.
A good starting point are the next Dial-Up talks.</p>

<p>Head over to the <a href="https://fossi-foundation.org/dial-up/">Dial-Up web site</a> for a listing of the upcoming talks on OpenROAD, cell design, OpenRAM, and Magic, an old, but surprisingly up-to-date tool!
To stay up-to-date with the latest developments in the FOSSi ecosystem <a href="https://librecores.us17.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=5d525b453672149a60c198960&amp;id=1241c8638b">subscribe to El Correo Libre</a>, our monthly newsletter bringing all the important news bits directly to your inbox (or <a href="https://medium.com/librecores">read it online</a>).</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EczW2IWdnOM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

  </div>

</article>

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fossi-foundation.org/2020/06/30/skywater-pdk</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23755693</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 04:26:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Faces of Microsoft (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23755238">thread link</a>) | @beefhash
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

		
			<figure data-blockname="pull_quote">
				<p>‘Why do we need more fonts?’ asked Bill Gates. ‘We’ve got a	serif, a sans, and a monospace font. Why do we need more?’...</p>
				
			</figure>
			
			<header data-blockname="article_title">

				
				<h2><a href="https://www.typemag.org/category/3">History of type</a></h2>
				

				

				<p>The people and the rich story of type at the first big tech company.</p>

			</header>
			
			
			
			<figure data-blockname="single_image">
				<a data-lightbox="type-mag-slideshow" data-title="Steven Shaiman, the first program manager for type at Microsoft. He’s been on his own since 2010, living in the Pacific Northwest and working on family enterprises with his wife and five children." href="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-05-Shaiman-Steve-47.jpg"><img data-src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-05-Shaiman-Steve-47.jpg" alt="" src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-05-Shaiman-Steve-47.jpg"></a>
				
				<figcaption>Steven Shaiman, the first program manager for type at Microsoft. He’s been on his own since 2010, living in the Pacific Northwest and working on family enterprises with his wife and five children.</figcaption>
			</figure>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-datetime.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>Gates was having an informal meeting with Steve Shaiman, a cheerful gnome of a man with a head of frizzy hair who was general manager of Microsoft’s hardware division, and with Raleigh Roark one of the two people who had started the division. They were talking about fonts and applications, especially Word.</p>

<p>Roark gave Gates his answer: For printers, basically. This was the era of desktop publishing and proliferating office applications, and users needed more than just the bitmapped system fonts on their computers to get their work done. Courier, Tms Rmn, and Helv were not going to be enough. </p>

<p>Bill Gates is known for asking hard questions, but also for accepting hard answers and acting on them. As soon as he got his answer, he pointed at Steve and told him: “Now you run type!”</p>

<p>That’s the way things worked at Microsoft in those days, says Shaiman: whoever knew the most about a subject tended to end up in charge of it. So he ended up starting Microsoft’s first fonts group. It was Spring, 1989.</p>
			</section>
			

			





			
			<section data-blockname="sub_heading_1">
				<h2>The conquest of TrueType</h2>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-phone.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>STEVE SHAIMAN was on a business trip to Atlanta with Nathan Myhrvold, Microsoft’s celebrated head of advanced technology, when they got an unexpected phone call. Myhrvold had with him a satellite phone—an early mobile phone, “which in those days,” as Shaiman put it, “meant something you’d carry in a suitcase.” The unexpected call was from Apple.</p>

<p>At that time, Adobe Systems dominated the digital font market, with its PostScript technology built into Apple’s LaserWriter printers, and with PostScript firmly established as the preferred format for high-quality fonts. Microsoft needed to find its own format and its own fonts if it didn’t want to be dependent on Adobe.</p>

<p>Like Microsoft, Apple was trying to find ways to license the PostScript language from Adobe, or to find an alternative. The Apple call was about font technology: Apple was developing its own font format, TrueType, as an alternative to PostScript, while Microsoft acquired a program called TrueImage, a potential PostScript clone, which Apple was interested in. How about a trade?</p>

<p>Shaiman says that his and Nathan Myhrvold’s reaction was immediate: “Sure!”</p>

<p>Ironically, once Microsoft got hold of TrueType, they loved the concept but didn’t like the way it was implemented. Although they ended up only making slight modifications to the version that shipped with Windows 3.1, when it came time for the next version of Windows, they ended up “throwing out Apple’s code and rewriting it from scratch.”</p>

<p>When Microsoft and Apple publicly announced their collaboration on TrueType at the Seybold conference in September 1989, the announcement was handled in a contentious and aggressive manner that antagonized Adobe and famously brought Adobe’s John Warnock to tears of frustration. Steve Shaiman feels now that it was a poor way to do it: “We couldn’t have done worse.” Although they were demonstrating what they felt was better technology, they made the mistake of shoving it in Adobe’s face. “What we really needed,” he says, “was a good PR person who could have helped us come up with a less aggressive approach.” But the deed was done. The “font wars” were in full swing.</p>

<p>The key developer of Microsoft’s new code was Eliyezer Kohen, whom Myhrvold met at a conference in Switzerland. Eliyezer was, as Steve Shaiman put it, “really, really smart.” He had a PhD from ETH Zurich, where he studied with Hans Eduard Meyer, the designer of the font Syntax, and Niklaus Wirth, designer of the Pascal language; and he developed his own technology for creating scalable fonts. Eliyezer, according to Shaiman, was “a Turkish Jew with a German wife, who wanted to move to the United States, as one or the other of them wasn’t welcome in any country in Europe where they might find decent working conditions.” Microsoft happily brought him in.</p>
			</section>
			
			<figure data-blockname="single_image">
				<img data-src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-03-Hitchcock-Greg-135.jpg" alt="" src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/MS-Type-Mag-2017-03-Hitchcock-Greg-135.jpg">
				<figcaption>Greg Hitchcock’s journey to Microsoft was a bit circuitous —he studied geography with a focus on computer cartography, and immersed himself in computer science.</figcaption>
			</figure>
			
			<section data-blockname="sub_heading_1">
				<h2>Even a DOS screen needs a font</h2>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-dosscreen.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>GREG HITCHCOCK was one of the early members of what he calls the “virtual team” that Shaiman and Dennis Adler put together in early 1990 to deal with fonts. Hitchcock is tall, blond, and slow-spoken; he doesn’t fit the image of the high-energy Microsoft employee, and he may seem unassertive, almost tentative, if you see him only in a neutral context. But when you see his attention snap to the subjects he knows and cares about, he is forceful and precise, and very, very knowledgeable. His memory is encyclopedic, and he has been at the heart of Microsoft’s typographic development for more than a quarter century. Today he manages Microsoft’s Advanced Reading Technologies (ART) team.</p>

<p>Although Microsoft had been dealing with fonts in one way or another from the very beginning (even a DOS screen needs a font to display its text), Hitchcock feels that the story of typography at Microsoft really begins here: When the first outline fonts were created for Windows 3.1, in 1990.</p>

<p>It was all brand-new technology. All fonts up until then had been bitmap fonts, crude forms made up of coarse screen pixels in a vague approximation of what real letters looked like. Although Microsoft’s new effort was driven by purely practical needs—mapping the screen fonts on a computer system to the fonts available on a printer—Hitchcock feels that it was also the beginning of thinking about screen fonts as something useful and readable in themselves.</p>

<p>The members of the virtual team came from all over Microsoft: Dennis Adler (Fonts), Jean-François Peyroux (OS/2, and later Windows), Michel Suignard (Windows International), Greg Hitchcock (OS/2), Eliyezer Kohen (Fonts), David Weise (Windows), Tim McCaffery (Windows), Raleigh Roark (Hardware), Gabe Newell (Printing), and later Ben Bauermeister, an outside consultant, whose “PANOSE system” for classifying typefaces by their visual characteristics (rather than their historical roots) might provide a roadmap between screen and print.</p>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="sub_heading_1">
				<h2>Monotype send out S.O.S.</h2>
			</section>
			
			<section data-blockname="body_copy">
				<p><span><img src="https://www.typemag.org/images/uploads/win31-shake.png" alt="" height="300" width="300"></span>STEVE SHAIMAN hired Dennis Adler to manage the fonts groups.&nbsp; Together, they talked with several potential sources of font libraries and font technologies, including most of the big guns in the field. Linotype, the venerable manufacturer of hot-metal typesetting equipment, which owned the rights to, among others, the very popular typeface Helvetica, was being hard-nosed. “Fonts were seen as incredibly valuable at the time,” says Shaiman, “and Linotype’s attitude was, ‘What’s Microsoft going to do for us?’” So they were asking an enormous price for licensing the fonts. And Microsoft didn’t want to license the fonts; it wanted to own the rights. (When Shaiman told me this, he laughed and proclaimed: “Microsoft doesn’t rent things!”)</p>

<p>Monotype, on the other hand, was much more receptive. Monotype was Linotype’s great rival; between them, the two companies had essentially created the business of mechanical typesetting in the late 19th century, with their competing hot-metal composition machines. But the Monotype Corporation had fallen on hard times. The typography division, the only part of the company working on digital fonts, was making money, but the larger machinery business was hemorrhaging cash, and the parent company was about to declare bankruptcy.</p>

<p>Out of that debacle rose a new type-only company, Monotype Typography Ltd, which was essentially the old typography division reconstituted as an independent business.</p>

<p>The new company, with its focus on digital fonts and information technology, was headed by a German, Rene Kerfante, who had joined Monotype in 1987 to head up the typography division, and an American, Ira Mirochnik, who had been Monotype’s chief financial officer. They were both quite ready to negotiate a deal with Microsoft.</p>

<p>So it was Monotype that began developing a set of “core fonts” for Microsoft: Scalable TrueType fonts that could be shipped with Windows and used freely by every Windows customer. The new fonts had to mimic the established core set of PostScript fonts, which included Times Roman and Helvetica. Since Monotype had originally developed the Times fonts back in the hot-metal days, that part was easy. To compete with Helvetica, though, they chose to adapt an earlier Monotype design with similar characteristics, called Arial.</p>

<p>Designing the outlines for these typefaces was the kind of task that the Monotype drawing office excelled at. The hard part was the hinting, the software instructions that control the rendering on various devices. That was what would make the fonts look good on screen.</p>

<p>Monotype had a team in the UK working on font hinting, but they were running into trouble. Although they had an auto-hinting program, called TypeMan, developed by Apple’s principal TrueType developer, Sampo Kaasila, the process was proving to be long, slow, and laborious. As Greg Hitchcock describes it, Monotype in desperation Monotype “sent out the bat signal.” In response, in September 1990, he and Eliyezer made the first of many trips to the UK to provide hands-on help and supervision. This was the start of a back-and-forth pattern for Greg—three weeks in the UK, one week in Redmond—that lasted for the next nine months. Their main job was hinting type, working in little rooms in archaic buildings at the old Monotype works. …</p></section></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft">https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.typemag.org/post/the-faces-of-microsoft</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23755238</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 02:53:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[It's Talos all the way down]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23754536">thread link</a>) | @classichasclass
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div id="post-body-6179143665681918893"><p>
Still can't bear the sticker shock of your very own Talos II, or even a itty bitty Blackbird? Why not do what we all do for the machines we can't own and emulate one instead? (And then decide you like it a lot, and save your pennies?)
</p><p>
QEMU 5.0.0 offers a machine model for the bare-metal PowerNV profile, to which the Raptor systems and other OpenPOWER POWER8 and POWER9 designs intended for Linux (i.e., not PowerVM machines) belong. Using the Talos II firmware image (mostly: one snag to be mentioned), you can boot the machine in QEMU and from there bring up an operating system in emulation. In this article we'll prove it works by bringing up <a href="https://voidlinux-ppc.org/">Void Linux for Power</a> (hi, Daniel!) in a variety of configurations. A set-up like this might be enough to test that your software or open-source package builds and runs on OpenPOWER, even if you don't own one yet. In a future article we'll talk about how you can boot your own code on the metal so you can port your favourite OS or build a unikernel.
</p><p>
(For the purposes of this article I'll assume an audience that isn't as familiar with OpenPOWER terminology as our usual readership. Kindly humour me.)
</p><p>
The emulation is imperfect, both if you're emulating it on a real Raptor family system or on an icky PC. While QEMU can emulate an AST2500 (i.e., the ARM-based Baseboard Management Controller, which acts as the service processor and provides the video framebuffer), and QEMU can also emulate a PowerNV system, it doesn't do both at the same time. That means the very lowest levels are actually being simulated here -- you can't watch Raptor's pretty Hostboot display, for example, and only the barest functions of the BMC are simulated enough to allow bring-up, not including the framebuffer. In fact, the hardware profiles we will use here do not in general match a real Raptor system either: we're just virtually plugging in PCI devices that give us necessary functionality, though of course none of the peripheral devices in a Raptor system is Raptor-proprietary. Finally, even though I have tagged this entry with KVM, KVM currently doesn't work right with the QEMU PowerNV machine model even though I'm pretty sure it should be technically possible. Sadly, I tried in vain to do so, could never get KVM-HV to be happy, and ended up kernel panicking the machine with KVM-PR. <a href="https://gist.github.com/classilla/0b95d7bea3e9a270385a2360fbcf7f40">See if you can triumph where I have failed</a>. In the meantime, naturally you can do everything here on a T2 or Blackbird as well because that's how I did it writing this article, but there is no special acceleration for those systems right now.
</p><p>
The first order of business is the first order of business with any emulator: get the ROMs. Fortunately, no one is going to bust you for pirating a set of these because we're an open platform, remember?
</p><p>
The two pieces required are Skiboot and Petitboot, both of which live in the system's PNOR flash. <a href="https://github.com/open-power/skiboot">Skiboot</a> contains OPAL, the OpenPOWER Abstraction Layer. It comes in after the BMC has turned on main power and started the Power CPUs' self-boot engines, which then IPL ("initial program load") Hostboot for the second-stage power-on sequence. When Hostboot completes, it chains into Skiboot, which initializes the PCIe host bus controllers (PHBs) and provides all the basic hardware calls needed by a guest kernel to support the platform. You can think of it as something like an overgrown BIOS. This is the lowest firmware level of an OpenPOWER system that QEMU currently supports emulating.
</p><p>
Skiboot lives only to service a kernel, so it immediately starts one. This initial payload is the bootloader for <a href="https://github.com/open-power/petitboot">Petitboot</a>, which is also stored in firmware. Petitboot has a small Linux root (Skiroot) and acts as a boot menu, finding bootable volumes on attached devices or over the network. Having found one (or you select one), it chains into it to start the main OS, and from then on Skiboot will provide platform services via OPAL for this final guest until the system is shut down or restarted. Because it's in firmware, Petitboot is always available, which can come in really handy when you're trying to do system recovery.
</p><p>
The first, best and most dedicated way is to <a href="https://github.com/open-power/op-build">build Skiboot and Petitboot yourself</a>. They are open-source and the process is relatively well documented and automated, and you should know how to do this if you own an OpenPOWER machine anyhow. If you aren't doing this on a real OpenPOWER machine you'll need a cross-compiler, but most Linux distros offer such a package nowadays. Do keep in mind that if it looks like you're building a tiny Linux distro, well, that's because that's exactly what you're doing. The advantage here is you can fool around with the firmware at your leisure, but it requires a bit of an investment in disk space and time.
</p><p>
The second way assumes you have a more casual interest and would prefer to go with something prefab. It's possible if you (or, you know, your "friend") has a Raptor-family system to extract the necessary components right from the BMC prompt. Log into the BMC over SSH (or via <a href="https://www.talospace.com/2020/04/what-to-do-when-bmc-wont-talk-to-you.html">direct serial connection</a>) and type <tt>pflash -i</tt>. You'll see a list of all the partitions stored in the PNOR flash. The ones we want are <tt>PAYLOAD</tt> (which contains Skiboot) and <tt>BOOTKERNEL</tt> (which contains Skiroot and Petitboot). The exact addresses may vary from system to system and firmware to firmware.
</p><p>
<tt>root@bmc:~# pflash -P PAYLOAD -r /tmp/pnor.PAYLOAD --skip=4096<br>
Reading to "/tmp/pnor.PAYLOAD" from 0x021a1000..0x022a1000 !<br>
[==================================================] 100%<br>
root@bmc:~# pflash -P BOOTKERNEL -r /tmp/pnor.BOOTKERNEL --skip=4096<br>
Reading to "/tmp/pnor.BOOTKERNEL" from 0x022a1000..0x03821000 !<br>
[==================================================] 100%
</tt></p><p>
We skip the first 4K page to avoid the wrapping around each partition. <tt>pnor.PAYLOAD</tt> is actually compressed and needs to be uncompressed prior to use, so:
</p><p>
<tt>root@bmc:~# cd /tmp<br>
root@bmc:/tmp# xz -d &lt; pnor.PAYLOAD &gt; skiboot.lid</tt>
</p><p>
Finally, <tt>scp</tt> both <tt>skiboot.lid</tt> and <tt>pnor.BOOTKERNEL</tt> to your desired system from the BMC.
</p><p>
Admittedly we just talked at length about the two ways most of you <em>won't</em> get the firmware, so let's talk about the third method and the way most of you will, i.e., you'll just download it. Currently there is an irregularity about Raptor's present Skiboot build for this purpose: it only boots if you are emulating a single <em>POWER8</em>. That's not a typo. If you use it to boot an emulated POWER9, the guest will simply panic, and the guest will go into a bootloop if you are emulating multiple POWER8 CPUs (necessary if you need a larger number of PCIe devices). This is undoubtedly a QEMU deficiency which will be corrected in future releases. In the meantime, if you just care about playing around using a single POWER8 on a terminal, then Raptor's builds (either from BMC flash or downloaded) will suffice. However, if you intend to emulate a POWER9 or SMP POWER8 system, <a href="https://github.com/qemu/qemu/blob/master/pc-bios/skiboot.lid">download QEMU's own pre-built <tt>skiboot.lid</tt></a> and use that instead.
</p><p>
For Petitboot, we will extract that directly from Raptor's PNOR images. Assuming you didn't get it using the process above, <a href="https://wiki.raptorcs.com/wiki/Talos_II/Firmware">download the current Talos II PNOR image</a> and decompress it. In the <tt>shell_upgrade</tt> directory you will see the <tt>bzip2</tt>-compressed PNOR image. Uncompress that, leaving you with a filename like <tt>talos-ii-v2.00.pnor</tt>. <a href="https://gist.github.com/classilla/4a2c907d0acec5b537cd4992a00801c3">Download my <tt>pnorex</tt> extractor tool</a> (it's in Perl, because I'm one of <em>those</em> people) and run it on the PNOR image:
</p><p>
<tt>% pnorex talos-ii-v2.00.pnor<br>
Version 1 PNOR archive with 33 entries.<br>
Extracting PAYLOAD at offset 8601.<br>
This is a xz format image.<br>
Wrote 1020K successfully.<br>
Extracting BOOTKERNEL at offset 8857.<br>
This is an ELF executable image.<br>
Wrote 22012K successfully.<br>
Extracted 2 partitions successfully.
</tt>
</p><p>
If you will be using Raptor's Skiroot, then uncompress <tt>pnor.PAYLOAD</tt> to <tt>skiroot.lid</tt> as above: <tt>xz -d &lt; pnor.PAYLOAD &gt; skiboot.lid</tt>
</p><p>
Now, with <tt>skiroot.lid</tt> (for this first example, either Raptor's or QEMU's) and <tt>pnor.BOOTKERNEL</tt> in the same folder, grab an ISO you want to boot. I used the prefab one Daniel offers on the <a href="https://voidlinux-ppc.org/">Void Linux for Power site</a> since I know it boots fine on OpenPOWER hardware. For our first example let's do a simple example of booting Void from a CD image on a POWER8 using the serial port. Our QEMU command line:
</p><p>
<tt>
qemu-system-ppc64 -M powernv8 -m 4G -cpu power8 \<br>
        -nographic \<br>
        -bios ./skiboot.lid \<br>
        -kernel ./pnor.BOOTKERNEL \<br>
        -device ich9-ahci,id=ahci0 \<br>
        -drive id=cd0,media=cdrom,file=void-live-ppc64le-musl-20200411.iso,if=none \<br>
        -device ide-cd,bus=ahci0.0,drive=cd0
</tt>
</p><p>
This configures a single-processor POWER8 system with 4GB of RAM, no graphics, and an Intel AHCI host controller with a single CD-ROM drive attached. The serial output should go to your terminal. It goes a little like this:
</p><p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3VII_RkIwcE/XvFb7tRycOI/AAAAAAAABs0/yyvLDu_1liEFaU2wpoZWtrf-au1P1YiDACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-44-48.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3VII_RkIwcE/XvFb7tRycOI/AAAAAAAABs0/yyvLDu_1liEFaU2wpoZWtrf-au1P1YiDACLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-44-48.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
Here we are with Skiboot chaining into Petitboot. You can ignore the errors; there will be a lot of them since the platform is still incomplete. It will take a little bit of time to decompress the kernel (much slower than it would be on a regular system). You will notice a single device attached to the three available PCIe host bridges on the single POWER8 CPU, i.e., the host controller itself. Don't you just love that the vendor code for Intel is <tt>8086</tt>?
</p><p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3IKOOE6kD80/XvFb7uxi8sI/AAAAAAAABss/yKU2WHvBCbgDmXPvyFdSvsCu7yLHnnGuACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-08.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-3IKOOE6kD80/XvFb7uxi8sI/AAAAAAAABss/yKU2WHvBCbgDmXPvyFdSvsCu7yLHnnGuACLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-08.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
This is Petitboot. When the bootable choices appear, cursor up to the starred option and press E before it autoboots, because we need to tell Void its console is the on-board serial port (otherwise it uses a VGA console: not sure whose bug that is).
</p><p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--dDE00hPAsk/XvFb7k5ug4I/AAAAAAAABsw/KD1kofJkAdIusk9rtl8WyjlknApxQRouQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-43.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--dDE00hPAsk/XvFb7k5ug4I/AAAAAAAABsw/KD1kofJkAdIusk9rtl8WyjlknApxQRouQCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-45-43.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
Add <tt>console=hvc0</tt> at the end, cursor down to <tt>OK</tt> and hit RETURN/ENTER a couple times to boot.
</p><p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-h6UHepGrXLo/XvFb8GHW5jI/AAAAAAAABs4/STBtGNaljU4-3EvsmhlstoBbIpU0aLaKgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-47-38.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="645" data-original-width="578" height="320" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-h6UHepGrXLo/XvFb8GHW5jI/AAAAAAAABs4/STBtGNaljU4-3EvsmhlstoBbIpU0aLaKgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/Screenshot%2Bfrom%2B2020-06-22%2B16-47-38.png" width="287"></a></p>
<p>
A successful login on your emulated baby POWER8. Ta-daa! To rudely pull the plug on the QEMU session, press Ctrl-A, and then X (<tt>QEMU: Terminated</tt>).
</p><p>
Let's now load out the POWER8. We would like to add a video card, an Ethernet card and a USB controller to our existing system, but POWER8 Turismo chips only offer enough PHBs for three PCI endpoints. How do we solve this problem? Easy: we'll add another processor!
</p><p>
At this point …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html">https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.talospace.com/2020/06/its-talos-all-way-down.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23754536</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 01:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Achaemenid Shields Are a Puzzle]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23753604">thread link</a>) | @diodorus
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://bookandsword.com/2020/06/06/achaemenid-shields-are-a-puzzle/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bookandsword.com/2020/06/06/achaemenid-shields-are-a-puzzle/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<!-- end .post-extras -->

		<div>
			<div data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_7331"><p><a href="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7331" data-attachment-id="7331" data-permalink="https://bookandsword.com/2020/06/06/achaemenid-shields-are-a-puzzle/fig_6_2_six_shields/" data-orig-file="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg" data-orig-size="1600,2400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="fig_6_2_six_shields" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=200" data-large-file="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=529" src="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=529&amp;h=794" alt="" width="529" height="794" srcset="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=529&amp;h=794 529w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=1058&amp;h=1588 1058w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=100&amp;h=150 100w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=200&amp;h=300 200w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=768&amp;h=1152 768w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/fig_6_2_six_shields.jpg?w=683&amp;h=1024 683w" sizes="(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px"></a></p><p id="caption-attachment-7331">Figure 6-2 from my forthcoming book from Franz Steiner Verlag.  Some types of <em>gerron</em> (wicker shield) used in the Achaemenid empire in the time of Darius I and Xerxes.  Top: <em>peltē</em> and wooden imitation of a sticks-and-leather shield from Tuekta in the Altai (different sections of ‘sticks’ are painted red, white, and black; similar shields appear in Neo-Assyrian art). Middle: rectangular wicker shields.  Bottom: violin-shaped or figure-eight shields.  Note that they are worn on the arm like a <em>peltē</em> or an Argive shield, not held in the fist like the Tuekta shield.  Source: The J. Paul Getty Museum, Malibu CA, no. 83.AE.247 (digital image courtesy of the Getty’s Open Content Program), State Hermitage Museum, St. Petersburg, no. 2179/96 (photo by author); Gerhard 1847: Taf. CLXVI; western entrance of the Tachara of Darius (sketch by author), Persepolis; two reliefs on the Apadana, Persepolis (photo by author)</p></div>
<p>  If you look at modern paintings and miniatures, you would think we have a good idea of the type of shield used by Achaemenid infantry in the time of Darius and Xerxes.  They cite <a href="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/text?doc=Hdt.+7.61&amp;fromdoc=Perseus%3Atext%3A1999.01.0126">Herodotus book 7 chapter 61</a> and show the large rectangular kind on the middle row of the picture above.  But as I argue in chapter 6.5.2 of my forthcoming book from Franz Steiner Verlag, things are more complicated.  These large rectangular shields appear on the doorposts of two buildings at Persepolis and on two or three vases from Athens (out of thousands of soldiers at Persepolis and Susa and thousands of Red Figure vases). The person who published the sketch on the middle left thought it showed a battle against the Phrygian allies of the Amazons.  And this type of shield does not agree with Herodotus’ words that quivers were hanging beneath the shields, unless we understand ‘beneath’ quite loosely.<br>
<span id="more-7332"></span></p>
<p>  The type in the top row is also popular with artists, but it seems specific to the Aegean/Sea of Marmara/Black Sea region.  Warriors of all the different nations in this region used small round, rectangular, or crescent-shaped shields, often made of wicker or covered with goatskin, but we do not see these shields in artwork from the heart of the empire.  Its also hard to imagine these forming a barrier which needed to be knocked over after a long struggle, like Herodotus describes.  But they are the type of shield which artists from Athens most often put in the hands of foreigners, probably because the Athenians were a bit provincial and Thracians and Scythians were the most exotic warriors they were familiar with.</p>
<p>  The type in the bottom row is the most common type at Persepolis, but it does not show up in Greek art at all.  This might be because it was too similar to the Boeotian or dipylon or figure-eight shield and Greek artists felt that it did not say ‘barbarian.’  A bronze boss for such a shield was found at Samos.  It is easy to imagine quivers hanging beneath such a shield, but hard to imagine them forming a solid barrier which needed to be pushed over.  </p>
<p>  We see even more types of shield in art from the empire, such as the small round center-grip shield on the Çan sarcophagus or the big deep round wicker shields carried by ?Thracians? at Persepolis.  But these three types in the three rows are the ones people today are most interested in.</p>
<p>  Diodorus describes the Persian shields at Thermopylae a bit differently than Herodotus describes them at Plataia (11.7.3, my translation) “For the barbarians used small <em>aspides</em> and <em>peltai</em> which were advantageous in broad open spaces, being easy to move, so because of the narrow space they were not able to harm their enemies very well because they were packed close together with their whole bodies covered with the great <em>aspides</em>, while being at a disadvantage because of the lightness of their defensive arms, they suffered wound after wound.”  He seems to imagine Persian warriors using <em>peltai</em> like the barbarians in paintings (Xen. Cyr. 1.2.13)</p>
<p>  People in my lifetime have written a lot of nonsense about wicker shields supposedly being ‘light’ or ‘weak.’  I don’t know of any tests of this, and traditional wooden shields tend to be thinner and lighter than people expect (like 8 mm thick wood plus a layer of linen or parchment in the centre, and 3-5 mm thick wood plus a layer of linen or parchment at the edge).  Modern wooden shields often use heavy plywood and rawhide so the shield can stand up to pounding with blunt weapons: the fact that these shields are unnecessarily heavy is not important because the owners don’t have to march 20 miles with them on their backs, camp, cook dinner, and march 20 miles again.  Tough warriors like the Ottoman Turks used wicker shields and I don’t know of any of their opponents who said that these were poor protection.  Also, until about the time of Xerxes’ punitive expedition against the Ionians-beyond-the-sea, Greek art often shows spearmen with a light figure-eight shields (Dipylon shields, Boeotian shields) which may well have been made of leather or wicker.  Neither art not archaeology shows that all Greek “bearers of spear and shield” in 480 BCE carried a heavy Argive shield and a single long thrusting lance.</p>
<p>  The type of shield in the middle row is the best fit for Herodotus’ descriptions of combat, but not the most common type in art, and it does not match his description of how Persian soldiers were armed.  And as we saw, <a href="https://bookandsword.com/2019/07/06/provisions-loin-girdling-and-battle-gear-in-the-long-sixth-century/">lists of equipment for soldiers in Babylonia</a> do not seem to mention shields at all.  So like a lot of things in ancient history, the idea that Xerxes’ men carried large rectangular wicker shields is our best guess based on pretty thin evidence, not something certain.</p>
<p><em>Further Reading:</em> There are tests of arrows against reproductions of sticks-through-rawhide shields based on artefacts from Dura Europos and Pazyrzk in Barry Molloy’s <em>The Cutting Edge</em> (Tempus: Stroud, 2007) [ISBN 9780752441696 on <a href="https://www.bookfinder.com/search/?isbn=9780752441696&amp;st=xl&amp;ac=qr">Bookfinder</a>]</p>
<p><strong>Don’t leave my sites naked against a hail of financial arrows!  Support them on <a href="https://www.patreon.com/bookandswordblog">Patreon</a> or <a href="https://www.paypal.me/bookandswordblog">paypal.me</a> or even <a href="https://liberapay.com/bookandswordblog/">liberapay</a></strong></p>
<p><em>Edit 2020-07-08:</em> Hi Hacker News!  <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23753604" rel="nofollow">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23753604</a><br>
<a href="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png"><img data-attachment-id="7751" data-permalink="https://bookandsword.com/2020/06/06/achaemenid-shields-are-a-puzzle/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped/" data-orig-file="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png" data-orig-size="989,236" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="2020-07-08_traffic_cropped" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png?w=529" src="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png?w=529&amp;h=126" alt="a bar chart of one month's traffic where half of all hits are on one day towards the end" width="529" height="126" srcset="https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png?w=529&amp;h=126 529w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png?w=150&amp;h=36 150w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png?w=300&amp;h=72 300w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png?w=768&amp;h=183 768w, https://bookandsword.files.wordpress.com/2020/07/2020-07-08_traffic_cropped.png 989w" sizes="(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px"></a></p>
					</div><!-- end .post-entry -->
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bookandsword.com/2020/06/06/achaemenid-shields-are-a-puzzle/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23753604</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 22:39:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Abusing linear regression to make a point]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23752561">thread link</a>) | @furcyd
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | http://www.goodmath.org/blog/2020/07/06/abusing-linear-regression-to-make-a-point/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.goodmath.org/blog/2020/07/06/abusing-linear-regression-to-make-a-point/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>A bunch of people have been sending me links to a particularly sloppy article that (mis)uses linear regression to draw an incorrect conclusion from some data. So I guess I’ve got to got back to good-old linear regression, and talk about it a bit.</p>



<p>Let’s start with the basics. What is linear regression?</p>



<p>If you have a collection of data – typically data with one independent variable, and one dependent variable (that is, the first variable can vary any way it wants; changing it will change the second variable), then you’re probably interested in how the dependent variable relates to the independent. <em>If</em> you have reason to believe that they should have a linear relationship, then you’d like to know just what that linear relationship is.</p>



<p>If your data were perfect, then you’d just need to plot all of the data points on a graph, with the independent variable on the X axis, and the dependent on the Y, and then your graph would be a line, and you could get its slope and Y intercept, and thus completely capture the relationship.</p>



<p>But data is never perfect. There’s a lot of reasons for that, but no real set of collected data is ever perfect. No matter how perfect the real underlying linear relationship is, real measured data will always show some scatter. And that means that you can draw a lot of possible lines through the collected data. Which one of them represents the best fit?</p>



<p>Since that’s pretty abstract, I’m going to talk a bit about an example – the very example that was used to ignite my interest in math!</p>



<p>Back in 1974 or so, when I was a little kid in second grade, my father was working for RCA, as a physicist involved in manufacturing electronics for satellite systems. One of the important requirements for the products they were manufacturing was that they be <em>radiation hard</em> – meaning that they could be exposed to quite a bit of radiation before they would be damaged enough to stop working.</p>



<p>Their customers – NASA, JPL, and various groups from the U. S. Military, had very strong requirements. They had to show, for a manufacturing setup of a particular component, what the failure profile was.</p>



<p>The primary failure mode of these chips they were making was circuit trace failure. If a sufficiently energetic gamma ray hit one of the circuit traces, it was possible that the trace would burn out – breaking the circuit, and causing the chip to fail.</p>



<p>The test setup that that they used had a gamma ray emitter. So they’d make a manufacturing run to produce a batch of chips from the setup. Then they’d take those, and they’d expose them to increasing doses of radiation from the gamma emitter, and detect when they failed.</p>



<p>For trace failure, the probability of failure is linear in the size of the radiation dose that the chip is exposed to. So to satisfy the customer, they had to show them what the slope of the failure curve was. “Radiation hard” was defined as being able to sustain exposure to some dose of radiation with a specified probability of failure.</p>



<p>So, my dad had done a batch of tests, and he had a ton of little paper slips that described the test results, and he needed to computer the slop of that line – which would give the probability of failure as a multiple of the radiation dose.</p>



<p>I walked into the dining room, where he was set up doing this, and asked what he was doing. So he explained it to me. A lot like I just explained above – except that my dad was a much better teacher than me. I couldn’t explain this to a second or third grader the way that he did!</p>



<p>Anyway… The method that we use to compute the best line is called <em>least squares</em>. The intuition behind it is that you’re trying to find the line where the average distance of all of the datapoints from that line is the smallest. But a simple average doesn’t work well – because some of the data points are above the line, and some are below. Just because one point is, say, above a possible fit by 100, and another is below by 100 doesn’t mean that the two should cancel. So you take the distance between the data points and the line, and you square them – making them all positive. Then you find the line where that total is the smallest – and that’s the best fit.</p>



<p>So let’s look at a real-ish example.</p>



<p>For example, here’s a graph that I generated semi-randomly of data points. The distribution of the points isn’t really what you’d get from real observations, but it’s good enough for demonstration.<img src="http://www.goodmath.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/graph.png" alt="scatter plot of randomly skewed data" srcset="http://www.goodmath.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/graph.png 346w, http://www.goodmath.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/graph-300x212.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 346px) 100vw, 346px"></p>



<p>The way that we do that is: first we compute the means of <img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=x&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title="x" alt="x"> and <img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=y&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title="y" alt="y">, which we’ll call <img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=%5Coverline%7Bx%7D&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title="\overline{x}" alt="\overline{x}"> and <img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=%5Coverline%7By%7D&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title="\overline{y}" alt="\overline{y}">. Then using those, we compute the slope as:</p>



<p><img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=%20m%20%3D%20%5Cfrac%7B%5CSigma_%7Bi%3D1%7D%5En%20%28x-%5Chat%7Bx%7D%29%28y-%5Chat%7By%7D%29%7D%7B%5CSigma_%7Bi%3D1%7D%5E%7Bn%7D%20%28x-%5Chat%7Bx%7D%29%5E2%7D&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title=" m = \frac{\Sigma_{i=1}^n (x-\hat{x})(y-\hat{y})}{\Sigma_{i=1}^{n} (x-\hat{x})^2}" alt=" m = \frac{\Sigma_{i=1}^n (x-\hat{x})(y-\hat{y})}{\Sigma_{i=1}^{n} (x-\hat{x})^2}"></p>



<p>Then for the y intercept: <img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=b%20%3D%20%5Chat%7By%7D%20-%20m%5Chat%7Bx%7D&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title="b = \hat{y} - m\hat{x}" alt="b = \hat{y} - m\hat{x}">.</p>



<p>In the case of this data: I set up the script so that the slope would be about 2.2 +/- 0.5. The slope in the figure is 2.54, and the y-intercept is 18.4.</p>



<p>Now, we want to check how good the linear relationship is. There’s several different ways of doing that. The simplest is called the correlation coefficient, or <img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=r&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title="r" alt="r">.</p>



<p><img src="http://l.wordpress.com/latex.php?latex=%20r%20%3D%20%5Cfrac%7B%5Cleft%28%5CSigma%20%28x-%5Chat%7Bx%7D%29%5Cright%29%20%5Cleft%28%5CSigma%20%28y%20-%20%5Chat%7By%7D%29%5Cright%29%7D%7B%5Csqrt%7B%20%5Cleft%28%5CSigma%20%28x-%5Chat%7Bx%7D%29%5E2%5Cright%29%20%5Cleft%28%5CSigma%20%28y%20-%20%5Chat%7By%7D%29%5E2%5Cright%29%20%7D%7D&amp;bg=FFFFFF&amp;fg=000000&amp;s=0" title=" r = \frac{\left(\Sigma (x-\hat{x})\right) \left(\Sigma (y - \hat{y})\right)}{\sqrt{ \left(\Sigma (x-\hat{x})^2\right) \left(\Sigma (y - \hat{y})^2\right) }}" alt=" r = \frac{\left(\Sigma (x-\hat{x})\right) \left(\Sigma (y - \hat{y})\right)}{\sqrt{ \left(\Sigma (x-\hat{x})^2\right) \left(\Sigma (y - \hat{y})^2\right) }}"></p>



<p>If you look at this, it’s really a check of how well the variation between the measured values and the expected values (according to the regression) match. On the top, you’ve got a set of products; on the bottom, you’ve got the square root of the same thing squared. The bottom is, essentially, just stripping the signs away. The end result is that if the correlation is perfect – that is, if the dependent variable increases linearly with the independent, then the correlation will be 1. If the dependency variable decreases linearly in opposition to the dependent, then the correlation will be -1. If there’s no relationship, then the correlation will be 0.</p>



<p>For this particular set of data, I generated it with a linear equation with a little bit of random noise. The correlation coefficient is slighly greater than 0.95, which is exctly what you’d expect.</p>



<p>Ok, so that’s the basics of linear regression. Let’s get back to the bozo-brained article that started this.</p>



<figure><img src="http://www.goodmath.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/EcCqXojUMAEBFnp.jpg" alt=""></figure>



<p>They featured this graph:</p>



<p>You can see the scatter-plot of the points, and you can see the line that was fit to the points by linear regression. How does that fit look to you? I don’t have access to the original dataset, so I can’t check it, but I’m guessing that the correlation there is somewhere around 0.1 or 0.2 – also known as “no correlation”.</p>



<p>You see, the author fell into one of the classic traps of linear regression. Look back at the top of this article, where I started explaining it. I said that <em>if</em> you had reason to believe in a linear relationship, then you could try to find it. That’s the huge catch to linear regression: no matter what data you put in, you’ll always get a “best match” line out. If the dependent and independent variables don’t have a linear relation – or don’t have any actual relation at all – then the “best match” fit that you get back as a result is garbage.</p>



<p>That’s what the graph above shows: you’ve got a collection of data points that to all appearances has no linear relationship – and probably no direct relationship at all. The author is interpreting the fact that linear regression gave him an answer with a positive slope as if that positive slope is meaningful. But it’s only meaningful <em>if</em> there’s actually a relationship present.</p>



<p>But when you look at the data, you don’t see a linear relationship. You see what looks like a pretty random scatterplot. Without knowing the correlation coefficient, we don’t know for sure, but that line doesn’t look to me like a particularly good fit. And since the author doesn’t give us any evidence beyond the existence of that line to believe in the relationship that they’re arguing for, we really have no reason to believe them. All they’ve done is demonstrate that they don’t understand the math that they’re using.</p>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.goodmath.org/blog/2020/07/06/abusing-linear-regression-to-make-a-point/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23752561</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 20:47:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ages of Discord: A Structural-Demographic Analysis of American History]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23752331">thread link</a>) | @Reedx
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://theworthyhouse.com/2020/01/10/ages-of-discord-a-structural-demographic-analysis-of-american-history-peter-turchin/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://theworthyhouse.com/2020/01/10/ages-of-discord-a-structural-demographic-analysis-of-american-history-peter-turchin/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div><figure><img src="https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?w=840&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?w=300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?resize=100%2C150&amp;ssl=1 100w, https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?w=300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?resize=100%2C150&amp;ssl=1 100w, https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?resize=200%2C300&amp;ssl=1 200w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Cover-7.jpg?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>
<p>I am skeptical of those who predict the future by looking at the past. It’s not that history follows a random walk, like the stock market. Quite the contrary—it is easy to show certain patterns in history. But predicting how and when those patterns will yield any particular result in any given society seems like astrology. Peter Turchin, however, offers a very convincing, and very well-supported, tying of patterns to data. I’m still not sure it’s not astrology, but I’m half convinced. And this is a good book to read in January 2020—because right now is when Turchin predicts, in America, the swelling discord of the title.</p>
<p>This book is, fortunately, nothing like the terrible <em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Fourth Turning (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2019/01/22/book-review-the-fourth-turning/" target="_blank">The Fourth Turning</a></em>, a more famous and very stupid book. Like that book, however, it does posit cycles in societies (as do many other books, ranging from <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Ibn Khaldun’s Muqaddimah (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2019/08/09/ibn-khaldun-an-intellectual-biography-robert-irwin/" target="_blank">Ibn Khaldun’s </a><em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Ibn Khaldun’s Muqaddimah (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2019/08/09/ibn-khaldun-an-intellectual-biography-robert-irwin/" target="_blank">Muqaddimah</a> </em>to <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Joseph Tainter’s The Collapse of Complex Societies (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2018/01/24/book-review-the-collapse-of-complex-societies-joseph-a-tainter/" target="_blank">Joseph Tainter’s </a><em><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Joseph Tainter’s The Collapse of Complex Societies (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2018/01/24/book-review-the-collapse-of-complex-societies-joseph-a-tainter/" target="_blank">The Collapse of Complex Societies</a></em>). “[A] typical historical state goes through a sequence of relatively stable political regimes separated by unstable periods characterized by recurrent waves of internal war. The characteristic length of both stable (or integrative) and unstable (or disintegrative) phases is a century or longer, and the overall period of the cycle is around two to three centuries.” Among many other examples Turchin gives, <a href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2016/10/11/book-review-considerations-on-the-causes-of-the-greatness-of-the-romans-and-their-decline-montesquieu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="the integrative phase of the Roman Republic (opens in a new tab)">the integrative phase of the Roman Republic</a> was 350–130 BC; its disintegrative phase was 130–30 BC, to be succeeded by Principate Rome. To take a less commonly known example, the integrative phase of Valois France was AD 1450–1560; its disintegrative phase was AD 1560–1660. Turchin sees America as being in a disintegrative phase that began in the 1970s and will peak starting in 2020. <em>Ages of Discord</em> is an attempt to substantiate that claim, and offers predictions of chaos in America’s near future. Like Hari Seldon in Isaac Asimov’s <em>Foundation</em>, Turchin sees this disintegrative phase as inevitable—but also, maybe, ameliorable.</p>
<p><span><span><a target="_blank" title="Print" rel="noopener" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Ages-of-Discord-Turchin-PDF.pdf"><span>Print (PDF)</span></a></span></span></p><p>Since this is the turn of the decade, we have, over the past few weeks, been subjected to endless news articles claiming that the 2010s were the best decade ever. Turchin is having none of that. (And all those claims are stupid on their face—their sole substantive “argument” is that due to the spread of free markets, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="poverty in the Third World (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2015/08/11/book-review-the-white-mans-burden-why-the-wests-efforts-to-aid-the-rest-have-done-so-much-ill-and-so-little-good-william-easterly/" target="_blank">poverty in the Third World</a> has declined sharply—which is true enough, but totally irrelevant to whether America had a good decade, or is going to have one over the next ten years). The method of <em>Ages of Discord </em>(which, interestingly, <a href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2019/06/19/the-war-on-normal-people-the-truth-about-americas-disappearing-jobs-and-why-universal-basic-income-is-our-future-andrew-yang/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="is given substantial attention in Presidential candidate Andrew Yang's recent book (opens in a new tab)">is given substantial attention in Presidential candidate Andrew Yang’s recent book</a>) is to use an enormous amount of data and mathematical modeling to add substance to Turchin’s theory of “secular cycles,” developed in an earlier book of that name by Turchin and Sergey Nefedov (where secular has its economic meaning of “a long-term trend of indefinite specific duration”). Turchin calls this the science of “cliodynamics,” a neologism formed from the name of the muse of history and the term for the science of why things change (and also reflecting that society is a web, a “dynamical system”). Cliodynamics is an attempt to view history through science, primarily through the science of statistics. It seeks to offer general principles that can be tested against historical data, and that testing is what Turchin offers here.</p>
<p>Turchin begins with the observation that, however it may feel to us, human societies are fragile. Somewhat melodramatically, he references the American Civil War, while unconvincingly disclaiming that he believes something like that is imminent. He <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="does not think that Steven Pinker is right (opens in a new tab)" href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2015/07/06/book-review-the-better-angels-of-our-nature-stephen-pinker/" target="_blank">does not think that Steven Pinker is right</a> that we are now more civilized than we used to be; for Turchin, there is no thing new under the Sun, except for, perhaps the science of cliodynamics. Turchin notes that in 2010 (this book was published in 2016) he predicted “the next decade is likely to be a period of growing instability in the United States and <a href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2017/09/08/book-review-the-strange-death-of-europe-douglas-murray/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="western Europe (opens in a new tab)">western Europe</a>.” He is well-satisfied that he was right, and I think most people would agree.</p>
<p>The framework of Turchin’s model, laid out in Part I, is the “Structural-Demographic Theory,” originated by Jack Goldstone to apply to agrarian societies and reformulated by Turchin and Nefedov in their earlier book to apply to industrial societies. SDT consists of three basic claims, or “principles.” First, population growth exceeding productivity (the Malthusian Trap, in essence) leads to falling wages, migration, and ultimately, wage protests such as riots. Actual starvation due to the Malthusian Trap is no longer a problem in industrial societies, of course—population increases rather lead to declining real wages, with similar negative effects on the wellbeing of the masses, “immiseration” (though the mechanics are more complex than in agrarian societies). This is the “labor oversupply principle.” Second, fast population growth also leads to “elite overproduction,” where elites compete for a largely fixed number of elite positions, which leads to elite disunity, the creation of a counter-elite, and elite conflict. This problem is worse in industrial societies, since unlike in agrarian societies, declining real wages actually benefit the elite, who get cheaper labor, and respond by engaging in ever greater, “runaway” consumption, exacerbating the intraelite conflict caused by their swelling ranks. This is the “elite overproduction principle.” And third, the “instability principle,” where population growth also leads to expansion of the state, resulting in increased taxes, which inevitably fail to cover expenses, leading to fiscal crisis. “As all these trends intensify, the end result is state bankruptcy and consequent loss of military control; elite movements of regional and national rebellion; and a combination of elite-mobilized and popular uprisings that expose the breakdown of central authority.” This drives the disintegrative phase of the secular cycle, involving increased mortality, decreased productivity, instability, political violence, war, and, potentially, collapse—followed, ultimately, by a new integrative phase, sometimes with a very different society, sometimes with much the same society, where the three principles reverse in unison.</p>
<p>Turchin is not claiming specific causation. He is showing correlations. He troubles himself to clarify that these three principles are simply proxies “for the movements of structural forces postulated by the theory. In other words, the Structural-Demographic Theory provides a holistic explanation not only for these three particular variables, but for a host of others.” Occasionally he will suggest possible causal links, the most notable being that elites, exhausted after a long period of instability (often including the death of many members of the elite), turn away from competition to cooperation, helping to end a disintegrative phase. (The <a href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2018/08/03/book-review-storm-storm-beginning-end-roman-republic-mike-duncan/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="end of the Roman Republic (opens in a new tab)">end of the Roman Republic</a> is the classic example.) Mostly, though, it is patterns tied to data that he offers, and often patterns within patterns.</p>
<p>Thus, his project is to develop mathematical models, then feed them historical data from different eras and see what comes out. This book is specifically written to apply such a model to the United States from its formation (roughly 1780) to the present (2016). It is not an easy read. Lengthy entire chapters are taken up with mathematical formulas—Turchin says the reader can skip these, but that undermines understanding, so I recommend against skipping. The point of the mathematics is to quantify and weight factors in a model that can be applied across different times and places, as well as perform various transforms and shifts, all of which Turchin explains (and he apparently offers most of his data and models for others to review). Complexities abound—for example, finding quantitative proxies for cultural mood, or for the willingness of elites to cooperate with each other, rather than engage in conflict. Much else goes into this, such as rejecting the idea of discrete generations, and instead modeling transmission of behavior across time, paying attention to the “fathers-and-sons dynamic,” feedback loops, and the intersection of different resulting sub-cycles, which aggregate to show certain patterns. Any reader is going to wonder if Turchin is fitting the math to his theories, but looking around, <a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="nobody seems (opens in a new tab)" href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/08/12/book-review-secular-cycles/" target="_blank">nobody seems</a> to accuse him of <a href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2019/09/02/book-review-ages-of-discord/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="doing that (opens in a new tab)">doing that</a>. </p>
<p>After introducing the three principles of SDT as applied to industrial societies, and offering an explanation and justification of his mathematical approach, in Part II Turchin expands on each of the three principles as applied to America. In “Demography and Wellbeing,” Turchin examines statistics about and patterns in labor supply since 1780. He analyzes both immigration and native births, compared to real wages over time, both absolutely and relative to GDP per capita. He then ties the resulting graphs to measures of wellbeing, such as height of adults (which declined four centimeters from 1830 to 1900!), life expectancy, age of first marriage (which he notes is “only imperfectly correlated with social optimism”), and so forth.</p>
<p>Tellingly for modern debates, Turchin here draws the firm conclusion that when immigration is high, not only wages, but wellbeing, are low, and not just for a few years, but correlating over decades—including the most recent phase, since 1970, where wellbeing has objectively declined (contrary to the propaganda we are fed), while immigration has skyrocketed and real wages stagnated. He takes this as demonstrating the accuracy of the labor oversupply principle. As he goes along, Turchin is also combining the data, in the form of various graphs, that he discusses. So, for example, he shows that when you overlay a graph of mass wellbeing on a graph for elite overproduction, you see that since 1780 there is a precise inverse relationship between the two—just as the SDT predicts.</p>
<p>In “Elite Dynamics,” Turchin focuses on the ruling class, defined as …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://theworthyhouse.com/2020/01/10/ages-of-discord-a-structural-demographic-analysis-of-american-history-peter-turchin/">https://theworthyhouse.com/2020/01/10/ages-of-discord-a-structural-demographic-analysis-of-american-history-peter-turchin/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://theworthyhouse.com/2020/01/10/ages-of-discord-a-structural-demographic-analysis-of-american-history-peter-turchin/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23752331</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 20:24:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Booting a 486 from floppy with the most up-to-date stable Linux kernel]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 285 | Comments 142 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23752284">thread link</a>) | @LeoPanthera
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://www.insentricity.com/a.cl/283 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.insentricity.com/a.cl/283">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p>
	<iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oBeE_z4HTwg" width="600"></iframe></p>
<div>
	<p>
		Back in August of 2019 I had a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/retrobattlestations/comments/cr6x9a/contest_singalong_week_until_aug_25/">Sing-Along Week contest on RetroBattlestations</a>&nbsp;with the challenge of playing a MIDI file synchronized to a speech synthesizer singing the lyrics. In my stash of cards I found an MQX-32M MIDI card (Roland MPU-401 clone) which I wanted to use for converting MIDI signals to interface to an Apple II+ with an Echo II speech synthesizer, but ended up using a laptop with a USB MIDI interface. The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/retrobattlestations/comments/fz6is8/contest_pizza_week_through_april_19th/">Pizza Week contest</a>&nbsp;made me more interested in finding a 486 in a pizza box case and so my search began for a suitable case.</p>
	
	<p>
		Searching eBay wasn't easy because there's not really a good search term that would find the kind of case I wanted. I didn't bother trying to make a saved search since this project wasn't a high priority. Instead every once in a while something would inspire to go hit eBay and try some other search terms. A couple of weeks ago I spotted this 486 and made a guess of the size based on the size of the 5.25" bay. It's fairly slim, it has a riser card to turn the cards sideways and the case <em>is</em> shorter than an ISA card, but I don't feel like it's slim enough to call it a pizza box. It's close though!</p>
	
	<p>
		The motherboard is a <a href="https://stason.org/TULARC/pc/motherboards/T/TMC-RESEARCH-CORPORATION-486-PAT48PG4-VER-1-2A.html">TMC PAT48PG4</a> and it came with 32MB of RAM (technically 36MB, it had four 30 pin SIMMs in it too) and 4 cards: VGA, SoundBlaster, modem, and multi-function IO. The seller had tested it and was sold as non-working, won't POST, although he said the cards all worked. I mostly wanted it for the case so I wasn't concerned. Of course when I got it I had to see if the motherboard was really dead. It didn't work for me either but then I discovered if I hit the reset button it would give me some error beeps. I tried another power supply and it came up after hitting reset! It still doesn't cold boot when powered on, not sure if there's a bad cap or if the very slight battery damage (battery was removed before I got it) is preventing the reset line from being pulled after power on. Nonetheless it was working enough that I needed to explore its capabilities more.</p>
	
	<p>
		My ultimate goal is to get a <em>very recent</em>&nbsp;Linux distro and Python 3 installed to a "large" hard drive, but being that this is a 486 installing a current Linux distro isn't trivial. The only Linux distros that still support installing from floppy media are quite dated. Normally I would bypass a floppy install entirely and just boot an older computer via PXE and then install over the network. I thought I could <a href="https://ipxe.org/appnote/buildtargets">put iPXE on a floppy</a> and stick in an ISA NIC but iPXE just hangs without any error messages right after it's loaded from floppy.&nbsp;</p>
	
	<p>
		The BIOS is ancient and struggles with handling the "large" hard drive I hooked up. The drive is 8.45GB and the BIOS can only see it as an 8.0GB drive. Enabling LBA in the BIOS causes the computer to hang during POST after it detects the drive. Win98 fdisk insists the drive is only 504MB. FreeDOS can't see the drive at all. I tried sticking in a NIC with XTIDE ROM on the socket and XTIDE also insists there's no drive connected.</p>
	
	<p>
		Since I wanted to see how Linux would detect the drive that meant I needed to find a way to boot Linux. After a bit of googling I discovered the <a href="http://tiny.wiki.kernel.org/">make tinyconfig option</a> which makes a very small (but useless) kernel, small enough to fit on a floppy. <a href="https://weeraman.com/building-a-tiny-linux-kernel-8c07579ae79d">I enabled a couple of other options</a>, found a small enough initramfs, and was able to get it to boot on the 486. And as expected Linux has no problem with seeing that the drive is connected and the drive's full capacity.</p>
	
	<p>
		Next step is to actually get Linux installed to the hard drive. I'd rather not roll my own distro but maybe I'll have to. Another possibility is to boot Linux from floppy and then download a kernel and initrd from a current distro and kexec over to it. But that feels to me like reinventing iPXE.</p>
	<h4>
		Compiling the Linux Kernel From Source</h4>
	<p>
		A quick rundown of the steps to build the floppy image:</p>
</div>
<ul>
	<li>
		git clone https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/stable/linux.git
		<ul>
			<li>
				v5.8-rc2-1-g625d3449788f&nbsp;at the time of writing</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
	<li>
		make ARCH=x86 tinyconfig</li>
	<li>
		make ARCH=x86 menuconfig
		<ul>
			<li>
				Set processor to 486: CONFIG_M486=y
				<ul>
					<li>
						Processor type and features &gt; Processor family &gt; 486</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>
				Enable tty: CONFIG_TTY=y
				<ul>
					<li>
						Device Drivers &gt; Character devices &gt; Enable TTY</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>
				Enable printk: CONFIG_PRINTK=y
				<ul>
					<li>
						General Setup &gt; Configure standard kernel features (expert users) &gt; Enable support for printk</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>
				Enable initramfs: CONFIG_INITRAMFS_COMPRESSION_GZIP=y
				<ul>
					<li>
						General Setup &gt;&nbsp;Initial RAM filesystem and RAM disk (initramfs/initrd) support &gt;&nbsp;Support initial ramdisk/ramfs compressed using gzip</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>
				Enable ELF: CONFIG_BINFMT_ELF=y
				<ul>
					<li>
						Executable file formats &gt;&nbsp;Kernel support for ELF binaries</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
		</ul>
	</li>
	<li>
		make ARCH=x86 bzImage</li>
</ul>


<p>
	Test boot with qemu:</p>
<div>
	<pre>qemu-system-i386 -kernel arch/x86/boot/bzImage -initrd ../system-image-486/rootfs.cpio.gz</pre>
</div>
<p>
	Create a blank floppy image:</p>
<div>
	<pre>dd if=/dev/zero of=linux-boot.img bs=1k count=1440
mkdosfs linux-boot.img
syslinux --install linux-boot.img
mount -o loop linux-boot.img /mnt
cp arch/x86/boot/bzImage /mnt
cp rootfs.cpio.gz /mnt</pre>
</div>
<p>
	Create /mnt/syslinux.cfg:</p>
<div>
	<pre>DEFAULT linux
LABEL linux
 SAY Now booting the kernel from SYSLINUX...
 KERNEL bzImage
 APPEND initrd=rootfs.cpio.gz
</pre><p>
	Write the image to a floppy:
	</p><pre>umount /mnt
fdformat /dev/fd0
ddrescue -f -D linux-boot.img /dev/fd0
</pre>
	
</div>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.insentricity.com/a.cl/283</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23752284</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 20:20:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Learn Programming Concepts Not Languages]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23751483">thread link</a>) | @rdd_user
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://remotedevdaily.com/learn-programming-concepts-not-languages/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://remotedevdaily.com/learn-programming-concepts-not-languages/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1707"><div><div><p>A good programmer or software developer should be learning programming concepts and not languages.</p><p>Knowing many programming languages is great. However, does this alone really make you a good programmer?</p><h3>Learning Languages</h3><p>There are so many programming languages out there from Python to C++ to Rust to Go, and many many more.</p><p>Knowing different programming languages and understanding their details and quirks is great.  There is absolutely nothing wrong with that.  The more you can learn about the tools you use everyday the better.</p><p>Over the years I've used many different languages ranging from low level languages like C++, to higher level languages like Ruby.</p><p>These days, I program a lot in python and javascript, and I love experimenting with new language features and discovering cool new code snippets.</p><p>However, I realize that simply knowing these languages doesn't make me a good programmer and doesn't say a lot about my skill set.</p><h3>Learn Concepts Not Languages</h3><p>The important thing is not just to learn a language itself.  We need to remember that programming languages are tools, and many of these tools change, evolve, and sometimes even become irrelevant. The moral of the story is that you shouldn't become dependent on a certain language.</p><p>You should learn how to use a language to solve a problem. And when you do that, you will inveitably pick up new concepts.</p><p>Let's use Python as an example. You don't want to just "learn python".  You want to, for example, learn how to use python to scrape data from a website. And by doing this, you will learn a ton of new and interesting concepts like how to make http requests, how to select html elements from the dom using xpaths and css selectors, among many other concepts.</p><p>We want to learn concepts, not just languages.</p><p>Here are some other examples:</p><ul><li>Maybe you want to learn how to use C++ to build a game and learn about the inner workings of computer graphics.</li><li>Maybe you want to learn how to use SQL to design efficient tables and optomize database queries.</li><li>Maybe you want to use Javascript with Vue.js or React to learn how to create reactive web pages.</li><li>Maybe you want to use Django to build a backend application and learn about how webservers handle incoming requests.</li></ul><h3>What Makes a Developer Valuable</h3><p>Knowing the languages and frameworks that a company or project uses is certainly a plus.</p><p>However, the true value that you'll bring to any project that you end up working on is your conceptual knowledge. Companies can find any number of applicants that have experience with their stack. But finding developers who have the deep experience and conceptual knowledge needed to use these tools to build well-designed software is much harder.</p><p>Good software developers are the people that focus on learning concepts and not just languages. Languages come and go, but the core fundamentals of computer science and programming do not.</p><p>I hope you enjoyed this article.  If you did, here are some other interesting <a href="https://remotedevdaily.com/" title="interesting articles">interesting articles</a> for you to read.</p></div></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://remotedevdaily.com/learn-programming-concepts-not-languages/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23751483</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 19:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Buying and Selling stocks with maximum profit]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23750763">thread link</a>) | @codingifmycraft
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | http://codingismycraft.com/index.php/2020/07/05/buying-and-selling-stocks-with-maximum-profit/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://codingismycraft.com/index.php/2020/07/05/buying-and-selling-stocks-with-maximum-profit/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://codingismycraft.com/index.php/2020/07/05/buying-and-selling-stocks-with-maximum-profit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23750763</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 18:03:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[D-Bus and Polkit, No More Mysticism and Confusion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23750162">thread link</a>) | @venamresm__
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/07/06/dbus-polkit.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/07/06/dbus-polkit.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p><img src="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/assets/dbus_polkit/freedesktop_logo.png" alt="freedesktop logo"></p>

<p>Dbus and Polkit are two technologies that emanate an aura of
confusion. While their names are omnipresent in discussions, and the
internet has its share of criticism and rants about them, not many have
a grasp of what they actually do. In this article I’ll give an
overview of these technologies.</p>

<p>D-Bus, or Desktop Bus, is often described as a software that allows other
processes to communicate with one another, to perform inter-process
communication (IPC). However, this term is generic and doesn’t convey
what it is used for. Many technologies exist that can perform IPC, from
plain socket, to messaging queue, so what differentiates D-Bus from them.</p>

<p>D-Bus can be considered a middleware, a software glue that sits
in the middle to provide services to software through a sort
of plugin/microkernel architecture. That’s what the bus metaphor
represents, it replicates the functionality of hardware buses, with
components attaching themselves to known interfaces that they implement,
and providing a mean of communication between them. With D-Bus these can
be either procedure calls aka methods or signals aka notifications.</p>

<p>While D-Bus does offer 1-to-1 and 1-to-many IPC, it’s more of a byproduct
of its original purpose than a mean of efficient process to process data
transfer — it isn’t meant to be fast. D-Bus emerges from the world of
desktop environments where blocks are well known, and each implements a
functionality that should be accessible from other processes if needed
without having to reinvent the transfer mechanism for each and every
software.<br>
This is the problem it tackles: having components in a desktop environment
that are distributed in many processes, each fulfilling a specific job. In
such case, if a process implements the behavior needed, instead of
reimplementing it, it can instead harness the feature already provided
by that other process.</p>

<p>Its design is heavily influenced by Service Oriented Architectures
(SOA), Enterprise Service Buses (ESB), and microkernel architectures.<br>
A bus permits abstracting communication between software, replacing
all direct contact, and only allowing them to happen on the bus
instead.<br>
Additionally, the SOA allows software to expose objects that have
methods that can be called remotely, and also allows other software to
subscribe/publish events happening in remote objects residing in
other software.<br>
Moreover, D-Bus provides an easy plug-and-play, a loose coupling,
where any software could detach itself from the bus and allow another
process to be plugged, containing objects that implement the same features
the previous process implemented.<br>
In sum, it’s an abstraction layer for functionalities that could be
implemented by any software, a standardized way to create pluggable
desktop components. This is what D-Bus is about, this is the role it
plays, and it explains the difficulty in grasping the concepts that
gave rise to it.</p>

<p>The big conceptual picture goes as follows.<br>
We have a D-Bus daemon running at an address and services that implement
well known behaviors. These services attach to the D-Bus daemon and the
attachment edge has a name, a bus name.<br>
Inside these services, there are objects that implement the well known
behavior. These objects also have a path leading to them so that you
can target which object within that service implements the specific
interface needed.<br>
Then, the interface methods and events can be called or registered
on this object inside this service, connected to this bus name, from
another service that requires the behavior implemented by that interface
to be executed.</p>

<p>This is how these particular nested components interact with one another,
and it gives rise to the following:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Address of D-Bus daemon -&gt;
Bus Name that the service attached to -&gt;
Path of the object within this service -&gt;
Interface that this object implements -&gt;
Method or Signal concrete implementation
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Or in graphical form:</p>

<p><img src="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/assets/dbus_polkit/dbus_method_invocation.png" alt="D-Bus ecosystem"></p>

<p>Instead of having everyone talk to one another:</p>

<p><img src="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/assets/dbus_polkit/processes_without_dbus.png" alt="p2p interaction"></p>

<p>Let’s take a method call example that shows these 3 required pieces
of information.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>org.gnome.SessionManager \
/org/gnome/SessionManager \
org.gnome.SessionManager.CanShutdown

   boolean true
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here, we have the service bus name <code>org.gnome.SessionManager</code>, the
object path <code>/org/gnome/SessionManager</code>, and the interface/method name
<code>org.gnome.SessionManager.CanShutdown</code>, all separated by spaces. If the
<code>/org/gnome/SessionManager</code> only implements a single interface then we
could call it as such <code>CanShutdown</code>, but here it doesn’t.</p>

<p>Let’s dive deeper into the pieces we’ve mentioned. They are akin to
the ones in an SOA ecosystem, but with the addition of the bus name,
bus daemon, and the abstraction for the plug-and-play.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Objects</li>
</ul>

<p>An object is an entity that resides in a process/service and that
effectuates some work. It is identified by a path name. The path name is
usually written, though not mandatory, in a namespace format where it
is grouped and divided by slashes <code>/</code>, just like Unix file system path.</p>

<p>For example: <code>/org/gnome/Nautilus/window/1</code>.</p>

<p>Objects have methods and signals, methods take input and return output,
while signals are events that processes can subscribe to.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Interfaces</li>
</ul>

<p>These methods and signals are concrete implementations of interfaces,
the same definition as in OOP.<br>
As with OOP, interfaces are a group of abstractions that have to be
defined in the object that implements them. The members, methods and
signals, are also namespaced under this interface name.</p>

<p>Example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>interface=org.gnome.Shell.Introspect
member method=GetRunningApplications
absolute name of method=org.gnome.Shell.Introspect.GetRunningApplications
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Some interfaces are commonly implemented by objects, such as the
<code>org.freedesktop.Introspectable</code> interface, which, as the name implies,
makes the object introspectable. It allows to query the object about
its capabilities, features, and other interfaces it implements. This is
a very useful feature because it allows discovery.<br>
It’s also worth mentioning that dbus can be used in a generic
way to set and get properties of services’ objects through the
<code>org.freedesktop.DBus.Properties</code> interface.</p>

<p>Interfaces can be described as standard, and for documentation, in D-Bus
XML configuration files so that other programmers can use the reference
to implement them properly. These files can also be used to auto-generate
classes from the XML, making it quicker to implement and less error-prone.<br>
These files can usually be found under <code>/usr/share/dbus-1/interfaces/</code>.
Our <code>org.gnome.Shell.Introspect</code> of earlier is there in the
file <code>org.gnome.Shell.Introspect.xml</code> along with our method
<code>GetRunningApplications</code>. Here’s an excerpt of the relevant section.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>&lt;!--
	GetRunningApplications:
	@short_description: Retrieves the description of all running applications

	Each application is associated by an application ID. The details of
	each application consists of a varlist of keys and values. Available
	keys are listed below.

	'active-on-seats' - (as)   list of seats the application is active on
								(a seat only has at most one active
								application)
--&gt;
&lt;method name="GetRunningApplications"&gt;
	&lt;arg name="apps" direction="out" type="a{sa{sv}}" /&gt;
&lt;/method&gt;
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Notice the <code>type=</code> part, which describes the format of the output,
we’ll come back to what this means in the message format section,
but in short each letter represents a basic type. The <code>out</code> direction
means that it’s the type of an output value of the method, similarly
<code>in</code> is for method parameters. See the following example taken from
<code>org.gnome.Shell.Screenshot.xml</code>.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>&lt;!--
	ScreenshotArea:
	@x: the X coordinate of the area to capture
	@y: the Y coordinate of the area to capture
	@width: the width of the area to capture
	@height: the height of the area to capture
	@flash: whether to flash the area or not
	@filename: the filename for the screenshot
	@success: whether the screenshot was captured
	@filename_used: the file where the screenshot was saved

	Takes a screenshot of the passed in area and saves it
	in @filename as png image, it returns a boolean
	indicating whether the operation was successful or not.
	@filename can either be an absolute path or a basename, in
	which case the screenshot will be saved in the $XDG_PICTURES_DIR
	or the home directory if it doesn't exist. The filename used
	to save the screenshot will be returned in @filename_used.
--&gt;
&lt;method name="ScreenshotArea"&gt;
	&lt;arg type="i" direction="in" name="x"/&gt;
	&lt;arg type="i" direction="in" name="y"/&gt;
	&lt;arg type="i" direction="in" name="width"/&gt;
	&lt;arg type="i" direction="in" name="height"/&gt;
	&lt;arg type="b" direction="in" name="flash"/&gt;
	&lt;arg type="s" direction="in" name="filename"/&gt;
	&lt;arg type="b" direction="out" name="success"/&gt;
	&lt;arg type="s" direction="out" name="filename_used"/&gt;
&lt;/method&gt;
</code></pre></div></div>

<ul>
  <li>Proxies</li>
</ul>

<p>Proxies are the nuts and bolts of an RPC ecosystem, they represent
remote objects, along with their methods, in your native code as if
they were local. Basically, these are wrappers to make it more simple
to manipulate things on D-Bus programmatically instead of worrying about
all the components we’ve mentioned above. Programming with proxies might
look like this.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Proxy proxy = new Proxy(getBusConnection(), "/remote/object/path");
Object returnValue = proxy.MethodName(arg1, arg2);
</code></pre></div></div>

<ul>
  <li>Bus names</li>
</ul>

<p>The bus name, or also sometimes called connection name, is the name
of the connection that an application gets assigned when it connects
to D-Bus. Because D-Bus is a bus architecture, it requires that each
assigned name be unique, you can’t have two applications using the
same bus name. Usually, it is the D-Bus daemon that generates this
random unique value, one that begins with a colon by convention,
however, applications may ask to own well-known names instead. These
well-known names, as reverse domain names, are for cases when people
want to agree on a standard unique application that should implement
a certain behavior. Let’s say for instance a specification for a
<code>com.mycompany.TextEditor</code> bus name, …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/07/06/dbus-polkit.html">https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/07/06/dbus-polkit.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://venam.nixers.net/blog/unix/2020/07/06/dbus-polkit.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23750162</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 17:22:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[1:60 scale Boeing 777 made from manila folders]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 785 | Comments 176 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23749821">thread link</a>) | @chha
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://www.lucaiaconistewart.com/model-777 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.lucaiaconistewart.com/model-777">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site">

      
      



      <div id="content">

        
        
          
            

  


          
        

        <main id="page" role="main">

          

          <div data-content-field="main-content">
            
            <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1561691883296" id="page-5cef0d874437940001629f3f"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559268252785_9085"><p><h2><em>1:60 SCALE MODEL OF AN AIR INDIA BOEING 777-300ER, MADE ENTIRELY FROM MANILA FOLDERS</em></h2></p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559266243734_6718"><div><p>This project traces its beginnings to an <a href="https://www.lucaiaconistewart.com/architecture"><span>architecture class</span></a> in high school where we learned to use manila file folders to roughly model our building ideas. The more I worked with paper, the more I fell in love with its versatility. At some point, I got the idea to make a model of an airplane as a way of challenging myself with an unconventional shape.</p><p>Though the project began on a much smaller and simpler scale in mid-2008, it has since evolved through multiple revisions to become a highly detailed, true-to-life representation of a Boeing 777. I originally drew my plans by hand, but my desire to increase the accuracy and amount of detail led me to start using Adobe Illustrator to design and print increasingly intricate parts directly onto the folder.</p><p><em>The project has been in progress since May 2008</em></p></div></div><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559711406501_11179"><div><h2>RESEARCH</h2><p>I start with as much source material as I can. Often that means photos and videos found on the web, but sometimes I’m lucky enough to get my hands on technical drawings as well. I study these materials to form an understanding of the intrinsic shape and function of the particular section I’m working on. Once I feel confident in my basic understanding of the part, I can begin the design process.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559711406501_13965"><div><h2>DESIGN</h2><p>Much of my work consists of figuring out how to flatten 3-D shapes into 2-D slices that can be printed onto paper and assembled. I work in Adobe Illustrator to create 2-D plans for all the parts of which the final product will be comprised. I typically start the process by working out the general shape and dimensions of the piece, then I drill down, adding more detail and functionality. Once the design has been “frozen,” I work to break it down into individual pieces and arrange them for printing. Often, if a piece is complex and I’m unsure of how well it will function in reality, I build a small test section to verify my designs.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559711406501_16684"><div><h2>PRINTING &amp; ASSEMBLY</h2><p>This stage is as time-consuming as the design process. I cut folders down to printer-friendly sizes and print my plans directly onto them. Then, I cut out the individual pieces using an <a href="http://www.xacto.com/products/cutting-solutions/knives/detail/X3201" target="_blank"><span>Xacto knife</span></a>, arrange them into sections, and glue them together with <a href="https://www.aleenes.com/aleenes-clear-gel-tacky-glue" target="_blank"><span>Tacky Glue</span></a>. Often, a complex piece is actually a collection of much smaller sub-sections that each needs to be assembled separately before being joined together; this is especially true of something like the wing, which contains many articulating functions and thousands of parts.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1561353870131_383468"><div><h2>TOOLS</h2><p>My tools of choice include the aforementioned Xacto knife, a cutting mat, straight edges, squares, and a toothpick for the precise application of glue.</p></div></div></div></div><div data-block-json="{&quot;hSize&quot;:null,&quot;floatDir&quot;:null,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77oRSCxGmYA&quot;,&quot;html&quot;:&quot;<iframe src=\&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/77oRSCxGmYA?wmode=opaque&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1\&quot; height=\&quot;480\&quot; width=\&quot;854\&quot; scrolling=\&quot;no\&quot; frameborder=\&quot;0\&quot; allowfullscreen=\&quot;\&quot;>\n</iframe>&quot;,&quot;resolveObject&quot;:&quot;Video&quot;,&quot;resolvedBy&quot;:&quot;youtube&quot;,&quot;resolved&quot;:true,&quot;description&quot;:&quot;Many people have asked how I design and build the parts for the manila folder 777 I'm putting together, and this video is perhaps the best answer yet. This covers the design and build process for the main landing gear, and was made from almost 130 hours of raw footage.&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Manila Folder 777 - Main Landing Gear - Design+Build Time-lapse with Info! **60FPS**&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:480,&quot;thumbnail_width&quot;:480,&quot;width&quot;:854,&quot;version&quot;:&quot;1.0&quot;,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;video&quot;,&quot;thumbnail_height&quot;:360,&quot;authorName&quot;:&quot;Luca Iaconi-Stewart&quot;,&quot;authorUrl&quot;:&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/lucaiaconistewart&quot;,&quot;providerName&quot;:&quot;YouTube&quot;,&quot;providerUrl&quot;:&quot;https://www.youtube.com/&quot;,&quot;thumbnailUrl&quot;:&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/77oRSCxGmYA/hqdefault.jpg&quot;}" data-block-type="22" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559834399264_13753"><div><div><p><iframe scrolling="no" data-image-dimensions="854x480" allowfullscreen="" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/77oRSCxGmYA?wmode=opaque&amp;enablejsapi=1" width="854" data-embed="true" frameborder="0" height="480">
</iframe></p></div></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559269142757_26027"><p><h3>CLICK BELOW FOR MORE INFO ON EACH SECTION</h3></p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1559870775542_20405"><div><p>Check out an expansive catalog of photos and videos about the project, and stay tuned for further updates!</p></div></div></div></div></div>
          </div>

          

          

        </main>

        

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.lucaiaconistewart.com/model-777</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23749821</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 16:57:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Code only says what it does]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 152 | Comments 107 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23749676">thread link</a>) | @mjb
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | http://brooker.co.za/blog/2020/06/23/code.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://brooker.co.za/blog/2020/06/23/code.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post">


<p>Only loosely related to what it should do.</p>


<p>Code says what it does. That's important for the computer, because code is the way that we ask the computer to do something. It's OK for humans, as long as we never have to modify or debug the code. As soon as we do, we have a problem. Fundamentally, debugging is an exercise in changing what a program does to match what it should do. It requires us to know what a program should do, which isn't captured in the code. Sometimes that's easy: What it does is crash, what it should do is <em>not crash</em>. Outside those trivial cases, discovering intent is harder.</p>

<p>Debugging when <em>should do</em> is subtle, such as when building distributed systems protocols, is especially difficult. In our <a href="https://www.usenix.org/conference/nsdi20/presentation/brooker">Millions of Tiny Databases</a> paper, we say:</p>

<blockquote><p>Our code reviews, simworld tests, and design meetings frequently referred back to the TLA+ models of our protocols to resolve ambiguities in Java code or written communication.</p></blockquote>

<p>The problem is that the implementation (in Physalia's case the Java code) is both an imperfect implementation of the protocol, and an overly-specific implementation of the protocol. It's overly-specific because it needs to be fully specified. Computers demand that, and no less, while the protocol itself has some leeway and wiggle room. It's also overly-specific because it has to address things like low-level performance concerns that the specification can't be bothered with.</p>

<p><em>Are those values in an ArrayList because order is actually important, or because O(1) random seeks are important, or some other reason? Was it just the easiest thing to write? What happens when I change it?</em></p>

<p>Business logic code, while lacking the cachet of distributed protocols, have even more of these kinds of problems. Code both over-specifies the business logic, and specifies it inaccurately. I was prompted to write this by a tweet from @mcclure111 where she hits the nail on the head:</p>

<blockquote data-conversation="none" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Since most software doesn't have a formal spec, most software "is what it does", there's an incredible pressure to respect authorial intent when editing someone else's code. You don't know which quirks are load-bearing.</p>— mcc 🏳️‍⚧️🏳️‍🌈 (@mcclure111) <a href="https://twitter.com/mcclure111/status/1274422600236765186?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 20, 2020</a></blockquote>




<p>This is a major problem with code: <em>You don't know which quirks are load-bearing.</em> You may remember, or be able to guess, or be able to puzzle it out from first principles, or not care, but all of those things are slow and error-prone. What can we do about it?</p>

<p><strong>Design Documentation</strong></p>

<p>Documentation is uncool. Most software engineers seem to come out of school thinking that documentation is below them (<em>tech writer work</em>), or some weird thing their SE professor talked about that is as archaic as Fortran. Part of this is understandable. My own software engineering courses emphasized painstakingly documenting the implementation in UML. No other mention of documentation was made. Re-writing software in UML helps basically nobody. I finished my degree thinking that documentation was unnecessary busywork. Even the <a href="https://agilemanifesto.org/">Agile Manifesto</a> agreed with me<sup><a href="#foot1">1</a></sup>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Working software over comprehensive documentation</p></blockquote>

<p>What I discovered later was that design documentation, encoding the intent and decisions made during developing a system, helps teams be successful in the short term, and people be successful in the long term. Freed from fitting everything in my head, emboldened by the confidence that I could rediscover forgotten facts later, I could move faster. The same applies to teams.</p>

<p>One thing I see successful teams doing is documenting not only the <em>what</em> and <em>why</em> behind their designs, but the <em>how they decided</em>. When it comes time to make changes to the system—either for debugging or in response to changing requirements—these documents are invaluable. It's hard to decide whether its safe to change something, when you don't know why it's like that in the first place. The record of how you decided is important because you are a flawed human, and understanding how you came to a decision is useful to know when that decision seems strange, or surprising.</p>

<p>This documentation process doesn't have to be heavyweight. You don't have to draw painstaking <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entity%E2%80%93relationship_model">ER diagrams</a> unless you think they are helpful. You should probably ignore UML entirely. Instead, describe the system in prose as clearly and succinctly as you can. One place to start is by building an RFC template for your team, potentially inspired by one that you find on the web. <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/56ab961ecbced617ccd2461e/t/5d792e5a4dac4074658ce64b/1568222810968/Squarespace+RFC+Template.pdf">SquareSpace</a>'s template seems reasonable. Some designs will fit well into that RFC format, other's won't. Prefer narrative writing where you can.</p>

<p>Then, keep the documents. Store them somewhere safe. Soak them in vinegar <a href="https://www.almanac.com/content/home-remedies-cough-relief">and tie them around your chest</a>. You're going to want to make sure that the people who need to maintain the system can find them. As they are spelunking through history, help them feel more like a library visitor and less like Lara Croft.</p>

<p>I'm not advocating for Big Design Up Front. Many of the most important things we learn about a project we learn during the implementation. Some of the most important things we learn years after the implementation is complete. Design documentation isn't a static one-time ahead-of-time deliverable, but an ongoing process. Most importantly, design documentation is not a commitment to bad ideas. If it's wrong, fix it and move forward. Documentation is not a deal with the devil.</p>

<p><strong>Comments</strong></p>

<p>Few topics invite a programmer flame war like comments. We're told that comments are silly, or childish, or make it hard to show how manly you are in writing that convoluted mess of code. If it was hard to write, it should be hard to read. After all, you're the James Joyce of code.</p>

<p>That silliness aside, back to @mcclure111's thread:</p>

<blockquote data-conversation="none" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">This means comments that *reveal* authorial intent are valuable, and comments that reveal *there was no authorial intent* are even more valuable. Without those hints, you're left editing superstitiously, preserving quirks even when you don't know why. <a href="https://t.co/YhvWnXjp9i">https://t.co/YhvWnXjp9i</a></p>— mcc 🏳️‍⚧️🏳️‍🌈 (@mcclure111) <a href="https://twitter.com/mcclure111/status/1274422825831596039?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 20, 2020</a></blockquote>




<p>Comments allow us to encode <em>authorial intent</em> into our code in a way that programming languages don't always. Types, traits, interfaces, and variable names do put intent into code, but not completely (I see you, type system maximalists). These same things allow us to communicate a lack of intent—consider <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/util/RandomAccess.html">RandomAccess</a> vs <a href="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/util/ArrayList.html">ArrayList</a>—but are also incomplete. Well-commented code should make the intent of the author clear, especially in cases where that intent is either lost in the translation to code, or where implementation constraints hide the intent of the design. Code comments that link back to design documents are especially useful.</p>

<p>Some languages need comments more than others. Some, like SQL, I find to nearly always obscure the intent of the design behind implementation details.</p>

<p><strong>Formal Specification</strong></p>

<p>In <a href="https://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2015/4/184705-who-builds-a-house-without-drawing-blueprints/fulltext">Who Builds a House Without Drawing Blueprints?</a> Leslie Lamport writes:</p>

<blockquote><p>The need for specifications follows from two observations. The first is that it is a good idea to think about what we are going to do before doing it, and as the cartoonist Guindon wrote: "Writing is nature's way of letting you know how sloppy your thinking is."</p>

<p>The second observation is that to write a good program, we need to think above the code level.</p></blockquote>

<p>I've found that specification, from informal specification with narrative writing to formal specification with TLA+, makes writing programs faster and helps reduce mistakes. As much as I like that article, I think Lamport misses a key part of the value of formal specification: it's a great communication tool. In developing some of the trickiest systems I've built, I've found that heavily-commented formal specifications are fantastically useful documentation. Specification languages are all about <em>intent</em>, and some make it easy to clearly separate intent from implementation.</p>

<p>Again, from our <a href="https://www.usenix.org/conference/nsdi20/presentation/brooker">Millions of Tiny Databases</a> paper:</p>

<blockquote><p>We use TLA+ extensively at Amazon, and it proved exceptionally useful in the development of Physalia.  Our team used TLA+ in three ways: writing specifications of our protocols to check that we understand them deeply, model checking specifications against correctness and liveness properties using the TLC model checker, and writing extensively commented TLA+ code to serve as the documentation of our distributed protocols. While all three of these uses added value, TLA+’s role as a sort of automatically tested (via TLC),and extremely precise, format for protocol documentation was perhaps the most useful.</p></blockquote>

<p>Formal specifications make excellent documentation. Like design docs, they aren't immutable artifacts, but a reflection of what we have learned about the problem.</p>

<p><strong> Conclusion </strong></p>

<p>Building long-lasting, maintainable, systems requires not only communicating with computers, but also communicating in space with other people, and in time with our future selves. Communicating, recording, and indexing the intent behind our designs is an important part of that picture. Make time for it, or regret it later.</p>

<p><strong>Footnotes</strong></p>

<ol>
<li><a name="foot1"></a> To be charitable to the Agile folks, <em>comprehensive</em> does seem to be load-bearing.</li>
</ol>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://brooker.co.za/blog/2020/06/23/code.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23749676</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 16:41:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Concurrency Cost Hierarchy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23749172">thread link</a>) | @benaadams
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2020/07/06/concurrency-costs.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2020/07/06/concurrency-costs.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    
<!-- boilerplate 
page.assets: /assets/concurrency-costs
assetpath: /assets/concurrency-costs
tablepath: /misc/tables/concurrency-costs
-->

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>Concurrency is hard to get <em>correct</em>, at least for those of us unlucky enough to be writing in languages which expose directly the guts of concurrent hardware: threads and shared memory. Getting concurrency correct <em>and</em> fast is hard, too. Your knowledge about single-threaded optimization often won’t help you: at a micro (instruction) level we can’t simply apply the usual rules of μops, dependency chains, throughput limits, and so on. The rules are different.</p>

<p>If that first paragraph got your hopes up, this second one is here to dash them: I’m not actually going to do a deep dive into the very low level aspects of concurrent performance. There are a lot of things we just don’t know about how atomic instructions and fences execute, and we’ll save that for another day.</p>

<p>Instead, I’m going to describe a higher level taxonomy that I use to think about concurrent performance. We’ll group the performance of concurrent operations into six broad <em>levels</em> running from fast to slow, with each level differing from its neighbors by roughly an order of magnitude in performance.</p>

<p>I often find myself thinking in terms of these categories when I need high performance concurrency: what is the best level I can practically achieve for the given problem? Keeping the levels in mind is useful both during initial design (sometimes a small change in requirements or high level design can allow you to achieve a better level), and also while evaluating existing systems (to better understand existing performance and evaluate the path of least resistance to improvements).</p>

<h3 id="a-real-world-example">A “Real World” Example</h3>

<p>I don’t want this to be totally abstract, so we will use a real-world-if-you-squint<sup id="fnref:realworld"><a href="#fn:realworld">1</a></sup> running example throughout: safely incrementing an integer counter across threads. By <em>safely</em> I mean without losing increments, producing out-of-thin air values, frying your RAM or making more than a minor rip in space-time.</p>

<h3 id="source-and-results">Source and Results</h3>

<p>The source for every benchmark here is <a href="https://github.com/travisdowns/concurrency-hierarchy-bench">available</a>, so you can follow along and even reproduce the results or run the benchmarks on your own hardware. All of the results discussed here (and more) are available in the same repository, and each plot includes a <code>[data table]</code> link to the specific subset used to generate the plot.</p>

<h3 id="hardware">Hardware</h3>

<p>All of the performance results are provided for several different hardware platforms: Intel Skylake, Ice Lake, Amazon Graviton and Graviton 2. However except when I explicitly mention other hardware, the prose refers to the results on Skylake. Although the specific numbers vary, most of the qualitative relationships hold for the hardware too, but <em>not always</em>. Not only does the hardware vary, but the OS and library implementations will vary as well.</p>

<p>It’s almost inevitable that this will be used to compare across hardware (“wow, Graviton 2 sure kicks Graviton 1’s ass”), but that’s not my goal here. The benchmarks are written primarily to tease apart the characteristics of the different levels, and <em>not</em> as a hardware shootout.</p>

<p>Find below the details of the hardware used:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Micro-architecture</th>
      <th>ISA</th>
      <th>Model</th>
      <th>Tested Frequency</th>
      <th>Cores</th>
      <th>OS</th>
      <th>Instance Type</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Skylake</td>
      <td>x86</td>
      <td>i7-6700HQ</td>
      <td>2.6 GHz</td>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>Ubuntu 20.04</td>
      <td>&nbsp;</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Ice Lake</td>
      <td>x86</td>
      <td>i5-1035G4</td>
      <td>3.3 GHz</td>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>Ubuntu 19.10</td>
      <td>&nbsp;</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Graviton</td>
      <td>AArch64</td>
      <td>Cortex-A72</td>
      <td>2.3 GHz</td>
      <td>16</td>
      <td>Ubuntu 20.04</td>
      <td>a1.4xlarge</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Graviton 2</td>
      <td>AArch64</td>
      <td>Neoverse N1</td>
      <td>2.5 GHz</td>
      <td>16<sup id="fnref:g2cores"><a href="#fn:g2cores">2</a></sup></td>
      <td>Ubuntu 20.04</td>
      <td>c6g.4xlarge</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="level-2-contended-atomics">Level 2: Contended Atomics</h2>

<p>You’d probably expect this hierarchy to be introduced from fast to slow, or vice-versa, but we’re all about defying expectations here and we are going to start in the <em>middle</em> and work our way outwards. The middle (rounding down) turns out to be <em>level 2</em> and that’s where we will jump in.</p>

<p>The most elementary way to safely modify any shared object is to use a lock. It mostly <em>just works</em> for any type of object, no matter its structure or the nature of the modifications. Almost any mainstream CPU from the last thirty years has some type of locking<sup id="fnref:parisc"><a href="#fn:parisc">3</a></sup> instruction accessible to userspace.</p>

<p>So our baseline increment implementation will use a simple mutex of type <code>T</code> to protect a plain integer variable:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>T</span> <span>lock</span><span>;</span>
<span>uint64_t</span> <span>counter</span><span>;</span>

<span>void</span> <span>bench</span><span>(</span><span>size_t</span> <span>iters</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>iters</span><span>--</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>lock_guard</span><span>&lt;</span><span>T</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>holder</span><span>(</span><span>lock</span><span>);</span>
        <span>counter</span><span>++</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We’ll call this implementation <em><abbr title="Uses a std::mutex and std::lock_guard to protect a plain integer counter.">mutex add</abbr></em>, and on my 4 CPU Skylake-S i7-6700HQ machine, when I use the vanilla <code>std::mutex</code> I get the following results for 2 to 4 threads:</p>



<p>The reported value is the median of all trials, and the vertical black error lines at the top of each bar indicate the <em>interdecile range</em>, i.e., the values at the 10th and 90th percentile. Where the error bars don’t show up, it means there is no difference between the p10 and p90 values at all, at least within the limits of the reporting resolution (100 picoseconds).</p>

<p>This shows that the baseline contended cost to modify an integer protected by a lock starts at about 125 nanoseconds for two threads, and grows somewhat with increasing thread count.</p>

<p>I can already hear someone saying: <em>If you are just modifying a single 64-bit integer, skip the lock and just directly use the atomic operations that most ISAs support!</em></p>

<p>Sure, let’s add a couple of variants that do that. The <code>std::atomic&lt;T&gt;</code> template makes this easy: we can wrap any type meeting some basic requirements and then manipulate it atomically. The easiest of all is to use <code>std::atomic&lt;uint64&gt;::operator++()</code><sup id="fnref:post"><a href="#fn:post">4</a></sup> and this gives us <em><abbr title="Uses an atomic increment on a single shared counter.">atomic add</abbr></em>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>std</span><span>::</span><span>atomic</span><span>&lt;</span><span>uint64_t</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>atomic_counter</span><span>{};</span>

<span>void</span> <span>atomic_add</span><span>(</span><span>size_t</span> <span>iters</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>iters</span><span>--</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>atomic_counter</span><span>++</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The other common approach would be to use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compare-and-swap">compare and swap (<abbr title="Compare-and-swap: an atomic operation implemented on x86 and other CPUs">CAS</abbr>)</a> to load the existing value, add one and then <abbr title="Compare-and-swap: an atomic operation implemented on x86 and other CPUs">CAS</abbr> it back if it hasn’t changed. If it <em>has</em> changed, the increment raced with another thread and we try again.</p>

<p>Note that even if you use increment at the source level, the assembly might actually end up using <abbr title="Compare-and-swap: an atomic operation implemented on x86 and other CPUs">CAS</abbr> if your hardware doesn’t support atomic increment<sup id="fnref:atomicsup"><a href="#fn:atomicsup">5</a></sup>, or if your compiler or runtime just don’t take advantage of atomic operations even though they are available (e.g., see what even the newest version of <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/5h4K7y">icc does</a> for atomic increment, and what Java did for years<sup id="fnref:java"><a href="#fn:java">6</a></sup>). This caveat doesn’t apply to any of our tested platforms, however.</p>

<p>Let’s add a counter implementation that uses <abbr title="Compare-and-swap: an atomic operation implemented on x86 and other CPUs">CAS</abbr> as described above, and we’ll call it <em><abbr title="Uses a CAS loop to increment a single shared counter.">cas add</abbr></em>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>std</span><span>::</span><span>atomic</span><span>&lt;</span><span>uint64_t</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>cas_counter</span><span>;</span>

<span>void</span> <span>cas_add</span><span>(</span><span>size_t</span> <span>iters</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>iters</span><span>--</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>uint64_t</span> <span>v</span> <span>=</span> <span>cas_counter</span><span>.</span><span>load</span><span>();</span>
        <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>cas_counter</span><span>.</span><span>compare_exchange_weak</span><span>(</span><span>v</span><span>,</span> <span>v</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>
            <span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here’s what these look like alongside our existing <code>std::mutex</code> benchmark:</p>



<p>The first takeaway is that, at least in this <em>unrealistic maximum contention</em> benchmark, using <abbr title="Uses an atomic increment on a single shared counter.">atomic add</abbr> (<a href="https://www.felixcloutier.com/x86/xadd"><code>lock xadd</code></a> at the hardware level) is significantly better than <abbr title="Compare-and-swap: an atomic operation implemented on x86 and other CPUs">CAS</abbr>. The second would be that <code>std::mutex</code> doesn’t come out looking all that bad on Skylake. It is only slightly worse than the <abbr title="Compare-and-swap: an atomic operation implemented on x86 and other CPUs">CAS</abbr> approach at 2 cores and beats it at 3 and 4 cores. It is slower than the atomic increment approach, but less than three times as slow and seems to be scaling in a reasonable way.</p>

<p>All of these operations are belong to <em>level 2</em> in the hierarchy. The primary characteristic of level 2 is that they make a <em>contended access</em> to a shared variable. This means that at a minimum, the line containing the data needs to move out to the caching agent that manages coherency<sup id="fnref:l3"><a href="#fn:l3">7</a></sup>, and then back up to the core that will receive ownership next. That’s about 70 cycles minimum just for that operation<sup id="fnref:inter"><a href="#fn:inter">8</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Can it get slower? You bet it can. <em>Way</em> slower.</p>

<h3 id="level-3-system-calls">Level 3: System Calls</h3>

<p>The next level up (“up” is not good here…) is level 3. The key characteristic of implementations at this level is that they make a <em>system call on almost every operation</em>.</p>

<p>It is easy to write concurrency primitives that make a system call <em>unconditionally</em> (e.g., a lock which always tries to wake waiters via a <code>futex(2)</code> call, even if there aren’t any), but we won’t look at those here. Rather we’ll take a look at a case where the fast path is written to avoid a system call, but the design or way it is used implies that such a call usually happens anyway.</p>

<p>Specifically, we are going to look at some <em>fair locks</em>. Fair locks allow threads into the critical section in the same order they began waiting. That is, when the critical section becomes available, the thread that has been waiting the longest is given the chance to take it.</p>

<p>Sounds like a good idea, right? Sometimes yes, but as we will see it can have significant performance implications.</p>

<p>On the menu are three different fair locks.</p>

<p>The first is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ticket_lock">ticket lock</a> with a <code>sched_yield</code> in the spin loop. The idea of the yield is to give other threads which may hold the lock time to run. This <code>yield()</code> approach is publicly frowned upon by concurrency experts<sup id="fnref:notwhat"><a href="#fn:notwhat">9</a></sup>, who then sometimes go right ahead and use it anyway.</p>

<p>We will call it <abbr title="A ticket lock that calls sched_yield in a spin loop while waiting for its turn.">ticket yield</abbr> and it looks like this:</p>



<div><div><pre><code><span>/**
 * A ticket lock which uses sched_yield() while waiting
 * for the ticket to be served.
 */</span>
<span>class</span> <span>ticket_yield</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>atomic</span><span>&lt;</span><span>size_t</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>dispenser</span><span>{},</span> <span>serving</span><span>{};</span>

<span>public:</span>
    <span>void</span> <span>lock</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>auto</span> <span>ticket</span> <span>=</span> <span>dispenser</span><span>.</span><span>fetch_add</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>memory_order_relaxed</span><span>);</span>

        <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>ticket</span> <span>!=</span> <span>serving</span><span>.</span><span>load</span><span>(</span><span>std</span><span>::</span><span>memory_order_acquire</span><span>))</span>
            <span>sched_yield</span><span>();</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>void</span> <span>unlock</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>serving</span><span>.</span><span>store</span><span>(</span><span>serving</span><span>.</span><span>load</span><span>()</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>memory_order_release</span><span>);</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>};</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Let’s plot the performance results for this lock alongside the existing approaches:</p>



<p>This is level 3 visualized: it is an order of magnitude slower than the level 2 approaches. The slowdown comes from the <code>sched_yield</code> call: this is a system call and these are generally on the order of 100s of nanoseconds<sup id="fnref:spectre"><a href="#fn:spectre">10</a></sup>, and it shows in the results.</p>

<p>This lock <em>does</em> have a fast path where <code>sched_yield</code> isn’t called: if the lock is available, no spinning occurs and <code>sched_yield</code> is never called. However, the combination of being a <em>fair</em> lock and the high contention in this test means that a lock convoy quickly forms (we’ll describe this in more detail later) and so the spin loop is entered basically …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2020/07/06/concurrency-costs.html">https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2020/07/06/concurrency-costs.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://travisdowns.github.io/blog/2020/07/06/concurrency-costs.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23749172</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 15:53:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: How I landed an interview almost every time I applied (as a developer)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23748953">thread link</a>) | @yassinerajallah
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://devhypercharged.com/how-to-land-an-interview-almost-every-time-as-a-programmer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://devhypercharged.com/how-to-land-an-interview-almost-every-time-as-a-programmer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span>Applying to startups, medium-big corps is a tedious task. The standard is to apply to 100+ companies and prepare 100+ programming problems. Does it have to be this hard? Short answer no. In fact, I applied to 30 companies and landed 25 interviews. And the good news is, it generally doesn’t take more than 2 weeks to finish with all that interview process (of course it depends on the company)&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>Let’s get started already. If you are applying to:</span></p>

<h4><span>Startup/Medium-Size Company:</span></h4>
<p><span>The hiring process depends on the company. More often than not, you talk to the CEO/CTO and are judged over your “compatibility” with the workplace’s culture. Generally, the first interview is just to get to know you, your rate (please don’t ask for a crazy salary if you are just starting out), and what you can bring to the ecosystem. At later stages, you are assigned a take-home project or a live coding interview.</span></p>
<p><span>Your responsibility depends on how much funding the startup has and its burn rate. The lesser the investment, the more critical your responsibility. It makes sense because the founder(s) can’t hire another developer to help you out. And you probably have been hired because you’re full-stack. You are also expected to have an “entrepreneurial mindset”, you get the chance to make influential decisions. It’s important to know that you aren’t a “code monkey”.You’ll need to make well-thought decisions for the sake of the startup.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><b>To land an interview, your best bet is to reach out to the founders: </b><span>Skip sending your application through the website. Instead, craft your best looking, most personal, and professional email out there. You research the startup, research the founders, and link what they work on to your skills.&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>Be careful of sounding too general “I’m interested in your company, it’s truly something the world needs”; Say what is special about it, if you have a question or 2, you can include them. But the main purpose is to show your interest.&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><span>Include your resume and make sure it’s clean and spacious enough. No one wants to read a 2-page resume full of little details. The most important on the top, and shoot your shot, no time to waste.</span></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><span>Include a call to action at the end of your email “Would love to hear from you.”&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>

<ul>
<li><span>You are set! You’ll be amazed by the response rate. And the founders are friendlier than you might think.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span>To find startups that match your profile, you can use: </span></p>
<p><a href="https://angel.co/"><span>angel.co</span></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.workatastartup.com/"><span>workatastartup.com</span></a></p>



<h4><span>Big tech</span></h4>
<p><span>This one is tricky. The application portals are heavily advertised and probably everyone applies through them. Result? Your application goes unnoticed.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>I won’t beat around the bush, you need a recommendation. Unless you are some high profile employee at company X, you won’t be noticed. Most people I know got in with a recommendation. This legacy system puts other applicants at a disadvantage in the resume screening process.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>But how can you get a recommendation? </span><span>So far there are 2 ways.</span></p>

<p><strong>Your circle/network</strong></p>
<p><span>Start by asking people in your circle. Note that a recommendation helps you with skipping the screening process and that’s it. The rest is on you. Being hired totally depends on your skills from this point forward.</span></p>
<p><strong>Create a relationship</strong></p>
<p><span>If you are applying to big corp XYZ, chances are you’re really interested in the company culture (salary aside). You can go on LinkedIn and connect with an employee from that company. Ideally, you want to stay in touch for months to come. A great way to do so is by asking questions!&nbsp; When you build this long term relationship, you can ask for a recommendation. Obviously, you don’t want to talk to employees just because of the recommendation, be authentic!&nbsp;</span></p>

<p><span>This brings it to the end of this article. If you learned something new or want to connect shoot me an email 🙂 Until next time. Take care!</span></p>
<p><span>Ps: If you found this helpful, please consider sharing and subscribing. It helps keep the website alive. Thank you!</span></p>

			
			
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://devhypercharged.com/how-to-land-an-interview-almost-every-time-as-a-programmer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23748953</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 15:30:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Purely Functional, Statically Typed Effect System for Python]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23748773">thread link</a>) | @suned
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://pfun.readthedocs.io/en | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pfun.readthedocs.io/en">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pfun.readthedocs.io/en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23748773</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 15:13:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I made a macro keypad with 3D-printed switches]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 147 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23748660">thread link</a>) | @jstanley
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/3pct-keyboard.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/3pct-keyboard.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<h3>I made a macro keypad with 3d-printed switches</h3>
<p><i>Mon  6 July 2020</i></p>
<p><i>Tagged: <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/electronics.html">electronics</a>, <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/tags/3dprinting.html">3dprinting</a></i></p>
<p>Latest on the 3d-printed keyboard switch project: I've reached a switch design that I think is probably reliable enough,
and I've put 3 of them together to form a macro keypad just to see how it all goes together before I commit to a
full keyboard. I don't have a number for how many presses the switch lasts, other than to say that
the motor on the testing machine stopped working before the switch did (after about 250,000 presses).</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2745"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2745"></a></p>
<p>You can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uHkOPBxnLtM">watch my short demo video</a> if you want.</p>
<p>"80%" and "60%" keyboard layouts are quite popular, which are correspondingly reduced versions of a full keyboard layout.
I like to think of this keypad as a "3%" keyboard, it's fine as long as you only want to type "jes".</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2746"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2746"></a></p>
<p>It's controlled by an Arduino Pro Micro. It's hard to tell from the pic because of the hot glue, but the switches are wired up to pins 2, 3, and 4, from
the other side of the board.</p>
<p>For the software side of it, I used the <a href="https://www.arduino.cc/reference/en/language/functions/usb/keyboard/">Arduino Keyboard library</a>,
using <a href="https://gist.github.com/jes/fe1aeb18457a06562516372684d1bd47">this quick and dirty Arduino code</a>.
Approximately all of the code is just related to the debounce logic.</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2748"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2748"></a></p>
<p>The switches are printed in some generic no-name clear PETG.
The case and keycaps are printed in <a href="https://shop.prusa3d.com/en/prusament/711-prusament-pla-prusa-galaxy-black-1kg.html">Prusament Galaxy Black PLA</a>.
I'm a big fan of this filament. The glittery effect means the layer lines almost completely disappear. It's basically the same effect you get when printing with
carbon fibre-filled nylon, but with none of the difficulties of printing carbon fibre-filled nylon.</p>
<p>All of these parts, including the switches, were printed on my new <a href="https://www.prusa3d.com/original-prusa-mini/">Prusa Mini</a> printer, which arrived last week and I'm very pleased
with so far.</p>
<h2>Switches</h2>
<p>The problem with the switch design <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/keyswitch-update.html">from last time</a> was that the copper tape was splitting apart, which prevents it from conducting along
its full length. I initially thought I had
solved this by applying a 2nd layer of copper tape, but that turned out not to be a workable solution. I did a bunch of tests of various combinations of 50% and 75% activation position, and 1 or 2 layers of copper
tape, and found no significant correlation between either of those 2 variables and how long the switch lasts. The switches lasted between 225 presses and 330,000 presses before
failure. 7 failed by the copper tape splitting, 2 failed by the PETG spiral spring breaking (both after more than 200,000 presses), and 1 didn't seem to have any broken parts, it just wasn't reliably working any more.</p>
<p>This is the CAD model of the latest design:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2749"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2749"></a></p>
<p>The "leaf spring" has that funny shape in its bend so that it can tilt easily, which ensures that it makes reliable contact with <i>both</i> contact wires, instead of
just the first one it happens to touch.</p>
<p>And here's a slow-motion video showing how it works (a slightly earlier iteration, but the same concept):</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/peXFqVMugO4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Also, just for fun, I did some <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/freecad-fea.html">FEA</a> on the spiral spring
design, and it behaved just like the real version:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2724"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2724"></a></p>
<p>The red areas show the areas of highest stress, and indeed the springs tend to break around
the middle of the spiral.</p>
<h2>Print your own</h2>
<p>I consider this a "release candidate" rather than a finished design, because there is still
some work to do on it (in particular, I want to make it a bit less tall). But you can have it if you want it.</p>
<p>You will need:</p>
<ul>
<li>FDM 3D printer (although I'd also be interested to see results from resin printers!)</li>
<li>PETG filament. You can try other materials. PLA works but makes for a heavier feel and breaks more quickly.</li>
<li>1.0 mm diameter copper wire, 90 mm length per switch should be more than enough</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/interest/3dpswitch-rc1.tar.gz">Download the STL files</a> and arrange them on the build plate something like this (you'll probably have to rotate the spiral spring):</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2750"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2750"></a></p>
<p>I suggest printing more than 1 of the "leafspring" part as it is a small part quite likely to
have defects in the print. Make sure you're printing at
a fine enough quality level to include all the features. In particular, make sure (both) the spirals on
the spring are connected all the way around, and that the leaf spring is connected all the way
along. I use the "0.15mm QUALITY" setting in PrusaSlicer. You shouldn't need any support material.
You might need to enable "detect thin walls".</p>
<p>You might need to add up to -0.3mm of X/Y size compensation. I have found that when printing
this on the Prusa Mini, optimal clearance is achieved when the 3.0 mm plunger rides inside
a 3.0 mm hole. On previous printers I've owned, this wouldn't even fit together. I'm not sure
what's going on, but obviously I modeled it to print on my machine, so you might need to apply X/Y
compensation on yours.</p>
<p><b>Step 1:</b> Print the parts. It takes about 40 minutes for me.</p>
<p><b>Step 2:</b> Clean up any stringing inside the case from the PETG. I use a lighter to burn off the worst of it,
and then a Stanley knife to trim off what remains.</p>
<p><b>Step 3:</b> Examine the spiral spring and ensure that it moves freely. You might need to cut any
stringing between the spirals with a knife, or re-print with different X/Y compensation, depending on whether it is a few small
tight spots or bad clearance all the way along.</p>
<p><b>Step 4:</b> Slide the spiral spring into the shelf at the top of the case. The orientation is not
critical, I tend to slide it in with the smoothest sides against the case just to make life easy
for myself.</p>
<p><b>Step 5:</b> Push the plunger through the top hole in the case, through the hole in the spiral
spring, and through the middle hole in the case. Verify that it moves up and down freely and that
the spring reliably returns it to the top. If not, take it back out and trim the tight spots with
a knife.</p>
<p><b>Step 6:</b> Cut off about a 13mm length of the copper wire. Slide it into the hole in the
leaf spring. If you can't get it through, you might need to widen the hole with a pin or sharp tool of
some kind. Use whatever you have.</p>
<p><b>Step 7:</b> Press the plunger down slightly to expose the attachment end inside the lower
chamber of the switch. Using a small pair of pliers or tweezers, push the attachment part of the
leaf spring onto the end of the plunger. Make sure it is pushed home. Looking in the big hole
at the bottom of the case, you should see the leaf spring roughly centred. When you let go
of the plunger, the spiral spring should still be stretched out slightly. This is desired, without
this preload the switch would start moving at 0 force.</p>
<p><b>Step 8:</b> Cut off 2x roughly 35mm lengths of copper wire. Using a pair of pliers, put a bend about
5mm from
one end. Insert the non-bent end through 1 of the wire holes and out the other side. Bend the wire
down the other side, and then in whatever direction you want your contacts to point. Repeat for
the second wire.</p>
<p>You should now have something that looks a bit like this:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2752"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2752"></a></p>
<p>And that should be it! Manually press the switch a few times and visually verify that the middle
copper wire appears to be making good contact with the other 2 wires, and then you're ready to
assemble it into a circuit! If you want it mechanically attached to a PCB, you could leave a longer
length of wire coming out of the first side, and you'd then have 4 soldering points. Otherwise,
mount it inside a 14mm square hole. You'll probably need cut-outs in the corners to accommodate
the wires sticking out, like this:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2753"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2753"></a></p>
<p>If you make one (or more!) I'd be really interested to hear your opinion on what could be designed
better, and to see pictures of your results. Email me: <a href="mailto:james@incoherency.co.uk">james@incoherency.co.uk</a>.</p>
<h2>Next steps</h2>
<p>We're getting pretty close to being able to put together a finished keyboard. I still
have the following things to do:</p>
<h3>Testing</h3>
<p>It would be good to get an accurate value for the number of presses that the switches can take. I
think currently a lot of the variability comes from the height at which the switch is positioned
relative to the tester. If it's doing 0.1mm short of a full stroke, the switch is likely to last
significantly longer than if it is being hammered 0.1mm longer than a full stroke. This is hard to
configure as I have only very coarse control of the height.</p>
<p>I watched the Linus Tech Tips tours of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pu1gP4PfqCQ">the
Cherry MX factory</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9fNiJKh6q-E">the Omron factory</a>. They're both interesting and worth watching. I took a screenshot of this testing machine in the
Omron video:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2712"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2712"></a></p>
<p>So there we have a single motor raising a platform up and down which is pressing 10 switches
at once. The platform glides on a pair of linear rails, and the exact vertical position of the press
is finely adjusted with a separate screw for each switch. The moving platform also has
a spring at each end, I am not completely sure why, I think just to take up some of its weight, to
reduce the load on the motor.</p>
<p>But this is a much better way to gang-test switches than what I have at the moment, which involves
wiring up a separate motor for each switch and gets messy quickly:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2755"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2755"></a></p>
<p>I'm past the point where more testing is critical (famous last words, I know), but it would be good
to do anyway, so I'd like to make a small-scale copy of the Omron testing machine.</p>
<h3>Switches</h3>
<p>The switch fits in a 14mm square hole (apart from the protruding wires), which is the same size
as a Cherry MX switch, but the total height from the bottom of the switch to the top of the keycap
is almost twice as large, about 45 mm vs 25 mm:</p>
<p><a href="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2757"><img src="https://img.incoherency.co.uk/2757"></a></p>
<p>This directly translates to increased keyboard height, so it would be good to cut this down
as much as possible. I should be able to lose 2 mm from the wire support at the bottom of the switch,
and another 1 or 2 mm in the height of the leaf spring attachment, but there's no way it's going to be
as thin as the Cherry MX.</p>
<p>I'd like to find a way to add a tactile bump (ideally with a clicky noise) to the motion of
the plunger. I did try simply adding a bump to the side of the casing that would catch on the
leaf spring, but it didn't work very reliably.</p>
<h3>Keycaps</h3>
<p>Currently my keycaps are based on the one I designed in <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/cad-dojo/stories/keycap.html">my
CAD Dojo project</a>. This is suboptimal for several reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>adding text in FreeCAD is extremely time-consuming, and it can't be edited without deleting it …</li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/3pct-keyboard.html">https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/3pct-keyboard.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://incoherency.co.uk/blog/stories/3pct-keyboard.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23748660</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 15:03:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build to learn – tame your shiny object syndrome]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23748435">thread link</a>) | @BartBoch
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://almostcake.com/buildToLearn.php | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://almostcake.com/buildToLearn.php">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>
                        It sounds simple, yet, it's challenging.<br>
<b>"Build to learn."</b><br>
It's a fantastic tool for chaotic minds.<br>
A way to benefit from your shortcomings.<br>
If you ever fell for the shiny object syndrome (chasing new cool thing, instead of focusing on the present project), then this is for you!
And the best part - you can turn it to your advantage!<br>
Turn it to build momentum, to become a better, wiser, fuller person.</p><p>

When you fell for the shiny, new, better idea, you could've gone through the guilt and growing anxiety for not finishing things.<br>
For some of us, this could end up in depression or/and quitting the whole "maker" realm.<br>
In this post, I will provide you a valid solution to make the most out of the shiny object syndrome. If you have it, at least you can get something positive out of it.<br>
The method, disguised under many names, sometimes called "build to learn," "build to fail," "ship to learn," is meant to make the most of your nature of jumping between the projects.<br>
It's also a way for you to grow as a builder and founder.</p><p>

I first started flirting with the idea independently - then, I found out that there is a micro-movement of sorts doing the same.<br>
Two main places are hubs for this, New York and Silicon Valley. Only there you could try to hack success and look for possible anomalies to benefit from, and still get support from your social circles!<br>
It's evident that financial capital (New York) is much less flexible about it (cross the border and you are gone) than Silicon Valley (cross the border, let's hire him, he might know something we don't).<br>
And then, culture and social conveniences are limiting this movement elsewhere, causing people to quit.<br>
Sadly - if you are from outside of those areas - how can you explain to people around that success is not your goal, and failure is acceptable?<br>
It's easy to treat people trying this method like fakes or daydreamers.<br>
When you go to college and spend 3-5 years learning, then you are a smart person.<br>
If you do the same, but in real life, you might be seen as an outsider.</p><p>

Let's get to the point, though!<br>
The idea is quite simple but might be tricky to pull it off.<br>
It's based on you abandoning the goal of achieving success while focusing on educational aspects.<br>
To create projects that you will stretch and experiment to gain knowledge with a slight chance of success.<br>
So next time you see great opportunity, instead of wondering how you can ride it to the top, wonder what you can get out of it short term.<br>
Will it give you more knowledge?<br>
If so, then how?<br>
Is it worth "educational" wise?<br>
Will you learn new tech/marketing/business knowledge that would be difficult to obtain otherwise?</p><p>

The worst part of working on a project and then quitting it is to get nothing from it.<br>
Sure, we can read a lot of post-mortems, but many say the same things. They ignore the whole process and often end up in a cliche, like "a startup doing exactly this opened at the same time."<br>
And how can you learn from reading the same things over and over?<br>
Going through the process while closely observing everything that happens is key to extensive experience.<br>
Practical knowledge always beats the theoretical.</p><p>

"Build to learn" is about being practical - using theory as a ground, and then build using practical knowledge.<br>
But instead of building a castle, or a palace, we create a set of small constructions first to learn the basics.<br>
Once we can handle the basics, we move to more advanced stuff.<br>
Sooner or later, we will be building the mentioned castles!<br>
If you think you might end up building dozens of projects in search of your success story, you might accept that instead of lying to yourself, and get the most of it.<br>
There is nothing worst than wasting your talents on something meaningful.<br>
Try to push forward; you might finally realize what your real goal is. What's behind your deepest intentions.</p><p>

"Build to learn" is meant to fuel your creativity, not to kill it.<br>
The first step of it is to put a clear goal:<br>
"I build this to learn."<br>
Assume that trophies and achievements are secondary goals.<br>
After all, every major player like Mark Zuckerberg, Steve Jobs, or Richard Branson started with small projects (sometimes failing), then used the knowledge to build something big!</p><p>

Force yourself to break your ego-infused box and look outside of it, to see what are real reasons for you to fail. Learn and keep trying to understand the events happening around you.<br>
You might find out the shortcomings that were unnoticeable!</p><p>

With this reasoning, don't be afraid to keep trying (as long as you won't bet everything on it). Fail, embrace the knowledge you get from it, grow your own self, and be a better person.<br>
Don't fall in the trap of glorifying the failures though - praise the experience instead.<br>
Don't build another shiny project to be the next unicorn company. When you are ready to make the next big thing, you'll know it (and feel it). There will be no guessing, no wondering (at least in the way you see now). There will be calculation and logic behind it.</p><p>

<b>"Experience is simply the name we give our mistakes."</b> - Oscar Wilde.</p><p>

World culture is critical of repeatable failure, even for a good cause.<br>
Fail once - at least you tried, fail twice - you are a fool.<br>
The social pressure is probably the most challenging part of this method.<br>
If success (or at least how people perceive success) is not achieved, you will be labeled as an outsider or even a loser.<br>
Missing a common goal (becoming wealthy) is perceived as an overall failure.<br>
You cannot really translate the perception of failure to make it look normal.<br>
You risk getting your close ones to be skeptical and even cynical of your journey. In extreme cases, I know situations where close circles would turn aggressive against the "rule breaker."<br>
The more "failures" you "achieve," the more negative the overall attitude of the society around you will be.<br>
It's not an easy road, but it's fruitful, to say the least.<br>
You can achieve a level of understanding, where you will see ALL the mechanics behind the money-making machinery.</p><p>

There are some risks when doing this method (as with everything).<br>
Do it for not long enough, and you can get overconfident and biased.<br>
Do it for longer than you should, and you will need months to get out from the trap of setting yourself impossible challenges.<br>
Out of around dozens of people following this method (that I knew directly that is, I assume there are thousands globally), only a few completed it.<br>
Some of them quit due to social pressure (even from their partners). They still got something out of it, and all but one run a small business now (they are unable to scale/grow though).<br>
The rest created profitable companies, often one of the key players in their industry.<br>
From the original group, I was the one that took the longest to complete the road. This is because of the opportunity given to me. My partner was studying, so I did not need to focus on sorting our life as of yet. And I felt that I needed to learn more (programming, viral growth) and to make sure that my ego is under control. I needed more time because my whole life was bumpy, and I thought that some scars could affect my business sense.<br>
I did miss a deadline, though, where I could complete this process without the substantial side-effects.<br>
I knew from conversations with others that by doing this method for too long, you would need to unwind. I thought it would take 2-3 months, but I am in my 9th month, and I feel that I need 2-3 more. Don't get me wrong, I still make money online, but focusing on a small project that's growing slowly is critical to prepare myself mentally for starting massive projects.<br>
I am working on <b>Almost <span>Cake</span></b>, which quickly turned into my full-time job.<br>
<b>Almost <span>Cake</span></b> is a reanimation of one of my old build-to-learn projects that performed well. This is another excellent part of this method - you have a set of field-tested projects, where some might prove to be moneymakers.</p><p>

It took me a few years, and over 30 projects completed to get where I am now, but as said, I did the extreme version of it.<br>
One of the guys that now run a massive operation did 4 "build to learn" projects and spent 1,5 year before he moved ahead (he had some business background though).<br>
Another person with no business experience and with no business-oriented parents completed it with 7 projects and 3 years. He now runs a company that's one of the USA's leading players in his niche.<br>
So, it's hard to say how long you need this run, but the timeframe should not be of the importance here.<br>
The whole point of this method is to tame yourself and start getting somewhere with yourself.</p><p>

The key concerns of "build to learn" are:<br>
-Can you finish the project before you get bored of it? Don't invest in long term projects, when you have a track of abandoning them. You don't need to ship the product or make thousands of dollars. Focus on your initial goals first.<br>
-Can you determine small goals before starting to work on the product? Can you identify a few realistic things you want to get out of this project?<br>
-Will working on this project help you to move forward in a space you want to? If you will learn things you don't feel you need, then maybe it's better to focus elsewhere for now.<br>
-Do you really need to work on the project, or should you turn around and do something completely different? Something that is far beyond your comfort zone?<br>
-Do you have significant chances of achieving your goals with this project? Try not to pursue goals that you assume you will fail. You need to take care of your mental health and not put to much strain on it.</p><p>

Using the "build to learn" method should not become an excuse for you failing to ship. Either you build to learn, or you build to achieve something. You should never go in the middle of the project and say, "just kidding, I was doing it to learn."</p><p>

Sure, if you are already in the middle of the project, then change your goals. But don't do this for future …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://almostcake.com/buildToLearn.php">https://almostcake.com/buildToLearn.php</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://almostcake.com/buildToLearn.php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23748435</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 14:44:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Addio Redis, I'm leaving Redis Labs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23748190">thread link</a>) | @kristoff_it
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://kristoff.it/blog/addio-redis/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kristoff.it/blog/addio-redis/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Thanks Antirez for the code, the Redis manifesto, and for the free karma especially.</p><div><p>Last week I resigned from my position as developer advocate at Redis Labs.</p>
<p>I’ve never talked much about Redis on this blog because I made a point of trying to write interesting posts about different topics, and also to avoid any form of conflict of interest: I didn’t want people to think this blog was being used as a marketing outlet by Redis Labs.</p>
<p>Now that I’m not with the company anymore, I’m looking forward to sharing some of my thoughts on open-source software and related topics, using the direct and energetic tone that I always employ here. </p>
<p>This was the first job I took that wasn’t strictly about programming. It taught me a lot about communication, how information flows between groups of people, and how companies try to shape that flow.</p>
<p>While Redis Labs as a company isn’t perfect — I wouldn’t have left otherwise, and it wouldn’t have hired me in the first place, as I’m not perfect either — I’m happy with my experience overall. The one regret I have is that my position was in part meant to help the community better understand Redis, and I’m leaving behind me basically the same level of confusion that was there when I joined 1.5 years ago.</p>
<p>Redis is less obvious to describe than other tools in the same space, but that alone is not enough to explain why no one seems to agree on what Redis is good at, or what even is Redis. To me, the current situation seems caused by an ongoing turf war between tech companies, starting from the direct competitors of Redis Labs, up to the Cloud giants, who see themselves as the ultimate gatekeepers of modern software architecture.</p>
<p>Each of these factions wants Redis to be a different thing, and so they spend their budget accordingly, starting from developer advocates like me, up to de-facto astroturfers that I’ll leave unnamed. While you and I, dear reader, are surely immune to marketing and scummy tactics, those techniques do work wonders on the public, and the strength of true statements is only used as a way of making marketing spend more efficient.</p>
<p>This is where I imagined I would spell out my take on Redis, but <a href="http://antirez.com/news/133" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">now that Antirez has left the project</a>, it doesn’t matter anymore. Whatever Redis is going to be in the future, it will be shaped by sales tactics, whatever the Clouds are going to do next, and other uninspired metrics.</p>
<p>Since this is my goodbye post to Redis, let me add an over-the-top Italian skit before jumping into the lessons learned.</p>
<h2 id="if-redis-were-pasta"><a href="#if-redis-were-pasta" aria-label="if redis were pasta permalink"></a>If Redis were pasta</h2>
<p>If Redis were pasta, it would be served in a restaurant called Salvatore’s. It would be a plate of spaghetti with tomato sauce and a single leaf of basil on top; basically the Italian symbol for a simple, versatile meal. </p>
<p>Big tech would be like McDonald’s and Burger King: convinced that the future of nutrition is fast-food and constantly screaming that Redis can’t be considered a real meal as it doesn’t contain any bacon: “Come eat our new burger, which now contains an extra 4th layer of meat, exquisitely designed to make it easier to digest the meal!”</p>
<p>On a table you would find Jepsen, essentially the equivalent of Yelp, ideally meant to keep restaurants honest, generally correct, but ultimately not that different from other tech companies, and thus well deserving of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pDlR_ccnZww" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">boogers and cum</a>.</p>
<p>Antirez, largely preferring cooking over serving, would end up selling the restaurant to the waiters, who at that point would make their priority to turn the restaurant into an Olive Garden.</p>
<h2 id="lessons-learned"><a href="#lessons-learned" aria-label="lessons learned permalink"></a>Lessons learned</h2>
<p>So where’s the Redis community in this story? Well, those are just the silent, mostly anonymous regulars that come, eat, and then go on with their lives. </p>
<p>It’s the people that occasionally show up on HN and point out that they’re happy with what Redis does for them, and that they rarely think about it even, as the software tends to chug along nicely. As much as I sympathize with them, the ultimate lesson I learned is that a passive community will inevitably lead to the death of a project.</p>
<p>While the “<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23690123" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">spontaneus software</a>” world is busy infighting, big tech is systematically strip-mining it of any value, even when 99% of the value gets lost in the process. Tech companies are willing to go to any length to capture that 1%, and over time have learned to use Free software arguments against Free software itself, to ensure nobody would stop them.</p>
<p>The future of what we call today open-source software needs to learn to be in equal parts principled and pragmatic. The principles of human spontaneity must be preserved, to ensure we don’t turn in yet another fast-food chain, but we must understand that sophisticated ethical arguments require an equally sophisticated infrastructure beneath them, as without the latter the former can’t materialize into reality.</p>
<p>We need to keep our communities as much as possible engaged and invested in the success of our projects. The flow of information must be kept open and at high pressure, to ensure that our values and goals are well-understood by the majority of the community. Failing to do that means becoming servants of large donors and opening the community to all kinds of manipulations.</p>
<p>We need to reinvent the way we approach spontaneous collaboration in software and we must understand that it’s not going to be a peaceful process. Maybe it’s my native-american blood talking, but I feel I’m ready to get up close and personal with the world I dealt with for the last 1.5 years, except this time I won’t be wearing formal attire.</p>
<p><strong>I’m joining the Zig Software Foundation as VP of Community and it’s going to be my honor and pleasure to try to make all of this a reality for at least one project.</strong> If you want to follow us on this journey, <a href="https://zig.show/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">join us Saturday 11th on Twitch for the live announcement and first fundraising</a>. It’s going to be fun and, if we hit the corresponding donation goal, I will reveal my (until now) secret recipe for a nice summer pasta. Not as simple as Salvatore’s, but pretty good nevertheless.</p>
<p>You can find more info at <a href="https://zig.show/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">https://zig.show</a>.</p>
<figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/fb329/IMG_5653.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <picture>
        <source srcset="https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/f5e3c/IMG_5653.webp 100w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/f2fbe/IMG_5653.webp 200w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/e227a/IMG_5653.webp 400w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/965c5/IMG_5653.webp 600w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/0cbce/IMG_5653.webp 800w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/34ef4/IMG_5653.webp 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" type="image/webp">
        <source srcset="https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/5fb09/IMG_5653.jpg 100w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/f544b/IMG_5653.jpg 200w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/41689/IMG_5653.jpg 400w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/82472/IMG_5653.jpg 600w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/a296c/IMG_5653.jpg 800w,
https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/fb329/IMG_5653.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" type="image/jpeg">
        <img src="https://kristoff.it/static/7ffb8dd2d51fdeda298fa5f212e48bbe/41689/IMG_5653.jpg" alt="A photo I took at the last AWS reinvent." title="Fuck you AWS.">
      </picture>
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption>Fuck you AWS.</figcaption>
  </figure></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kristoff.it/blog/addio-redis/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23748190</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 14:23:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why is Berkshire Hathaway sitting on $137B in cash?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23747918">thread link</a>) | @sunnykgupta
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://eachlist.com/why-is-berkshire-hathaway-sitting-on-137-billion-in-cash/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://eachlist.com/why-is-berkshire-hathaway-sitting-on-137-billion-in-cash/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
<p>Think finance and Mr. Buffet is one of the first names that comes to mind. Warren Buffet has had humble beginnings, his life changed drastically with an impulsive takeover of the Berkshire Hathaway Inc.</p>



<p>If you aren’t aware of the history behind Buffet’s reasoning behind acquiring Berkshire, it is worth reading and marvelling over.</p>



<p>Over the course of next few decades, Warren Buffet went on to take the company to new highs. In 2019, the company reported having more than 817 Billion USD in assets. </p>



<p>The most surprising part for avid investors though, has been the fact that Berkshire Hathaway has north of $137 Billion in cash and cash reserves!</p>



<p>That is a lot of cash to keep in had, especially when the markets seem to be going up. Most recently in May 2020, they exited almost all their holdings in the airline industry netting them about $6 Billion.</p>



<p>Does that mean Berkshire thinks the markets are overvalues and hyped at the moment? It is not very clear.</p>



<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> As we were about to publish this article, we got a notification about <a href="https://eachlist.com/buffets-10-billion-bet-on-dominion-energy-inc/">Berkshire’s largest deal in 4 years – the $10 Billion bet on Dominion Energy.</a></p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://eachlist.com/why-is-berkshire-hathaway-sitting-on-137-billion-in-cash/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23747918</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 14:01:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[H.266/Versatile Video Coding (VVC)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 434 | Comments 382 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23747626">thread link</a>) | @caution
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://newsletter.fraunhofer.de/-viewonline2/17386/465/11/14SHcBTt/V44RELLZBp/1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://newsletter.fraunhofer.de/-viewonline2/17386/465/11/14SHcBTt/V44RELLZBp/1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://newsletter.fraunhofer.de/-viewonline2/17386/465/11/14SHcBTt/V44RELLZBp/1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23747626</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 13:28:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[M60 – Open-Source USB&BLE, Hot-Swappable Mechanical Keyboard Powered by Python]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 119 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23747255">thread link</a>) | @kfihihc
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://makerdiary.com/pages/m60-mechanical-keyboard | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://makerdiary.com/pages/m60-mechanical-keyboard">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="PageContainer">

    <main id="MainContent" role="main" tabindex="-1">
      <div id="shopify-section-landing-page-hero"><div data-section-id="landing-page-hero" data-section-type="hero-section">
  
     <a href="https://github.com/makerdiary/python-keyboard" aria-label="View source on GitHub"></a>
  
<div id="Hero-landing-page-hero" data-layout="full_width" data-bg="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_300x300.jpg?v=1593771860" data-bgset="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_180x.jpg?v=1593771860 180w 120h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_360x.jpg?v=1593771860 360w 240h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_540x.jpg?v=1593771860 540w 360h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_720x.jpg?v=1593771860 720w 480h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_900x.jpg?v=1593771860 900w 600h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_1080x.jpg?v=1593771860 1080w 720h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_1296x.jpg?v=1593771860 1296w 864h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_1512x.jpg?v=1593771860 1512w 1008h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_1728x.jpg?v=1593771860 1728w 1152h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0_1950x.jpg?v=1593771860 1950w 1300h,
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60_hero_2048x_168dcced-db74-498b-94f3-01b98f24ada0.jpg?v=1593771860 2048w 1365h" data-sizes="auto" data-parent-fit="cover"><div>
        <div><h2>M60 Mechanical Keyboard</h2><p>An Open Source, USB &amp; BLE 5.0, Modular, Hot-Swappable, 60% Keyboard powered by Python</p><p><a href="https://makerdiary.com/products/m60-mechanical-keyboard-pcba" aria-label="Pre-Order PCBA: M60 Mechanical Keyboard PCBA (Pre-Order)">Pre-Order PCBA</a></p></div>
      </div>
    </div>
    </div>



</div>





<div id="shopify-section-landing-page-map">

<div id="MapSection--landing-page-map" data-section-id="landing-page-map" data-section-type="map">
  <div>
    <div>
      <div>
        
        
          <h3>The Story of M60</h3>
        
        
          <p>A few months ago, we made a hand-wired keyboard and brought Python to it. This project received plenty of attention, but it is difficult for most people to make such a keyboard. We believe that a Python powered keyboard will make a big difference. We'd really like to take this work further, so we start to design a new keyboard hardware. It is called <em>M60</em>.</p>
          
        
      </div>
    </div>
    
  </div>
</div>




</div>

<div>

<div id="shopify-section-landing-page-feature-row">
<div>
  

  <div>
    
      
    <p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-connectivity-1_1080x_5c2254bf-6f4a-41b8-a449-1c0f4088f20a_600x600@2x.jpg?v=1593785687" alt="" data-old-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-connectivity-1_1080x_5c2254bf-6f4a-41b8-a449-1c0f4088f20a_200x200.jpg?v=1593785687" data-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-connectivity-1_1080x_5c2254bf-6f4a-41b8-a449-1c0f4088f20a_{width}x.jpg?v=1593785687">

        
      
    </p>
  
    

    <div>
      
        <h2>USB Type-C &amp; BLE 5.0 Connectivity</h2>
      
      
        <p>M60 uses Nordic’s nRF52840 SoC to provide USB Type-C wired and Bluetooth LE 5.0 wireless connectivity. It can easily pair to your PC, laptop, smartphone, or tablet with Bluetooth LE.</p>
      
      
    </div>

    
  </div>
</div>


</div>

<div id="shopify-section-landing-page-feature-row-1">
<div>
  

  <div>
    

    <div>
      
        <h2>Powered by Python</h2>
      
      
        <p>It's not just a keyboard but also a USB drive containing Python files. Its Python code can be changed with any text editor and executed simultaneously, which makes it super easy to customize the keyboard or to add a new function. No need to download any software or setup a development environment.</p>
      
      
    </div>

    
      
    <p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-feature-row-2-python_1_600x600@2x.jpg?v=1593761089" alt="" data-old-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-feature-row-2-python_1_200x200.jpg?v=1593761089" data-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-feature-row-2-python_1_{width}x.jpg?v=1593761089">

        
      
    </p>
  
    
  </div>
</div>




</div>

<div id="shopify-section-landing-page-feature-row-2"><div>
  

  <div>
    
      
    <p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-feature-row-3_600x600@2x.jpg?v=1593752688" alt="" data-old-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-feature-row-3_200x200.jpg?v=1593752688" data-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-feature-row-3_{width}x.jpg?v=1593752688">

        
      
    </p>
  
    

    <div>
      
        <h2>Modular, Hot-Swappable &amp; Solder-Free</h2>
      
      
        <p>To take advantage of the <a href="https://makerdiary.com/products/nrf52840-m2-module" title="nRF52840 M.2 Module w/ PCB Antennas">removable M.2 module</a> and hot-swap sockets, assembly made easy. Everyday we find innovative assembly solutions to make things even easier for you because we care about the quality of our products.</p>
      
      
    </div>

    
  </div>
</div>




</div>



</div>

<div id="shopify-section-landing-page-logo-list">

<div>
  
    
  

  
    <ul>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>GitHub</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Cross-platform</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Multi-connections</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Python</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>60% Layout</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Multi-layers</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Highly configurable</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>RGB Lighting</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Battery</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>NKRO - Anti-ghost</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Productivity</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Modular Design</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>BLE 5.0</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>USB Type-C</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>NFC</p>
          
        </li>
      
        <li>
          
          
              
          
          
          
            <p>Hot-swappable</p>
          
        </li>
      
    </ul>
  

  
</div>




</div>

<div id="shopify-section-landing-page-hero-small">


<div data-section-id="landing-page-hero-small" data-section-type="hero-section"><div id="Hero-landing-page-hero-small" data-layout="full_width" data-bg="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_300x300.jpg?v=1593684925" data-bgset="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_180x.jpg?v=1593684925 180w 65h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_360x.jpg?v=1593684925 360w 130h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_540x.jpg?v=1593684925 540w 194h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_720x.jpg?v=1593684925 720w 259h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_900x.jpg?v=1593684925 900w 324h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_1080x.jpg?v=1593684925 1080w 389h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_1296x.jpg?v=1593684925 1296w 466h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_1512x.jpg?v=1593684925 1512w 544h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_1728x.jpg?v=1593684925 1728w 622h,
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x_1950x.jpg?v=1593684925 1950w 702h,
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    //cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/files/m60-sample-2048x.jpg?v=1593684925 2048w 737h" data-sizes="auto" data-parent-fit="cover"><div>
        <div><p>We have prepared a few M60 PCBAs for developers before launch. If you really want to get involved early in the process, you can apply for an engineering sample.</p><p><a href="https://forms.office.com/Pages/ResponsePage.aspx?id=DQSIkWdsW0yxEjajBLZtrQAAAAAAAAAAAAa__aO1qn1UQktDRjFSN1FWRFRFRU0yRzhOT0xIUlNKSi4u" aria-label="Request a Sample">Request a Sample</a></p></div>
      </div>
    </div>
    </div>



</div>



<div id="shopify-section-landing-page-feature-update">
<div>
  
    
  

    <ul>
      
        <li>
          <article aria-labelledby="FeaturedBlogTitle-0-landing-page-feature-update">
            <header>
              <a href="https://makerdiary.com/blogs/mechanical-keyboards/the-story-of-m60-mechanical-keyboard">
                
                  
                  


                  <p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/articles/m60-feature-row-1-1080x_1024x1024_45ae6d5b-e37c-4137-a179-bf1f89d42730_345x345@2x.jpg?v=1593768689" alt="M60 Mechanical Keyboard - from Prototype to Production" data-old-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/articles/m60-feature-row-1-1080x_1024x1024_45ae6d5b-e37c-4137-a179-bf1f89d42730_300x300.jpg?v=1593768689" data-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/articles/m60-feature-row-1-1080x_1024x1024_45ae6d5b-e37c-4137-a179-bf1f89d42730_{width}x.jpg?v=1593768689">
                    </p>
                  
                

                <h3 id="FeaturedBlogTitle-0-landing-page-feature-update">
                  M60 Mechanical Keyboard - from Prototype to Production
                </h3>
              </a>

              

              
                <span>
                  <time datetime="2020-07-03T08:49:00Z">July 3, 2020</time>
                </span>
              
            </header>

            <div>
              <p><span>A few months ago, we made a hand-wired keyboard powered by Python. It's a typical prototype, which got a lot of feedback. So we decided to turn the prototype into production, to make a new keyboard called M60.</span>
                
              </p>

              

              <ul>
                <li>
                  <a href="https://makerdiary.com/blogs/mechanical-keyboards/the-story-of-m60-mechanical-keyboard" aria-label="Read more: M60 Mechanical Keyboard - from Prototype to Production">
                    Read more
                  </a>
                </li>

                
              </ul>
            </div>
          </article>
        </li>
      
        <li>
          <article aria-labelledby="FeaturedBlogTitle-1-landing-page-feature-update">
            <header>
              <a href="https://makerdiary.com/blogs/mechanical-keyboards/a-hand-wired-usb-bluetooth-keyboard-powered-by-python">
                
                  
                  


                  <p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/articles/python-inside-keyboard_345x345@2x.png?v=1593765150" alt="Hand-wiring a USB &amp; Bluetooth keyboard powered by Python" data-old-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/articles/python-inside-keyboard_300x300.png?v=1593765150" data-src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0066/0865/0355/articles/python-inside-keyboard_{width}x.png?v=1593765150">
                    </p>
                  
                

                <h3 id="FeaturedBlogTitle-1-landing-page-feature-update">
                  Hand-wiring a USB &amp; Bluetooth keyboard powered by Python
                </h3>
              </a>

              

              
                <span>
                  <time datetime="2020-05-04T11:39:00Z">May 4, 2020</time>
                </span>
              
            </header>

            <div>
              <p>Before making this keyboard, I knew Python can be used in a microcontroller thanks to MicroPython and its variant CircuitPython. But I did not know Python can work so well and be so powerful in a keyboard. It's beyond my expectation.</p>

              

              <ul>
                <li>
                  <a href="https://makerdiary.com/blogs/mechanical-keyboards/a-hand-wired-usb-bluetooth-keyboard-powered-by-python" aria-label="Read more: Hand-wiring a USB &amp; Bluetooth keyboard powered by Python">
                    Read more
                  </a>
                </li>

                
              </ul>
            </div>
          </article>
        </li>
      
    </ul>
  

  
    
    
  
</div>




</div>


    </main>

    

    

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://makerdiary.com/pages/m60-mechanical-keyboard</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23747255</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 12:42:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How People Learn – The Brain Basics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23746896">thread link</a>) | @iuliangulea
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://iuliangulea.com/blog/how-people-learn-the-brain-basics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://iuliangulea.com/blog/how-people-learn-the-brain-basics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

    
    <p>Have you ever thought about how people learn? What happens inside your brain when you learn some new information or practice a novel skill? And is there a way to enhance the outcomes of learning?</p>
<p>This article is the first in the series on “How People Learn,” in which I invite you to embark on a journey toward a better understanding of the most sophisticated construct in the Universe—the human brain.</p>
<p>And I would like to start with and exercise. You will need a piece of paper and something to write with. When you have them ready, write down the following sentence:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>I can write fast and beautiful.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>It should be pretty easy, if not effortless, isn’t it?</p>
<p>Now, I would like you to write the same sentence one more time, below the first one, but at this time, use the opposite hand (let’s call it the inexperienced hand). Therefore, if you initially wrote the sentence with your right hand, switch your pen to the left side and vice-versa.</p>
<p>Think about how was it now? Unless you are a person that learned to write with both hands, I bet your second sentence is not that beautiful, and you wrote it not that fast either. When I was lecturing at the university and doing this exercise with my students, it took them somewhere between 3 to 10 times longer to write down the second sentence than the first one.</p>
<p>If you did follow through and write the two sentences, I highly encourage you to write it with the inexperienced hand for the third (and last) time below the first two sentences. It should be slightly easier to write it now, but there will still be inadvertent trembling and awkward lines.</p>
<p>How do you explain this? You know how each letter should look, how it should be tilted, and how curved it should be—you possess the theory at 100%. Yet very few can draw a well-rounded letter ‘a’ or ‘o’ with their inexperienced hand. It is very likely that you are also holding your pen as though it weighs 5kg, and your hand is trembling in the process.</p>
<h2 id="a-primer-on-brain-structure">A Primer On Brain Structure</h2>
<p>The answer resides in the structure of the brain. As you might know, the brain consists of brain cells called “neurons.” Let’s represent a neuron as in the next image.</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/one-neuron.png" alt="A Conceptual Representation Of A Neuron"></p>
<p>Neurons connect to other neurons, forming a complex net of interconnected brain cells. According to the latest plausible estimates,<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> there are 86 billion neurons in a human brain. And each cell can connect to up to ten thousand other neurons. That is an astounding amount!</p>
<p>I will not attempt to draw such a complex, interconnected set of neurons as in a human brain. I will not try to represent even the 302 neurons with its ~7,500 connections of a roundworm.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> Instead, I will rely on this <em>extremely</em> simplified version of a <strike>brain</strike> group of interconnected neurons to describe some essential events that take place inside one’s brain.</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/many-interconnected-neurons.png" alt="A Conceptual Representation Of Many Interconnected Neurons"></p>
<p>All our memories, experiences, skills, thoughts, sensations, etc. are encoded and stored within those interconnected brain cells.</p>
<h2 id="neural-patterns">Neural Patterns</h2>
<p>Neurons communicate with each other through electric pulses and chemical neurotransmitters. Whenever we do something or think about something, specific neurons responsible for that action or thought get activated by sending impulses to each other. For instance, when you raise your right hand, a particular group of neurons gets activated simultaneously:</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/neurons-raise-hand.png" alt="A conceptual representation of the neural pattern responsible for raising your right hand"></p>
<p>When you write, another group of neurons fires together:</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/neurons-write.png" alt="A conceptual representation of the neural pattern responsible for writing"></p>
<p>These groups of neurons that fire together are called <em>neural patterns.</em> When activated, they are responsible for specific actions or thoughts. Keep in mind that the examples above are extremely simplified. Real patterns spread throughout large portions of the brain and can incorporate billions of neurons.</p>
<p>Note that these patterns can overlap, meaning that the same neuron or even huge chunks of neurons can be part of several patterns. Below you can see that <em>“writing”</em> and <em>“raising hand”</em> share some of their neurons.</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/neurons-common-neurons.png" alt="A conceptual representation of the neurons that participate in both raising hand and speaking"></p>
<p>This explains the associative nature of memory and our experiences—as you are thinking about something specific (i.e., your favorite childhood cartoon), parts of the neural patterns that get activated are also parts of circuits related to other memories. That gives you the possibility to “hop” from one memory to the other. Just try to recall an instance of when you watched that cartoon and let your mind wander for some time. You’ll be pleasantly surprised with where it might lead you.</p>
<h2 id="it-is-not-only-about-the-number-of-connections">It Is Not Only About The Number Of Connections</h2>
<p>Besides the number of neurons, one essential thing that characterizes a pattern is the strength of its connections. A connection can be strong or can be weak, and it represents the relationship between two neurons.</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/neurons-strong-connections.png" alt="A conceptual representation of a neural pattern with different connection strengths between neurons"></p>
<p>In the image above, the thicker lines represent more durable links. The stronger a bond is, the easier it is to communicate between neurons through it, and the harder and longer it takes to break it apart. We’ll see the implications of this in the next section below.</p>
<p>Therefore, activities that we know how to do and with which we have experience and thoughts that we think about often have strong links between neurons in their associated patterns. Conversely, skills we have just begun to practice, or thoughts we rarely think about have weak circuits.</p>
<p>To make an analogy, think of a link between two neurons as a pathway during winter.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://storage.needpix.com/rsynced_images/trace-3438236_1280.jpg" alt="Snow Trail"> <figcaption>
            <p>Source:
                    <a href="https://www.needpix.com/photo/download/1618289/trace-snow-background-mood-wintry-snow-tramp-footprints-snow-lane-deep-snow">Needpix.com</a></p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Initially, when you have to go from point A to B, there is no path, so you have to walk through deep snow, leaving a narrow trail in the process. Have you ever walked in deep snow? That is exhausting, and so forming new circuits is. But the more you travel along that path, the more trodden it becomes, and the easier it is to walk it. Eventually, it will become a wide sidewalk that you can use to travel between point A and B effortlessly. But if you will abandon that path, the snow will gradually claim it back, until one day it will just disappear.</p>
<h2 id="the-process-of-forming-new-circuits">The Process Of Forming New Circuits</h2>
<p>Thus, all the information we know and skills we possess are encoded in our brains’ neural patterns. It is time to discuss the process of brain circuits administration. Research from the last 100 years has incredibly advanced the understanding of how the brain rewires itself. This process is called  <em>Neuroplasticity.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Neuroplasticity,</strong> also known as <strong>brain plasticity,</strong> is the ability of the brain to undergo biological changes ranging from the cellular level (i.e., individual neurons) all the way to large-scale changes involving cortical remapping.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>One of the fundamental principles of how neuroplasticity functions is the idea that individual connections within the brain are continually being created, strengthened, or removed, largely dependent upon how they are used.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup> Thus, neurons that are in close proximity and fire at the same time tend to form new connections (or, if they are already connected, the link strengthens). But in case a relationship is not used, it weakens over time, and eventually, it disappears, leaving the two neurons disconnected.</p>
<p>This theory was first introduced by Donald Hebb in 1949, and it is often summarized as <em>“neurons that fire together, wire together."</em></p>
<h2 id="going-back-to-writing">Going Back To Writing</h2>
<p>Knowing all that about our brain circuits and how they function, let’s analyze the previous writing exercise and describe it using our freshly acquired information.</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/neurons-write-strong-connections.png" alt="Strong neural circuit responsible for writing with the experienced hand"></p>
<p>When you first wrote the sentence with your “regular” hand, you have used your existing, robust neural pattern responsible for writing with that hand. That’s why it felt natural and seamless.</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/2-hands-with-question-mark.png" alt="Inexistent neural circuit responsible for writing with the inexperienced hand"></p>
<p>But when you switched to the other hand, no pattern was found responsible for writing with that hand, so a new one started to emerge.</p>
<p><img src="https://iuliangulea.com/images/how-people-learn/2-hands-with-both-patterns.png" alt="Emerging neural circuit responsible for writing with the experienced hand"></p>
<p>Different neurons fired together while you were striving to write each letter, and new links started to form. In case you followed my advice and wrote the sentence for the third time, the writing process should have flown more easygoing. That’s because the new pattern is strengthening in the brain! The more you will practice writing with that hand, the easier it will become for you.</p>
<p>This simple exercise demonstrated a fundamental truth that we sometimes ignore:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Knowledge != Skills</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>We have a sound pattern responsible for the knowledge about each individual letter and another circuit that is responsible for writing those letters. If you would take one thing out of this article, please remember this: <strong>knowledge</strong> does not necessarily mean <strong>skills.</strong> You might know something (the alphabet), but this does not imply than you will be able to write those letters.</p>
<p>This principle applies to many areas of our lives. For instance, reading a book on self-improvement, sales, public speaking, or anything else, does not magically teach you the skills described in those books. Reading those books will strengthen your neuronal pattern related to knowing. It’s like learning the shape of letters, the theory. Only when you begin to write, when you apply the theory into practice, then you start developing the patterns responsible for the actual skills.</p>
<p>There is much more to possessing an ability than just knowing the theory:</p>
<ul>
<li>Knowing the shape of the letters is not enough to be able to write. You need to develop proper muscle movement to hold the pen and draw the lines that form the letters.</li>
<li>Knowing some five steps to efficient sales is not enough to be a salesman. You need to learn to listen to customers, understand what relevant questions to ask, process the information you receive, formulate correct benefits that solve their problems, etc.</li>
<li>Knowing how to write code does is not enough to be a programmer. You need to understand how to define the architecture of a project based on the requirements, how to organize and structure your code, how to test it, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>It does not mean that the theory is not essential. Conversely, knowledge about a domain helps you gain experience faster since you can interpret how good or bad the outcome of your practice is. As described in <a href="https://iuliangulea.com/blog/the-path-toward-mastery-how-to-become-an-expert/">The Pyramid Of Mastery</a>, knowledge and skills are complementary. …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://iuliangulea.com/blog/how-people-learn-the-brain-basics/">https://iuliangulea.com/blog/how-people-learn-the-brain-basics/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://iuliangulea.com/blog/how-people-learn-the-brain-basics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23746896</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 11:50:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[“Industrial Society and its Future”: the writings of the Unabomber]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 117 | Comments 167 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23746087">thread link</a>) | @roelp_be
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://www.roelpeters.be/industrial-society-and-its-future-the-intelligent-yet-angry-writings-of-a-terrorist/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.roelpeters.be/industrial-society-and-its-future-the-intelligent-yet-angry-writings-of-a-terrorist/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<h2>Preface to this blog post</h2>



<p>Why review a book from the hand of a notorious terrorist who killed three and maimed dozens of people? That seems like the right question to answer before continuing this blog post. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ted_Kaczynski">Theodore J. Kaczynski</a> is an extremely intelligent yet wounded man. He’s been a victim of cold-war era social experiments and, throughout his life, has always been an outsider. He retreated from society and lived like a hermit in the woods in Montana. Nevertheless, he was an activist in search of attention for his ideology and manifesto.</p>



<p>Numerous human lives have been sacrificed on the altars of freedom, ideology, and a better world. Wherever you position yourself on the political spectrum, from left to right, your heroes have blood on their hands. Reagan, Lenin, Bush, Mao, Napoleon, Robespierre, Obama, Chavez, Macron, Selassie, and Guevara, in one way or another, are responsible for the death and suffering of many. Yet we read their memoirs, manifestoes, and biographies. We have their posters on the walls of our children’s rooms. In this light, <strong>the refusal to read and review <em>Industrial Society and its Future</em> would be an act of hypocrisy. </strong></p>



<p>Finally, the central claim that technology is inherently bad for society is of relevance to this blog. I completely distance myself from the man’s actions, but his manifesto definitely struck a chord. I currently cannot think of a better way to scrutinize my techno-optimism than to write about it.</p>



<h2>The Power Process</h2>



<p><em>Industrial Society and its Future</em> is an essay of 232 numbered paragraphs in which Kaczynski explains what’s wrong with society, how it should be, and how we can get there. The most interesting parts of the essay describe the core concept of the <em>Power Process</em>, its consequences, and how technology has an impact on it.</p>



<p><strong>Human drives</strong> can be classified in three broad categories:</p>



<ul><li>Drives that can be satisfied with minimal effort: a walk around the block.</li><li>Drives that can be satisfied at the cost of serious effort: chopping down a tree for burning wood.</li><li>Drives that cannot be satisfied, no matter the effort one puts in it: somersault from a high cliff and survive it</li></ul>



<p>Kaczynski claims that <strong>all humans need a power process</strong>: (1) we all need goals, (2) effort to attain them, and (3) the attainment of some of these goals. Finally, it requires a degree of (4) autonomy. Consequently, the power process is part of the second category of human drives.</p>



<p>If unattained goals result in death, they are important. If the non-attainment of one’s goals is compatible with survival (i.e. not important), it will lead to defeatism, low self-esteem, and depression (as I explain later on). In the Western world, one only needs minimum effort to survive. Satisfying biological needs has been reduced to triviality. One can live off welfare checks, or have a bullshit job to satisfy physical needs. The only thing required is a minimal degree of obedience. Humans have given up autonomy and effort to attain the needs to survive — the important goals.  That’s why humans artificially create the four components of the power process for themselves: they are involved in <strong>surrogate activities</strong>: long-distance running, blogging, collecting stamps, gardening and even pursuing an academic career. </p>



<h2>Technology messes with the power process</h2>



<p>Kaczynski distinguishes between <strong>two kinds of technology</strong>: The first one is <strong>small-scale technology</strong>, like a mill or a water wheel. The second kind is <strong>organization-dependent technology</strong> that requires large-scale social organization: A refrigerator depends on complicated and industrially created parts and requires electricity. The first kind can produce real progress and freedom. The second kind has a negative impact on our freedom: the externalities outweigh the benefits. It’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prisoner%27s_dilemma">the prisoner’s dilemma</a> on a global scale.</p>



<p>Since the Industrial Revolution, most new technologies are of the second kind. The wave of <em>smart</em> and <em>connected</em> devices and software that’s heading our way is no different. Algorithms can curate all available information on our timelines, only inviting more and more (fake?) articles to be produced. Autonomous cars are safer and offer the freedom to keep the hands of the wheel. Yet as self-driving cars are simply sensors on wheels, you will have zero privacy regarding your location. Self-service checkouts are supposed to be faster. Yet as supermarket customers more often use them, fewer registers with cashiers will be available, reducing human personal contact. Oh, and you need a loyalty card, which is digital-only, for which you need a smartphone.</p>



<p>Social and psychological problems arise when humans cannot go through the power process. <strong>In modern society, technology (especially of the second kind) tends to push drives into the first group</strong>: gathering food is now <a href="https://www.ubereats.com/">one tap away</a>.  Intimacy can be achieved by <a href="https://tinder.com/">swiping</a> or paying a <a href="https://www.pornhub.com/live">minimum fee</a>. Leisure can be found on <a href="https://www.netflix.com/be-en/">Netflix</a> or <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/">Steam</a>. Turn up the heat by asking your <a href="https://store.google.com/us/magazine/compare_thermostats">Nest</a>. </p>



<p>On the other hand,<strong> technology also moved other drives into the third category</strong>. With urbanization reaching record numbers; experiencing authenticity, harmony, nature, silence, and clean air is nearly impossible for many inhabitants of this planet.</p>



<p><strong>Some important goals that remain in the second category, like achieving status, can no longer be done autonomously</strong>. To reach the highest echelons of the corporate ladder, one needs to adhere to company culture, engage in networking, and pass opaque assessments. A management position is often at the goodwill of another manager, higher up.</p>



<p>The primitive man only had to fear disease and certain aspects of the environment. He could accept this stoically, or invent gods and demons. But these problems weren’t man-made, imposed on them by someone’s decision which he had no impact on. Although many of us create them for themselves, for others,<strong> surrogate activities do not suffice. The results are aggression, mental breakdowns, burnouts, depressions, mid-life crises, and declining fertility.</strong> As decisions are increasingly outsourced to <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/machine-bias-risk-assessments-in-criminal-sentencing"><em>trustworthy </em>and <em>unbiased</em> machines</a> — think<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/01/12/technology/facial-recognition-police.html"> facial recognition by police departments</a>, or <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2019/01/21/137783/algorithms-criminal-justice-ai/">algorithms sending people to jail</a> — hopelessness and rebellion will only increase.</p>



<p>In modern society, mental health is defined by how one behaves in accord with the needs of the system.</p>



<h2>Technology is a rational response to problems</h2>



<p>A compromise between freedom and technology is impossible because technology is a more powerful social force than the aspiration for freedom. That’s because each new technology appears to be desirable<strong> and only threatens our freedom later on</strong>. Motorized transport allows us to travel a lot farther. Yet once the adoption of cars reaches a critical threshold, one is <em>expected</em> to own a car: Local shops and public services disappear and become centralized in malls and government buildings. The internet allowed us to communicate with each other faster than ever. As companies adopted the internet, one can no longer apply for a job without an internet connection. Technology changes society as to make itself indispensable.</p>



<p>The following words read like a prophecy: “<em>Generally speaking, <strong>technological control over human behavior will probably not be introduced with a totalitarian intention</strong> or even through a conscious desire to restrict human freedom. Each new step in the assertion of control over the humankind will be taken as a rational response to a problem that faces society…”</em></p>



<p>For example, society has given up privacy to battle COVID-19 with apps and track&amp;trace strategies. Facebook promised us freedom of speech and unlimited reach, but without the financial means, you’re <a href="https://blog.hootsuite.com/facebook-algorithm/">shouting in a vacuum</a>. The Patriot Act (and the <a href="https://www.aclu.org/issues/national-security/privacy-and-surveillance/surveillance-under-patriot-act">mass surveillance technology</a> that came with it) was designed to battle terrorism but introduced legal arbitrariness. These three examples were all <strong>rational responses to existing problems but produced unforeseen externalities</strong>.</p>



<p>As technology makes itself indispensable, machines will take care of more and more tasks and “<em>on those who are employed, ever-increasing demands will be placed: the will need more training, more and more ability, and will have to be ever more reliable, conforming and docile, because they will be more and more like cells of a giant organism.</em>“</p>



<p>Think of the swarm of Uber or Lyft drivers who took a short training on how to use the app and are now driving people around in servile silence. Their data feeds the algorithm, and the algorithm thinks for them. <strong>The only thing left is to abide by the system.</strong></p>



<h2>Revolution</h2>



<p>Which brings us to Kaczynski’s “solution”. This topic lacks the depth and cunning analogies that can be found in the earlier chapters. His recipes aren’t new: one can find elements of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mikhail_Bakunin">Bakunist</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cultural_hegemony">Gramscist</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foco">Debrayist</a> thinking.</p>



<p>Because technology is the strongest social force, <strong>gradual change is impossible</strong>. The only way to break this circle, this slippery slope to servitude to the machine, is a revolution. While the system might collapse under its own internal difficulties, Kaczynski claims we should promote social stress and instability in industrial society. Humanity should return to nature to live in small groups and to be in control of life-and-death issues: food, clothing, shelter, and defense. This is true freedom: the power to control the circumstances of one’s own life. It’s not an ideology, it’s Nature with a big N:</p>



<p><em>“We have no illusions about the feasibility of creating a new, ideal form of society. Our goal is only to destroy the existing form of society.”</em></p>



<h2>Final thoughts</h2>



<p>Manifestos are always dull, so I didn’t expect this book to be an enjoyable read. But quite a lot of insights were so masterfully crafted, that I often had to allow my mind to wander off in a quest to find (counter-)examples and arguments to what I just read. If you’re into political theory, this will be a treat.</p>



<p>Nevertheless, the structure of the book and the order of the chapters seemed strange to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.roelpeters.be/industrial-society-and-its-future-the-intelligent-yet-angry-writings-of-a-terrorist/">https://www.roelpeters.be/industrial-society-and-its-future-the-intelligent-yet-angry-writings-of-a-terrorist/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.roelpeters.be/industrial-society-and-its-future-the-intelligent-yet-angry-writings-of-a-terrorist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23746087</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 09:26:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News Design Is Ugly]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23745595">thread link</a>) | @neilpanchal
<br/>
July 6, 2020 | https://neil.computer/notes/hacker-news-design-is-ugly/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://neil.computer/notes/hacker-news-design-is-ugly/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <article>
        <h2>Hacker News Design is Ugly</h2>
        <p>This thing is straight up ugly. It is too simple, useful, pragmatic, dense and practical. Boring. These days the cool things are purple gradients, lots of negative space and loss of contrast. People on HN keep <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23199603">raving</a> about this design thing but boy they are so wrong.</p><p>Let's fix it.</p><h2 id="current-state">Current State</h2><p>This is what HN front-page looks like when you login. It has absolutely zero pop. Typical engineers, what do they know about design?</p><figure><img src="https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.01-PM.png" alt="" width="1938" height="2254" srcset="https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.01-PM.png 600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.01-PM.png 1000w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.01-PM.png 1600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.01-PM.png 1938w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Let's make it pop, shall we?</p><h2 id="fixing-hn-design">Fixing HN Design</h2><p>First things first. <em>Padding</em>. When I am bored, running out of ideas, I like to do one thing that usually makes things 10x better. Padding is like a chef's knife in the kitchen. Know how to use it well and you'll be cutting through information rich UI like butter. It is what sets professional designers from these gray-beard types.</p><p>It is difficult to do it right, so please allow me to exemplify the process. First, add padding to the <code>body</code> tag.</p><figure><img src="https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.35-PM.png" alt="" width="1938" height="2254" srcset="https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.35-PM.png 600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.35-PM.png 1000w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.35-PM.png 1600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.35.35-PM.png 1938w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>See the difference? Holy crap. The UI just suddenly started <em>breathing</em>.</p><p>Let's add more spacing between this conjested highly dense information rich piece of shit.</p><figure><img src="https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.37.35-PM.png" alt="" width="1938" height="2254" srcset="https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.37.35-PM.png 600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.37.35-PM.png 1000w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.37.35-PM.png 1600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.37.35-PM.png 1938w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>The color orange is fine with me but it is not gonna get you through the design school and into the real world. The world today demands magenta. Magenta/Purple/Cyan all inspired by Stripe UI since 2015 or so and it really set the standard for a modern color palette. Throw your creativity and objectivity away, the trend dictates what we should choose<em>.</em> May be it PANTONE will come up with a <a href="https://www.pantone.com/color-intelligence/color-of-the-year/color-of-the-year-2020">color of the year</a> and it will change. But as per current design trends, purple is the safe choice.</p><figure><img src="https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.53.20-PM.png" alt="" width="2598" height="2254" srcset="https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.53.20-PM.png 600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.53.20-PM.png 1000w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.53.20-PM.png 1600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w2400/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.53.20-PM.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>BAM. What you didn't notice is I also got rid of all background colors to flatten things a bit. I hate borders which are a graphical device invented to create logical spatial layouts but those things are for boring websites for techy folks.</p><p>Next up. Pro tip: Border-radius. It is not as complicated as it sounds. Simply put, we like to make things rounded as allows us to compete for a one of those web design <a href="https://www.awwwards.com/">awwwards</a> and border-radius is a mandatory requirement before creating a <a href="https://dribbble.com/">dribbble</a> account. So we must comply without the thought of originality.</p><figure><img src="https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.54.51-PM.png" alt="" width="2598" height="2254" srcset="https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.54.51-PM.png 600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.54.51-PM.png 1000w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.54.51-PM.png 1600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w2400/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.54.51-PM.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>See? It really ties the web page together.</p><p>Those pesky informative sub-titles are jarring as it helps the user too much. Let's make it so that it loses contrast and fades away in the background. As a side effect, it makes the whole thing more minimal. Minimalism at all costs. Try to make things minimal by removing features and neutring functionality - no one will ever notice. </p><figure><img src="https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.55.33-PM.png" alt="" width="2598" height="2254" srcset="https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.55.33-PM.png 600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.55.33-PM.png 1000w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.55.33-PM.png 1600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w2400/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-05-at-11.55.33-PM.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>It looks minimal af.</p><p>That's all folks. Hacker News redesigned. These are the basics but if there is enough interest, I can probably make another tutorial on how to do <em>this</em>:</p><figure><img src="https://neil.computer/content/images/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-06-at-12.05.17-AM.png" alt="" width="2510" height="2166" srcset="https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-06-at-12.05.17-AM.png 600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1000/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-06-at-12.05.17-AM.png 1000w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w1600/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-06-at-12.05.17-AM.png 1600w, https://neil.computer/content/images/size/w2400/2020/07/Screen-Shot-2020-07-06-at-12.05.17-AM.png 2400w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Until then, go here and browse some more trends to follow at the cost of authenticity, objectivity, originality, reasoning and fundamental understanding of how to design user interfaces: <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=design+trends+2020">https://www.google.com/search?q=design+trends+2020</a></p>
        </article>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://neil.computer/notes/hacker-news-design-is-ugly/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23745595</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 07:40:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to process more than 350K requests per month free using 3 free ETA services]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23745223">thread link</a>) | @Gen1us
<br/>
July 5, 2020 | https://blog.maddevs.io/how-to-make-three-paid-eta-services-one-free-6edc6affface | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.maddevs.io/how-to-make-three-paid-eta-services-one-free-6edc6affface">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><div><div><div><div><div><div><p><a href="https://blog.maddevs.io/@meder33kg?source=post_page-----6edc6affface----------------------" rel="noopener"><img alt="Akkozov Meder" src="https://miro.medium.com/fit/c/96/96/2*87H69ujCEx7VLZYSZPQyig.jpeg" width="48" height="48"></a></p></div></div></div></div><figure><div><div><div><p><img alt="Estimated time of arrival." src="https://miro.medium.com/max/8000/1*q9EOHqrYhaLpY1ZIL0C4Qw.jpeg" width="4000" height="2172" srcset="https://miro.medium.com/max/552/1*q9EOHqrYhaLpY1ZIL0C4Qw.jpeg 276w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1104/1*q9EOHqrYhaLpY1ZIL0C4Qw.jpeg 552w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1280/1*q9EOHqrYhaLpY1ZIL0C4Qw.jpeg 640w, https://miro.medium.com/max/1400/1*q9EOHqrYhaLpY1ZIL0C4Qw.jpeg 700w" sizes="700px" data-old-src="https://miro.medium.com/max/60/1*q9EOHqrYhaLpY1ZIL0C4Qw.jpeg?q=20"></p></div></div></div><figcaption>Estimated time of arrival</figcaption></figure><p id="cce6">This is a story on how to not spend even a penny by using three ETA (estimated time of arrival) services instead of one. Everything is based on my personal experience working as a back-end developer at GoDee project. GoDee is a start-up project that offers booking seats on a bus online. You could find more information about this project here:</p><p id="e338">GoDee is a public transportation service. Bus transportation by GoDee is more convenient than motorbikes common for Southeast Asia and cheaper than a taxi. The app-based system allows users to find an appropriate route, select the time, book the seat, and pay for the ride online. And one of the problems of GoDee is traffic jams that severely impact the user experience. Users get tired of waiting and get annoyed by trying to guess the bus arrival time. So, to make the commuting more convenient, it needed service to calculate the bus’s approximate arrival time, aka ETA.</p><p id="5226">Developing ETA from scratch would take at least a year. So, to speed up the process, GoDee decided to implement the Google Distance Matrix API tool. Later they developed their own Pifia micro-service.</p><figure><div><div><p><img alt="Image for post" src="https://miro.medium.com/max/500/1*vq9Ao08BtAdAMx5OYhbSlA.gif" width="250" height="429" data-old-src="https://miro.medium.com/freeze/max/34/1*vq9Ao08BtAdAMx5OYhbSlA.gif?q=20"></p></div></div></figure><p id="b97d">Over time, the business grew, and the user base increased. We encountered a problem with increasing requests in the Google Distance Matrix API.</p><h2 id="8971">Why is this a problem?</h2><p id="2a4f">Because every request costs money, Google API provides 10.000 free queries per month, after which every 1.000 queries are charged $20. At that time, we had about 150,000 requests per month.</p><p id="7492">My mentor was very dissatisfied with that. And said that system should change caching to store ETA every 30 minutes. At that time, the system sent requests to the Google API every 3 seconds to get fresh data. However, such a caching algorithm wasn’t efficient, since minibuses were stuck in traffic. And so the distance only changed once every ten minutes. There was another nuance. For example, five users are asking for information about the same bus, and this is the same request. The cache solved this type of problem.</p><figure><div></div><figcaption>Сache Code</figcaption></figure><p id="8a43">The cache worked, but not for long since GoDee grew even further and faced the same problem — the number of queries has increased again.</p><p id="9a57">It was decided to replace the Google API with OSRM. Basically, OSRM is a service for building a route based on ETA (this is a rough but the short description, if you need details, here is the <a href="http://project-osrm.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">link</a>).</p><blockquote><p id="113f">The Open Source Routing Machine or OSRM is a C++ implementation of a high-performance routing engine for the shortest paths in road networks.</p><p id="15be">Wikipedia.</p></blockquote><p id="97d4">OSRM has one problem: it builds routes and calculates ETA without taking traffic into account. To solve this problem, I started looking for services that can provide information about traffic in the specified part of the city. HERE Traffic was providing the data I needed. After a little study of the documentation, I wrote a small code that gets traffic information every 30 minutes. And to upload traffic information to OSRM, I wrote a small script with the command <code>./osrm-contract data.osrm --segment-speed-file updates.csv</code> (more details <a href="https://github.com/Project-OSRM/osrm-backend/wiki/Traffic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>).</p><p id="cbda">Math time: every half of the hour, there is a request to HERE to get traffic information this are two requests per hour, that is, a day is 48 requests (24 * 2 = 48) and a month is about ≈ 1.488 (48*31 = 1.488) a year 17.520. Yes, we have these free requests from HERE for 15 years would be enough.</p><figure><div></div><figcaption>Code for getting traffic</figcaption></figure><p id="b1d9">Preliminary tests showed that the service works perfectly, but there is a problem, HERE gives traffic information in “gibberish” and the data does not match the OSRM format. In order for the information to fit, you need to use another service HERE for geocoding + OSRM (for getting points on the map). This is approximately 450.000 requests per month. Later, OSRM was abandoned because the number of requests exceeded the free limit. We didn’t give up and enabled the HERE Distance Matrix API and temporarily removed the Google Distance Matrix API. The logic HERE is simple: we send coordinates from point A to point B and get the bus arrival time.</p><figure><div></div></figure><p id="2e81">After we installed everything on the test server and started checking, we received the first feedback from the testers. They said that ETA reads the time incorrectly. We started looking for the problem, looked at logs (we used Data dog for logs), logs, and tests showed that everything works perfectly. We decided to ask about the problem in a little more detail, and it turned out that if the car is in traffic for 15 minutes, ETA shows the same time. We decided that this is because of the cache because it stores the original time and does not update it for 30 minutes.</p><p id="1d5a">We started looking for the problem, at the beginning we checked the data on the web version of the HERE Distance Matrix API (which is called we go here), everything worked fine, we received the same ETA. This problem was also checked on the google map service. There was no problem. The services themselves show this ETA. We explained everything to testers and businesses, and they accepted everything.</p><p id="18ce">Our team lead suggested connecting another ETA service and returning the Google API as a backup option and writing code with the logic of switching services (the switch was needed if the requests pass the free number of requests).</p><p id="e9c2">The code works the following way:</p><pre><span id="b4e7">val = getCount() // getting the number of queries used</span><span id="9ff9"><em>if</em> getMax() &lt;= val { // checking for the limit of free requests for the service used</span><span id="e935">newService = switchService(s) // // if the limit is reached, switch the service return</span><span id="cae7"><em>return</em> newService(from, to) // giving the logic of the new service </span></pre><p id="054f">We found the following Mapbox service, connected it, installed it, and it worked. As a result, our ETA had:</p><blockquote><p id="625d">“Here” — 250,000 free requests per month<br>Google — 10,000 free requests per month<br>Mapbox — 100,000 free requests per month</p></blockquote><p id="4def">Always look for alternatives, sometimes it happens that the business doesn't want to pay the money for the service and refuses it. As a developer who has worked hard on the service, you should bring the task to real use. This article describes how we were trying to connect more services for the free use of ETA because the business did not want to pay for the service.</p><p id="4330">P.S. As a developer, I believe that if the tool is good and does its job well, then you can pay for the tool’s services (or find Open source projects :D).</p><figure><div></div></figure></div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.maddevs.io/how-to-make-three-paid-eta-services-one-free-6edc6affface</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23745223</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 06:26:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[CoreBGP – Plugging in to BGP]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 126 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23744167">thread link</a>) | @jordanwhited
<br/>
July 5, 2020 | https://www.jordanwhited.com/posts/corebgp-plugging-in-to-bgp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jordanwhited.com/posts/corebgp-plugging-in-to-bgp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://www.jordanwhited.com/posts/corebgp-plugging-in-to-bgp/cover.png" alt="cover"></p>
<hr>

<p><a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4271" target="_blank">BGP</a> is one of many protocols that powers the Internet. Chances are you have heard of it, even if you don’t work in or around the computer networking space. If you aren’t familiar, I’ll try to provide some quick background:</p>
<ul>
<li>BGP is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distance-vector_routing_protocol" target="_blank">distance-vector routing protocol</a> used to disseminate routing information.</li>
<li>A BGP speaker implements a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finite-state_machine" target="_blank">finite state machine</a> with 6 states:
<ul>
<li>Idle</li>
<li>Active</li>
<li>Connect</li>
<li>OpenSent</li>
<li>OpenConfirm</li>
<li>Established</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Inputs to the BGP FSM include messages, timer events, and administrative events.</li>
<li>Routing information is exchanged via UPDATE messages in the Established state.</li>
<li>BGP is extensible; speakers communicate their capabilities via OPEN messages.</li>
</ul>
<p>Expanding on that last bullet point, it’s difficult to summarize exactly how/where BGP is used due to its flexibility and extensibility. Various <a href="https://ietf.org/about/" target="_blank">IETF</a> Working Groups continue to publish BGP-related RFCs for a protocol that took shape in the early 90s. As the BGP landscape and application widens, we need software that enables us to keep up.</p>
<p>In this post I’ll provide some of my personal experience and history working with BGP, and introduce a new BGP library, <a href="https://github.com/jwhited/corebgp" target="_blank">CoreBGP</a>, which can be used to build the next generation of BGP-enabled applications.</p>

<p>In October of 2010 I attended my first <a href="https://www.nanog.org/" target="_blank">NANOG</a> meeting in Atlanta, GA after accidentally falling into the position of Network Operations Engineer at work. I worked for a modest-sized hosting provider at the time, and was intrigued with BGP. Upon arriving in Atlanta, I vaguely remember some confusion after telling a cab driver that the hotel I needed to be dropped at was on Peachtree St. I later learned that there are 71 streets in Atlanta with a variant of “Peachtree” in their name, according to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peachtree_Street#Nomenclature" target="_blank">Wikpedia</a>.</p>
<p>I got where I needed to go, eventually, and the first talk I attended was <a href="https://archive.nanog.org/meetings/nanog50/presentations/Sunday/NANOG50.Talk33.NANOG50-BGP-Techniques.pdf" target="_blank">BGP techniques for Internet Service Providers</a> by <a href="http://www.bgp4all.com.au/" target="_blank">Philip Smith</a>. Philip started with the basics before getting into the techniques used at ISPs. So many light bulbs went off for me during this talk. I have yet to see any other BGP presentation cover such a breadth of information but still do it in a way that is beginner-friendly, useful as a refresher for any expert, and just downright interesting.</p>
<p>Fast-forward 10 years and I’ve gained a fair share of experience operating networks that use BGP. In more recent years I’ve shifted to software engineering where I’ve had the opportunity to implement various BGP-enabled applications for network observability, data analytics, and SDN purposes.</p>
<p>Each time I started a new BGP-enabled app, I had to answer the following question – which existing BGP implementation should be its foundation?</p>

<p>Of the handful of open source BGP implementations out there, I’ve had hands-on experience with projects making use of:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://bird.network.cz/" target="_blank">BIRD</a></li>
<li><a href="https://osrg.github.io/gobgp/" target="_blank">GoBGP</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.opendaylight.org/what-we-do/odl-platform-overview" target="_blank">OpenDaylight</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.quagga.net/" target="_blank">Quagga</a></li>
</ul>
<p>BIRD shines where a <a href="https://bird.network.cz/?get_doc&amp;v=20&amp;f=bird-5.html" target="_blank">rich policy language</a> is needed. GoBGP has a <a href="https://github.com/osrg/gobgp/tree/master/api" target="_blank">feature-rich gRPC API</a>, and can be embedded as a library. OpenDaylight’s BGP implementation is part of a larger SDN controller solution and has extensive support for <a href="https://docs.opendaylight.org/en/stable-oxygen/user-guide/bgpcep-guide/bgp/bgp-user-guide-linkstate-family.html" target="_blank">BGP-LS</a>. Quagga can reliably produce <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6396" target="_blank">MRT</a> dumps and has been around a long time, though I believe <a href="https://frrouting.org/" target="_blank">FRRouting</a> is now considered its successor.</p>
<p>These are all mature, established implementations. Some of them are in production at large ISPs, <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/blog/scaling-droplet-public-networking/" target="_blank">Cloud Providers</a>, and <a href="https://joinup.ec.europa.eu/collection/open-source-observatory-osor/document/bird-manages-routing-worlds-largest-internet-exchanges-bird" target="_blank">Internet Exchange Points</a>. They are purpose-built and make various tradeoffs to suit their use cases (programming language, threading model, data structures, API, etc…).</p>
<p>But what if we are building something that doesn’t line up with the primary use cases of these widely used implementations? We may be locked in to decisions that are ultimately burdensome if we choose to build around them. Swapping in our own data structures for routing tables, or adding a new NLRI is non-trivial. Even if an implementation is intended to be embedded as library, it can still back us into a corner with resource consumption. There’s clearly a need to plug in or hook into specific parts of the BGP FSM, without inheriting decisions that went into a full-blown BGP daemon.</p>
<p>At the 27th IEEE International Conference On Network Protocols (ICNP), a group from the Université catholique de Louvain presented a paper on <code>The Case for Pluginized Routing Protocols</code>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Abstract—Routing protocols such as BGP and OSPF are key components of Internet Service Provider (ISP) networks. These protocols and the operator’s requirements evolve over time, but it often takes many years for network operators to convince their different router vendors and the IETF to extend routing protocols. Some network operators, notably in enterprise and datacenters have adopted Software Defined Networking (SDN) with its centralised control to be more agile. We propose a new approach to implement routing protocols that enables network operators to innovate while still using distributed routing protocols and thus keeping all their benefits compared to centralised routing approaches. We extend a routing protocol with a virtual machine that is capable of executing plugins. These plugins extend the protocol or modify its underlying algorithms through a simple API to meet the specific requirements of operators. We modify the OSPF and BGP implementations provided by FRRouting and demonstrate the applicability of our approach with several use cases.</p>
<p>— <!-- raw HTML omitted -->The Case for Pluginized Routing Protocols<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In their paper they present a method for plugging into a previously mentioned open-source BGP implementation, FRRouting. Plugins exist at a function level, either prior to invocation (PRE), as a replacement (REPLACE), or just before returning (POST). Much of their BGP plugin focus is around the reception of messages, and decisions made shortly after:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The BGP daemon is also extended similarly. We add insertion points on functions receiving BGP messages from neighbours, on filters and inside the decision process. We also expose specific functions to the plugins that are executed by the uBPF VM.</p>
<p>— <!-- raw HTML omitted -->The Case for Pluginized Routing Protocols<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
</blockquote>
<p>They take a clever approach with plugin sandboxing by leveraging a user space eBPF VM (<a href="https://github.com/iovisor/ubpf" target="_blank">uBPF</a>) linked to the FRRouting protocol implementation. Each plugin compiles to eBPF bytecode and runs inside of said VM. Plugins can be loaded and unloaded without impacting the primary protocol implementation. Using an eBPF VM also allowed them to utilise all the pre-existing Linux Kernel tooling.</p>
<p>I found this approach inspiring, but still not quite a match for my use cases:</p>
<ul>
<li>Plugins appear to be built around “incoming” events, or messages. What if I want to inject an UPDATE message to a peer irrespective of what FRRouting wants to send?</li>
<li>FRRouting was not built with this plugin model in mind. Changes/Updates to FRRouting will result in a maintenance headache for the VM hook points.</li>
<li>eBPF bytecode is typically compiled from C. Writing C can be time-consuming in comparison to more modern languages.</li>
<li>I need to be an FRRouting expert to do anything non-trivial.</li>
</ul>
<p>This experience and research led me to create CoreBGP, a BGP library that I could re-use across my BGP-enabled applications.</p>

<p>CoreBGP is a BGP library written in Go that implements the BGP FSM with an event-driven, pluggable model. It exposes an API that empowers the user to:</p>
<ul>
<li>send and validate OPEN message capabilities</li>
<li>handle “important” state transitions</li>
<li>handle incoming UPDATE messages</li>
<li>send outgoing UPDATE messages</li>
</ul>
<p>CoreBGP does not decode UPDATE messages (besides header validation), manage a routing table, or send its own UPDATE messages. These responsibilities are all passed down to the user. Therefore, the intended user is someone who wants that responsibility.</p>
<p>The primary building block of CoreBGP is a Plugin, defined by the following interface:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="go"><span>// Plugin is a BGP peer plugin.
</span><span></span><span>type</span> Plugin <span>interface</span> {
	<span>// GetCapabilities is fired when a peer's FSM is in the Connect state prior
</span><span></span>	<span>// to sending an Open message. The returned capabilities are included in the
</span><span></span>	<span>// Open message sent to the peer.
</span><span></span>	<span>GetCapabilities</span>(peer <span>*</span>PeerConfig) []<span>*</span>Capability

	<span>// OnOpenMessage is fired when an Open message is received from a peer
</span><span></span>	<span>// during the OpenSent state. Returning a non-nil Notification will cause it
</span><span></span>	<span>// to be sent to the peer and the FSM will transition to the Idle state.
</span><span></span>	<span>//
</span><span></span>	<span>// Per RFC5492 a BGP speaker should only send a Notification if a required
</span><span></span>	<span>// capability is missing; unknown or unsupported capabilities should be
</span><span></span>	<span>// ignored.
</span><span></span>	<span>OnOpenMessage</span>(peer <span>*</span>PeerConfig, capabilities []<span>*</span>Capability) <span>*</span>Notification

	<span>// OnEstablished is fired when a peer's FSM transitions to the Established
</span><span></span>	<span>// state. The returned UpdateMessageHandler will be fired when an Update
</span><span></span>	<span>// message is received from the peer.
</span><span></span>	<span>//
</span><span></span>	<span>// The provided writer can be used to send Update messages to the peer for
</span><span></span>	<span>// the lifetime of the FSM's current, established state. It should be
</span><span></span>	<span>// discarded once OnClose() fires.
</span><span></span>	<span>OnEstablished</span>(peer <span>*</span>PeerConfig, writer UpdateMessageWriter) UpdateMessageHandler

	<span>// OnClose is fired when a peer's FSM transitions out of the Established
</span><span></span>	<span>// state.
</span><span></span>	<span>OnClose</span>(peer <span>*</span>PeerConfig)
}
</code></pre></div><p>Here’s an example Plugin that logs when a peer enters/leaves an established state and when an UPDATE message is received:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="go"><span>type</span> plugin <span>struct</span>{}

<span>func</span> (p <span>*</span>plugin) <span>GetCapabilities</span>(c <span>*</span>corebgp.PeerConfig) []<span>*</span>corebgp.Capability {
	caps <span>:=</span> <span>make</span>([]<span>*</span>corebgp.Capability, <span>0</span>)
	<span>return</span> caps
}

<span>func</span> (p <span>*</span>plugin) <span>OnOpenMessage</span>(peer <span>*</span>corebgp.PeerConfig, capabilities []<span>*</span>corebgp.Capability) <span>*</span>corebgp.Notification {
	<span>return</span> <span>nil</span>
}

<span>func</span> (p <span>*</span>plugin) <span>OnEstablished</span>(peer <span>*</span>corebgp.PeerConfig, writer corebgp.UpdateMessageWriter) corebgp.UpdateMessageHandler {
	log.<span>Println</span>(<span>"peer established"</span>)
	<span>// send End-of-Rib
</span><span></span>	writer.<span>WriteUpdate</span>([]<span>byte</span>{<span>0</span>, <span>0</span>, <span>0</span>, <span>0</span>})
	<span>return</span> p.handleUpdate
}

<span>func</span> (p <span>*</span>plugin) <span>OnClose</span>(peer <span>*</span>corebgp.PeerConfig) {
	log.<span>Println</span>(<span>"peer closed"</span>)
}

<span>func</span> (p <span>*</span>plugin) <span>handleUpdate</span>(peer <span>*</span>corebgp.PeerConfig, u []<span>byte</span>) <span>*</span>corebgp.Notification {
	log.<span>Printf</span>(<span>"got update message of len: %d"</span>, <span>len</span>(u))
	<span>return</span> <span>nil</span>
}
</code></pre></div><p>Plugins are attached to peers when they are added to the Server, which manages their lifetime:</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.jordanwhited.com/posts/corebgp-plugging-in-to-bgp/">https://www.jordanwhited.com/posts/corebgp-plugging-in-to-bgp/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jordanwhited.com/posts/corebgp-plugging-in-to-bgp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23744167</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 02:39:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What should we do about network-effect monopolies]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23743610">thread link</a>) | @dmnd
<br/>
July 5, 2020 | https://www.benkuhn.net/nwe/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.benkuhn.net/nwe/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>Many large companies today are software monopolies that give their product away for free to get monopoly status, then do <a href="https://github.com/uBlockOrigin/uBlock-issues/issues/338#issuecomment-496009417" target="_blank">the</a> <a href="http://www.fbpurity.com/news/important-news-facebooks-legal-team-have-told-me-i-am-banned-from-facebook-because-of-f-b-purity/" target="_blank">most</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/28/19154220/grubhub-seamless-fake-restaurant-domain-names-commission-fees" target="_blank">horrible</a> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/blog/amazon-counterfeit-fake-products/" target="_blank">things</a> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/16/21293419/hey-apple-rejection-ios-app-store-dhh-gangsters-antitrust" target="_blank">once</a> <a href="https://www.polemicdigital.com/google-amp-go-to-hell/" target="_blank">they’ve</a> <a href="https://thetechnoskeptic.com/yelp-extortion-starring-role/" target="_blank">won</a>. (<a href="https://www.benkuhn.net/skinner/">Previously</a>, <a href="https://www.benkuhn.net/product/">previously</a>.) Can we do anything about this?</p><p>Unfortunately, “you’re the product” is a popular business model for a reason: businesses like Facebook would be really hard to support without them.</p><p>Facebook would be suicidal to charge its users money, because its entire selling point is that everyone uses it, and “everyone” <em>hates</em> paying money. In the US, Facebook makes over $25 per person on ads (<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/251328/facebooks-average-revenue-per-user-by-region/" target="_blank">source</a>). Can you imagine if instead of ads they tried to charge people $25 a year?</p><p>Even on the margin, anything that costs Facebook users also makes it less valuable for its remaining users—it’s a negative feedback loop. The same goes for any other site where users create value for other users, like Twitter or Craigslist or Yelp or Wikipedia. (It’s not an accident that these are some of the most stagnant popular websites!)</p><p>In fact, this is a fundamental problem with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network_effect" target="_blank">network effects</a> and low marginal costs. If a company wants to maintain a network effect, they need as many users as possible. If their marginal cost is low, then the easiest way to get users is to give the product away. To do that, they have to get paid by someone else. And when they start getting paid by someone else, they’ll inevitably start prioritizing that person’s interests.</p><p>Historically with other network-effect businesses, we’ve addressed this in a few different ways:</p><ul><li><p>regulation (e.g. local utilities)</p></li><li><p>breakups (e.g. Bell)</p></li><li><p>standardization and interoperability (e.g. email, the Web, cryptocurrency)</p></li></ul><p>So far for tech monopolies, people seem to be focused mostly on breakups—e.g. Facebook from Instagram/Whatsapp—but standardization seems to have produced much better outcomes in the past. (I like email and the Web a lot more than National Grid…) I’d be interested to see more exploration of that option!</p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.benkuhn.net/nwe/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23743610</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:46:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Rust for JavaScript Developers – Functions and Control Flow]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 182 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23743363">thread link</a>) | @rkwz
<br/>
July 5, 2020 | http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-for-javascript-developers-functions-and-control-flow/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-for-javascript-developers-functions-and-control-flow/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>This is the third part in a series about introducing the Rust language to JavaScript developers. Here are the past chapters:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-for-javascript-developers-tooling-ecosystem-overview/">Tooling Ecosystem Overview</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-for-javascript-developers-variables-and-data-types/">Variables and Data Types</a></li>
</ol>
<h2 id="Functions"><a href="#Functions" title="Functions"></a>Functions</h2><p>Rust’s function syntax is pretty much similar to the one in JavaScript.</p>
<pre><code><span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> income <span>=</span> <span>100</span><span>;</span>
  <span>let</span> tax <span>=</span> <span>calculate_tax</span><span>(</span>income<span>)</span><span>;</span>
  <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span> tax<span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>fn</span> <span>calculate_tax</span><span>(</span>income<span>:</span> i32<span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> i32 <span>{</span>
  <span>return</span> income <span>*</span> <span>90</span> <span>/</span> <span>100</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>The only difference you might see above is the type annotations for arguments and return values.</p>
<p>The <code>return</code> keyword can be skipped and it’s very common to see code without an explicit return. If you’re returning implicitly, make sure to remove the semicolon from that line. The above function can be refactored as:</p>
<pre><code>fn main() {
  let income = 100;
  let tax = calculate_tax(income);
  println!("{}", tax);
}

fn calculate_tax(income: i32) -&gt; i32 {
<span>- return income * 90 / 100;</span>
<span>+ income * 90 / 100</span>
}</code></pre>
<h2 id="Arrow-Functions"><a href="#Arrow-Functions" title="Arrow Functions"></a>Arrow Functions</h2><p>Arrow functions are a popular feature in modern JavaScript - they allow us to write functional code in a concise way.</p>
<p>Rust has something similar and they are called “Closures”. The name might be a bit confusing and would require getting used to because in JavaScript, closures can be created using both normal and arrow functions.</p>
<p>Rust’s closure syntax is very similar to JavaScript’s arrow functions:</p>
<p><strong>Without arguments:</strong></p>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> greet <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span><span>&gt;</span> console<span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>"hello"</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

<span>greet</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> greet <span>=</span> <span>||</span> <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"hello"</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

<span>greet</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<p><strong>With arguments:</strong></p>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> greet <span>=</span> <span>(</span>msg<span>)</span> <span>=</span><span>&gt;</span> console<span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>msg<span>)</span><span>;</span>

<span>greet</span><span>(</span><span>"good morning!"</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> greet <span>=</span> <span>|</span>msg<span>:</span> <span>&amp;</span>str<span>|</span> <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span> msg<span>)</span><span>;</span>

<span>greet</span><span>(</span><span>"good morning!"</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<p><strong>Returning values:</strong></p>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> add <span>=</span> <span>(</span>a<span>,</span> b<span>)</span> <span>=</span><span>&gt;</span> a <span>+</span> b<span>;</span>

<span>add</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> add <span>=</span> <span><span>|</span>a<span>:</span> i32<span>,</span> b<span>:</span> i32<span>|</span></span> <span>-&gt;</span> i32 <span>{</span> a <span>+</span> b <span>}</span><span>;</span>

<span>add</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<p><strong>Multiline:</strong></p>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> add <span>=</span> <span>(</span>a<span>,</span> b<span>)</span> <span>=</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> sum <span>=</span> a <span>+</span> b<span>;</span>
  <span>return</span> sum<span>;</span>
<span>}</span><span>;</span>

<span>add</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<pre><code>
<span>let</span> add <span>=</span> <span><span>|</span>a<span>:</span> i32<span>,</span> b<span>:</span> i32<span>|</span></span> <span>-&gt;</span> i32 <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> sum <span>=</span> a <span>+</span> b<span>;</span>
  <span>return</span> sum<span>;</span>
<span>}</span><span>;</span>

<span>add</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> </code></pre>
<p>Here’s a cheatsheet:<br><img src="http://www.sheshbabu.com/images/2020-rust-for-javascript-developers-3/image-2.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Closures don’t need the type annotations most of the time, but I’ve added them here for clarity.</p>
<h2 id="If-Else"><a href="#If-Else" title="If Else"></a>If Else</h2><pre><code><span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> income <span>=</span> <span>100</span><span>;</span>
  <span>let</span> tax <span>=</span> <span>calculate_tax</span><span>(</span>income<span>)</span><span>;</span>
  <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span> tax<span>)</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>fn</span> <span>calculate_tax</span><span>(</span>income<span>:</span> i32<span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> i32 <span>{</span>
  <span>if</span> income <span>&lt;</span> <span>10</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span> <span>else</span> <span>if</span> income <span>&gt;=</span> <span>10</span> <span>&amp;&amp;</span> income <span>&lt;</span> <span>50</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>20</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span> <span>else</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>50</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<h2 id="Loops"><a href="#Loops" title="Loops"></a>Loops</h2><p>While loops:</p>
<pre><code><span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> <span>mut</span> count <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>

  <span>while</span> count <span>&lt;</span> <span>10</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span> count<span>)</span><span>;</span>
    count <span>+=</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>Normal <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Statements/for" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for loops</a> don’t exist in Rust, we need to use <code>while</code> or <code>for..in</code> loops. <code>for..in</code> loops are similar to the <code>for..of</code> loops in JavaScript and they loop over an iterator.</p>
<pre><code><span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> numbers <span>=</span> <span>[</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>3</span><span>,</span> <span>4</span><span>,</span> <span>5</span><span>]</span><span>;</span>

  <span>for</span> n <span>in</span> numbers<span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span> n<span>)</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>Notice that we’re not iterating directly over the array but instead using the <code>iter</code> method of the array.</p>
<p>We can also loop over <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/reference/expressions/range-expr.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ranges</a>:</p>
<pre><code><span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>for</span> n <span>in</span> <span>1</span><span>..</span><span>5</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span> n<span>)</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<h2 id="Iterators"><a href="#Iterators" title="Iterators"></a>Iterators</h2><p>In JavaScript, we can use array methods like map/filter/reduce/etc instead of <code>for</code> loops to perform calculations or transformations on an array.</p>
<p>For example, here we take an array of numbers, double them and filter out the elements that are less than 10:</p>
<pre><code><span>function</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> numbers <span>=</span> <span>[</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>3</span><span>,</span> <span>4</span><span>,</span> <span>5</span><span>]</span><span>;</span>

  <span>let</span> double <span>=</span> <span>(</span>n<span>)</span> <span>=</span><span>&gt;</span> n <span>*</span> <span>2</span><span>;</span>
  <span>let</span> less_than_ten <span>=</span> <span>(</span>n<span>)</span> <span>=</span><span>&gt;</span> n <span>&lt;</span> <span>10</span><span>;</span>

  <span>let</span> result <span>=</span> numbers<span>.</span><span>map</span><span>(</span>double<span>)</span><span>.</span><span>filter</span><span>(</span>less_than_ten<span>)</span><span>;</span>

  console<span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>result<span>)</span><span>;</span> 
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>In Rust, we can’t directly use map/filter/etc over vectors, we need to follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Convert the vector into an iterator using <code>iter</code>, <code>into_iter</code> or <code>iter_mut</code> methods</li>
<li>Chain <code>adapters</code> such as map/filter/etc on the iterator</li>
<li>Finally convert the iterator back to a vector using <code>consumers</code> such as <code>collect</code>, <code>find</code>, <code>sum</code> etc</li>
</ol>
<p>Here’s the equivalent Rust code:</p>
<pre><code><span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> numbers <span>=</span> <span>vec!</span><span>[</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>3</span><span>,</span> <span>4</span><span>,</span> <span>5</span><span>]</span><span>;</span>

  <span>let</span> double <span>=</span> <span><span>|</span>n<span>:</span> <span>&amp;</span>i32<span>|</span></span> <span>-&gt;</span> i32 <span>{</span> n <span>*</span> <span>2</span> <span>}</span><span>;</span>
  <span>let</span> less_than_10 <span>=</span> <span><span>|</span>n<span>:</span> <span>&amp;</span>i32<span>|</span></span> <span>-&gt;</span> bool <span>{</span> <span>*</span>n <span>&lt;</span> <span>10</span> <span>}</span><span>;</span>

  <span>let</span> result<span>:</span> Vec<span>&lt;</span>i32<span>&gt;</span> <span>=</span> numbers<span>.</span><span>iter</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>.</span><span>map</span><span>(</span>double<span>)</span><span>.</span><span>filter</span><span>(</span>less_than_10<span>)</span><span>.</span><span>collect</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

  <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>,</span> result<span>)</span><span>;</span> 
<span>}</span></code></pre>
<p>You should be able to understand most of the code above but you might notice few things off here:</p>
<ul>
<li>The usage of <code>&amp;</code> and <code>*</code> in the closure</li>
<li>The <code>Vec&lt;i32&gt;</code> type annotation for the <code>result</code> variable</li>
</ul>
<p>The <code>&amp;</code> is the reference operator and the <code>*</code> is the dereference operator. The <code>iter</code> method instead of copying the elements in the vector, it passes them as references to the next adapter in the chain. This is why we use <code>&amp;i32</code> in the map’s closure (double). This closure returns <code>i32</code> but <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/iter/trait.Iterator.html#method.filter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">filter</a> calls its closure (less_than_10) with reference so that’s why we need to use <code>&amp;i32</code> again. To dereference the argument, we use the <code>*</code> operator. We’ll cover this in more detail in future chapters.</p>
<p>Regarding <code>Vec&lt;i32&gt;</code>, so far we haven’t added type annotations to variables as Rust can infer the types automatically, but for <code>collect</code>, we need to be explicitly tell Rust that we expect a <code>Vec&lt;i32&gt;</code> output.</p>
<p>Aside from map and filter, there are ton of other <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/iter/trait.Iterator.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">useful adapters</a> that we can use in iterators.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading! Feel free to follow me in <a href="https://twitter.com/sheshbabu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter</a> for updates :)</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.sheshbabu.com/posts/rust-for-javascript-developers-functions-and-control-flow/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23743363</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:07:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
