<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 13:03:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 13:03:17 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[CTO day 2: downsizing the team]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 28 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25712771">thread link</a>) | @delebe
<br/>
January 10, 2021 | https://danlebrero.com/2020/12/02/cto-diary-downsizing-team-firing/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danlebrero.com/2020/12/02/cto-diary-downsizing-team-firing/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p id="entry-summary">On your first day as newly appointed CTO you are working on your hiring strategy, the second day your organization asks you to downsize the team.</p><div><p>A very important project that was a done deal, and that will secure the organization’s future for the next five years, failed to happen.</p><p>Not winning this project meant that the organization was forced to <em>“focus”</em> and reduce costs.</p><p>It never crossed my mind that one of the first things that I would be asked to do as an inexperienced CTO would be to fire part of the team.</p>
<p>when such bad news becomes public, host an open door day where the team can openly talk about the situation, share their feelings, see each other, feel connected, and be listened to. It would not stop the gossiping but it will help.</p><h2>Cuts and team principles</h2><p>The Dev team slice of the <em>“focus”</em> meant cutting cost by 10 to 15%. In human terms, firing two to four people (out of 17).</p><p>After some failed attempts to approach this task, this is what worked for me.</p><p>I started by listing some principles: </p>
<ul>
  <li>For each product, we need to cover the following disciplines: Frontend, Backend, Architecture, Operations, Mobile, UX, Design, QA, Leadership, and Product Management.</li>
  <li>There are broadly 3 experience levels:
  <ul>
    <li>Senior: creates the plan.</li>
    <li>Mid-level: follows the plan.</li>
    <li>Junior: needs to be taught to follow the plan.</li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>No number of junior people can do some work a senior person can do.</li>
  <li>Not having a senior person in a discipline will mean that the product quality will suffer:
  <ul>
    <li>If a senior creates a plan, a team of mid-level+juniors can follow the plan for some time (2-3 years?) before the product becomes a big mess.</li>
    <li>To get out of a big mess, we need senior people.
    <ul>
      <li>We are already in a big mess with Product A and Product B.</li>
      <li>With the current team, it feels Product A is getting out of the mess.</li>
    </ul></li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>Independent (cross-functional) teams are more efficient:
  <ul>
    <li>More focus.</li>
    <li>No handoffs, faster feedback.</li>
    <li>No shared “resource” contention.</li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>People working in multiple products/teams are less efficient.</li>
  <li>Multidisciplinary (generalist) people:
  <ul>
    <li>Can cover the need for several of the disciplines.</li>
    <li>They can be junior in one discipline and senior in another.</li>
    <li>Allow focusing on any priority, without creating artificially important work for single-disciplined members.</li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>Max team size: 2 pizza teams 6-8.</li>
</ul><p>The ideal team would be one that has all disciplines covered at a senior level with multidisciplinary people working in just one team, and with enough overlap to avoid a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor">bus factor</a> of one. Additional people will bring additional capacity.</p><h2>Inverse Conway’s maneuver</h2><p>We have been working on bringing three of the products together for some time. They were already under the same product manager, but they were still three teams working on their own priorities. Merging them into one team, in a classic <a href="https://danlebrero.com/2020/01/08/do-i-need-a-gateway-api-team-dynamics/#content">inverse Conway’s maneuver</a> would hopefully accelerate the integration between the products.</p><p>One of the other products was small enough that for this task I decided to temporarily ignore it.</p><p>Following the principles above and the product considerations, the plan was to move the previous team setup from:</p><p><img src="https://danlebrero.com/images/blog/cto/day2/old-team-structure.jpg" alt="old team structure"> </p><p>To something like (boxes represent skills, not people):</p><p><img src="https://danlebrero.com/images/blog/cto/day2/new-team-structure.jpg" alt="new team structure"> </p><p>So two products, two cross-functional teams. Platforms and design teams will be reshuffled inside those two teams.</p><h2>Which parent do you love most? A computer will tell</h2><p>With a clear plan for the team, the next step was to <em>“just”</em> pick up who will work on each team, and who we will need to let go. The most painful decision in my career. </p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://danlebrero.com/2019/11/27/becoming-a-technical-leader-book-notes/#content">People with a strong technical background can convert any task into a technical task, thus avoiding work they don’t want to do.</a> <cite>Jerry Weinberg, Becoming a Technical Leader</cite></p>
</blockquote><p>And I didn’t want to do the task so, consciously ignoring Mr. Weinberg, I transformed the ordeal into an optimization problem, for which I wrote an application to help me with.</p><h3>The app</h3><p>The application took as input the amount of $$$ to cut, the list of people, their salary, and the skill level on each discipline mentioned above, and outputted the possible two teams that would be within budget and match the minimum requirements, sorted by a scoring system.</p><p>The minimum requirements and scoring system configuration looked like:</p>
<pre><code>{
"FE" [at-least-senior sum-skills]
"PM" [senior-plus-somebody-else (fix-points 5)]
"Design" [two-mid-or-senior (senior-better 6 2)]
...
}
</code></pre><p>The first function filters out invalid teams while the second scores the valid ones.</p><p>In the example we say that the team has to have:</p>
<ul>
  <li>At least one senior FE developer. The more FE developers, the better team score.</li>
  <li>At least one senior product manager and one mid or junior one. Only one senior is not enough. No matter how many PMs the team has, the score for this discipline is 5. A team with loads of FE devs will score higher than one with loads of PMs.</li>
  <li>At least a senior designer or two mid-level designers, but we prefer one senior designer (6 points) instead of two mid-level ones (2 points).</li>
</ul><h3>The result</h3><p>As heartless as this may seem:</p>
<ul>
  <li>It removed some bias. There is still bias on the skill level evaluation and in the team scoring system.</li>
  <li>I was part of the people on that list. To be honest, little consolation here. Big bias.</li>
  <li>It forced me to be very very precise on what a “functioning team” meant.</li>
  <li>It allowed me to see what different scoring systems would output.</li>
  <li>I noticed some people would never show in the output, and had to dig into why. It was enlightening.</li>
  <li>It allowed me to analyze tens of thousands of different team combinations, with different scoring systems.</li>
  <li>Programming gave me a respite from the task. This was the first time, but now I embrace more regularly “keep my sanity” programming days.</li>
</ul><p>Most important, the application gave me a few starting points. Of those, I still had to consider the team dynamics, existing teams, personalities, seniority, potential, personal situation, future needs, …</p>
<p>yes, I still have the code. No, I am not going to share it publicly. It would kill me to find there is a bug.</p><h2>Delivering the bad news</h2><p>Once the decision was made, it was time to swallow the last bitter pill.</p><p>Some tips:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ensure that the people affected are the first ones to know.</li>
  <li>Warn beforehand:
  <ul>
    <li>Do not use your regular one-to-one meeting slot.</li>
    <li>In your message, give a strong hint: “HR person will be in the meeting”, “Really bad news”.</li>
    <li>Give them time to get ready for the meeting.</li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>You don’t need to do it alone. Our HR manager was present and was a huge support for both of us.</li>
  <li>Treat people like adults.</li>
  <li>At the meeting, follow Nadia van der Vlies’ <a href="https://danlebrero.com/2020/04/01/no-nonsense-leadership-summary/#bad-news">advice</a>:
  <ul>
    <li>Deliver the blow:
    <ul>
      <li>Go straight to the bad news.</li>
      <li>Give one or two reasons.</li>
    </ul></li>
    <li>Manage the reaction:
    <ul>
      <li>Be understanding. Do not justify yourself.</li>
      <li>Give space. Do not fill silences.</li>
    </ul></li>
    <li>Solution, explanation, follow-up appointment:
    <ul>
      <li>Wait for the employee to be ready. When she starts asking “why” or “what now”.</li>
      <li>Reiterate reasons.</li>
    </ul></li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>In a couple of days follow up with another more informal meeting. The news would have sunk, and the conversation would be more forward-thinking and productive.</li>
</ul>
<hr><p>A slap in the face to awaken me from the dream that a CTO role is mostly about technology.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danlebrero.com/2020/12/02/cto-diary-downsizing-team-firing/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25712771</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 09:27:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Noise Planets (Generative Art)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25712767">thread link</a>) | @atulvi
<br/>
January 10, 2021 | https://avinayak.github.io/art/2021/01/09/noise-planets.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://avinayak.github.io/art/2021/01/09/noise-planets.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/erporydxmaarwcd.png" alt=""></p>

<p>I recently found this piece of art (LINES 2A (2017)) created by <a href="https://twitter.com/tylerxhobbs">Tyler Hobbs</a>. This picture kinda looked very hand drawn, but it’s completely generative. Something about this drawing and it’s texture kind of resonated with me, so I wanted to try to study and replicate (or make something inspired by this work) using p5js.</p>

<p>I started out by plotting a bunch of random points within a circle like so.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>w = 1000
function setup() {
  createCanvas(w, w);
  background('#F9F8F4');
}

function draw() {
  x = random(w)
  y = random(w)
  if (pow(w/2 - x, 2) + pow(w/2 - y, 2) &lt; 7e4) {
    point(x,y)
  }
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/download-25.png" alt=""></p>

<p>This is a painfully slow process to generate random points in a circle. I found a better way to do this later. What I wanted to do next was to generate flow fields, but restricted to the circular region.</p>

<p>It’s super easy to generate flow field patterns using perlin noise.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Choose a random point <code>&lt;x,y&gt;</code></li>
  <li>Plot <code>&lt;x,y&gt;</code></li>
  <li>Calculate <code>n = noise(x,y)</code></li>
  <li>Do <code>x+=cos(n * 2 * PI)</code> and <code>y+=sin(n * 2 * PI)</code></li>
  <li>Repeat 2.</li>
</ol>

<p>We’re going to plot flow fields inside the circle. Let’s try this.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>const is_in_circle = (x, y) =&gt; 
  (pow(w / 2 - x, 2) + pow(w / 2 - y, 2) &lt; 7e4)

function draw() {
  if (is_in_circle(x = random(w), y = random(w)))
    while (is_in_circle(x, y)) {
      n = noise(x, y)
      x += sin(n * TAU)
      y += cos(n * TAU)
      point(x, y)
    }
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/download-28.png" alt=""></p>

<p>OK, not very good. The noise at this level is pretty rough. we’re going to zoom in to the noise function (by dividing the <code>x,y</code> inputs by some constant value) and probably use <code>circle(x ,y ,0.3)</code> to plot points instead if point function, because I feel it looks way smoother. Also, I’m adding a <code>random() &gt; 0.01</code> condition in the loop so that we also get short lines that are not trimmed away by the edge of the circle.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>function draw() {
  if (is_in_circle(x = random(w), y = random(w)))
    while (is_in_circle(x, y) &amp;&amp; random() &gt; 0.01) {
      n = noise(x / 500, y / 500)
      x += sin(n * TAU)
      y += cos(n * TAU)
      circle(x, y, .3)
    }
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/download-27.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Actually.. not bad. I think we manage almost replicate the original texture. The inverted version also looks pretty good.</p>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/download-19.png" alt=""></p>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/ppanets.png" alt=""></p>

<p>I went ahead and made a つぶやきProcessing version of this.</p>

<blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">function setup(){createCanvas(w=1e3,w),background("<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%81%A4%E3%81%B6%E3%82%84%E3%81%8DProcessing?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#つぶやきProcessing</a>")}function draw(){if(g(x=random(w),y=random(w)))for(;g(x,y)&amp;&amp;random()&gt;.01;)n=noise(x/500,y/500),x+=sin(n_TAU),y+=cos(n_TAU),circle(x,y,.3)}g=((n,o)=&gt;pow(w/2-n,2)+pow(w/2-o,2)&lt;w*w/16); <a href="https://t.co/iVZTMtCn3i">pic.twitter.com/iVZTMtCn3i</a></p>— yakinavault (@yakinavault) <a href="https://twitter.com/yakinavault/status/1347903013042622467?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2021</a></blockquote>


<h2 id="going-further-animations">Going Further: Animations</h2>

<p>The code we wrote right now technically is animated. The animation however is not very smooth.</p>

<video loop="" autoplay="" muted=""> <source src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/simplescreenrecorder-2021-01-10_03-52-31.mp4" type="video/mp4"> </video>

<p>To make smooth animations, we need to generate new points in the circle, keep track of these points outside the <code>draw()</code> function. I found this neat <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/50746409">technique</a>, to find random points in a circle where a random radius <code>r</code> and angle <code>theta</code> are chosen and the <code>x,y</code> points are obtained as <code>x = centerX + r * cos(theta)</code> and <code>y = centerY + r * sin(theta)</code></p>

<p>Let’s try that first.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>function random_point() {
  r = random(w / 4)
  t = random(TAU)
  return [
    w/2 + cos(t) * r, 
    w/2 + sin(t) * r
  ]
}

function setup() {
  createCanvas((w = 1e3), w);
  background(255)
  k = w / 2
  m = (Array(w).fill(0)).map(random_point)
}

function draw() {
  for (i = k; --i;) {
    [x, y] = m[i]
    circle(x, y, .3);
  }
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/screenshot-from-2021-01-10-04-51-20.png" alt=""></p>

<p>and now we apply flow fields and try to move these points.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>function random_point() {
  r = random(w / 4)
  t = random(TAU)
  return [
    w/2 + cos(t) * r, 
    w/2 + sin(t) * r
  ]
}

const w = 1000
function setup() {
  createCanvas(w, w);
  background('#F9F8F4')
  k = w / 2
  points = (Array(k).fill(0)).map(random_point)
}

function draw() {
  for (i = k; --i;) {
    [x, y] = m[i]
    x += sin(n = noise(x / 400, y / 400) * TAU) * h
    y += cos(n) * h
    stroke(i%255)
    circle(x, y,.3)
    if (pow(k - x, 2) + pow(k - y, 2) &lt; 7e4)  // if point is in circle
      points[i] = [x, y, t]
    else points[i] = random_point() // replace with new point if not
  }
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<video loop="" autoplay="" muted=""> <source src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/simplescreenrecorder-2021-01-10_04-56-11.mp4" type="video/mp4"> </video>

<p>And a つぶやきProcessing version of course..</p>

<blockquote><p lang="cy" dir="ltr">t=0,p=i=&gt;\[k+(r=random(w/4))_cos(t+=.1),k+r_sin(t)\],setup=i=&gt;{createCanvas(w=1e3,w),m=Array(k=w/2).fill(0).map(p)},draw=r=&gt;{for(i=k;--i;)\[x,y\]=m\[i\],x+=sin(n=noise(x/k,y/k)_TAU),y+=cos(n),stroke(i%4_85),point(x,y),k_w+x_x+y_y-w_(x+y)&lt;7e4?m\[i\]=\[x,y\]:m\[i\]=p()};//<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%E3%81%A4%E3%81%B6%E3%82%84%E3%81%8DProcessing?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#つぶやきProcessing</a> <a href="https://t.co/xVhCBNUltL">pic.twitter.com/xVhCBNUltL</a></p>— yakinavault (@yakinavault) <a href="https://twitter.com/yakinavault/status/1347930637227855874?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 9, 2021</a></blockquote>


<h2 id="adding-colors">Adding Colors</h2>

<p>There are many strategies to colorizing this sketch. One is by just giving each particle a random initial color.</p>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/download-21.png" alt=""></p>

<p>However, I found that maintaining the initial x or y position in the particle array and using that to derive the hue information gives us some nice Jupiter/gaseous planet vibes.</p>

<video loop="" autoplay="" muted=""> <source src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/simplescreenrecorder-2021-01-10_05-18-19.mp4" type="video/mp4"> </video>

<p>The fringing at the sides can be avoided by moving 50% of the points in the reverse direction.</p>

<video loop="" autoplay="" muted=""> <source src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/simplescreenrecorder-2021-01-10_05-28-03.mp4" type="video/mp4"> </video>

<video loop="" autoplay="" muted=""> <source src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/simplescreenrecorder-2021-01-10_08-43-25.mp4" type="video/mp4"> </video>

<p>More color variations</p>

<p><img src="https://avinayak.github.io/uploads/untitled.png" alt=""></p>

<p>And that’s it. Hope this was educational!</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://avinayak.github.io/art/2021/01/09/noise-planets.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25712767</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 09:26:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Blocks Courtesy of Konrad Zuse (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25712727">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
January 10, 2021 | https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/blocks-courtesy-of-konrad-zuse | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/blocks-courtesy-of-konrad-zuse">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Apparently, I've got a theme going of Weird Syntax. Let's run with it.</p>

<p>Konrad Zuse was an early pioneer in computer science, although his name is perhaps somewhat less well-known than others. Zuse holds the honor of having built the first programmable computer—-the Z3—-back in the 40's, as well as several other computing firsts<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="nofollow">1</a></sup>. Of particular interest to this blog post is his early unimplemented programming language, Plankalkül.</p>

<p>Plankalkül was, like the Z3, in many respects ahead of its time. Zuse's explicit goal was to be able to describe programs at a high level, which meant he included control structures and datatype definitions<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="nofollow">2</a></sup> and other high-level constructs that were often missing in languages of the early years of computing. Zuse was working on Plankalkül at a time when his machines were not useable, which meant that his language work was more theoretical than it was technical, and consequently he allowed features that he wasn't entirely sure how to program. Despite his notes on it having been written in the mid-40's, they were not published until the 70's, and it was not implemented until the year 2000.</p>

<p>One thing that struck me, as I read programs in this notation that had been set down on a typewriter<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="nofollow">3</a></sup>, is that certain kinds of grouping were handled by explicit indication of scope: not via matched delimiters as in ALGOL-style languages, or via indentation in languages such as Python and Haskell, but by formatting the code so that a line bordered on the left of the scoped parts of the code:</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/static/zuse-01.png" alt=""></p>

<p>This is meant to capture the way grouping works in the hand-written or typeset notation, with brackets spanning multiple lines:</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/static/zuse-02.png" alt=""></p>

<p>I think this is notationally interesting: it's like Python's significant whitespace, but not, uh, whitespace. It would be incredibly tedious to type out, but still entirely compatible with current programming notation:</p>

<pre><code>class Tet
 | @staticmethod
 | def new_tet()
 |  | n = randint(0, len(Tet.Tets) - 1)
 |  | for p in Tet.Tets[n]
 |  |  | if p in Board.permanent
 |  |  |  | Game.lose()
 |  | Game.current = Tet(Tet.Tets[n], Tet.TetColors[n])
 |
 | def __init__(self, points, color)
 |  | self.points = points
 |  | self.color = color
</code></pre>

<p>and would be entirely amenable to beautifying via judicious application of Unicode:</p>

<pre><code>class Tet
 ┃ @staticmethod
 ┃ def new_tet()
 ┃  ┃ n = randint(0, len(Tet.Tets) - 1)
 ┃  ┃ for p in Tet.Tets[n]
 ┃  ┃  ┃ if p in Board.permanent
 ┃  ┃  ┗  ┗ Game.lose()
 ┃  ┗ Game.current = Tet(Tet.Tets[n], Tet.TetColors[n])
 ┃
 ┃ def __init__(self, points, color)
 ┃  ┃ self.points = points
 ┃  ┗ self.color = color
</code></pre>

<p>Looking at this notation, however, an interesting possibility struck me: a programmer could explicit annotate information about the <em>kind of scope</em> involved in a given line. In this Python-like example, I could, for example, distinguish class scope using double lines, function scope with thick lines, and control structure scope with thin lines:</p>

<pre><code>class Tet
 ║ @staticmethod
 ║ def new_tet()
 ║  ┃ n = randint(0, len(Tet.Tets) - 1)
 ║  ┃ for p in Tet.Tets[n]
 ║  ┃  │ if p in Board.permanent
 ║  ┃  └  └ Game.lose()
 ║  ┗ Game.current = Tet(Tet.Tets[n], Tet.TetColors[n])
 ║
 ║ def __init__(self, points, color)
 ║  ┃ self.points = points
 ║  ┗ self.color = color
</code></pre>

<p>One advantage of this scheme is that a handful of lines, viewed in isolation, still give you a clear view of what surrounds them. For example, I can view these two lines in isolation and still tell that they are within a control structure used within a function declared within a class:</p>

<pre><code> ║  ┃  │ if p in Board.permanent
 ║  ┃  └  └ Game.lose()
</code></pre>

<p>You could also imagine a hypothetical language in which choice of scope delimiter is important. In Python, <code>for</code> and <code>if</code> do not form a new lexical scope. What if instead we could stipulate the kind of scope they form by this notational convention?</p>

<pre><code>def okay()
 ┃ if True
 ┃  └ n = 5   # n is declared in function scope
 ┗ return n   # n leaks out of the if-scope

def not_okay()
 ┃ if True
 ┃  ┗ n = 5   # n is declared in the if's scope
 ┗ return n   # error: no n in scope here
</code></pre>

<p>That being said, there are a number of reasons that this notation is in inferior to existing notations:</p>
<ul><li>It makes refactoring code <em>much</em> more difficult.</li>
<li>It requires that the programmer <em>pay attention</em> to the sequence of enclosing scopes on a <em>line-by-line</em> basis, which is generally too pedantic and not particularly useful for a programmer.</li>
<li>The ability to select “which kind of scope” is by no means only expressible by this notation, as other syntactic features such as keywords and delimiters could express the same thing.</li>
<li>There are only so many line-like characters which can serve as a scope marker, so this scheme is not very extensible.</li>
<li>It complicates parsing (especially by introducing an entirely new class of parse errors in which adjacent lines feature incompatible sequences of delimiting lines), and so it also...</li>
<li>Complicates parse <em>error messages</em>, which are an important part of a language's UI and should be considered seriously.</li></ul>

<p>So, as in my previous post on <a href="https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/2014/8/noun-case" rel="nofollow">grammatical case in programming languages</a>, I urge readers <em>not</em> to use this notation as the concrete syntax for a programming language. This is merely an entertaining peek through the looking glass at a curious notational convention which was never adopted.</p>

<p>That said: this makes a very nice notation for <em>viewing</em> code, where the programmer does not have to explicitly draw ASCII art around their code; indeed, it bears more than a passing similarity to the graphical interface used in <a href="http://scratch.mit.edu/" rel="nofollow">Scratch</a>, and Sean McDirmid's <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/projects/liveprogramming/typography.aspx" rel="nofollow">Experiments in Code Typography</a> features this very convention as an interactive ornament on code in a Python-like language.</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://journal.infinitenegativeutility.com/blocks-courtesy-of-konrad-zuse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25712727</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 09:21:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Top Ranked Tweets on Hacker News 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25712499">thread link</a>) | @hgarg
<br/>
January 10, 2021 | https://harishgarg.com/writing/hacker-news-front-page-tweets-2020/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://harishgarg.com/writing/hacker-news-front-page-tweets-2020/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <ul>
<li>Data curated from <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="http://explorehackernews.xyz/?ref=harishgarg.com">Hacker News Front Page Explorer</a></li>
</ul>
<p>1.Every Google result now looks like an ad </p><p>2.macOS unable to open any non-Apple application </p><p>3.John Conway has died </p><p>4.iOS14 reveals that TikTok may snoop clipboard contents every few keystrokes </p><p>5.This electrical transmission tower has a problem </p><p>6.Apple does not keep the 30% commission on a refund </p><p>7.AWS forked my project and launched it as its own service </p><p>8.Google no longer providing original URL in AMP for image search results </p><p>9.Guido van Rossum joins Microsoft </p><p>10.When a customer refunds your paid app, Apple refunds its 30% cut </p>
<p>Get the Full list (162 records) <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://gum.co/hacker-news-tweets-2020">here for FREE</a></p>
<p>Want to run this and other kind of analysis on your own? Get the Full Database <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="http://explorehackernews.xyz/?ref=harishgarg.com">here</a></p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://harishgarg.com/writing/hacker-news-front-page-tweets-2020/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25712499</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 08:52:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Breakthrough in Measuring the Building Blocks of Nature]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25712475">thread link</a>) | @CapitalistCartr
<br/>
January 10, 2021 | http://m.nautil.us/blog/a-breakthrough-in-measuring-the-building-blocks-of-nature | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://m.nautil.us/blog/a-breakthrough-in-measuring-the-building-blocks-of-nature">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			

			<figure data-alt=""><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18082_ad5db5924e3e97ed8a387a499efa9fa0.jpg" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><span><i>An artistic rendering of the quarks and gluons that make up a proton.</i></span><span>Illustration by D. Dominguez / CERN</span></figcaption></figure><p><span>I</span>n a recent experiment done at the Max Planck Institute for Quantum Optics, in Germany, physicist Alexey Grinin and his colleagues came a step closer to resolving one of the more significant puzzles to have arisen in particle physics over the past decade. The puzzle is this: Ordinarily, when you set about measuring the size of something, you’d expect to get the same answer no matter what you use to measure it—a soda can has the diameter it does whether you measure it with a tape measure or callipers (provided these are properly calibrated, of course). Something must be amiss if your attempts to measure the can return different answers depending on the equipment, yet this is precisely what’s happened over multiple attempts to measure the spatial extent of a proton. What’s potentially at stake is our understanding of the building blocks of reality: the <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/370/6520/1061.abstract" target="_blank">differing measurements</a> could be heralding the existence of new forces or particles.</p><p>What does it mean for a subatomic particle to have a measurable “size”? Mathematically, fundamental particles are idealized as point particles, which is to say that, as far as we can tell, they have no meaningfully discernible spatial extent, or substructure, at all. True, all fundamental particles are associated with a quantum mechanical wave packet, which does have a spatial extent that depends on the energy of the particle. Yet these basic bits of Lego are entities whose wave packets you can, in principle, pack into as small a region as you’d like before the very notion of continuum geometry starts, at the Planck scale, to lose meaning. Fundamental particles organize into something analogous to a mini periodic table—consisting of the various force carrying particles, such as photons and gluons (the carrier particles of the strong nuclear force), along with three generations of quarks and leptons and the mass-generating Higgs boson—and can stack together in different combinations to form a zoo of so-called composite particles.</p><blockquote><p>There is less than one in about a trillion chance that the discrepancy could be a statistical fluke.</p> </blockquote><p>Perhaps the most familiar and ubiquitous of these is the proton. With at least one in every kind of element, it’s made up of two up quarks and a down quark that dance around each other in a tightly bound orbit maintained by exchanging gluons. This exchange process is so energetic that most of the mass of the proton (or for that matter, most of the material that makes us up) derives from the energy contained in these gluons—a consequence, as Einstein informed us, of <i>E</i> being equal to <i>mc</i><sup>2</sup>.&nbsp;<br></p><figure data-alt=""><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18083_78b8d6620afcd434a4b7fb41b22e595b.png" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><span><i>Fundamental particles organize into something analogous to a mini periodic table (above).</i></span><span>CERN</span></figcaption></figure><p>So it’s not meaningless to ask what the “size” of the proton is. The study by Grinin’s team highlights the fact that defining this notion remains a rather tricky affair. And, as we’ll see, their results serve to sharpen the mystery as to why other measurement methods researchers have used previously disagree.<br></p><p>A physicist can reasonably infer a proton’s size from the “charge radius”—roughly the averaged spatial extent of quark orbits inside. This quantity is probed in slightly different ways by electrons and muons (another sort of fundamental particle), when you probe their orbital configurations as they form “bound states” with the proton—atomic hydrogen in the case of electrons, muonic hydrogen in the case of muons. Because muons are about 200 times heavier than electrons, their lowest energy orbital configurations are much more tightly bound around the proton than are electrons in atomic hydrogen. Consequently, the differences in the energies of various orbitals in muonic hydrogen are much more sensitive to the proton’s size as well as being more “high pitched” than that of regular atomic hydrogen.&nbsp;</p><p>In other words, similar to how plucking a guitar string at a given tension produces a much higher note were we to fret it open, or at 1/200th its open length, the typical frequencies of the radiation emitted by transitions in muonic hydrogen are about 200 times higher than that in atomic hydrogen. These frequencies relate to something called the Rydberg constant—the tension of the guitar string in the analogy—which appears to be one of the potentially more significant sources of uncertainty proton size-wise. Orbital energy levels depend on both this constant and the charge radius of the proton.</p><p>Proton-size measurements didn’t conflict for decades. Different methods—like measuring the radius by observing electrons orbit within hydrogen atoms, or by scattering energetic electrons off of unbound protons—had converged on a value of 0.875 (give or take 0.006) femtometers. That’s a little less than a trillionth of a millimeter. That convergence was disrupted in 2010, when a paper came out titled, “The size of the proton.” As the researchers reported, <a href="http://www.quantum.physik.uni-potsdam.de/teaching/ss2015/pqt/Pohl2010.pdf" target="_blank">measurements</a> involving orbital configurations in muonic hydrogen returned a value of 0.842, give or take 0.001 femtometers. This may not seem like much of a difference, but it’s the accompanying error bars that matter. The measurements are, individually, so precise that their disagreement is over seven standard deviations—there is less than one in about a trillion chance that the discrepancy could be a statistical fluke.</p><p>There are only two possibilities for the anomalous result if the equipment used in the experiments and their calibrations all check out after careful scrutiny. Either some combination of physical constants, which researchers assume in order to experimentally infer the proton charge radius, isn’t known as accurately as we thought, or there is something different about the way muons interact with protons, compared to electrons, that renders particle physics incomplete.</p><p>The latter possibility, if substantiated, would, of course, cause a flurry of excitement among theoretical physicists to say the least, as it could imply the existence of new forces and particles. Not only would it reshape our understanding of the universe, it would represent a throwback to the days when physicists discovered particles (<a href="https://timeline.web.cern.ch/anderson-and-neddermeyer-discover-muon" target="_blank">such as the muon itself</a>) using equipment that could fit on a proverbial tabletop.</p><div id="inpagesub">
	<p>Get the <span>Nautilus</span> newsletter</p>
<p>
	The newest and most popular articles delivered right to your inbox!
</p>
			<!-- Begin MailChimp Signup Form -->
			




</div><p>Over the past few years, various teams have been attempting to get to the bottom of the matter by looking at different orbital transitions in atomic hydrogen that are sensitive to different combinations of the Rydberg constant and the charge radius. A 2019 <a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/365/6457/1007" target="_blank">measurement</a> by a group of researchers at York University in Canada looked at a particular orbital transition that was independent of the value of this constant, finding a value of 0.833 ± 0.010 femtometers, consistent with the smaller value obtained in muonic hydrogen.&nbsp;</p><p>Grinin’s team went a step further. They used a technique known as frequency comb spectroscopy. It involves pulses of laser light that are a superposition of equally spaced frequencies—a ruler in frequency space if you will—that allowed them to look at two different orbital transitions in atomic hydrogen sensitive to two different combinations of the proton size and the Rydberg constant. This permitted them to determine both with unprecedented accuracy. The technique reduced, to only about one part in ten trillion, the observational uncertainties in the frequency of light these transitions emitted—a staggering degree of accuracy by any standard.&nbsp;</p><p>Not only did Grinin’s team find a value for the charge radius of the proton consistent with the value obtained in muonic hydrogen, they inferred a much more precise value for the Rydberg constant. This accounted for some part of the discrepancy seen in other measurements in atomic hydrogen (which presumed a less accurate value).</p><p>It thus appears that the experimental value of the proton charge radius Grinin’s team obtained in atomic hydrogen is converging on the smaller values for the proton charge radius other researchers initially obtained in muonic hydrogen. The smaller value has by now even been adopted as the <a href="https://physics.nist.gov/cgi-bin/cuu/Value?rp" target="_blank">official value</a> on the National Institute of Standards and Technology <a href="https://www.nist.gov/programs-projects/codata-values-fundamental-physical-constants" target="_blank">CODATA</a> list of recommended physical constants—the official almanac for nuclear and atomic chemists and physicists.&nbsp;</p><p>Although this convergence, based on the continued refinement of experimental techniques, did not deliver the new physics some may have been hoping for, even the most despondent theoretical physicist can acknowledge the experimental artistry that seems to be bringing the matter closer to conclusion. What remains unresolved is the reason why measurements, relying on different spectroscopic methods in atomic hydrogen, return different values for the charge radius of the proton. The mystery, and along with it, the diminishing hope of particle physicists, endures for the time being.&nbsp;</p><p>This was enough motivation for a team of theoretical physicists, led by Cliff Burgess at the Perimeter Institute, in Canada, to systematically catalogue all possible sources of theoretical uncertainty in atomic spectroscopy over a <a href="https://inspirehep.net/literature?sort=mostrecent&amp;size=25&amp;page=1&amp;q=find%20a%20burgess,%20c%20and%20a%20zalavari" target="_blank">series of papers</a>. By isolating the ways in which new forces and particles might leave a tell-tale signature, they’ve thrown the gauntlet firmly back to the experimentalists. Future experiments, as always, will be the ultimate arbiter in this matter.&nbsp;</p><p><i>Subodh Patil is an assistant professor at the Lorentz Institute for Theoretical Physics at Leiden University. He tweets on occasion at @_subodhpatil.</i></p>

		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://m.nautil.us/blog/a-breakthrough-in-measuring-the-building-blocks-of-nature</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25712475</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 08:48:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A guide to SQL interview questions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25709870">thread link</a>) | @data4lyfe
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-sql-interview-questions/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-sql-interview-questions/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <p><strong>Table of Contents</strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: html-->
<!--kg-card-end: html--><h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3><p>SQL is the good old friend that has always worked. It’s something you always come back to, even as Pandas, Julia, Spark, Hadoop, and NoSql attempt to dethrone and replace SQL as the new de-facto data tool.</p><p>Eventually though, they all fail in the face of the consistently reliable SQL. And that's why SQL continues to get asked in interviews. </p><blockquote><strong>A note before we start...</strong></blockquote><blockquote>This guide should be used for anyone who is preparing for an interview in which they know SQL will show up. This guide<strong> is not</strong> a search engine optimized listacle (top 50 sql questions for 2021...really?).</blockquote><blockquote>Rather, this is <strong>real advice and REAL interview questions and exercises </strong>gathered from hundreds of data scientists, engineers, and analysts. We sprinkle exercises throughout this post after learning concepts. Be sure to try attempting the questions first before we walk through solving them. &nbsp;</blockquote><blockquote>Lastly, if you enjoy this article, <strong>please give us a share</strong> and check out our <a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/courses/data-science-course">SQL course</a> that goes a little deeper with more exercises and problems. </blockquote><h2 id="1-why-does-sql-show-up-on-the-interview">1. Why does SQL show up on the interview?</h2><figure><img src="https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/2021/01/image-6.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/2021/01/image-6.png 600w"></figure><p>SQL allows data scientists and engineers to do a couple of important things.</p><p>One is to <strong>effectively store and retrieve information at scale for analytics</strong>. Even though Google Sheets allows users to easily manipulate and visualize data, it cannot store and scale like a SQL database can. Other popular programs –namely Hadoop and Spark– can scale much further than SQL, but still don’t have a clean and easy-to-use language like SQL to retrieve data efficiently.</p><p>Another great thing about SQL is that understanding the fundamentals bridges the gap between <strong>engineering and data science</strong>. Knowing SQL well gives you a competitive edge over any other candidate, whether you're competing for a position as a product manager, software engineer, or even as a business analyst. Having the skillset to write and pull your own queries is like being a magician that can come up with analyses out of thin air. </p><p>And at the end of the day, you could just be really good at SQL if you wanted to and make tons of money creating ETL jobs or pulling dashboards with efficiency. That's how valued SQL is. </p><h3 id="how-often-does-sql-show-up-in-interviews">How often does SQL show up in interviews?</h3><p>One prevailing question is how often SQL shows up in interviews. </p><p>At Interview Query, we analyzed a dataset of Glassdoor data science interview experiences and responses submitted by our users. The analysis came back that SQL was asked:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/interview-experiences/facebook/data-scientist" rel="nofollow">70% of the time during Facebook’s data science interviews</a></li><li><a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/interview-experiences/Amazon/business-analyst" rel="nofollow">94% of the time during Amazon’s business intelligence and analyst interviews</a></li></ul><figure><img src="https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/2021/01/image-7.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/image-7.png 600w, https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/image-7.png 1000w, https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/2021/01/image-7.png 1262w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption><a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/interview-experiences/facebook/data-scientist">Skills tested in Facebook's Data Science Interview as of 2021</a></figcaption></figure><p>Due to its nature in being able to get and manipulate your own data, this is by far the most important skill now towards nabbing a data science position. And while pandas and other languages are useful, note that <a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-why-your-data-scientist-interviewer-wont-ask-pandas-questions/" rel="nofollow">SQL will always be the one that matters</a>.</p><h2 id="2-strategies-for-the-live-sql-interview">2. Strategies for the live SQL interview</h2><p>Let's go over the common strategies when tackling SQL interview questions. </p><p><strong>1.Repeat the problem statement</strong></p><p>When presented with a SQL question, listen carefully to the problem description and repeat back what you think the crux of the problem is. The interviewer can then help verify if your understanding is correct.</p><p><strong>2. Understand the edge cases</strong></p><p>If time permits, write out a base case and an edge case to show that you understand the problem. For example: if the interviewer asks you to pull the average number of events per user per day, write out an example scenario where you're verifying this metric. </p><p>Do duplicate events matter? Are we looking at distinct users? These are questions we need to clarify. </p><p><strong>3. Try working backwards if the problem is tricky</strong></p><p>Sketching out what the output of the SQL question will look like is a great strategy towards solving the problem. Usually, if I know what the end output table is supposed to look like, I can work backwards from there on what functions need to be applied before. </p><p>For example, if the output looks like this:</p><pre><code>date        | average events per user
------------+-----------------------
2021-12-01  |  3.5
2021-12-02  |  4.0</code></pre><p>I know that the table before this aggregation would have to look something like this.</p><pre><code>date       | event | user_id
-----------+-------+--------
2021-12-01 | click | 1
2021-12-01 | view  | 1
......</code></pre><p>And then, I can figure out what functions I should use to get to my desired output!</p><p><strong>4. Pattern match to different functions</strong></p><p>As you practice more and more SQL exercises, what you'll find is that many SQL problems follow similar patterns. There are techniques we can use in SQL, like utilizing <code>HAVING</code> on aggregations, self-joins and cross-joins, and applying window functions. But, additionally, we'll see problems that run in a similar vein. </p><p>For example, writing a query to get the second highest salary or writing a query to isolate every fifth purchase by a user utilizes the same <code>RANK</code> function in SQL. </p><p>Understanding the commonalities between questions will help you understand the first step to solving SQL questions faster because you can re-use similar code and stitch together techniques on top of each other. </p><p><strong>5. Start writing SQL</strong></p><p>Finally, it's important to just start writing SQL. It's better to start writing an imperfect solution vs trying to perfectly understand the problem or trying to perfect the solution on the first try. </p><p>Verbalize your assumptions and what you're doing as you write SQL and your interviewer can then be put on the same page as you. </p><h2 id="3-the-7-different-sql-interview-questions">3. The 7 different SQL interview questions</h2><p>SQL questions asked during interviews can vary widely across companies, but even more so across positions. You won't see data scientists asked the same SQL questions as software engineers, and that's because data scientists have to write different types of queries compared to software engineers. </p><p>Generally, each SQL interview question can be bucketed into these categories:</p><ul><li>Definition based SQL questions</li><li>Basic SQL questions</li><li>Reporting and metrics SQL questions</li><li>Analytics SQL questions</li><li>ETL SQL questions</li><li>Database design questions</li><li>Logic based SQL questions</li></ul><p>In this next section, we'll go over which types of SQL questions are expected for different roles and what those different kinds of SQL questions are in detail. </p><h2 id="4-sql-questions-for-data-scientists-and-analysts">4. SQL questions for data scientists and analysts</h2><p>SQL interview questions for data scientists and data analysts will likely show up in three parts of the interview process: the technical round, the take-home challenge, and the onsite interview. </p><p>The technical round and take-home challenge will usually consist of SQL questions <strong>designed to filter out candidates</strong>. Since SQL is commonly used as a filter mechanism for data scientists, it's important to perform well on this part of the interview in order to demonstrate competence. </p><p>Depending on what type of data science role you're interviewing for, you'll find that most SQL questions will be split into these three types:</p><ul><li>Basic SQL Interview Questions</li><li>Reporting and Metrics SQL Interview Questions</li><li>Analytics SQL Interview Questions</li></ul><h3 id="basic-sql-interview-questions">Basic SQL Interview Questions</h3><p>Basic SQL questions are what they sound like. These questions will be generally easy and focus on assessing if you know the basics. </p><p><strong>Definition based SQL questions </strong>are grouped into this category because they're super easy to learn. All you have to do is study a list of definitions of SQL terms and applications. These questions will include understanding the differences between joins, what kinds of aggregations exist, and knowing the basic functions like <code>CASE WHEN</code> or <code>HAVING</code>. </p><p>Basic SQL interview questions that involve a user actually writing a query are slightly different. These will involve getting the <code>COUNT</code> of a table, knowing what the <code>HAVING</code> clause does, and figuring out how to utilize <code>LEFT JOIN</code> versus <code>INNER JOIN</code> to give you the values that you need.</p><blockquote>Read more on the the <a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-three-sql-questions-you-must-know-to-pass/">basic concepts you need to know to pass your data science interview</a> here. </blockquote><figure><a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-three-sql-questions-you-must-know-to-pass/"><div><p>Three SQL Concepts for your Data Scientist Interview</p><p>I’ve interviewed a lot of data scientist candidates and have found there are a a lot of SQL interview questions for data science that eventually boil down to three generalized types of conceptual understandings.</p><p><img src="https://blog.interviewquery.com/favicon.ico"><span>Interview Query Blog</span></p></div><p><img src="https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/2020/02/sql_join.jpeg"></p></a></figure><p><strong>Basic SQL Concepts to Review</strong></p><ul><li>What's the difference between a <code>LEFT JOIN</code> and an <code>INNER JOIN</code>?</li><li>When would you use <code>UNION</code> vs <code>UNION ALL</code>? What if there were no duplicates?</li><li>What's the difference between <code>COUNT</code>and <code>COUNT DISTINCT</code>?</li><li>When would you use a <code>HAVING</code> clause versus a <code>WHERE</code> clause?</li></ul><p><strong>Basic SQL Question Example:</strong></p><figure><img src="https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/2021/01/image.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/size/w600/2021/01/image.png 600w, https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/size/w1000/2021/01/image.png 1000w, https://blog.interviewquery.com/content/images/2021/01/image.png 1306w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><blockquote><em>We're given two tables, a <code>users</code> table with demographic information and the neighborhood they live in and a <code>neighborhoods</code> table.</em></blockquote><blockquote><em>Write a query that returns all of the neighborhoods that have 0 users.</em></blockquote><p>Try answering this question with our <a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/questions/empty-neighborhoods">interactive SQL editor</a>.</p><p><strong>Here's a hint:</strong></p><p><em>Our predicament is to find all the neighborhoods without users that live in them. This means we have to introduce a <strong>concept of existence of a field in one table, while not existing in another.</strong></em></p><p><em>For example, let's say we generate some fake data of user's and the neighborhoods they live in. We would expect it to look something like this. </em></p><pre><code>neighborhoods.name  | users.id
____________________|__________
castro              | 1
castro              | 2
cole valley         | null
castro heights      | 3
sunset heights      | 4</code></pre><p><em>We see each user from one to four is appropriately placed in their respective neighborhood except for the neighborhood of Cole Valley. That's the neighborhood we're targeting for returning in our query. </em></p><p><em>Strategies: whenever the question asks about finding values with 0 something (users, employees, posts, etc..), immediately think of the concept of <strong><code>LEFT JOIN</code></strong>! An inner join finds any values that are in both tables, <strong>a left join keeps only the values in the left table</strong>.</em></p><p><em>Our predicament is to find all the neighborhoods without users. To do this, we must do a left join from the <code>neighborhoods</code> table to the <code>users</code> table.</em></p><p><em>If we then add in a where condition of <strong><code>WHERE users.id IS NULL</code></strong>, we will get every single neighborhood …</em></p></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-sql-interview-questions/">https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-sql-interview-questions/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.interviewquery.com/blog-sql-interview-questions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25709870</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 04:15:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Platform Is the Enemy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 20 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25708099">thread link</a>) | @nomdep
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://danielbmarkham.com/the-platform-is-the-enemy/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danielbmarkham.com/the-platform-is-the-enemy/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div id="post-body">
        <p>The premise of the movie "Idiocracy" is simple: in the future mankind has de-evolved into morons. Technology does so much for everybody that nobody knows how it all works anymore. &nbsp;If we can't fix it, we're all going to die.</p><p>One character asks the other what he likes, The answer is money.</p><p>"I can't believe you like money too!" the first character says without irony, "We should hang out!"</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.danielbmarkham.com/2021/01/JRJcXbeoSOlkRRzbC7HJ_idiocracy.jpg" alt=""></figure><p>The gag here is that of course, most everybody likes money. If you reduce all of your life enough, it's just food, sex, money, and looking cool. But who would want to do that? Over the centuries, humans have created massively-complex societies because everybody has different things they like doing and thinking about, but all of that complexity can be reduced to, well, an idiocracy if you try hard enough.</p><p>The movie, however, is just a joke, right? We would never allow that to happen, of course, because that's not the goal of technology. Technology's goal is to make us better, not dumber.</p><p>Wait one. Is that true? What <em>is</em> the goal of technology, anyway? Has anybody ever clearly stated it?</p><p>Recently I've heard two goals:</p><ol><li>The goal of technology is to become a <strong>brain extension</strong>, <em>helping you to decide what to do</em> and then helping you get it done.</li><li>The goal of technology is to become a <strong>hand-held power tool</strong>, helping you accomplish the things you've <em>already decided to do</em></li></ol><p>That's not the same thing. It turns out the difference is critical.</p><p>The old goal was much simpler: make something people want. I like that goal! It boils down the job of creating technology to the most important parts, need and ability. But was that sustainable? At the end of the day, don't we always end up making some combination of stuff that either helps us <em>make decisions</em> or helps us <em>implement decisions</em> we've already made? And aren't the two fundamentally incompatible in a future society?</p><p>Yelp tells you which restaurant to go to. Your GPS automatically takes you there. These are not just different problems, they're different <em>kinds of problems</em>. Getting from point A to point B is a matter of math and geometry. Which restaurant is the best tonight? You could spend hours debating that with friends.</p><p>If you reduce anything down enough it becomes idiotic. Each piece of technology we deploy can have the goal of helping us do what we've already decided or helping us decide what to do. The first option leaves the thinking up to us. The second option "helps" us think.</p><figure><iframe width="267" height="200" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sZHCVyllnck?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></figure><p>You like money too? Wow! I like money! We should hang out!</p><p>Human brains are not computers. Brains are designed to help us survive and pass on our genes using the minimum amount of energy available. If the GPS takes me where I'm going, I don't need to know how to use maps anymore. So I stop knowing how to use maps. Dump those neurons, they're not needed. If Yelp picks the restaurants for me enough, I stop having nuanced preferences about restaurants. That energy expenditure is no longer needed for survival and reproduction. Dump those neurons. Over time people stop caring about the tiny details of what the difference is between a good and a great restaurant. Yelp handles that.</p><p>For some folks, who cares? It's food. Go eat it. For other folks, picking the right place can be a serious undertaking, worthy of heavy thought and consideration. But if over the years apps like Yelp boil all of that down to four or five stars, then our collective brain is not going to bother with it. Human brains are not computers. If computers do the work for us, we turn off those neurons and save energy.</p><p>Meanwhile, on social media there's currently this huge discussion. One bunch of folks says that social media is being overbearing in its censorship of fringe and sometimes hateful opinions. The other bunch of folks says social media is a festering sore full of people who are ugly, hateful, and abusive to those weakest among us. The community has to set standards.</p><p>There doesn't have to be a right and wrong here. I think the crucial thing to to understand that both sides can be entirely correct. We are dealing with the same kind of question.</p><p>All three of these topics -- whether humanity is becoming idiots or not, what the ultimate goal of technology is or should be, and how social media should work -- are intricately related. They're related because of this: <em>the platform is the enemy</em>.</p><p>The minute we create a platform for something, whether it's rating movies, tracking projects, or chatting with friends about work, as that platform takes over mindshare, <em>the assumption becomes that this is a solved problem</em>.</p><p>The telephone was great. Once we had the telephone, people didn't have to worry about how to talk to people far away anymore. Just pick up the phone. Solved problem.</p><p>Facebook is great. Once we had Facebook, people didn't have to worry about how to interact with their friends in a social setting anymore. Just click on the little FB notification (Which seems to be always flashing for some reason to get my attention) Solved problem?</p><p>But these are entirely different things! With the phone, I know who I want to call and why. I push buttons and we are connected. The tech helps me do what I've already decided to do. With Facebook, on the other hand, they get paid to show me things in a certain order. The premise is that I'm waiting (or "exploring" if you prefer) until I find something to interact with. The phone is a tool for me to use. I am the tool Facebook is using. I am no longer acting. I am reacting.</p><p>And even if they weren't paid, interacting with friends socially is an extremely complex affair. What kind of mood are they in? What's their life history? What things are bad to bring up? How does their body language look? Facebook's gimmick is "Hey, we've reduced all of this to bits and bytes, and we'll even show you what bits and bytes to look at next!"</p><p>Solved problem.</p><p>Many, many people do not use the internet, the internet uses them. And this percentage is constantly growing.</p><figure><img src="https://cdn.danielbmarkham.com/2021/01/9EBNeUmSy6TMDUpKTLL6_terminator-robot.jpg" alt=""></figure><p>Just like the restaurant example, maybe that's fine. I have friends, I have opinions, who cares? It's all idle chat anyway.</p><p>That logic can be true for a bunch of things, but can't be true for <em>everything</em>. Otherwise, at some point 100 years from now, we're comparing our life values and end up saying something like "I like money too". Everything can't all be reduced down to the lowest common denominator. If it does, we all die.</p><p>Life is not a bit or byte, a number to be optimized. It's meaning we define ourselves, in ways we should not quantize.</p><p>Platforms, by their very nature, constantly send out the subtle message: <em>This is a solved problem. No further effort on your part is required here. No thinking needed.</em> Platforms resist change. They resist their own evolution by subtly poisoning the discussion before it even starts.</p><p>Are restaurant choices more or less important than which movie to watch tonight? There's no right or wrong answer to these questions. We have nice categories like restaurants and movies because currently people consider those things to be different kinds of choices. But why? If the algorithm is king, why shouldn't an algorithm determine both of those things for me? And if it does, why should I bother with worrying about which category is which?</p><p>Human brains are not computers. Let the platform decide. Energy not needed. Dump those neurons.</p><p>This is the more important point. It's not that the platforms turn what might be complex things into simple numbers, or even that they monetize attention. It's that by turning everything into numbers, over time they destroy the distinction between the categories entirely. Platforms are the enemy because they resist analysis in the areas they dominate.</p><p>Platforms turn into settled fact things that should be open for debate, like whether or not Taco Bell is a Mexican restaurant, or whether Milo is an artist with something useful to tell us. (I'm going with "no" and "no" for both of these.) More dangerously, they do the work of deciding <em>what categories various things go into</em>. This category over here is important. That category over there is not. We all make these decisions, and they're all different, and the categories each of us pays careful attention to and loves obsessing about are all different, and because we all have different viewpoints and priorities humankind advances in thousands of directions simultaneously. We survive. We evolve.</p><p>Twitter has to decide whether PERSON_X can speak or not because on the Twitter platform, that question has to have a yes or no answer based on the person. Twitter's category for deciding who can speak is "who is that?" Is that the right category for social conversations? For political conversations? For conversations about philosophy? Math? Who knows? Who cares? Twitter has decided. Solved problem.</p><p>Everybody has different things they like doing and thinking about. Different conversations and audiences have different criteria. Some problems should never be solved. Or rather more directly, some problems should never have a universal answer.</p><p>An aside: We see the same thing in programming. One bunch of folks creates various platforms in order to do the thinking for another bunch of folks. Sometimes these platforms take off and become industry standards. That's quite rare, however. Most of the time we end up training morons who can weakly code against the platform but can't reason effectively about the underlying architecture or reason for the platform to exist in the first place. In our desire to help, we harm the very people we're trying to assist -- by subtly giving them the impression that this is a solved problem. Programmers are just a decade or so ahead of the rest of us.</p><p>Popular platforms aren't just a danger economically because they control commerce. They're not just a danger politically because they selectively control and amplify political discourse. They're an extinction-level, existential danger to humans because they prevent people from seriously considering what kinds of categories are important in …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://danielbmarkham.com/the-platform-is-the-enemy/">https://danielbmarkham.com/the-platform-is-the-enemy/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danielbmarkham.com/the-platform-is-the-enemy/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25708099</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 02:23:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Podcast on innovation systems, with Ben Reinhardt]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25707442">thread link</a>) | @willbobaggins
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://narrativespodcast.com/2020/12/21/21-innovation-systems-with-ben-reinhardt/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://narrativespodcast.com/2020/12/21/21-innovation-systems-with-ben-reinhardt/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1985">

                    
                    <div>
                        
<p>In this episode, we talk with Ben Reinhardt about different innovation systems, how to create more sci-fi technology a reality, and why our research institutions are not as effective as they used to be. You can check out Ben’s work at https://benjaminreinhardt.com/about/.</p>



<div><p>Some things mentioned in the episode: </p><p><a href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2020/05/12/studies-on-slack/">Studies on Slack</a></p></div>



<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donald_Braben">Don Braben</a></p>



<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DARPA">DARPA</a></p>



<p>Ben’s <a href="https://twitter.com/ben_reinhardt?lang=en">Twitter</a></p>



<figure></figure>
                                            </div>

                </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://narrativespodcast.com/2020/12/21/21-innovation-systems-with-ben-reinhardt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25707442</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 01:30:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Blocks Courtesy of Konrad Zuse (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25705391">thread link</a>) | @Tomte
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/2014/9/blocks-courtesy-of-konrad-zuse | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/2014/9/blocks-courtesy-of-konrad-zuse">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Apparently, I've got a theme going of Weird Syntax. Let's run with it.</p>

<p>Konrad Zuse was an early pioneer in computer science, although his name is perhaps somewhat less well-known than others. Zuse holds the honor of having built the first programmable computer—-the Z3—-back in the 40's, as well as several other computing firsts<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="nofollow">1</a></sup>. Of particular interest to this blog post is his early unimplemented programming language, Plankalkül.</p>

<p>Plankalkül was, like the Z3, in many respects ahead of its time. Zuse's explicit goal was to be able to describe programs at a high level, which meant he included control structures and datatype definitions<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="nofollow">2</a></sup> and other high-level constructs that were often missing in languages of the early years of computing. Zuse was working on Plankalkül at a time when his machines were not useable, which meant that his language work was more theoretical than it was technical, and consequently he allowed features that he wasn't entirely sure how to program. Despite his notes on it having been written in the mid-40's, they were not published until the 70's, and it was not implemented until the year 2000.</p>

<p>One thing that struck me, as I read programs in this notation that had been set down on a typewriter<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="nofollow">3</a></sup>, is that certain kinds of grouping were handled by explicit indication of scope: not via matched delimiters as in ALGOL-style languages, or via indentation in languages such as Python and Haskell, but by formatting the code so that a line bordered on the left of the scoped parts of the code:</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/static/zuse-01.png" alt=""></p>

<p>This is meant to capture the way grouping works in the hand-written or typeset notation, with brackets spanning multiple lines:</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/static/zuse-02.png" alt=""></p>

<p>I think this is notationally interesting: it's like Python's significant whitespace, but not, uh, whitespace. It would be incredibly tedious to type out, but still entirely compatible with current programming notation:</p>

<pre><code>class Tet
 | @staticmethod
 | def new_tet()
 |  | n = randint(0, len(Tet.Tets) - 1)
 |  | for p in Tet.Tets[n]
 |  |  | if p in Board.permanent
 |  |  |  | Game.lose()
 |  | Game.current = Tet(Tet.Tets[n], Tet.TetColors[n])
 |
 | def __init__(self, points, color)
 |  | self.points = points
 |  | self.color = color
</code></pre>

<p>and would be entirely amenable to beautifying via judicious application of Unicode:</p>

<pre><code>class Tet
 ┃ @staticmethod
 ┃ def new_tet()
 ┃  ┃ n = randint(0, len(Tet.Tets) - 1)
 ┃  ┃ for p in Tet.Tets[n]
 ┃  ┃  ┃ if p in Board.permanent
 ┃  ┃  ┗  ┗ Game.lose()
 ┃  ┗ Game.current = Tet(Tet.Tets[n], Tet.TetColors[n])
 ┃
 ┃ def __init__(self, points, color)
 ┃  ┃ self.points = points
 ┃  ┗ self.color = color
</code></pre>

<p>Looking at this notation, however, an interesting possibility struck me: a programmer could explicit annotate information about the <em>kind of scope</em> involved in a given line. In this Python-like example, I could, for example, distinguish class scope using double lines, function scope with thick lines, and control structure scope with thin lines:</p>

<pre><code>class Tet
 ║ @staticmethod
 ║ def new_tet()
 ║  ┃ n = randint(0, len(Tet.Tets) - 1)
 ║  ┃ for p in Tet.Tets[n]
 ║  ┃  │ if p in Board.permanent
 ║  ┃  └  └ Game.lose()
 ║  ┗ Game.current = Tet(Tet.Tets[n], Tet.TetColors[n])
 ║
 ║ def __init__(self, points, color)
 ║  ┃ self.points = points
 ║  ┗ self.color = color
</code></pre>

<p>One advantage of this scheme is that a handful of lines, viewed in isolation, still give you a clear view of what surrounds them. For example, I can view these two lines in isolation and still tell that they are within a control structure used within a function declared within a class:</p>

<pre><code> ║  ┃  │ if p in Board.permanent
 ║  ┃  └  └ Game.lose()
</code></pre>

<p>You could also imagine a hypothetical language in which choice of scope delimiter is important. In Python, <code>for</code> and <code>if</code> do not form a new lexical scope. What if instead we could stipulate the kind of scope they form by this notational convention?</p>

<pre><code>def okay()
 ┃ if True
 ┃  └ n = 5   # n is declared in function scope
 ┗ return n   # n leaks out of the if-scope

def not_okay()
 ┃ if True
 ┃  ┗ n = 5   # n is declared in the if's scope
 ┗ return n   # error: no n in scope here
</code></pre>

<p>That being said, there are a number of reasons that this notation is in inferior to existing notations:</p>
<ul><li>It makes refactoring code <em>much</em> more difficult.</li>
<li>It requires that the programmer <em>pay attention</em> to the sequence of enclosing scopes on a <em>line-by-line</em> basis, which is generally too pedantic and not particularly useful for a programmer.</li>
<li>The ability to select “which kind of scope” is by no means only expressible by this notation, as other syntactic features such as keywords and delimiters could express the same thing.</li>
<li>There are only so many line-like characters which can serve as a scope marker, so this scheme is not very extensible.</li>
<li>It complicates parsing (especially by introducing an entirely new class of parse errors in which adjacent lines feature incompatible sequences of delimiting lines), and so it also...</li>
<li>Complicates parse <em>error messages</em>, which are an important part of a language's UI and should be considered seriously.</li></ul>

<p>So, as in my previous post on <a href="https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/2014/8/noun-case" rel="nofollow">grammatical case in programming languages</a>, I urge readers <em>not</em> to use this notation as the concrete syntax for a programming language. This is merely an entertaining peek through the looking glass at a curious notational convention which was never adopted.</p>

<p>That said: this makes a very nice notation for <em>viewing</em> code, where the programmer does not have to explicitly draw ASCII art around their code; indeed, it bears more than a passing similarity to the graphical interface used in <a href="http://scratch.mit.edu/" rel="nofollow">Scratch</a>, and Sean McDirmid's <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/projects/liveprogramming/typography.aspx" rel="nofollow">Experiments in Code Typography</a> features this very convention as an interactive ornament on code in a Python-like language.</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.infinitenegativeutility.com/2014/9/blocks-courtesy-of-konrad-zuse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25705391</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 22:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: JavaScript Program Synthesis]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25705059">thread link</a>) | @coolvision
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://grgv.xyz/inductive_program_synthesis/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://grgv.xyz/inductive_program_synthesis/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p>Any compiler or transpiler is doing some form of program synthesis. But “proper” program synthesis usually means generation of high level programs from scratch, given only high level problem descriptions.</p>
<p>This post is about one of the most simple and straightforward methods of automatic program synthesis: inductive synthesis based on <strong>input-output examples</strong> specification and <strong>brute-force enumerative</strong> search.</p>
<h3>Synthesis task specification</h3>
<p>Let's start with a simple example. Suppose that we want to automatically generate a program that reverses an array.</p>
<p>How to formulate this task for the automatic program generator? One option is to just describe it in natural language. But it would be quite hard to automatically parse and understand. A simpler way is to provide examples of inputs and expected outputs:</p>
<p>[1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6] → [6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1]</p>
<p>[5, 2, 7, 6] → [6, 7, 2, 5]</p>
<p>It's similar to a programmer working on a task using test-driven development, with a set of self-explanatory tescases.</p>
<h3>Brute-force search</h3>
<p>How to find a program that satisfies some input-output examples? There are several possible search strategies, but the simplest one is just with a brute force enumeration.</p>
<p>The idea is to generate all programs (within some size liimts and a limited language subset), and pick the first one that works correctly for all specified examples.</p>
<p>This is probably the least efficient approach of all, but with some additional optimizations and heuristics for reducing the search space it can actually be practical.</p>
<p>For example, an algorithm that won last year's synthesis competition <a href="https://sygus.org/comp/2019/">SyGuS-Comp 2019</a> in programming-by-examples track, is based on brute-force enumerative search strategy. As well as some previous years winners (<a href="#examples" id="ref1">EUSOLVER, Enumerative CEGIS Solver</a>). There are even some practical applications, for example brute-force search can be used for <a href="http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2462174">synthesising distributed systems protocols</a>.</p>
<h3>Generating Javascript</h3>
<p>For generating and manipulating programs, code has to be represented as a data structure. This is not a problem in homoiconic languages like Lisp, but in Javascript it’s harder.</p>
<p>One simple idea (used, for example in miniMAL project <a href="https://github.com/kanaka/miniMAL">https://github.com/kanaka/miniMAL</a>), is to use JSON for representing programs. In this case, JSON arrays are serving as an analog of Lisp s-expressions.</p>
<p>Similar to an s-expression, each JavaScript expression is represented as a JSON array. First element is a function name, and the rest of elements are for function arguments.</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<table>
  <thead>
  <tr>
   <td><strong>Javascript</strong></td>
   <td><strong>JSON</strong></td>
  </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody><tr>
   <td>Math.pow(x, 2)</td>
   <td>["Math.pow", "x", 2]</td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>Math.pow(Math.sin(x), 2)</td>
   <td>[“Math.pow”, [“Math.sin”,  “x”], 2]</td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>For operators, can use prefix notation:</p>
<table>
  <tbody><tr>
   <td>x = 2 + 2</td>
   <td>["=", x, ["+", 2, 2]]</td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>There are some special expressions formats: control flow, variables declaration.</p>
<table>
  <tbody><tr>
   <td><strong>Javascript</strong>
   </td>
   <td><strong>JSON</strong>
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>let x = 1
   </td>
   <td> ["let", "x", 1]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>for (let i = 0; i &lt; 10; i += 1) { console.log(i) }
   </td>
   <td>["for”, ”i”, ”0”, ”10”, ”1”,["block", [“console.log”, “i”]]]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>if (i &gt; 1) { i = 1; }
   </td>
   <td>["if", [“&gt;“, “i”, 1], ["block", [“=“, “i”, 1]]]
   </td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>Also need syntax conventions for calling methods, accessing properties, and indexing arrays:</p>
<table>
  <tbody><tr>
   <td>let a = new Array(0, 1, 2)
   </td>
   <td>["let", "a", ["new Array", 0, 1, 2]]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>a.shift()
   </td>
   <td>[".shift", "a"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>let n1 = a.length
   </td>
   <td>["let",  "n1", [".length_", "a"]]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>let n2 = a[1]
   </td>
   <td>["let",  "n2", ["get_index", a, 1]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>a[1] = 2
   </td>
   <td>["set_index", a, 0, 0]
   </td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>This allows to represent a wide range of possible JavaScript expressions, and covers all language features needed for a simple demo.</p>
<p>Code for transforming from JSON representation to Javascript is fairly simple. It just has to traverse arrays, print out expressions elements in correct order, and deal with code formatting.</p>
<h3>Simple DSL</h3>
<p>For brute-force search to be feasible, search space has to be limited to some restricted domain-specific language subset, which depends on the kind of the target problem.</p>
<p>For example, can design a simple DSL targeted for simple array processing. It should have functions for array access and manipulation, simple arithmetics, and control flow functions.</p>
<table>
  <tbody><tr>
   <td><strong>function</strong>
   </td>
   <td><strong>Javascript</strong>
   </td>
   <td><strong>JSON</strong>
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>subtract
   </td>
   <td>number = number?? - number??
   </td>
   <td>["-", "number??", "number??", "number"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>add
   </td>
   <td>number = number?? + number??
   </td>
   <td>["+", "number??", "number??", "number"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>greater than
   </td>
   <td>boolean = number?? &gt; number??
   </td>
   <td>["&gt;", "number??", "number??", "boolean"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>less than
   </td>
   <td>boolean = number?? &lt; number??
   </td>
   <td>["&lt;", "number??", "number??", "boolean"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>equal
   </td>
   <td>boolean = number?? == number??
   </td>
   <td>["==", "number??", "number??", "boolean"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>array length
   </td>
   <td>number = array??.length
   </td>
   <td>[".length_", "array??", "number"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>get array element at index
   </td>
   <td>number = array??[number??]
   </td>
   <td>["get_index", "array??", "number??", "number"]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>set array element at index
   </td>
   <td>array??[number??] = number
   </td>
   <td>["set_index", "output", "number??", "number??", ""]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>for loop
   </td>
   <td>for (let i in array??) { ?? }
   </td>
   <td>["for", "i", ["block", "??"], "in", "array??", ""]
   </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
   <td>If condition
   </td>
   <td>if (boolean??) { ?? }
   </td>
   <td>["if", "boolean??", ["block", "??"], ""],
   </td>
  </tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>In the DSL description, "??" stands for an undefined value, that can be replaced with an expression or a variable. This notation is taken from <a href="#sketch" id="ref2">SKETCH language</a>, where "??" represents a <em>hole,</em> a placeholder that the synthesizer can replace with an integer constant.</p>
<p>Some undefined values have annotated types. For example "number??" means that the argument should be replaced with an expression that has "number" return value. This allows for additional limitations on the search space.</p>
<h3>Algorithm for program generation</h3>
<p>How to generate all programs that can be represented with the DSL? The algorithm is fairly simple: start with some undefined values, and iteratively replace them with all possible options picked from the list of DSL expressions. Selected and pasted expressions would contain some undefined values of their own, so the process is repeated until all the options are used, or until expressions tree depth reaches some limit.</p>
<p>It’s like iterative template rewriting, and it’s easier to demonstrate with an example:</p>
<table>
<tbody><tr>
	<td>1. Start with an empty/undefined program </td>
	<td>["??", "??", "??", "??"] </td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>2. Traverse the expressions tree, and pick the first occurring undefined value </td>
	<td>[<span>"??"</span>, "??", "??", "??"] </td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>3. List all options for replacing this value (expressions that have an empty return type) </td>
	<td><span>["set_index", "output", "number??", "number??", ""]</span><br>
		["if", "boolean??", ["block", "??"], ""]<br>
		["if", "boolean??", ["block", "??"], ""]
	</td>
</tr>
<tr>
	<td>4. Repace undefined value with the first option </td>
	<td>[<span>["set_index", "output", "number??", "number??", ""]</span>, "??", "??" ,"??"] </td>
</tr>
</tbody></table>
<p>Steps 2-4 are repeated iteratively. Expressions tree is traversed depth-first, and each found leaf corresponds to a unique program. Press “next” button in the demo below, to see next iterations.</p>


<div id="demo2">

	<p>
		Demo: iterative program generation
	</p>

	<p>step</p>
	<p>reset</p>

	
</div>

<p>Generated programs are verified with the given input-output examples:</p>
<ol>
<li>Translate from JSON represenation to Javascript</li>
<li>Fill pre-defined input array variable with an example</li>
<li>Evaluate the program with eval()</li>
<li>Check if contents of the pre-defined output variable correspond to the output example.</li>
</ol>
<p>The demo below shows program generation for "array reversal" problem. Press “generate” button to see continuous generation, or use “next” to see generation steps. It generates and checks around a million of short programs per minute, and is able so solve the problem in ~10-20s. I tweaked the DSL to have a bare minimum of available expressions, for search to be faster. Size of the program is also limited by number of used varialbes (limited to 4). It would still work with larger more generic DSL, just would take more time.</p>

<div id="demo5">

	<p>
		Demo: generate a program for reversing an array.
	</p>

	<p>step</p>
	<p>generate</p>
	<p>stop</p>
	<p>reset</p>

	<div>

		<div>

			<p>Input/output examples</p>
			

			<p>Generated program</p>
			

			<p>Evaluation result</p>
			
		</div>

		

	</div>
</div>

<p>Some more examples are show below. They also have custom DSLs tuned for each problem, so that it does not take too much time (~10-20s).</p>


<h3> Example: generate a program that finds sum of array elements</h3>

<div id="demo3">

	<p>
		Demo: generate a program that finds sum of array elements
	</p>

	<p>step</p>
	<p>generate</p>
	<p>stop</p>
	<p>reset</p>

	<div>

		<div>

			<p>Input/output examples</p>
			

			<p>Generated program</p>
			

			<p>Evaluation result</p>
			
		</div>

		

	</div>
</div>



<h3> Example: generate a program that finds max element in an array</h3>

<div id="demo4">

	<p>
		Demo: generate a program that finds max element in an array
	</p>

	<p>step</p>
	<p>generate</p>
	<p>stop</p>
	<p>reset</p>

	<div>

		<div>

			<p>Input/output examples</p>
			

			<p>Generated program</p>
			

			<p>Evaluation result</p>
			
		</div>

		

	</div>
</div>

<h2>Refenences &amp; links</h2>
<p>(book) <a href="https://rishabhmit.bitbucket.io/papers/program_synthesis_now.pdf">Program Synthesis</a><br>
Sumit Gulwani, Oleksandr Polozov, Rishabh Singh</p>
<p>(course materials) Introduction to Program Synthesis<br>
<a href="http://people.csail.mit.edu/asolar/SynthesisCourse/Lecture2.htm">http://people.csail.mit.edu/asolar/SynthesisCourse/Lecture2.htm</a></p>
<h3>Papers</h3>
<p><a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.367.9604&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf">Dimensions in Program Synthesis</a><br>
Sumit Gulwani</p>
<p><a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download;jsessionid=7EC748B93DCDCE0DABC810450BD07AE1?doi=10.1.1.180.1237&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf">Inductive Programming (A Survey of Program Synthesis Techniques)</a><br>
Emanuel Kitzelmann</p>
<p><span id="examples"><a href="#ref1">↑</a></span><br>
Scaling Enumerative Program Synthesis via Divide and Conquer<br>
Rajeev Alur, Arjun Radhakrishna, and Abhishek Udupa</p>
<p>CVC4SY for SyGuS-COMP 2019<br>
Andrew Reynolds, Haniel Barbosa, Andres Nötzli, Clark Barrett, Cesare Tinelli</p>
<p><span id="sketch"><a href="#ref2">↑</a></span><br>
The Sketching Approach to Program Synthesis<br>
Armando Solar-Lezama</p>
<h3>Blog posts</h3>
<p><a href="https://thegradient.pub/p/577a122d-df49-4e1f-8dc3-324f5c784236/">Software that writes software: on program synthesis</a><br>
Adithya Ganesh</p>
<p><a href="https://barghouthi.github.io/2017/04/24/synthesis-primer/">A Program Synthesis Primer </a><br>
Aws Albarghouthi</p>
<p><a href="https://alexpolozov.com/blog/program-synthesis-2018/">Program Synthesis in 2017-18</a><br>
Alex Polozov</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~asampson/blog/minisynth.html">Program Synthesis is Possible</a><br>
Adrian Sampson</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.sigplan.org/2020/03/25/homoiconicity-lisp-and-program-synthesis/">Homoiconicity, Lisp, and Program Synthesis</a><br>
Rajesh Jayaprakash</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.sigplan.org/2019/07/31/program-synthesis-in-2019/">Program Synthesis in 2019</a><br>
<a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~bornholt/post/synthesis-explained.html">Program Synthesis Explained</a><br>
<a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~bornholt/post/building-synthesizer.html">Building a Program Synthesizer</a><br>
<a href="https://blog.sigplan.org/2019/11/26/building-your-first-program-synthesizer/">Building Your First Program Synthesizer</a><br>
James Bornholt</p>


			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://grgv.xyz/inductive_program_synthesis/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25705059</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 21:38:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building a runtime reflection system for Rust (Part 3)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25704707">thread link</a>) | @lukastyrychtr
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://www.osohq.com/post/runtime-reflection-pt-3 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.osohq.com/post/runtime-reflection-pt-3">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><h2><strong>Part 3: <code>dyn Method</code></strong></h2>
<h3>Introduction</h3>
<p>Welcome to the third and final installment of our series on how we implemented a runtime reflection system in Rust.</p>
<p>So far, we've shown how we came up with a fairly simple <code>Class</code> and <code>Instance</code> model for thinking about runtime Rust classes. In <a href="https://www.osohq.com/post/rust-reflection-pt-1">Part 1</a>, we used these for type checking, and in <a href="https://www.osohq.com/post/runtime-reflection-pt-2">Part 2</a> we added support for reading attributes off of a struct.</p>
<p>In this post, we pick up where we left off with attribute getters, and expand into <strong>method calls</strong>. In some ways, the same techniques we used for attributes work just as well here. We can store a map from method name to functions implementing them. However, there's a curveball: the Rust <code>Fn*</code> traits. We'll talk through the wrong turns we took, and the tidbits of Rust knowledge we picked up along the way.</p>
<h2>Method Calls</h2>
<p>Now that we have classes, instances, and attributes, the next obvious step is to add methods.</p>
<p>In oso policies, it is possible to call both class and instance methods, with and without arguments.</p>
<p>So given the struct:</p>
<pre><code>struct Cat;

impl Cat {
    /// A class method (note lack of `self`).
    fn meow() -&gt; String {
       "meowww".to_string()
    }

    /// An instance method.
    fn feed(&amp;self, food: &amp;str) -&gt; String {
        if food == "tuna" { "purr".to_string() } else { Self::meow() }
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>We should be able to write policy logic:</p>
<pre><code>favourite_food(cat: Cat, food) if cat.feed(food) != Cat.meow();
</code></pre>

<p>Which says that the input <code>food</code> is the cat's favourite food if the result of feeding the cat is not the same as the result of the cat meowing.</p>
<h3>Step 1: Zero arguments</h3>
<p>Let's start with a simple implementation for methods that take <em>zero</em> arguments. The approach for implementing zero-argument methods is extremely similar to how we'd implement attribute getters, and we've actually done this already in Part 2:</p>
<pre><code>/// Class definitions
struct Class {
    ...

    /// Map from attribute name to the attribute lookup
    methods: HashMap&lt;&amp;'static str, InstanceMethod&gt;
}

struct InstanceMethod(Arc&lt;dyn Fn(&amp;Instance) -&gt; PolarValue);
</code></pre>

<p>Similarly, we need to add a method onto our <code>ClassBuilder</code> struct to allow us to register new methods:</p>
<pre><code>pub fn add_method&lt;F, R&gt;(mut self, name: &amp;'static str, f: F) -&gt; Self
where
    F: Fn(&amp;T) -&gt; R,
    R: crate::ToPolar,
{
    self.class.methods.insert(name, InstanceMethod::new(f));
    self
}
</code></pre>

<p>Super easy! End of blog post. See you next time 😎 </p>
<p>But wait, what about methods with multiple arguments?</p>
<h3>Step 2: Multiple Arguments and the <code>Fn*</code> traits</h3>
<p>Let's take what we have above and add in support for multiple arguments.</p>
<pre><code>struct InstanceMethod(Arc&lt;dyn Fn(&amp;Instance, Vec&lt;PolarValue&gt;) -&gt; PolarValue&gt;);
</code></pre>

<p>This mostly works for what we need! Polar doesn't care about method arities (how many arguments the method accepts) – it will send over however many arguments it has as a vector. Polar supports both variable number of arguments (varargs) and keyword arguments (kwargs). The latter is only supported for host languages that also have that concept, and Rust does not.</p>
<p>But this isn't the end of the story. The crucial part of the <code>AttributeGetter</code> interface was that you could pass in any method or closure for the attribute getter, and the <code>AttributeGetter::new</code> method handled all the type-conversions transparently. This hid the messy, error-prone details from the user and kept the interface clean.</p>
<p>So let's do the same for <code>InstanceMethod</code>!</p>
<pre><code>impl InstanceMethod {
    pub fn new&lt;T, F, ???&gt;(f: F) -&gt; Self
    where
        F: Fn(&amp;T, ???)
        F::Result: ToPolarResult,
        T: 'static,
    {
        Self(Arc::new(
            move |receiver: &amp;Instance, args: Vec&lt;PolarValue&gt;| {
                let receiver = receiver
                    .downcast()
                    .map_err(|e| e.invariant().into());
                // ermm.... what next?
            },
        ))
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>We've hit our first problem.</p>
<p>The input to an attribute getter never accepted any arguments, and we only needed it to work for all <code>Fn(&amp;T)</code>. In order to support <em>multiple arguments</em>, we now need to cover <code>Fn(&amp;T)</code>, <code>Fn(&amp;T, A)</code>, <code>Fn(&amp;T, A, B)</code>, and so on.</p>
<p>The first problem is how to convert <code>A</code>, <code>B</code>, etc. into <code>PolarValue</code>s.</p>
<p>The second problem is that these are all <em>completely distinct traits</em>. There is no trait capturing "functions of arity 2, 3, 4...". –&nbsp;at least not until the feature is available in stable Rust. In the future, this <em>might</em> be represented with the syntax <code>Fn&lt;Args, Output=T&gt;</code>, but right now using this syntax results in:</p>
<pre><code>error[E0658]: the precise format of `Fn`-family traits' type parameters is subject to change
 --&gt; src/main.rs:2:14
  |
2 |     where F: Fn&lt;(u32,), Output=u32&gt; {
  |              ^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^ help: use parenthetical notation instead: `Fn(u32) -&gt; u32`
  |
  = note: see issue #29625 &lt;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/29625&gt; for more information
</code></pre>

<p>We could opt to use Rust nightly to get these features, but it's not a huge stretch to implement them ourselves.</p>
<h3>Implementing our own <code>Method</code> trait</h3>
<p>This is where as the writer it's tempting to unveil my newly-created trait, perfectly matching what we needed, and make it look like I just put fingers to keyboard to get to the definition.</p>
<p>In reality, we spent a sizeable chunk of our engineering effort for this project on this one trait. We made mistakes. We wrote code that we threw out. And a lot of that is because we didn't understand some of the nuances of Rust functions and the trait resolution system. Instead of papering over all of that, we thought it would be more interesting to show you what we tried. </p>
<p><strong>Attempt #1</strong></p>
<p>The first thing we tried was, in hindsight, a little greedy. Why not just skip straight to writing a trait to encapsulate precisely what we need?</p>
<pre><code>pub trait Method {
   fn invoke(&amp;self, receiver: Instance, args: Vec&lt;PolarValue&gt;) -&gt; PolarValue;
}
</code></pre>

<p>This looks great, let's try implementing it for one of our <code>Fn</code> variants:</p>
<pre><code>impl&lt;F, T, R&gt; Method for F
where
   F: Fn(&amp;T) -&gt; R,
   T: 'static,
   R: ToPolarValue,
{
    fn invoke(&amp;self, instance: Instance, args: Vec&lt;PolarValue&gt;) -&gt; PolarValue {
        debug_assert!(args.is_empty());
        let receiver = instance.downcast::&lt;T&gt;().unwrap();
        self(receiver).to_polar()
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Results in:</p>
<pre><code>impl&lt;F, T, R&gt; Method for F
        ^ unconstrained type parameter
the type parameter `T` is not constrained by the impl trait, self type, or predicates

impl&lt;F, T, R&gt; Method for F
           ^ unconstrained type parameter
the type parameter `R` is not constrained by the impl trait, self type, or predicates
</code></pre>

<p>It's likely that most people have hit some variation of this error in their Rust adventures! What is going on here? <code>T</code> and <code>R</code> <em>look</em> pretty constrained to me? They are right there inside the definition of <code>F: Fn(&amp;T) -&gt; R</code>. </p>
<p>Our mistake was reading those trait bounds as: <code>F</code> is a function from <code>&amp;T</code> to <code>R</code>, whereas in reality this is a regular old trait bound with slightly different syntax for the trait itself. And one function might implement multiple of these trait bounds.</p>
<p>E.g.</p>
<pre><code>// do nothing
fn ident&lt;T&gt;(t: T) -&gt; T { t }

let _ = &amp;ident as &amp;dyn Fn(u32) -&gt; u32;
let _ = &amp;ident as &amp;dyn Fn(String) -&gt; String;
</code></pre>

<p>So which trait should we use for the implementation of <code>Method</code> for <code>ident</code>?</p>
<p>Here's another way of looking at this problem. Suppose instead we decided to exhaustively implement our <code>Method</code> trait for all types we care about:</p>
<pre><code>impl&lt;F&gt; Method for F
where
   F: Fn(&amp;u32) -&gt; u32,
{
    fn invoke(&amp;self, instance: Instance, args: Vec&lt;PolarValue&gt;) -&gt; PolarValue {
        debug_assert!(args.is_empty());
        let receiver = instance.downcast::&lt;u32&gt;().unwrap();
        self(receiver).to_polar()
    }
}

impl&lt;F&gt; Method for F
where
   F: Fn(&amp;String) -&gt; String,
{
    fn invoke(&amp;self, instance: Instance, args: Vec&lt;PolarValue&gt;) -&gt; PolarValue {
        debug_assert!(args.is_empty());
        let receiver = instance.downcast::&lt;String&gt;().unwrap();
        self(receiver).to_polar()
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Ignoring for now just how bad an idea this is, it doesn't even work! We get:</p>
<pre><code>conflicting implementations of trait `Method`:
</code></pre>

<p>Look back to <code>ident</code>. That one function implements both <code>Fn(String) -&gt; String</code> and <code>Fn(u32) -&gt; u32</code> traits. Similarly, in the above case, a function that implements both <code>Fn(&amp;String) -&gt; String</code> and <code>Fn(&amp;u32) -&gt; u32</code> would have two possible implementations for <code>Method</code>. So we get conflicting implementations.  </p>
<p><em>Actually</em>, it goes even further than that. Implementing a blanket trait implementation over <em>any</em> two function trait bounds results in conflicting implementations. Even though such a function couldn't exist:</p>
<pre><code>trait Test {}

impl&lt;F: Fn()&gt; Test for F { }
impl&lt;F: Fn(String) -&gt; String&gt; Test for F { }
</code></pre>

<p>Results in:</p>
<pre><code>error[E0119]: conflicting implementations of trait `Test`:
  |
4 | impl&lt;F: Fn()&gt; Test for F { }
  | ------------------------ first implementation here
5 | impl&lt;F: Fn(String) -&gt; String&gt; Test for F { }
  | ^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^^ conflicting implementation
</code></pre>

<p>One day (or today, if you're on Rust nightly), Rust might let you implement <code>Fn</code> for your own types, support variadic functions (what do you mean Rust already supports <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/nomicon/ffi.html#variadic-functions">variadic functions</a>?), and do all kinds of fun things of the sort. But for now we're not going to get much farther with this approach.</p>
<p><strong>Attempt #2</strong></p>
<p>This <code>Method</code> trait looks too convenient to throw away entirely at the first sign of complication. Let's try something different. If our original mistake was thinking of <code>Fn</code> as a function instead of a trait, perhaps we can heed the wisdom of the Rust docs and use <code>fn</code> instead.</p>
<p><img alt="Building%20a%20runtime%20reflection%20system%20for%20Rust%20(Par%20e9d46e4c771847e7ba119df92cf2a8b9/Untitled.png" src="https://images.osohq.com/runtime-reflection-pt-3/Building%20a%20runtime%20reflection%20system%20for%20Rust%20%28Par%20e9d46e4c771847e7ba119df92cf2a8b9/Untitled.png"></p>
<p>Based on the docs, we can use <code>fn</code> with both regular functions and closures! Great, let's do just that:</p>
<pre><code>impl&lt;T, R&gt; Method for fn(&amp;T) -&gt; R
where
    T: 'static,
    R: ToPolarValue,
{
     fn invoke(&amp;self, instance: Instance, args: Vec&lt;PolarValue&gt;) -&gt; PolarValue {
        debug_assert!(args.is_empty());
        let receiver = instance.downcast().unwrap();
        self(receiver).to_polar()
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Works fine! Let's try it out:</p>
<pre><code>let clone = |receiver: &amp;String| -&gt; String { receiver.clone() };
let clone_method: Box&lt;dyn Method&gt; = Box::new(clone);
let …</code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.osohq.com/post/runtime-reflection-pt-3">https://www.osohq.com/post/runtime-reflection-pt-3</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.osohq.com/post/runtime-reflection-pt-3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25704707</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 21:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What is happening to Lazada is happening to all companies acquired by Alibaba]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25703505">thread link</a>) | @7d7n
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://thelowdown.momentum.asia/what-is-happening-to-lazada-is-happening-to-all-companies-acquired-by-alibaba/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thelowdown.momentum.asia/what-is-happening-to-lazada-is-happening-to-all-companies-acquired-by-alibaba/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thelowdown.momentum.asia/what-is-happening-to-lazada-is-happening-to-all-companies-acquired-by-alibaba/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25703505</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 19:12:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Making of Counterstrike's Dust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 9 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25703171">thread link</a>) | @sillysaurusx
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://www.johnsto.co.uk/design/making-dust/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.johnsto.co.uk/design/making-dust/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
		

<p>For many FPS players Dust - and the later Dust 2 - are the quintessential Counter-Strike maps. They’ve been featured in nearly every major Counter-Strike tournament, and been responsible for countless millions virtual deaths, bomb detonations and defusals. But these maps actually owe their existence to Team Fortress 2 - a game that was released eight years <em>after</em> Dust became a staple of the Counter-Strike map rotation.</p>

<h2 id="time-travelling">Time Travelling</h2>

<p>It started in the summer of 1999, Suffolk, England. I was 16 years old, recuperating from end-of-year exams and enjoying my newfound freedom from school work. Half-Life was only a few months old, yet was scooping up more ‘Game of the Year’ awards than there were game magazines, leaving gamers desperate to know what Valve Software were going to make next.</p>

<p>Thankfully, news broke that Valve had hired the team behind ‘Team Fortress’, a free mod for Quake that added class-based team multiplayer to the game. Like any responsible teenager, I’d spent more hours sat staring into a screen zooming around dodging rockets, slinging grenades and capturing the flag than I had with my head stuck in schoolwork, much to the chagrin of my parents. Their next project? A sequel, excitingly titled ‘Team Fortress 2’.</p>

<p>It seemed that whilst I had been busy ambushing my future educational prospects, behind closed doors Valve had been hammering away at updating and upgrading Team Fortress for a new generation of hardware. News of Team Fortress 2 was rare and sporadic, but occasionally a tidbit here or a screenshot there would nervously peer out to an excited but nervous audience of TF fans.</p>

<p>Before too long, a <a href="http://wiki.teamfortress.com/wiki/Promotional_images">handful of screenshots</a> started their steady journey around the gaming websites of the late nineties. Two particular screenshots leapt out at me:</p>

<figure>
	<div><p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_01.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_01_thumb.jpg" alt="Team Fortress 2"></a></span></p>

<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_02.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_02_thumb.jpg" alt="Team Fortress 2"></a></span></p>
</div>
	<figcaption>Two early screenshots of Team Fortress 2.</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>The seed had been sown.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a new Half-Life modification known as ‘Counter-Strike’ had been picking up a steady stream of players. In the autumn of 1999, Minh ‘gooseman’ Le and Jess Cliffe released its second beta - and it supplanted Team Fortress to become my new addiction. It came with a texture pack of urban textures (‘cstrike.wad’) that, upon discovery, I set about making a map with - this became ‘<a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/blog/a-little-wad-the-story-of-cs_tire/">cs_tire</a>’, a hostage rescue map set in (of all places) a retirement home. Surprisingly, this map was deemed good enough to be included in the third beta release of Counter-Strike, and Jess subsequently asked me if I’d be interested in making a map for the fourth beta. He was very keen to hook me up with their texture artist to help me make something absolutely and completely original.</p>

<p>Jess introduced me to artist Chris ‘MacMan’ Ashton - the same artist behind the urban texture set used in my retirement home map - and we got to work creating a new, totally original Counter-Strike map. Unfortunately it was too late to save me from TF2’s influence and I asked for these instead:</p>

<figure>
	<p><span><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2-textures.jpg" alt="Team Fortress 2 texture selection"></span></p>
	<figcaption>Team Fortress 2 screenshots were used to create a core texture set</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>Undeterred by my complete lack of originality, Chris quickly got back to me with beautiful lookalikes. While not exact replicas, I selfishly became completely infatuated with them, just like I had the screenshots they were based on . I quickly bundled them all together into my own texture pack and called it “cs_dest.wad” - shorthand for “Destiny”.</p>

<p>With these TF2-alike textures I could finally make a map and pretend I was playing Team Fortress 2, but something was wrong. I felt guilt - TF2 wasn’t even out yet and I was already trying to sap all the effort Valve had been putting into it. It was akin to snatching a duckling from under its mothers beak. “But surely”, I thought, “Valve wouldn’t mind one me making one small map for one small mod for their one and only published game? A map that maybe only a handful of people would ever play?”</p>

<p>I marched on.</p>

<h2 id="copy-and-paste">Copy and Paste</h2>

<p>Starting the map was the easy bit - the first area boasted a long road flanked by buildings, leading to an archway and a wall dividing it in two, just like I’d seen in the screenshots. I decorated every building and wall with ornate trims along the top or bottom, again aping TF2, as I tried my hardest to evoke the same sense of place, desolation, and scale. These features would go on to define the underlying architectural style of Dust.</p>

<p>My effort wasn’t <em>quite</em> identical to the map featured in those coveted TF2 screenshots, but it was close enough, and - somewhat more importantly - it was a start.</p>

<p>The arched doorways became a hallmark of the Dust theme - a Dust map is simply not Dust without at least two or three arches dividing the map into distinct zones. Creating the first one was at the time a great test of my technical mapping ability, and I struggled for a little while before landing on a technique that worked. My design eschewed the Reuleaux triangle shape of the TF2 arches for a simpler semi-circle, partly because it was simpler, but primarily to ease player passage through them. I extruded the arches from their adjoining wall - lifted straight from the screenshots.</p>

<figure>
	<div><p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/start_01.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/start_01_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>

<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/start_02.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/start_02_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>
</div>
	<figcaption>The first  incarnation of what became the CT spawn</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>I considered against copying the screenshots verbatim for fear of upsetting Valve, and so started guessing how the rest of the area should look. I’d already created a raised platform, and had decided that this could be the area that the Counter-Terrorist team would spawn in at the start of the match. This necessitated defensive measures to protect their spawn area, so I made some windows:</p>

<figure>
	<div><p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/early_windows_01.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/early_windows_01_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>

<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/early_windows_02.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/early_windows_02_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>
</div>
	<figcaption>The view from inside a building next to the CT spawn</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>Not only did they look hideous, but the windows didn’t give the defensively-advantageous views I wanted the CT team to have. Nor did they fit with the intended gameplay. I didn’t want to encourage the CTs to hold back, and removed them - although in all honestly, at this point I really didn’t know where the map was going.</p>

<h2 id="under-the-influence">Under the Influence</h2>

<p>Side-by-side, the TF2 ‘influence’ is plain to see:</p>

<figure>
	<div><p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_01.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_01_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>

<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2compare_01.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2compare_01_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>
</div>
	<figcaption>Side-by-side, the influence of TF2 on the design of the CT spawn area is apparent.</figcaption>
</figure>


<figure>
	<div><p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_02.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2_02_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>

<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2compare_02.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tf2compare_02_thumb.jpg" alt="Early CT spawn area"></a></span></p>
</div>
	<figcaption>TF directly influenced building placement and the design of the arches.</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>In many respects, the TF2 screenshot looks nicer to me - smoother and softer than the harsh edges of the Dust buildings. I was far more comfortable working with standard geometric shapes, 90 degree corners and 45 degree angles, which is why Dust looks far boxier in comparison to the TF2 screenshot it was based on.</p>

<p>That was the easy part done - after all, Valve had already created this much of the map for me and all I’d had to do was copy it. But what I had wasn’t much - it was barely enough for a one-on-one deathmatch, let alone two teams of eight players gunning it out. Worse still, there were no more screenshots to use for ‘inspiration’ - I had to make the rest of the map off my own back and imagination.</p>



<p>Having nailed down the design of the first area, producing the rest of the map was merely a case of extrapolating it into a complete, playable environment. However this was much easier said than done - the next section of the map proved rather more challenging.</p>

<p>I had created a T-junction out of the CT spawn, but struggled to know what to do with it. My past mapping experience was mostly creating tight interiors rather than not vast exteriors, and so I was feeling very lost. Desperate, I shoe-horned a bend in the road leading to a downward slope, and at the end of it - an underground cavern.</p>

<figure>
	<div><p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/underground_01.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/underground_01_thumb.jpg" alt="An underground chamber"></a></span></p>

<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/underground_02.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/underground_02_thumb.jpg" alt="An underground chamber"></a></span></p>
</div>
	<figcaption>The underpass originally descended into a vast underground facility, but this was scrapped the moment I played it.</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>It didn’t work, of course. While the CT spawn area was light and airy, this giant room was gloomy, boxy and felt dead compared to the sunny exterior I’d already made. Observing it also lacked any gameplay potential, I swiftly deleted it. Dust would be an outdoor map.</p>

<p>I was still stuck. It’s at times like these where working without an initial design can prove extremely difficult. You look at what you’ve got, and struggle to see where to take it, knowing that a step in one direction is a step away from a solution in another direction - and you don’t know which will turn out better. It can be very tough and incredibly tempting to just scrap  <em>everything</em> and start again. I’d made all my previous maps one room at a time, making it up as I go along with precious little pre-planning, and they had gone reasonably well. I had to hope I could do the same again.</p>

<p>Mercifully, that’s exactly what happened.</p>

<figure>
	<div><p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tspawn.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/tspawn_thumb.jpg" alt="Terrorist spawn"></a></span></p>

<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/underpass.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/underpass_thumb.jpg" alt="Underpass"></a></span></p>
</div>
	<figcaption>The Terrorist spawn area, and shallow decline into the underpass.</figcaption>
</figure>


<p>Within just a few hours - and seemingly out of nowhere - the Terrorist spawn area was complete. I was far happier with this side of the map, perhaps a product of becoming comfortable with the visual and architectural style. The shallow decline into the underpass is perhaps one of my favourite aspects, both aesthetically and as a player who spent many hours armed with a Steyr Scout at the crest popping off opponents’ heads.</p>

<p>At one point I planned an alleyway from the Terrorist side of the underpass that fed around to the CT ‘sniper nest’, but this path seemed like it would be too long, too linear, and simply too <em>dull</em>. I just blocked it up with crates instead, still visible in the original version of the map (and the screenshot above.)</p>

<p>Dust’s central hallway was pivotal in tying all these pieces together. Unfortunately, I can recollect very little about its creation, bar my explicit efforts to ensure players couldn’t see all the way through it from one end to the other. Every crate found in the intersection was strategically positioned to cut off lines-of-sight and improve performance. It was in this corridor that each team would typically meet, and so it needed to be fair, and balanced, with a slight defensive bias.</p>

<figure>
	<p><span><a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/corridor.jpg"><img src="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/i/design/making-dust/corridor_thumb.jpg" alt="A screenshot of the central corridor"></a></span></p>
	<figcaption>The central corridor, Terrorists approached from the top, Counter-Terrorists from the bottom. Note the stack …</figcaption></figure></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.johnsto.co.uk/design/making-dust/">https://www.johnsto.co.uk/design/making-dust/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.johnsto.co.uk/design/making-dust/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25703171</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 18:44:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Which smartphone, laptop and tablet brands break down the most?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25702727">thread link</a>) | @vanpythonista
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/smartphone-survey-marketplace-1.5860881 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/smartphone-survey-marketplace-1.5860881">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A CBC Marketplace survey that asked more than 3,200 Canadians about smartphone, laptop and tablet breakdowns and repairs&nbsp;revealed that an overwhelming majority of them are dealing with broken technology that is too difficult or too expensive to repair.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861152.1609866490!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/jason-bolduc.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Jason Bolduc holds a 14-day-old Samsung S20 Galaxy Plus with a hairline crack.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Stephanie Matteis/CBC)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Of the electronic devices used in Canada, LG smartphones top the list of devices Canadians said have broken the most over the last five years, according to an investigation by CBC's<em> Marketplace</em>.&nbsp;</p>  <p>An online survey that asked 3,201 Canadians&nbsp;about smartphone, laptop and tablet breakdowns and repairs&nbsp;revealed that an overwhelming majority of them are dealing with broken technology that is too difficult or too expensive to repair. The survey was&nbsp;conducted&nbsp;between Aug. 6 and Aug. 20 by Leger Marketing on behalf of <em>Marketplace.</em></p>  <p>Sixty-five per cent of respondents said they had multiple devices break down within the past five years.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>  <p>Gay Gordon-Byrne, the head of the Repair Association, a consumer advocacy group in the United States established to hold manufacturers of electronic devices more accountable for reparability, said that in general, manufacturers want a consumer to have to return to the store to repair an item, which in turn may entice them into buying the newest products.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"We literally have to go buy new ones and throw away the old ones because we're not allowed either by design or by policy to fix them," she told <em>Marketplace</em>.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861144.1609799082!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/gay-gordon-byrne.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861144.1609799082!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/gay-gordon-byrne.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861144.1609799082!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/gay-gordon-byrne.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861144.1609799082!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/gay-gordon-byrne.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861144.1609799082!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/gay-gordon-byrne.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861144.1609799082!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/gay-gordon-byrne.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Gay Gordon-Byrne of The Repair Association at the border at Derby Line, Vermont.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Stephanie Matteis/CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>For the survey, people across the country shared their stories about lifespan, reparability and the brand and type of device that broke down more than others in the last five years.&nbsp;</p>  <h2>4-month fight to fix LG smartphone</h2>  <p>Laurie Hood of Canmore, Alta., recently purchased LG's G8 Thin Q smartphone. Not long after, she said it started having problems.</p>  <p>"I just bought the phone, and I'm not blaming myself, but that's really a drag," Hood said.</p>  <p>"I wish I'd done my research before. I didn't."&nbsp;</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5863229.1609951856!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/laurie-hood.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5863229.1609951856!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/laurie-hood.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5863229.1609951856!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/laurie-hood.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5863229.1609951856!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/laurie-hood.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5863229.1609951856!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/laurie-hood.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5863229.1609951856!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/laurie-hood.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Laurie Hood of Canmore, Alta., began having problems with her LG G8 Thin Q smartphone not long after she purchased it.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Dave Rae/CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Both a certified LG repair shop and LG told her she would have to pay for a repair for the nearly new phone, which retails for about $1,250.</p>  <p>She estimated it took four months and, "fair to say about 20 hours of emails and on the phone,"&nbsp; but after persistent fighting for a fix, the phone eventually was returned to her repaired at no cost.</p>  <p>LG declined requests for on-camera interviews.</p>  <p><em>Marketplace </em>told the company about Hood's experience and a spokesperson for the company wrote that they'll look into it.</p>  <p>To understand which brands experienced more breakdowns than others based on the survey data, David Bellhouse, a professor emeritus of statistical and actuarial sciences at&nbsp;Western University, calculated the percentage share of breakdowns for each brand using market share data.</p>  <p>According to Bellhouse's analysis, LG smartphones had a disproportionately higher percentage of breakdowns than the company's percentage of the Canadian smartphone market and were the devices that broke down most&nbsp;over the last five years when compared with other brands in the survey and when market share was taken into account.</p>  <p>When <em>Marketplace </em>told the company about its position in the survey analysis, the company said in a statement that it stands behind the quality of its devices, claimed LG doesn't limit parts for phone repairs&nbsp;and said it is trying to make it easier for its customers to get their phones fixed.</p>  <ul>   <li><strong><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/marketplace/the-people-vs-the-tech-giants-1.5865424">Read more about how <em>Marketplace </em>conducted the survey and how companies responded</a></strong></li>  </ul>  <h2>Top breakdown issues identified</h2>  <p>The vast majority of respondents (96 per cent) had an identified problem with their device. They indicated "it became slow or buggy" (40 per cent) or had "a weak/dead battery" (26 per cent).&nbsp;</p>  <p>Other problems included the device wouldn't turn on, had a cracked or broken screen, would not charge or overheated.</p>  <p>According to Gordon-Byrne, tech companies generally don't want a consumer&nbsp;to repair a&nbsp;device&nbsp;and get "another two years of life out of it."</p>  <h2>Apple vs. Samsung smartphones</h2>  <p>Apple dominates the smartphone market, followed by Samsung.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Bellhouse's survey analysis showed Samsung smartphones experience more breakdowns relative to market share than Apple iPhones.</p>  <p>The survey received 563 reports about Samsung phones of the 1,922 reports about smartphones overall.</p>  <p>Data also showed that smartphones break down more than any other device.</p>  <p><em><strong>WATCH | Between Apple and Samsung, here's the phone brand Canadians tell us broke more than others:</strong></em></p>  <p><span><span><div><div title="Apple vs. Samsung: Which phone brand breaks down the most?" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1842063427989-metadata-" title="Apple vs. Samsung: Which phone brand breaks down the most?"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/569/595/APPLE_vs_SAMSUNG_horizontal.png" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>Here is the top smartphone brand that breaks down the most based on a CBC Marketplace survey and market share analysis.<!-- --> <!-- -->1:42</span></span></span></p>  <p>Jason Bolduc owns a Samsung S20 Galaxy Plus 5G that sells for $1,875, but he paid $1,280.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The phone immediately had problems, including overheating, which he said resulted in a hairline crack on the back glass.</p>  <p>It was still under warranty, and Telus, which sold it to him, has a 15-day return policy, so Bolduc attempted to return it to the store in Bracebridge, Ont., where he purchased it.</p>  <p>In a written statement to <em>Marketplace</em>, Telus said that it couldn't help Bolduc because he didn't buy an extended care warranty and the issues with the phone had to be addressed by the manufacturer.</p>  <p>He also approached Samsung, which wanted to charge him for repairs.</p>  <p>"I still have to be out of pocket costs because they are claiming that it's the [user's] fault," he said, though he noted the company had no evidence of that.</p>  <p>Samsung was also asked for an on-camera interview but instead provided a statement that its Galaxy products are some of the industry's "most durable." The company also said it will look into Bolduc's situation.</p>  <h2>Seeking repairs</h2>  <p>Almost three out of four survey respondents have had at least one device break down in the past five years. And 65 per cent have had multiple device breakdowns in that time.</p>  <p>Half (51 per cent) of devices taken to the manufacturer weren't repaired because the survey respondents said it would be too costly or the manufacturer couldn't fix the device.</p>  <p>Ricardo Borja owns a three-year-old Apple iPhone 7 but the audio only worked if connected to Bluetooth. As a result, he was in his car often to make or receive phone calls.</p>  <p>"I will be talking through the microphone of my car. So this is a pretty expensive headset," he said.</p>  <p>The battery also drained quickly, he said.</p>  <p>Borja sought repairs with both the manufacturer and a certified Apple repair shop where he lives in Montreal. He said both times he was told he could pay $400 and trade in the phone.&nbsp;</p>  <p>But the Quebecker didn't want to contribute to growing e-waste&nbsp;and as a product designer, couldn't understand why there wasn't a solution that allowed a repair.</p>  <p>"That is something that kind of sucks as a pattern as a whole if you look at consumer electronics. It's that they're making them less and less repairable at home."</p>  <h2>Apple replaces customer's iPhone, thanks to Quebec law</h2>  <p>Weeks after meeting with <em>Marketplace</em>, Borja sent a message to say he had gotten his iPhone 7 replaced for free with the same model from Apple.</p>  <p>He had researched Quebec's consumer protection laws, which say if a product doesn't last as long as another just like it, the manufacturer might have to repair it at no cost, replace it or provide a refund.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861159.1609799963!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_300/ricardo-borja.png 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861159.1609799963!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_460/ricardo-borja.png 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861159.1609799963!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_620/ricardo-borja.png 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861159.1609799963!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_780/ricardo-borja.png 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861159.1609799963!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_1180/ricardo-borja.png 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5861159.1609799963!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/original_780/ricardo-borja.png"></p></div><figcaption>Ricardo Borja in Montreal with the iPhone 7 he only uses in his vehicle for calls. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Stephanie Matteis/CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Right to repair advocates told <em>Marketplace </em>that of anywhere in Canada, the law may be strongest in Quebec. But even still, Borja wasn't told about it.</p>  <p>"If we don't know our rights, then they don't tell us that we're entitled to have a replacement phone at no charge, and I would have paid $400," he said of his experience with Apple.</p>  <p>Apple declined <em>Marketplace </em>requests for an on-camera interview about Borja's experience and the survey analysis, but in a statement told <em>Marketplace </em>the company has a new repair program that is making it easier to get phones fixed.&nbsp;</p>  <h2>Rating laptops: Acer vs. Apple&nbsp;versus HP</h2>  <p>When it comes to laptops, Acer, Apple and HP&nbsp;are Canada's top sellers.</p>  <p>Of those brands, Bellhouse's analysis looking at market share in households relative to breakdowns from the survey found that Canadians have experienced more breakdowns with HP over the last five years.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866933.1610144339!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/acer-and-hp-graphic.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866933.1610144339!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/acer-and-hp-graphic.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866933.1610144339!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/acer-and-hp-graphic.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866933.1610144339!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/acer-and-hp-graphic.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866933.1610144339!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/acer-and-hp-graphic.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866933.1610144339!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/acer-and-hp-graphic.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Acer and HP are among Canada's top selling laptops.<!-- --> <!-- -->(David Abrahams/CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>HP declined <em>Marketplace</em>'s request for an interview, but wrote that in the past five years, its line of notebooks "have realized a 30 per cent reduction in&nbsp;[failure] rates as measured by the industry standard metric of Annualized Failure Rates (AFR)."</p>  <p>And by that same metric, the failure rate is "the lowest it has been in the company's history."</p>  <p>As for repairability, the company noted that some of its products are highly rated on iFixit's reparability scale. The California company is a well-known advocate for the right to repair.</p>  <h2>Tablets are a 'bad investment,' says expert</h2>  <p>When it comes to tablets, Gordon-Byrne said people should save their money.&nbsp;</p>  <p>She said they're often made with a lot of glue, which makes them difficult to take apart and repair. Add to that, right to repair advocates say manufacturers usually don't grant consumers and most repair shops, other than certified dealers,&nbsp;access to parts, repair instructions and software. Both impede successful repair, making them "a bad investment," Gordon-Byrne said.</p>  <p>When it comes to market share of tablets, Apple dominates the market at more than 75 per cent of sales, followed by Samsung at 17 per cent.</p>  <p>Bellhouse said iPads have broken down the least compared to all other brands.</p>  <p>The survey, which has a 1.7 per cent margin of error 19 out of 20 times, also had 201 respondents from Canada's North, which is also one of the toughest spots …</p></span></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/smartphone-survey-marketplace-1.5860881">https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/smartphone-survey-marketplace-1.5860881</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/smartphone-survey-marketplace-1.5860881</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25702727</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 18:05:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Readable Bash Scripts]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25702062">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://brianschiller.com/blog/2021/01/07/readable-bash-scripts | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://brianschiller.com/blog/2021/01/07/readable-bash-scripts">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
      <div>
        <article>
          <p>I really love the feeling of writing a bash pipeline. It’s fun to string commands together, peek at the output, add another couple pipes to massage the data closer to my goal. I even gave a short class on them: <a href="https://github.com/bgschiller/shell-challenges">bgschiller/shell-challenges</a>.</p>

<p>But it’s easy to find that a pipeline that was delightful to write is painful to maintain. Even if you’re the one reading it a month later, it’s difficult to remember what the purpose of each piece is. This is a trick I learned to break pipelines into intermediate files for more readable scripts.</p>

<h3 id="the-task">The task</h3>

<p>The product I’m working on has a list of “Alarms”—conditions that the end user needs to be alerted to. We also have a localization file for each supported language that maps Alarm names to human-readable names, descriptions, etc. There are a lot of alarms, enough to make it difficult to keep track of which ones are already translated. This calls for a script!</p>

<p>The Alarms file looks something like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>&lt;!-- Alarms.xml --&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?&gt;</span>
<span>&lt;config</span> <span>name=</span><span>"AlarmConfig"</span><span>&gt;</span>
   <span>&lt;AlarmList</span> <span>name=</span><span>"IngredientAlarms"</span> <span>version=</span><span>"1.0"</span><span>&gt;</span>
      <span>&lt;Alarm</span> <span>name=</span><span>"MozzarellaTooWarm"</span><span>&gt;</span>
        <span>&lt;!-- some alarm-specific stuff here --&gt;</span>
      <span>&lt;/Alarm&gt;</span>
      <span>&lt;Alarm</span> <span>name=</span><span>"PizzaTooCold"</span><span>&gt;</span>
      <span>&lt;/Alarm&gt;</span>
      <span>&lt;!-- ... --&gt;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And the localization something like this:</p>

<!-- prettier-ignore -->
<div><div><pre><code><span>[{</span> <span>stringId</span><span>:</span> <span>"</span><span>alarm_id_MozzarellaTooWarm</span><span>"</span><span>,</span>
   <span>localString</span><span>:</span> <span>"</span><span>MozzarellaTooWarm</span><span>"</span> <span>},</span>
 <span>{</span> <span>stringId</span><span>:</span> <span>"</span><span>alarm_title_MozzarellaTooWarm</span><span>"</span><span>,</span>
   <span>localString</span><span>:</span> <span>"</span><span>Mozzarella Too Warm</span><span>"</span> <span>},</span>
 <span>{</span> <span>stringId</span><span>:</span> <span>"</span><span>alarm_description_MozzarellaTooWarm</span><span>"</span><span>,</span>
   <span>localString</span><span>:</span> <span>"</span><span>The mozzarella has become too warm and must be used within the next five minutes</span><span>"</span> <span>},</span>
  <span>//...</span>
<span>]</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="make-a-plan">Make a plan</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Extract the alarms names from Alarms.xml using <code>xpath</code>.</li>
  <li>Each alarm needs to be prefixed with <code>alarm_id_</code>, <code>alarm_title_</code>, <code>alarm_description_</code>, <code>alarm_operator_actions_</code> in order to match the localization file. Figure out some way to do that.</li>
  <li>Extract the <code>"stringId"</code> from each entry in the localization file. Oh, but there are other entries for things that need to be localized, and aren’t alarms at all. Figure out a way to filter those out. Probably use <code>jq</code> for that.</li>
  <li>Use <code>diff</code> to compare the expected keys with the actual keys.</li>
</ol>

<p>This isn’t a post on how to make bash pipelines, so I’ll gloss over that piece. Here’s what I came up with:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>diff <span>\</span>
  &lt;<span>(</span><span>join</span> <span>-j</span> 99999 <span>\</span>
    &lt;<span>(</span><span>echo</span> <span>'alarm_id_
alarm_title_
alarm_description_
alarm_operator_actions_'</span><span>)</span> <span>\</span>
    &lt;<span>(</span>xpath <span>-q</span> <span>-e</span> config/AlarmList/Alarm/@name Alarms.xml |
      <span>cut</span> <span>-d</span><span>=</span> <span>-f2</span> | <span>tr</span> <span>-d</span> <span>'"'</span><span>)</span> <span>\</span>
    | <span>tr</span> <span>-d</span> <span>' '</span> | <span>sort</span><span>)</span> <span>\</span>
  &lt;<span>(</span>jq <span>'.[] | select(.stringId | startswith("alarm_")) |
        .stringId '</span> i18n/en.json | <span>sort</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It’s convoluted and kinda impressive in that way. But not code you’d be happy to maintain.</p>

<h3 id="one-step-at-a-time">One step at a time</h3>

<p>The prior step accomplished what we needed, but it was pretty difficult to see what was going on. In my opinion, that’s because</p>

<ul>
  <li>Nothing has a name. Because each process substitution is fed directly into a parent, nothing ever receives a name. We need to name our intermediates!</li>
  <li>No comments. It’s difficult to add comments because every line ends in a backslash, meaning “continue this line as if I hadn’t pressed enter”. Bash doesn’t allow you to say “continue this line” and also add a comment.</li>
</ul>

<p>Let’s see if we can tease out each part using intermediate files.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>cat</span> <span>&gt;</span> alarm_attrs <span>&lt;&lt;</span> <span>EOF</span><span>
alarm_id_
alarm_title_
alarm_description_
alarm_operator_actions_
</span><span>EOF

</span>xpath <span>-q</span> <span>-e</span> config/AlarmList/Alarm/@name Alarms.xml |
  <span>cut</span> <span>-d</span><span>=</span> <span>-f2</span> | <span>tr</span> <span>-d</span> <span>'"'</span> <span>&gt;</span> expected_alarm_names

<span>join</span> <span>-j</span> 999 alarm_attrs expected_alarm_names |
  <span>tr</span> <span>-d</span> <span>' '</span> | <span>sort</span> <span>&gt;</span> expected_localization_keys

jq <span>-r</span> <span>'.[] | select(.stringId | startswith("alarm_")) |
       .stringId'</span> en.json | <span>sort</span> <span>&gt;</span> actual_localization_keys
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is better! Each piece can be understood in isolation, and the dependencies between steps are explictly tracked with named files. All that’s left is to add comments and some error checking, and clean up our intermediate files.</p>

<p>Cleaning up after ourselves is a little tricky. Ideally, we’d like to avoid leaving the intermediate results files laying around regardless of whether the script exits normally, crashes, or is cancelled with ctrl-c. We can use <code>trap</code> to handle this. <code>trap</code> sets up a command to run when a “signal” occurs. We’ll put all our intermediate files into a directory and use <code>trap</code> to delete that directory when a signal that indicates our script is ending fires.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#!/bin/bash</span>

<span>set</span> <span>-ef</span> <span>-o</span> pipefail

<span>readonly </span><span>script_name</span><span>=</span><span>`</span><span>basename</span> <span>"</span><span>$0</span><span>"</span><span>`</span>
usage<span>()</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>cat</span> <span>&gt;</span>&amp;2 <span>&lt;&lt;</span> <span>EOF</span><span>
Usage: </span><span>$script_name</span><span> &lt;path-to-Alarms.xml&gt; &lt;path-to-en.json&gt;

  Compare the alarms specified in Alarms.xml against the
  localizations keys provided in a [language-code].json file
  (eg, en.json). Warn if any keys are missing or unexpected.
</span><span>EOF
</span>  <span>exit </span>2
<span>}</span>

<span>if</span> <span>[[</span> <span>$# </span><span>!=</span> 2 <span>]]</span><span>;</span> <span>then
   </span><span>echo</span> <span>"error: expected 2 arguments, received $#"</span> 1&gt;&amp;2
   usage
<span>fi

</span><span>readonly </span><span>ALARM_CONFIG_XML</span><span>=</span><span>$1</span>
<span>if</span> <span>[[</span> <span>${</span><span>ALARM_CONFIG_XML</span>:<span> -4</span><span>}</span> <span>!=</span> <span>".xml"</span> <span>||</span> <span>!</span> <span>-e</span> <span>$ALARM_CONFIG_XML</span> <span>]]</span><span>;</span> <span>then
   </span><span>echo</span> <span>"error: unable to find XML file at </span><span>$ALARM_CONFIG_XML</span><span>"</span> 1&gt;&amp;2
   usage
<span>fi
</span><span>readonly </span><span>LOCALIZATION_JSON</span><span>=</span><span>$2</span>
<span>if</span> <span>[[</span> <span>${</span><span>LOCALIZATION_JSON</span>:<span> -5</span><span>}</span> <span>!=</span> <span>".json"</span> <span>||</span> <span>!</span> <span>-e</span> <span>$LOCALIZATION_JSON</span> <span>]]</span><span>;</span> <span>then
   </span><span>echo</span> <span>"error: unable to find JSON file at </span><span>$LOCALIZATION_JSON</span><span>"</span> 1&gt;&amp;2
   usage
<span>fi</span>

<span># Make a directory for intermediate results</span>
<span>tmpdir</span><span>=</span><span>$(</span><span>mktemp</span> <span>-d</span> <span>-p</span> .<span>)</span>
<span># ensure it's removed when this script exits</span>
<span>trap</span> <span>"rm -rf </span><span>$tmpdir</span><span>"</span> EXIT HUP INT TERM
<span># note: when debugging, turn off that `trap` line to keep</span>
<span># intermediate results around</span>

<span># The plan is ultimately to use diff to compare names between</span>
<span># Alarms.xml and en.json. diff will tell us if any names</span>
<span># appear in one file but are missing in the other (checks</span>
<span># both directions for a mismatch).In pursuit of this, we need</span>
<span># to create a couple of temporary files:</span>
<span>#  1) all the alarm names we expect to find (based on Alarms.xml)</span>
<span>#  2) all the names actually present in the localization file.</span>
<span># A complication: the location file uses a flat format to</span>
<span># store the id, title, description, and operator_actions:</span>
<span>#   { "stringId": "alarm_id_MozzarellaTooWarm", ... },</span>
<span>#   { "stringId": "alarm_title_MozzarellaTooWarm", ... },</span>
<span>#   { "stringId": "alarm_description_MozzarellaTooWarm", ... },</span>
<span>#   { "stringId": "alarm_operator_actions_MozzarellaTooWarm", ... },</span>
<span># We want to check that *all* of these keys are present, so</span>
<span># we use a cross product of (alarm names) X (those attributes)</span>

<span>cat</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>$tmpdir</span>/alarm_attrs <span>&lt;&lt;</span> <span>EOF</span><span>
alarm_id_
alarm_title_
alarm_description_
alarm_operator_actions_
</span><span>EOF

</span>xpath <span>-q</span> <span>-e</span> config/AlarmList/Alarm/@name <span>$ALARM_CONFIG_XML</span> |
 <span>cut</span> <span>-d</span><span>=</span> <span>-f2</span> | <span>tr</span> <span>-d</span> <span>'"'</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>$tmpdir</span>/expected_alarm_names

<span># trick to compute cross product: use `join` with a join</span>
<span># field that doesn't exist (999). since both files lack a</span>
<span># field at 999, they will compare equal for every key, and</span>
<span># each line of the left file will be joined with each line</span>
<span># of the right file--a cross product.</span>
<span>join</span> <span>-j</span> 999 <span>$tmpdir</span>/alarm_attrs <span>$tmpdir</span>/expected_alarm_names |
<span>tr</span> <span>-d</span> <span>' '</span> | <span>sort</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>$tmpdir</span>/expected_localization_keys

jq <span>-r</span> <span>'.[] | select(.stringId | startswith("alarm_")) |
       .stringId'</span> <span>$LOCALIZATION_JSON</span> |
  <span>sort</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>$tmpdir</span>/actual_localization_keys

<span>if </span>diff <span>$tmpdir</span>/expected_localization_keys <span>$tmpdir</span>/actual_localization_keys<span>;</span> <span>then
   </span><span>echo</span> <span>"Success! Found all"</span> <span>$(</span><span>wc</span> <span>-l</span> <span>$tmpdir</span>/expected_localization_keys<span>)</span> <span>"expected localization keys"</span>  1&gt;&amp;2
<span>else
   </span><span>echo</span> <span>"Failure. Found discrepancies between expected alarm names and actual localization keys"</span> 1&gt;&amp;2
   <span>exit </span>1
<span>fi</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

        </article>

        
        
        
        

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://brianschiller.com/blog/2021/01/07/readable-bash-scripts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25702062</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 17:03:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Marxist Analysis of the iPhone (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25702019">thread link</a>) | @moigagoo
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | http://www.socialisteconomist.com/2019/09/a-marxist-analysis-of-iphone.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.socialisteconomist.com/2019/09/a-marxist-analysis-of-iphone.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span><b>Workers who make iPhones in the 21st century</b>, are twenty-five times more exploited than textile workers in England in the 19th century. Based on a marxist analysis, the current&nbsp;<i>rate of exploitation </i>is&nbsp;2458%.</span></p><div>
<p><span><span><b>W</b></span></span>e are interested in looking at the production
of the iPhone – a commodity – through the
framework of a Marxist analysis. We are interested not in being angry at Apple and Foxconn
alone, but in being able to measure how much
workers are exploited to produce this commodity. In other words, we are interested in measuring <b>the rate of exploitation</b>.</p><p>

The rate of exploitation is one of the most
important concepts in Marx’s theory. This
measurement allows us to show how much the
worker contributes to the increase of value in
the production process. It shows that even if the
worker is paid more, by the special magic of
mechanisation and of efficient management of
the production process, the rate of exploitation
increases. The rate expresses quantitatively the
contradictory interests of the capitalists and of
the workers. There is a radical politics implicit in
the analysis of the rate of exploitation. It enables workers to see how much of the share of
the value produced is appropriated from them
by the capitalists, and to therefore make the
case for a different way to organise production
and to end exploitation.</p><p>

To understand the rate of exploitation, we have
to first grasp what Marx means by the commodity itself and what he means by value, a key term
in the Marxist system of economic thought.</p><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-C5uknsT1Qo8/XZCEHtKcdVI/AAAAAAAAFRU/ske4yAP-_xY8lyclVj_QI14X31w008uqQCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/book2.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="536" data-original-width="542" height="316" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-C5uknsT1Qo8/XZCEHtKcdVI/AAAAAAAAFRU/ske4yAP-_xY8lyclVj_QI14X31w008uqQCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/book2.png" width="320"></a></p>
<p>
What is a commodity? Marx begins his epic
work Capital (1867) with a discussion of the
commodity. ‘A commodity’, he notes, ‘is an object outside us, a thing that by its properties
satisfies human wants of some sort or another.
The nature of such wants, whether, for instance,
they spring from the stomach or from fancy,
makes no difference. Neither are we concerned
to know how the object satisfies these wants,
whether directly as a means of subsistence, or
indirectly as means of production’. The commodity is a useful object. But it is more than a
useful thing that serves a purpose to a consumer. It is also something that can be sold – something that enables the person who has it made
to realise a profit. Inside the commodity, then, is
both <b>use value</b> and <b>value</b>.</p><p>

The use value of the commodity is merely its
utility, something that is left to the consumer.
An iPhone is a good example, because it can
be used for many things: to make a phone call,
to watch a video, to use as a compass, to hold
onto when you are feeling awkward (or even to
improve your image).</p><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XSTB0AJ3dE8/XZCEcFG4l8I/AAAAAAAAFRc/zQgbE9cGZ20opRyyiarpiQQVm8vlXer2QCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/values.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="595" data-original-width="465" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-XSTB0AJ3dE8/XZCEcFG4l8I/AAAAAAAAFRc/zQgbE9cGZ20opRyyiarpiQQVm8vlXer2QCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/values.png"></a></p>
<p>
The expression of the value of the commodity
(i.e. exchange value) is the price of the commodity. We are aware that there is a rich and
long debate amongst Marxists over the relationship between prices and the value of a
commodity. This debate is known as the transformation problem – namely the problem of the
transformation of values to prices of production. Nevertheless, for our iPhone example, we
believe that this level of concreteness need not
detain us. We are still able to capture something
significant. In the case of the iPhone X, the expression of its value is $999. The value is merely
what the commodity is able to command in
the market. But behind that price is a mass of
crystallised values, which can be grouped into
three parts of the total value: <b>constant capital</b>,
<b>variable capital,</b> and <b>surplus value</b>. These are
key concepts for Marxist analysis.</p><p>

<b><span>Constant capital</span></b></p><p>

Various raw materials are brought on to the
factory floor that are to be transformed by the
actions of labour and machines into commodities. These raw materials – and other auxiliary
materials, including the instruments of labour
(machines, tools, etc.) – have already been
fashioned from nature elsewhere. Inside these
raw materials, which are not really ‘raw’ any
longer, is embodied labour. The values of the
various raw materials and instruments of labour
are quantitatively fixed in terms of their labour
content. This fixed amount of value is now
transferred to the newly produced commodities
in the process of production. Its value enters
into the new commodities. Karl Marx calls the
values of the raw materials and the instruments
of labour <b>constant capital</b>.</p><p>

The constant capital for the iPhone includes
all of those minerals and metals that appear on the assembly line as well as the depreciated
parts of machines that work those raw materials.
These are then collectively transformed into
the iPhone. In the process of transformation,
the minerals, metals, and machines do not
alter their value. Their value is preserved in the
iPhone. The value remains constant.</p><p>

At the end of the process of production, the
total transferred value of those means of production – the raw materials, the machines, the
buildings – cannot be more than what they
originally contained in themselves. Their value,
which remains constant, is preserved in the
iPhone.</p><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Q_pB4fCgz5I/XZCFCPeC69I/AAAAAAAAFRo/PocXIl65lesBDVnMU7IPnoRo6THryPOjwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/capital.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="579" data-original-width="378" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Q_pB4fCgz5I/XZCFCPeC69I/AAAAAAAAFRo/PocXIl65lesBDVnMU7IPnoRo6THryPOjwCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/capital.png"></a></p>
<p>

<b><span>Variable capital.</span></b></p><p>

The capitalist firm makes an initial investment in
the production process:</p><ul>
<li>Wages and salaries for workers.</li>
<li>Expenses on all non-human inputs, notably
tools, machinery, buildings, energy, and so
on.</li>
</ul><p>
The latter expense – the expense on all non-human inputs – is known as <b>constant capital</b>, as
explained above.</p><p>

The former expense – the expense on wages
and salaries – is known as variable capital.
To simplify our calculation, we assume that all
workers are productive in the Marxist sense
(namely, that they produce surplus value and
do not merely distribute surplus value – as do
‘unproductive’ workers, such as those who are
involved in trade).</p><p>

In the capitalist system, people are ‘free’ in two
ways. They are free from bondage and free to
starve. The freedom from bondage and from
the means to feed themselves forces people to sell their capacity to labour to those with capital
(land or money). What the person sells is not
themselves (since they are free from bondage),
but they sell their labour power in exchange
for wages. The wages correspond to a certain
amount of money – representing a certain
amount of value – that is necessary to satisfy the
consumption needs of the workers.</p><p>

Marx called labour power <i>a peculiar commodity</i>. Like other commodities, this one must have
two aspects – a use value and a value. Wages
are the <b>exchange value</b> of labour power,
whereas labour is the use value of labour power. This distinction between the use value of
labour power and the exchange value of labour
power is fundamental to a Marxist understanding of surplus value and its production.</p><p>

In a given working day, workers transform
their capacity to labour into an act of labour.
Their various skills are utilised to transform raw materials and machines into commodities.</p><blockquote>
 Workers produce more value than they are paid in wages. This extra value is called&nbsp;<b>surplus value</b>.</blockquote><p>
During the working day and given the conditions of work, the total amount of value produced by the workers exceeds what is needed
for their own consumption and reproduction.
The value they require for their consumption
and reproduction – represented in wages – is
only a part of the value that they make during
the working day.</p><p>

Workers produce more value than they are
paid in wages. This extra value is called
<b>surplus value</b>. If the management of labour
changes or if the machines work at a different
speed, then either more or less value is produced in a day, which means that the surplus
value can be increased (or decreased). The fact
that labour power – this peculiar commodity –
has the quality of producing an extra amount of
value than what is needed for its own reproduction makes it <b>variable capital</b>.</p><p>

<b><span>Surplus Value</span></b></p><p>

The various raw materials that are on the assembly line, the machines, and the electricity that
help fashion the raw materials, would all be idle
without the necessary work of the labour power
put into the system by the workers. The workers
take the raw materials and the tools and shape
them into a commodity. It is the input of the
labour power that is crucial. Unlike any other
commodity, the labour power purchased from
the worker has to produce these new values.
When the workers tire, they go home and reproduce their labour power to be sold again.</p><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JPwsXDRUiDU/XZCFarXi6jI/AAAAAAAAFRw/luib4DD_tPkBGGIdJ0FOfSFmS-HNhJOmACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/SV.png" imageanchor="1"><img data-original-height="595" data-original-width="566" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JPwsXDRUiDU/XZCFarXi6jI/AAAAAAAAFRw/luib4DD_tPkBGGIdJ0FOfSFmS-HNhJOmACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/SV.png"></a></p>
<p>
The workers sell their labour power for a set
amount of money. When they start to work on
the production of commodities, it takes them
only a fraction of their working day to make
enough commodities to cover their own wages.
Marx called that the <b>necessary labour time</b>. It
was ‘necessary’ because in different epochs and in different countries it takes different amounts
of goods and services to reproduce the worker’s depleted labour power. In some countries,
the standard of living is lower than that of
others, which means the necessary labour time
is also shorter. The remainder of the working
day – after the necessary labour time – is the
<b>surplus labour time</b>. It is the time that the
worker spends producing commodities that are
above and beyond the amount needed to be
produced to pay the wage bill of the worker.</p><p>

<b><span>Rate of Surplus Value</span></b></p><p>

Marx’s concept – the rate of exploitation – is
measured by using the categories of variable
capital and surplus value. Variable capital is
the share of the values produced in the process of production that goes to the workers.
Surplus value, on the other hand, is the share
of the values that goes to the capitalist. The ratio of surplus value to variable capital – or
s/v – can be seen as a quantitative expression
of the exploitation of workers, also called the
<b>rate of surplus value</b>.</p><p>

Take a hypothetical commodity whose total
value is $1,000. The constant capital is worth
$500. That capital – raw material, tools and energy – goes into the process of production and
remerges in a different form but with the value
intact. There is no change in its value. The variable capital – what the worker earns – is $250.
The surplus value – what the capitalist appropriates – is the amount of value created during
the surplus labour time, which in …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.socialisteconomist.com/2019/09/a-marxist-analysis-of-iphone.html">http://www.socialisteconomist.com/2019/09/a-marxist-analysis-of-iphone.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.socialisteconomist.com/2019/09/a-marxist-analysis-of-iphone.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25702019</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 16:59:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Chinese FM welcomes Elon Musk statement praising Chinese government]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25701603">thread link</a>) | @jimmy2020
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202101/1212242.shtml#.X_nTsdClAgQ.twitter | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202101/1212242.shtml#.X_nTsdClAgQ.twitter">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          
          <p>Elon Musk's praise of China's government for being 'very responsible' to its people's needs and happiness is objective: Chinese FM</p>
          
          
        </div><div>
          <div> <center><img src="https://www.globaltimes.cn/Portals/0/attachment/2021/2021-01-08/acc29ac0-e6f1-4707-acc9-d248a6631a80.jpeg"></center>
<p>Elon Musk. Photo: VCG</p><p>Chinese FM said the praise from Elon Musk to China's government for being "very responsible" to its people's needs and happiness is objective, and it is a conclusion that reflects the real situation, adding that China welcomes more foreign friends to visit and get a comprehensive, correct impression of the nation.&nbsp;</p><p>The remarks came after Elon Musk hailed China as "more responsible" than the US in an interview with Business Insider, according to express.co.uk on January 4.&nbsp;</p><p>Musk said he had a positive experience when talking to Chinese government officials during his visits to the country and said they could "possibly" be "more responsible" to their people's happiness than the US.</p><p>Anyone who is unbiased and hopes to understand the real China objectively will come to such a conclusion, which reflects the reality of China's development history over the past 100 years, and the rapid changes that are currently taking place across Chinese land, Hua Chunying, spokesperson of China's Foreign Ministry, said on Friday.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>We welcome more foreign friends to visit China and gain an accurate impression of the country through close contact with Chinese people, she added.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Hua noted that, during the fight against the pandemic, everyone has also seen that the Chinese government insisted on putting people and their livelihoods first and spared no effort in protecting everyone's life, health, value and dignity.</p><p>We have also implemented the largest and most powerful battle against poverty in human history and successfully lifted 850 million people out of poverty, she added.</p><p>"This year, we have embarked on a new journey of building a modern socialist country in an all-round way. I think our Chinese people's growing needs or yearning for a better life will be further satisfied," Hua said.&nbsp;</p></div>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.globaltimes.cn/page/202101/1212242.shtml#.X_nTsdClAgQ.twitter</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25701603</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 16:20:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Next Gen Static Blogging]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 219 | Comments 168 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25701053">thread link</a>) | @mmackh
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://inoads.com/articles/2020-01-09-Next-Gen-Static-Blogging | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://inoads.com/articles/2020-01-09-Next-Gen-Static-Blogging">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://inoads.com/articles/2020-01-09-Next-Gen-Static-Blogging</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25701053</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 15:25:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Holiday Hacking – Tracking my heart rate while playing Call of Duty]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 74 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25700872">thread link</a>) | @lukastyrychtr
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://jcdav.is/2021/01/04/Holiday-Hacking-COD-HR/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jcdav.is/2021/01/04/Holiday-Hacking-COD-HR/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
  
  <p><span>04 Jan 2021</span></p><p>Over the holidays, I got a <a href="https://www.polar.com/us-en/products/accessories/oh1-optical-heart-rate-sensor">Polar OH1+</a> as a Christmas present. Its an optical heart rate monitor with similar tech to those found in smart watches (including my Garmin running watch), but much more accurate (at least for running) due to being smaller &amp; lighter, as well as fitting against the fleshier upper arm:</p>

<p><img src="https://jcdav.is/public/oh1-small.jpg" alt="Polar OH1"></p>

<p>Like any modern gadget these days, it supports Bluetooth (specifically Bluetooth Low Energy, or BLE/BTLE) for talking to your phone and/or smart watch. Which got me wondering, will it pair with a computer?</p>

<p><img src="https://jcdav.is/public/bluetooth.jpg" alt="It pairs"></p>

<p>This piqued my curiosity. I had long been at least somewhat curious about tracking my heart rate while say playing video games, if nothing else for curiosity. So how easy is it to grab data from this thing? As with the last few years, I had spent a bit of December doing a bunch of <a href="https://adventofcode.com/">Advent of Code</a> in rust, only to forget and have to re-learn everything the next year. So figured I could maybe try my hand at a “real” project.</p>

<p>Some quick googling later, I found the promising-looking <a href="https://crates.io/crates/btleplug">btleplug</a> crate. Lets dump data from all nearby devices…</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>extern</span> <span>crate</span> <span>btleplug</span><span>;</span>

<span>use</span> <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>thread</span><span>;</span>
<span>use</span> <span>std</span><span>::</span><span>time</span><span>::</span><span>Duration</span><span>;</span>

<span>#[cfg(target_os</span> <span>=</span> <span>"linux"</span><span>)]</span>
<span>use</span> <span>btleplug</span><span>::</span><span>bluez</span><span>::{</span><span>adapter</span><span>::</span><span>ConnectedAdapter</span><span>,</span> <span>manager</span><span>::</span><span>Manager</span><span>};</span>
<span>#[cfg(target_os</span> <span>=</span> <span>"windows"</span><span>)]</span>
<span>use</span> <span>btleplug</span><span>::</span><span>winrtble</span><span>::{</span><span>adapter</span><span>::</span><span>Adapter</span><span>,</span> <span>manager</span><span>::</span><span>Manager</span><span>};</span>
<span>#[cfg(target_os</span> <span>=</span> <span>"macos"</span><span>)]</span>
<span>use</span> <span>btleplug</span><span>::</span><span>corebluetooth</span><span>::{</span><span>adapter</span><span>::</span><span>Adapter</span><span>,</span> <span>manager</span><span>::</span><span>Manager</span><span>};</span>
<span>use</span> <span>btleplug</span><span>::</span><span>api</span><span>::{</span><span>UUID</span><span>,</span> <span>Central</span><span>,</span> <span>Peripheral</span><span>};</span>

<span>#[cfg(any(target_os</span> <span>=</span> <span>"windows"</span><span>,</span> <span>target_os</span> <span>=</span> <span>"macos"</span><span>))]</span>
<span>fn</span> <span>get_central</span><span>(</span><span>manager</span><span>:</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>Manager</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Adapter</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>adapters</span> <span>=</span> <span>manager</span><span>.adapters</span><span>()</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>();</span>
    <span>adapters</span><span>.into_iter</span><span>()</span><span>.nth</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>)</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>()</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>#[cfg(target_os</span> <span>=</span> <span>"linux"</span><span>)]</span>
<span>fn</span> <span>get_central</span><span>(</span><span>manager</span><span>:</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>Manager</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>ConnectedAdapter</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>adapters</span> <span>=</span> <span>manager</span><span>.adapters</span><span>()</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>();</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>adapter</span> <span>=</span> <span>adapters</span><span>.into_iter</span><span>()</span><span>.nth</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>)</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>();</span>
    <span>adapter</span><span>.connect</span><span>()</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>()</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>manager</span> <span>=</span> <span>Manager</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>()</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>();</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>central</span> <span>=</span> <span>get_central</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>manager</span><span>);</span>

    <span>central</span><span>.start_scan</span><span>()</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>();</span>
    <span>thread</span><span>::</span><span>sleep</span><span>(</span><span>Duration</span><span>::</span><span>from_secs</span><span>(</span><span>2</span><span>));</span>

    <span>for</span> <span>per</span> <span>in</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>central</span><span>.peripherals</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>,</span> <span>per</span><span>);</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>(Note that though this part should work cross-platform, I couldn’t get bluetooth working from WSL, so this was all done natively on Windows).</p>

<p>Sure enough, among the shockingly large list of nearby devices is my new toy:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>A0:9E:1A:XX:XX:XX properties: PeripheralProperties { address: A0:9E:1A:XX:XX:XX, address_type: Public, local_name: Some("Polar OH1 XXXXXXXX"), tx_power_level: Some(-64), manufacturer_data: Some([]), discovery_count: 6, has_scan_response: true }, characteristics: {}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Let’s see what characteristics it supports:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>    <span>let</span> <span>ohr</span> <span>=</span> <span>central</span><span>.peripherals</span><span>()</span><span>.into_iter</span><span>()</span><span>.find</span><span>(|</span><span>p</span><span>|</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>p</span><span>.properties</span><span>()</span><span>.local_name</span><span>.map</span><span>(|</span><span>n</span><span>|</span> <span>n</span><span>.starts_with</span><span>(</span><span>"Polar OH1"</span><span>))</span>
            <span>.unwrap_or</span><span>(</span><span>false</span><span>)</span>
    <span>})</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>();</span>

    <span>ohr</span><span>.connect</span><span>();</span>
    <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>,</span> <span>ohr</span><span>.discover_characteristics</span><span>()</span><span>.unwrap</span><span>());</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Turns out..a lot?</p>

<div><div><pre><code>[Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:00:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:01:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:04:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:A6:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:05:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: INDICATE }, Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:29:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:24:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:25:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:27:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:26:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:28:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:23:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:51:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: WRITE_WITHOUT_RESPONSE | WRITE | NOTIFY },
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:52:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: NOTIFY }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:53:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: WRITE_WITHOUT_RESPONSE | WRITE },
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:37:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: NOTIFY }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 00:00:2A:19:00:00:10:00:80:00:00:80:5F:9B:34:FB, properties: READ | NOTIFY }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:21:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:22:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: WRITE | INDICATE }, Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:26:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: NOTIFY }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 62:17:FF:4C:C8:EC:B1:FB:13:80:3A:D9:86:70:8E:2D, properties: READ }, 
Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: 62:17:FF:4D:91:BB:91:D0:7E:2A:7C:D3:BD:A8:A1:F3, properties: WRITE | INDICATE }, Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:81:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: READ | WRITE | INDICATE }, Characteristic { start_handle: 0, end_handle: 0, value_handle: 0, uuid: FB:00:5C:82:02:E7:F3:87:1C:AD:8A:CD:2D:8D:F0:C8, properties: NOTIFY }]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Which of these do I want? The <a href="https://btprodspecificationrefs.blob.core.windows.net/assigned-values/16-bit%20UUID%20Numbers%20Document.pdf">Bluetooth UUID specifications</a> lists a bunch of different potentially interesting IDs, but they are all 16 bits, whereas are 128 bit. Making matters more confusing, <code>btleplug</code> ‘s UUID definition seems to allow for either:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>pub</span> <span>enum</span> <span>UUID</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>B16</span><span>(</span><span>u16</span><span>),</span>
    <span>B128</span><span>([</span><span>u8</span><span>;</span> <span>16</span><span>]),</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>However it seems like a lot of them seem to only differ in the 3rd and 4th bytes <sup><a href="#suff1">1</a></sup>, and those to roughly correspond to GATT Characteristic Ids, and in there is a <code>2A:37</code>, which represents Heart Rate Measurement - sounds promising. Lets see if we can listen &amp; dump that data:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>    <span>let</span> <span>mut</span> <span>bytes</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>u8</span><span>;</span> <span>16</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span><span>0x00</span><span>,</span><span>0x00</span><span>,</span><span>0x2A</span><span>,</span><span>0x37</span><span>,</span><span>0x00</span><span>,</span><span>0x00</span><span>,</span><span>0x10</span><span>,</span><span>0x00</span><span>,</span><span>0x80</span><span>,</span><span>0x00</span><span>,</span><span>0x00</span><span>,</span><span>0x80</span><span>,</span><span>0x5F</span><span>,</span><span>0x9B</span><span>,</span><span>0x34</span><span>,</span><span>0xFB</span><span>];</span>
    <span>bytes</span><span>.reverse</span><span>();</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>uuid</span> <span>=</span> <span>UUID</span><span>::</span><span>B128</span><span>(</span><span>bytes</span><span>);</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>chars</span> <span>=</span> <span>ohr</span><span>.discover_characteristics</span><span>()</span>
        <span>.expect</span><span>(</span><span>"Couldn't discover characteristics"</span><span>);</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>hr_char</span> <span>=</span> <span>chars</span><span>.iter</span><span>()</span><span>.find</span><span>(|</span><span>c</span><span>|</span> <span>c</span><span>.uuid</span> <span>==</span> <span>uuid</span><span>)</span>
        <span>.expect</span><span>(</span><span>"couldn't find HR characteristic"</span><span>);</span>

    <span>ohr</span><span>.on_notification</span><span>(</span><span>Box</span><span>::</span><span>new</span><span>(|</span><span>not</span><span>|</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>println!</span><span>(</span><span>"{:?}"</span><span>,</span> <span>not</span><span>.value</span><span>);</span>
    <span>}));</span>
    <span>ohr</span><span>.subscribe</span><span>(</span><span>hr_char</span><span>)</span><span>.expect</span><span>(</span><span>"Couldn't subscribe"</span><span>);</span>
    <span>loop</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Endianness issues out of the way this….seems to be working?</p>

<div><div><pre><code>C:\Users\jackson\Dev\hroverlay&gt;cargo run
    Finished dev [unoptimized + debuginfo] target(s) in 0.14s
     Running `target\debug\hroverlay.exe`
[0, 59]
[0, 58]
[0, 58]
[0, 59]
[0, 60]
[0, 61]
[0, 62]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>At least that second number sure looks like a heart rate reading. To confirm this, I hopped over to the technical specifications for the Heart Rate Service (downloadable <a href="https://www.bluetooth.com/specifications/gatt/">here</a>). Sure enough, byte 0 represents various flags and byte 1 is a heart rate measurement. The spec authors have even figured out support for heart rates &gt;255 on off chance you ever slap one of these bad boys on a hummingbird:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>3.1.1.2Heart Rate Measurement Value Field</p>

  <p>The Heart Rate Measurement Value field shall be included in the Heart Rate Measurement characteristic. While most human applications require support for only 255 bpm or less, special applications (e.g. animals) may require support for higher bpm values. If the Heart Rate Measurement Value is less than or equal to 255 bpm a UINT8 format should be used for power savings. If the Heart Rate Measurement Value exceeds 255 bpm a UINT16 format shall be used. See 3.1.1.1.1for additional requirements on the Heart Rate Value format change.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Other potentially interesting bit flags include a way to indicate if the sensor thinks it has lost skin contact.</p>

<h2 id="displaying-things">Displaying things</h2>

<p>Now its time to figure out a UI. Faced with a <a href="https://www.areweguiyet.com/">large number of different options</a>, I ended up settling on the not-even-listed-there <a href="https://crates.io/crates/native-windows-gui">native-windows-gui crate</a> , throwing cross-platform support into the wind on the suspicion I would need easy access to the underlying win32 APIs, since it is largely just a series of nice convenience abstractions over those. Using the associated native-windows-derive macro crate, I had a basic UI setup working fairly quickly:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#[derive(Default,</span> <span>NwgUi)]</span>
<span>pub</span> <span>struct</span> <span>BasicApp</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>#[nwg_control(size:</span> <span>(</span><span>300</span><span>,</span> <span>115</span><span>),</span> <span>flags:</span> <span>"WINDOW|VISIBLE"</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>#[nwg_events(OnWindowClose:</span> <span>[</span><span>BasicApp::exit]</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>window</span><span>:</span> <span>nwg</span><span>::</span><span>Window</span><span>,</span>

    <span>#[nwg_layout(parent:</span> <span>window)]</span>
    <span>grid</span><span>:</span> <span>nwg</span><span>::</span><span>GridLayout</span><span>,</span>

    <span>#[nwg_control(text:</span> <span>"--"</span><span>,</span> <span>readonly:</span> <span>true</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>#[nwg_layout_item(layout:</span> <span>grid,</span> <span>row:</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>col:</span> <span>0</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>hr</span><span>:</span> <span>nwg</span><span>::</span><span>TextInput</span><span>,</span>

    <span>#[nwg_control(parent:</span> <span>window,</span> <span>interval:</span> <span>500</span><span>,</span> <span>stopped:</span> <span>false</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>#[nwg_events(OnTimerTick:</span> <span>[</span><span>BasicApp::draw_hr]</span><span>)]</span>
    <span>timer</span><span>:</span> <span>nwg</span><span>::</span><span>Timer</span><span>,</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>impl</span> <span>BasicA…</span></code></pre></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jcdav.is/2021/01/04/Holiday-Hacking-COD-HR/">https://jcdav.is/2021/01/04/Holiday-Hacking-COD-HR/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jcdav.is/2021/01/04/Holiday-Hacking-COD-HR/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25700872</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 15:03:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ray Tracing in pure CMake]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 272 | Comments 142 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25700038">thread link</a>) | @networked
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://64.github.io/cmake-raytracer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://64.github.io/cmake-raytracer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    
    

    <div>
      <p>Without further ado, I present: a basic whitted ray tracer, complete with multicore rendering, written in 100% pure CMake. If you don't care about the details, and just want to see the code, you can <a href="https://github.com/64/cmake-raytracer">find it here</a>.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://github.com/64/cmake-raytracer/raw/master/render.png">
    <figcaption><i>Rendered in 7m23s on a i5-10210U, 8 processes</i> </figcaption>
</figure>
<p>At this point, those familiar with CMake may have some questions, so keep reading to find out how it all works.</p>

<p><strong>Good news:</strong> CMake has a <a href="https://cmake.org/cmake/help/latest/command/math.html?highlight=math"><code>math</code></a> command. <strong>Bad news:</strong> it only supports integers. If you've written a ray tracer before, you probably did it with floating point numbers. So how do you go from representing signed integers to representing something-resembling-floating-point numbers? One answer is to use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed-point_arithmetic"><strong>fixed-point arithmetic</strong></a>.</p>
<p>The basic idea with fixed point is simple. We define some large integer to represent the number 1.0; let's choose <strong>1000</strong>. Then we can represent 2.0 as 2000, 0.5 as 500, -3.0 as -3000 etc. When we want to add two numbers, we simply add their fixed-point representations. Here's how that looks in CMake:</p>
<pre><span>function(add a b res)
    math(EXPR tmp </span><span>"(${</span><span>a</span><span>}) + (${</span><span>b</span><span>})"</span><span>)
    set(</span><span>"${</span><span>res</span><span>}" "${</span><span>tmp</span><span>}" </span><span>PARENT_SCOPE)
endfunction()
</span></pre>
<p>This takes two values <code>a</code> and <code>b</code> to be added and stored in the variable <code>res</code>. I use <code>PARENT_SCOPE</code> so that the variable we create is actually visible from the calling function, otherwise CMake will destroy it when the function ends.</p>
<p>To multiply two numbers, we simply multiply their fixed-point representations, and then divide by the thing we chose to represent 1.0:
<span><span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>1.5</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>4.0</mn><mo>↦</mo><mfrac><mrow><mn>1500</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>4000</mn></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>6000</mn><mo>↦</mo><mn>6.0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">1.5 \times 4.0 \mapsto \frac{1500 \times 4000}{1000} = 6000 \mapsto 6.0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span></p>
<p>Division is similar:
<span><span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>1.5</mn><mo>÷</mo><mn>4.0</mn><mo>↦</mo><mfrac><mrow><mn>1500</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>1000</mn></mrow><mn>4000</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>375</mn><mo>↦</mo><mn>0.375</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">1.5 \div 4.0 \mapsto \frac{1500 \times 1000}{4000} = 375 \mapsto 0.375</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span>
We could have multiplied by 1000 after doing the division, but as integer division rounds towards zero this would wipe out all our precision (as <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mfrac><mn>1500</mn><mn>4000</mn></mfrac><mo>×</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\frac{1500}{4000}\times 1000 = 0 \times 1000 = 0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>). Multiplying first gives us better results, as long as the dividend isn't too huge (which would cause overflow).</p>
<p>CMake's <code>math</code> command only supports basic integer arithmetic. For more complicated operations, like square root, we use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newton%27s_method">Newton-Raphson iteration</a>. You can read more about this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Methods_of_computing_square_roots#Babylonian_method">here</a>, but the basic idea is to make a 'guess' as to what the output should be then iteratively refine the guess towards the answer. This gives a surprisingly accurate result within only three or four iterations, subject to the quality of the initial guess:</p>
<pre><span>function(sqrt x res)
    div_by_2(${x} guess)

    </span><span>foreach</span><span>(counter RANGE 4)
        </span><span>if</span><span>(${guess} EQUAL 0)
            set(</span><span>"${</span><span>res</span><span>}" </span><span>0 PARENT_SCOPE)
            return()
        </span><span>endif</span><span>()

        div(${x} ${guess} tmp)
        add(${tmp} ${guess} tmp)
        div_by_2(${tmp} guess)
    </span><span>endforeach</span><span>()

    set(</span><span>"${</span><span>res</span><span>}" "${</span><span>guess</span><span>}" </span><span>PARENT_SCOPE)
endfunction()

</span><span># sqrt(123) = 11.09072626, actual answer is 11.0905365064
</span></pre>
<p>I also implemented a similar function for computing <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mfrac><mn>1</mn><msqrt><mi>x</mi></msqrt></mfrac></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">\frac{1}{\sqrt{x}}</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> separately as I found that it lead to better numerical stability, as opposed to computing the square root as above and then doing the reciprocal. This comes in handy when we need to normalize vectors.</p>
<p>Almost everything in computer graphics is done with vectors, so I started implementing vector operations: <code>vec3_add</code>, <code>vec3_mul</code>, <code>vec3_div</code>, <code>vec3_dot</code> etc. These make use of CMake built-in lists, which are pretty horrible, but save me from having to use three separate variables to keep track of the individual components of each vector. For example, here's what the dot product looks like:</p>
<pre><span>function(vec3_dot x y res)
    list(GET ${x} 0 x_0)
    list(GET ${x} 1 x_1)
    list(GET ${x} 2 x_2)
    list(GET ${y} 0 y_0)
    list(GET ${y} 1 y_1)
    list(GET ${y} 2 y_2)
    mul(${x_0} ${y_0} z_0)
    mul(${x_1} ${y_1} z_1)
    mul(${x_2} ${y_2} z_2)
    add(${z_0} ${z_1} tmp)
    add(${tmp} ${z_2} tmp)
    set(</span><span>"${</span><span>res</span><span>}" </span><span>${tmp} PARENT_SCOPE)
endfunction()
</span></pre>
<p>And here's how we'd use it to normalize a vector:</p>
<pre><span>function(vec3_normalize x res)
    vec3_dot(${x} ${x} x_2)
    rsqrt(${x_2} one_over_length)
    vec3_mulf(${x} ${one_over_length} tmp)
    set(</span><span>"${</span><span>res</span><span>}" </span><span>${tmp} PARENT_SCOPE)
endfunction()
</span></pre>
<p>As well a few other bits and bobs, like <code>clamp</code> and <code>truncate</code>, that's all the arithmetic that's needed.</p>

<p>If you're new to ray tracing, I'd refer you to <a href="https://twitter.com/peter_shirley">Peter Shirley's</a> wonderful book series '<a href="https://raytracing.github.io/">Ray Tracing in One Weekend</a>', which my code is loosely based on. The general intuition is to trace rays out from the camera into the scene and see what they intersect. Since we represent all our scene geometry and rays as mathematical objects, computing intersections between rays and geometry is just a case of solving equations. Once we have found an intersection, we compute the color of the point we intersected with, which may itself be computed by tracing rays towards light sources or towards other scene geometry.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://developer.nvidia.com/sites/default/files/pictures/2018/RayTracing/ray-tracing-image-1.jpg">
    <figcaption><i>The ray tracing algorithm.</i>  Credit: <a href="https://developer.nvidia.com/discover/ray-tracing">https://developer.nvidia.com</a></figcaption>
</figure> 
<p>To keep it simply I went with a simple scene consisting of a sphere sitting atop an infinite plane in a checkerboard color. I also ended up faking the shadow underneath the sphere, simply drawing a black circle (well done if you spotted it from the image). I had implemented whitted ray tracing and even path tracing at one point, but they were much more complicated and performed a lot worse for the same result. In theory, though, there's no reason why I couldn't do it properly, it would just require some additional effort and patience.</p>
<p>Here's what the main 'trace' function looks like, with some of the unnecessary bits stripped out for clarity:</p>
<pre><span># Traces a ray into the scene, computes the color returned along the ray
</span><span>function(trace ray_origin ray_dir depth color)
    </span><span># Base case for recursion
    </span><span>if</span><span>(${depth} GREATER_EQUAL 3)
        return()
    </span><span>else</span><span>()
        math(EXPR depth </span><span>"${</span><span>depth</span><span>} + 1"</span><span>)
    </span><span>endif</span><span>()

    </span><span># Calculate intersection points with the sphere and plane
    </span><span>sphere_intersect(${ray_origin} ${ray_dir} hit_t_1 hit_point_1 hit_normal_1)
    plane_intersect(${ray_origin} ${ray_dir} hit_t_2 hit_point_2 hit_normal_2)

    </span><span># Did we hit the sphere?
    </span><span>if</span><span>(${hit_t_1} GREATER ${ray_epsilon})
        </span><span># Calculate reflected ray direction
        </span><span>offset_origin(hit_point_1 hit_normal_1 new_origin)
        vec3_dot(hit_normal_1 ${ray_dir} scalar)
        mul_by_2(${scalar} scalar)
        vec3_mulf(hit_normal_1 ${scalar} refl_a)
        vec3_sub(${ray_dir} refl_a new_dir)

        </span><span># Recursively trace the new ray into the scene
        </span><span>trace(new_origin new_dir ${depth} traced_col)

        </span><span># Calculate contribution from lights
        </span><span>set(col 0 0 0)
        light_contrib(hit_point_1 hit_normal_1 light1_pos light1_col out_col1)
        light_contrib(hit_point_1 hit_normal_1 light2_pos light2_col out_col2)
        vec3_add(col out_col1 col)
        vec3_add(col out_col2 col)
        vec3_add(col traced_col col)

        set(base_col ${sphere_color})
        vec3_mul(base_col col col)

    </span><span># Did we hit the plane?
    </span><span>elseif</span><span>(${hit_t_2} GREATER ${ray_epsilon})
        </span><span># ...snip: Use equation of a circle to fake shadow, if we're within range
        # ...snip: Calculate checkerboard pattern
    </span><span>else</span><span>()
        </span><span># We hit nothing, return black
        </span><span>set(col 0 0 0)
    </span><span>endif</span><span>()

    set(</span><span>"${</span><span>color</span><span>}" </span><span>${col} PARENT_SCOPE)
endfunction()
</span></pre>
<p>When I started, I wouldn't sure if it would be possible to do in pure CMake, but with a little trickery we can manage it.</p>
<p>For <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>N</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">N</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> processes, the basic plan is to divide up the image vertically and let each sub-process render a few rows. We can invoke sub-processes with the <a href="https://cmake.org/cmake/help/v3.0/command/execute_process.html"><code>execute_process</code></a> command, passing arguments (such as the worker index) via <code>-D</code>. Each process then spits their row data into a text file, which gets merged together by the master process once they've all finished.</p>
<p>One subtlety is that as we need all the sub-processes to run in parallel, we can't simply call <code>execute_process</code> <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>N</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">N</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> times, as it would run them sequentially. Luckily, we can specify multiple processes to run simultaneously in one command (I think this is intended to be used for long chains where one program is piped into the next), but in order to avoid hardcoding <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>N</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">N</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> we have to programmatically construct the call to <code>execute_process</code> with CMake's <a href="https://cmake.org/cmake/help/git-stage/command/cmake_language.html"><code>EVAL CODE</code></a> feature (thanks to <a href="https://github.com/martty/vuk">martty</a> for this idea):</p>
<pre><span>message(STATUS </span><span>"Launching ray tracer with ${</span><span>num_procs</span><span>} processes, ${</span><span>image_width</span><span>}x${</span><span>image_height</span><span>} image..."</span><span>)

set(exec_command </span><span>"execute_process(</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>)
</span><span>foreach</span><span>(worker_index RANGE 1 ${num_procs})
    set(exec_command </span><span>"${</span><span>exec_command</span><span>}COMMAND cmake . -Wno-dev -Dworker_index=${</span><span>worker_index</span><span>} -Dimage_width=${</span><span>image_width</span><span>} -Dimage_height=${</span><span>image_height</span><span>} -Dnum_procs=${</span><span>num_procs</span><span>}</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>)
</span><span>endforeach</span><span>()
set(exec_command </span><span>"${</span><span>exec_command</span><span>} )"</span><span>)

</span><span># Begin the worker processes
</span><span>cmake_language(EVAL CODE ${exec_command})

message(STATUS </span><span>"Finished ray tracing, gathering results..."</span><span>)
</span></pre>
<p>As per <a href="https://raytracing.github.io/">Ray Tracing in One Weekend</a>, I use the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netpbm#PPM_example">PPM image format</a>. This is a really simple text-based format which is perfect for my purposes as I don't have to bother with compression. Once we're done rendering we simply read all the data that the workers have spat out, write the PPM header, and print everything to <code>stderr</code>:</p>
<pre><span>set(image_contents </span><span>"P3 ${</span><span>image_width</span><span>} ${</span><span>image_height</span><span>}</span><span>\n</span><span>255</span><span>\n\n</span><span>"</span><span>)

</span><span>foreach</span><span>(worker_index RANGE 1 ${num_procs})
    file(READ </span><span>"worker-${</span><span>worker_index</span><span>}.txt" </span><span>file_contents)
    set(image_contents </span><span>"${</span><span>image_contents</span><span>}${</span><span>file_contents</span><span>}"</span><span>)
</span><span>endforeach</span><span>()

message(</span><span>"${</span><span>image_contents</span><span>}"</span><span>)
</span></pre>
<p>The division of work among the worker processes is pretty sub-optimal as the rows towards the top of the image are mostly empty whereas the rows at the bottom are entirely full, which means that some processes finish very fast while others take much longer. Fixing this problem is left as an exercise to the reader.</p>

<p>If you made it this far, thanks for reading! Feel free to create issues, send pull requests or star <a href="https://github.com/64/cmake-raytracer">the code on GitHub</a>.</p>

    </div>

    
    

    

    
        
            
              
        
    
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://64.github.io/cmake-raytracer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25700038</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 13:04:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Authoritarianism Through Coding: Signal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 38 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25699993">thread link</a>) | @m3rcury
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://www.oyd.org.tr/en/articles/signal/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.oyd.org.tr/en/articles/signal/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div class="page">
  <article>
    
     
      
    <p>This isn’t a theoretical piece about freedom and digital technologies. This is a real ongoing trend that is at best observed around secure messaging application Signal by Open Whisper Systems and it’s founder Moxie Merlinspike. His view and management of Signal reflects a wider trend that jepordises world’s freedom.</p>
<p>Signal is a secure messaging software that has changed the field a lot. Signal is built upon propriety software Textsecure and RedPhone applications that had been developed by Merlinspike and his co-founder Stuart Anderson. When Twitter acquired Whisper Systems, it releases both software under free software licenses. Merlinspike left Twitter acquired Whisper Systems, founded Open Whisper Systems and merged -once the private property of himself- TextSecure and Redphone into Signal.</p>
<p>Signal is free software. “Free as in freedom”, their client and server code is licenced under GPLv3 and AGPLv3. This makes the code and only the code itself pro-freedom. Just because the code it self free does not necessarily make the coder “free” as well and that is the problem we face today!</p>
<p>Open Whisper Systems led by Moxie Merlinspike, who is behind Signal, is and was never behind freedom. This has been seen in the light of LibreSignal (<a href="https://github.com/LibreSignal/LibreSignal/issues/37#issuecomment-217211165">https://github.com/LibreSignal/LibreSignal/issues/37#issuecomment-217211165</a>) debate where a fork of Signal client is build without unfree dependencies and published on the F-droid free software repository on Android. After much debate about federation, the claimed server resources and freedom, followed by legal trademark threats Libresignal has been removed from F-droid and so was anybody’s chance of using Signal as a secure messenger who doesn’t use Google services. <a href="https://wire.com/en/blog/axolotl-proteus-encryption-protocols/">Wire</a> case is just another example.</p>
<p>This approach is not only a threat to free software it is a recurring threat to human kind!</p>
<p>To prove this bold claim one needs to look at one recent blog post from Open Whisper Systems and a presentation made in 36C3 by Merlinspike.</p>
<p><a href="https://signal.org/blog/the-ecosystem-is-moving/">Signal’s blog post</a>
<a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2020/01/02/on-privacy-versus-freedom/">Matrix’s blog Post</a></p>
<p>The main points of his claims can be listed as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Decentralized systems are harder to build</li>
<li>Decentralized systems are harder to evolve</li>
<li>Decentralized systems are harder to secure</li>
<li>Decentralized systems are becoming concentrated in predominant provider anyways</li>
<li>If users don’t trust their app provider they have the freedom to use something else</li>
</ul>
<p>While his claims are true up to a certain point they are only superficial. Through these points Merlinspike claims that, centralized services are superior in modern times!</p>
<p><a href="https://matrix.org/blog/2020/01/02/on-privacy-versus-freedom/">anyone who is interested in the depth of this debate can start reading Martix’s answer to Merlinspike at the link here</a></p>
<p>It is really unnecessary to explain in depth why this type of thinking is dangerous when a simple change in words can tell more than 1000 page work. Let’s rename the object and compare his digital dystopia with one that has occured several times through-out analog human history and which once again recures today;</p>
<ul>
<li>Democracies are harder to build</li>
<li>Democracies are harder to improve</li>
<li>Democracies are harder to secure</li>
<li>In democracies power is becoming concentrated in predominant hands anyways</li>
<li>If people do not like their democracy provider (country) they have the freedom to leave and go another provider.</li>
</ul>
<p>One doesn’t need to think hard to see what Merlinspike is advising. He claims democracies suck because of the hardships of human organization and proposes autocracy to manage the world in favour of the helpless people occupying it. Why? Because democracies are inefficient and people don’t want that!</p>
<p>If he had given the same statement about democracies and governmental politics as he gave about federative systems it would have provoked outrage! People died for freedom, they are still dying and struggling around the globe. Then someone comes and stomps over every ideal which human society ever build up until this point in history and proclaims themselves the world leader! Think about it!</p>
<p>The example given is bad but why are Merlinspike’s claims about decentralized systems not considered bad as well? Because digital freedom has not yet been lost and won by blood or are we still asleep? Just because code is free, it doesn’t necessarily mean that the coders mind is also free! Freedom is not just a license, it is an ideal in any condition that we must stand for!</p>

    
        <hr>



    
  </article>
  
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.oyd.org.tr/en/articles/signal/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25699993</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 12:56:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Haskell is a Bad Programming Language (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 331 | Comments 286 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25699574">thread link</a>) | @fpoling
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://blog.shitiomatic.tech/post/haskell-is-a-bad-programming-language/#👾 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.shitiomatic.tech/post/haskell-is-a-bad-programming-language/#👾">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.shitiomatic.tech/post/haskell-is-a-bad-programming-language/#👾</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25699574</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 11:40:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Deep neck flexor exercises – Back and neck]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 181 | Comments 110 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25699510">thread link</a>) | @whereistimbo
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/patient-exercises/back-and-neck/deep-neck-flexor-exercises.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/patient-exercises/back-and-neck/deep-neck-flexor-exercises.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="mainContent">
	<div>
        <div id="leftCol_normal">

<h2>Deep neck flexor exercises</h2>
<br>
<h3>Why train them?</h3>
<p>
<img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/patient-exercises/deep_neck_1.jpg"></p><p>The deep neck flexor muscles sit deep in the front of the neck, behind the trachea (windpipe). Because of their close proximity to the vertebrae (spine) and their short length, they have an important role in providing stability to the neck. People with a history of neck or upper back injury, such as whiplash, can show great improvement in pain and function if they strengthen these muscles. Those with postural neck pain often have weakness in these muscles and overuse in the muscles on the top of the shoulders. They too can show a great response to retraining the deep neck flexor muscle group.
</p><br>

<h3>How do I exercise them?</h3>
<h5>Exercise 1</h5>
<p>
<img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/patient-exercises/deep_neck_2.jpg"></p><ul>
<li>Lie on your back with knees comfortably bent. Find your neutral spine position, as explained by your physiotherapist. Use a small rolled towel under the head if needed.</li>
<li>Lift your head off the towel and feel the muscles on the front of the neck. These are NOT the deep neck flexor muscles - these muscles often overwork to try and help with stability, they are not designed for this purpose.</li>
<li>Perform a small nodding movement, as if to look towards your toes. Don't lift your head up. You should not feel the muscles on the front of the neck moving, but rather you should be using the muscles deep behind them.</li>
<li>Hold for 5 seconds. Repeat 10 times.</li>
</ul>
<h5>Exercise 2</h5>
<p>
<img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/patient-exercises/deep_neck_3.jpg"></p><ul>
<li>Position as above.</li>
<li>Place your hand on the side of your head and provide gentle resistance, as if you are bending your head to one side.</li>
<li>Hold for 5 seconds. Repeat 10 times.</li>
<li>Use hand to resist small rotation movement.</li>
<li>Hold for 5 seconds. Repeat 10 times.</li>
</ul>
<h5>Exercise 3</h5>
<p>
<img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/patient-exercises/deep_neck_4.jpg"></p><ul>
<li>Lie on your tummy with hands supporting the forehead.</li>
<li>Perform the small nodding movement and float the head and breastbone off the floor.</li>
<li>Hold for 5 seconds. Repeat 10 times.</li>
</ul>
<h5>Exercise 4a:</h5>
<p>
<img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/patient-exercises/deep_neck_5.jpg"></p><ul>
<li>Stand with your back to the wall and your feet slightly in front, hip width apart. Perform the small nodding movement, while sliding the base of the skull up the wall. You should feel the neck lengthen.</li>
<li>Hold for 5 seconds. Repeat 10 times.</li>
</ul>
<h5>Exercise 4b:</h5>

<ul>
<li>Same as exercise above.</li>
<li>From the lengthened position, move your head away from the wall so that you're looking at the floor.</li>
<li>Then return to the starting position.</li>
<li>Do not allow your chin to poke forward through either movement.</li>
</ul>

<h5>Exercise 4c:</h5>
<p>
<img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/patient-exercises/deep_neck_8.jpg"></p><ul>
<li>Sitting in a chair, look up at the ceiling.</li>
<li>When returning the head back to the neutral position, do not let the chin poke forward.</li>
<li>Curl forward one level at a time, starting from the top.</li>
<li>Do not allow your chin to poke forward.</li>
</ul>
<br>

<h3>Where do I go from here?</h3>
<p>
Once you have mastered these exercises, you should feel more aware of your neck posture and how to position yourself correctly. You can use this knowledge:</p>
<ul>
<li>When sitting at your desk/computer or on the couch.</li>
<li>Performing any weights in the gym or doing exercise classes.</li>
</ul>

<p>

Please <a href="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/contact-us/index.html">contact us</a> to book an appointment or for more information on any of the services available at our clinic in Kensington.</p>
<p>
<a href="#top" title="Back To Top">↑ Back To Top</a></p>






        </div>
        
		



				
				<p><b>Insurance providers...</b></p><p><img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/insurance-logos.png">
				</p>
				<br>


	</div>
</div><div id="jumpsContainer">
	<div>
			<div id="j1">
				<p><a>Physiotherapy</a></p><p><a href="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/services/physiotherapy.html"><img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/physiotherapy-jump.jpg" alt="Physiotherapy" title="Physiotherapy"></a></p>
				<div><p>
					Our physiotherapists specialise in restoring your normal function and movement patterns so you can get on with everyday life. </p></div>
				<p>Read more »</p>
			</div>
			<div id="j2">
 				<p><a>Pilates</a></p><p><a href="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/services/pilates.html"><img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/pilates-jump.jpg" alt="Pilates" title="Pilates"></a></p>
				<div><p>
					Pilates focuses on building the body???s core strength and improving posture through a series of low repetition, low impact stretching and conditioning exercises. </p></div>
				<p>Read more »</p>
			</div>

            <div id="j3">
            	<p><a>Sports injuries</a></p><p><a href="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/services/sports-assessments.html"><img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/sports-injuries-jump.jpg" alt="Sports injuries" title="Sports injuries"></a></p>
				<div><p>
					At Sprint Physiotherapy we are experts at treating a variety of sporting injuries, including; swimming, running, golfing, etc.</p></div>
				<p>Read more »</p>
			</div>

            <div id="j4">
				<p><a>Massage Therapy</a></p><p><a href="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/services/massage.html"><img src="https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/images/massage-therapy-jump.jpg" alt="Massage Therapy" title="Massage Therapy"></a></p>
				<div><p>
					Our massage therapists specalise in a range of massage techniques; remedial, sports, pregnancy, etc.</p></div>
				<p>Read more »</p>
			</div>
			

	</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.sprintphysio.co.uk/patient-exercises/back-and-neck/deep-neck-flexor-exercises.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25699510</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 11:27:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: DevBooks – Help Developers find indy books]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 113 | Comments 31 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25698707">thread link</a>) | @simon-holdorf
<br/>
January 9, 2021 | https://thesmartcoder.dev/books/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thesmartcoder.dev/books/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-server-rendered="true" id="__nuxt"><!----><div id="__layout"><div data-app="true" id="app" data-v-8b44678a=""><div> <main data-v-8b44678a=""><div><div data-v-405cec28="" data-v-8b44678a=""><div><div data-v-405cec28=""><div data-v-405cec28=""><div> <p data-v-405cec28="">
        Find the best books for developers.
      </p></div></div></div></div></div> <div data-v-8b44678a=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb="" data-v-8b44678a=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><h2>What is DevBooks?</h2> <p>DevBooks helps developers to find the best books for developers and authors to showcase their amazing work. </p></div></div> </div> <div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><div data-v-58ecdbbb=""><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        A React Developer’s Guide to Hooks
      </h2> <p>by Sebastien Castiel</p> <p>
        React Hooks are awesome, but they are not easy to use every day.
In my experience with React and hooks, I have faced a lot of issues, spent some time debugging to understand where these issues came fr...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Practical Bootstrap
      </h2> <p>by Panos Matsinopoulos</p> <p>
        Learn to use one of the most popular CSS frameworks and build mobile-friendly web pages. Used for numerous websites and applications, Bootstrap is a key tool for modern web development.
      </p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Coding Career Handbook
      </h2> <p>by Shawn Swyx Wang</p> <p>
        10 hours of audio. 40 chapters. 450+ pages. 1,400+ links to original sources curated over 3 years. Priceless insights from dozens of developers at the top of their fields. Proven ideas, tested by pers...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Jest Handbook
      </h2> <p>by Hugo Di Francesco</p> <p>
        Learn Advanced JavaScript Testing patterns with Jest.

Take your JavaScript testing to the next level by learning the ins and outs of Jest, the top JavaScript testing library.
      </p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Practical Test Automation
      </h2> <p>by Panos Matsinopoulos</p> <p>
        Learn the principles behind test-driven development (TDD) and behavior-driven development (BDD) and see how Jasmine, RSpec and Cucumber can be used to your advantage. This book examines some of the le...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Tech Resume Inside Out
      </h2> <p>by Gergely Orosz</p> <p>
        What a good developer resume looks like, and how to write one. I've reviewed hundreds of developer resumes at tech companies like Microsoft, Skype, and Uber. This guide helps you craft a developer res...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Lean from the Trenches
      </h2> <p>by Henrik Kniberg</p> <p>
        You know the Agile and Lean development buzzwords, you’ve read the books. But when systems need a serious overhaul, you need to see how it works in real life, with real situations and people. Lean fro...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Code Your Way Up
      </h2> <p>by Greg Thomas</p> <p>
        Code Your Way Up is the book for new developers looking to get started in software and asks the hard questions on growth, delivery, and initiative and what you need to think of in order to succeed.  I...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Master HTML &amp; CSS
      </h2> <p>by Panos Matsinopoulos</p> <p>
        Want to become a Web developer? HTML and CSS are a must for your foundation. And this book takes you from zero to advanced level. From classical hello world things to how you can position elements on ...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        How To Host, Secure, and Deliver Static Websites on Amazon Web Services
      </h2> <p>by Kyle Galbraith</p> <p>
        "How To Host, Secure, and Deliver Static Websites on Amazon Web Services" is a book and video course that cuts through the sea of information to accelerate your learning of AWS. Giving you a learning ...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Road to GraphQL
      </h2> <p>by Robin Wieruch</p> <p>
        The Road to GraphQL is your personal journey to master pragmatic GraphQL in JavaScript. The book is full with applications you are going to build along the way with React.js and Node.js. Afterward, yo...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Letters To a New Developer
      </h2> <p>by Dan Moore</p> <p>
        Learn what you need to succeed as a developer beyond the code. The lessons in this book will supercharge your career by sharing lessons and mistakes from real developers. 

Wouldn’t it be nice to lear...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        How to Get a Job in Web Development
      </h2> <p>by RealToughCandy</p> <p>
        "How to Get a Job in Web Development" is designed for junior web developers. 
In this book, you will learn how to:

• Expertly craft the ‘holy clover’ of application materials: your resume, cover lett...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Portfolio Surgery
      </h2> <p>by RealToughCandy</p> <p>
         In Portfolio Surgery, you'll start with a massive upgrade of the look and feel of your portfolio. You'll learn about common pitfalls, dos and don'ts, and portfolio optimization techniques. Then, in t...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Case of IBM 386 PC: A Detective Story for Techies
      </h2> <p>by Jim Grep</p> <p>
        Take a break, have some fun reading a tech mystery story on programming--a first of its kind. A nostalgic story from the early days of IBM PC when some programmers get together to play detective and h...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Freelance Newbie
      </h2> <p>by RealToughCandy</p> <p>
        Are you ready to jump-start your freelance web development career? Freelance Newbie has you covered! In this book, you’ll learn practical, actionable steps you can start using TODAY to get your first ...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Your First Year in Code
      </h2> <p>by Isaac Lyman</p> <p>
        Starting a career in programming can be intimidating. Whether you're switching careers, joining a boot camp, starting a C.S. degree, or learning on your own, Your First Year in Code can help, with pra...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Good Parts of AWS
      </h2> <p>by Daniel Vassallo</p> <p>
        This is a book by Daniel Vassallo and Josh Pschorr. Between us, we have worked with AWS for 15 years, including 11 years working inside AWS. We have worked on all sorts of web applications, from small...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Pure React
      </h2> <p>by Dave Ceddia</p> <p>
        Learning new skills is one of the best ways to invest in yourself.

Knowing React can be the deciding factor in getting hired for a new job, or set you up for a promotion at your current one.

You cou...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Practical Vavr
      </h2> <p>by Alexandre Grison</p> <p>
        Practical Vavr is all about making you want to use Vavr in your day to day Java programming.

If you want to improve the quality of your code by using a well-thought and beautifully designed functiona...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Programming Interview Problems: Dynamic Programming (with solutions in Python)
      </h2> <p>by L. Rossi</p> <p>
        The most common dynamic programming problems asked in programming interviews, with detailed solutions in Python. The solutions consist of cleanly written code, with plenty of comments, accompanied by ...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Building an Effective Dev Portfolio
      </h2> <p>by Josh Comeau</p> <p>
        I got so many replies! A couple hundred developers were willing to share their portfolios with me, and I went through as many as I could over the next couple of weeks. I found I kept giving the same f...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        PHP Mentors - Advice from PHP Experts around the world
      </h2> <p>by Flávio Silveira</p> <p>
        Answers from PHP masters around the world for your questions.
Code, Career, Team work, Working environment, Logs, Tests, Future and much more.

PHP Mentors Book is a set of questions with topics that ...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Content for Developers
      </h2> <p>by Maedah Batool</p> <p>
        A whole new workflow to Write. Publish. Market. Authentic &amp; professional content writing meant for developers. Zero bull-shit and to-the-point tips to improve your technical content writing skills. Le...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        14 Habits of Highly  Productive Developers
      </h2> <p>by Zeno Rocha</p> <p>
        You can learn the most popular frameworks, use the best programming languages, and work at the biggest tech companies, but if you cultivate bad habits, it will be hard for you to become a top develope...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Outstanding Developer
      </h2> <p>by Sebastien Castiel</p> <p>
        Being a developer is not only about writing code. And improving as a developer is not only about improving in writing code. This book explores how to become an outstanding developer through several ax...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        A Smart Guide for Your Career as a Software Engineer
      </h2> <p>by Mike Nikles</p> <p>
        I started my software engineer career 20 years ago. Since then, I have interviewed hundreds of candidates and reviewed even more resumes. This book is a guide for your own career, whether you are new ...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        5 Little Potions
      </h2> <p>by Mark Wilbur</p> <p>
        In 5 Little Potions, you'll begin your journey into Elixir programming by creating increasingly complex games.

You'll start with a simple guessing game. Next you'll work with Elixir Structs in a boar...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Data Analysis with Rust Notebooks
      </h2> <p>by Dr. Shahin Rostami</p> <p>
        A practical book on Data Analysis with Rust Notebooks that teaches you the concepts and how they're implemented in practice.

- All code examples in Rust,
- Rust (Jupyter) Notebooks for each Section,
...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Distributed Systems with Node.js
      </h2> <p>by Thomas Hunter II</p> <p>
        In this hands-on guide, author Thomas Hunter II proves that Node.js is just as capable as traditional enterprise platforms for building services that are observable, scalable, and resilient. Intermedi...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Python re(gex)?
      </h2> <p>by Sundeep Agarwal</p> <p>
        This book will help you learn Python Regular Expressions, a mini-programming language for all sorts of text processing needs.

The book heavily leans on examples to present features of regular express...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Road to React
      </h2> <p>by Robin Wieruch</p> <p>
        In "The Road to React" you will learn about all the fundamentals of React.js with Hooks while building a full-blown React application step by step. While you create the React application, every chapte...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        Cloud Native Web Development
      </h2> <p>by Mike Nikles</p> <p>
        In this book, we will walk through the end-to-end process of developing a cloud-native web application. You will learn technologies, processes, tips &amp; tricks and gain hands-on experience. You will fin...

        <span>more</span></p></div>  </div></div><div xs="12"><div> <div><h2>
        The Road to Firebase
      </h2> <p>by Robin Wieruch</p> <p>
        The Road to React with Firebase is your personal journey to master advanced React for business web applications in JavaScript whereas Firebase is used to …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></main></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thesmartcoder.dev/books/">https://thesmartcoder.dev/books/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thesmartcoder.dev/books/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25698707</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 08:43:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Over: Board – Raspberry Pi CM4 ITX Motherboard]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25697993">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
January 8, 2021 | https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/overboard-raspberry-pi-cm4-itx-motherboard/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/overboard-raspberry-pi-cm4-itx-motherboard/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-3401">

	

	<div>
		
<p>The Over:Board is an IO board for the Raspberry Pi Compute Module 4. It is designed to use a standard PC ATX power connector and features a full size PCI-E 16x slot although its only running at 1x bandwidth and unfortunately it is not compatible with a GPU.   <br></p>



<figure><img src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201%201'%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-src="https://c0.iggcdn.com/indiegogo-media-prod-cld/image/upload/c_fill,w_762,g_center,q_auto:best,dpr_1.6,f_auto,h_506/fjlirebv3qpqd7xdlsek" alt="The Over:Board" data-old-src="https://c0.iggcdn.com/indiegogo-media-prod-cld/image/upload/c_fill,w_762,g_center,q_auto:best,dpr_1.6,f_auto,h_506/fjlirebv3qpqd7xdlsek" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>The Over:Board</figcaption></figure>



<p><br>It breaks out the following ports: <br></p>



<ul><li>24-pin ATX Power</li><li>40-pin GPIO</li><li>Full Size PCI-E @ 1x bandwidth</li><li>SATA Controller (Powered by USB)</li><li>Front Panel Header</li><li>CPU Fan Header</li><li>UART Header</li><li>Micro USB</li><li>RS232 Com Port</li><li>2x USB 2.0 Ports</li><li>Micro SD card slot</li><li>3.5mm Audio</li></ul>



<p>The Over:Board costs £199 for an early prototype or £99 for the Final Production board and is available to back now on indiegogo. <br></p>



<div><p>Whilst £99 is expensive for a IO board this is likely down to the limited production and it is likely still the cheapest ARM based ITX motherboard on the market even when factoring in the cost of a RPI CM4. </p><p>You can back the Over:Board on indiegogo <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/over-board-raspberry-pi-4-mini-itx-motherboard#/" target="_blank">here</a></p><p>For another ARM IO board with SATA check out my Nano Pi Neo2 NAS review <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/nano-pi-neo2-nas-enclosure-a-small-linux-home-server-nas/" target="_blank">here</a></p><p>The project currently has £1654 in backing from 11 backers. With 28 days left it is looking likely to hit its £5000 target. </p><p>Ross Nicoholls is leading the campaign: </p></div>



<blockquote><p>I’ve lost count exactly how many, but this will be about my 35th commercial electronics PCB to be manufactured, so I am no stranger to getting these things to market. That said however, this will be the first of my own venture so represents my most exciting project to date and something I feel very passionate about.</p><cite>Ross has lots of experience in this field</cite></blockquote>



<p>I wish Ross good luck and hope to see the Over:Board available soon! </p>

	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/overboard-raspberry-pi-cm4-itx-motherboard/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25697993</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 06:31:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pfizer vaccine appears effective against mutation in new coronavirus variants]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 629 | Comments 227 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25696577">thread link</a>) | @awnird
<br/>
January 8, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/pfizer-biontech-vaccine-appears-effective-against-mutation-in-new-coronavirus-variants-study-suggests-1.5865885 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/pfizer-biontech-vaccine-appears-effective-against-mutation-in-new-coronavirus-variants-study-suggests-1.5865885">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Pfizer Inc. and BioNTech's COVID-19 vaccine appeared to work against a key mutation in the highly transmissible new variants of the coronavirus discovered in Britain and South Africa, according to a laboratory study conducted by the U.S. drugmaker.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5852149.1608672062!/cumulusImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/covid-vaccinations-toronto.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A nurse prepares a dose of the Pfizer-BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine for care home workers at St. Michael’s Hospital in Toronto on Dec. 22, 2020.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Evan Mitsui/CBC)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Pfizer Inc. and BioNTech's COVID-19 vaccine appeared to work against a key mutation in the highly transmissible new variants of the coronavirus discovered in Britain and South Africa, according to a laboratory study conducted by the U.S. drugmaker.</p>  <p>The study by Pfizer and scientists from the University of Texas Medical Branch, which has not yet been peer-reviewed, indicated the vaccine was effective in neutralizing virus with the so-called N501Y mutation of the spike protein.</p>  <p>The mutation could be responsible for greater transmissibility and there had been concern it could also make the virus escape antibody neutralization elicited by the vaccine, said Phil Dormitzer, one of Pfizer's top viral vaccine scientists.</p>  <p>The first results of tests on the variants offer a glimmer of hope while more studies are carried out as Britain and other countries try to tame the more infectious variants that&nbsp;authorities believe are driving a surge in infections that could overwhelm health-care systems.</p>  <p>The Pfizer-BioNTech study was conducted on blood taken from people who had been given the vaccine. Its findings are limited because it does not look at the full set of mutations found in either of the new variants of the rapidly spreading virus.</p>  <p>Dormitzer said it was encouraging that the vaccine appears effective against the mutation, as well as 15 other mutations the company has previously tested against.</p>  <p>"So we've now tested 16 different mutations, and none of them have really had any significant impact. That's the good news," he said. "That doesn't mean that the 17th won't."</p>  <p><em><strong>WATCH | What scientists know about the new coronavirus variant:</strong></em></p>  <p><span><span><div><div title="What scientists know about the new coronavirus variant" role="button" tabindex="0"><div><div aria-labelledby="1842141251676-metadata-" title="What scientists know about the new coronavirus variant"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/643/819/COVID-VARIANT-SCI-BIRAK-080121.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p></div></div></div></div></div><span>The B1-17 coronavirus variant, first discovered in the U.K., is now in at least 40 countries, including Canada. It has 23 mutations, including one that attaches to healthy cells like a key going into a lock.<!-- --> <!-- -->1:56</span></span></span></p>  <p>Dormitzer said another mutation found in the South African variant, called the E484K mutation, was also concerning.</p>  <p>The researchers plan to run similar tests to establish whether the vaccine is effective against other mutations found in the British and South African variants and hope to have more data within weeks.</p>  <p>The variants are said by scientists to be more transmissible than previously dominant ones, but they are not thought to cause more serious illness.</p>  <p>The virus's spikes act as a key that must unlock our cells to cause the infection.&nbsp;The variant first identified in the U.K. has a mutation that appears to make it easier for the coronavirus to grab hold of the lock more tightly, scientists say.</p>    <p>Scientists said the results of the study would help calm concerns that people will not be protected by vaccines being given to millions of people around the world in the fight against the pandemic, which has killed more than 1.8 million people and roiled economies.</p>  <p>But they cautioned that more clinical tests and data are still needed to come to a definitive conclusion.</p>  <p>"This is good news, mainly because it is not bad news," said Stephen Evans, professor of pharmacoepidemiology at the&nbsp;London School of Hygiene &amp; Tropical Medicine.</p>  <p>"So, yes this is good news, but it does not yet give us total confidence that the Pfizer (or other) vaccines will definitely give protection."</p>  <h2>AstraZeneca, Moderna, CureVac testing against variants</h2>  <p>AstraZeneca, Moderna and CureVac are also testing whether their shots work against the fast-spreading variants. They have said they expect them to be effective, but the timing of those studies is not known.</p>  <p>A senior British lawmaker expressed concerns in an interview on Friday that COVID-19 vaccines might not work properly against the South African variant. He was not responding to questions about Friday's data.</p>  <p>The Pfizer-BioNTech vaccine and the one from Moderna Inc., which use synthetic messenger RNA technology, can be quickly tweaked to address new mutations of a virus if necessary. Scientists have suggested the changes could be made in as little as six weeks.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866498.1610132224!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/virus-outbreak-new-variants.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866498.1610132224!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/virus-outbreak-new-variants.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866498.1610132224!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/virus-outbreak-new-variants.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866498.1610132224!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/virus-outbreak-new-variants.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866498.1610132224!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/virus-outbreak-new-variants.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5866498.1610132224!/cpImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/virus-outbreak-new-variants.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Graphic shows a diagram of the COVID-19 virus.<!-- --> <!-- -->(AP)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Some other vaccines to protect against COVID-19 also use the spike protein to show our immune system what the enemy looks like.</p>  <p>Canadian microbiologist Benjamin tenOever, a professor at the&nbsp;Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai in New York,&nbsp;said our immune system learns to recognize and attack the viral attachment protein at many different sites.</p>  <p>"It would require many many mutations to render our vaccines non-effective,"&nbsp;tenOever&nbsp;said.</p>  <p>The variant is also not the first of the pandemic to emerge and Eleanor Riley, professor of immunology and infectious disease at the University of Edinburgh, said these types of studies&nbsp;will be needed as they appear.</p>  <p>"It may be necessary to tweak the vaccine over time," she said.</p>  <p>Dr. Theresa Tam, Canada's chief public health officer, said Friday that 14 cases of the variant first reported in the U.K. have been reported in Canada.</p>  <p>Researchers in Ontario have developed a faster test to identify variants.</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/pfizer-biontech-vaccine-appears-effective-against-mutation-in-new-coronavirus-variants-study-suggests-1.5865885</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25696577</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 03:48:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Writing an iRacing SDK Implementation in F#]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25696493">thread link</a>) | @sanesmith
<br/>
January 8, 2021 | https://markjames.dev/2021-01-08-writing-an-iracing-sdk-implementation-fsharp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://markjames.dev/2021-01-08-writing-an-iracing-sdk-implementation-fsharp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article role="main">
        <p>In my <a href="https://markjames.dev/2021-01-04-why-learning-fsharp-2021/">previous post</a>, I discussed how I’ve decided to learn F# in 2021 for a number of reasons. Around the same time, I also happened to setup my Sim Racing rig so that I could continue to play <a href="https://www.iracing.com/" target="_blank">iRacing</a> with my VR headset (HTC Vive). Its been several years since I’ve last played, but with COVID-related curfews being implemented here in Montreal tomorrow, I’ve been increasingly taking up home-based pursuits which I didn’t always have the time for pre-lockdown. Since the last time I played iRacing, I’m running a PC with a much better processor, motherboard, and only SSDs. The VR performance has been a huge leap forward since I used to play with my old machine and I was quite impressed. After spending a couple of hours setting up, here’s what my current humble racing setup looks like:</p>

<p><img src="https://markjames.dev/img/posts/irsdk-fsharp/racing-rig.jpg" width="650" height="488" alt="Photo of my current iRacing VR setup"></p>

<p>Having a dedicated table really helps, as in my old apartment it was fairly difficult to setup a station with limited space, but now I can fortunately just jump in. Despite the past limitations, I was able to get fairly competitive and still remember the thrill of my first win agaisnt a field of real racers in a Mazda MX-5:</p>

<p><img src="https://markjames.dev/img/posts/irsdk-fsharp/iracing-win.jpg" width="500" height="279" alt="Photo of my iRacing first win certificate"></p>

<p>Inspired by setting everything up and doing some laps to practice for an eventual return to comeptition, I started thinking about how I once experimented with using the <a href="https://github.com/kutu/pyirsdk" target="_blank">Python implementation</a> of the iRacing SDK to connect to an arduino and display a speedometer readout in realtime on a small screen. In reminiscing about the experience, I thought about how I could look into writing an F# implementation of the SDK as a learning project. In addition to learning through the project, it also has the benefit of being of use in a future project involving an iRacing stats tracker web app that I’ve been thinking about writing as a project for my upcoming <a href="https://markjames.dev/2020-12-09-back-to-school/">cloud computing courses</a>.</p>

<h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h2>

<p>I tend to learn best when projects are slightly outside of my comfort zone, and this would be both my first time writing a library, as well as writing one in a functional language! Having used an array of libraries at this point, I had some confidence in choosing an organizational structure, and the Python implementation is only <a href="https://github.com/kutu/pyirsdk/blob/master/irsdk.py" target="_blank">739 lines of code</a> which felt doable compared to some of the larger libraries out there.</p>

<p>Moreover, the python implementation of the SDK has the ability to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Get session data (WeekendInfo, SessionInfo, etc…)</li>
  <li>Get live telemetry data (Speed, FuelLevel, etc…)</li>
  <li>Broadcast messages (camera, replay, chat, pit and telemetry commands)</li>
</ul>

<p>and I figured that this would be a good featureset to aim for in the final version of the F# SDK. Out of these features, the session data and live telemetry data would be the ones I plan to implement first.</p>

<h2 id="creating-the-library">Creating the Library</h2>

<p>After coming up with some desired features, the first step was to create a new FSharp solution called iRacingFSharp. Inside the solution, I created two projects. One was our actual library, called iRacingFSharp, and the other was a basic console app called SDKReader (located in the Examples Folder) to test the functionality of the library as I worked on it. Note, if you’d like to see the full codebase you can <a href="https://github.com/markjamesm/irsdk-fsharp" target="_blank">here on github</a>.</p>

<h2 id="the-first-function">The First Function</h2>

<p>Starting small, I decided that a good first function would be to find out the state of the simulator. Fortunately, the iRacing SDK allows you to check if the sim is running using the following URL which points to a localhost server:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>http://127.0.0.1:32034/get_sim_status?object=simStatus
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Getting this URL in Postman returns a JSON object which looks like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>var simStatus={
   running:0 // 1 if the sim is running
};
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I decided to make use of the <a href="https://fsharp.github.io/FSharp.Data/library/Http.html" target="_blank">F# Data HTTP library</a> in order to download the response and so I installed it from NuGet at this point.</p>

<p>Next, inside my iRacingFSharp project I created a file called Irsdk.fs and wrote the following code:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>namespace</span> <span>IrsdkFS</span>

<span>open</span> <span>FSharp</span><span>.</span><span>Data</span>

<span>///&lt;summary&gt;F# implementation of the iRacing SDK.&lt;/summary&gt;</span>
<span>module</span> <span>IrsdkFS</span> <span>=</span>

    <span>///&lt;summary&gt;Returns the simStatus in string format&lt;/summary&gt;</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>SimStatus</span><span>()</span> <span>=</span>
        <span>let</span> <span>simStatusURL</span> <span>=</span> <span>"http://127.0.0.1:32034/get_sim_status?object=simStatus"</span>
        <span>let</span> <span>simStatusObject</span> <span>=</span> <span>Http</span><span>.</span><span>RequestString</span><span>(</span><span>simStatusURL</span><span>)</span>
        <span>simStatusObject</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>In the above code, I’ve created a module which contains a function called SimStatus that takes no parameters. It then binds the JSON response to simStatusURL and passes it to the HTTP library via Http.RequestString(). Finally, simStatusObject is returned in string format which can be parsed further by another function in a later step.</p>



<p>With this simple function in place, the next step was to create SDKReader.fs inside my SDKReader console app. This file contained code to call the SimStatus() function and print the output:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>[&lt;</span><span>EntryPoint</span><span>&gt;]</span>
<span>let</span> <span>main</span> <span>argv</span> <span>=</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>test</span> <span>=</span> <span>IrsdkFS</span><span>.</span><span>SimStatus</span><span>()</span>
    <span>printf</span> <span>"%s"</span> <span>test</span>
    <span>0</span> <span>// return an integer exit code</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Running dotnet build inside the SDKReader folder displayed the following output while iRacing was running:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>"var simStatus={
   running:1
};
"</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Success! With this method working, we now have the very beginnings of an F# implementation of the iRacing SDK! Although it is a small step, we were also able to create and structure the project. Lastly, I also setup a a basic .NET build through Github Actions for CI.</p>



<p>iRacing’s API telemetry comes in three variations; data written to a .ibt file 60 times a second, live data exposed to the telemetry API 60 times per second, and a session string in YAML format that contains more or less static information about the session. The YAML string is appended to the end of the .ibt file but only a small portion of that data is exposed. This means that going forward, I’ll need to look into parsing the YAML as well as mapping more of the API endpoints. The iRacing API appears to be nonstandard and so it may take a little more work than just a typical REST API.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for Part Two where I plan to implement some telemetry functions and look into parsing the aforementioned YAML. In addition, be sure to follow along with the <a href="https://github.com/markjamesm/irsdk-fsharp" target="_blank">Github Repo here</a> if you’re interested in seeing how to project progresses (or would like to contribute)!</p>

      </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://markjames.dev/2021-01-08-writing-an-iracing-sdk-implementation-fsharp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25696493</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 03:42:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ad-Tech Is a Bezzle]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25695482">thread link</a>) | @freediver
<br/>
January 8, 2021 | https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#adfraud | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#adfraud">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1719">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	
	<div>
		<p><!--
Tags:
reviews, damon knight, science fiction, statistics, statistical literacy, gift guide,books, uk, dsa, democratic socialists of america, elections, california, ads, at-tech, fraud, google, labor, unions, alphabet, alphabet workers union, cwa,

Summary:
Ad-tech is a bezzle; Google's unionizing; The Data Detective; Damon Knight's Why Do Birds is back; Endorsing the Forward 43 slate

URL:
https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/

Title:
Pluralistic: 04 Jan 2021

Bullet:
🎬

Separator:
_,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,__,.-'~'-.,_

Top Sources:
Today's top sources: Ken Snider (https://twitter.com/orenwolf), Slashdot (https://slashdot.org/), Margo Rowder (https://twitter.com/margorowder).

--><br>
<a href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/"><img src="https://i0.wp.com/craphound.com/images/04Jan2021.jpg?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/craphound.com/images/04Jan2021.jpg?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></a></p>

<ul>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#adfraud">Ad-tech is a bezzle</a>: The subprime attention crisis is upon us.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#awu">Google's unionizing</a>: Solidarity vs worker misclassification.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#harford">The Data Detective</a>: How to truth with statistics.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#an-oval">Damon Knight's Why Do Birds is back</a>: Reviving a grand master's comic masterpiece.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#fwd-43">Endorsing the Forward 43 slate</a>: For my California comrades.
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#retro">This day in history</a>: 2016
</li>
<li attrs="{'class': ['xToC']}"><a attrs="{'href': '#xslug'}" href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#bragsheet">Colophon</a>: Recent publications, upcoming/recent appearances, current writing projects, current reading
</li>
</ul>

<hr>
<p><a name="adfraud"></a><br>
<img src="https://i1.wp.com/craphound.com/images/ad-3242595_960_720.jpeg?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/craphound.com/images/ad-3242595_960_720.jpeg?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>

<p>There are lots of problems with ad-tech:</p>
<ul>
<li>being spied on all the time means that the people of the 21st century are less able to be their authentic selves;
</li>
<li>
<p>any data that is collected and retained will eventually breach, creating untold harms;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>data-collection enables for discriminatory business practices ("digital redlining");</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>the huge, tangled hairball of adtech companies siphons lots (maybe even most) of the money that should go creators and media orgs; and</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>anti-adblock demands browsers and devices that thwart their owners' wishes, a capability that can be exploited for even more nefarious purposes;</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>That's all terrible, but it's also <em>ironic</em>, since it appears that, in addition to everything else, ad-tech is a fraud, a bezzle.</p>
<p>Bezzle was John Kenneth Galbraith's term for "the magic interval when a confidence trickster knows he has the money he has appropriated but the victim does not yet understand that he has lost it." That is, a rotten log that has yet to be turned over.</p>
<p>Bezzles unwind slowly, then all at once. We've had some important peeks under ad-tech's rotten log, and they're increasing in both intensity and velocity. If you follow Aram Zucker-Scharff, you've had a front-row seat to the fraud.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/Chronotope/status/1078003966863200256">https://twitter.com/Chronotope/status/1078003966863200256</a></p>
<p>Time and again, everything in the ad-tech stack has been demonstrated to be fraudulent: fake audiences firing fake clicks at fake videos on fake sites that suck real dollars out of advertisers' accounts.</p>
<p>This was masterfully elucidated in Tim Hwang's short 2020 book SUBPRIME ATTENTION CRISIS, whose thesis is: we must deflate the ad-tech bubble intentionally, lest we get a messy rupture that destroys many of the good things the parasite has colonized.</p>
<p><a href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/10/05/florida-man/#wannamakers-ghost">https://pluralistic.net/2020/10/05/florida-man/#wannamakers-ghost</a></p>
<p>The ad-tech fraud is many-layered. On the surface, there's the counting frauds: fake clicks, fake sites, fake videos, etc. But there's a deeper fraud, a theory fraud, the fraud that with enough surveillance data and machine learning, ad-tech can sell anyone anything.</p>
<p>That is: even if we count accurately, ads are still overvalued and underperforming. This is also a lesson whose examples are coming with increasing tempo, as when Ebay simply stopped buying Google search ads and saw <em>no</em> decrease in sales.</p>
<p><a href="https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/06/surveillance-tulip-bulbs/#adtech-bubble">https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/06/surveillance-tulip-bulbs/#adtech-bubble</a></p>
<p>In a piece for Forbes, marketer-turned-antifraud-auditor Dr Augustine Fou rounds up some of the grossest things festering under the ad-tech log.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2021/01/02/when-big-brands-stopped-spending-on-digital-ads-nothing-happened-why/?sh=5a4f9c9a1166">https://www.forbes.com/sites/augustinefou/2021/01/02/when-big-brands-stopped-spending-on-digital-ads-nothing-happened-why/?sh=5a4f9c9a1166</a></p>
<p>Like that time in 2018 when Procter and Gamble – inventors of "brand marketing" – turned off $200m worth of ad-tech buys and saw no change to their sales. Or when Chase killed 95% of its advertising and kept all of its business.</p>
<p>Most interesting is the tale of how Uber allowed itself to be defrauded of $150m/year, for years, by ad-tech intermediaries. It's a story told in detail by former Uber head of "performance marketing" Kevin Frisch on the Marketing Today podcast:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.marketingtodaypodcast.com/194-historic-ad-fraud-at-uber-with-kevin-frisch/">https://www.marketingtodaypodcast.com/194-historic-ad-fraud-at-uber-with-kevin-frisch/</a></p>
<p>It starts with the revelation that $50m of its annual spend on customer acquisitions – money paid when an ad leads to a new Uber customer downloading the app, entering payment details and taking their first ride – was fraudulent.</p>
<p>Here's how that worked: scummy marketers fielded low-quality apps (like battery monitors) that requested root access. These apps spied on every app you installed. If you installed Uber, they "fired a click" to the system to report you as having been "converted" by an ad.</p>
<p>After clearing $50m of fraud, Frisch continued to dig into the system. In the end, about $120m of the $150m was being stolen, pocketed for fake clicks on fake sites by fake users.</p>
<p>In a fascinating turn, Frisch describes how his colleagues were indifferent or actively hostile to his efforts. Uber was in "growth mode," trying to beef up its numbers prior to the IPO where suckers would relieve its Saudi royal investors.</p>
<p>Uber is a company that will never, ever be profitable. It, too, is a bezzle. It only "works" if outside investors – marks – can somehow be convinced to buy the insiders' stock, which requires the appearance of growth – AKA "A pile of shit this big <em>must</em> have a pony under it!"</p>
<p>So execs like Frisch were required to "spend to budget" – to maintain the appearance of growth, including (especially) the growth of its "precision analytics" marketing, where ad-tech spends turned into directly attributable customer acquisitions.</p>
<p>This is the story that keeps on giving, because it all starts with Sleeping Giant's campaign to force Uber to stop advertising on Breitbart, and Uber's inability to get its ad-tech "partners" to definitively switch off Breitbart ads.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nandoodles/status/1345774768746852353">https://twitter.com/nandoodles/status/1345774768746852353</a></p>
<p>The system's layers of misdirection – there to hide the fraud – meant that it behaved nondeterministically and couldn't fulfil simple requests, which triggered the search.</p>
<p>There's a theory that the reason Big Tech spies on us so much is that they're really good at turning data into sales (and, by extension, influence, as in elections, referenda, etc). But it is increasingly apparent that Big Tech's spying is part of a bezzle.</p>
<p>That is, we're being surveilled, doxed, placed under automated suspicion and digitally discriminated against all to put on a show that separates marks from their dollars.</p>
<p>This is the theme of my 2020 book HOW TO DESTROY SURVEILLANCE CAPITALISM:</p>
<p><a href="https://onezero.medium.com/how-to-destroy-surveillance-capitalism-8135e6744d59">https://onezero.medium.com/how-to-destroy-surveillance-capitalism-8135e6744d59</a></p>
<p>Namely, that we are under constant surveillane because monopolies can get away with obviously fraudulent and dangerous conduct by mobilizing their monopoly profits to buy political outcomes that serve their ends.</p>
<p>This is also what happened with California's Proposition 22, the most expensive ballot initiative in US history: Uber didn't spearhead a $200m campaign to legalize worker misclassification to become profitable.</p>
<p>Uber will never be profitable.</p>
<p>All that money was spent to maintain the fiction, the fraud, the bezzle – it was an appeal to rescue the wholly fictional pony underneath that gigantic pile of shit.</p>
<hr>
<p><a name="awu"></a><br>
<img src="https://i1.wp.com/craphound.com/images/Homestead_Strike_-_Mob_attacking_Pinkerton_men-1-1-9.jpeg?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/craphound.com/images/Homestead_Strike_-_Mob_attacking_Pinkerton_men-1-1-9.jpeg?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>

<p>Google workers have announced their intention to form a union, under the auspices of CWA Local 1440. The union is called The Alphabet Workers Union (Google maintains the legal and accounting fiction that it is a division of a holding company called "Alphabet").</p>
<p>Speaking of legal fictions, the union is opening membership to "TVCs" – temps, vendors and contractors – employees who have been deliberately misclassified so as to avoid paying them benefits or extending normal workplace protections to them.</p>
<p>It's a bold move, a countermeasure to thwart the other commercial advantage from worker misclassification: by creating multiple categories of workers, bosses can pit employees against one another, by dangling privileges in front of one group but not the other.</p>
<p>But it comes at a high price: to gain official legal recognition, more than 50% of eligible workers must join the union. By including more workers, the union is setting a higher bar for official status.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/3an5q9/google-workers-publicly-launch-union">https://www.vice.com/en/article/3an5q9/google-workers-publicly-launch-union</a></p>
<p>But the union has momentum: a series of high-profile googler uprisings – driven by official tolerance for sexual misconduct, complicity in US military drone programs, secret collaboration with Chinese surveillance and censorship, and more – show how radicalized googlers are.</p>
<p>Google's management – who cultivated an air of participatory, cuddly collaboration – have arrived at a point where the contradictions between their "values" and the company's profits can no longer be reconciled.</p>
<p>In Dec 2020, Google fired Timnit Gebru, an eminent Black AI scientist who refused to retract a paper critical of its profitable Big Data research. Management compounded their sins by making false claims about Gebru's dismissal.</p>
<p>The unionization drive is under the CWA's #CODE (Coalition to Organize Digital Employees) project. Though CODE is no stranger to conflict, Google represents a serious challenge, thanks to its partnership with notorious union-busters IRI Consultants.</p>
<p>(IRI's tactics pale in comparison to the mercenaries that Amazon has hired to bust its unions: the Pinkerton company, who have spilled rivers of workers' blood in their murderous history):</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/5dp3yn/amazon-leaked-reports-expose-spying-warehouse-workers-labor-union-environmental-groups-social-movements">https://www.vice.com/en/article/5dp3yn/amazon-leaked-reports-expose-spying-warehouse-workers-labor-union-environmental-groups-social-movements</a></p>
<p>For important context on the drive, check out Collective Action in Tech's article on the announcement, which explains why googlers have formed a "non-contract union" that does not yet have official recognition.</p>
<p><a href="https://collectiveaction.tech/2021/the-abcs-of-googles-new-union/">https://collectiveaction.tech/2021/the-abcs-of-googles-new-union/</a></p>
<p>"Non-contract unions embody the idea that worker power does not come from legal processes, but rather through building power through solidarity."</p>
<hr>
<p><a name="harford"></a><br>
<img src="https://i0.wp.com/craphound.com/images/data-detective.png?w=840&amp;ssl=1" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/craphound.com/images/data-detective.png?w=840&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>

<p>Publishing works on long schedules, which means that long-planned books can be overtaken by events…like covid.</p>
<p>2020 was tough for those of us with books in trail, especially nonfiction. But for a few lucky writers, covid imparted a terrible salience to their books.</p>
<p>One such writer is Tim Harford, host of BBC Radio 4's More or less, which is hands-down the greatest statistical literacy program in the world, …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#adfraud">https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#adfraud</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/04/how-to-truth/#adfraud</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25695482</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 02:19:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Archive of 43k+ Donald Trump Twitter Screenshots]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25693054">thread link</a>) | @soheilpro
<br/>
January 8, 2021 | https://pikaso.me/blog/donald-trump-twitter-archive | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pikaso.me/blog/donald-trump-twitter-archive">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  
  <div>


    <section>
      <p>
        <h2>Donald Trump Twitter Screenshot Archive</h2>
      </p>
      
        
      

      <div><p>Donald Trump loves to tweet and everyone knows that.
Twitter is his favorite medium to express his ideas and to communicate with the world.
He has been an active Twitter user since 2009. Much longer than many other world leaders.</p>
<p>Last month (May 2020) he tweeted 845 times â€” that's 28 tweets per day on average!</p>
<center>
  <a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/491324429184823296"><img src="https://pikaso.me/blog/files/pikaso.me-realDonaldTrump-20140721_205046-491324429184823296.png" alt="Trump Tweet" width="500" height="244"></a>
</center>
<p>A while ago we received a request from one of our users who was looking for a way to screenshot all Donald Trump tweets.
We realized that's a good opportunity to put <a href="https://pikaso.me/">Pikaso</a> into test and see if it can perform such a task without any problems.
It went smoothly and there was only an issue with one of his tweets which included a deleted image.</p>
<p>Today, we are releasing the resulting files to the public.
This archive contains screenshots of 43,475 Donald Trump tweets from May 2009 to May 2020.
Whether you are pro- or anti- Trump, this is an important part of Internet history that we believe should be preserved.</p>
<h3 id="download">Download</h3>
<p>The Donald Trump Twitter Screenshot Archive can be downloaded through the following links:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://pikaso.me/go/trump-twitter-archive-v1.zip">trump_twitter_archive_v1.zip</a> (Direct download, 2.6 GB)</li>
<li><a href="https://pikaso.me/go/trump-twitter-archive-v1.torrent">trump_twitter_archive_v1.torrent</a> (Torrent download, 28.2 KB)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="howthiswasmade">How This Was Made?</h3>
<p>To create this archive, we first extracted all tweet ids from the realDonaldTrump.csv file that was provided to us.
That file only contained Donald Trump tweets up to March 29, 2020. To get the later tweets, we used <a href="http://trumptwitterarchive.com/">trumptwitterarchive.com</a>.</p>
<p>We then used the <a href="https://pikaso.me/api">Pikaso API</a> to screenshot each individual tweet.</p>
<h3 id="updates">Updates</h3>
<p>We have no plans to keep this archive up to date after the initial release.
However, if you are interested in doing so, you can use <a href="https://pikaso.me/">Pikaso</a>.
You can even <a href="https://pikaso.me/automate">automate</a> it so that each time he tweets, an automatic screenshot is taken.</p>
<h3 id="credit">Credit</h3>
<p>All the tweets are copyright https://twitter.com/realdonaldtrump.<br>
All the media embedded in tweets are copyright their respective owners.<br>
Original tweets data provided by <a href="https://twitter.com/twentysox">@twentysox</a>.</p>
<h3 id="copyrightlicense">Copyright &amp; License</h3>
<p>Copyright © 2020 https://pikaso.me.<br>
This work by https://pikaso.me is licensed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0">CC BY 4.0</a>.</p>
<h3 id="contact">Contact</h3>
<p>If you have any feedback or questions regarding this work, please <a href="https://pikaso.me/contact">contact us</a>.</p></div>
    </section>

    

    
      <section>
        <h2>More from the Blog</h2>

        
      </section>
    

      </div>
  
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pikaso.me/blog/donald-trump-twitter-archive</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25693054</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:14:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
