<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:58:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:58:40 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The rise and fall of the industrial R&D lab]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24321799">thread link</a>) | @npalli
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-rise-and-fall-of-the-american-rd-lab/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-rise-and-fall-of-the-american-rd-lab/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
					<div>
						<p><span>Once, small firms centred on inventors were responsible for most of our innovation. Larger firms might buy or exploit these steps forwards, but they did not typically make them. And then for a brief period, this changed: many of the best new products, tools, and ideas came from research labs within large corporations. This brief period also happened to be the era when scientific, technological, and economic productivity sped forward at its fastest ever clip. Yet almost as soon as it arrived, the fruitful period was over and we returned to a situation where small companies and small-business-like teams at universities developed innovations outside of large companies and sold them in a market for ideas. Though we might enjoy the innovation created by small flexible firms, we should not dismiss the contributions made by large corporate labs. The corporate lab may be creeping back, but aggressively prosecuting antitrust against large firms growing organically through in-house research could easily snuff this spark out.</span></p>
<h3>The USA’s first system of innovation</h3>
<p><span>When the USA began to contribute to the progress of technology, in the early 19th century, it was largely practically-minded, not based on deep scientific understanding. Rather, it largely consisted of individual inventors commercialising their own inventions. Whereas nuclear power depended on decades or centuries of progress in physics, many late 19th century innovations were more like the cotton gin, which came together through practical-minded trial and error in the field. By the late 19th century, the system had morphed into one we would find strangely familiar today: inventors invented, venture capitalists invested, and companies commercialised. The system even had </span><a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/business-history-review/article/patent-alchemy-the-market-for-technology-in-us-history/90991329A8D4A49EBF7B49D2EAD1CE7A"><span>patent lawyers</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://www.hoover.org/sites/default/files/khan_ip2_working_paper.pdf"><span>non-practising entities</span></a>, <span>which own patents purely </span><a href="https://www.hbs.edu/businesshistory/Documents/BHR870102.pdf"><span>to litigate on their behalf</span></a><span>. There were still startups commercialising an idea and scaling it up themselves, but many inventors found that the division of labour enabled by the market ideas allowed them to </span><a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/business-history-review/article/patent-alchemy-the-market-for-technology-in-us-history/90991329A8D4A49EBF7B49D2EAD1CE7A"><span>focus on what they did best</span></a><span>.</span></p>
<p><span>Large firms were consumers of ideas created by inventors, and were sceptical of the value of doing in-house science. They believed it was easier to buy new science off the shelf. In 1885 T. D. Lockwood, head of American Bell Telephone Company’s patent department, said:&nbsp;</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span>“I am fully convinced that it has never, is not now, and never will pay commercially, to keep an establishment of professional inventors, or of men whose chief business it is to invent”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span>Of course, Bell Labs itself later grew to be one of the marquees of commercial labs—in the late 1960s it employed 15,000 people including 1,200 PhDs, who between them made too many important inventions to list, from the transistor and the photovoltaic cell to the first digitally scrambled voice audio (in 1943) and the first complex number calculator (in 1939). Fourteen of its staff went on to win Nobel Prizes and five to win </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_Award"><span>Turing Awards</span></a><span>. </span></p>
<p><span>The 1920s stock market boom was in large part driven by a huge rise in the value that investors </span><a href="https://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/aer.98.4.1370"><span>accorded to intangible capital</span></a><span> and ideas held within companies. A similar thing happened in the </span><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Capitalism-Without-Capital-Intangible-Economy/dp/0691175039"><span>1990s Dot-com Bubble</span></a><span>. Between 1921 and 1927 the number of scientists and engineers in industrial labs more than doubled. When the stock market crashed and the Great Depression hit it caused a </span><a href="https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/d71a/90cfa2d0d0d72f13724d27dd326209431974.pdf"><span>massive and persistent decline</span></a><span> in independent inventing and the startup-like activity around it. But large labs continued to boom, increasing staffing and research spending throughout the lean 1930s, and earning more patents. By 1930, most patents were issued to large firms, rather than independent innovators, and this gap only widened into the 1950s. The industrial lab had become king.</span></p>
<h3>Why labs work well</h3>
<p><span>The question of why the industrial lab works is a microcosm of the question of why the firm works in general. Economist Ronald Coase, who won the Nobel Prize in 1991 (and who lived to be 102) bookended the most productive period of his career with two insights about transaction costs. The first, published in 1937 and entitled </span><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1468-0335.1937.tb00002.x"><span>“The Nature of the Firm”</span></a><span>, tells us why firms exist. In economics, situations are typically approached from the perspective of competitive behaviour in open markets. Most of the things we buy are from open, competitive markets like these. But when we sell our labour, we are usually bound to a single “buyer”—our employer—for an extended period of time for everything we have to offer. If market competition is so efficient, why do we not set up mini-firms for every instance of cooperative work and receive pay in line with our output? Why do we instead generally sell a promise to do whatever our boss says within limits for certain hours of the day for months or years in advance?</span></p>
<p><span>The other, </span><a href="https://www.law.uchicago.edu/files/file/coase-problem.pdf"><span>“The Problem of Social Cost”</span></a><span>, reads like a reflection of the first. Published in 1960, it spawned the so-called Coase Theorem, which holds that so long as transaction costs—the costs of interacting with other individuals or institutions, such as the costs of drawing up and enforcing a contract—are low, people will contract to deal with the problems emerging from positive and negative externalities, like the benefits of a new park to a neighbourhood or the costs of pollution. Where transaction costs are too high, institutions and policies are needed to deal with the externalities instead.</span></p>
<p><span>Coase answers the question of why businesses exist as he answers the question of why people simply don’t contract away all externalities: transaction costs. If there is a cost on both sides every time one person wants to pay another for a task, then some tasks will not be worth paying for, or worth doing at the going rate. Concretely: an employer who does not negotiate contracts for each and every individual work unit can afford to offer higher wages, and an employee who does not do so can afford to accept lower wages. Companies organized in this way thus outcompete pure market organization—in cases where transaction costs are large.</span></p>
<p><span>In many ways, this general story for why firms exist also explains why large firm R&amp;D labs were so successful. The transaction costs of collaboration are extremely large, and prevent all sorts of potentially-valuable crossovers: not just the financial costs of contracting with others, but the costs of finding people you work well with, of corresponding and collaborating with people far from you, and so on. University lecturers collaborate more with those in their department than in other departments, and more with those in their university or city than elsewhere, despite all the tools and technologies the internet has brought. Chance meetings are another driver of serendipitous discovery and unexpected but fruitful collaborations.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span>What’s more, without great efforts in ‘translation’, many scientific ideas can be completely disconnected from practical applications. A research lab brings an array of scientific experts together from different disciplines, for collaboration and drawing on expertise at low cost. Fellow researchers bump into one another. And the firm context means the potential impact in terms of usable products is always taken into account.</span></p>
<h3>The DARPA Era</h3>
<p><span>The era of the R&amp;D lab has one particularly legendary story and paradigmatic example: PARC. Xerox’s Palo Alto Research Centre—the location in Palo Alto, now the home of companies like Tesla, Palantir, and Google, is no coincidence—developed many of the foundational building blocks of today’s technology and economy. In the 1970s, PARC researchers built the first computer with a graphical user interface, the first laser printer, the first Ethernet cable, and the first user-friendly word processor. Steve Jobs visited PARC in 1979, aged 24, and incorporated many of the ideas into Apple products. Charles Simonyi, a key developer at PARC, moved to Microsoft, where he developed the Office suite. But Xerox itself, which is still largely known for making photocopiers, did not capitalise on these inventions.</span></p>
<p><span>PARC, in turn, had hired many of its workers from Augmentation Research Centre, a publicly-funded project which pioneered the computer mouse, hyperlinks, the earliest predecessor to the internet, and many smaller innovations we take for granted in today’s computer ecosystem. ARC was funded by ARPA, the Advanced Research Projects Agency, now DARPA. Though DARPA (then ARPA) is funded by the US Department of Defence, it shares many elements with golden era R&amp;D labs. They are organised around a mission and a goal—even the most basic research is done with an end in mind—but researchers are given a lot of freedom to make their own decisions.</span></p>
<h3>A return to the market for ideas</h3>
<p><span>The scale of the change since the 1970s is huge—big businesses have retreated from research. In the 1960s, DuPont, the chemicals giant, published more in the </span><i><span>Journals of the American Chemical Society</span></i><span> than both MIT and Caltech combined. R&amp;D magazine, which awards the R&amp;D 100 to the hundred innovations it judges most innovative in a given four year period, gave 41% of its awards to Fortune 500 companies in its 1971 iteration and 47% in 1975. By 2006, 6% of the awards were going to firms in the Fortune 500. The great majority of these awards are now being won by federal labs, university teams, and spin-offs from academia. The lone inventor is back.</span></p>
<p><span>This is reflected by declines in the shares of patents going to the biggest businesses, and in the shares of scientists working there. In 1971 just over seven per cent of scientists in industry tracked by the US National Science Foundation worked in firms with under 1,000 employees; by 2004 this was 32%. In 2003 around a quarter worked at firms with fewer than ten employees. Even pharmaceuticals, the one area where large internal research labs are still significant, has been affected—around half of the drugs approved so far in the 2010s were originally discovered by small biotech startups.</span></p>
<p><span>In general, participation by large American firms in …</span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-rise-and-fall-of-the-american-rd-lab/">https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-rise-and-fall-of-the-american-rd-lab/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-rise-and-fall-of-the-american-rd-lab/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24321799</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 06:40:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Exploring mullender.c – A deep dive into the first IOCCC winner]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 110 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24321403">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | https://lainsystems.com/posts/exploring-mullender-dot-c/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lainsystems.com/posts/exploring-mullender-dot-c/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div>
        <ul>
<li>Table of Contents
<ul>
<li><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li>
<li><a href="#mullenderc">Mullender.c</a></li>
<li><a href="#running-the-thing-on-a-pdp-11">Running the thing on a PDP-11</a></li>
<li><a href="#examining-the-pdp-11-code">Examining the PDP-11 code</a></li>
<li><a href="#the-meat-of-the-code">The meat of the code</a></li>
<li><a href="#where-is-the-string">Where is the string?</a></li>
<li><a href="#looking-at-the-vax-code">Looking at the VAX code</a></li>
<li><a href="#how-the-program-happened-in-sjoerds-own-words">How the program happened in Sjoerd’s own words</a></li>
<li><a href="#the-original-source">The Original Source</a></li>
<li><a href="#extra-bits">Extra bits</a></li>
<li><a href="#documents-and-websites-i-used">Documents and Websites I used</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

<p>A few years ago I wrote <a href="https://medium.com/@LainIwakura/deobfuscating-obfuscated-code-for-fun-and-no-profit-36ec615c8f5d">two</a> <a href="https://medium.com/@LainIwakura/deobfuscating-code-for-fun-and-no-profit-round-2-60d78b67ebce">posts</a>
on medium.com explaining the workings of some obfuscated programs. After these posts other stuff took priority and I forgot about the world of obfuscation for a while. Now though, I find myself returning to it.
For reasons I’ll explain in a different post I find studying obfuscated code to be quite valuable. So, I thought to myself ‘Well, those last programs I examined were honestly pretty simple. What would it be like to research a truly obfuscated program?’</p>
<p>This post is the story of that journey. I will discuss the code, how I got such old and obscure code to run, as well as include snippets from my conversations with
one of the original authors (who was very helpful in figuring some of this out). If all that wasn’t enough I managed to obtain the original PDP and VAX source code, it will be hosted here with permission. I want to give a huge thank you to Sjoerd Mullender and Don Libes for their assistance and permission in reproducing some of this material.</p>

<p>Because older obfuscated programs tend to be easier to dissect I decided to stay in the early years of the IOCCC (International Obfuscated C Code Contest).
Among those early programs one sticks out as truly interesting - and that is the first IOCCC winner <a href="https://www.ioccc.org/1984/mullender/mullender.c">mullender.c</a>, which I’ve also replicated below because it’s quite short.



  </p><div>
    <p>
    <label for="187453296">
      <span>c</span>
      <span>mullender.c</span>
      <span data-label-expand="△" data-label-collapse="▽"></span>
    </label></p><pre><code>
  short main[] = {
	  277, 04735, -4129, 25, 0, 477, 1019, 0xbef, 0, 12800,
	  -113, 21119, 0x52d7, -1006, -7151, 0, 0x4bc, 020004,
	  14880, 10541, 2056, 04010, 4548, 3044, -6716, 0x9,
	  4407, 6, 5568, 1, -30460, 0, 0x9, 5570, 512, -30419,
	  0x7e82, 0760, 6, 0, 4, 02400, 15, 0, 4, 1280, 4, 0,
	  4, 0, 0, 0, 0x8, 0, 4, 0, ',', 0, 12, 0, 4, 0, '#',
	  0, 020, 0, 4, 0, 30, 0, 026, 0, 0x6176, 120, 25712,
	  'p', 072163, 'r', 29303, 29801, 'e'
  };
</code></pre>
  </div>


<p>Where do you start with a program like this? Well, the <a href="https://www.ioccc.org/1984/mullender/hint.text">hint</a> provided by the IOCCC is always a good first step.
From this hint, we can learn a few things necessary to understanding how the program works:</p>
<ul>
<li>Perhaps most importantly, this program will only run on a PDP-11 or VAX-11.</li>
<li>The C startup routine - provided by crt0.o - transfers control to a location named ‘main’ - usually intended to be a function, but in this case it’s an array of shorts</li>
<li>These shorts (represented in different formats to enhance obfuscation) form a meaningful set of PDP-11 and VAX-11 instructions</li>
<li>The first instruction is a branch to the PDP code, and due to the way VAX calls the main ‘function’ it skips the first word of the program (I’ll discuss this more later).</li>
<li>The program prints a string</li>
</ul>
<p>Essentially, the program is a bunch of machine code instructions encoded in various formats. It runs because this code predates ANSI C by a half decade and old compilers seem to have had significantly less qualms about
‘main’ being a function or not (I tried to define ‘main’ as an array of shorts with a modern compiler and it did not like that one bit).</p>

<p>I admit it, the PDP-11 was before my time. I grew up in the Windows 95/98/2000 era, and until recently I didn’t even know what a PDP-11 was.
This ignorance left me kind of stuck, and a brief look on eBay confirmed that I was not going to get a working PDP-11 any time soon. Fortunately though,
an emulator exists. Enter <a href="http://simh.trailing-edge.com/">SimH</a>, it’s more of a suite of emulators for a wide range of historical computers - of which the
PDP-11 is one, and lucky for us the VAX-11 is another.</p>
<p>After a few false starts and misadventures with 2.11BSD, I realized I had no idea what I was doing so I decided I needed some help.
The two original authors of this program are Robbert van Renesse and Sjoerd Mullender, why not try to contact them? So I did.
Robbert didn’t answer my e-mail, but luckily Sjoerd got back to me and was happy to discuss the program. He told me that the
PDP-11 OS they used was Unix v7, so I proceeded on that route.</p>
<p>I managed to <a href="http://a.papnet.eu/UNIX/v7/Installation">find a guide</a> on installing Unix v7 onto this emulator that worked;
and now with my emulator running, and OS installed, I could slap it into a file, compile, and run the thing. Below is what I got.</p>

<figure>
	<img src="https://lainsystems.com/img/running_on_pdp11.gif">
	
		<figcaption>Running the program on the PDP-11 using Unix v7</figcaption>
	
</figure>


<p>The animation is a little choppy, but even still you can hopefully see that it is printing “:-)” across the screen until it is forced to exit (there is no clean way to stop it).</p>
<p>In my discussions with Sjoerd, it was revealed that the string it prints is not exactly “:-)” but instead "  :-)\b\b\b\b”
(NOTE: there should be 2 space characters at the start but my templating engine is removing one for some reason).
It is exactly 9 bytes long. The first 2 characters are whitespace, followed by the :-), finally followed by four ‘\b’
characters. The ‘\b’ characters indicate a backspace. What does the backspace accomplish? Well, if you count 4 characters back from when they begin you’ll see we’re left with a single space - it is at this point
that the program loops and prints the string again. This happens quickly enough that to our eyes it looks like the “:-)” is scrolling across the screen - a clever effect.</p>

<p>As it turns out, the C code is not very useful to examine directly. As it also turns out, the assembly isn’t much better. Below is a small sample of what the assembly looks like (from the PDP-11’s perspective):</p>
<pre><code>    .text
    .globl  _main
    .data
    .even
_main:
    .word   0425 
    .word   04735
    .word   -010041
    .word   031
    .word   0
    .word   0735
    .word   01773
    .word   05757
</code></pre><p>So, what to do? Well, you can actually set up a cross compiler for the PDP-11 and if you go through that effort you can use the objdump program targeted at PDP-11 binaries.</p>
<p>Below is the relevant portion of the objdump - the whole thing is <a href="https://lainsystems.com/mull_objdump.txt">here</a>, but not all of it is useful. Sjoerd confirmed that the PDP code is
from _main+0x2c to _main+0x4a (inclusive). Of course, the first word is also a PDP-11 instruction. Everything I’ve ommitted is related to the VAX portion of
the program which we will get back to. (It’s also not proper VAX code since the disassembler thinks everything is PDP-11).</p>
<pre><code>   0:   0115            br  0x2c
  2c:   11c4            mov pc, r4
  2e:   0be4            tst -(r4)
  30:   e5c4 0009       sub $11, r4
  34:   1137 0006       mov r4, $0x3e
  38:   15c0 0001       mov $1, r0
  3c:   8904            sys 4
  3e:   0000            halt
  40:   0009            .word   11
  42:   15c2 0200       mov $1000, r2
  46:   892d            sys 55
  48:   7e82            sob r2, 0x46
  4a:   01f0            br  0x2c
</code></pre><p>Before going further there are 2 important things to know about PDP-11 assembly code:</p>
<ul>
<li>The PDP-11 works primarily with octal. All the addresses and instructions are encoded in octal.</li>
<li>In an instruction like <code>mov pc, r4</code>, you are moving pc INTO r4, not r4 into pc. Personally, I got used to this pretty quickly.</li>
</ul>
<p>The first number in the original program is 277, put that into a hex converter and you’ll get 115 like we see in the objdump. More interesting though is what you get translating it into octal - 425.
How does 0425 get you br 0x2c though? Well for that you need to grab some <em>manuals</em>. I got my hands on a lot of old manuals for these computers but the most useful one was the PDP-11/45 Handbook from 1973.
It would helpfully describe the instruction format, and exactly what it did. Below is an example of the page for the unconditional branch instruction.</p>

<figure>
	<img src="https://lainsystems.com/img/pdp11-branch.png">
	
		<figcaption>PDP-11/45 Handbook Describing the Branch instruction</figcaption>
	
</figure>


<p>As you can see, it sets the program counter to pc + 2x the offset - which is 25 (octal) in our case. Since the program counter at the start of our program is 2 (because it points to the next word to execute),
we get 2 + (25 x 2), or 2 + 52 = 54, which translating back into hex gives us 2c. Cool!</p>

<p>Now that we know how the branch works we can examine the main stuff - I won’t go into huge depth with the manuals for each little instruction but doing so is fun if you’re bored and enjoy that sort of thing.</p>
<p>The next relevant portion of code is this:</p>
<pre><code>  mov pc, r4
  tst -(r4)
  sub $11, r4
  mov r4, $0x3e
  mov $1, r0
  sys 4
  halt
  .word   11
</code></pre><p>We move the program counter into the r4 register and then use the ‘test’ (tst) instruction. This has the effect of clearing the some flags in the PSW (processor status word), and because
the register is using ‘Autodecrement mode’ it will subtract 2 from the value stored at r4. When using autoincrement / decrement, it will go by 1 in byte instructions or 2 in word instructions.
After this we subtract 11 from r4, but 11 is actually 9 (used to octal yet?). Then we store r4 into…0x3e? Well, if you look back at the objdump you’ll see that 0x3e is ‘halt’ or 0000. This
mov instruction overwrites that value with the contents of r4. We move 1 into r0 (1 indicating STDOUT), and call ‘sys 4’. The next line will be the value of r4 as just mentioned, and <code>.word 11</code>
simply inserts octal 11 directly into that spot. If you’re wondering what exactly is in r4 and why we’re doing all this stuff, be patient - we’re getting there.</p>
<p>If you’re familiar with system calls, you probably know what’s going on. If not, all of this is to setup the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Write_(system_call)">write</a> system call. I
actually made a <a href="https://retrocomputing.stackexchange.com/questions/15590/trying-to-understand-some-assembly-syntax-in-the-unix-v7-write-system-call">post on the retro-computing stackexchange</a>
asking about the workings of this call internally - I recommend checking it out if you want further clarity on how this works.</p>
<p>After this we have the final 3 lines of PDP code which are:</p>
<pre><code>  mov $1000, r2
  sys 55
  sob r2, 0x46
</code></pre><p>We put 1000 into r2, and call system call 55. After this, we use the ‘sob’ instruction - which is ‘subtract one and branch’ and not an invitation to cry - to see if r2 is 0 yet. If it isn’t, we branch
to the previous line and call system call 55 again. loop until r2 is 0. Syscall 55 eh? Which …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://lainsystems.com/posts/exploring-mullender-dot-c/">https://lainsystems.com/posts/exploring-mullender-dot-c/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lainsystems.com/posts/exploring-mullender-dot-c/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24321403</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 04:37:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Longevity FAQ: A beginner's guide to longevity research]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 90 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24320846">thread link</a>) | @apsec112
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | https://www.ldeming.com/longevityfaq | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ldeming.com/longevityfaq">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Senescent cell removal</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">135%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Does not affect rotarod performance, object discrimination. Slight delay in wound closure.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">1</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Rapamycin</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">110%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2009</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Late-life rapamyicn treatment extends lifespan (pooled females from multiple-site NIA study)</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">2</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">NR</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">105%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Claim an increase in running distance</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">3</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Catalase</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">117%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2005</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Mitochondrially-targeted catalase expression extended mouse lifespan compared to control</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">4</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Sirt6 overexpression</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">115%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2012</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Sirt6-overexpression increases male mouse lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">5</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Metformin</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">106%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">In males, small but significant lifespan extension after metformin application</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">6</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">DN-IκBα</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">110%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Dominant negative to downregulate IKK-beta activity, delivered to hypothalamus of middle-aged mice</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">7</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Klotho</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">120%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2005</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Overexpression under human elongation factor 1α promoter increases lifespan, slight fertility loss</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">8</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">S6K1</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">118%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2009</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">KO of S6K1 extends lifspan compared to wildtype mice</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">9</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">p66</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">128%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">1999</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Mutation of a p66shc, member of proto-oncogene locus SHC, extends lifespan. May be just due to cancer effect.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">10</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Lowering protein:carbohydrate ratio</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">128%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2014</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Varied protein, carbohydrate, and total energy levels.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">11</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Fat-specific insulin receptor knockout mice</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">111%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2003</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Fat-specific insulin receptor knockout mice show a significant increase in lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">12</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">C57BL/6 mice with NZB/OlaHsd mitochondrial mutations</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">120%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Same nuclear, different mitochondrial DNA.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">13</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Fasting mimicking diet</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">112%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2015</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">FMD followed by 10 days of normal, then repeat</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">14</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Rapamycin</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">127%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2014</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Rapamycin from 9 months of age, weight decreased ~30% at highest dose</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">15</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Brain-specific Sirt1 expression</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">116%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Brain-specific Sirt1 expression in female mice increases lifespan over wildtype</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">16</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">SRT1720</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">104%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2014</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Start diet at 28 weeks of age, very small increase on lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">17</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Spermidine</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">111%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Polyamine, administered in drinking water</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">18</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Atg5 overexpression</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">117%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Transgenic mice ubiquitously expressing Atg5 (crucial for autophagasome confirmation) live longer.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">19</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Telomerase</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">124%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2012</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Paper showing telomerase therapy increasing life</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">20</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Insulin receptor substrate null</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">132%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2008</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Insulin receptor substrate 1 null mouse lifespan extension in females</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">21</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Snell Dwarf Mice</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">142%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2001</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Snell dwarf mouse paper showing life extension</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">22</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Ames Dwarf Mice</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">168%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">1996</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Original Ames dwarf mouse paper showing life extension</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">23</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">s-Arf/p53</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">113%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2007</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">An extra copy of p53 and upstream regulator Arf/p16Ink4a increases lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">24</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Slow growth during lactation</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">106%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2004</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Male mice suckled by dams fed a low-protein diet lived longer than their control cohort</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">25</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Methionine restriction</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">111%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2005</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Methionine restriction increases mouse lifespan, here median lifespan increase in mice that survived at least 1 yr.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">26</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Rapamycin (3 months)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">114%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Lifespan given from time of treatment which was 23-24 mo, used 24 mo to get percentage so this is an estimate</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">27</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">GHR-BP</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">138%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2000</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Mice deficient in growth hormone receptor / binding protein live longer (female mean, not median, lifespan shown here)</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">28</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">mTOR</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">116%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">mTOR depletion extends lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">29</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">PTEN overexpression</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">112%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2012</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Overexpression of PTEN, a tumor suppressor which counteracts PI3K, extends mouse lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">30</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Myc (+/-)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">121%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2015</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Claim no correlation between weight and lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">31</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">FGF-21</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">139%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2012</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Hepatic-specific expression of FGF-21 (which suppresses growth hormone and reduces the production of IGF) increases lifespan, female lifespan shown here</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">32</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">BubR1 overexpression</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">114%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2012</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Kinase which localizes to kinetochore, overexpression increases lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">33</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">AC5 KO</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">132%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2007</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">AC5 knockount mice lived longer than control, potentially linked to effects on cAMP production and beta-adrenergic receptor signaling.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">34</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">17-alpha-estradiol</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">112%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">17-alpha-estradiol extended lifespan in males, but not females (as expected)</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">35</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Acarbose</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">122%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Acarbose extended male more than female lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">36</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">TRPV1 -/-</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">114%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2014</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Resting exchange ratio similar at 16 mo to 3 mo</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">37</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">SRT2104</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">106%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2014</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Start diet at 28 weeks of age, very small increase if there</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">38</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Hcrt-UCP2</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">128%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2006</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">UCP2 under hypocretin promoter lowers core body temp, increases lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">39</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">G6PD overexpression</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">114%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Reduces NADP+</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">40</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">IGF-1 Receptor Brain KO (+/-)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">109%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2008</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Brain-specific IGF-1 Receptor +/- mice live longer than WT</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">41</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">SURF-1 KO</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">121%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2007</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Mutations in SURF1, a cytochrome c oxidase assembly factor, extend lifespan. Mitochondrial.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">42</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Litter enlargemnet (CR)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">118%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2009</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">50% enlargement of litter in first 20 days, to induce caloric restriction</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">43</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">mclk-1 heterozygous</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">115%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2005</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">A heterozygous knockout of mclk1 (important in mitochondrial respiration) results in mouse lifespan extension compared to wildtype</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">44</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Nordihydroguairaitic acid</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">112%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2008</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">NDGA and aspirin extend lifespan by a little bit. Small molecule.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">45</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Aspirin</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">108%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2008</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">NDGA and aspirin extend lifespan by a little bit. Small molecule.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">46</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">SOD mimetic carboxyfullerene</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">115%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2008</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Carboxyfullerene, described as an SOD mimetic, increased the lifespan of treated mice compared to wildtype control</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">47</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Removal of visceral fat tissue</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">108%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2008</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Removal of visceral fat tissue increases lifespan over control</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">48</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Low glycotoxin diet</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">112%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2007</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Low glycotoxin (low levels of AGE's) shown to extend lifespan</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">49</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Per2 (-/-)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">118%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Lifespan study incomplete</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">50</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Neonatal metformin</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">120%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2015</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Animals recieved on 3, 5, 7th day after birth - bad for females, good for males.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">51</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">GHRH KO</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">146%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">GHRH (Growth-Hormone Releasing Hormone) disruption extends lifespan, presumably through the insulin/IGF pathway axis</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">52</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Sod-2 overexpresion</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">104%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2007</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Overexpression of SOD-2 targeted to the mitochondrion increases mouse lifespan relative to wildtype</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">53</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Metallothionein cardiac-specific expression</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">114%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2006</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Cardiac-specific expression of antioxidant metallothionein extended the lifespan of wildtype mice compared to WT FVB control.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">54</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">IGF1R(+/-)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">121%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Tyrosine kinase receptor activated by IGF1/2</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">55</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Ink4a/Arf/Ink4b</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">116%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2009</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Encodes 2 CDKs (p16 and p15), and Arf (upstream of p53)</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">56</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Adult-onset Ghr (-/-)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">100%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2016</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Male mice have &gt;2x higher insulin than female mice</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">57</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Ovary Transplantation</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">117%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2003</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Original paper showing that transplantation of young ovaries into old animals could result in lifespan increase</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">58</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">UCP-1 transgenic</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">111%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2007</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Transgenic mice with skeletal muscle-specific UCP1 had increased longevity. Small increase if there.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">59</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">PAPP</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">131%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2010</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Knockout of PAPP-A (which enhances IGF-1 activity by degrading the inhibitory IGF-binding protein) increases lifespan over wildtype, female lifespan shown here</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">60</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">CR diet with lard</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">132%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2015</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">40% decrease starting at 4 months</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">61</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">loss of function of Riib (PKA subunit)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">114%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2009</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Knockout of RIIbeta, a subunit of PKA, increased lifespan in mice compared to wildtype</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">62</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Myostatin (+/-)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">109%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2015</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Knockout induces double-muscle mice</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">63</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Akt1 +/-</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">113%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2013</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Haploinsufficiency of Akt1 increases mouse lifespan relative to wildtype. Insulin/IGF-1 pathway.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">64</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">miR-17</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">117%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2014</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Not clear if there is a main function for miR-17</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">65</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">NDGA</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">111%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2015</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Makes up ~12.5% of the dry weight of leaves</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">66</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">FAT10ko</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">119%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2014</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Ubiquitin-like protein which can signal for protein to go to proteasome.</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">67</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">Intranasal Hsp70</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">116%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2015</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Seemed to extend lifespan when started at 17 months</td>
					<td data-title="Reference">68</td>
				</tr>
			

				<tr>
					<td data-title="Intervention">RasGRF1(-/-)</td>
					<td data-title="Median lifespan increase (treated/control)">120%</td>
					<td data-title="Year Published">2011</td>
					<td data-title="Notes">Ras-guanine nucleotide exchange factor …</td></tr></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.ldeming.com/longevityfaq">https://www.ldeming.com/longevityfaq</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ldeming.com/longevityfaq</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24320846</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 02:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Deep Dive into PHP 8's JIT]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 86 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24320024">thread link</a>) | @nawarian
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | https://thephp.website/en/issue/php-8-jit/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thephp.website/en/issue/php-8-jit/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<div>
<p><time datetime="2020-03-03">
2020-03-03
</time></p>
<p><a href="https://thephp.website/br/edicao/php-8-jit">Leia em Português</a></p>
<p>PHP has a Just In Time compiler (JIT) since its most recent major version, PHP 8.</p>
<p>Here's a demo of JIT's impact on PHP. The video was recorded by Zeev, a core
developer of the php engine, to demonstrate the performance difference between
php 7.0 and JIT when generating fractals.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dWH65pmnsrI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""><iframe style="margin: auto; margin-bottom: 20px;" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/dWH65pmnsrI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>It is fair to expect great performance improvements after watching this video,
especially if you remember the amazing boost when migrating from php 5 to 7.
But soon you'll notice that such gains aren't for most applications (unless
you do fractals for a living 🤷🏻‍♀️).</p>
<p>So before you get too hyped or too disappointed about JIT, let me explain what
this thing is and how you can get the most out of it.</p>
<h2>What is a Just In Time compiled language and why do we need it?</h2>
<p>Let me introduce you to compilation first, I believe we will need it.</p>
<p>CPUs can't read english, you already know that. They can kind of read a series
of bits and bytes which represent addresses, values, instructions... But guess
who can't code this? That's right, us! (At least I can't 👀 (I kind of can, but... no.))</p>
<p>A solution to this problem is to translate something we, humans, can write into
something CPUs can execute. This translation can be called "compilation". So
<strong>compilation is a translation of human-readable code to machine code.</strong>
Simple, oder?</p>
<p>Translating human-readable code to machine code can happen in three different
ways: Ahead Of Time (AOT) compilation, Just In Time (JIT) compilation or, our
favorite, interpretation (or Implicit Compilation).</p>
<p><strong>Languages like C, C++ or Rust are AOT-compiled languages.</strong> You write the code,
you compile it and the output is a binary object that a CPU immediately understands
how to execute. It is called Ahead Of Time because you compile the binary object
BEFORE you run it.</p>
<p><strong>Languages like PHP, Java or JavaScript are interpreted.</strong> A code written in such
languages will be translated into an intermediate representation and another
program (a compiled one) will understand and execute such intermediate
representation. It is very common to call such programs "Virtual Machines" or
"Interpreters".</p>
<p><strong>Normally interpreted languages have less performance and freedom when compared
with AOT-compiled languages</strong> because things like memory management, CPU-targeted
instructions and funky low-level tricks are not available to the user space. So
another program (the interpreter) has to manage all of this plus be polyglot
enough to talk to different kinds of processors and operating systems.</p>
<p><strong>Languages like Java, LUA and now PHP are not only interpreted but also Just
In Time compiled!</strong> They still need a VM, but their VMs are capable of compiling
this intermediate representation of code into binary objects in runtime. These
JIT-capable VMs operate in a hybrid mode where code is partially compiled and interpreted.</p>
<p>When JIT kicks in, parts of your php code will be compiled into machine code so the
Zend VM (php's virtual machine) won't interpret these parts anymore. Your php
code will talk directly to the CPU.</p>
<p>So why can't we just compile everything, then? If the VM is a bottleneck, why
bother to run through it in the first place? We could just compile our php code
into machine code and be happy about it.</p>
<p>Well, we'd have to compile to specific CPU architectures, be prepared to talk to
different operating systems, be extremely clear about our variable types and
perform way more bare-metal operations than we should if we want to be productive.
There are decent abstractions for Golang and Rust, for example, but they aren't
very practical and require control over the environment they're deployed against.</p>
<p><strong>Interpreted languages, on the other hand, can be easily deployed to different
servers, allow rapid development and create room for dynamic typing systems.</strong></p>
<p>Just In Time compilation is potentially the best of the two worlds, combining
good speed and developer experience.</p>
<p>Dynamic typing, as you know, is one of the core features of PHP. It is very
complex and is tattooed into php's core in a way that removing the dynamic
typing is almost unthinkable.
<a href="https://thephp.website/en/issue/php-type-system/">Here’s a great summary on how php’s type system works.</a></p>
<p>And because of Dynamic Typing (and some other things you'll learn about below)
the Just In Time compiler present in PHP is not yielding big performance gains.
At least not yet.</p>
<p>Curious why? Keep reading!</p>
<h2>Let's see how PHP works with and without JIT</h2>
<p>In PHP there are three steps before executing your code: <strong>tokenizing</strong>,
<strong>parsing</strong> into an AST and <strong>compiling</strong> to an intermediate representation
known as <strong>Opcode</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Tokenizing (or Lexing) is the process of reading php code and splitting
it into understandable units called tokens.</strong> <code>&lt;?php</code> becomes a _T_OPEN<em>TAG</em>,
<code>echo</code> becomes a _T<em>ECHO</em> and <code>"Hello, friend"</code> becomes T_CONSTANT_ENCAPSED_STRING.
<a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/tokens.php">A complete list of PHP's tokens can be found here.</a></p>
<p>Parsing is the process of making sense out of such tokens. In PHP parsed tokens
are organized in a tree structure named AST (Abstract syntax tree).
The AST's job is to represent what operations should be. In <code>echo 1+1</code> the interpreter
should in fact understand <code>print the result of the expression 1+1</code>. Such tree would
look something like the following:</p>
<pre><code>operation =&gt; ECHO,
operand =&gt; expression (
    operation =&gt; ADD,
    operand1 =&gt; 1,
    operand2 =&gt; 1
)</code></pre>
<p>PHP is then able to <strong>compile this tree into an intermediate representation
called Opcode.</strong></p>
<p>The Opcode is what is actually executed by the virtual machine, so executing
is the final step. Here's a diagram illustrating how this process looks like.</p>
<figure>
<a href="https://thephp.website/assets/images/posts/10-php-8-jit/zendvm-no-opcache.png" target="_blank">
<img src="https://thephp.website/assets/images/posts/10-php-8-jit/zendvm-no-opcache.png" alt="The PHP's interpreting flow.">
</a>
<figcaption>A simplified overview on PHP's interpreting flow.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>You probably realized that tokenizing, parsing and compiling code every single time
can be a big bottleneck. PHP engineers thought so too and that's why the
Opcache extension exists. Let's have a quick look at it.</p>
<h2>The Opcache extension</h2>
<p>The Opcache extension is shipped with PHP and generally there's no big reason to
deactivate it. If you use PHP, you should probably have Opcache switched on.</p>
<p>It adds an in-memory shared cache layer to store Opcodes. So tokenizing, parsing
and compiling will happen once for each file and will be shared with every request.</p>
<p>With Opcache extension enabled, the execution of PHP code looks like in the following
diagram:</p>
<figure>
<a href="https://thephp.website/assets/images/posts/10-php-8-jit/zendvm-opcache.png" target="_blank">
<img src="https://thephp.website/assets/images/posts/10-php-8-jit/zendvm-opcache.png" alt="The PHP's interpreting flow with Opcache">
</a>
<figcaption>The PHP's interpreting flow with Opcache. If a file was already parsed, php fetches the cached Opcodes for it instead of parsing all over again.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Side note:</strong> this is where <a href="https://wiki.php.net/rfc/preload">PHP 7.4's preloading feature</a>
shines! It allows you to tell PHP FPM to parse your codebase, transform it into
Opcodes and cache them even before you execute anything.</p>
<h2>Enters the Just In Time compilation</h2>
<p>While the Opcache extension will prevent PHP from tokenizing, parsing and compiling
over and over again, the Just In Time compilation aims to skip the virtual machine's
Opcode interpretation and let it execute machine code directly.</p>
<p>PHP's JIT implementation uses a C library called
<a href="https://luajit.org/dynasm.html">DynASM (Dynamic Assembler)</a>
which maps a set of CPU instructions in one specific format into assembly code for
many different CPU types. So the Just In Time compiler transforms Opcodes into an
architecture-specific machine code using DynASM.</p>
<p>The compilation happens between fetching Opcodes from cache and executing them.
Since compiling Opcode into machine code can be very expensive, PHP has to decide
which portions of your code might make sense to be compiled or not.</p>
<p><strong>PHP then profiles Opcodes being executed by the Zend VM and checks which ones
might make sense to compile. (based on your configuration)</strong></p>
<p>When an Opcode is compiled its execution doesn't happen through the Zend VM handlers,
they are directly executed by the CPU.</p>
<figure>
<a href="https://thephp.website/assets/images/posts/10-php-8-jit/zendvm-opcache-jit.png" target="_blank">
<img src="https://thephp.website/assets/images/posts/10-php-8-jit/zendvm-opcache-jit.png" alt="The PHP's interpreting flow with JIT">
</a>
<figcaption>The PHP's interpreting flow with JIT. If compiled, Opcodes don't execute through the Zend VM.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>When an Opcode should be compiled is decided based on your INI configurations. You'll
get more details in the next section.</p>
<h2>JIT Configuration</h2>
<p>Configuring JIT in PHP is very simple, there are two INI directives we need to set:
<code>opcache.jit_buffer_size</code> and <code>opcache.jit</code>. The first indicates how much memory
we're willing to allocate for compiled code, while the later one dictates how JIT
should behave.</p>
<p>There's also an optional directive named <code>opcache.jit_debug</code> for debugging purposes.
I will not cover this one here.</p>
<p>For example, the snippet below indicates that we're willing to give up to 100 Megabytes
of compiled code, enabling AVX instruction generation, using a global linear-scan register
allocator, profiling each request and jitting hot functions, optimizing the compiled
code based on static type inference. (👀 WUT?)</p>
<pre><code>opcache.jit_buffer_size=100M
opcache.jit=1235</code></pre>
<p>To make your life easier, I’m bringing some presets that
<a href="https://beberlei.de/2020/07/05/what_to_look_out_for_when_testing_php_jit.html">Benjamin Eberlei kindly shared in his blog</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>opcache.jit=1205</code> (JIT everything)</li>
<li><code>opcache.jit=1235</code> (JIT hot code based on relative usage)</li>
<li><code>opcache.jit=1255</code> (trace hot code for JITability, the best so far)</li>
</ul>
<p>The <code>opcache.jit</code> entry is a sequence of values named "CRTO", each character can have different
behavioural effect on your application. Below I explain what each of these letters can do:</p>
<p><strong>C - CPU-specific optimization</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Flag</th>
<th>Meaning</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>0</td>
<td>No optimization whatsoever</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Enable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Vector_Extensions">AVX instruction</a> generation</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>R - Register Allocation Modes</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Flag</th>
<th>Meaning</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>0</td>
<td>Never perform <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Register_allocation">register allocations</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Use local linear-scan register allocation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>Use global linear-scan register allocation</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>T - JIT trigger</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Flag</th>
<th>Meaning</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>0</td>
<td>JIT everything on first script load</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>JIT functions when they execute</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>Profile first request and compile hot functions on second requests</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>Profile and compile hot functions all the time</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Compile functions with a <code>@jit</code> in doc blocks</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>O - Optimization level</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Flag</th>
<th>Meaning</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>0</td>
<td>Never JIT</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Minimal JIT (use regular VM handlers)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>Selective VM handler inlining</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>Optimized JIT based on static type inference of individual function</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Optimized JIT based on static type inference and call tree</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>Optimized JIT based on static type inference and inner procedure analyses</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I don't fully understand every term there, but the main takeaway is that you should play
around with each flag and keep profiling …</p></iframe></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thephp.website/en/issue/php-8-jit/">https://thephp.website/en/issue/php-8-jit/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thephp.website/en/issue/php-8-jit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24320024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 23:00:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Inventing Monads]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 105 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24318244">thread link</a>) | @stopachka
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | https://stopa.io/post/247 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://stopa.io/post/247">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><span><p>I got into a discussion about monads recently. On a search to find some resources to share, I realized that most essays explained them with type signatures and rules. A missing ingredient to grok them, I think, is to understand the intuition behind them. How could you end up <em>inventing</em> monads?</p><p>Okay, let’s try to build that intuition. We’ll avoid both types and category theory.</p><p>Say you have a few functions to get a user, a profile, and a display picture:</p><pre><code>function getUser(id) { 
  return USERS[id] 
}

function getProfile(user) { 
  return user.profile
}

function getDisplayPicture(profile) { 
  return profile.displayPicture
}</code></pre><p>Now, given an id, how would you get the profile picture?</p><p>You could write this: </p><pre><code>getDisplayPicture(getProfile(getUser(id)))</code></pre><p>Buut, this would throw an error: all these functions <em>could</em> return null. If <code>getUser</code> returned null for example, you would see: </p><pre><code>Uncaught TypeError: Cannot read property 'profile' of undefined</code></pre><p>To fix this, you may end up writing something like this:</p><pre><code>function getDisplayPictureFromId(id) { 
  const user = getUser(id)
  if (!user) return
  const profile = getProfile(user)
  if (!profile) return
  return getDisplayPicture(profile)
}</code></pre><p>But, this is getting pretty ugly. All these conditional returns distract from what you’re really trying to do. <strong>What if there was a way to get rid of these conditionals?</strong></p><p>So, that’s our challenge: let’s get rid of these conditionals. One way we can do this, is to make some kind of helper. This helper would let us chain these functions together: </p><pre><code>new Chainer(getUser(id))
  .whenExists(user =&gt; getProfile(user))
  .whenExists(profile =&gt; getDisplayPicture(profile))</code></pre><p>This looks pretty good. Let’s implement it.</p><h2>whenExists</h2><p><code>.whenExists</code> would only run the callback if the value exists. Here’s how you could write this:</p><pre><code>class Chainer {
  constructor(v) { 
      this.value = v
  }
  whenExists(f) { 
      if (!this.value) return this;
      return new Chainer(f(this.value))
  }
}</code></pre><p>And voila, with just this, we can now write</p><pre><code>function getProfilePictureFromId(id) { 
  return new Chainer(getUser(id))
    .whenExists(user =&gt; getProfile(user))
    .whenExists(profile =&gt; getDisplayPicture(profile))
}</code></pre><h2>More Problems</h2><p>Notice that <code>getDisplayPictureFromId</code> now returns a <code>Chainer</code>. </p><p>Imagine we had another function <code>resizeDisplayPicture</code>, that <em>also</em> returned a Chainer</p><pre><code>function resizeDisplayPicture(pic) { 
    return new Chainer(pic).whenExists(pic =&gt; ...
}</code></pre><p>What would happen, if we wrote:</p><pre><code>getProfilePictureFromId(id).whenExists(pic =&gt; resizeDisplayPicture(pic))</code></pre><p>Let’s look at whenExists again:</p><pre><code>whenExists(f) { 
  if (!this.value) return this;
  return new Chainer(f(this.value))
}</code></pre><p>If <code>getProfilePictureFromId(id)</code> did exist, we would run </p><pre><code>new Chainer(f(this.value))</code></pre><p>which in this case is</p><pre><code>new Chainer(resizeDisplayPicture(this.value)) </code></pre><p>Which becomes </p><pre><code>new Chainer(new Chainer(this.value)...</code></pre><p><strong>Uh oh. We now have a Chainer inside of a Chainer.</strong> Ideally, we’d want a function that somehow “merged” these chainers together.</p><h2>whenExistsMerge</h2><p>So let’s do that. We can call it <code>whenExistsMerge</code></p><pre><code>class Chainer {
  constructor(v) { 
      this.value = v
  }
  whenExists(f) { 
      if (!this.value) return this;
      return new Chainer(f(this.value))
  }
  whenExistsMerge(f) { 
      if (!this.value) return this;
      return f(this.value)
  }
}</code></pre><p>And with that, we can write </p><pre><code>getProfilePictureFromId(id)
  .whenExistsMerge(pic =&gt; resizeDisplayPicture(pic))
  .whenExists(resizedPic =&gt; ...)</code></pre><p><strong>Aand voila, you’ve just invented a specific type of monad.</strong> Kind of (1). Chainer is analogous to the <code>Maybe</code> monad. <code>whenExists</code> is analogous to its <code>fmap</code> operation, and <code>whenExistsMerge</code> is analogous to its <code>bind</code> operation. If you’re curious about the type-based technicalities now, <a href="http://adit.io/posts/2013-04-17-functors,_applicatives,_and_monads_in_pictures.html" target="_blank">see this essay</a>. </p><p>So, now we’ve found this cool <code>Chainer</code>. We can stop here, or think a bit further. What’s so special about it? </p><p>Well, it’s like a box that wraps around some information. We can interact with that box with  <code>whenExists</code> and <code>whenExistsMerge</code>.</p><p>How else can we use the idea of <code>box</code> and <code>whenExists?</code></p><p>Here’s one. Let’s say you were dealing with callback hell: </p><pre><code>fetchUser(id, (err, user) =&gt; {
  if (err) ... 
    fetchProfile(profile, (err, profile) =&gt; { 
      if (err) ...
        fetchDisplayPicture(...
    }
}</code></pre><p>What if we created something like an <code>Async Chainer</code>: it stores the result of some future computation. Then, you could use the <code>whenExists*</code> functions, which let you interact with the value <em>when</em> it is computed. We turn the callback hell into</p><pre><code> fetchUser(id).whenExistsMerge(fetchProfile).whenExistsMerge(fetchDisplayPicture)</code></pre><p>Well, replace <code>whenExistsMerge</code> with <code>then</code>, and you're on a road to discover <code>Promise</code>, which is also a monad. Kind of (2). </p><p>Now, it’s pretty cool to notice that both the nullable use case and the async use case have the same interface. The name <code>whenExists</code> may be a bit too specific. Really, what it does is give you an interface to <code>map</code> over the value. If you use the word <code>map</code>, <code>whenExistsMerge</code> really lets you <code>flatMap</code> over the value. </p><p>This begins to get us to the fundamental abstraction of a monad: a box, with an interface for <code>map</code>, and <code>flatMap</code>. As you look deeper, you’ll notice that this abstraction can handle a lot of other things. If you’re curious, research the <code>Result</code> monad for example.</p><p>And with that, you’ve invented monads : ) </p><h2>Aside: Do you <em>really</em> need this?</h2><p>As you went through this, you may have realized that there are other ways to solve the problems that monads solve. Instead of <code>Chainer</code>, your language could have a <a href="https://kotlinlang.org/docs/reference/null-safety.html#safe-calls" target="_blank">safe call</a> abstraction. Instead of <code>Promise</code>, your language could have an <code>async/await</code> abstraction. Sometimes those can be a better <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YR5WdGrpoug" target="_blank">better choice</a>. Nevertheless, if your language doesn’t have those abstractions, you can use monads to solve them. And of course, like any powerful abstraction, you can invent new monads to simplify your business logic.</p><hr><p>(1) I cheated a bit with <code>Chainer</code>, by avoiding the subtypes <code>Just</code> and <code>Nothing</code>. This makes it so you can’t express something like <code>Just(null)</code>. Still, it gets at the essence : ) </p><p>(2) Likewise, <code>Promise</code> isn’t quite a monad, because it mixes both <code>flatMap</code> and <code>map</code> with <code>then</code>. This makes it so you can’t have a <code>Promise&lt;Promise&lt;Res&gt;&gt;</code>. Again though, it gets at the essence</p><p><em>Thanks to Joe Averbukh, Mark Shlick, Daniel Woelfel, Irakli Safareli, Jacky Wang for reviewing drafts of this essay</em></p></span></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://stopa.io/post/247</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24318244</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 18:22:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[She’s Got Game]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24316556">thread link</a>) | @woldemariam
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | https://restofworld.org/2020/you-just-got-pwned-habibi/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2020/you-just-got-pwned-habibi/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>In April 2012, three college juniors — Felwa, Tasnim, and Najla — waited anxiously on the campus of Prince Sultan University in Riyadh. For the previous six months, their lives had been consumed by the pursuit of a single, radical idea: frustrated that women, year after year, were barred from the annual Gamers’ Day convention, <a href="http://gamersday.com/en/about-us.php#:~:text=Gamers'%20Day%20is%20a%20gaming,numbers%20of%20visitors%20and%20exhibitors">the largest annual gaming convention in Saudi Arabia</a>, they had decided to launch the first-ever gamers’ convention for women in the kingdom. As the organizers hurried around counting consoles and hanging posters near stalls, they wondered whether anyone would show up.</p>



<p>Over the past decade, Saudi Arabia’s gaming scene has dramatically evolved, especially for women. In the early 2000s, the country had strict moral regulations on entertainment, and games were mostly sold in a gray market or through unofficial channels. Areej, a 23-year-old university graduate, picked up her interest in gaming from her father, who once frequented the informal neighborhood stores that sold pirated copies of popular games for 10 riyals ($2). “He played Japanese and English games, even though he didn’t even understand English back then,” she recalled. “He would keep dictionaries around while playing. That’s actually how he learned the language.” Areej hopes to become a “localizer,” a job that entails translating English-language games into Arabic. A decade ago, this wouldn’t have been possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After Sony’s 2007 release of the PlayStation 3 in the kingdom, the gaming industry began to take shape in Saudi Arabia. The first <a href="https://www.gamersday.com/en/">Gamers’ Day</a> took place in 2008, and it now draws upward of 60,000 male visitors over the course of four days. The convention presents video game companies with a lucrative opportunity to demo their latest equipment and products; devoted players, in turn, get to try out highly anticipated games that have not yet been released. In 2012, as the three girls were setting up Girls Con (or GCON as it would come to be known), the industry was estimated to have a global revenue stream of $70 billion.</p>



<p>In the months prior to GCON, Tasnim, the only one in the group with work experience, took the lead pitching sponsorship proposals to the all-male staffs at Nintendo and PlayStation Arabia. Without any real data on female gamers in the Middle East, and with barely any on girl gamers in North America, she had pitched on the assumption that the <a href="https://newzoo.com/insights/articles/male-and-female-gamers-how-their-similarities-and-differences-shape-the-games-market/">gender ratio for gamers in Saudi Arabia</a> was likely the same as in the United States: 47%. But there was no way to prove this. Until then, the world of female gaming in Saudi Arabia was a private one, usually set in the intimacy of people’s bedrooms.</p>



<p>“You could find girls who played video games, just for fun or on their mobile phone, but I had no idea how many girls were into hardcore gaming,” Felwa said. While mobile games like Angry Birds and Candy Crush were popular — the Kingdom boasts a <a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/xe/Documents/technology-media-telecommunications/GMCS-whitepaper.pdf">90% cell phone penetration rate</a> — Felwa was curious to see how many girls had grown up like her playing Tomb Raider, Tekken, and League of Legends.</p>



<p>When the hall flooded with nearly 3,000 women, some as young as 13 and others in their 50s, it was a shock. “I definitely did not expect moms to come,” Felwa said. Back then, it was mandatory for women to wear the traditional black abaya, and often a headscarf, while in public. It was only when the women walked through the doors into the all-female space that their abayas slipped off to reveal an array of cosplay costumes.</p>



<p>Inside the hallway, girls who were expected to behave discreetly at all times rushed around trying to play as many PlayStation- and Nintendo-sponsored games as they could. On one side of the hall, first-time cosplayers shared a rare opportunity to express their fandom. On the other, 150 people stood in a rowdy line waiting their turn in a Call of Duty tournament.</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ghada_AlMoqbel_25-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ghada_AlMoqbel_25-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ghada_AlMoqbel_25-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ghada_AlMoqbel_25-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ghada_AlMoqbel_25-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ghada_AlMoqbel_25-2800x1867.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, (max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>While the Middle</strong> <strong>East</strong> represents only a small portion of the international gaming industry, it is a rapidly expanding market. In 2017, the countries of the Gulf Cooperation Council accounted for around $693 million of gaming revenue, most related to esports. By 2021, that number is expected to exceed <a href="https://www.strategyand.pwc.com/m1/en/press-releases/2020/gcc-gaming-market.html">$821 million</a>, boosted in part by the pandemic-induced lockdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Saudi Arabia expects to be at the forefront<strong> </strong>of that expansion. In a country where roughly 50% of the population is under 30, gaming has become an emblem for a generation of young Saudis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In recent years, Prince Faisal bin Bandar, a young member of the royal family raised on Atari consoles, set out to make Saudi Arabia the Middle East’s hub for the $160 billion gaming industry. Under his leadership, the<strong> </strong><a href="https://safeis.sa/">Saudi Arabian Federation for Electronic and Intellectual Sports (SAFEIS)</a> aims for esports revenue to amount to 1% of the country’s GDP (approximately $22 billion) by 2030.</p>



<p>While Saudi Arabia was a late arrival to esports, its male players have already made their mark. Since 2017, Prince Faisal and the federation have been scouting, coaching, and sending professional esports players to competitions across the world. Mossad Al-Dossary, then 18, made headlines in 2018 after <a href="https://www.ea.com/games/fifa/news/msdossary-triumphs-fifa-eworld-cup-grand-final-london">winning first place</a> at the FIFA eWorld Cup in London, taking home a $250,000 cash prize.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Female gamers, however, are still finding their way. Women in Felwa, Tasnim, and Najla’s generation grew up under the watch of religious police, in a time when public spaces were segregated by gender. While women still do not have the same rights as men, Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman<strong> </strong>has relaxed male-guardianship rules and mandatory dress codes and legalized certain forms of entertainment for women. “I still struggle to convey what Saudi Arabia was like at that time to those that haven’t had that experience,” Tess said. There were no theaters, and sports facilities for girls were limited, “So, mostly, we had to stay inside and make do with what we had — and games were all that we had.”</p>



<p>Raghad, 23, currently works for a mining company, but she dreams of becoming a voice actor for video games. Although she’s never lived anywhere but Saudi Arabia, she has a distinctly squeaky American accent — a curious trait she picked up from a fifth-grade teacher who had lived in the U.S. and a torrent of YouTube videos. She is considering taking voice-acting classes online, assuming she can find any, because she’s not allowed to travel abroad alone to study until after she’s married. It’s still common to meet women who come to gaming as a result of these kinds of restrictions, as Felwa, Tasnim, and Najla did years ago. This is why going to GCON can be such a powerful experience.&nbsp;</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1010892174-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1010892174-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1010892174-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1010892174-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1010892174-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-1010892174-2800x1867.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, (max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="Mossad Al-Dossary (right) made headlines in 2018 after winning first place at the FIFA e-World Cup in London, taking home a $250,000 cash prize.&nbsp;">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder">Ben Hoskins/FIFA via Getty Images</span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>In 2018, Felwa,</strong> Tasnim, and Najla handed GCON over to Ghada Al-Moqbel, who attended her first GCON in 2013 at the age of 18. Now she leads Saudi Arabia’s women’s gaming community. This occurred right after bin Salman took control and began dismantling the country’s gender segregation. For Ghada and the wider community of female gamers, these changes forced them to decide whether they wanted to stay on the fringes of the gaming community or take a more central role. In 2018, GCON organizers met regularly to discuss whether there was still value in creating an exclusively female space for gaming.</p>



<figure><blockquote><p>“We had to stay inside and make do with what we had — and games were all that we had.”</p></blockquote></figure>



<p>For Ghada, the answer was yes. While attitudes toward female gamers have improved, parts of Saudi society remain uncomfortable with this burgeoning culture. When GCON first launched, participants were criticized for indulging in supposedly immoral behavior, and social media accounts of female gamers were routinely hacked. Likewise, after the first Comic Con in Jeddah, in 2017, a<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/%D9%83%D9%88%D9%85%D9%8A%D9%83%D9%88%D9%86_%D8%AD%D9%81%D9%84_%D8%B9%D8%A8%D8%AF%D8%A9_%D8%A7%D9%84%D8%B4%D9%8A%D8%B7%D8%A7%D9%86_%D8%A8%D8%AC%D8%AF%D9%87?src=hashtag_click"> hashtag</a> accusing participants of being Satan worshippers flooded social media along with pictures of women who had dressed up for cosplay. Thanks in part to the continuing fear of societal backlash, many Saudi women still advocate for all-female events.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But like the kingdom, GCON is also evolving. “We’re not just entertainment anymore,” Ghada said. “It’s about empowering and enabling women to be serious in the gaming and esports industry.” In mid-August, Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University, the largest women-only university in the world, <a href="https://www.arabnews.com/node/1718151/saudi-arabia">announced</a> that it would be creating a degree program for animation.</p>



<p>Since Ghada took over, the organization has expanded, hosting regular skill-development workshops as well as the annual convention. While she has maintained GCON’s focus on female gamers, she has been open to collaborating with their male peers. In 2017, organizers from Gamer’s Day worked with GCON to arrange their first mixed-gender gaming event. While 2020 was supposed to be a big year for Ghada and GCON, Covid-19 disrupted their plans. Nonetheless, it’s unlikely that GCON — a force that arose in far more challenging terrain — will be going away anytime soon.</p>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2020/you-just-got-pwned-habibi/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24316556</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 15:04:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Don't trust default timeouts]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 111 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24315239">thread link</a>) | @kiyanwang
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | https://robertovitillo.com/default-timeouts/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://robertovitillo.com/default-timeouts/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><header><p>May 03, 2020</p></header><p>Modern applications don’t crash; they hang. One of the main reasons for it is the assumption that the network is reliable. It isn’t. </p><p>When you make a network call without setting a timeout, you are telling your code that you are 100% confident that the call is going to succeed. Would you really take that bet?</p><p>If you are a making synchronous network call that never returns, then to very least your thread hogs forever. Whoops. Asynchronous network calls that don’t return are not free either. Sure, you are not hogging threads, but you are leaking sockets. Any HTTP client library worth its salt uses socket pools to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_persistent_connection">avoid recreating connections</a>. And those pools have a limited capacity. Like any other resource leak, it’s only a matter of time until there are no sockets left. When that happens, your application is going to get stuck waiting for a connection to free up.</p><p>If the network is not reliable, why do we keep creating APIs that have infinity as the default timeout? Some APIs don’t even have a way to set a timeout in the first place! A good API should be easy to use the right way and hard to use the wrong way. When the default timeout is infinity, it’s all too easy for a client to shoot itself in the foot. </p><p>If you remember one thing from this post, then let it be this: <strong>never use “infinity” as a default timeout</strong>.</p><p>Let’s take a look at some concrete examples.</p><p>Javascript’s XMLHttpRequest is THE web API to retrieve data from a server asynchronously. Its <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/XMLHttpRequest/timeout">default timeout is zero</a>, which means there is no timeout!</p><div data-language="javascript"><pre><code><span>var</span> xhr <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>XMLHttpRequest</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
xhr<span>.</span><span>open</span><span>(</span><span>'GET'</span><span>,</span> <span>'/api'</span><span>,</span> <span>true</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>


xhr<span>.</span>timeout <span>=</span> <span>10000</span><span>;</span> 

xhr<span>.</span><span>onload</span> <span>=</span> <span>function</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
 
<span>}</span><span>;</span>

xhr<span>.</span><span>ontimeout</span> <span>=</span> <span>function</span> <span>(</span><span>e</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
 
<span>}</span><span>;</span>

xhr<span>.</span><span>send</span><span>(</span><span>null</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Client-side timeouts are as crucial as server-side ones. There is a <a href="https://hpbn.co/primer-on-browser-networking/#connection-management-and-optimization">maximum number of sockets your browser</a> can open for a particular host. If you make network requests that never returns, you are going to exhaust the socket pool. When the pool is exhausted, you are no longer able to connect to the host. </p><p>The fetch web API is a modern replacement for the XMLHttpRequest API, which uses Promises. When the API was initially introduced, there was <a href="https://github.com/whatwg/fetch/issues/951">no way to set a timeout at all</a>! Browsers have recently added experimental support for the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/AbortController">Abort API</a> to support timeouts, though.</p><div data-language="javascript"><pre><code><span>const</span> controller <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>AbortController</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>

<span>const</span> signal <span>=</span> controller<span>.</span>signal<span>;</span>

<span>const</span> fetchPromise <span>=</span> <span>fetch</span><span>(</span>url<span>,</span> <span>{</span>signal<span>}</span><span>)</span><span>;</span>  


<span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> controller<span>.</span><span>abort</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>,</span> <span>10000</span><span>)</span><span>;</span> 

fetchPromise<span>.</span><span>then</span><span>(</span><span>response</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
 
<span>}</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Things aren’t much rosier in Python-land. The requests library uses a default timeout of <a href="https://requests.readthedocs.io/en/master/user/quickstart/#timeouts">infinity</a>. </p><div data-language="python"><pre><code>
response <span>=</span> requests<span>.</span>get<span>(</span><span>'https://github.com/'</span><span>,</span> timeout<span>=</span><span>10</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div><p>What about Go? Go’s HTTP package <a href="https://github.com/golang/go/issues/24138">doesn’t use timeouts</a> by default either. </p><div data-language="go"><pre><code><span>var</span> client <span>=</span> <span>&amp;</span>http<span>.</span>Client<span>{</span>
  
  Timeout<span>:</span> time<span>.</span>Second <span>*</span> <span>10</span><span>,</span> 
<span>}</span>

response<span>,</span> <span>_</span> <span>:=</span> client <span>.</span><span>Get</span><span>(</span>url<span>)</span></code></pre></div><p>Modern HTTP clients for Java and .NET do a much better job and usually, come with default timeouts. For example, .Net Core’s HttpClient has a default timeout of <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/api/system.net.http.httpclient.timeout?view=netcore-3.1#remarks">100 seconds</a>. It’s lax but much better than no timeout at all. That comes as no surprise since those languages are used to build large scale distributed systems that need to be robust against network failures. Network requests without timeouts are the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fallacies_of_distributed_computing">top silent killer</a> of distributed systems.</p><h3 id="remember-this"><a href="#remember-this" aria-label="remember this permalink"></a>Remember this</h3><p>As a rule of thumb, always set timeouts when making network calls. And if you build libraries, always set reasonable default timeouts and make them configurable for your clients.</p><p>Do you want to learn more about stability patterns and anti-patterns of distributed systems? Check out my <a href="https://systemdesignmanual.com/">upcoming book</a>.</p><hr></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://robertovitillo.com/default-timeouts/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24315239</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:58:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Literate DevOps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24315057">thread link</a>) | @geocar
<br/>
August 29, 2020 | http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
<header>

</header><p>
((tl;dr See <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dljNabciEGg">my video presentation/demonstration</a> of this essay))
</p>

<p>
Maintaining servers falls into two phases:
</p>

<ol>
<li>Bang head until server works</li>
<li>Capture effort into some automation tool like Puppet or Chef.</li>
</ol>

<p>
Recently, I’ve been playing around with making the first phase closer
to the second.  For lack of a better word, I’m calling it <i>literate
devops</i>.
</p>

<p>
I’ve talked about using <a href="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/LP/introduction.html">org-mode’s <i>literate programming</i> model</a> to
investigate new ideas and crystallize thoughts, and this approach
appears to work well for me since I lack those esoteric sysadmin
skills.
</p>

<div id="outline-container-orgbcbce75">
<h2 id="orgbcbce75">Tell us a Story</h2>
<div id="text-orgbcbce75">
<p>
Once upon a time, I was tasked with patching an RPM, which is not in
my comfort zone, so my initial plan of attack was:
</p>

<ol>
<li>Use Vagrant to create a disposable CentOS system</li>
<li>SSH into this virtual machine to download needed tools</li>
<li>Run various unknown commands</li>
<li>Rinse and repeat this step until successful</li>
</ol>

<p>
Of course, once I figure out the solution, I need to document it for
others on my team, and maybe create a <i>repeatedable</i> script.
</p>

<p>
First step is well documented elsewhere, but today I learned (TIL)
you can <code>ssh</code> directly to your Vagrant-based virtual machine with
this little magic (<b>Note:</b> <i>client</i> is the name of my virtual
machine I specified in the <code>Vagrantfile</code>):
</p>

<div>
<pre>vagrant ssh-config --host clientvm &gt;&gt; $<span>HOME</span>/.ssh/config
</pre>
</div>

<p>
This command appends some lovely host-connection magic so you can
issue: <code>ssh clientvm</code>
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org8dff3db">
<h2 id="org8dff3db">Literate Devops</h2>
<div id="text-org8dff3db">
<p>
Instead of opening up a terminal to my virtual machine, I pop into
Emacs and load this sprint’s <i>note file</i><sup><a id="fnr.1" href="#fn.1">1</a></sup>, create a new header,
and enter the shell and ruby commands in this text file.
</p>

<p>
What good is this? Unlike a traditional terminal, this allows me to
<i>log</i>, <i>document</i> and <i>execute</i> each command.
</p>

<p>
For instance, here is a screen-shot of a section of my Emacs buffer:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops.png" alt="literate-devops.png">

</figure>

<p>
As an old bear with very little brains, my prose can explain the
background and purpose of each command.  Clicking the hyperlink
refreshes my memory of previous discoveries. A keychord <i>executes</i>
the code block…
</p>

<p>
Yes. I execute the commands from within Emacs.
</p>

<p>
Hitting <code>C-c C-c</code> (Control-C twice) runs the code (based on the
language).  This example runs in the shell. The results are placed
back into the file, which can be used by other code blocks (and <a href="http://orgmode.org/manual/results.html#results">many
other options</a>).
</p>

<p>
For instance, here is the first half of a section for downloading
the GPG Keys from a repository (the URL is placed in a <i>property</i>
that is shared among all code blocks in his section):
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-14.png" alt="literate-devops-14.png">

</figure>

<p>
The Shell script block (in the center of the screen-shot) uses
<code>wget</code> to download the HTML index file and parse and extract the key
file URLs.  We’ll have a Ruby script do that parsing, and since the
script may be a bit hairy, we’ll define it in another code block.
</p>

<p>
One technique from <a href="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/LP/introduction.html">literate programming</a> is the idea that one code
block can be inserted into another block (the reference is a name
within double angle brackets, <code>&lt;&lt;...&gt;&gt;</code>). Donald Knuth called this
feature WEB. Since it can accidentally conflict with some languages
(like Ruby), I have it off by default, but turn it on for this block
with the <code>noweb</code> parameter.
</p>

<p>
Here is the Ruby script. Having it in a separate Ruby-specific code
block allows me to turn on all the Ruby magic that Emacs can muster.
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-15.png" alt="literate-devops-15.png">

</figure>

<p>
The last step is to take the URLs produced by the first script and
feed them to another Shell script that will call <code>wget</code> to download
each:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-16.png" alt="literate-devops-16.png">

</figure>

<p>
The <code>key-list</code> was the name of our original code block, as well as
the name of its results. We assign that list of results to a
variable, <code>LIST</code> that the shell script would access as <code>$LIST</code>.
</p>

<p>
This example demonstrated how literate programming can weave code
and data through different languages.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org5d7bdd1">
<h2 id="org5d7bdd1">What about the Virtual Machine?</h2>
<p>
Normally, specifying <code>sh</code> as the code block’s <i>language</i>, tells
Emacs to run the code in my local system’s shell, but in this case,
I want it ran on my virtual machine (or on my development server in
my lab). I’ll describe two options for doing this, using <a href="http://www.emacswiki.org/TrampMode">Tramp</a> and
Babel Sessions.
</p>

<div id="outline-container-org2251b72">
<h3 id="org2251b72">Tramp to the Rescue</h3>
<div id="text-org2251b72">
<p>
Tramp is an Emacs feature that allows one to edit a file on a
remote machine using <code>ssh</code> and other protocols. For instance,
running the <code>find-file</code> function (bound to <code>C-x C-f</code>) lets you type
something like:
</p>

<pre>/ssh:howard.abrams@goblin.howardism.org:web/files/robot.txt
</pre>

<p>
If you put the following in your <code>.emacs</code> initialization file:
</p>

<div>
<pre><span>(</span><span>setq</span> tramp-default-method <span>"ssh"</span><span>)</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
And update your <code>~/.ssh/config</code> file to know what user account goes
with the host name, the file reference above can be shorten to:
</p>

<pre>/goblin.howardism.org:web/files/robot.txt
</pre>

<p>
Emacs looks for the <code>:</code> character to determine if Tramp should be
invoked.  Tramp uses SSH keys if available, or will prompt you for
a password if needed.
</p>


<p>
Each org-mode code block can specify a <code>:dir</code> option that specifies
where the code snippet should run, for instance, the following
blocks are equivalent:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-9.png" alt="literate-devops-9.png">

</figure>

<p>
The <code>:dir</code> option allows full Tramp functionality, allowing me to
run a block on a different machine. Remember how I added my
<code>client</code> Vagrant virtual machine to my <code>~/.ssh/config</code> file?
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-10.png" alt="literate-devops-10.png">

</figure>

<p>
<i>But I need access to my machine behind a firewall!?</i>
</p>

<p>
My job deals with virtual machines running in a highly protected
data center, where I need to first log into jump boxes and bastion
machines. Tramp handles these sorts of hops. For instance:
</p>

<pre>/ssh:10.98.18.229|ssh:10.0.1.122|sudo:/etc/network/interfaces
</pre>

<p>
Uses my account name to log into the bastion machine, and
then uses my account name to <code>ssh</code> into a virtual machine running
in a private cloud. And then uses the <code>sudo</code> command to let me edit
a file owned by <code>root</code>.
</p>

<p>
Tramp pipe references works with the <code>:dir</code> option for <code>org-mode</code>
source blocks:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-11.png" alt="literate-devops-11.png">

</figure>

<p>
Few tricks to keep in mind:
</p>

<ul>
<li>All but the last hop uses a pipe character, |, instead of the
colon character, :</li>
<li>If you use the pipe character, you need to specify all
protocols, like <code>ssh</code>, even if it is the default.</li>
<li>If your local machine’s operating system is different than the
machine you are connecting to, you need to fix a bug in
<code>org-mode</code>, which I can show you how to fix<sup><a id="fnr.2" href="#fn.2">2</a></sup>.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org0d027af">
<h3 id="org0d027af">Using org-mode Sessions</h3>
<div id="text-org0d027af">
<p>
Another approach is to create a <i>session</i> that connects different
code blocks together. Each screen shot below, each code block below
has the same <code>session</code> value, <code>client</code> (which is conveniently the
same my virtual machine’s hostname, <code>client</code>):
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-2b.png" alt="literate-devops-2b.png">

</figure>

<p>
If I execute the first block, a <i>shell</i> is started in the
background, and it ssh’s into the machine. Note, to get this
working, you need to enable <i>password-less access</i> by placing your
SSH’s public key into the remote system’s <code>.ssh/authorized_keys</code>
file, or using the <code>ssh</code> Emacs package.<sup><a id="fnr.3" href="#fn.3">3</a></sup>
</p>

<p>
From this point on, each code block I execute with the <code>client</code>
session value, uses this connection, and the code is executed on the
remote machine (a virtual machine in this case, but that doesn’t
matter).
</p>

<p>
Either of these approaches works well, but the second approach,
allows me to set variables to create a particular state that other
blocks may expect.  However, this requires execution of each block in
order.
</p>

<p>
I have a third, more interactive, approach<sup><a id="fnr.4" href="#fn.4">4</a></sup> using <code>screen</code>, but
it doesn’t allow passing variables to the code, and as you’ll see
below, this is pretty important to me.
</p>


<p>
Regardless, I continue learning how to accomplish my goal, all the
while documenting and <i>validating</i> my steps. The end result can be
exported to web or wiki page.
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org39ccdca">
<h2 id="org39ccdca">What about Verbose Commands?</h2>
<div id="text-org39ccdca">
<p>
Yes, executing some commands can be quite time-consuming and
verbose, but often I need to search the results, and having the
results placed in an Emacs buffer allows better searching.
</p>

<p>
Often I use a collapsible “drawer” (which is just a way to identify
the beginning and end of the output):
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-3.png" alt="literate-devops-3.png">

</figure>

<p>
Place the cursor on this drawer and hit the <code>Tab</code> key to hide or
show the output:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-4.png" alt="literate-devops-4.png">

</figure>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org3721d6c">
<h2 id="org3721d6c">Can you Use the Output?</h2>
<div id="text-org3721d6c">
<p>
The results of some commands are often needed for the next command,
and I’m sure you just love using your mouse to copy and paste part
of the output, but I have a better way.
</p>

<p>
For instance, I needed a list of an RPM’s dependencies:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-5.png" alt="literate-devops-5.png">

</figure>

<p>
Notice I <i>named</i> this source code block. Also notice how Emacs
automatically broke the results up into a table. By default, the
output from shell commands are split along newlines and
spaces.
</p>

<p>
I can feed the results of these execution to another code block.
The following source block creates a variable named <code>DEPENDS</code> that
uses rows 2 through 10 of the first column as an array.
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-6.png" alt="literate-devops-6.png">

</figure>

<p>
I then download the RPMs I want without any mouse interaction.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-orgdfa5caa">
<h2 id="orgdfa5caa">Setting Variables and Values</h2>
<div id="text-orgdfa5caa">
<p>
A key aspect of reusing devops programs (like a Chef
cookbooks) is the separation of the <i>code</i> from the <i>values</i> the code
uses…a key aspect of <i>any</i> program you reuse.
</p>

<p>
In my world, I create a new <code>org-mode</code> file for each sprint, and
each task or problem gets its own header and section. Each section
can have a <i>drawer</i> of properties, including variables shared among
all code blocks in that section.
</p>

<p>
To create a <i>section variable</i>, simply hit: <code>C-c C-x p</code>, and set the
<code>Property</code> to <code>var</code> and the value to a <i>variable=value</i>, as in:
</p>



<p>
This drawer can contain any code block values you wish, like
<code>session</code> or <code>results</code>. These values can then be overridden as
settings on the code block, as you see in this screen-shot:
</p>


<figure>
<img src="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops-8.png" alt="literate-devops-8.png">

</figure>

<p>
Setting variables and settings (especially the <code>session</code> setting),
ties the code blocks together.
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org874102b">
<h2 id="org874102b">Communicating with Others</h2>
<div id="text-org874102b">
<p>
While investigations in operations and administrations (as I’ve
described) are useful to oneself when understanding the problem
domain, I need to communicate the results with my team mates.
Since my <a href="https://github.com/howardabrams/dot-files/blob/master/emacs-mail.org#sending-email">Emacs configuration</a> allows me to send mail messages, I kick
off the function, <code>org-mime-org-buffer-htmlize</code>, which exports the
<code>org-mode</code> file to an HTML mail message (This function is part of
the latest <code>org-plus-contrib</code> package).
</p>

<p>
However, some times the exported results are not quite perfect.
</p>

<p>
For instance, some blocks may result in some JSON data, and since</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops.html">http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/literate-devops.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24315057</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:10:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Millions of Americans could lose their electricity as shutoff moratoriums expire]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24310684">thread link</a>) | @claudeganon
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://carbonswitch.co/energy-insecurity-and-covid-19 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://carbonswitch.co/energy-insecurity-and-covid-19">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content"><div><div id="primary"><main id="main"><article class="page" id="post-563" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="itemscope"><div itemprop="text"><div data-elementor-type="wp-page" data-elementor-id="563" data-elementor-settings="[]"><div><div><section data-id="48973c0d" data-element_type="section" data-settings="{&quot;background_background&quot;:&quot;classic&quot;}"><div><div><div data-id="90c0a03" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="3526bfb1" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h5>In this new report we show that 34.5 million households will lose shutoff protections in the next month leaving 9.5 million unemployed people at risk by October 1st.</h5></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="87d10c7" data-element_type="section"></section><section data-id="da8eaca" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="3f74f0b" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="b3b7a3c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>Introduction</h3><p>In the early weeks of the COVID-19 pandemic, millions of Americans lost their jobs as the economy ground to a near halt. Unemployment rose to levels not seen since the Great Depression.</p><p>Shortly afterwards states around the country passed emergency laws to protect the most vulnerable people. In 32 states, governors and public utility commissions (PUCs) passed <strong>utility shut-off moratoriums</strong> to ensure that no households lost their electricity because they couldn’t pay their bill.</p><p>Six months later many of those moratoriums have expired or are set to expire in the next month. Between May and mid-August, 10 states allowed their moratoriums to expire. In the next month another 14 state moratoriums will expire. That means <strong>by October 1st a total of 36 states won’t have moratoriums in place.</strong></p><p>In order to understand the impact of these policy changes, Carbon Switch analyzed data provided by public utility commissions in these states, unemployment data, and energy spending data. Our goal was to understand how many people could be at risk of losing their electricity this year.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="2104617" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="847ece8" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="8833eed" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>Key highlights</h3><ul><li><strong>In the next month 34.5 million households will lose their utility shutoff protections as moratoriums in 14 states expire.</strong> About 4 million of those households are currently below the federal poverty line. 4 million people in those states are unemployed.</li><li><strong>76 million American households won’t have utility shutoff moratoriums after October 1st.</strong> By that point moratoriums will be voluntary in 36 states. About 10 million of the households in those states are currently below the federal poverty line. Another 9.5 million people in those states are unemployed.</li><li><strong>In some states 33% of utility customers are behind on bills.</strong> In North Carolina 1,369,786 households are behind on payments. When the statewide moratorium expires on September 1st they will all be at risk of losing their power.</li><li><strong>8 of the country’s 10 biggest utilities will shut off customers’ power by Sept 15.</strong> These utilities serve 53 million Americans. The only two utilities that won’t resume shut offs by September 15th are PG&amp;E and SCE, California-based utilities that legally can’t resume shutoffs until at least next year due to the state’s moratorium.</li><li><strong>Black families are twice as likely to have their power shut off as white families.</strong> According to the 2009 United States Energy Information Administration’s Residential Energy Consumption Survey African American households at or below 150% of the federal poverty level were shut off twice as frequently as white households (11.3% compared to 5.5%).</li><li><strong>Utility shutoffs cost lives, people’s health, and their dignity.</strong> Every year brings stories of people killed after their power is shut off (often due to fires and heat stroke). A recent study showed that people often forgo essentials like food in order to save up enough money to get the power back on.</li></ul></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="1c509ff" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="a0ede7a" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="02187c7" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>Millions will be at risk of losing power</h3><p>In the next month utility shutoff moratoriums will expire in 14 states. As you can see in the second column of the table below there are ~34.5 million households in those states. About 4 million of those households are below the federal poverty line according to the Department of Housing and Urban Development. And another 4 million people in those states are unemployed according to data released last week by the Bureau of Labor and Statistics.</p><p>By October 1st moratoriums will be voluntary in 36 states meaning that investor-owned utilities can shut off the power on some of the most vulnerable people in America. As you can see in the third column in the table below, there are 76 million American households in those states. About 10 million of them are below the federal poverty line. And 9.5 million people in those states are unemployed.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="181f1e9" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="ce8e956" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="0d9f47b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="1312" height="424" src="https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_1312/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-showing-people-impacted.png" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_1312/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-showing-people-impacted.png 1312w, https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_300/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-showing-people-impacted-300x97.png 300w, https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_1024/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-showing-people-impacted-1024x331.png 1024w, https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_768/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-showing-people-impacted-768x248.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1312px) 100vw, 1312px"></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="18bd146" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="7941542" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="0ca8bfa" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>Where will people be at risk?&nbsp;</h3><p>The map below shows the number of unemployed people in states with utility shutoff moratoriums that won’t be active after October 1st.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Click a state to learn more</strong> about how many people will be at risk in any given place.&nbsp;<em>Note: Grey states have moratoriums that last beyond October 1st.</em></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="5040e1e" data-element_type="section"></section><section data-id="d1d909e" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="3beeb15" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="dd31cd9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>In some states 33% of utility customers are behind on payments</h3><p>In a <a href="https://starw1.ncuc.net/NCUC/ViewFile.aspx?Id=e14a91f0-650c-416c-9a30-c6d94ea9a4b1">July 15 report</a>, the Governor’s office reported that 1.3 million customers had been spared from disconnects due to his emergency order that banned utility shutoffs. As they wrote: “Between April 1 and June 30, 1,369,786 residential customer accounts have become eligible for disconnection but have not been disconnected.”</p><p>For context, there are 3,815,392 households in North Carolina meaning that more than a third of households are behind on payments.</p><p>Unfortunately little has changed in North Carolina since that July 15 report and the moratorium is set to expire on September 1st. According to the most recent BLS data, there are 419,812 unemployed people in the state (compared to 199,494 a year ago).</p><p>Wisconsin is another state that released data on how many customers are behind on their utility bills. According to <a href="https://www.wpr.org/sites/default/files/5-ui-120_data_update_august_2020.pdf">a recent government report</a> about 33% of utility customers were behind on payments as of July (compared to 12% a year ago).</p><p>When surveyed for that report, 36 of the 41 utilities that responded said they planned to resume shutoffs. We Energies, a utility that serves 1,183,000 customers in Wisconsin said 32,000 customers met disconnect criteria (27% of their total).</p><p>But with millions of shutoffs looming the Public Service Commission in Wisconsin <a href="https://madison.com/wsj/news/local/govt-and-politics/wisconsin-regulators-extend-shutoff-ban-one-third-of-households-behind-on-utility-bills/article_e35facbb-0812-5a32-b213-a8761e3e5036.html">voted</a> to extend the moratorium until October 1st.</p><p>In Florida “accounts in arrears” (the industry term for customers that are behind on payments), are up 60% compared to the year before according to <a href="http://www.psc.state.fl.us/Files/PDF/Utilities/CovidWorkshop/FPL.pdf">presentations</a> by executives at the biggest utilities obtained by Carbon Switch.</p><p>Florida Power and Light, one of the country’s biggest utilities, had 250,000 accounts in arrears as of the end of June. The company began shutting off the power on customers in mid-July.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="4bc9e81" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="4fe6dd3" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="372bafe" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>Shutoff policies at the 10 biggest utilities</h3><p>In March utilities across the country announced that they would temporarily suspend shutoffs. Few of them specified when they would resume shutoffs. Many of them have quietly resumed shutting off the power on their customers in the months since. While others plan to resume shutoffs in mid-September. One of the country’s biggest utilities, Southern Company — a Georgia-based utility with 9 million customers — never had an internal shutoff moratorium in the first place.</p><p>Carbon Switch gathered data on the number of customers at the 10 largest utilities and their shut off policies. We found that the top 10 utilities control 62% of the investor-owned utility market and serve 63 million customers. (It’s important to note that a customer is a household, not an individual. Considering the average household in America has 2.5 people, their policies likely affect about 157.5 million Americans).</p><p>Here’s a summary of these utilities shutoff policies during the pandemic:</p><ul><li>1 utility (Southern Company) never stopped shutting off their customers’ power.</li><li>3 utilities (Exelon, Xcel, and Florida Power and Light) quietly resumed shutoffs in May and July.</li><li>4 utilities (Duke Energy, Dominion Energy, First Energy, and AEP) plan to resume shut offs in September.</li><li>2 utilities (PG&amp;E and SCE) are barred by California’s moratorium from shutting off their customers’ power until at least next year.</li></ul><p>It’s worth emphasizing that the only utilities that have extended their moratoriums past September 15th are the two utilities based in California, a state with the nation’s longest spanning moratorium. The others plan to resume shut offs despite recent reports that as many as a third of customers are behind on payments in some states.</p></div></div></div><div data-id="b958695" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="1240" height="974" src="https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_1240/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-2.png" alt="" srcset="https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_1240/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-2.png 1240w, https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_300/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-2-300x236.png 300w, https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_1024/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-2-1024x804.png 1024w, https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_768/https://carbonswitch.co/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/table-2-768x603.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1240px) 100vw, 1240px"></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="bbfb297" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="fb983df" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="e7cba1b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>Shutoffs and injustice</h3><p>In 2018 a 72-year-old woman living in Sun City West, Arizona died during a heat wave in which temperatures reached 100 degrees. Shortly after her death investigators learned that she died because Arizona Public Service Co., her local utility had shut off her power (she died of a heat-related illness).</p><p>According to a report by The Phoenix New Times, she had been paying $125 per week — all she could afford on a fixed income — but it wasn’t enough. The utility shut her power off because her balance was $176.84 in the negative.</p><p>Every year there are similar heartbreaking stories. There are stories of people who die of carbon monoxide poisoning, people who freeze to death, and people who die from fires started by candles — all because their utilities were shut off.</p><p>And as the NAACP report pointed out in <a href="https://naacp.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Lights-Out-in-the-Cold_NAACP-ECJP-4.pdf">Lights Out in the Cold</a>, utility shutoffs disproportionately affect black people in America. According to the 2009 United States Energy Information Administration’s Residential Energy Consumption Survey African American households at or below 150% of the federal poverty level were shut off twice as frequently as white households (11.3% compared to 5.5%).</p><p><a href="https://theconversation.com/energy-is-a-basic-need-and-many-americans-are-struggling-to-afford-it-in-the-covid-19-recession-140416?utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=newsletter_axiosgenerate&amp;stream=top">Recent data</a> from academics at Indiana University shows that in the time of COVID-19 this racial injustice hasn’t changed. In a poll the percentage of black respondents who struggled to pay an energy bill in April or May of this year was twice as high as their white counterparts.</p><p>The threat of utility shutoffs also affect people’s health. According to that same Indiana University study, “Approximately 22% of respondents reported that in the previous month they had reduced or put off expenses for basic needs like medicine or food in order to pay their energy bills.”</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="9e34ff2" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="edacb53" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="ea9e492" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>As a social enterprise we are obligated to do social good, not maximize profits. That’s why we felt compelled to produce this report, despite the fact that it may frustrate utility companies that we will likely work with in the future.</p><p>The millions of Americans that lost their jobs in the wake of COVID-19 shouldn’t be subjected to more pain. They shouldn’t lose more of their dignity. They shouldn’t have to forgo more meals just to keep the lights on so …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section></div></div></div></div></article></main></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://carbonswitch.co/energy-insecurity-and-covid-19">https://carbonswitch.co/energy-insecurity-and-covid-19</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://carbonswitch.co/energy-insecurity-and-covid-19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24310684</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 22:07:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple Removes Epic Games Account from App Store]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 138 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24310083">thread link</a>) | @GamerNintendo
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://nintendosmash.com/apple-removes-epic-games-account-from-app-store-will-not-affect-unreal-engine-support/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nintendosmash.com/apple-removes-epic-games-account-from-app-store-will-not-affect-unreal-engine-support/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="the-post">
			
			<p><img width="593" height="330" src="https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fortnite-vs-apple-593x330.jpg" alt="Apple Removes Epic Games Account From App Store - Will Not Affect Unreal Engine Support" srcset="https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fortnite-vs-apple.jpg 593w, https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fortnite-vs-apple-300x167.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 593px) 100vw, 593px">		</p>
	
		


			<div>

							

						
<p>
		
	
	
		
	<span><i></i>3 days ago</span>	
	<span><i></i><a href="https://nintendosmash.com/category/news/" rel="category tag">News</a></span>
	
	
</p>

			
				<div>
					
					
					
<p>At the moment, the Epic Games page in the App Store is not available – journalist John Voorhees was one of the first to notice this. The store gives an error whenever you try to go to the page of the company itself or one of its applications using a direct link, but you cannot find it in the search.</p>




<p>Users also noted that downloading apps from Epic, including Fortnite, will not work, even if they are already assigned to a user account.</p>



<figure><img src="https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/apple.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/apple.jpg 289w, https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/apple-195x300.jpg 195w" sizes="(max-width: 289px) 100vw, 289px"></figure>



<p>Apple released an official statement on this matter – the company noted that they were “very sorry” to take such measures, but Epic left no choice.</p>



<blockquote><p>The court recommended that Epic follow the App Store’s guidelines and policies while the case is in progress – the rules they followed over the past ten years until they created the current situation themselves. Epic refused.</p><p><br> Instead, the company has repeatedly submitted Fortnite updates that violate store rules. This is unfair to all other developers in the App Store and makes users suffer from conflict.</p><p><br> We hope to be able to cooperate again in the future, but at the moment this is unfortunately not possible.</p><p><br> from Apple statement</p></blockquote>



<p>The corporation has warned that it is going to delete Epic Games accounts back on August 17th. Apparently, another account of the company, Epic International, is still available in the App Store – it was previously banned from blocking in court. Therefore, the situation should not touch upon the support of the Unreal Engine.</p>



<p>On the day Epic’s profiles were deleted, the App Store began to actively promote Fortnite’s direct competitor, PUBG Mobile. The online shooter appeared on the main page of the “Games” section, and the promo was published on the store’s official twitter.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>The tweet was also noticed by the head of Epic Games, Tim Sweeney.</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>While you wait for Fortnite to return to iOS and Mac, here’s another great Battle Royale powered by the Unreal Engine!</p>

 
















<!-- AI CONTENT END 3 -->
					
									</div><!-- .entry /-->
								
				
				 <!-- .share-post -->				
			</div><!-- .post-inner -->
		</article><section id="check-also-box">
		<a href="#" id="check-also-close"><i></i></a>

		<p>
			<h3>Check Also</h3>
		</p>

				
				<div>
						
			<p><a href="https://nintendosmash.com/immortals-fenyx-rising-rated-in-taiwan-possibly-new-title-of-gods-monsters/">
					<img width="310" height="165" src="https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/gods-310x165.jpg" alt="Immortals: Fenyx Rising Rated In Taiwan - Possibly New Title Of Gods &amp; Monsters">					<span></span>
				</a>
			</p><!-- post-thumbnail /-->
						
			<h2><a href="https://nintendosmash.com/immortals-fenyx-rising-rated-in-taiwan-possibly-new-title-of-gods-monsters/" rel="bookmark">Immortals: Fenyx Rising Rated In Taiwan – Possibly New Title Of Gods &amp; Monsters</a></h2>
			<p>Immortals: Fenyx Rising has been rated for PS4, Xbox One, Switch, and PC in Taiwan. …</p>
		</div>
				<div>
						
			<p><a href="https://nintendosmash.com/activision-sues-the-creator-of-cheats-for-cod-warzone-and-modern-warfare/">
					<img width="310" height="165" src="https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cx-310x165.jpg" alt="Activision sues the creator of cheats for CoD: Warzone and Modern Warfare">					<span></span>
				</a>
			</p><!-- post-thumbnail /-->
						
			<h2><a href="https://nintendosmash.com/activision-sues-the-creator-of-cheats-for-cod-warzone-and-modern-warfare/" rel="bookmark">Activision suing popular hacking installation website</a></h2>
			<p>A lawsuit has been filed against CXCheats for illegally creating software to modify gameplay in …</p>
		</div>
				<div>
						
			<p><a href="https://nintendosmash.com/astral-chain-2-might-be-coming-to-switch/">
					<img width="310" height="165" src="https://nintendosmash.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/astral-chain-2-310x165.jpg" alt="Astral Chain 2 might be coming to Switch">					<span></span>
				</a>
			</p><!-- post-thumbnail /-->
						
			<h2><a href="https://nintendosmash.com/astral-chain-2-might-be-coming-to-switch/" rel="bookmark">Astral Chain 2 might be coming to Switch</a></h2>
			<p>Despite the fact that Hideki Kamiya deleted the tweet, it remained in the web cache. …</p>
		</div>
			</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nintendosmash.com/apple-removes-epic-games-account-from-app-store-will-not-affect-unreal-engine-support/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24310083</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 21:19:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Objective-Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24309565">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://belkadan.com/blog/2020/08/Objective-Rust/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://belkadan.com/blog/2020/08/Objective-Rust/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>This is going to be another one of those posts where I did something ridiculous and then show you how I got there, so letâ€™s just get right to it.<!--more--></p>

<div><pre><code><span></span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>objc_rust</span>::<span>*</span><span>;</span><span></span>
<span>use</span><span> </span><span>std</span>::<span>ffi</span>::<span>CStr</span><span>;</span><span></span>

<span>pub</span><span> </span><span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>#[link(name = </span><span>"Foundation"</span><span>, kind = </span><span>"framework"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>extern</span><span> </span><span>{}</span><span></span>
<span>    </span>
<span>    </span><span>objc</span><span>!</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>cls</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>ObjCClass</span>::<span>lookup</span><span>(</span><span>"NSNumber</span><span>\0</span><span>"</span><span>).</span><span>unwrap</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>value</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>[[</span><span>cls</span><span>.</span><span>into</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>numberWithUnsignedInt</span>:<span>42</span><span>u32</span><span>]</span><span> </span><span>stringValue</span><span>];</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>result</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>unsafe</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> </span><span>CStr</span>::<span>from_ptr</span><span>([</span><span>value</span><span> </span><span>UTF8String</span><span>])</span><span> </span><span>};</span><span></span>
<span>        </span><span>println</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>"string: {}"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>result</span><span>.</span><span>to_string_lossy</span><span>());</span><span> </span><span>// string: 42</span>
<span>    </span><span>}</span><span></span>
<span>}</span><span></span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>Yep, thatâ€™s Rust code with embedded Objective-C syntax, and it works. Why would you do such a thing? Maybe you want tighter interop between the Rust and Objective-C parts of your iOS app. Maybe you want to write your iOS app <em>entirely</em> in Rust. Or maybe you just wanted to see if it was possible after your <a href="https://twitter.com/porglezomp">colleague</a>â€™s offhand remark.</p>

<p>(For me, it was the last one, absolutely.)</p>

<p>This post is going to walk through what it took to make this possible, so hereâ€™s a table of contents:</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="#background-on-objective-c">Background on Objective-C</a></li>
  <li><a href="#objective-c-from-rust-manually">Objective-C from Rust, manually</a></li>
  <li><a href="#recursive-rust-macros">Recursive Rust macros</a></li>
  <li><a href="#rust-macro-gotchas">Rust macro gotchas</a></li>
  <li><a href="#related-work">Related work</a></li>
  <li><a href="#appendix-what-about-swift">Appendix: What about Swift?</a></li>
</ol>

<p>Sections 3-5 might actually be useful to other people looking to write Rust macros, so even though this project is a toy, you may still get something out of reading the post. However, if youâ€™re looking to use Objective-C from Rust in production, you should not be using my unsafe toy here. Instead, use Steven Sheldonâ€™s <a href="https://crates.io/crates/objc"><code>objc</code> crate</a>. Sheldon also has a blog post from near the start of the project that talks about <a href="https://sasheldon.com/blog/2014/11/28/interoperating-between-objective-c-and-rust/">his design process beyond the bare message-send implementation</a>.</p>

<p>That said, if you want to see the full source of my little monstrosity, you can <a href="https://belkadan.com/source/rust-inline-objc/">check out the repository</a>.</p>

<h2 id="background-on-objective-c">Background on Objective-C</h2>

<p>My normal audience these days is probably Swift developers, but I expect this one to make rounds with at least some Rust people as well. Itâ€™d be easy for both groups to not have much direct experience with Objective-C, the primary language used by Apple for both macOS<sup id="fnref:osx" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:osx">1</a></sup> and iOS since their releases in 2001 and 2007. So, hereâ€™s the quick summary: itâ€™s â€œjustâ€� C, except when you start working with â€œobjectâ€� types. And nearly everything you do with those objects is based on a dynamic dispatch model implemented in the <em>runtime.</em> Because of the two parts of that sentence (â€œdynamic dispatchâ€� and â€œimplemented in the runtimeâ€�), people have come up with a lot of clever and powerful techniques to make programs simpler, more expressive, or more extensible, though sometimes at the cost of security, secrecy, and stability.</p>

<p>More relevant to us, however, is that a language whose features are (nearly) all available in a runtime library is a language thatâ€™s easy to bridge to dynamically, as long as you donâ€™t have really tight performance constraints. So hereâ€™s the deal: nearly everything you do in Objective-C is calling methods by <em>sending messages,</em> and the way this works is that methods are regular C functions stored in a dispatch table keyed by a uniqued string called a <dfn>selector</dfn>. It is likely that the most heavily-optimized piece of code in Appleâ€™s libraries is <code>objc_msgSend</code>, which takes a <dfn>receiver</dfn>, a selector, and the arguments to the method, does a (cached) lookup of the selector in the receiverâ€™s classâ€™s dispatch table(s), and then jumps directly to the appropriate, polymorphically-selected implementation of the method.</p>

<p>There are more things the Objective-C runtime exposes, but messages are absolutely the most important.</p>

<p>â€¦Oh, one more thing. Because Objective-C is an extension to C, it has to use syntax that doesnâ€™t conflict with C syntax. That means keywords with <code>@</code> signs in front of themâ€”one of the few symbols on the US keyboard that doesnâ€™t already have a meaning in Câ€”and a unique bracket-based â€œmessage sendâ€� syntax that takes a while to get used to:</p>

<pre><code>// Objective-C
NSString *fileStr = [[NSString alloc] initWithData:fileContents encoding:NSUTF8StringEncoding];

// Pseudo-Swift
let fileStr: NSString = NSString.alloc().initWithData(fileContents, encoding: NSUTF8StringEncoding)

// Actual Swift
let fileStr = NSString(data: fileContents, encoding: .utf8)

// Pseudo-Rust
let fileStr: *const NSString = NSString::alloc().initWithData(fileContents, NSUTF8StringEncoding)

// Idiomatic-ish Rust
let file_str = NSString::from_data(file_contents, NSStringEncoding::UTF8)
</code></pre>

<p>People almost universally think Objective-C syntax is ugly when they first see it, almost universally find it completely normal after a few years, and largely (though <em>not</em> almost universally) find idiomatic Swift easier to read even if theyâ€™re used to Objective-C.</p>

<h2 id="objective-c-from-rust-manually">Objective-C from Rust, manually</h2>

<p>From this point on youâ€™ll be expected to read Rust syntax without step-by-step explanations. Iâ€™ll try to explain whatâ€™s going on for my Swift and other non-Rust readersâ€”I myself am still a relative newcomer to Rustâ€”but itâ€™ll be pretty fast. This is <em>not</em> intended to be an introduction to Rust or Rust macros!</p>

<p>Given that the Objective-C runtime exposes a public API, we should be able to pretty much just call that from Rust, and indeed we can:</p>

<div><pre><code><span></span><span>use</span><span> </span><span>std</span>::<span>ffi</span>::<span>CStr</span><span>;</span><span></span>

<span>#[repr(C)]</span><span></span>
<span>struct</span> <span>ObjCObject</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>isa</span>: <span>isize</span>
<span>}</span><span></span>

<span>#[repr(transparent)]</span><span></span>
<span>#[derive(Clone,Copy)]</span><span></span>
<span>struct</span> <span>Selector</span><span>(</span><span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u8</span><span>);</span><span></span>

<span>#[link(name = </span><span>"objc"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>extern</span><span> </span><span>"C"</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>fn</span> <span>sel_registerName</span><span>(</span><span>name</span>: <span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u8</span><span>)</span><span> </span>-&gt; <span>Selector</span><span>;</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>fn</span> <span>objc_getClass</span><span>(</span><span>name</span>: <span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u8</span><span>)</span><span> </span>-&gt; <span>Option</span><span>&lt;&amp;</span><span>'static</span><span> </span><span>ObjCObject</span><span>&gt;</span><span>;</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>fn</span> <span>objc_msgSend</span><span>();</span><span> </span><span>// see below</span>
<span>}</span><span></span>

<span>fn</span> <span>main</span><span>()</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>#[link(name = </span><span>"Foundation"</span><span>, kind = </span><span>"framework"</span><span>)]</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>extern</span><span> </span><span>{}</span><span></span>

<span>  </span><span>// Get a function pointer for transmuting later.</span>
<span>  </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>msg_send</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>objc_msgSend</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>unsafe</span><span> </span><span>extern</span><span> </span><span>"C"</span><span> </span><span>fn</span><span>();</span><span></span>

<span>  </span><span>unsafe</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>url_class</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>objc_getClass</span><span>(</span><span>"NSURL</span><span>\0</span><span>"</span><span>.</span><span>as_ptr</span><span>()).</span><span>unwrap</span><span>();</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>description_sel</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>sel_registerName</span><span>(</span><span>"description</span><span>\0</span><span>"</span><span>.</span><span>as_ptr</span><span>());</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>description_method</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>std</span>::<span>mem</span>::<span>transmute</span>::<span>&lt;</span><span>_</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>unsafe</span><span> </span><span>extern</span><span> </span><span>"C"</span><span> </span><span>fn</span><span>(</span><span>_</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>_</span><span>)</span><span> </span>-&gt; <span>_</span><span>&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>msg_send</span><span>);</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>description_obj</span>: <span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>ObjCObject</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>description_method</span><span>(</span><span>url_class</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>description_sel</span><span>);</span><span></span>

<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>utf8_sel</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>sel_registerName</span><span>(</span><span>"UTF8String</span><span>\0</span><span>"</span><span>.</span><span>as_ptr</span><span>());</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>utf8_method</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>std</span>::<span>mem</span>::<span>transmute</span>::<span>&lt;</span><span>_</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>unsafe</span><span> </span><span>extern</span><span> </span><span>"C"</span><span> </span><span>fn</span><span>(</span><span>_</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>_</span><span>)</span><span> </span>-&gt; <span>_</span><span>&gt;</span><span>(</span><span>msg_send</span><span>);</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>utf8_ptr</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>utf8_method</span><span>(</span><span>description_obj</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>utf8_sel</span><span>);</span><span></span>
<span>    </span><span>println</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>CStr</span>::<span>from_ptr</span><span>(</span><span>utf8_ptr</span><span>).</span><span>to_string_lossy</span><span>());</span><span></span>
<span>  </span><span>}</span><span></span>
<span>}</span><span></span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>Now, this code should make most Rust users pretty horrified. It starts out okay, declaring some types and then declaring the Rust versions of the C API from libobjc. Then itâ€™s got a funny empty extern block to link the Foundation framework, but sure, thatâ€™s fine. And itâ€™s got explicitly-null-terminated strings because thatâ€™s what C-based APIs generally use. (Rust doesnâ€™t guarantee null termination by default, which makes slicing a Rust string easier.)</p>

<p>But then thereâ€™s a monstrosity of a line involving <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/mem/fn.transmute.html"><code>std::mem::transmute</code></a>, Rustâ€™s equivalent of Swiftâ€™s <code>unsafeBitCast(_:)</code> or C++â€™s <code>reinterpret_cast</code> (and now <a href="https://en.cppreference.com/w/cpp/numeric/bit_cast"><code>bit_cast</code></a>) or Câ€™sâ€¦well, okay, C doesnâ€™t have a direct equivalent, but a plain old cast when youâ€™re talking about function pointers like this. The <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/mem/fn.transmute.html">docs for <code>transmute</code></a> even tell you to go use other things if possible.</p>

<p>So, what are we doing? Well, remember what I said about Objective-C and <code>objc_msgSend</code>: methods are regular C functions, and <code>objc_msgSend</code> â€œjumps directly to the appropriate, polymorphically-selected implementation of the methodâ€�. That means that the correct way to call <code>objc_msgSend</code> is to <em>pretend it has the right type for the method youâ€™re calling.</em></p>

<p>In C (and Swift, for that matter), that conversion would require explicitly specifying the type of all arguments and return values. But Rust has really powerful type inference within a function body, and that extends to specifying only <em>some</em> generic parameters, and leaving others out.<sup id="fnref:swift-inference" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:swift-inference">2</a></sup> In this case I need to specify that weâ€™re casting to a C function pointer with two arguments and a non-void return, but not anything more than that. The remaining information will be filled in based on how the function pointer is used.</p>

<p>With that, you should understand the (cursed) code above. Go ahead. Try it on your own machine (if your machine is a Mac).</p>

<h2 id="recursive-rust-macros">Recursive Rust macros</h2>

<p>Rust has a pretty robust macro system, so it wouldnâ€™t be impossible or even too hard to make a macro for â€œmessage sendâ€�. Thatâ€™s the route that the <a href="https://crates.io/crates/objc"><code>objc</code> crate</a> takes:</p>

<div><pre><code><span></span><span>let</span><span> </span><span>url_class</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>class</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>NSURL</span><span>);</span><span></span>
<span>let</span><span> </span><span>description_obj</span>: <span>*</span><span>mut</span><span> </span><span>Object</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>msg_send</span><span>!</span><span>[</span><span>url_class</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>description</span><span>];</span><span></span>
<span>let</span><span> </span><span>utf8_ptr</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>msg_send</span><span>!</span><span>[</span><span>description_obj</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>UTF8String</span><span>];</span><span></span>
<span>println</span><span>!</span><span>(</span><span>"{}"</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>CStr</span>::<span>from_ptr</span><span>(</span><span>utf8_ptr</span><span>).</span><span>to_string_lossy</span><span>());</span><span></span>
</code></pre></div>

<p>But while thatâ€™s clearly the right choice for serious Rust work, I wanted something more ambitious. More integrated. Moreâ€¦ridiculous.</p>

<blockquote data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">wait a minute. this is just objective-c <a href="https://t.co/dVQMYKKVTI">pic.twitter.com/dVQMYKKVTI</a></p>— Harlan Haskins (@harlanhaskins) <a href="https://twitter.com/harlanhaskins/status/1133210047952015360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 28, 2019</a></blockquote>


<p>What I wanted was for Objective-Câ€™s messaging syntax, or something like it, to be valid anywhere in Rust code. It didnâ€™t have to be exactly Objective-C, but I quickly realized the <em>advantage</em> of Objective-Câ€™s syntax: itâ€™s delimited, i.e. itâ€™s a self-contained expression that can be dropped into something larger without changing how that larger thing parses. (Thatâ€™s probably why itâ€™s bracketed in C as well.) Within the brackets, thereâ€™s basically two forms:</p>

<pre><code>[receiver-expr no-arg-selector]
[receiver-expr selector-piece:arg-expr selector-piece:second-arg-expr...]
</code></pre>

<p>If I were <em>just</em> matching that, I could use Rustâ€™s original <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/ch19-06-macros.html#declarative-macros-with-macro_rules-for-general-metaprogramming">pattern-matching macros</a>. But to take a whole block of code, and replace everything that looks like a message lock <em>in</em> that blockâ€¦well, it might be possible with pattern-matching and quite a bit of recursion, but itâ€™s going to be a lot easier to use <em><a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2018/12/21/Procedural-Macros-in-Rust-2018.html">procedural macros</a>,</em> a Rust macro interface written in Rust and used as a compiler plugin. (Swift folks, basically what <a href="https://github.com/apple/swift-syntax">SwiftSyntax</a> allows you to do, but invoked on-demand during compilation.)</p>

<p>The procedural macro examples …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://belkadan.com/blog/2020/08/Objective-Rust/">https://belkadan.com/blog/2020/08/Objective-Rust/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://belkadan.com/blog/2020/08/Objective-Rust/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24309565</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 20:28:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Squad Wealth]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24309312">thread link</a>) | @Kinrany
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://otherinter.net/squad-wealth/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://otherinter.net/squad-wealth/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<p><img alt="SQUADS HAVE EXISTED FOR THOUSANDS OF YEARS" src="https://otherinter.net/squad-ancient.png"></p>
<p>Recent events&nbsp;have completely exposed the limits of individual agency, creating a powerful demand for squad-based forms of resiliency. The COVID-19 pandemic is the most recent of these social bonding agents: though we're <em>physically</em> distancing, <em>emotionally</em> we're getting closer. First priority when the virus dropped was securing your squad. The need for group coordination and decision-making soon followed.</p>
<p>But today's emerging culture of group cohesion is driven equally by the social and financial precarity of urban life. <em>Family are those we share space and rent with</em>. Priced out of tier-1 cities, individuals have banded together to survive a jobless market with no social safety net.</p>
<p>Squads are both a product of—and a response to—contemporary social atomization. The trope of "getting a place upstate" signifies young city-dwellers' desire for new kinds of squad-based homesteading. HOMESQUADING is a modern day <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back-to-the-land_movement">back-to-the-land movement</a>—swap Whole Earth-inspired post-war communes with post-internet surf clubs microblogging the virtues of cooperative housing, permaculture gardening, and solar-powered mesh networks.</p>
<p>Squad culture is the antithesis of neoliberal individualism. Millennials are healing from decades of irony poisoning, rediscovering what it's like to have generative, exploratory relationships with one another. Younger generations are already imbued with extremely powerful squad energy, equipped with formative experiences in Minecraft, DOTA 2, and Fortnite parties.</p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-ngram.png" alt="Military connotations aside, the arrival of group DMs ushers a new age of &quot;SQUAD&quot; discourse."></p>
<p>Military connotations aside, the arrival of group DMs ushers a new age of "SQUAD" discourse.</p>
<p>Whether bound together for survival or for lols, the squads formed by today's crisis will be resilient. Distance is no longer a barrier with the closeness of network space—soon vital culture will be predominantly enacted by fictive kin. Group collaboration is now the strong default, putting squads at the center of social, cultural, and economic life. To paraphrase Bill Bishop: today people are born as individuals, and have to find their squad.</p>

<p>While ancient squads were brought together by the struggle for survival, always-on group communication sets the scene for contemporary squad culture. Group chats and adapted team workspaces create shared context and institutional memory. One necessary condition of the squad is this sense of <em>persistence</em>: co-presence and continuous availability to one another.</p>
<p>But the squad is more than a loose network of affiliations, it's a coherent body. A second prerequisite of squad formation is self-recognition. It's not you or me. It's <em>Us</em>. <em>We.</em> <em>Ours</em>. This pillar often follows from the first. Squads may start as one-off Telegram channels, but they soon become "The Group Chat," a metonym for the squad itself.</p>
<p>For the squad to understand itself as a whole, it maintains boundaries circumscribing strong group norms. Fuck a Dunbar number—the ideal squad count is no more than 12. How can you really be <em>present</em> with more than a dozen people? Small groups are crucial for tight coordination. A greater network may surround the squad, making it appear big and fuzzy from the outside. But for the core crew, an invisible circle binds and protects a space of group identity.</p>
<p>As SQUAD VIBES grow, so does the possibility of interdependence and resource sharing—social, emotional, financial. Trust brought by consistent socialization and self-recognition is a foundation for exploring what the squad is capable of together. SQUAD CULTURE has only just <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kvJ7yW7Y3RY">begun</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-theory.png" alt="Theory of the squad"></p>

<p>The pandemic flipped the script on sharing space IRL, but our newly domestic reality only brought to the physical world what was already extremely online. Originally conceived as series of linked documents, Web 2.0 mass productization turned the internet into a series of linked interiors.</p>
<p>Today's squads are expressions of digital locality and the new squad era forces us to reconsider the individuated logic of early social networks. Contrary to early visions of hypertext, the internet is not a singular World Wide Web, traversed by individuals. To be online today is to enter the global arena. Mass social media are hazardous PvP zones no one should traverse without team support.</p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-network-groupings.png" alt="Network graph of twitter with people-based groupings"></p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-network.png" alt="Network graph of twitter"></p>
<p>The Twitter subcultures shown above are only a sliver of an expansive social deep web. Beneath this fuzzy graph is SQUAD SPACE, the network of inner-zones where digital microcultures are born: group DMs, Discords, Slacks, Keybases. Memes forged in SQUAD SPACE bubble out into the "clearnet" above, pwning NPCs on the <a href="https://www.ribbonfarm.com/2020/01/16/the-internet-of-beefs/">internet of beefs</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-spaces.png" alt="Evolution of squad spaces"></p>
<p>Squad culture is downstream of squad space, and the digital places squads inhabit are only getting more advanced. The Discord can suddenly be on calls together. The Keybase can now use Git. <a href="https://subpixel.space/entries/come-for-the-network-pay-for-the-tool/">The team toolkit defines its capabilities</a>, and different platforms enable different modes of squad thought. Squad space is more than environment, it's a collective body, a shared cognition layer. Squad space is where market-moving trades are planned, conspiracies are conceived, and memes are spawned. Members of the squad may live in different geographies—but within this space, everyone is on SQUAD TIME. <a href="https://aaronzlewis.com/blog/2020/07/07/the-garden-of-forking-memes/">The founding of a new group DM is year zero</a>.</p>
<p>Group dynamics ebb and flow with their environment, and nowhere more than SQUAD SPACE. Ecology calls this process “niche formation.” Online it's SQUAD CULTURE.</p>

<p>Inside the subterranean caves of the social deep web, chosen-kin groups grow their own culture. The squad doesn't need its own micro-currency—images, art, music, takes, shitposts, and, indeed, roasts are the native medium of exchange. Likewise squads have little use for internal financial incentives. Instead, playful exchanges produce trust, reciprocity, and VIBES—the ineffable group energy that squads value most. Accordingly, the core of squad production is the continuous production of the squad itself.</p>
<p>Evidenced by the power of crypto memetics, ragtag squads of shitposters have the power to define new forms of value based on their own esoteric social frameworks. Memeing produces "assets" that cannot be traditionally valued, but are capable of commanding cultural and economic movements.</p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-vibes.png" alt="Examples of squad vibes, including Twitch plays Pokemon, Chainlink $LINK Marines, Weird Sun Twitter, Brockhampton, Tik Tok Hype Houses, Theory of Vibe by Peli Grietzer, Bitcoin, and Headless Brands"></p>
<p>Memes, hot takes, internal language, 𝓪𝓮𝓼𝓽𝓱𝓮𝓽𝓲𝓬𝓼... artifacts that can only be formulated as a group are the mainstay of squad production. The group exudes potent SQUAD VIBES, and vibes attract. Outsiders want to share the vibe—sometimes for the social capital, sometimes because the content produced is of strategic value, and always because the energy is infectious. After enough fire in the group DM, some squads begin to externalize their social products. Podcasting is obviously a squad technology. Rapid publishing turns memes into whitepapers, quickly flooding the marketplace of ideas with locally-grown squad humor.</p>
<p>Whether formed by necessity or chance, once together the squad's potential for creative production is immeasurable. <a href="https://www.glass-bead.org/article/a-theory-of-vibe/?lang=enview">VIBE</a> is an unstable substance of high informtion density. In formalizing their vibes, squads may accidentally give birth to <a href="https://otherinter.net/web3/headless-brands/">headless brands</a>, virtual personalities, and pseudonymous entities they may not even be able to control. Thus the squad transitions from its youthful, entropic state, harnessing its vibes to create a source of unfathomable squad energy.</p>


<p>Group identity. Shared space. Vibes. These not only enable the creation of social capital, but strengthen the squad's capacity to organize, minimizing transaction costs and leading to greater productive capacities and resilience; this is "<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Nature_of_the_Firm">the nature of the squad</a>." But while squads can be viewed as a "nexus of contracts", unlike the Coasean firm, they are without legal structure. Social contracts are instead effected through the unspoken bonds of <a href="https://medium.com/enspiral-tales/the-vibes-theory-of-organisational-design-937a73f791cd">mutual respect and ingroup norms</a>.</p>
<p>But to sustain this solidarity economy the squad may look for ways to translate vibes into monetizable modes of public engagement: clients, subscribers, sponsors, music deals, yields. SQUAD PRODUCTION begins with the creation of processes and interfaces to convert creative labor into units that can be transmitted by global network participants. Here SQUAD TOOLS come into play. Vibes generated at the DAW, on the Figma board, or in the gaming lobby are turned consumable cultural instruments. Then it's just a matter of distribution. Young artists create online galleries and independent labels because they allow groups to interact (and transact) with the world through familiar organizational patterns. Bandcamps, Twitch pages, DAOs are public APIs for squads to interact with entities beyond their trust boundary.</p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-trust-stream.png" alt="Example of a Twitch stream from Berlin-based Trust (squad)"></p>
<p>Some digital tools are public interfaces, while others are used to coordinate internally. Today this SQUAD INFRASTRUCTURE is comprised of simple software primitives: Venmo, Splitwise, Cash App. These apps are financial plumbing that facilitate internal coordination between squad members by minimizing the awkwardness of asking your friends for money. Despite the strong demand for SQUAD RESILIENCY, the social stigma of group finances is still a major barrier to economic exchange among friends.</p>
<p>In-app mechanics like budget trackers, polls, and coin-flips offer a half-way point between social agreements and technical solutions. For instance Splitwise relies heavily on the social norms to ensure expenses are entered accurately. By allowing individuals to opt-in to a set of rules for retroactive settlement the group's social friction and coordination costs are reduced. Civilization advances by extending the number of important functions squads can perform without thinking.</p>
<p>Some believe new software can liberate "individual creators." But this kind of thinking inevitably leads to Uberized platform-mediated wage labor. We want to liberate squads. <em>The <strong>group</strong> is the basic user class for the tools we need today as a society, yet few pieces of software allow the squad as a whole to produce cooperatively and generate wealth together</em>. To fully realize SQUAD CULTURE this must change.</p>
<p><img src="https://otherinter.net/squad-2x2.png" alt="Squad collectivism is a better form of autonomy than neoliberal individualism"></p>

<p>With new plug-and-play financial tools, squads are becoming more …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://otherinter.net/squad-wealth/">https://otherinter.net/squad-wealth/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://otherinter.net/squad-wealth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24309312</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 20:03:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Firefox 80 and my confusion over its hardware accelerated video on Linux]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 114 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24307277">thread link</a>) | @eitau_1
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/Firefox80VideoAccelConfusion | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/Firefox80VideoAccelConfusion">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Firefox 80 and my confusion over its hardware accelerated video on Linux</h2>

	<p><small>August 28, 2020</small></p>
</div><div><p>The news of the time interval is that Firefox 80 is out and in
theory it can support hardware video acceleration on X11, not just
Wayland (<a href="https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2020/08/firefox-80-release-linux-gpu-acceleration">source</a>,
<a href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Firefox-80-Released">also</a>).
The master Mozilla tracking bug for hardware accelerated video on
X11 is <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1619523">bug #1619523</a>, with all
sorts of information. So I downloaded the official release (one of
my Firefox setups uses the official builds these days for reasons
beyond the scope of this entry) and tried to get it to do accelerated
video playback. The short version is that I think I've failed, but I'm
not sure why.</p>

<p>Even in Firefox 80, getting VA-API accelerated video playback
requires a whole series of magic incantations in <code>about:config</code>
preferences and perhaps environment variables when you start Firefox
(this may change in the next release). Assuming that all of those
are set right, Firefox can apparently still decide that it doesn't
like your Linux video driver (or its version), your specific hardware,
or perhaps either or both of the resolution of the source video and
the resolution of your display. Some or many of these can be forced
with Firefox settings, but at the same time the bug reports I've
read say that sometimes Firefox ignores hardware acceleration because
it's slower for the specific circumstances, or because it has known
bugs. If Firefox is making a sensible decision for <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/linux/HomeMachine2018">my specific
hardware</a>, that's one thing and I want
it to do what will work best. But if I've missed a setting or if
Firefox is just being twitchy about something, I also want to
override it. In general I know my hardware is capable of hardware
accelerated playback of videos at far lower CPU usage than Firefox
manages (on the same videos).</p>

<p>Unfortunately, Firefox won't tell me what it's doing or why, at
least not in a way that I can understand. I've peered into the
depths of <code>about:support</code>, which tells me some of the 'what' but
not the 'why', and I've tried some of the things from <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1619523">bug #1619523</a>
without success. If Firefox is or isn't going to do hardware
accelerated video playback, I wish it would tell me both what it was
doing and why. Otherwise I'm probably going to go on being confused
and annoyed with it.</p>

<p>(I care about hardware acceleration not just because of CPU load
but because my perception is that hardware acceleration is necessary
to play back a full sized video smoothly without dropping frames
every so often. This may be wrong on modern hardware, even on my 4k
display.)</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/Firefox80VideoAccelConfusion</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24307277</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 17:06:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: 3D first person game rendered in CSS/HTML]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 279 | Comments 91 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24305834">thread link</a>) | @pantelisk
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://pantel.is/projects/css3d/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pantel.is/projects/css3d/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="sb" onclick="window.SetBright(this,event,0)">
	<div>
		<p>Part 1</p>
		<p>Part 2</p>
		<p>Part 3</p>
	</div>

	<p>Adjust your screen brightness, until text on the left is not visible, and the text in the center is barely visible.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pantel.is/projects/css3d/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24305834</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 15:14:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Painting a better life through side SaaS hustles]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24305484">thread link</a>) | @sergiomattei
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://getmakerlog.com/stories/micah-iverson-founder-and-ceo-of-retrospect | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://getmakerlog.com/stories/micah-iverson-founder-and-ceo-of-retrospect">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>"This was a very special interview for me since it was my first at Makerlog. I hope you enjoy reading it as much as I enjoyed making it. I want to thank Micah for giving me the opportunity to learn from him and showcase his work to our community." -Leilany</p><h2 id="tell-us-a-bit-about-yourself-">Tell us a bit about yourself!</h2><figure><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/NnSAWn7UoXi8GS8REutxeE0cVfrnAae2YeqMWOGcj0Iw4DRaoSHUOTRyZLZl73ZEfujCiecwTzKOrdYzkEVZYkbcChPHZq4cJtksDXbfHbV6kafDilLX-A6kmLIIUw"></figure><p>Hello, my name is Micah Iverson. I am many things: Husband, Father, Designer, Developer, Entrepreneur, and Interior House Painter to name a few. My wife and I have been married since 2016 and have two boys (10 and 12). We live in Castle Rock Colorado, which is located about 30 minutes South of Denver. I am originally from Iowa, have lived in Minnesota, and of course now Colorado.</p><p>I have two degrees, one in design and another in 3D Animation. I have also studied computer science, photography, pottery, and grew up helping my dad build and remodel things. <em>(He is a carpenter/cabinet builder.)</em></p><p>In September of 2018, I stepped away from my design and development career and started my own interior house painting company which has continued to be extremely successful and continues to grow. In my free time, I focus on my own personal, digital products to relax and hopefully, one day will be my primary focus and revenue source.</p><h2 id="what-are-you-making">What are you making?</h2><p>As many people know, I make a lot of things, of which you can check out here: <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.krazier.com&amp;sa=D&amp;ust=1598466186406000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0RVfOCL3YgTIhIkAVAXbe8">https://www.krazier.com</a> but the one I spend a lot of my time on and has been growing the fastest is Retrospect. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.retrospect.team&amp;sa=D&amp;ust=1598466186406000&amp;usg=AOvVaw18nsSYhG0Y9pINGNtWMKO0">https://www.retrospect.team</a></p><p>Retrospect is a real-time collaboration tool for retrospectives, tasks, and ideas.</p><h2 id="how-did-the-idea-for-your-product-come-to-mind">How did the idea for your product come to mind?</h2><p>I was working for a company a couple of years ago and we needed a tool to do retrospectives and the existing solutions we found were not designed well and didnâ€™t work all that great, not to mention the bigger solutions costing a lot of money to use for a relatively small need that we had. I set out to build a simple, affordable solution that looked good too.</p><h2 id="what-inspired-you-to-make-your-product">What inspired you to make your product?</h2><figure><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/wmkyhgs67HaZAalvciwqT6cj56V3OKmQQdK9SojC05r4XwoelQxx7YjFCk3t_Hst_HHV7-yXuXpD8FqWziizHUeAMW6T-BTTbfeGwVC8m2p-iNoaXEsFipWMuIoytQ"><figcaption>Retrospect.</figcaption></figure><p>As mentioned above, it was originally out of necessity, but it is become a bit of a passion project to see just how far I can take it. With the Covid19 lockdown situation, this type of tool has only become more important for businesses to take advantage of.</p><p>Retrospect is purposefully â€œsimpleâ€�, we did not set out to make another Trello or Asana type of tool. Those tools are great and are a nice compliment to what we are building. One important focus for us has been â€œanonymityâ€� in the product. With Retrospectives, it is important to be able to provide critical feedback, it can be hard to do that if there is the potential for your co-workers to get upset with something you may have said. With Retrospect, everything you publish to a board is kept anonymous so that you can give that critical feedback without fear of retaliation.</p><p>Retrospect will always be affordable; we want this service to be approachable to as many people as possible while still being worth our time financially. We provide great pricing and a great solution and hope people will recognize that and find value in what we offer.</p><blockquote>I make because it is fun, I make because I know how, I love the challenge, the risk, and the huge potential it offers.</blockquote><h2 id="why-embark-on-the-maker-s-journey">Why embark on the makerâ€™s journey?</h2><p>I have always enjoyed building things, from Legos and plastic models to do-it-yourself projects around the house and of course digital designs and products. We live in a world that is very digital and very accessible for anyone to learn to design or code their own software. With tools like Makerlog, we can now share our progress, connect with other makers, and build things together. By nature, building software is often an â€œindividualâ€� thing to do, so having resources to connect with others makes the journey a lot more fun and open to learning from so many types of people.</p><p>A lot of people have a bit of an ambition to make something, whether it is art, electronics, gardening, woodworking, jewelry, or software. It is a way for us to get away from the day-to-day requirements in our lives and focus on something that we love to do without the stress of having to do it for anyone else. I make because it is fun, I make because I know how, I love the challenge, the risk, and the huge potential it offers.</p><h2 id="how-do-you-see-the-future-of-your-product">How do you see the future of your product?</h2><p>Retrospect has come a long way since the initial launch about two years ago, we have provided more permissions, more functionality, and improved the experience. The future has a lot of potential for new features and growth.</p><p>With the number of projects, I work on, I tend to push out a lot of smaller updates rather than huge feature releases. It is easier for us to manage and it also does not overwhelm our uses with huge UI changes that might make the tool unexpectedly harder for them to use.</p><p>As we continue to push out updates, our user audience will continue to expand. At first, our focus was on â€œretrospectivesâ€� which mostly development teams would find value in, the average person does not need a retrospective tool in their day-to-day lives. We are working towards making this a tool that has a useful impact on a daily level both professionally and personally. This means new types of functionality and a refreshed focus on our marketing and branding. Some of which will be happing over the coming weeks.</p><h2 id="as-of-today-what-are-your-stats">As of today, what are your stats?</h2><p>As of today, our stats areâ€¦</p><ul><li><strong>Users:</strong> 6,290</li><li><strong>Boards:</strong> 3,925</li><li><strong>Cards:</strong> 48,947</li><li><strong>Monthly Pageviews:</strong> 10K+</li><li><strong>Revenue:</strong> $2K+ (We will be switching to a subscription model soon.)</li></ul><h2 id="how-do-you-use-makerlog">How do you use Makerlog?</h2><p>I post my daily updates but try to focus on important tasks rather than â€œI had a coffee todayâ€�, I do not want to spam the feed with things that are not important to know. I read most of the discussions and contribute when it makes sense.</p><p>I love Makerlog because it has allowed me to meet so many people that I never would have met any other way (other than maybe through Twitter). I feel like I have some lifelong friends despite having never met anyone in person, yet.</p><blockquote>I love Makerlog because it has allowed me to meet so many people that I never would have met any other way (other than maybe through Twitter).</blockquote><h2 id="what-are-the-biggest-challenges-of-being-a-maker">What are the biggest challenges of being a maker?</h2><p>The life of a maker is basically learning to deal with challenges daily, things you never would have thought you have to deal with. The bigger, more obvious challenges are lack of motivation, lack of revenue, and plain old fear.</p><p>Motivation, as makers we are by default motivated to work on things, that is what makes us a maker in the first place. The challenge comes into play when you have been working on something for a long time and it just feels like it will never be completed. There is always that â€œone more thingâ€� to do, person to reach out to, reason not to go live. When you do almost everything yourself, you simply get exhausted and lack of motivation is inevitable. Iâ€™m not sure itâ€™s a bad thing, it just means you need to learn how to renew that motivation to push forward. For me I like to go to or watch movies, it is one easy way for me to reset my mind and get back into thigs. I also like to clean my desk or house, make a list of every task I have, and then work through the easy ones as fast as possible since lack of motivation often comes from knowing you should be doing something else so you end up doing nothing at all. If you can get the easy things done, then it helps you get motivated again.</p><p>Lack of revenue, this is a devastating challenge to a lot of people. We often see those â€œovernight successâ€� stories, that usually are not overnight. Though, these days we are seeing a lot of people who will literally build something one day and have a lot of success the next, the question is how long-term is that success? The obvious goal of being a maker is to generate revenue so you can get away from that 9-5 job, the unobvious issue is that it can take years to get enough revenue to do that. A lot of people do not realize this fact and give up too early and go back to what they were doing before. We also canâ€™t â€œdo it allâ€� so we often have to hire some pieces out, if you have no revenue, this becomes a big burden and can literally prevent you from even finishing your project.</p><p>Fear, people have a lot of fear in their minds. It is an important thing to be aware of and work on as being maker means dealing with a lot of unknowns. Fear is a good motivator though; it can force you to learn something faster than you thought possible. When I first started launching products, I was scared to death. Now that I have launched so many projects, I barely stress out at all. It just comes with practice and experience to get over or at least manage your fears.</p><p>You are likely not able to cause too much damage with something you build, so go out and build something, launch it, and learn from it. The more you do it, the more interesting it becomes.</p><blockquote>The more you fail the more you learn.</blockquote><h2 id="managing-so-many-projects-how">Managing so many projects, how?</h2><p>As of right now, I have 11 public projects plus my day job, plus several new projects I am working on and my #MakerMillion journey. It looks like a lot, it is a lot, but it is not as crazy as it sounds.</p><p>Retrospect is my primary focus; I spend the most time on this project compared to any other one I have (outside of my day job). Everything else sort of just â€œruns itselfâ€�, I have very little time commitment reserved for them on a day-to-day basis. Yes, I work on them, but it is not a constant, urgent requirement. Some things I have not hardly touched in months, partly because I am focused on other things and partly because I just lose interest in them for a while.</p><p>I work in cycles and sprints, I will come up with a feature idea, work hard on it for a week or two, launch it and then move onto the next thing. I do this over and over across all my projects. If I tried to focus on one thing, for a long time, I would get super bored with it, I like having the ability to jump around. This approach very likely prevents me …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://getmakerlog.com/stories/micah-iverson-founder-and-ceo-of-retrospect">https://getmakerlog.com/stories/micah-iverson-founder-and-ceo-of-retrospect</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://getmakerlog.com/stories/micah-iverson-founder-and-ceo-of-retrospect</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24305484</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:45:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bcrypt Step-by-Step]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 73 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24305247">thread link</a>) | @lanecwagner
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://qvault.io/2020/08/24/bcrypt-step-by-step/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://qvault.io/2020/08/24/bcrypt-step-by-step/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>Bcrypt is a <a href="https://qvault.io/2019/12/30/very-basic-intro-to-key-derivation-functions-argon2-scrypt-etc/">key derivation function</a>, which can be thought of as a slow <a href="https://qvault.io/2020/01/01/very-basic-intro-to-hash-functions-sha-256-md-5-etc/">hash function</a>. Its purpose is to <em>slowly</em> convert a piece of input data to a fixed-size, deterministic, and unpredictable output. A common use-case is to convert a password into an n-bit cryptographic key, which can then be used for safe authentication. </p>



<p>Here at <a href="https://classroom.qvault.io/">Qvault,</a> we use Bcrypt in our security systems. Bcrypt is a very popular password hashing function, so much so that it’s the hash function we currently teach the implementation of in our <a href="https://classroom.qvault.io/">Practical Cryptography</a> course.</p>



<h2>What Bcrypt Looks Like</h2>



<p>Using Bcrypt on the password <em>myPassword123</em> would produce something like the following:</p>



<pre><strong><em>myPassword123</em> </strong>-&gt;
$2y$12$vUw4OU4EAl4w4vC6/lA33OtDSYGhiIdekdT9iOoSs9/ckwrffaEui</pre>



<p>That output can be used to compare against future hashes against to see if the original data matches.</p>



<h2>Why not compare passwords directly?</h2>



<p>In web development,<em> </em>it is insecure to store user’s passwords in plain text. If an attacker were to gain access to the server’s database they could find raw email/password combinations and use them to attack the same users on other sites. </p>



<p>At the <em>very least</em> we must hash user’s passwords, but hash functions like <a href="https://qvault.io/2020/07/08/how-sha-2-works-step-by-step-sha-256/">SHA-2</a> and MD5 are too fast to be secure. Using a KDF like Bcrypt provides security benefits over fast hashes because it is computationally expensive and slow. If an attacker gains access to a database of password hashes made with fast algorithms it is easy for them to “reverse” the hashes by guessing different inputs and seeing if the outputs match.</p>



<p>For example, let’s say the attacker finds the following entry in a database:</p>



<pre>user@gmail.com 5906ac361a137e2d286465cd6588ebb5ac3f5ae955001100bc41577c3d751764</pre>



<p>They can try hashing common passwords like:</p>



<pre>password1 -&gt;
0b14d501a594442a01c6859541bcb3e8164d183d32937b851835442f69d5c94e
password2 -&gt;
6cf615d5bcaac778352a8f1f3360d23f02f34ec182e259897fd6ce485d7870d4
password3 -&gt; 5906ac361a137e2d286465cd6588ebb5ac3f5ae955001100bc41577c3d751764</pre>



<p><br>The password, <code>password3</code>, produced a matching hash! Now the attacker knows that <code>user@gmail.com</code> is likely to use the password <code>password3</code> on other sites and can go hack other accounts. This is only possible because the attacker is able to quickly compute many hashes per second and guess millions of potential passwords.</p>



<p>A slow KDF like Bcrypt solves this problem.</p>



<h2>Bcrypt Output Format</h2>



<pre>$2a$10$N9qo8uLOickgx2ZMRZoMyeIjZAgcfl7p92ldGxad68LJZdL17lhWy
\___/\__/\_____________________________/\___________________________________/
Alg   Cost                  Salt                                            Hash</pre>



<ul><li><code>2a</code>: The hash algorithm identifier (Bcrypt)</li><li><code>10</code>: Cost factor (2<sup><code>10</code></sup>&nbsp;= 1,024 rounds of key expansion)</li><li><code>N9qo8uLOickgx2ZMRZoMye</code>: 16-byte (128-bit) salt, base64 encoded to 22 characters</li><li><code>IjZAgcfl7p92ldGxad68LJZdL17lhWy</code>: 24-byte (192-bit) hash, base64 encoded to 31 characters</li></ul>



<p>Direct from <a aria-label="Wikipedia (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt#Description" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a></p>



<h2>Bcrypt Explained Step by Step</h2>



<p>Bcrypt can be visualized with the following Go-like pseudo code:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">func bcrypt(cost int, salt [16]byte, password [72]byte) (hash string) {
	// Initialize Blowfish state with expensive key setup algorithm
	// This is the slow part of the algorithm
	pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes := expensiveBlowfishSetup(cost, salt, password)

	// Repeatedly encrypt the text "OrpheanBeholderScryDoubt" 64 times
	// 24 bytes = three 64-bit blocks
	ctext := "OrpheanBeholderScryDoubt"
	for i := 0; i &lt; 64; i++ {
		// Encrypt using standard Blowfish in ECB mode
		ctext = encryptECB(pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes, ctext)
	}

	// return the version, cost, salt, and ctext in the proper format
	return "$2a${cost}${salt}{ctext}"
}</code></pre>



<p>As you can see, Bcrypt depends heavily on the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blowfish_(cipher)" rel="noopener">Blowfish</a> cipher. Put simply, Bcrypt is an expensive key expansion coupled with Blowfish encryption.</p>



<p>The <code>expensiveBlowfishSetup</code> function can be understood by following pseudo code:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">// pEighteenSubkeys: array of 18 subkeys
// sFourSubBoxes: Four substitution boxes
// Each S-Box is a 256-length array of uint32
func expensiveBlowfishSetup(cost int, salt [16]byte, password [72]byte) (pEighteenSubkeys [18]uint32, sFourSubBoxes [4][256]uint32) {
	// Initialize arrays
	pEighteenSubkeys := [18]uint32
	sFourSubBoxes := [4][256]uint32

	// Fill pEighteenSubkeys and sFourSubBoxes with the hex digits of pi 
	// This initial state works as in the original Blowfish algorithm
	// it populates the P-array and S-box entries with the fractional part of pi in hexadecimal
	pEighteenSubkeys = fillWithPi(pEighteenSubkeys)
	sFourSubBoxes = fillWithPi(sFourSubBoxes)

	// Permutate P and S based on the password and salt
	pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes = expandKey(pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes, salt, password)

	// This is the "Expensive" part of the "Expensive Key Setup"
	// Otherwise the key setup would be identical to Blowfish
	// Expand the key an exponentially increasing number of times
	// depending on the cost factor
	for i := 0; i &lt; math.Pow(2, cost); i++ {
		pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes = expandKey(pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes, 0, password)
		pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes = expandKey(pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes, 0, salt)
	}

	return pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes
}</code></pre>



<p><code>The expandKey function</code> is executed an exponentially increasing number of times depending on the value of the <code>cost</code> parameter. The <code>expandKey</code> function is explained by the following pseudo-code:</p>



<pre><code lang="go">func expandKey(pEighteenSubkeys [18]uint32, sFourSubBoxes [4][256]uint32, salt [16]byte, password [72]byte) (
	pEighteenSubkeys [18]uint32, sFourSubBoxes [4][256]uint32
	) {

	// Mix password into the pEighteenSubkeys array
	// by XORing password with subkeys
	for i := 0; i &lt; 18; i++{
		// treat the password as cyclic, XOR 32 bit chunks of password with subkeys
		pEighteenSubkeys[i] ^= password[i % 18]
	}
 
   // Treat the 128-bit salt as two 64-bit halves 
   saltHalf[0] = salt[0:63]
   saltHalf[1] = salt[64:127]

   // Initialize an 8-byte (64-bit) buffer with all zeros.
   block := [8]byte

   // Mix internal state into P-boxes   
   for i := 0; i &lt; 9; i++ {
	  // XOR 64-bit block with a 64-bit salt half
	  // Each iteration alternating between saltHalf[0], and saltHalf[1]
      block ^= saltHalf[(i-1) mod 2]

	  // Encrypt block using current key schedule with blowfish block encryption
	  block = Encrypt(pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes, block)
	  
	  // Split block and use as new subkeys
      pEighteenSubkeys[2*i] = block[0:31]
	  pEighteenSubkeys[2*i + 1] = block[32:63]
   }

   // Mix encrypted state into the internal S-boxes of state
   for i := 0; i &lt; 4; i ++ {
      for j := 0; j &lt; 127; j++ {
		// Encrypt block using blowfish block encryption
		// where salt[i] is 64 bit chunks
        block = Encrypt(pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes, block ^ salt[i])
        sFourSubBoxes[2*i] = block[0:31]
		sFourSubBoxes[2*i + 1] = block[32:63]
	  }
	}
    return pEighteenSubkeys, sFourSubBoxes
}</code></pre>



<p>It helps me to visualize the details of the pseudo-code by using a more “real” programming syntax like Go. If that doesn’t help you then take a look at the code on the <a aria-label="Wikipedia (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bcrypt#Algorithm" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a> page here.</p>



<div><div>
<h2>Thanks For Reading!</h2>



<p>Follow us on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/q_vault" rel="noopener">@q_vault</a> if you have any questions or comments</p>



<p>Take game-like coding courses on <a href="https://classroom.qvault.io/#/">Qvault Classroom</a></p>



<p><a href="https://mailchi.mp/5c7f5c281bbe/qvault-newsletter-subscribe" rel="noopener">Subscribe</a> to our Newsletter for more educational articles</p>
</div></div>



<h2>Related Articles</h2>



<ul><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/07/08/how-sha-2-works-step-by-step-sha-256/">SHA-2 Step by Step</a></li><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/08/18/very-basic-shamirs-secret-sharing/">Shamir’s Secret Sharing Step by Step</a></li><li><a href="https://qvault.io/2020/07/27/very-basic-intro-to-pgp-gpg/">Basic Intro to PGP</a></li></ul>

		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://qvault.io/2020/08/24/bcrypt-step-by-step/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24305247</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 14:27:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Is Cyberpunk Dead? A Conversation with Bruce Bethke]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 144 | Comments 155 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24304799">thread link</a>) | @keiferski
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://www.markeverglade.com/iscyberpunkdead | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.markeverglade.com/iscyberpunkdead">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.markeverglade.com/iscyberpunkdead</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24304799</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 13:52:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[100 years to solve an integral: The history of the Mercator map]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24304311">thread link</a>) | @the_origami_fox
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://liorsinai.github.io/mathematics/2020/08/27/secant-mercator.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://liorsinai.github.io/mathematics/2020/08/27/secant-mercator.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div>
      <div>

        <p><em>The integral of the secant is well known to any beginners calculus student. Yet this integral was once a major outstanding maths problem. It was first introduced by Geradus Mercator, who needed it to make his famous map, in 1569. He couldn’t find it, and used an approximation instead. The exact solution was found accidently 86 years later without calculus in 1645. It then took another two decades until a formal proof was given in 1668, 99 years after Mercator first proposed the problem.</em></p>

<p>As this <a href="https://www.smbc-comics.com/comic/how-math-works">comic</a> by SMBC rightly teases, the history of mathematics is often not so straightforward. 
Theorems, formulas and notation that are routinely discussed in class, were once insights or accidents themselves.
This is the story of one such formula, the integral of the secant. 
I first read about it almost a decade ago<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>, when I got interested in cartography: the science and art of mapmaking. 
This integral is of vital importance to the Mercator map, and therefore many online maps that use it, like <a href="https://www.apple.com/ios/maps/">Apple Maps</a> and <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/">Google Maps</a>.</p>

<p>This story has been told several times before: see <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/3603395">1</a>, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/0025570X.1980.11976846">2</a> or <a href="https://scholarworks.umt.edu/tme/vol7/iss2/12/">3</a>.
But these are all journal articles, consigned mostly to academics.
I want to present it here in a less formal and more colourful setting, to make it more accessible.</p>

<p>This is an article about mathematics, so familiarity with the following is helpful: algebra, trigonometry, radians and basic calculus. 
These are usually covered in advanced high school maths classes or first year maths courses.</p>

<h2 id="first-year-maths">First year maths</h2>

<p>In first year maths at university, after a month of differentiation, we were starting the inverse problem: integration. 
Differentiation  is the mathematics of finding gradient functions for curves.
Integration is the mathematics of inverting this - given a gradient function, what is the curve? 
My lecturer was introducing the integration of trigonometric functions.
He started off with:</p><p>

\[\int sin(x) dx = -cos(x) + c \:\text{  and } \int cos(x) dx = sin(x) + c\]

</p><p>This relationship made sense, because sine and cosine derivatives were opposites. Just had to be careful of minus signs. Next he derived the integral for the tangent:</p><p>

\[\int tan(x) dx = \int \frac{sin(x)}{cos(x)}dx = -ln|cos(x)| + c\]

</p><p>Ok, that was tricky. It was not immediately obvious that the inverse of the chain rule could be used here, because the function $cos(x)$ was present with its derivative $sin(x)$.
But given enough thought, it made sense. Then he said, this is the integral of the secant, and learn it off by heart:</p><p>

\[\int sec(x) dx = ln|sec(x) + tan(x)| + c\]

</p><p>OK, where did that come from? My lecturer offered no explanation. It was easy to verify that it worked by finding the derivative. 
(Paper <a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/0025570X.1980.11976846">2</a> has a more complex proof using only integration.)
But how had he come up with that?</p>

<p>I think, at this point, most first year calculus students like me have the following fleeting thoughts:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Integration is much harder than differentiation.</li>
  <li>Some mathematician must have stumbled on this through differentiation first.</li>
  <li>It doesn’t matter anyway because where will I ever use this?</li>
</ol>

<p>Actually, number 1 is true, as many a student can testify after writing a test. 
Number 2 is false - in fact it was found by a teacher while looking at raw numbers. 
Such a method for finding an integral is so unusual, that one might conjecture it is the <em>only</em> integral that has been found like this.
Surely in calculus class, where raw numbers are so rare, you would be laughed at if you attempted to solve an integral like that.
Lastly, number 3 remains true for me. But this doesn’t mean this integral isn’t useful - it is used to construct the Mercator map. 
That is why a teacher was crunching numbers when he serendipitously realised what the formula was.</p>

<h2 id="quick-revision-trigonometry">Quick revision: trigonometry</h2>

<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/secant_def.png" alt="Definition of the secant">
</figure>

<p>The secant is a standard trigonometric function. It is defined as the ratio of the hypotenuse $c$ to the adjacent side $a$ for an angle $\varphi$ in a right angled triangle.
In mathematical notation, the definition is:</p><p>

\[sec(\varphi) = \frac{c}{a}\]

</p><p>It is the reciprocal of the more widely used cosine function:</p><p>

\[sec(\varphi) = \frac{1}{cos(\varphi)}\]

</p><p>Here are the graphs of the secant and cosine for the angles from $-2\pi$ (-360°) to $2\pi$ (360°):</p>

<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/secant_graph.png" alt="Definition of the secant">
</figure>

<p>The integral of the secant can be interpreted as the area under the graph<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>. This is illustrated by the shaded region.</p>

<h2 id="an-introduction-to-cartography">An introduction to cartography</h2>

<p>The earth, which is a sphere<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup>, cannot be projected onto a flat map without distortion. 
Over the years, cartographers have devised many different map projections which try to balance minimising distortion with other properties. 
They come in all shapes and sizes.
Lists of these projections can be found <a href="https://map-projections.net/singleview.php">here</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_map_projections">here</a>.
I will explain two of the simplest here, which will help with understanding the Mercator map in the next section.</p>

<p>All map projections can be represented as equations that transform spherical co-ordinates to flat map co-ordinates.
The co-ordinates on the sphere are the angles $\varphi$ and $\lambda$. These correspond to lines of latitude (parallels) and longitude (meridans) respectively. 
The co-ordinates on the flat map are $x$ and $y$. A map projection is therefore a transformation from $\varphi$ and $\lambda$ to $x$ and $y$.</p>

<p>One of the simplest and oldest known projections is the equirectangular projection:</p>

<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/equirectangular.png" alt="Equirectangular map">
	<figcaption>Equirectangular map. From <a href="https://map-projections.net/single-view/rectang-0">map-projections.net/singleviewp/rectang-0</a>  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>It is made by mapping meridians and parallels to vertical and horizontal straight lines of constant spacing.
This has the affect of stretching out objects along the parallels.
The equations for this projection are:</p><p>

\[\begin{align} y &amp;= R\varphi\\ x &amp;= R\lambda \end{align}\]

</p><p>While the equations are simple, the construction process can be hard to visualise. Here is my attempt:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/equirectangular_construction.png" alt="Equirectangular map construction">
	<figcaption>A segment of the sphere is peeled off and flattened.
The right most image shows a top view of the flattening. The arcs are pulled flat in the longitudial direction, so that they become straight lines.
They do not change length in this process, but that requires stretching out the sides along the $x$-axis. 
Thus a single point where all the arcs meet, is stretched into a line.   </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The equirectangular map has a total area of $(2\pi R)(\pi R)=2\pi^2 R^2$ while the surface area of the sphere is $4\pi R^2$. 
Therefore this projection distorts the area by a factor of $\frac{\pi}{2}\approx1.57$.</p>

<p>A different kind of projection can be obtained by projecting lines from the sphere onto the mapping plane. 
An example is the Lambert cylindrical projection. 
It is made by wrapping a cylinder around the sphere and projecting points onto it via lines parallel to the $x$-axis. 
Here is a visualisation of this construction:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/Cilinderprojectie-constructie.jpg" alt="Lambert cylindrical map construction">
	<figcaption>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Cilinderprojectie-constructie.jpg">Wikipedia</a>  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>And here is a cross section of the sphere along side the final map:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/Lambert_construction.png" alt="Lambert cylindrical  map">
	<figcaption>Lambert cylindrical  map. Edited from <a href="https://map-projections.net/single-view/lambert">map-projections.net/singleviewp/lambert</a>  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The equations are:</p><p>

\[\begin{align} y &amp;= Rsin(\varphi)\\ x &amp;= R\lambda \end{align}\]

</p><p>For objects near the equator, this results in very little distortion, such as for Africa. But objects near the poles are compressed because of the sphere’s curvature. 
This can be seen clearly with Greenland.</p>

<p>This map has the useful property that its area is equal to the surface area of the sphere. Thus, while objects are distorted, their areas are still correct.
The relative scale of Greenland to Africa is therefore accurately represented in this map.</p>

<h2 id="the-mercator-map">The Mercator map</h2>

<p>In 1569, Gerardus Mercator wanted to make a global world map that would be useful for navigation. 
He lived in a time when sailing across vast ocean distances was the norm. (In 1492, Christopher Columbus had discovered America by sailing all the way from Spain.)
The maps shown above are fine for artistic impressions and applications, but not for navigation.
The distortions prevent doing any accurate distance and bearing measurements on the map. 
At a local level, lines (eg. roads) which in reality intersect perpendicularly to each other, would be appear to be slanted with respect to each other.</p>

<p>In particular, Mercator wanted to make a map where rhumb lines would be straight. Rhumb lines are curves of constant bearing relative to meridians. 
To follow a rhumb line, a navigator only needs to maintain the same bearing on their compass for the whole journey.
For example, here is the rhumb line through modern day New York and Cape Town:</p>

<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/NY_to_CPT.png" alt="Arcs from NY to CPT">
	<figcaption>Made with software from <a href="https://imaginary.org/program/rhumb-lines-and-spirals">imaginary.org/program/rhumb-lines-and-spirals</a> and Inkscape </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>At each point along the rhumb line, the angle $\theta$ with the meridian is 48.56°, which corresponds to a bearing of 311°26’18’’ from Cape Town to New York. 
I’ve also shown the great circle, which is a circle whose centre lies on the centre of the sphere. 
Travelling along the great circle is always shorter. In this case, the distance is 12550 km instead of 12600 km along the rhumb line.
With modern technology, it is easy for ships and aeroplanes to stick to the great circles. But back in Mercator’s day, this was rather difficult. 
So sailors preferred to stick to rhumb lines. They would rather get to their destination by travelling a little longer, then get lost and travel a lot more.</p>

<p>Mercator’s idea was to stretch out a cylindrical projection map in the North-South direction to preserve shapes and angles.
Looking at the Lambert projection<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup>, it can be seen that a different stretch factor is required for each latitude. At the equator, no stretch is required.
At the 45° parallel only a small amount of upward stretching is required. The objects close to the poles have to be stretched a lot to uncompress them.</p>

<p>This stretch factor can be calculated as follows:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://liorsinai.github.io/assets/posts/secant-mercator/Mercator_construction.png" alt="Mercator construction">
	<figcaption>Construction process for the Mercator map. Edited from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercator_projection"> Wikipedia</a> images </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>First Mercator divided the globe into graticules of equal spacing $\delta\varphi$ and $\delta\lambda$. 
Along the meridians, the arc length of each graticule is $R\delta\varphi$.
Along the parallels, the radius of the circle is …</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://liorsinai.github.io/mathematics/2020/08/27/secant-mercator.html">https://liorsinai.github.io/mathematics/2020/08/27/secant-mercator.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://liorsinai.github.io/mathematics/2020/08/27/secant-mercator.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24304311</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 12:59:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ham radio is not dying, it's evolving]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 304 | Comments 204 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24303952">thread link</a>) | @lightlyused
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | http://k0lwc.com/ham-radio-is-dying-no-its-not-its-evolving/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://k0lwc.com/ham-radio-is-dying-no-its-not-its-evolving/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-124">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>I’ve heard ham radio is dying since as far back as I can remember. It’s one of those common sayings you always hear. Like, “get off my lawn,” and “kids these days.” But is it true? Is there any evidence to support this? Let’s take a closer look.</p>



<h2>Ham radio licensees are increasing</h2>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="http://k0lwc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/85F2F076-403E-44C1-8418-1D54A6FB8EB0.png" alt="" width="733" height="447" srcset="http://k0lwc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/85F2F076-403E-44C1-8418-1D54A6FB8EB0.png 900w, http://k0lwc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/85F2F076-403E-44C1-8418-1D54A6FB8EB0-300x183.png 300w, http://k0lwc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/85F2F076-403E-44C1-8418-1D54A6FB8EB0-768x469.png 768w, http://k0lwc.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/85F2F076-403E-44C1-8418-1D54A6FB8EB0-850x519.png 850w" sizes="(max-width: 733px) 100vw, 733px"></figure>



<p>Data from the ARRL shows that ham radio licensees are increasing. When you look at the chart above, you see two significant markers that are likely driving this growth. </p>



<ul><li>The removal of the code requirement by the FCC.</li><li>The economic collapse of 2008.</li></ul>



<p>The Morse code requirement was always an intimidating part of obtaining your General FCC license. Learning Morse code is like learning a second language. It takes time and effort to learn, and that’s not a bad thing. However, it doesn’t change that it scared many people away from the hobby. When the FCC removed this requirement in 2007, I believe it opened the door for many who spent years on the fence. Then you have the economic downturn of 2008. What does that have to do with ham radio? A lot.</p>



<p>After the economic downturn, the United States watched as survivalism, now commonly calling “prepping,” entered mainstream culture. People were worried as the country was involved in multiple wars and our economy was on the brink of collapse. Citizens stocked up on food storage, water, firearms, and…<em>communications equipment</em>. As our country spiraled into more turmoil ham radio licenses steadily increased to more than 750,000 by the end of 2019. </p>



<h2>Is ham radio a hobby or a public service?</h2>



<p><strong>The debate between ham radio being a public service or just a hobby is a common argument</strong>. The reason we exist is to ultimately have a trained citizenry that can response to natural disasters. This will always be a thread in our hobby, but this thread is merging more and more with digital functions, including the Internet. That’s where some people get grumpy.</p>



<h3>FT8/JS8Call</h3>



<p><a href="https://physics.princeton.edu/pulsar/K1JT/wsjtx.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FT8/JS8Call</a> has drew the ire from older operators who don’t see it as “real ham radio.” Though the technology could have huge implications for passing traffic when conditions are rough in remote parts of the world.</p>



<h3>Digital Mobile Radio (DMR)</h3>



<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_mobile_radio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Digital Mobile Radio</a> has exploded in growth in the past decade. Many amateur radio operators use <a href="http://k0lwc.com/what-is-the-range-of-a-dmr-hotspot/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Internet-connected hotspots</a> to operate from their shack without tying up local repeaters. These Internet-connected repeaters hold value, the biggest is the ability to have two different time slots carrying voice traffic simultaneously on one repeater, whether they have an Internet connection or not. DMR doesn’t need to have an Internet backbone to be a game-changer for emergency communications.</p>



<p>Ham radio will always be a hobby where those engaged are practicing to help if the need ever arises, whether they participate in public service events with local clubs or not. And younger operators are redefining how it’s done with new digital technologies — and that’s a great thing!</p>



<h2>Millennials are not killing ham radio… they’re the future</h2>



<p>Some ham radio operators believe younger hams are “killing” the hobby. These often dismissive and vile opinions are not great for the future of amateur radio. Integrating new technology like VOIP and microcomputers into amateur radio is what it’s all about—using the resources available to communicate and exchange information with others around the world. Who cares how we get it done?</p>



<h3>Getting young kids involved in ham radio</h3>



<p>We must get children interested in the hobby. Today, kids aren’t impressed with the ability to talk around with the world on 100 watts and a wire. They’re just not. How do we get young people interested in the digital age where they can communicate anywhere in the world with a tap of a button? The ARRL hasn’t done a great job in attracting young people — but there are things we can do!</p>



<h3>Capitalize on the next generation of space exploration</h3>



<p>The United States is embarking on the next generation of space exploration. Companies like SpaceX and Blue Origin are making space and engineering cool again, and ham radio could easily ride that wave. Focus on targeting kids interested in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics and educate them on AMSAT and the potential to communicate with the International Space Station (ISS). Using space exploration as a drive for getting a ham license would be a fantastic entry point for space geeks everywhere.</p>



<h3>Use remote HF and SWL stations to spark interest</h3>



<p>For young ham radio operators who already have their license, look no further than <a href="https://www.remotehamradio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Remote Ham Radio</a> as a shining example of how to get kids interested in upgrading their license. <a href="https://www.remotehamradio.com/youth/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">They offer a program where kids can win free time</a> using world-class remote DX contest stations. The young hams have to meet the following criteria:</p>



<ul><li>Be 25 years old or younger</li><li>Hold a General class or higher license</li><li>Be a member of the ARRL</li><li>Have an interest or experience in DXing/Contesting</li><li>Tell us why RHR would be a good fit for you</li></ul>



<p>Kudos to Remote Ham Radio for offering this program to young hams!</p>



<h3>POTA/SOTA combines ham radio and outdoor adventure</h3>



<p>Living in Colorado, I grew fond of Summits On The Air (SOTA) rather quickly. I mean, it’s cool. You can exercise while playing ham radio all at the same time. We should be focusing on how we can use these outdoor portable operations to attract young hams who love the outdoors. For the extreme outdoor enthusiasts, it would be wise to focus on the usefulness of being able to communicate from the wilderness where cell phone signals are non-existent.</p>



<p><strong>Ham radio has evolved</strong>, albeit slowly compared to other technology sectors. That evolution is inevitable. We can’t fight it. We shouldn’t fight it. We need to find ways to encourage new exploration of communication methodology. That all starts with younger ham radio operators bringing new ideas and skills to our hobby.</p>



<p>Let’s not fight it. Let’s embrace it.</p>
<br>
			</div><!-- .entry-content -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://k0lwc.com/ham-radio-is-dying-no-its-not-its-evolving/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24303952</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 12:16:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[One Year with ThinkPad and Linux (From MacBook Pro)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 272 | Comments 358 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24303938">thread link</a>) | @drikerf
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://drikerf.com/one-year-with-thinkpad-and-linux-from-macbook-pro/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://drikerf.com/one-year-with-thinkpad-and-linux-from-macbook-pro/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <figure>
                <img srcset="https://drikerf.com/content/images/size/w300/2020/08/barn-images-t5YUoHW6zRo-unsplash.jpg 300w,
                            https://drikerf.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/08/barn-images-t5YUoHW6zRo-unsplash.jpg 600w,
                            https://drikerf.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/08/barn-images-t5YUoHW6zRo-unsplash.jpg 1000w,
                            https://drikerf.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/08/barn-images-t5YUoHW6zRo-unsplash.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://drikerf.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/08/barn-images-t5YUoHW6zRo-unsplash.jpg" alt="One Year With ThinkPad and Linux (From Macbook Pro)">
            </figure>

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p>A few thoughts about my experiences switching from Mac to a ThinkPad with Linux the past year. For context, I'm the founder and maker of <a href="https://wobaka.com/">Wobaka.com</a> and <a href="https://bootstrap.email/">Bootstrap.email</a>. I work with front/backend development, design, marketing and sales every day. I code primarily in Clojure + ClojureScript but I also do some JavaScript, Ruby/Rails, Python and Bash on a regular basis.</p><p>I wrote this post for my past and future self. I was looking for something like this last year but couldn't find much.</p><h2 id="past-experience">Past experience</h2><p>Growing up I used Windows and later on Linux (Slackware!). I started using Macs around 2009. So it's been roughly 10 years straight in Apple land.</p><h2 id="setup">Setup</h2><ul><li>ThinkPad T480 (14")</li><li>Fedora Linux with Gnome, and sometimes i3.</li><li>Editor: Emacs</li><li>Terminal: Gnome, and sometimes urxvt</li><li>Shell: Bash</li><li>Brower: Firefox, and sometimes Chromium</li></ul><figure><img src="https://drikerf.com/content/images/2020/08/Screenshot-from-2020-08-19-17-10-37.png"><figcaption>Neofetch dump</figcaption></figure><figure><img src="https://drikerf.com/content/images/2020/08/Screenshot-from-2020-08-28-14-13-19.png"><figcaption>Desktop environment</figcaption></figure><h2 id="what-s-been-working-great">What's been working great</h2><p>It's a really solid machine. Especially for development work.</p><ul><li>More performance for the $.</li><li>More control over the environment, like <code>/ls/proc/&lt;id&gt;</code></li><li>Faster Docker</li><li>Emacs and programs in general feels snappier</li><li>Can disable webcam in BIOS when not used</li><li>Ports: USB-C, USB and SD card reader (for DSLR camera)</li><li>Great keyboard</li><li>Maintenance: T480 is not slim and this is for the better. I can replace/upgrade most components by myself.</li><li>Thermodynamics: There's a proper fan and heatsink on this one. Fan rarely spins loudly.</li></ul><h2 id="what-hasn-t">What hasn't</h2><ul><li>Battery time is not like Macs. ~ 5 hours (after one year)</li><li>Can't debug issues in Safari without borrowing a Mac</li><li>Can't do iOS development</li><li>Need a VM with Windows to sync my Suunto GPS watch</li><li>Touchpad is not close to Mac</li><li>Emoji support is not 100%</li><li>Some video conference tools can be a bit glitchy until you get the setup right</li></ul><ul><li>Emacs</li><li>Gnome Terminal</li><li>Todoist (Homemade Electron wrapper but I believe they're working on Linux release)</li><li>Peek (GIF recording)</li><li>Kdenlive (Video editing)</li><li>GIMP (Photo editing)</li><li>Darktable (RAW Photo editing)</li><li>FFMPEG (Converting videos etc)</li><li>ImageMagick (Converting and resizing images)</li><li>LibreOffice (Spreadsheets)</li><li>Bitwarden (Password manager)</li><li>Evince (PDF reading and annotating)</li><li>Spotify (Music)</li><li>Telegram (Messaging)</li><li>Evolution (Mail, Calendar)</li><li>Geary (Lightweight mail)</li><li>Gnome Calendar</li></ul><p>In general I think I've found a worthy replacement for every essential tool that I used on my Mac.</p><h2 id="staying-with-linux">Staying with Linux?</h2><p>Yes. It took a few weeks of tinkering but now I feel at home. Only reason to buy a Mac would be if I needed to work on an iOS/macOS project.</p><p>Got questions? I'm on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/drikerf">@drikerf</a>.</p>
                </div>
            </section>

                <section>
    <h3>Subscribe to Drikerf.com</h3>
    <p>Get the latest posts delivered right to your inbox</p>
    <form data-members-form="subscribe">
        
        <p><strong>Great!</strong> Check your inbox and click the link to confirm your subscription.
        </p>
        <p>
            Please enter a valid email address!
        </p>
    </form>
</section>

        </article>

    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://drikerf.com/one-year-with-thinkpad-and-linux-from-macbook-pro/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24303938</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 12:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Testing Database Transactions in Go]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24303322">thread link</a>) | @marvinblum
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://marvinblum.de/blog/testing-database-transactions-in-go-jEaOGXravM | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://marvinblum.de/blog/testing-database-transactions-in-go-jEaOGXravM">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">




<section>
    
    <small>Published on 28. August 2020</small>
    <p>You can find a lot of articles about how to prevent deadlocks in Go, but most of them focus on concurrency patterns and synchronization tools like mutexes. While it is important to know some techniques to prevent them, a trap you can stumble across more easily without noticing, are database transaction deadlocks.</p><p>A transaction deadlock can occur when you start one or more transactions and run queries outside of transactions while they are still active. If you run too many transactions and queries at the same time, you might run out of database connections in the connection pool. Here is a simple example of that:</p><pre><code language="text/x-go">// We will ignore errors for this example,
// you should always check them of course.

tx, _ := db.Begin()
tx.Exec(`INSERT INTO "foo" ("a", "b") VALUES (4, 2)`)

// ...

db.Query(`SELECT * FROM "foo" WHERE "a" = $1 AND "b" = $2`, 4, 2)

// DEADLOCK

tx.Commit()</code></pre><p>In this example, we create a new transaction and insert something to the database. Later on, we try to query the same result from the database. That the inserted row has not been committed yet, is not the actual issue, as you would receive no result in that case. The real issue here is that if you run this code concurrently, you might run out of connections. How many connections are opened to the database can be configured. As soon as your code reaches the <code>db.Query</code> the last connection might be occupied by the transaction and therefore blocks until a connection is available, which might never happen.</p><p>So how do you fix this? First of all, all queries should be run either outside or inside a transaction for a specific part of your code. Even if you run a transaction block and a non-transaction block concurrently, the non-transaction block will not be blocked by the transaction forever (but the non-transaction block might need to wait for the other part to finish). Additionally, you can use a linter or another tool to make sure all queries are run completely inside or outside of transactions.</p><p>I usually write integration tests against the database. If you do the same, you can configure the connection pool size to make sure the tests will only use a single connection. That way the tests will run into a deadlock should you have forgotten to use a transaction somewhere. You can easily configure that inside the <code>TestMain</code> function for a package.</p><pre><code language="text/x-go">func TestMain(m *testing.M) {
	db.SetMaxOpenConns(1) // db is the *sql.DB created somewhere
}</code></pre><p>I hope this helps you to prevent some nasty deadlock bugs. I found quite a few in a larger code base by limiting the connection pool. In production, you should use multiple connections to speed up things of course.</p>
</section>

    <hr>
    <section>
        <p>
            Would you like to see more? Read my blog articles on <a href="https://emvi.com/blog" target="_blank">Emvi</a>, my project page on <a href="https://github.com/Kugelschieber" target="_blank">GitHub</a> or send me a <a href="mailto:marvin@marvinblum.de">mail</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
            This page uses <a href="https://concrete.style/" target="_blank">concrete</a> for styling. Check it out!
        </p>
        <p>
            This page does not use cookies. <a href="https://marvinblum.de/legal">Legal</a>
        </p>
    </section>



</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://marvinblum.de/blog/testing-database-transactions-in-go-jEaOGXravM</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24303322</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 10:33:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[WebAssembly Is Not a Stack Machine (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24303182">thread link</a>) | @arto
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | http://troubles.md/wasm-is-not-a-stack-machine/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://troubles.md/wasm-is-not-a-stack-machine/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  
  <blockquote>
<h3 id="preamble">Preamble</h3>
<p>This is part 1 of a 4-part miniseries on issues with WebAssembly and proposals to fix them. <a href="http://troubles.md/why-do-we-need-the-relooper-algorithm-again/">Part 2 here</a>, <a href="http://troubles.md/the-stack-is-not-the-stack/">part 3 here</a>, <a href="http://troubles.md/microwasm/">part 4 here</a>.
<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
This article assumes some familiarity with virtual machines, compilers and WebAssembly, but I’ll try to link to relevant information where necessary so even if you’re not you can follow along.
<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Also, this series is going to come off as if I dislike WebAssembly. I love WebAssembly! I wrote a <a href="http://troubles.md/why-wasm/">whole article about how great it is</a>! In fact, I love it so much that I want it to be the best that it can be, and this series is me working through my complaints with the design in the hope that some or all of these issues can be addressed soon, while the ink is still somewhat wet on the specification.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I’m sure you’re all familiar with WebAssembly by now. It’s seeing use everywhere, from plugins to blockchain smart contracts to, of course, the web. If you go to the Wikipedia article for WebAssembly right now, you’ll get a great overview of the technology, except for one thing: the “Design” section states:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>WebAssembly code is intended to be run on a portable abstract structured stack machine</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nope.</p>
<h2 id="stack-machines-vs-register-machines">Stack machines vs register machines</h2>
<p>The difference between a stack and a register machine is essentially this: a stack machine pops values from and pushed values onto a stack, so for example a <code>+</code> operation will pop the last two values off of the stack, add them together, and then push the result back onto the stack. A register machine has some number of places where values can be stored, and operations reads and writes to those registers. So <code>+</code> will take 3 arguments, 2 that represent the registers to read the operands from and 1 that represents the register to write the result to<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>.</p>
<p>The problem with registers is that there is no liveness analysis. If you have some code like so:</p>
<pre><code>%0 = 1
%1 = 2
%2 = add %0, %1
...
</code></pre><p>Are <code>%0</code> and <code>%1</code> used after the addition? Without lookahead, you have no way of knowing. Even in SSA<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> register machines like LLVM IR (where each register is written to exactly once) the liveness of each register must be continuously recalculated. This means that you have overhead associated with compilation - knowing the liveness of variables is extremely important for generating efficient assembly, but instead of the liveness being calculated when creating the IR and stored as a part of it you have to recalculate this data every time.</p>
<p>If the IR is entirely in-memory this isn’t so bad, especially if your code is in SSA form, but it means that you have to do extra work for the same quality of code and it means that a streaming compiler (like FireFox’s Wasm baseline compiler) is unable to produce good code.</p>
<p>You can, of course, add liveness analysis metadata to the machine, but that liveness analysis is only useful if your code is in SSA form - if it’s not SSA form then the liveness is <em>extremely</em> coarse-grained.</p>
<p>Well, that’s where WebAssembly comes in. See, WebAssembly has these things called locals. Locals are mutable variables that live for the lifetime of a function. Since WebAssembly blocks can’t take arguments, they’re the only way for blocks to receive data from outside. This includes stuff like loop counters, the classic example for SSA-defeating mutable variables, but it also includes regular blocks. For example:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="lisp"><span>(</span><span>func</span> <span>(</span><span>result</span> <span>i32</span><span>)</span>
  <span>(</span><span>add</span> <span>(</span><span>i32.const</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>i32.const</span> <span>2</span><span>))</span>
  <span>(</span><span>block</span> <span>(</span><span>result</span> <span>i32</span><span>)</span>
    <span>; Can't read the result of the add above</span>
  <span>))</span>
</code></pre></div><p>You have to do this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="lisp"><span>(</span><span>func</span> <span>(</span><span>result</span> <span>i32</span><span>)</span>
  <span>(</span><span>local</span> <span>i32</span><span>)</span>
  <span>(</span><span>local.set</span> <span>0</span> <span>(</span><span>add</span> <span>(</span><span>i32.const</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>(</span><span>i32.const</span> <span>2</span><span>)))</span>
  <span>(</span><span>block</span> <span>(</span><span>result</span> <span>i32</span><span>)</span>
    <span>(</span><span>local.get</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span>
  <span>))</span>
</code></pre></div><p>This is a problem. Usually a stack machine can be trivially converted to SSA form with liveness analysis - an item on the stack is dead when it is used as the argument to an operator - no ifs, no buts. Even a <code>pick</code> operator<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> can be thought of in these terms as long as the argument to <code>pick</code> is a compile-time constant, although generally the SSA conversion of a stack machine that includes a <code>pick</code> instruction would be implemented using refcounting - meaning that reading a variable doesn’t involve creating an unnecessary new one. However, locals are a problem. They’re mutable, so you can’t trivially convert them to SSA, and they always live for the lifetime of the function.</p>
<p>This poses a problem for optimisation. SSA form is one of the most powerful optimisation tools. The fact that locals are mutable defeats that, and the fact that they’re global to the function defeats liveness analysis. For an example of why this is an issue, say you’re trying to compile WebAssembly into some native architecture. You’ll compile your code into one that uses some number of arguments in registers, but now unless you do your own liveness analysis on that function those registers are permanently marked “in use” by those arguments. Without extra analysis you don’t know when the last usage of that argument is, and so you can’t ever reuse the register used by that argument for something else. Even a function that never uses any of its arguments still can’t reuse the space used by those arguments for anything else.</p>
<p>This essentially makes WebAssembly a register machine without liveness analysis, but not only that, it’s a register machine that isn’t even in SSA form - both of the tools at our disposal to do optimisation are unavailable. In a true, optimising compiler we can recreate that information, but WebAssembly was already emitted by a compiler that generated that information once. There’s no technical reason why we should have to do that work again, it’s just a deficiency in the language. A compiler that has to act on a stream of WebAssembly has less ability to recreate this information and will end up generating significantly worse code for essentially no good reason.</p>
<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>
<p>The developers of the WebAssembly spec aren’t dumb. For the most part it’s an extremely well-designed specification. However, they are weighed down by WebAssembly’s legacy. WebAssembly started out not as a bytecode, but more like a simplified binary representation for asm.js. Essentially it was originally designed to be source code, like JavaScript. It would be a more-efficient representation thereof but it still wasn’t a proper virtual machine instruction set. Then, it became a register machine<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>, and only at the last minute did it switch to stack-based encoding for the operators. At that point, concepts like locals were quite entrenched in the spec. Not only that, but for the most part the WebAssembly specification team were flying blind. No streaming compiler had yet been built, hell, no compiler had yet been built. It wasn’t clear that having locals would be problematic - after all, C gets by just fine using local variables that the compiler constructs the SSA graph for.</p>
<p>It’s only by working on a streaming WebAssembly compiler for integration with <a href="https://github.com/CraneStation/wasmtime">Wasmtime</a> that I realised these issues, as well as more issues that I’ll get to in later articles in this series. Before then I considered WebAssembly’s design to be utterly rock-solid, and in fact I still strongly believe that most of the decisions made were the right ones. Although it has problems, it’s incredible how much the WebAssembly working group got right considering it was such relatively unknown territory at the time of the specification’s writing.</p>
<h2 id="whats-the-alternative">What’s the alternative?</h2>
<p>So currently locals represent both function arguments and local variables. There is <a href="https://github.com/WebAssembly/multi-value/blob/master/proposals/multi-value/Overview.md">a proposal to allow blocks to have arguments and both functions and blocks to return more than one value</a>. With this, it becomes possible to get rid of locals entirely. Loop counters are implemented by having the counter be given as an argument, and then when you jump to the header of the loop you must have the new value of the counter on the stack. This acts like a phi function but is much conceptually simpler. Since it’s impossible to get the address of locals in WebAssembly there’s no need for <code>alloca</code> in any form - unlike in LLVM, you don’t need to have locals at all. The only thing left is to implement function arguments by having the function start with its arguments on the stack and you no longer need locals at all.</p>
<p>This massively reduces the complexity of the WebAssembly specification and compilers for it without reducing the expressivity, and allows the compilers generating the WebAssembly to encode more of their knowledge about the original source into the WebAssembly itself. Although optimising compilers will probably not generate better code from this, they will become much simpler and easier to maintain, and streaming compilers will become significantly simpler and produce significantly better code.</p>
<p>Finally, not only is a stack machine like this automatically in SSA form, but it’s automatically in <em>strict</em> SSA form. This means that it is statically impossible to access undefined variables. In WebAssembly as it exists now, you have to zero locals when entering a function unless you can statically prove that the local is always set before it is accessed. Again, the compilers almost always have this information, and removing locals makes accessing undefined memory statically impossible.</p>
<p>Join me next time where I tackle WebAssembly’s problematic control flow.</p>
<section role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Yes, I know that many register machines such as x86 output into one of the input registers, but that’s still conceptually the same as taking separate arguments for input and output, just more limited. <a href="#fnref:1" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>if you don’t know what SSA form is you can see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_single_assignment_form">the Wikipedia article on it</a> <a href="#fnref:2" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p>A <code>pick</code> operator duplicates the nth item of the stack to the top of the stack. Unfortunately, it’s not available in WebAssembly. <a href="#fnref:3" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I believe that it had infinite registers and so it was possible to generate it in SSA form, but it had no liveness analysis. <a href="#fnref:4" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://troubles.md/wasm-is-not-a-stack-machine/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24303182</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 10:03:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using Microsoft Word with Git]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 213 | Comments 127 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24302896">thread link</a>) | @the_dripper
<br/>
August 28, 2020 | https://blog.martinfenner.org/2014/08/25/using-microsoft-word-with-git/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.martinfenner.org/2014/08/25/using-microsoft-word-with-git/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
          <div>
            

<p>One of the major challenges of writing a journal article is to keep track of versions - both the different versions you create as the document progresses, and to merge in the changes made by your collaborators. For most academics Microsoft Word is the default writing tool, and it is both very good and very bad in this. Very good because the <em>track changes</em> feature makes it easy to see what has changed since the last version and who made the changes. Very bad because this feature is built around keeping everything in a single Word document, so that only one person can work on on a manuscript at a time. This usually means sending manuscripts around by email, and being very careful about not confusing different versions of the document, which requires <a href="http://www.phdcomics.com/comics/archive.php?comicid=1531">creativity</a>.<!--more--></p>
<p>Approaches to overcome these challenges are to a) integrate the Word documents into collaboration tools such as Sharepoint and Office 365, or document sharing services such as Dropbox and Google Docs (if you use it just for that), or b) use a different authoring tool altogether. If neither of these approaches works for you, you have a third option: use the version control system <strong>git</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mulvany.net/presentations/WikimaniaOpenScholarshipTalk.slides.html#/3">Git</a> is software that helps with <a href="https://blog.martinfenner.org/2014/08/25/using-microsoft-word-with-git/(http://git-scm.com/book/en/Getting-Started-About-Version-Control)">tracking changes to files</a> so that you can recall specific versions later. Git is typically used to track changes of software source code (and was originally developed by Linus Torvalds for Linux kernel development in 2005), but in fact git can be used for any file where we need to keep track of versions over time. Git is open source software that runs locally on your computer, so please go ahead and start tracking changes to your manuscripts (or other complex documents) with git. Any time you want to store a version, do a <code>git commit</code> with a little description and an optional tag.</p>
<p>This approach is not ideal, as git was written with source code in text format in mind and for example doesn’t understand what has changed between two revisions of a Word document. Some people will tell you to never store binary files in a version control system, but don’t listen to them. Instead give git a tool to convert Word documents into plain text, and git will then happily tell you what has changed between revisions. Several tools can do this, but since earlier this month Pandoc can read Word documents in <code>docx</code> format. Do the following to have Pandoc convert Word documents into markdown, and to compare the revisions by word and not by line (which makes more sense):</p>
<pre><code># .gitattributes file in root folder of your git project
*.docx diff=pandoc</code></pre>
<pre><code># .gitconfig file in your home folder
[diff "pandoc"]
  textconv=pandoc --to=markdown
  prompt = false
[alias]
  wdiff = diff --word-diff=color --unified=1</code></pre>
<p>You can then use <code>git wdiff important_file.docx</code> to see the changes (with deletions in red and insertions in green), or <code>git log -p --word-diff=color important_file.docx</code> to see all changes over time.</p>
<p>While you can now track revisions of a Word document and see the changes, you also want to be able to merge different versions of a Word document together so that you and your collaborators can work on the manuscript in parallel. Git can’t merge binary files together, so you need to first convert the Word document into a format that git understands. Just as in the previous example we can use Pandoc for that, with markdown as the textual format. This would also work with HTML or LaTeX, but the simplicity of markdown makes it better suited for version control which doesn’t know about the markup of these formats.</p>
<p>One of the reasons that git became so popular with software developers is that it is a <strong>distributed version control system</strong> instead of a centralized system such as Subversion. This means that you can track all revisions locally on your computer, but can still synchronize your revisions with another user. <strong>Github</strong> is a popular service that facilitates this synchronization and adds some nice features on top. One way to collaborate with your co-authors is therefore to set up a Github repository (public or private) for your manuscript, and store the master version of the manuscript in markdown format. Instead of working on the master version directly, you would use Pandoc to convert back and forth between this master version in markdown format and your Word document, and would continue to use Word as authoring tool. <a href="https://blog.martinfenner.org/2014/08/18/introducing-rakali/">Rakali</a> is a Pandoc tool that I released last week that can help automate this document conversion. Github has a a number of features to facilitate collaboration that can be used here, e.g.&nbsp;Github issues for discussion and task management.</p>
<p>There are still a few rough edges in the workflow described above (e.g.&nbsp;only partial support of Word track changes), but it is an interesting approach to collaborate using Microsoft Word and git. And this workflow can of course be enhanced to also include authors that write in LaTeX or one of the other formats that Pandoc supports. One nice side effect of using markdown is that Github will automatically render a webpage for the document (which it will not do for HTML without extra effort).</p>




            

            


<p><a href="http://disqus.com/">blog comments powered by </a>

          </p></div>
        </div>

        <!-- COinS metadata (for citation managers like Zotero etc), goes in body text -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.martinfenner.org/2014/08/25/using-microsoft-word-with-git/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24302896</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 09:15:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Who needs a case? The 3D Printed Mil-Plastic is here]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24301031">thread link</a>) | @lvturner
<br/>
August 27, 2020 | https://back7.co/home/back7co-mil-plastic | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://back7.co/home/back7co-mil-plastic">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <article id="article-5f376d5bacc4a17e49bd6a03">
      
      <div>
        <p><time datetime="2020-08-25" pubdate="">
          <p><span>Aug </span><span>25</span>
          </p>
        </time></p><h2 itemprop="headline" data-content-field="title"><time itemprop="datePublished" datetime="2020-08-25" pubdate="">Aug 25 </time>Who needs a case?  The 3D Printed Mil-Plastic is here!</h2>

        
      </div>
      
      <div data-controller="BlogProgressBar">
        
        
        <div><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" data-updated-on="1597468799436" id="item-5f376d5bacc4a17e49bd6a03"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-aa3aa8aa384f9523ca70"><div><p>This is a project that I’ve been working on for a few months over the quarantine, and I’m happy to share it here.  The idea is a simple one- many Makers asked me over the last year about printing smaller parts for the <a href="https://back7.co/home/raspberry-pi-recovery-kit">Raspberry Pi Recovery Kit</a>, and I started playing around with options.  I knew I didn’t want to just re-hash the old deck, and I knew I really wanted a better display for this year.  Let’s jump in with what’s different:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p>No Pelican case required!  It’s pretty obvious from the photos that you don’t need to spend $50 or more on a case, especially if you are going to drill holes in it, or don’t actually need a waterproof case.</p></li><li><p>Smaller Bill of Materials (BOM).  The original Raspberry Pi Recovery kit was very expensive to build, primarily because I sourced the coolest looking parts I could, which can be expensive or just hard to get (like the keyboard).  This project has a much simpler BOM, so simple that here it is:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p>1 kg spool of Paramount 3D’s Olive Green PETG - <a href="https://amzn.to/31lMcqy">Amazon Link</a></p></li><li><p>(Optional) 1K spool of Carbon Fiber PETG and hardened steel nozzle - <a href="https://www.matterhackers.com/store/l/carbon-fiber-pro-series-petg-filament-1.75mm/sk/MHQ646TD">Link</a> and <a href="https://www.matterhackers.com/store/l/e3d-v6-extra-nozzle-hardened-steel-1.75mm-x-0.40mm/sk/MSDV7HN9">Link</a></p></li><li><p>Low profile, stainless steel M5 screws - <a href="https://www.mcmaster.com/92855A513/">McMaster Carr Link</a></p></li><li><p>M5 threaded rod - <a href="https://www.mcmaster.com/93325A413/">McMaster Carr</a> (<a href="https://amzn.to/2Evq9Vu">bolt cutters</a> are optional, but use safety gear)</p></li><li><p>Four threaded inserts - <a href="https://amzn.to/2FWzNBj">Amazon Link</a></p></li><li><p>Pimoroni HDMI Display - <a href="https://www.adafruit.com/product/4337">Adafruit Link</a></p></li><li><p>Short HDMI Cable - <a href="https://amzn.to/31tQP21">Amazon Link</a></p></li><li><p>Four brass M2.5 standoffs - <a href="https://amzn.to/2CUUKeF">Amazon Link</a></p></li><li><p>Raspberry Pi 4 - <a href="https://amzn.to/2YwHFzF">Amazon Link</a></p></li><li><p>Core Design - <a href="https://www.tinkercad.com/things/b4bWC7f62Ab-sizzling-fyyran/">Tinkercad Print Layout</a>, <a href="https://www.tinkercad.com/things/eTexyDTsTKR-stunning-kieran/">Tinkercad Assembled Version</a>, <a href="https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:4579460">Thingiverse</a></p></li><li><p>Thumb Screws - <a href="https://www.mcmaster.com/93886A240/">McMaster Carr</a></p></li><li><p>Cord Grip - <a href="https://www.mcmaster.com/8302K161/">McMaster Carr</a></p></li></ul></li><li><p>Something easier to modify/hack over time.  The <a href="https://back7.co/home/raspberry-pi-recovery-kit">RPRK</a> was designed to be a “finished” product and execution on an idea, and with people making their own, I thought it would be more fun this time around if people could swap out parts for their own, even ones to radically change the look of the deck.</p></li><li><p>I abandoned panel mount ports on this project.  Panel mounts are often for looks only, at least on many of my older builds, and to keep costs down I just ditched them.  Big, rounded rectangle holes work for me, and don’t cost $15 each time I want to change something.</p></li><li><p>Finally, I wanted a design I could continue to refine and modify for my own projects.  Hopefully I’ll have more of those to share soon!</p></li></ul><p>With that out of the way, let’s go over the basic design.  This can be used as assembly instructions in a pinch too.  Here’s the front frame, which the Pimoroni display will connect to.  That’s really done last, so we won’t see this part again for a while.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597467959462_38425"><p>With that out of the way let’s focus on the main frame, which helps hold it all together.  Here are some of the parts.</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_18333"><div><p>The design is simple for the front- there are four threaded inserts for holding the display on the front.  Make sure they go on the front of the front frame.  There are two halves of the front frame, which is held together by the “joiner” part, which has spare M5 holes in case you want to mount something here.  I was still on a carbon fiber kick (read: I still had the hardened steel nozzle installed) so that part was printed with that stuff.  It’s great, but not required if you don’t want to deal with a second and somewhat picky filament.</p><p>Next it’s all about printing all of the rear parts, including what I call the ends and the top/bottom.  </p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_22206"><p>The top and bottom parts are not interchangeable between top and bottom, they go on one orientation only.  This will likely take a while to print!</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_26233"><div><p><strong>CAUTION:</strong></p><p>As you start to assemble be careful of the resistance of some of the deeper holes that screws and threaded rods are going into.  If you feel too much resistance you may need to drill or tap some of the holes- this depends a ton on your printer.  This is especially true of the M5 threaded rod in the next section, which can get bound in the many parts and get very difficult to move.  If you think that’s happening, back out the M5 rod and use a power drill to drill the part holes.  You really only need threading on the parts on each end of the enclosure, and even if you drill it all out, end caps/nuts will do fine to hold the whole thing together.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_27776"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022592672-CHP4FNLHL6RO70YQ2SEG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBVxXg3JER61MsoWKWcKfol7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UZbFdycb01AmW4vjaQKIyvghOOxQi7TrCWT_NwZC2hRGQK7PAiDfWd0Koy0MH7DUzQ/JAY02369.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022592672-CHP4FNLHL6RO70YQ2SEG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kBVxXg3JER61MsoWKWcKfol7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UZbFdycb01AmW4vjaQKIyvghOOxQi7TrCWT_NwZC2hRGQK7PAiDfWd0Koy0MH7DUzQ/JAY02369.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2048x1361" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="JAY02369.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3fe3bf116eef64c6cef698" data-type="image" src="https://back7.co/home/JAY02369.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_29282"><p>The way I assembled it was to drill out slightly some of the upper/lower parts where the M5 screws go, then bolt the main frame to the uppers and lowers that have screw holes to line up.  Not all the uppers and lowers will need to be bolted in, but each of the uppers and lowers has the screw hole just in case.  This just makes it easier to keep parts organized.  With all of them bolted it should look like this:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_33687"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022899524-OCP0V9TW02GZ7BC4PTBY/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02367.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022899524-OCP0V9TW02GZ7BC4PTBY/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02367.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2048x1366" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="JAY02367.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3fe4f267bd924bc4b10d73" data-type="image" src="https://back7.co/home/JAY02367.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_33976"><p>Now you can pressure fit (squeeze) each of the ones that don’t bolt in, just like this:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_36298"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022942372-TKCMUYOUEJ3RIUWH1OMH/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02368.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022942372-TKCMUYOUEJ3RIUWH1OMH/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02368.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2048x1366" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="JAY02368.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3fe51ddde5f05236d89ea4" data-type="image" src="https://back7.co/home/JAY02368.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_36587"><p>Again remember, if the threaded rod gets too hard to screw in, back it out and drill out some wider holes, or else it’s time consuming to deconstruct it with the rods in place. Also be careful to measure your threaded rod- push too far in and you’ll get a bulge on the end like this:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_38139"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022981280-6H1LASFYNOJ57BE4AF0K/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02372.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598022981280-6H1LASFYNOJ57BE4AF0K/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02372.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2048x1366" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="JAY02372.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3fe543abd53803da9cc223" data-type="image" src="https://back7.co/home/JAY02372.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_38428"><p>With the ends on, it’s time to think about how you want to do the side access panels.  Here are some options, but you should customize them to what you plan to do with the case.</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_44006"><p>Here’s what I ended up doing, and rather than going with panel mounts for USB, power, etc. I wanted something more universal option- a cord grip (<a href="https://www.mcmaster.com/8302K161/">McMaster Carr</a>).  This lets me change cables as I want, with a single cord grip being a bit more economical than a bunch of USB ports that have to get changed over time.  After all, this one will live on a desk.  Here’s what I ended up with:</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_41093"><p>Now you also get a peek at the back- you could easily modify the back with vents, seal it shut, add more ports, etc.  In my case I wanted something I could easily modify, so that means a giant hole where I can fit my hand.  It scrapes a bit, but it fits!  You can see the Pi4 in there too.  There should be room for a ton of different boards, but beware- the Odyssey x86 board does not fit in this case when you add all the cables, and doesn’t appear to be compatible with the Pimoroni display.</p></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_47664"><div><p>Finally, what I suspect you’re all looking for- the final photos and my reasoning and motivation for this design.  First, the photos!</p><p>Here’s the front!</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_51153"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598023608620-5BMX2ST5SEJWOB5UNAIO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02403.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598023608620-5BMX2ST5SEJWOB5UNAIO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02403.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2048x1366" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="JAY02403.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3fe7b725780250f7ac6762" data-type="image" src="https://back7.co/home/JAY02403.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_53185"><p>In the photo below, you can see the display attached- for those of you building one, I didn’t forget the front!  The black plastic frame bolts to the green main frame, and then you gently connect the display ribbon cable, then use four M2 bolts to attach the screen.</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_54596"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598023650944-4FFKHCGX75TVIG0P6P66/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02406.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598023650944-4FFKHCGX75TVIG0P6P66/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02406.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2048x1366" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="JAY02406.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3fe7e267bd924bc4b18e1d" data-type="image" src="https://back7.co/home/JAY02406.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_54885"><p>Here’s the rear with plenty of room for future mods:</p></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_60557"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598023783872-F49TAXPBOPMZJFTO03EL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02407.jpg" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5caa4adb92441be122fcead4/1598023783872-F49TAXPBOPMZJFTO03EL/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNbLqx_FIYjfhtEsCHEHzad7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UX_hdIVndeO72MD00jTnc1n42Pd5vs4VrV4yXG_EV_fzwRAeN1AbZG4OR41R6pDVyg/JAY02407.jpg" data-image-dimensions="2048x1366" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="JAY02407.jpg" data-load="false" data-image-id="5f3fe867abb22d7fde54f345" data-type="image" src="https://back7.co/home/JAY02407.jpg">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1597469013003_60846"><div><p><br>Finally, a few words about this project and why I built this one.  This design took about 7 months to design, including a 3 month break due to life and COVID impacts.  I am lucky so far to be able to continue to work on these projects, and it’s been a great relief to “finish” it.  Like all of my previous projects here, all of the design files and parts lists are in this article so people can make/modify as they see fit.  I would remind fellow makers that it’s licensed under a non-commercial license, so while you can print/modify, doing so commercially is not supported under this project.  Want to do that?  Just reach out to me and we can figure something out.</p><p>Going forward though, many of my originals like this one will be for sale in my shop.  They will be more expensive than making it yourself, so if you’re willing to try- make one!  Commissions are limited and not guaranteed, so the items from my project builds may not last.  Check out <a href="https://back7.co/store">https://back7.co/store</a> to see what’s in stock.</p><p>With that out of the way, here are some quick FAQs on my projects related to this one, the Mil-Plastic case:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p><strong>Aren’t these just Raspberry Pi laptops?</strong>  Actually, they’re a bit more than that.  This is part sculpture, part functional electronics, and part exercise in design and DIY.  If you want a laptop, then that’s probably the option for you.  These are meant to be hacked/modded/upgraded and redesigned.  I don’t know of a laptop that comes even close to that.</p></li><li><p><strong>Do you realize this isn’t waterproof?</strong>  Yes, this is closer to a desk toy than a field computer. </p></li><li><p><strong>How do you get your prints to look like that?</strong>  One simple answer- slow prints (no faster than 45mm/sec), a clean build plate, and no supports.</p></li><li><p><strong>Are you open to commissions or building these for sale?</strong>  I am doing very limited commissions, and they are more expensive than building it yourself.  <a href="https://back7.co/store/original-raspberry-pi-mil-plastic-assembled-kit">This original version is available in the Back7 store here</a>, but after that any additional builds will …</p></li></ul></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://back7.co/home/back7co-mil-plastic">https://back7.co/home/back7co-mil-plastic</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://back7.co/home/back7co-mil-plastic</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24301031</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 03:14:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
