<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 12:26:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 12:26:42 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pieter Levels Makes $600k a Year from Nomad List and Remote OK]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 42 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24259201">thread link</a>) | @Pete-Codes
<br/>
August 24, 2020 | https://www.nocsdegree.com/pieter-levels-learn-coding/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.nocsdegree.com/pieter-levels-learn-coding/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                    <div>
                        <p><a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio">Pieter Levels </a>makes about $600,000 a year. He taught himself to code and has an unconventional philosophy. This is not an interview but an analysis piece. Pieter defied the critics and built Nomad List and Remote OK into successful businesses without cutting edge tools like React or other modern frameworks. I send articles like this twice a week - <a href="https://nocsdegree.carrd.co/">join 2,000 developers that get the newsletter</a>.</p><h2 id="who-is-pieter-levels">Who is Pieter Levels</h2><p>Pieter is a self-taught developer from The Netherlands. He has an MBA but no coding qualifications. As we will see in today's article he has a rough and ready approach to coding but it pays off handsomely. </p><p>His <a href="https://www.nomadlist.com/">Nomad List</a> directory and community for digital nomads draws in over $300k a year and that's despite a recent fall in revenue due to people not travelling during the Corona virus crisis. </p><figure><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/05/Screenshot-2020-05-14-at-23.30.06.png" alt=""></figure><p>His Remote Ok job board for remote workers made <a href="https://remoteok.io/open">$300,000 over the last 12 months</a></p><figure><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/05/Screenshot-2020-05-14-at-23.23.51.png" alt="Revenue chart for Remote OK job board"></figure><p>So that's a total of $600,00 from the last 12 months! Not bad for a self-taught developer! Pieter is active on Twitter and has a very stong following there. </p><p>As he works for himself he is able to travel extensively and live where he choses. Although, rather than the common misconception of digital nomads being constantly on the move, Pieter recommends spending a few months in each place. This way you avoid travel burnout. </p><h2 id="how-did-pieter-levels-learn-to-code">How did Pieter Levels learn to code?</h2><p>Not a lot is known about his very earlies forays into coding apart from the fact that as a teenager he played around programming. His first attempt at a web business was an analytics service for Youtube which would let you see how all your videos/channels were performing in one place. Unfortunately, he worked on it for a year without making any money from it. </p><p>From that point Pieter adopted his now familar approach to coding and business - build websites quickly and monetize from the beginning. He only adds more features if there is money coming in and the idea is validated by the market.</p><p>Pieter takes the "search on Google" approach to Google. So when he wanted to connect a database to a website or make a button do something on his website he would just search the terms on Google and find solutions in places like Stackoverflow. Pieter is a strong critic of the approach of doing courses as he believes people learn best by doing and building. </p><p>One analogy would be different approaches to learning Spanish. One person might study a course, learn the correct grammar and then go to Spain. Whereas Pieter would go to Spain, ask for the words he needs to use and go from there. </p><p>When asked in the past why he didn't use modern frameworks like React he made the point that as he was a solo founder he couldn't afford to spend time re-building his websites as this would mean his project would stall. </p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><a href="https://gum.co/GGofo"><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/08/monetize.png" alt="monetize"></a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h2 id="what-technologies-does-pieter-levels-use">What technologies does Pieter Levels use?</h2><p>Pieter is famous (or infamous) for having a rather eccentric choice of stack by modern standards. It's essentially the easiest, least glamorous tools you could imagine. But that's ok because Pieter makes $600k a year! </p><p>Here is his stack:</p><ul><li>HTML (hand coded so no template to make life easier)</li><li>CSS (He has used pre-processors like LESS and SASS in the past)</li><li>Javascript (No frameworks - this is sometimes referred to jokingly as Vanilla Javascript. There is no such thing as Vanilla JS though. It's just plain-old Javascript without a framework such as React, Vue or Angular) </li><li>jQuery (An unfashionable choice nowadays but it does the job)</li><li>PHP (He doesn't use any frameworks like Laravel)</li><li>SQLite - Pieter says it's super quick and swears by it. SQLite is a database written in a single file so Pieter doesn't need to set up a server for it. &nbsp;</li><li>his sites are hosted on a single VPS running Ubuntu with NGINX.</li></ul><p>Here are some modern options Pieter doesn't use </p><ul><li>React - he jokes a lot about how he never wants to learn it due to it's (perceived) complexity. </li><li>Node - for a time he considered using it but he's never used it in production</li><li>Angular/ Vue - he doesn't use any Javascript frameworks </li><li>SQL/ Postgres - he doesn't use any of the conventional databases </li></ul><h2 id="get-a-job-without-a-cs-degree-">Get a job without a CS degree 👇</h2><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><a href="http://nocsok.com/"><img src="https://www.nocsdegree.com/content/images/2020/08/Screenshot-2020-08-07-at-17.35.28-2.png" alt="No-CS-OK-screenshot-1"></a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><h2 id="what-results-has-pieter-had-with-this-approach-to-coding">What results has Pieter had with this approach to coding?</h2><p>Despite the technical critics, Pieter has been consistently making six figures since 2014. He currently makes approximately $600,000 a year which is far more than most developers. He has been able to live in countries with a low cost of living so he will likely be able to have financial independence and not need to work relatively soon. </p><figure><blockquote data-width="550"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">📈 Record sales yesterday of $2,342.04 on <a href="https://t.co/S9Qv34rpbP">https://t.co/S9Qv34rpbP</a> for no apparent reason (maybe companies are spending their EOY HR budgets?). Normal sales is like $299 or 1 post per day. <a href="https://t.co/8HukglDuiv">pic.twitter.com/8HukglDuiv</a></p>— ؜ (@levelsio) <a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio/status/938699122445451265?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2017</a></blockquote>

</figure><figure><blockquote data-width="550"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/rORz8xdCQp">https://t.co/rORz8xdCQp</a> is a single PHP file called "index.php" generating $2,342.04 in a day. No frameworks. No libraries. 💖</p>— ؜ (@levelsio) <a href="https://twitter.com/levelsio/status/938707166508154880?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 7, 2017</a></blockquote>

</figure><h2 id="what-is-pieter-levels-working-on-now">What is Pieter Levels working on now?</h2><p>He just released a new project, <a href="https://remoteworkers.dev/">Remote Workers</a>, where people can post their resumé. He "built in public" - that is to say he gave daily updates of his code on Twitter. This is also a great way for developers to build an audience! You can check out what people are saying about Remote Workers on <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/remote-workers">Product Hunt</a>. </p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>Pieter is like a bare knuckle boxer so don't compare him to a Judo practioner going to the Olympics. One is going to win no matter what and one is going to follow the rules they have trained under and have finer technique. Neither is better or worse. It depends on the situation. </p><p>Pieter's approach would not be good if you were trying to get a job in a lot of companies. But Pieter isn't looking for a job and the proof for him is in his bank balance. So Pieter's scrappy technique is better suited if you are attracted to coding for entrepreneurship and being a solo founder who doesn't have to share their code with others to work on. He doesn't use Github to save his code, for instance and this is an industry standard that most employers expect. If you want to be an indie hacker/entrepreneur though then Pieter is a fine act to follow. </p><h3 id="if-you-enjoyed-this-article-please-send-it-to-a-friend">If you enjoyed this article please send it to a friend </h3><!--kg-card-begin: html--><!--kg-card-end: html--><h3 id="and-you-should-totally-sign-up-for-the-newsletter">And you should totally <a href="https://nocsdegree.carrd.co/">sign up for the newsletter</a> </h3>
                    </div>
                </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.nocsdegree.com/pieter-levels-learn-coding/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24259201</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A tale of webpage speed, or throwing away React]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24258855">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
August 24, 2020 | https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section itemprop="articleBody">
  <p>Back in 2011, I happened to get a job writing <a href="https://backbonejs.org/">Backbone.js</a> app. If you never did that, don’t. I was complaining about difficulties with composition left and right to whoever would listen. As I started digging into alternatives for the front-end, I discovered <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_reactive_programming">FRP</a> and <a href="https://www.flapjax-lang.org/">Flapjax</a>, and <a href="https://clojurescript.org/">ClojureScript</a>. The last one got me hooked on <a href="https://clojure.org/">Clojure</a>. I even did a <a href="https://fwdays.com/event/js-frameworks-day-2013/review/Functional-Reactive-Programming-&amp;-ClojureScript">successful talk</a> on FRP and ClojureScript (and precursor to <a href="https://hoplon.io/">Hoplon</a>, called hlisp).</p>
<h2 id="react">React</h2>
<p>Then in May 2013 React was released. I championed it on my new job and discovered during Clojure-themed hackaton (<a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2013/clojurecup/">Clojure Cup 2013</a>) that CLJS and React are a great match. What’s so good about React though? To me, the main selling point is that it composes well.</p>
<p>When you use predecessors like jQuery or Backbone or Angular or whatever after just a year of development your code is a mess of event listeners and triggers. Don’t get me started on unobtrusive JS, code locality is non-existent with jQuery. Which handler is bound where and what it does? It’s too hard to discover to be a good base for a good codebase!</p>
<p>Then I started working at <a href="https://kasta.ua/">Kasta</a>, where web frontend was exactly that jQuery-ish mess. Nobody ever wanted to touch checkout, since you could spend hours, if not days, making the smallest change. Then QA would find more invalid states than you can dream of. And then users would report more bugs to our call center. It was just as awful as you can imagine.</p>
<p>So after some experiments, tests, and checks, I decided that we’re going React + ClojureScript way with server-side rendering done in Clojure.</p>
<h2 id="demise">Demise</h2>
<p>And for a while, things were looking good. We had this <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2017/server-side-rendering/">architecture</a> where our components are executed as Clojure on the backend, so no Node.js on the server, hurray! And developer UX is through the roof with the excellent live reload (thanks CLJS), ability to connect from your editor to browser REPL, and experiment there. It is just great!</p>
<p>To make a long story short, our frontend grew bigger and bigger. Incremental compilation started to become slower — it now routinely takes more than a second or two. And while there were few attempts on keeping the whole app performant, ultimately we failed. It’s a death by a thousand cuts. The application became too big and its boot time became too long. Server side rendering helps partially, but then hydration freezes the browser. On the older hardware or Androids it became unacceptable!</p>
<p>One of the main reasonings back in 2016 was that we take a hit on startup time, but in turn, get no page loads and have a rich web application with a lot of interactions. And for a while that worked! But startup time became longer and longer, leading to a shameful rating of 5/100 from Google’s PageSpeed (okay, it was sometimes up to ~25/100, whatever).</p>
<p>More than that, while doing what is described below, we’ve discovered that React also leads to some questionable practices. Like hovers in JS (rather than in CSS), drop-down menus in JS, not rendering hidden (under a hover) text (Google won’t be happy), weird complex logic (since it’s possible!), etc. You can have a React app without those problems, but apparently, you have to have better self-control than we had (nobody’s perfect!).</p>
<p>Also since then, the vast majority of our users switched to mobile apps. This made the web app the main entry point for new users. This means its main goal is rendering fast for a newcomer, because old-timers, which want more functionality, are on mobile app now. And <a href="https://web.dev/tti/">TTI</a> (time to interactive) is so much more important here.</p>
<h2 id="time-for-a-change">Time For A Change</h2>
<p>So given that circumstances have changed, what do we do? I read articles “how I survive on vanilla JS” since before React appeared and they usually don’t make sense — it’s either a pink-glassed rant about how great it is, disregarding all the problems (separation of concerns, cohesion, composability, code locality) or a project by one (or few) persons, who just keep everything in their head.</p>
<p>Somewhere back in February I stumbled upon <a href="https://intercoolerjs.org/">Intercooler.js</a>. I’m not sure if I ever saw it before — maybe I did but skimmed over — it does not matter. This time it captured my attention.</p>
<p>The idea is that all HTML is rendered on the server. And client updates parts of HTML, controlled by element’s attributes. Basically like HTML+XHR on steroids. You can’t do anything you want, but that’s partially the point: some limits are good so you won’t do crazy stuff. And you need some support from the server, so you can render partial results — just an optimization, but quite an important one.</p>
<p>There is an alternative library — <a href="https://unpoly.com/">Unpoly</a>. It has more features around layout and styling but has a little bit less thought out XHR stuff (hard to do a POST request with parameters without having a form, for example). And the library size is much bigger. And it’s written in CoffeeScript with lots of classes, <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/inheritance/">ugh</a>.</p>
<p>So I made a proof-of-concept implementation of our catalogue page in Intercooler and it worked! Except there was a dependency on jQuery and some other irritating stuff… As I was struggling to make a batch request for HTML fragments I understood one thing: when I wrote down a roadmap for catalogue the last point was “small intercooler-like thing for analytics”.</p>
<p>So why wait?</p>
<h2 id="twinspark">TwinSpark</h2>
<p>I liked Intercooler’s coherent approach to working around AJAX, so I decided to name the library after some automotive stuff as well, and TwinSpark seems like an appropriate name. So what’s the deal?</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/kasta-ua/twinspark-js">TwinSpark</a> is a framework for declarative HTML enhancement: you put additional attributes on your element and TwinSpark does something with them. Like makes an AJAX call and replaces target with a response, or adds a class, or… well, see <a href="https://kasta-ua.github.io/twinspark-js/">examples</a>, shall you?</p>
<p>There are some differences with Intercooler, of course, because why would it exist? The most noticeable one is that there is no dependency on jQuery. It supports only modern browsers (not IE or Opera Mini) but drops that 88kb monster.</p>
<p>It also has:</p>
<ul>
<li>no inheritance — can’t stress that enough!</li>
<li>clear extension points for your directives</li>
<li>support for batching requests to a server</li>
<li>tighter attribute name convention (my own opinion, but <code>ic-get</code> and <code>ic-post</code> irritate me: do not make me change keys!)</li>
<li>much smaller payload (thanks to no jQuery!)</li>
<li>should be faster (thanks to no jQuery again)</li>
</ul>
<p>Honestly speaking, the main reasons are <a href="https://kasta-ua.github.io/twinspark-js/#batch">batching</a> and <a href="https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/inheritance/">no inheritance</a>. Inheritance is particularly painful here. In Intercooler, if you declared <code>ic-target</code> on the body, all tags inside will think it’s their target too. So you include a component somewhere in HTML tree and an attribute higher on tree changes this component behavior. I mean this is a freaking dynamic scope, I want none of that! :)</p>
<p>Funnily enough, after about a month of dabbling with TwinSpark, Intercooler’s author announced that he’s doing a jQuery-less modern version: <a href="https://htmx.org/">htmx</a>. :) It has really good extensions points, so maybe it’s possible to add batching… but inheritance is still there. :-(</p>
<h2 id="why-is-that-a-good-idea">Why is that a good idea</h2>
<p>We need to look at it from two sides: if it’s good for developers and if it’s good for users. React was great at former and terrible at later.</p>
<p>TwinSpark approach is much better in most cases for the user: less JavaScript, less jitter, more common HTML-like behavior. In the worst case, we would serve you 2.5MB of minified (non-gzipped) JS and 700KB of HTML (half of it were initial data for React) for catalogue. JS bundle is not that big because of embedded images or css or some other obscure stuff, it’s big because it’s the whole app, with a lot of views and logic.</p>
<p>Now it’s 40KB of minified non-gzipped JS (TwinSpark, analytics, some behavior, IntersectionObserver polyfill) and 350KB of HTML. Two orders of magnitude difference and even HTML is smaller! This is just like Christmas in childhood!</p>
<p>On the developer side, I think React is better still, but code locality is great, composability is much better (since you are forced in a limited world of working in a simplistic model) than with jQuery. Plus there are a lot of ways to improve it.</p>
<p>The good news is that the development process did not change that much! We’re still writing components that query necessary data from site-wide memory store (and make a call to API when needed), but they are executed only on the server. We effectively piggy-backend on our previous architecture, and this gives us the perfect ability to render “partial” HTML - since components do not wait for some “controller” to give them all necessary data. This is what allowed us to have both React and non-React versions to co-exist and make an A/B test without writing the markup twice.</p>
<h2 id="results">Results</h2>
<p>It took us four months since the first experiments to release. Not exactly the amount of time I imagined when we started (“should take two to three weeks at most!"), heh, but we were not exclusively doing that. It still took a lot of time and energy to remove React-isms from the code and wrangle our app to be a server-side citizen. It still could use some polishing, but we decided to release it despite that just to cut it short. And A/B test showed that we were right — especially for Android phones.</p>
<p>Google gives our catalogue 75/100 now instead of 5/100. Hurray, I guess? :)</p>

  </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://solovyov.net/blog/2020/a-tale-of-webpage-speed-or-throwing-away-react/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24258855</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 09:25:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Principal Component Analysis]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24257468">thread link</a>) | @keyboardman
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>

<p>Principal components analysis (PCA) is one of a family of techniques for taking high-dimensional data, and using the dependencies between the variables to represent it in a more tractable, lower-dimensional form, without losing too much information. It has been widely used for data compression and de-noising. However, its entire mathematical process is sometimes ambiguous to the user.</p>



<p>In this article, I would like to discuss the entire process of PCA mathematically, including PCA projection and reconstruction, with most of the derivations and proofs provided. At the end of the article, I implemented PCA projection and reconstruction from scratch. After reading this article, there should be no more black box in PCA anymore.</p>

<h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites</h3>

<h4 id="orthogonal-matrix">Orthogonal Matrix</h4>

<p>In linear algebra, an orthogonal matrix is a real square matrix whose columns and rows are orthogonal unit vectors (orthonormal vectors).</p>



<p>Equivalently, the mathematical expression is</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\top}A = AA^{\top} = I
\end{align}\]

</p><p>By <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Invertible_matrix">the definition of invertible matrix</a>, this means matrix $A$ is invertible and $A^{-1} = A^{\top}$.</p>



<p>We could also view this from the perspective of determinant.</p>



<p>Because $A$ and $A^{\top}$ are square matrices and using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Determinant#Properties_of_the_determinant">the properties of determinant</a></p><p>

\[\begin{align}
\det(I) &amp;= \det(A^{\top}A) \\
&amp;= \det(AA^{\top}) \\
&amp;= \det(A) \det(A^{\top}) \\
&amp;= \det(A) \det(A) \\
&amp;= \det(A)^2 \\
&amp;= \det(A^{\top})^2 \\
&amp;= 1 \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Since $\det(A) \neq 0$, matrix $A$ is invertible. We multiply $A^{-1}$ on both side of the orthogonal matrix definition.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\top}A A^{-1} &amp;= I A^{-1}\\
A^{\top} I &amp;= A^{-1} \\
A^{\top} &amp;= A^{-1} \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We have also derived the conclusion that $A^{-1} = A^{\top}$.</p>



<p>Similarly, a complex square matrix $A$ is unitary if its transpose conjugate $A^{\dagger}$ is also its inverse.</p>



<p>Equivalently, the mathematical expression is</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\dagger}A = AA^{\dagger} = I
\end{align}\]

</p><h4 id="symmetric-matrix">Symmetric Matrix</h4>

<p>Real symmetric matrix has the following useful properties:</p>



<p>If $A$ is a real symmetric matrix, all of its eigenvalues are real numbers.</p>



<p>Because of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complex_conjugate#Generalizations">the conjugate properties</a> and $\overline{A} = A$ since $A$ is a real value matrix,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
\overline{Av} &amp;= \overline{\lambda v} \\
&amp;= \overline{A} \overline{v} \\
&amp;= A \overline{v} \\
&amp;= \overline{\lambda} \overline{v} \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We got $A \overline{v} = \overline{\lambda} \overline{v}$.</p>



<p>Let $\lambda \in \mathbb{C}$ be an eigenvalue of the symmetric matrix $A$. $Av = \lambda v$ and $v \neq 0$. We multiply $v^{\dagger}$ ($v^{\dagger} = \overline{v}^{\top}$) to the both sides, and because of $A^{\top} = A$ and the property we have just derived $A \overline{v} = \overline{\lambda} \overline{v}$,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
v^{\dagger} A v &amp;= \lambda v^{\dagger} v \\
&amp;= v^{\dagger} A^{\top} v \\
&amp;= \overline{v}^{\top} A^{\top} v \\
&amp;= (A\overline{v})^{\top} v \\
&amp;= (\overline{\lambda} \overline{v})^{\top} v \\
&amp;= \overline{\lambda}^{\top} \overline{v}^{\top} v \\
&amp;= \overline{\lambda} v^{\dagger} v \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We have $\lambda v^{\dagger} v = \overline{\lambda} v^{\dagger} v$, thus $\lambda$ is real.</p>



<p>This concludes the proof.</p>

<h4 id="positive-semi-definite-matrix">Positive Semi-Definite Matrix</h4>

<p>The $n \times n$ symmetric matrix $A$ is defined to be positive semi-definite, if $x^{\dagger} A x \geq 0$ for $x \in \mathbb{C}^n$.</p>



<p>The positive semi-definite matrix has the following important property:</p>



<p>The eigenvalues of positive semi-definite matrix are non-negative.</p>



<p>Because $x^{\dagger} A x \geq$ for $x \in \mathbb{C}^n$, suppose $x$ is an eigenvector of $A$ and $Ax = \lambda x$ where $x \neq 0$,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
x^{\dagger} A x &amp;= x^{\dagger} \lambda x \\
&amp;= \lambda x^{\dagger} x \\
&amp;\geq 0 \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Because $x^{\dagger} x$ must be real number and $x^{\dagger} x &gt; 0$, we have $\lambda \geq 0$.</p>



<p>This concludes the proof.</p>

<h4 id="covariance-matrix">Covariance Matrix</h4>

<p>The covariance matrix has the following important property:</p>



<p>Covariance matrix is positive semi-definite. This means that the eigenvalues of covariance matrix is non-negative.</p>



<p>The proof of that covariance must be positive semi-definite could be found in my previous post on <a href="https://leimao.github.io/blog/Multivariate-Gaussian-Covariance-Matrix/">Multivariate Gaussian and Covariance Matrix</a>.</p>

<h4 id="singular-values">Singular Values</h4>

<p>The singular values, $\sigma_1$, $\sigma_2$, $\cdots$, $\sigma_r$, of an $m \times n$ matrix $A$ are the square roots, $\sigma_i = \sqrt{\lambda_i}$, of non-negative eigenvalues of the associated Gram matrix $K = A^{\dagger}A$. The corresponding eigenvectors of $K$ are known as singular vectors of $A$.</p>



<p>Note that the associated Gram matrix $K = A^{\dagger}A$ is real and symmetric, so the eigenvalues of $K$ are all real.</p>



<p>$K = A^{\dagger}A$ is also positive semi-definite.</p>



<p>For any vector $x$</p><p>

\[x^{\dagger} (A^{\dagger} A) x = (Ax)^{\dagger} Ax\]

</p><p>Because $Ax$ is also a vector,</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
x^{\dagger} (A^{\dagger} A) x \geq 0
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Therefore, all the eigenvalues of $K = A^{\dagger}A$ are non-negative and they all have a corresponded singular value of $A$.</p>

<h4 id="singular-value-decomposition">Singular Value Decomposition</h4>

<p>In linear algebra, the singular value decomposition (SVD) is a factorization of a real or complex matrix that generalizes the eigendecomposition of a square normal matrix to any $ m\times n$ matrix via an extension of the polar decomposition.</p>



<p>Specifically, the singular value decomposition of an $m \times n$ real or complex matrix $M$ is a factorization of the form $U \Sigma V^{\dagger}$, where $U$ is an $m \times m$ real or complex unitary matrix, $\Sigma$ is a $m \times n$ rectangular diagonal matrix with non-negative real numbers on the diagonal, and $V$ is an $n \times n$ real or complex unitary matrix.</p>



<p>The diagonal entries $\sigma_{i}=\Sigma_{ii}$ of $\Sigma$ are known as the singular values of $M$. The number of non-zero singular values is equal to the rank of $M$.</p>



<p>In particular, for any matrix $A \in \mathbb{C}$,</p><p>

\[A_{m \times n} = U_{m\times m} \Sigma_{m \times n} V_{n \times n}^{\dagger}\]

</p><p>We will skip the proof for why every matrix has SVD and the algorithm for SVD.</p>

<h4 id="singular-value-decomposition-for-norm-matrix">Singular Value Decomposition for Norm Matrix</h4>

<p>For any matrix $A \in \mathbb{C}$, $A^{\dagger} A$ could be expressed as</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\dagger} A &amp;= (U \Sigma V^{\dagger})^{\dagger} U \Sigma V^{\dagger} \\
&amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} U^{\dagger}  U \Sigma V^{\dagger} \\
&amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} I \Sigma V^{\dagger} \\
&amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma V^{\dagger}
\end{align}\]

</p><p>We multiply $V$ at both side of the equation.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A^{\dagger} A V &amp;= V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma V^{\dagger} V \\
&amp;=  V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma I \\
&amp;=  V \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma \\
&amp;= \Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma V \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Note that $\Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma$ is a square diagonal matrix. Based on the definition of eigenvalue and eigenvectors, the diagonal values of $\Sigma^{\dagger} \Sigma$, including the zeros, are the eigenvalues of $A^{\dagger} A$. All the columns of $V$ are the corresponding eigenvectors of $A^{\dagger} A$.</p>



<p>Similarly, $A A^{\dagger}$ could be expressed as</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
A A^{\dagger} U &amp;= \Sigma \Sigma^{\dagger} U \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Note that $\Sigma \Sigma^{\dagger}$ is a square diagonal matrix. Based on the definition of eigenvalue and eigenvectors, the diagonal values of $\Sigma \Sigma^{\dagger}$, including the zeros, are the eigenvalues of $A A^{\dagger}$. All the columns of $U$ are the corresponding eigenvectors of $A A^{\dagger}$.</p>

<h3 id="mathematics-of-principal-components-analysis">Mathematics of Principal Components Analysis</h3>

<p>We start with $p$-dimensional vectors, and want to summarize them by projecting down into a $q$-dimensional subspace, where $q \leq p$. Our summary will be the projection of the original vectors on to $q$ directions, the principal axes, which span the subspace.</p>

<h4 id="minimizing-projection-residuals">Minimizing Projection Residuals</h4>

<p>Given a dataset $X \in \mathbb{R}^{n \times p}$ whose row is the centered data vectors $x_i \in \mathbb{R}^p$ for $0 \leq i \leq n-1$ ($\sum_{i=0}^{n-1} x_{i} = 0$), if we have a unit vector $w \in \mathbb{R}^p$ ($|w| = 1$) and we project the all the data vectors to this unit vector $w$.</p>



<p>The length of projection for data vector $x_i$ on $w$, by definition, is</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
|x_i| \cos \theta &amp;= \frac{\langle x_i, w \rangle}{|w|} \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, w \rangle \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>where $\langle x_i, w \rangle$ is the inner product of $x_i$ and $w$.</p>



<p>The projection vector for data vector $x_i$ on $w$ is $\langle x_i, w \rangle w$.</p>



<p>The residual, which is the distance from data vector $x_i$ to $w$, is the length of vector $x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w$.</p>



<p>Let’s check what the residual square $| x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w | ^2$ is.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
| x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w |^2 &amp;= \langle x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w, x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w \rangle \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - \langle x_i, \langle x_i, w \rangle w \rangle - \langle \langle x_i, w \rangle w, x_i \rangle + \langle \langle x_i, w \rangle w, \langle x_i, w \rangle w \rangle \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - \langle x_i, w \rangle \langle x_i, w \rangle - \langle x_i, w \rangle \langle w, x_i \rangle + \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \langle w,  w \rangle \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - 2 \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 + \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 |w| ^2 \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - 2 \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 + \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \\
&amp;= \langle x_i, x_i \rangle -  \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>The optimization goal of projection is to minimize mean squared error $\text{MSE}(w)$, which is the mean of the residual sum of squares.</p><p>

\[\begin{align}
\text{MSE}(w) &amp;= \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1} | x_i - \langle x_i, w \rangle w |^2 \\
&amp;= \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1} \big( \langle x_i, x_i \rangle -  \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2 \big)\\
&amp;= \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1} \langle x_i, x_i \rangle - \frac{1}{n} \sum_{i=0}^{n-1}  \langle x_i, w \rangle ^2\\
\end{align}\]

</p><p>Remember the relationship between variance and expected value, $\mathbb{V}(X) = \mathbb{E}(X^2) - \mathbb{E}(X)^2$, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/">https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://leimao.github.io/article/Principal-Component-Analysis/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24257468</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 04:12:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How an unemployed 29 year old created the biotech industry]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24255736">thread link</a>) | @unignorant
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://www.baybridgebio.com/blog/lessons-from-genentech.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.baybridgebio.com/blog/lessons-from-genentech.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <div>
                
                
                <p>by Richard Murphey</p>
                <p>
                <img src="https://www.baybridgebio.com/Images/tom_perkins_on_bob_swanson.png"></p><p>There is no shortage of online content about how to start a tech company, but there is comparatively little on how to start a biotech startup.  I recently came across an amazing set of interviews with the founders of Genentech that is the one of the best resources I've seen on biotech entrepreneurship.</p>
                <p>In this post, I'll highlight 16 key quotes from early Genentech leaders and comment on how they can be applied to biotech startups today.</p>
                <p>The interviews that these quotes came from were originally conducted as source material for Sally Smith Hughes' book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00629MDKI/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">Genentech: The Beginnings of Biotech</a>.  This book is a must-read for anyone looking to learn about the industry (it's a quick and engaging read as well -- I finished it in a day).  The interview transcripts are worth reading in their entirety (especially the <a href="https://oac.cdlib.org/view?docId=kt9c6006s1&amp;query=&amp;brand=oac4">Bob Swanson</a> and <a href="https://oac.cdlib.org/view?docId=kt467nb7wh&amp;query=&amp;brand=oac4">Dave Goeddel</a> interviews) and are available for free online through <a href="http://bancroft.berkeley.edu/ROHO/projects/biosci/oh_list.html">Berkeley's Bancroft Library Oral History Center</a><sup>1</sup>.</p>
                <br>
                <h3>Early Genentech at a glance</h3>
                
                <p>To set the stage, here is a chart with major value inflection points during the early days of the company.  At this time, Bob Swanson, the founding CEO, was in his late 20s / early 30s, and most of Genentech's scientists, led by Dave Goeddel, were also in their 20s and 30s.  Bob's co-founder, UCSF professor Herb Boyer, was more experienced, but he took a fairly hands-off approach to the science.  Prior to starting Genentech, Bob had been laid off by venture fund Kleiner Perkins.</p>
                <p><img src="https://www.baybridgebio.com/Images/genentech_vc_valuation.png"></p><p>Genentech was created to use emerging genetic engineering technology to create new medicines.  When the company was founded, genetic engineering was a new and relatively unknown field.  The leading scientists in the area thought it would be years or decades before genetic engineering was advanced enough to create medicines.  Big pharma companies were universally dismissive of the technology.</p>
                <p>The venture capital and startup industry was also in its infancy.  There was no such thing as a biotech startup, and there hadn't been a new pharma company created in decades.  Kleiner Perkins, one of the first venture capital funds, had just started (Bob was an early employee of the fund).  Apple was founded on April 1, 1976, less than a week before Genentech was founded.</p>
                <p>(As a side note, Apple and Genentech have always been somewhat linked.  Steve Jobs and Bob Swanson were the original young tech entrepreneurs.  When Genentech went public in 1980, it was the biggest tech IPO ever -- until Apple went public months later.  Art Levinson, who took over as Apple's chairman after Steve Jobs passed away and was on Google's board from 2004-2009, was an early employee at Genentech and was Genentech's CEO in the 1990s and 2000s).</p>
                <br>
                <h4>Overview of early Genentech's strategy</h4>
                
                <p>Genentech's strategy was to first prove that the technology could work -- that bacteria or yeast could be engineered to make human proteins -- and then to use genetic engineering to make products.  They proved the concept by getting bacteria to produce somatostatin, a small hormone.  Somatostatin wasn't useful as a medicine, but it was a relatively simple molecule to make with their tech and thus a good proof-of-concept.</p>
                <p>Genentech's first major product was recombinant insulin.  At the time, insulin was obtained by killing pigs or cows and extracting it from their tissues.  This was an expensive and potentially less safe approach than producing human insulin from bacteria or yeast.  Cloning insulin put Genentech on the scientific and financial map and kickstarted the biotech industry.</p>
                <p>With that context in hand, here's how Genentech approached building a biotech startup:</p>
                <br>
                <h3>Create value by eliminating risk</h3>
                <br>
                <div>
                    <p>Bill Hambrecht…has said the only common characteristic he has noticed in the successful entrepreneurs he's invested in has been that they're all basically conservative…they're willing to go for it, but everyone is looking at how you minimize the risks as you're doing so.</p>
                    <p>- Bob Swanson</p>
                </div>
                <p>In most industries, companies create value by growing revenue or profits.  In biotherapeutics, companies cannot sell products until FDA approves them, which can take years.  But pre-revenue drugs can still be immensely valuable.  In development-stage drug companies, value is created by eliminating technical risk.</p>
                <p>Like many other entrepreneurs, Bob had a unique attitude toward risk: part risk-averse, part risk-seeking.  In the <a href="https://www.perell.com/podcast/josh">words of Josh Wolfe</a>, co-founder of Lux Capital, "entrepreneurs aren't risk takers.  They're risk killers".</p>
                <br>
                <h3>Build a "staircase of value"</h3>
                <br>
                <div>
                    <p>I tried to organize things so that once you had success and created value in the company, then you raised the next round of money for the next success that would create greater value…. So it's sort of building a staircase…to the point where your cash flow is positive from product sales.</p>
                    <p>- Bob Swanson</p>
                </div>
                <p>Bob's goal from the beginning was to build a fully integrated pharma company -- one that developed and sold its own products.  He broke this goal into small units of value creation, and raised a new round of capital to fund each unit.</p>
                <br>
                <h3>"Make something people want"</h3>
                <br>
                <div>
                    <p>This is the essence of a company. The better you understand customers' needs…the more value the product has that they're willing to buy. Then you make more money, and the more money you make, the more it says, "I'm doing things right. I'm a healthy company.”</p>
                    <p>- Bob Swanson</p>
                </div>
                <p>Bob understood that the success of the company depended on its ability to create value for customers.  In the words of Paul Graham, co-founder of Y Combinator, <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/good.html">"make something people want"</a>.</p>
                <p>This holds true in biotech today.  Understanding a patient's condition, the available treatment options, and unmet clinical needs is the starting point for developing a drug.</p>
                <br>
                <h3>Science first</h3>
                <br>
                <div>
                    <p>One of the reasons companies succeed or fail is which projects get cut and which ones don’t…. It's a judgement call, and that's where you need the very top scientists and medical doctors and everybody to make that call--when to stop it, when is enough, and when to go the next round.</p>
                    <p>- Bob Swanson</p>
                </div>
                <p>Genentech focused on recruiting the best scientists and creating a culture that prized science above all else.  Genentech needed the best scientists because it was working in a competitive, cutting edge field, but also knew that the company needed to be rigorous and scientific in its business decision making.</p>
                <br>
                <h3>Scientists first</h3>
                <br>
                <div>
                    <p><i>Bob Swanson</i>: Boyer's idea was…"Let's give [the young scientists] the credit." He didn't put his name on the insulin paper. And that, for a postdoc, is pretty attractive, rather than having your boss trying for the credit all the time and to keep you as the worker….</p>
                    <p>So the advantages were freedom from seeking out grants, a chance to be owners of the company.</p>
                    <p><i>Sally Smith Hughes</i>: Could you in addition to the equity offer them higher salaries than they were making in academia?</p>
                    <p><i>Bob</i>: Oh, yes. Postdocs continue to be very poorly paid. So yes, we could offer them good salaries.</p>
                </div>
                <p>To recruit the best scientists, Genentech combined the best attributes of academia and industry.  Genentech gave scientists the opportunity to work on important scientific problems, a large degree of freedom, and encouraged them to publish their results.  At the same time, Genentech gave credit based on merit, not seniority, paid scientists much more than they would make in academia, and issued stock grants that could provide life-changing financial gains if the company succeeded.</p>
                <br>
                <h3>Work on ambitious problems</h3>
                <br>
                <div>
                    <p>We don't work on any projects we can't get someone excited about…I think the key to any organization is hiring outstanding people, and helping them get excited about what they're doing.</p>
                    <p>- Bob Swanson</p>
                </div>
                <p>Genentech's ambition was key to recruiting and motivating the best scientists.  As <a href="http://blog.samaltman.com/how-to-be-successful">Sam Altman</a> says, "It’s easier to do a hard startup than an easy startup. People want to be part of something exciting and feel that their work matters."</p>
                <br>
                <h3>Products before platform</h3>
                <br>
                <div>
                    <p>We were very focused on products, and that made a big difference. I know Cetus at the time was more into developing the technology. I said, "Well, let's make a product, and we'll develop the technology we need to make the product, and let the product drive the science, rather than the other way around." Actually, we wound up doing better science because of that, and also we got a product.</p>
                    <p>- Bob Swanson</p>
                </div>
                <p>Genentech was developing arguably the most powerful tech platform in the history of pharma, but it didn't focus on building a platform.  Genentech focused first on products, and built their platform to support product development efforts.  This ended up being a …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.baybridgebio.com/blog/lessons-from-genentech.html">https://www.baybridgebio.com/blog/lessons-from-genentech.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.baybridgebio.com/blog/lessons-from-genentech.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24255736</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 22:12:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Clean Start for the Web]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24255541">thread link</a>) | @tannhaeuser
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>The web is in need of some reinvention right now.</p><p>The web’s evolution over the last decade has mirrored the American economy. All of the essential indicators are going “up and to the right,” a steady stream of fundamental advances reassure use that there “is progress,” but the actual experience and effects for individuals stagnates or regresses.</p><p>The crisis affects platforms, creators, and consumers alike.</p><p><em>I’m going to try and dissect and diagnose this situation, a bit. You can skip forward if you just want to read my casual, unprofessional pitch for a reboot of the web. The idea is that we could choose a new lightweight markdown format to replace HTML &amp; CSS, split the web into documents and applications, and find performance, accessibility, and fun again.</em></p><details><summary>This post uses the pedantic definition of "the web"</summary>I've discussed attempts to reinvent the "Internet" a few times. Things like dat, IPFS, and arweave are all projects to reinvent an Internet, or a transport and data-sharing layer. The web is what lies on top of that, the HTML, CSS, URLs, JavaScript, browsing experience.</details><h3 id="the-platform-collapse">The platform collapse</h3><p>The platform side is what changed last week, when <a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2020/08/firefox-maker-mozilla-lays-off-250-workers-says-covid-19-lowered-revenue/">Mozilla laid off 250 employees</a> and indicated that it would affect Firefox development. Firefox wasn’t the #2 browser - that’s Safari, mainly because of the captive audience of iPhone and iPad users. But it was the most popular browser that people <em>chose</em> to use.</p><p><img alt="Chart of browser market share, with Chrome becoming the monopoly" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-chart-of-browser-market-share-with-chrome-becoming-the-monopoly.png"></p><p><em>Chart from <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share#monthly-200901-202007">statcounter</a></em></p><p>The real winner is not just Chrome, but Chrome’s engine. One codebase, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KHTML">KHTML</a>, split into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebKit">WebKit</a> (Safari), and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blink_(browser_engine)">Blink</a> (Chrome, Microsoft Edge, Opera, etc.)</p><p>This a textbook monoculture. In one sense, it’s a victory for collaboration because nobody’s ‘wasting time’ on competing implementations and web developers can expect the same features and bugs across different browsers. But in a deeper way, it threatens one of the basic principles of how the web has evolved.</p><h3 id="specs--implementations">Specs &amp; implementations</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-decline.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Decline" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-decline.jpg"></picture></p><p>The web has evolved through a combination of <em>specifications</em> and <em>implementations</em>. Organizations like the <a href="https://whatwg.org/">WHATWG</a>, <a href="https://www.w3.org/">W3C</a>, and <a href="https://www.ietf.org/">IETF</a> have been collaboration spaces for independent developers, corporations, and academics to discuss potential new features of the web. Then, browsers would test those ideas out in a variety of implementations.</p><p>This was an interesting structural piece: it reassured us all that it was <em>possible</em> to follow along, and that a multi-participant web was one of our goals. It was frustrating to pull up <a href="https://caniuse.com/">caniuse</a> and see blank spots, but the idea was that different browsers may take the lead in some areas, but everyone catches up eventually. Chrome was not always the first to jump on features, or the first to optimize.</p><p>It’s slower to collaborate than to work alone, but it was beneficial in some ways that we’ve lost now. Chrome has been moving extremely fast, adding new specifications and ideas at a startling rate, and it’s becoming one of the hardest pieces of software to replicate.</p><p>Mike Healy I think <a href="https://twitter.com/mike_hasarms/status/1296575224599556097">said it best</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Do you think the web has almost ‘priced itself out of the market’ in terms of complexity if only 1-2 organisations are capable of building rendering engines for it?</p></blockquote><p>Not only is it nearly impossible to build a new browser from scratch, once you have one the ongoing cost of keeping up with standards requires a full team of experts. Read Drew DeVault’s <a href="https://drewdevault.com/2020/08/13/Web-browsers-need-to-stop.html">Web browsers need to stop</a> for that point, and keep reading all of Drew’s stuff.</p><details><summary>What about Flow?</summary>Yep, there’s a <a href="https://www.ekioh.com/flow-browser/">browser called Flow</a>, which may exist and may support a full range of web standards. If it does exist, I’ll be very excited about it, but it has been teased for almost a year now without any concrete evidence, so it could equally be vaporware.</details><h3 id="the-problem-for-creators">The problem for creators</h3><p>The web has gotten much harder to develop for.</p><p>The web has had about 25 years to grow, few opportunities to shrink, and is now surrounded by an extremely short-sighted culture that is an outgrowth of economic and career short-termism. There are lots of <a href="https://frankchimero.com/blog/2018/everything-easy/">ways to do anything</a>, and some of the most popular ways of building applications on the web are - in my opinion - <a href="https://macwright.com/2020/05/10/spa-fatigue.html">usually ghoulish overkill</a>.</p><p>The best way for folks to enter <em>web development</em> in 2020 is to choose a niche, like <a href="https://vuejs.org/">Vue.js</a> or <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a>, and hope that there’s a CSS and accessibility expert on their team.</p><p>For folks who just want to create a web page, who don’t want to enter an industry, there’s a baffling array of techniques, but all the simplest, probably-best ones are stigmatized. It’s easier to stumble into building your resume in React with GraphQL than it is to type some HTML in Notepad.</p><h3 id="the-problem-for-consumers">The problem for consumers</h3><p>We hope that all this innovation is <em>for the user</em>, but often it isn’t. Modern websites seem to be as large, slow, and buggy as they’ve ever been. Our computers are <a href="https://macwright.com/2019/11/15/something-is-wrong-with-computers.html">barely getting faster</a> and our internet connection speeds are stagnating (don’t even <em>try</em> to mention 5G). Webpage <a href="https://www.pingdom.com/blog/webpages-are-getting-larger-every-year-and-heres-why-it-matters/">size growth</a> is outpacing it all.</p><p>The end result is that I no longer expect pages to be fast, even with <a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock">uBlock</a> installed in Firefox and a good local <a href="https://sonic.net/">fiber internet provider</a>.</p><p>I don’t want to lay all of the blame at <em>those web developers</em>, though. Here’s a story from an old job that I find kind of funny. We were collecting some data from user interactions to answer simple questions like “do people click to upload or do they drag &amp; drop?” So we enabled <a href="https://segment.com/">Segment</a>, a tool that lets you add data-collection pipelines by including a single script. The problem, though, is that Segment offered a big page of on/off switches with hundreds of data providers &amp; ad-tech companies on it. And, sure, enough, some folks closer to the business side started <em>clicking all those buttons</em>.</p><p>See, the problem with ads and data tracking is that <em>you can</em>, and who is going to say no? (In that instance, I said no, and added a <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/CSP">CSP</a> that would block new advertiser access at the page level.)</p><h2 id="recreating-simplicity">Recreating simplicity</h2><blockquote><p>You cannot get a simple system by adding simplicity to a complex system. - <a href="http://erlang.org/pipermail/erlang-questions/2012-March/065087.html">Richard O’Keefe</a></p></blockquote><p>Where do we go from here? Some of the smartest folks out there have been <a href="https://twitter.com/_developit/status/1296628134406692865">advocating for a major version revision</a> of the web.</p><p><em>I am in no way qualified to speculate on a whole new web from scratch, but the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/08/21/us/california-wildfires.html">air quality</a> is scary so I’m skipping my run and it’s Saturday morning so here we are.</em></p><p>How do we make the web fun, participatory, and good?</p><p>My first thought is that there are two webs:</p><h3 id="the-document-web">The document web</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-web-pages.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Illustration of web pages" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-web-pages.jpg"></picture></p><p>There is the “document web”, like blogs, news, Wikipedia, Twitter, Facebook. This is basically the original vision of the web, as far as I can understand it (I was 2). Basically CSS, which we now think of as a way for designers to add brand identity and tweak pixel-perfect details, was instead mostly a way of making plain documents readable and letting the <em>readers</em> of those documents customize how they looked. This attribute actually <a href="https://twitter.com/autiomaa/status/1296755641164468224">survived for a while in Chrome, in the form of user stylesheets</a>, and <a href="https://davidwalsh.name/firefox-user-stylesheet">still works in Firefox</a>. Though it’s going to be a rough ride in the current web which has basically thrown away <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_HTML">semantic HTML</a> as an idea.</p><h3 id="the-application-web">The “application” web</h3><p><picture><source srcset="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-machines.webp" type="image/webp"><img alt="Illustration of machines" src="https://macwright.com/images/2020-08-22-clean-starts-for-the-web-illustration-of-machines.jpg"></picture></p><p>Then there’s the “application web”. This started as <em>server</em> applications, built with things like <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a> and <a href="https://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> and before them a variety of technologies that will live forever in corporations, like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jakarta_Servlet">Java Servlets</a>.</p><p><a href="https://backbonejs.org/">Backbone.js</a> demonstrated that a lot of these applications could be moved into the browser, and then <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a> and its many SPA-style competitors established a new order for the web – highly-interactive, quite complex, client-side applications.</p><h3 id="the-war-between-the-parts-of-the-web">The war between the parts of the web</h3><p>I posit that this dual-nature is part of what gives the web its magic. But it’s also a destructive force.</p><p>The magic is that a simple blog can be creative expression, can be beautifully interactive. This one isn’t, but I’m just saying - <a href="https://www.typewolf.com/site-of-the-day">it’s possible</a>.</p><p>The problem is that the “document web” is often plagued by application characteristics - it’s the JavaScript and animations and complexity that makes your average newspaper website an unmitigated disaster. Where document websites adopt application patterns they often accidentally sacrifice <a href="https://www.a11yproject.com/">accessibility</a>, performance, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_scraping">machine readability</a>.</p><p>And the “application web” is plagued by the document characteristics - interactive applications are going to great lengths to avoid most of the essential characteristics of HTML &amp; CSS and just use them as raw materials - avoiding writing any HTML directly at all, avoiding <a href="https://mxstbr.com/thoughts/css-in-js">writing any CSS directly at all</a>, avoiding <a href="https://www.react-spring.io/">default animation features</a>, replacing <a href="https://reactrouter.com/">page-based navigation with something that looks like it but works completely differently</a>. The application web uses <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/introducing-jsx.html">JSX</a>, not HTML, and would like that in the browser itself, or <a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a>, instead of JavaScript, and would like that too.</p><p>When I read blog posts from ‘traditional web developers’ who are mad that HTML &amp; CSS aren’t enough anymore and that everything is complicated –&nbsp;I think this is largely that the application stack for building websites has replaced the document stack in a lot of places. Where we would use Jekyll or server-side rendering, we now use React or Vue.js. There are advantages to that, but for a lot of minimally-interactive websites, it’s throwing away decades worth of knowledge in exchange for certain performance perks that might not even matter.</p><p>The appeal of social networks is partly because they let us create <em>documents</em> without thinking about web technology, and they provide guarantees around performance, accessibility, and polish that otherwise would take up our time. You don’t have to think about whether your last Facebook post will load quickly on your friend’s phone or whether your Instagram post will be correctly cropped and resized in the timeline - those things are taken care of.</p><p>To some extent, this doesn’t <em>need</em> to be something that only social networks provide, though: standards like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS">RSS</a> and services like <a href="https://www.instapaper.com/">Instapaper</a> show that pleasing formatting and distribution can be done at the <em>platform level</em> and be provided on top of existing vanilla websites.</p><details><summary>These are not absolutes.</summary>Yeah, I can hear it now: but these categories are not …</details></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html">https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://macwright.com/2020/08/22/clean-starts-for-the-web.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24255541</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 21:47:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Loot boxes in online games and their effect on consumers [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24254712">thread link</a>) | @infodocket
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/ATAG/2020/652732/IPOL_ATA(2020)652732_EN.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/ATAG/2020/652732/IPOL_ATA(2020)652732_EN.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/ATAG/2020/652732/IPOL_ATA(2020)652732_EN.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24254712</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 19:47:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bare Metal Rust Generics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 195 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24254048">thread link</a>) | @cube00
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>I've had the pleasure to work with very experienced firmware developers; the
kind of people who know the size of their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_zone_(computing)">red
zones</a> and routinely
transform coffee into linker scripts and pointer dereferences. In other words,
the <a href="http://www.catb.org/%7Eesr/jargon/html/story-of-mel.html">Mels</a> and <a href="https://www.usenix.org/system/files/1311_05-08_mickens.pdf">Zeus
Hammers</a> of the
world.</p>
<p>When it comes to the tools of our trade, many of them are curious and
experimental. Some of them—very much myself included—explore far enough to leave
pragmatism behind and veer into idealism, stubbornly forcing beautiful round
pegs into industrial square holes. Hey, maybe they're square for a reason, but
it doesn't hurt to try.</p>
<p>The majority of them aren't like that. Your average battle-tested firmware
developer has accrued a healthy distrust of the abstract, probably born of
watching shiny platonic constructs crash and burn with painfully <em>real</em> and
<em>concrete</em> error traces. It is sobering, having to chase a hardfault on a tiny
MCU across enough vtables and templated code to make Herb Sutter puke angle
brackets. No wonder modern approaches are met with some resistance unless the
LOADs and the STOREs are in clear view.</p>
<p>I felt this way too when someone suggested to me, back in 2014, that an
up-and-coming language called <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> showed promise
in the embedded field. <em>Surely not</em>, I thought, <em>too high level.</em> Even though I
had been playing with it already, my profoundly ingrained bit-twiddling
instincts told me not to trust a language that supported functional programming,
or one that dared to have an <em>opinion</em> on how I managed my memory. Bah! That's
how you get philosophers to run out of forks, and your forks to turn into
SIGSEGVs.</p>
<p>I was wrong.</p>
<p>Through the past five years of experimentation, I've gone from intrigued, to
optimistic, to <em>convinced</em> that Rust is an ideal language to build industrial
grade, bulletproof bare metal software. Beyond that, I've come to realize that
even the highest level constructs that the base language offers are applicable
to firmware development, very much unlike other languages that span a wide range
of paradigms (I'm looking at you, C++). There are a few reasons I felt this way:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rust's safety guarantees and general strictness bring the debug time down
significantly, so there's less need to spend time developing mental maps of
how high level constructs correspond to hardware primitives.</li>
<li>The type system is <em>great</em> at enforcing local reasoning and preventing leaky
abstractions. Building decoupled systems with no runtime cost is easy.</li>
<li>The compiler error messages are worthy of an AI assistant with <em>concerning</em>
mind-reading abilities.</li>
</ul>
<p>Lately, I've had the chance to work on a Rust
<a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f412.html">STM32F412</a>
project in a professional setting, with one of the goals being to foster a Rust
knowledge pool at my company. The project, <code>Loadstone</code>, is a 32kb secure
bootloader targeting bare metal devices for the medical industry.</p>
<p>While it would've been easier—and much less of a headache to my colleagues—to
stick to a subset of Rust more familiar to C developers, with your <code>for</code>s, your
<code>*mut u8</code>s and your <code>unsafe</code>s, I instead decided not to pull any punches and
make liberal use of generics, iterator adapters, typestate programming and other
stuff that would've made 2010's cuervo cry blood and hug the closest copy of
Kernighan and Ritchie.</p>
<p>The pressures of a real collaborative project have taught me a lot, and many
assumptions have been refined thanks to the criticism of several skilled
outsiders who, as outsiders often do, had a privileged view on things I took for
granted.</p>
<p>A topic that came up frequently in code review is
<a href="https://thume.ca/2019/07/14/a-tour-of-metaprogramming-models-for-generics/">generics</a>.
Perhaps still recovering from a SFINAE nightmare, some colleagues were
unsure about the use of generics to group behaviour that we'd normally write
separate implementations for. The concerns tended to fall in one of three
categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Runtime performance.</li>
<li>Binary size bloat.</li>
<li>Habitability and readability.</li>
</ul>
<p>The first is easy to dispel, as it often comes from unfamiliarity with static
dispatch. No vtables or heap allocations in anything we're doing, promise! The
second concern is valid but I've found it to be negligible in practice; I have
plans for another blog post giving some concrete benchmarks.</p>
<p>The last concern is the most subjective and thus the hardest to argue, so I
decided to focus on it in this blog series. I'll go over the design process of
two similar flash memory drivers, and hopefully show how generic programming can
make the job easier and the result more habitable, even in the barren, heapless,
rugged world of bare metal firmware.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Compile times are another common—and very valid—argument against liberal use
of generics. However, it is not a big problem for low footprint embedded
projects like this one.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_memory">Flash memory</a> is electronic
non-volatile storage. It's ubiquitous in consumer electronics; any time you
switch a small device off and it <em>remembers something</em>—whether it's settings,
songs, documents, even its own program—chances are you have flash memory to
thank. We'll be looking at two different <em>NOR</em> flash chips, since the first demo
port of <code>Loadstone</code> requires us to operate both:</p>
<ul>
<li>The embedded
<a href="https://www.st.com/en/microcontrollers-microprocessors/stm32f412.html">STM32F412</a>
1MB MCU flash.</li>
<li>The external 128MB <a href="https://www.micron.com/-/media/client/global/documents/products/data-sheet/nor-flash/serial-nor/n25q/n25q_128mb_1_8v_65nm.pdf">Micron
N25Q128</a>
flash chip present in the <a href="https://www.st.com/en/evaluation-tools/32f412gdiscovery.html">STM32F412ZGT6 Discovery
Kit</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You probably knew what flash memory is used for already, but what non-firmware
developers may not know is that flash memory is <em>quirky</em>. You cannot simply
write a byte to a NOR flash address, sir, that would be rude. While a blob of
flash memory will happily turn a <code>1</code> into a <code>0</code>, the opposite operation will
fail silently.</p>
<p>You can think of every <code>1</code> bit (NOR flash's <em>erased</em> state) as a lit candle you
can blow out. However, in this metaphor you don't get a lighter
to light them back up; you get a flamethrower. Without getting into the hardware
principles involved, the design of NOR flash memory requires that you erase
(i.e. set to <code>1</code>) memory <em>in bulk</em>, in chunks often orders of magnitude bigger
than the minimum addressable memory. On most chips you even have a three way
mismatch: your read, write and erase sizes aren't equal. Ugh.</p>
<p>As you can imagine, this makes writing flash drivers a bit of a pain,
particularly because even the smallest write operations turn into <em>read/write
cycles</em>. Writing a single byte requires reading the minimum erasable block
surrounding the targeted address (which may itself require multiple reads),
potentially erasing the entire block, then writing back the original data merged
with the desired byte.</p>
<p>As you can also imagine, nobody but the person writing this driver <em>wants to
care about this</em>. Even in the minimalistic world of bare metal software,
productive collaboration depends on developers filing away these sharp edges,
presenting interfaces that uniformize or hide any aspects of hardware irrelevant
to the bigger design. As such, a first stab at a flash memory interface should
simply offer a way to read and write ranges of memory.</p>
<p>Let's look at some code:</p>
<pre><code><span>pub trait </span><span>ReadWrite {
   </span><span>type </span><span>Error;
   </span><span>type </span><span>Address;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>address</span><span>: </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>bytes</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span><span> [</span><span>u8</span><span>]) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>write</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>, </span><span>address</span><span>: </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>bytes</span><span>: </span><span>&amp;</span><span>[</span><span>u8</span><span>]) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
   </span><span>fn </span><span>range</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>) -&gt; (</span><span>Self::</span><span>Address, </span><span>Self::</span><span>Address);
   </span><span>fn </span><span>erase</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>mut </span><span>self</span><span>) -&gt; </span><span>Result</span><span>&lt;(), </span><span>Self::</span><span>Error&gt;;
}
</span></code></pre>
<p>The above is what I converged on as a generic interface to a flash
driver. If you're unfamiliar with Rust generics, the above isn't a type, or a
parent class to inherit from. It's more like a Haskell typeclass; a set of
requirements for a concrete type to implement, described in this case in the
form of associated types (<code>Error</code> and <code>Address</code>) and method signatures (<code>read</code>,
<code>write</code>, <code>range</code> and <code>erase</code>).</p>
<p>Even at this early step, some tradeoffs have to be made. The keen,
hardfault-traumatized reader will notice that this interface doesn't lend itself
well to timing sensitive problems. All methods are blocking, and abstracting the
read/write cycle away will naturally lead to non-deterministic write times; a
write may take very little if it only requires toggling bits off, or it might
take very long if it straddles two big sectors requiring erase operations. The
<code>bytes</code> output parameter in <code>read</code> might also strike you as not too rusty, where
returning a <code>Vec&lt;u8&gt;</code> is often idiomatic. Unfortunately we have no heap to work
with, so if you want to take your bytes home you'll have to bring your own bag.</p>
<p>Indeed, it's hard to write the universal interface. This one made sense for the
problems we're solving, but make sure to keep in mind the requirements of your
project!</p>
<h3 id="why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type">Why not simply write a concrete type?<a href="#why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type" aria-label="Anchor link for: why-not-simply-write-a-concrete-type">🔗</a></h3>
<p>Ah, the word "simply" is tricky. Datasheet in hand, it may have been easier to
write. It might even save us a few bytes down the line. But altogether I think
the benefits of starting here are well worth the drawbacks:</p>
<ul>
<li>Makes it easy to write test doubles and leverage static dispatch for unit
testing. This kind of approach is what I miss the most when writing C, where
I'm forced to resort to link time substitution or to do things with the
preprocessor too vile to even mention here.</li>
<li>Decouples your design from the get go and makes collaboration easy. Another
developer can immediately start working against this interface, and it's
abstract enough to give you confidence it won't need to be changed as more
knowledge of the hardware emerges.</li>
<li>Going abstract first forces you to think long and hard about what behaviour is
common to each implementation and what behaviour isn't, which helps to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don%27t_repeat_yourself">not
repeat yourself</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>But the biggest reason, and one where C++ and Rust diverge, is the fact that
<em>you can reason about this interface locally</em>. This stems from a non-obvious
difference between the C++ template system and Rust traits. Where C++ templates
type check at the point of instantiation, Rust traits type check at the point of
definition.</p>
<p>What does this mean? It means that the inscrutable, seven-feet-deep-in-a-library
C++ template errors are impossible in Rust, because the compiler doesn't need to
go beyond the interface to prove it is used correctly.</p>
<p>A similar interface using C++ …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/">https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ecorax.net/as-above-so-below-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24254048</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 18:26:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Covid-19 fatality rate “worst miscalculation in the history of humanity”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24253636">thread link</a>) | @mrfusion
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/worst-miscalculation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/worst-miscalculation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
		<!-- #masthead .site-header -->

	<div id="main">

		<div id="primary">
			<div id="content" role="main">

			
				

				
<article id="post-1262">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
		
<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ron-Brown-PhD-.jpg" alt="Ron Brown Phd" width="167" height="171" srcset="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ron-Brown-PhD-.jpg 333w, https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Ron-Brown-PhD--292x300.jpg 292w" sizes="(max-width: 167px) 100vw, 167px"><figcaption><sup>Ronald B. Brown PhD</sup></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>This month, Dr. Ronald B. Brown had a daring paper published in <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/disaster-medicine-and-public-health-preparedness/article/public-health-lessons-learned-from-biases-in-coronavirus-mortality-overestimation/7ACD87D8FD2237285EB667BB28DCC6E9#" target="_blank">Disaster Medicine and Public Health Preparedness</a>, conservatively entitled <em>Public health lessons learned from biases in coronavirus mortality overestimation</em>. </p>



<p>“The subject of this article is disruptive, to say the least, although it is not as obvious from the title,” Dr. Brown told me in an email. “The manuscript cites the smoking-gun, documented&nbsp;evidence showing that the public’s overreaction to the coronavirus pandemic was based on the worst miscalculation in the history&nbsp;of humanity,&nbsp;in my opinion. My manuscript underwent an intensive&nbsp;peer-review process. You are the first media guy who has responded to my invitation.”</p>



<p>It’s sadly no surprise the media has not kept Dr. Brown’s phone ringing with interview requests. The abstract, in itself, contains a firecracker where he says: </p>



<p>“Results of this critical appraisal reveal information bias and selection bias in coronavirus mortality overestimation, most likely caused by misclassifying an influenza infection fatality rate (IFR) as a case fatality rate (CFR).”</p>



<p>Is that not what we’ve seen? The number of people they said would be buried in mass COVID-19 graves better reflects how many people simply ended up with a cough and fever.</p>



<p>Dr. Brown added that CDC and WHO documents show that the case fatality rate for influenza was similar to the coronavirus, implying that the lockdowns were pointless. His paper questions why the 2017-2018 influenza season in the United States did not “receive the same intensive media coverage as COVID-19.”</p>



<p>He points out that “the accuracy of coronavirus tests rushed into production during the pandemic were unknown.” And he explores how the  media began focusing on an increase in coronavirus cases while ignoring the decrease in  death rates.</p>



<p>Much of the article looks at how lockdowns and anti-social distancing probably had little or no effect on reducing COVID-19 deaths. He says that “the public’s belief that mitigation measures were responsible for reducing coronavirus mortality may be a post hoc fallacy if lower mortality was actually due to the overestimation of coronavirus deaths.”</p>



<p>Speaking on the damage done by the counter-measures, Brown writes: “The ethics of implementing fear-based public health campaigns needs to be reevaluated for the potential harm these strategies can cause.”</p>



<p>His report includes this mind-map on how we were all mind-warped:</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="447" height="447" src="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image.png" alt="" srcset="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image.png 447w, https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image-300x300.png 300w, https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/image-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 447px) 100vw, 447px"></figure></div>



<p>You can read Brown’s full paper at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/7ACD87D8FD2237285EB667BB28DCC6E9/S1935789320002980a.pdf/public_health_lessons_learned_from_biases_in_coronavirus_mortality_overestimation.pdf" target="_blank">Cambridge University Press</a>. It succinctly dismisses the notion that the <a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/resist-the-corona-craze/" data-type="post" data-id="405">corona craze</a> has anything to do with welfare of the people. As Albert Camus warned: “The welfare of the people in particular has always been the alibi of tyrants, and it provides the further advantage of giving the servants of tyranny a good conscience.”</p>
 	



</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
</article><!-- #post-1262 -->
	
<p><span>				
<hr>
<p><a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/face-mask-flyer/" rel="prev">previous</a> | 
<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/subscribe">subscribe</a> | 
<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/sanity-and-her-son/" rel="next">next</a></p>

<p colspan="3">
<img src="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/john-manley-outside-aug-2020-e1598311423971.jpeg" width="100" alt="John C. A. Manley">
	
	
	
	
	<strong>John C. A. Manley</strong>&nbsp;has spent over a  decade ghostwriting for medical doctors, as well as naturopaths, chiropractors  and Ayurvedic physicians. He publishes the&nbsp;<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/subscribe">COVID-19(84) Red Pill Posts</a>&nbsp;–  an email-based newsletter dedicated to preventing the governments of the world  from using an exaggerated pandemic as an excuse to violate our freedom, health,  privacy, livelihood and humanity. He is also writing a novel,&nbsp;<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/covid-27">COVID-27: A Dystopian Love Story</a>. You can visit his website at:&nbsp;<a href="https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/">MuchAdoAboutCorona.ca</a>
	
	
	
	</p></span>
			
			</p></div><!-- #content .site-content -->
		</div><!-- #primary .content-area -->


<!-- #masthead .site-header -->

	</div><!-- #main .site-main -->


	<!-- #colophon .site-footer -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://muchadoaboutcorona.ca/worst-miscalculation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24253636</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 17:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Finding vulnerable Twitter accounts with expired domains]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 183 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252524">thread link</a>) | @zainamro
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <p><a href="https://zainamro.com/hacks">← hacks</a></p>
    <h3>Finding vulnerable Twitter accounts with expired domains</h3>
    <p>August 23, 2020</p>
    <p>Recently, I discovered a simple yet suprisingly effective attack vector against Twitter accounts (and which likely applies to other platforms as well). This attack vector makes it easy to find and hack vulnerable accounts with login emails that are using expired domains. If a user creates a Twitter account with an email on their own domain, then forgets to renew their domain at some point, that account can be hijacked by registering the domain, forwarding all emails to your email, then submitting a password reset on that account. By itself, this is hardly an attack vector since finding such vulnerable accounts is the more important part, and we already know that owning someone's email is essentially a "game over" situation. This attack becomes more dangerous when you can combine it with an efficient method to find these vulnerable accounts quickly and at scale. As it turns out, this is trivial on Twitter for several reasons attributable to their platform design.</p>
    <p>If you're familiar with Twitter, you know that users are given the option to add a public website url. With a simple script and proxy, an attacker can quickly iterate over millions of accounts and check if the domain in that url is not registered; this usually indicates some likelihood that the Twitter account was created with an email address on a now-expired domain. To verify this, they can submit a password reset which will show them a censored version of the account email address for confirmation; however, even though it's censored, it still provides enough information to check if the email domain matches the expired domain listed on their account profile. If it does, the attacker now knows this is an account that can be hacked. Once this entire process is automated, it makes finding these accounts very easy. This method of account hijacking is very likely being used right now by malicious hackers, and I believe it accounts for a large portion of stolen accounts/handles on the platform.</p>
    <img src="https://zainamro.com/assets/img/twitter-emails.png">
    <p>This attack can potentially be executed on other platforms besides Twitter, assuming one can find a similar discovery method. In Twitter's case, they could make it harder to discover these accounts by not showing any email confirmation upon requesting a password reset. This would make the process more costly for attackers who would no longer be able to verify whether an account can be hacked prior to registering the domain. Or perhaps, Twitter should monitor and unlist domains that are no longer registered and notify users when this happens so that they're aware. As for most users, in addition to turning on 2FA, it's important to be very cautious when using an email on your own domain to create accounts; it makes it much easier to lose access if you forget to renew or can't under certain extreme circumstances like incarceration or death.</p>
    <p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252524">Comments</a></p>
    <!-- Global site tag (gtag.js) - Google Analytics -->
    
    
  

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://zainamro.com/hacks/finding-vulnerable-twitter-accounts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24252524</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 15:25:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Writing a simple Python to C compiler: hello, fibonacci]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24252233">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <p>In this post we'll write a Python to C compiler in Python. This is
especially easy to do since Python has a <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/ast.html">builtin parser
library</a> and because a
number of <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/">CPython internals are exposed for extension
writers</a>.</p>
<p>By the end of this post, in a few hundred lines of Python, we'll be able to
compile and run the following program:</p>
<pre><code>$ cat tests/recursive_fib.py
def fib(n):
    if n == 0 or n == 1:
        return n

    return fib(n - 1) + fib(n - 2)


def main():
    print(fib(40))
$ python3 pyc tests/recursive_fib.py
$ ./bin/a.out
102334155
</code></pre>
<p>This post implements an extremely small subset of Python and
<strong>completely gives up on even trying to manage memory</strong> because I
cannot fathom manual reference counting. Maybe some day I'll find a
way to swap in an easy GC like Boehm.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/eatonphil/pyc">Source code for this project is available on Github.</a></p>
<h3 id="dependencies">Dependencies</h3><p>We'll need Python3, GCC, libpython3, and clang-format.</p>
<p>On Fedora-based systems:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo dnf install gcc python3-devel clang-format python3
</code></pre>
<p>And on Debian-based systems:</p>
<pre><code>$ sudo apt install gcc python3-dev clang-format python3
</code></pre>
<p>
  This program will likely work as well on Windows, Mac, FreeBSD,
  etc. but I haven't gone through the trouble of testing this (or
  providing custom compiler directives). Pull requests welcome!
</p><h3 id="a-hand-written-first-pass">A hand-written first-pass</h3><p>Before we get into the compiler, let's write the fibonacci program by
hand in C using libpython.</p>
<p>As described in the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/extending/embedding.html#very-high-level-embedding">Python embedding
guide</a>
we'll need to include libpython and initialize it in
our <code>main.c</code>:</p>
<pre><code>#define PY_SSIZE_T_CLEAN
#include &lt;Python.h&gt;

int main(int argc, char *argv[]) {
  Py_Initialize();

  return 0;
}
</code></pre>
<p>To compile against libpython, we'll use
<a href="https://helpmanual.io/man1/python3-config/">python3-config</a> installed
as part of <code>python3-devel</code> to tell us what should be linked
at each step during compilation.</p>
<pre><code>$ gcc -c -o main.o $(python3-config --cflags) main.c
$ gcc $(python3-config --ldflags) main.o
$ ./a.out; echo $?
0
</code></pre>
<p>Cool! Now as we think about translating the fibonacci implementation,
we want to keep everything as Python objects for as long as
possible. This means passing and receiving
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/object.html">PyObject*</a> to and from
all functions, and converting all C integers to
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html">PyLong*</a>, a "subtype" of
<code>PyObject*</code>. You can imagine that everything in Python is
an <code>object</code> until you operate on it.</p>
<p>
  For more information on objects in Python, check out
  the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/reference/datamodel.html">Data
  model</a> page in Python docs.
</p><p>To map a C integer to a <code>PyLong*</code> we use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html#c.PyLong_FromLong">PyLong_FromLong</a>. To
map in reverse, we use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html#c.PyLong_AsLong">PyLong_AsLong</a>.</p>
<p>To compare two <code>PyObject*</code>s we can use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/object.html#c.PyObject_RichCompareBool">PyObject_RichCompareBool</a>
which will handle the comparison regardless of the type of the two
parameters. Without this helper we'd have to write complex checks to
make sure that the two sides are the same and if they are, unwrap them
into their underlying C value and compare the C value.</p>
<p>We can use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/number.html#c.PyNumber_Add">PyNumber_Add</a>
and
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/number.html#c.PyNumber_Subtract">PyNumber_Subtract</a>
for basic arithmetic, and there are many similar helpers available to
us for operations down the line.</p>
<p>Now we can write a translation:</p>
<pre><code>#define PY_SSIZE_T_CLEAN
#include &lt;Python.h&gt;

PyObject* fib(PyObject* n) {
  PyObject* zero = PyLong_FromLong(0);
  PyObject* one = PyLong_FromLong(1);
  if (PyObject_RichCompareBool(n, zero, Py_EQ) || PyObject_RichCompareBool(n, one, Py_EQ)) {
    return n;
  }

  PyObject* left = fib(PyNumber_Subtract(n, one));

  PyObject* two = PyLong_FromLong(2);
  PyObject* right = fib(PyNumber_Subtract(n, two));

  return PyNumber_Add(left, right);
}

int main(int argc, char *argv[]) {
  Py_Initialize();

  PyObject* res = fib(PyLong_FromLong(7)); // Should be 13

  return PyLong_AsLong(res);
}
</code></pre>
<p>Compile and run it:</p>
<pre><code>$ gcc -c -o main.o $(python3-config --cflags) main.c
$ gcc $(python3-config --ldflags) main.o
$ ./a.out; echo $?
13
</code></pre>
<p>That's great! But we cheated in one place. We assumed that the input
to the <code>fib</code> function was an integer, and we propagated
that assumption everywhere we wrote <code>PyNumber_*</code>
operations. When we write the compiler, we'll need to check that both
arguments are an integer before we call a numeric helper, otherwise we
may need to call a string concatenation helper or something else
entirely.</p>
<h3 id="compiler-architecture">Compiler Architecture</h3><p>We'll break the code into four major parts:</p>
<ol>
<li><code>libpyc.c</code>: helper functions for generated code</li>
<li><code>pyc/context.py</code>: utilities for scope and writing code in memory</li>
<li><code>pyc/codegen.py</code>: for generating C code from a Python AST</li>
<li><code>pyc/__main__.py</code>: the entrypoint</li>
</ol>
<p>
  When I'm writing a new compiler using an existing parser I almost
  always start with the entrypoint and code generator so I can explore
  the AST. However, it's easiest to explain the code if we start with
  the utilities first.
</p><p>We'll also want an empty <code>pyc/__init__.py</code>.</p>
<h3 id="libpyc.c">libpyc.c</h3><p>This C file will contain three helper functions for safely adding,
subtracting, and printing. It will be concatenated to the top of the
generated C file. We'll only support integers for now but this
structure sets us up for supporting more types later on.</p>
<p>We'll use
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/c-api/long.html#c.PyLong_Check">PyLong_Check</a>
before calling number-specific methods.</p>
<pre><code>#define PY_SSIZE_T_CLEAN
#include &lt;Python.h&gt;

inline PyObject* PYC_Add(PyObject* l, PyObject* r) {
  // TODO: allow __add__ override

  // Includes ints and bools
  if (PyLong_Check(l) &amp;&amp; PyLong_Check(r)) {
    return PyNumber_Add(l, r);
  }

  // TODO: handle str, etc.

  // TODO: throw exception
  return NULL;
}

inline PyObject* PYC_Sub(PyObject* l, PyObject* r) {
  // TODO: allow __add__ override

  // Includes ints and bools
  if (PyLong_Check(l) &amp;&amp; PyLong_Check(r)) {
    return PyNumber_Subtract(l, r);
  }

  // TODO: handle str, etc.

  // TODO: throw exception
  return NULL;
}

inline PyObject* PYC_Print(PyObject* o) {
  PyObject_Print(o, stdout, Py_PRINT_RAW);
  printf("\n");
  return Py_None;
}
</code></pre>
<p>That's it! We could generate these as strings in Python but it gets
hairy to do so. By using a dedicated C file, we can take advantage of
syntax highlighting since this file is only C code. And since we've
marked all functions as <code>inline</code>, there's no runtime cost
to using not embedding these as strings in Python.</p>
<h3 id="pyc/context.py">pyc/context.py</h3><p>This file will contain a <code>Context</code> class for managing
identifiers in scope and for proxying to a <code>Writer</code> class
that contains helpers for writing lines of C code.</p>
<p>We'll have two instances of the <code>Writer</code> class in
<code>Context</code> so that we can write to a body (or
current/primary) region and an initialization region.</p>
<p>The initialization region is necessary in case there are any variables
declared at the top-level. We can't initialize these variables in C
outside of a function since every <code>PyObject*</code> must be
created after calling <code>Py_Initialize</code>. This section will be
written into our C <code>main</code> function before we enter a
compiled Python <code>main</code> function.</p>
<pre><code>import copy


class Writer():
    content = ""

    def write(self, exp: str, indent: int = 0):
        self.content += ("  " * indent) + exp

    def writeln(self, stmt: str, indent: int = 0):
        self.write(stmt + "\n", indent)

    def write_statement(self, stmt: str, indent: int = 0):
        self.writeln(stmt + ";", indent)


class Context():
    initializations = Writer()
    body = Writer()
    indentation = 0

    scope = 0
    ret = None
    namings = {}
    counter = -1

    def __getattr__(self, name: str) -&gt; object:
        # Helpers to avoid passing in self.indentation every time
        outputs = [initializations", "body"]
        for output in outputs:
            if name.startswith(output):
                return lambda s, i=None: getattr(getattr(self, output), name[len(output)+1:])(s, i if i is not None else self.indentation)

        return object.__getattr__(self, name)

    def get_local(self, source_name: str) -&gt; dict:
        return self.namings[source_name]

    def register_global(self, name: str, loc: str):
        self.namings[name] = {
            "name": loc,
            "scope": 0,
        }

    def register_local(self, local: str = "tmp") -&gt; str:
        self.counter += 1
        self.namings[local] = {
            "name": f"{local}_{self.counter}",
            # naming dictionary is copied, so we need to capture scope
            # at declaration
            "scope": self.scope,
        }
        return self.namings[local]["name"]

    def copy(self):
        new = copy.copy(self)
        # For some reason copy.deepcopy doesn't do this
        new.namings = dict(new.namings)
        return new

    def at_toplevel(self):
        return self.scope == 0
</code></pre>
<p>This is all pretty boring boilerplate. Let's move on.</p>
<h3 id="pyc/<strong>main</strong>.py">pyc/<strong>main</strong>.py</h3><p>The entrypoint is responsible for reading source code, parsing it,
calling the code generator, writing the source code to a C file, and
compiling it.</p>
<p>First, we read and parse the source code:</p>
<pre><code>import ast
import os
import subprocess
import shutil
import sys

from context import Context
from codegen import generate

BUILTINS = {
    "print": "PYC_Print",
}


def main():
    target = sys.argv[1]
    with open(target) as f:
        source = f.read()
    tree = ast.parse(source, target)
</code></pre>
<p>Then we write <code>libpyc.c</code> into the body, register builtins,
and run code generation:</p>
<pre><code>
...

def main()
    ...

    ctx = Context()
    with open("libpyc.c") as f:
        ctx.body_write(f.read() + "\n")

    for builtin, fn in BUILTINS.items():
        ctx.register_global(builtin, fn)

    generate(ctx, tree)
</code></pre>
<p>Next, we create a clean output directory and write
<code>main.c</code> with the generated code and a <code>main</code>
function to initialization Python and any global variables:</p>
<pre><code>...

def main():
   ...

    # Create and move to working directory
    outdir = "bin"
    shutil.rmtree(outdir, ignore_errors=True)
    os.mkdir(outdir)
    os.chdir(outdir)

    with open("main.c", "w") as f:
        f.write(ctx.body.content)

        main = ctx.namings.get("main")["name"]
        f.write(f"""int main(int argc, char *argv[]) {{
  Py_Initialize();

  // Initialize globals, if any.
{ctx.initializations.content}
  PyObject* r = {main}();
  return PyLong_AsLong(r);
}}""")
</code></pre>
<p>Finally, we run <code>clang-format</code> and <code>gcc</code> against
the generated C code:</p>
<pre><code>...

def main():
    ...

    subprocess.run(["clang-format", "-i", "main.c"])

    cflags_raw = …</code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html">https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://notes.eatonphil.com/writing-a-simple-python-compiler.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24252233</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 14:35:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Microsoft .NET SDK is violating the GDPR, object now]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251579">thread link</a>) | @dgl
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-sdk-gdpr | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-sdk-gdpr">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p><b>Skip to the end if you just want a template for a "Right to object"
letter.</b></p>

<p>The .NET Core software development kit (SDK) is a set of command line tools
that allow development against Microsoft's .NET. When the command line tool is
run it sends some telemetry back to Microsoft.</p>

<p>This telemetry is <a href="https://aka.ms/dotnet-cli-telemetry">documented</a>, however the way it is implemented appears
against the <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/">GDPR</a> in multiple ways.</p>

<h3>Collection by default</h3>

<p>Running <code>dotnet help</code> on a clean install, will print a message about telemetry,
but will send the details on that run.</p>

<p><a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-help.png"><img src="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-help.png"></a></p>

<p>Therefore the GDPR requriements under <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/recitals/no-42/">"Burden of proof and requirements for
consent"</a> cannot be met -- even if we
give Microsoft the benefit of doubt and consider a command line application
somewhat special, it does not give us a chance to opt-out, yet alone opt-in.</p>

<p><a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-installer.png"><img src="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-installer.png"></a></p>

<p>During the installation process, there is a link to Microsoft's <a href="https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/privacystatement">Privacy
statement</a>, however this
does not mention the environment variable needed to opt-out, so there is no way
to opt out before the first piece of data is sent.</p>

<h3>Collecting personal data</h3>

<p>The linked information page, as well as the text printed  in the CLI both say "The data is
anonymous.", it clearly isn't. They collect MAC addresses and the current
working directory, which are sent to their servers hashed.</p>

<p>A key thing to understand: <b>Hashing without a salt does not make the data
anonymous or even pseudonymous.</b></p>

<p>See for example <a href="https://medium.com/@alexewerlof/gdpr-pseudonymization-techniques-62f7b3b46a56">GDPR pseudonymisation
techniques</a>.
Given this, it is a clear violation as <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-6-gdpr/">Article
6</a> requires specific purposes for processing,
but the data was claimed to be anonymous, which it isn't.</p>

<p>A common place to run "dotnet help" might be a home directory, which can often
include a username, e.g. <code>/home/dgl</code>. So while it's hashed it is easily
possible to find the hash that relates to a particular user:</p>

<pre><code>$ pwd
/home/dgl
$ echo -n $PWD | sha256sum
67acfe0ddd44867e1e5da5ddaf25a5b90e928f523cecf614e201c683b7533cf6  -
</code>
</pre>

<p>This matches the relevant part of the JSON sent:</p>

<pre><code>  "Current Path Hash": "67acfe0ddd44867e1e5da5ddaf25a5b90e928f523cecf614e201c683b7533cf6",
</code></pre>

<p>There are some discussions about the collection of MAC addresses in
<a href="https://github.com/dotnet/sdk/issues/6145">issue #6145</a> but no
particular reply from Microsoft; people suspect it's a GDPR violation. Note
that under the GDPR there are time limits for replying, so that's another
potential GDPR issue.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/ms-report.txt">report</a> I sent to Microsoft detailed how a
MAC address is likely not even 48-bits of search space, as we know what ones
are assigned, so brute-forcing is quite possible, particularly when combined
with the fact the search space can be reduced by filtering on the path
hash.</p>

<p>One principle of the GDPR is you need to explain why you're collecting
information, Microsoft do in a round about way, rather than on the link
printed by the command (<a href="https://aka.ms/dotnet-cli-telemetry">https://aka.ms/dotnet-cli-telemetry</a>) which explains what they are collecting, the "why" is hidden on a <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/dotnet/what-weve-learned-from-net-core-sdk-telemetry/">blog post</a>.</p><p>

It says:
</p><blockquote>
Hashed MAC address â€” Determine a cryptographically (SHA256) anonymous and unique ID for a machine. Useful to determine the aggregate number of machines that use .NET Core. This data will not be shared in the public data releases.
<p>

Hashed current working directory â€” Determine build machines from dev machines using the heuristic of a large number of working directories. This distinction helps explain large #s of builds from a machine.
</p></blockquote>


<p>This shows a clear intention to join the data, for some purposes. The "Hashed
MAC address" is obviously understood to be somewhat sensitive as it mentions
they won't share it. Interestingly the same is not said for the current working
directory, which is also sensitive.</p>

<h3>Privacy policy</h3>

<p>As mentioned Microsoft has a <a href="https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/privacystatement">general privacy policy</a>.</p>

<p>This could allow some collection, however:</p>

<blockquote>
You have choices when it comes to the technology you use and the data you
share. When we ask you to provide personal data, you can decline.
</blockquote>

<p>This behaviour would be GDPR compliant, but the key point is due to the first
collection behaviour of e.g. running <code>dotnet help</code> there is no chance to
decline. So the behaviour of the dotnet tool is inconsistent with their own
privacy policy.</p>

<h3>How to respond?</h3>

<p>I sent a report to Microsoft's security team, because arguably incorrect use of
a cryptographic hashing function (SHA256 of the items, without a salt) is a
"Security Design Flaw" which qualifies under the <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/msrc/bounty-dot-net-core">dotnet 
bug bounty</a>. This was
obviously fishing a bit, and Microsoft denied me. More surpsingly they don't
seem to consider this a problem at all, their final reply was:</p>

<blockquote>
We have updates scheduled for the first run experience and related documentation to make it more accurate. Personal data is handled consistently with GDPR requirements.
</blockquote>

<p>You'll notice that they don't talk about any actual collection changes. Also
interestingly if the data is anonymous as they claim, what "Personal data" are
they referring to in this reply?</p>

<h4>What's the route the GDPR gives us here?</h4>

<p>This is an interesting one, partly <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-11-gdpr/">Article 11 Processing which does not
  require identification</a> could apply, in that they can exclude themselves
from right of access, etc. With the exception of "Right to object".</p>

<p>There are two routes, either we give enough information for Microsoft to be
happy we identify ourselves (and use the right to erasure), or we use the right
to object, which while it doesn't require Microsoft to delete the data
entirely does require them to limit their use of it.</p>

<p>So I can object to any processing of my data, and as I've proved we can use
the MAC address to find my machine in their data. I believe given this has gone
on for several years that even if they make the data collection GDPR compliant,
there is a huge historical collection of data that may need clearing as it has
been collected unlawfully.</p>

<p>In my original <a href="https://dgl.cx/2020/08/ms-report.txt">report</a> to Microsoft I made some recommendations:</p>

<pre><code>
Recommendations:
<ul><li>Remove the telemetry, it avoids any potential GDPR issues;</li>
<li>Delete the historical data (I am not a lawyer, but I suspect this has GDPR
implications);
</li></ul></code></pre>

<p>It appears they do not intend to follow these so I suggest that any user of
.NET Core SDK in the European Union takes matters into their own hands and use
their right to object:</p>

<div>
<p>
[Your full address]
[The date]</p>

<p>To Data Controller, Microsoft Corporation</p>

<p>I am exercising my right to object under the General Data Protection
Regulation (Article 21).</p>

<p>It has come to my attention that Microsoft .NET Core SDK collects telemetry,
and the opt-out process for this data is flawed.</p>

<p>In particular setting the <code>DOTNET_CLI_TELEMETRY_OPTOUT</code> variable
is only suggested the first time the tool is run, so some data may have been
collected against my will.</p>

<p>In light of Microsoft not deleting this telemetry data for everyone (per the
report of David Leadbeater on 3 August 2020). I wish that my telemetry data is
restricted from further processing, as I have set the opt-out environment
variable, but I cannot be sure that some data has not reached Microsoft
already.</p>

<p>The MAC addresses of my machine(s) is/are:</p>

<p>XX:XX:XX:XX:XX:XX</p>

<p>I believe this is enough to identify my records, as they are stored as a
SHA256 hash of this MAC address.</p>

<p>Please send a full response within one calendar month confirming if you will
comply with my request. If you cannot respond within that timescale, please
tell me when you will be able to respond.</p>

<p>If there is anything you would like to discuss, please contact me.</p>

<p>Thank you,
</p></div>

<p>Obviously the somewhat strange thing about this is you reveal your MAC
address to Microsoft in the process, but I'm fairly sure the data protection
around GDPR requests is something that is well scrutinized.</p>

<p>If you do want to send this to Microsoft go to
<a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-GB/concern/privacy">https://www.microsoft.com/en-GB/concern/privacy</a> and select "I want to contact
Microsoftâ€™s Data Protection Officer".</p>

<p>It's strange this is still an issue as this was previously discussed over
two years ago (see this <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17177241">Hacker News
thread</a>). Let's use our right to object!</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dgl.cx/2020/08/dotnet-sdk-gdpr</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24251579</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:57:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Persisting as a solo founder]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 622 | Comments 232 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251403">thread link</a>) | @vishnumohandas
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><img src="https://sa.vishnu.tech/noscript.gif" alt="">




    



  



    
    <p><time itemprop="datePublished">August 19, 2020</time>
    </p>
    

<p>I quit my job in January 2020 to build a privacy friendly photo organizer.</p>

<p>As a 30 year old whose friends are either getting married or planning
off-springs, what I had underestimated was the difficulty involved in finding a co-founder and how that would compound the difficulty involved in
finding an investor.</p>

<p>Once I accepted the loneliness and the lack of a financial cushion I had to figure out a way to keep building without burning myself out.</p>

<p>It took me a while, but I have found a rhythm that works, and with it, a steady
source of endorphins. Here are some changes that helped me to keep things
moving.</p>

<h2 id="being-patient">Being patient</h2>

<p>Life is no longer as comfortable as it used to be and things are not always
going the way I want them to. Preseverance has been key and indirectly patience
too. Naval’s <a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/1261481752448524289" target="_blank">take on
meditation</a> (60 minutes x
60 days), was an eye opener. I’ve stuck with it since, and I now have an easier
time identifying negative thought patterns and sitting out situations that would
otherwise overwhelm me.</p>

<p>On some level, spending the last few months locked indoors with my parents, who
are not the most rational people in the world has also helped. But I wouldn’t
recommend it.</p>

<h2 id="reducing-procrastination">Reducing procrastination</h2>

<p>Over time I’ve realized that action precedes motivation and procrastination precedes guilt.</p>

<p>Breaking down tasks into chunks that seem trivial to accomplish has helped reduce the friction in getting started on unexciting grunt work.</p>

<p>Then there are tasks which I loathe from my core, like writing out applications
to VCs explaining why what I’m doing will matter. To those I attach reinforcing
personal reasons, like, “I need the $50k to hire that college junior who I love
working with, and that will give me spare bandwidth to focus on traction channels”.</p>

<h2 id="thinking-clearer">Thinking clearer</h2>

<p>It is sub-optimal to not have a coworker to bounce ideas off and rant about problems to. A lot of times it’s these conversations that help you gain clarity.</p>

<p>It’s a luxury I do not have so every time I feel stuck, I type/scribble my thoughts out, and then question everything that was written, and then document my realizations.</p>

<p>Task tracking has also helped in clearing the path. I write down unstructured
thoughts into a diary, and once I’ve clarity, I promote them to a Notion board
(that’s divided into <em>Thinking</em>, <em>Building</em>, <em>Reading</em>, <em>Writing</em> and
<em>Adulting</em>) and every Monday within an Excel sheet I track what was done, and
what is left to be done.</p>

<h2 id="reducing-distractions">Reducing distractions</h2>

<p>I’ve reduced my information consumption to free up brain cycles. I’ve disabled all notifications on my phone barring a few contacts, and I’ve more or less stopped browsing on it. As an added bonus, this has reduced the negativity with which I perceived the world.</p>

<p>To minimize the overhead of context switches, I split tasks into a tree of checkpoints. Before taking a break I note down the next simplest checkpoint so that when I get back to work there’s little friction to resume.</p>

<p>To help me zone out I keep <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5qap5aO4i9A" target="_blank">lofi
beats</a> or
<a href="http://github.audio/" target="_blank">github.audio</a> playing in the background. Listening to the
latter gives me a strange sense of motivation and makes me feel less alone.</p>

<h2 id="staying-grounded">Staying grounded</h2>

<p>I’m lucky to have some friends who call/text every other week. I look at them as my accountability partners and I talk to them about what I’m doing on a high level. While not all of them genuinely care, some do, and these conversations force me to reflect on how well I’m doing what I’m doing.</p>

<p>While Silicon Valley wisdom suggests that if I’m not sleeping I should be
working, failing because of a burn out would be stupid. An advantage of not
having a VC onboard so far has been the freedom to dictate my pace. So I spend
days thinking, reading, fiddling with my violin or just doing nothing when I
feel like writing code is not what I want to do.</p>

<hr>

<p>It’s been 7 months of building alone, and while this is not how I pictured things to be on my last day at work, this is the happiest I have ever been. There’s a long way to go, and the grind seems inviting.</p>

<p>This list is by no means exhaustive, for I’m still learning. If you’ve
anything to share, please join <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251403" target="_blank">the discussion on HackerNews</a>.</p>

<hr>

<p>If you are curious about what I’ve been building, check out
<a href="https://ente.io/" target="_blank">ente.io</a>.</p>

    <br>
    


</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vishnu.tech/posts/persistence/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24251403</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 12:27:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Automate third-party tools without API or writing a single line of code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24251082">thread link</a>) | @kinderjaje
<br/>
August 23, 2020 | https://community.vanila.io/automatio/general/automate-third-party-tools-without-api-or-writing-a-single-line-of-code~90f13832-1d14-4961-8bd7-a72fa98011de | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://community.vanila.io/automatio/general/automate-third-party-tools-without-api-or-writing-a-single-line-of-code~90f13832-1d14-4961-8bd7-a72fa98011de">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>Less than 1% of web have API. This means if the website or web app doesn't provide API, you will need to build a bot and automate it. If you are not programmer, it means you will need to hire someone to do it, which takes a lot of time and money. Even if you are a web developer, still it gonna take you days or weeks, depending on complexity. But!</p><h3>Meet Automatio</h3><p>This is how you can automate third-party tools without API or writing a single line of code. In this case, I am automating a website/tool for checking domain authority (DA) of the given URL.</p><p>Automatio will be able to deal with the complex scenario of inputting data (URL) into the input field, then solving Google re-captcha, clicking on the submit button, and then extracting the data we need.</p><p>🤖 Built with <a href="https://automatio.co/" target="_blank">Automatio</a> - No Code Web Automation Tool</p><p>🎥 Video URL: <a href="https://youtu.be/3KMDeQo8In8" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollower">https://youtu.be/3KMDeQo8In8</a></p><p><iframe title="iframe-https://www.youtube.com/embed/3KMDeQo8In8" width="100%" height="200" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3KMDeQo8In8"></iframe></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://community.vanila.io/automatio/general/automate-third-party-tools-without-api-or-writing-a-single-line-of-code~90f13832-1d14-4961-8bd7-a72fa98011de</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24251082</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 11:05:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[2020: An Isolation Odyssey]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24250068">thread link</a>) | @unhammer
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | http://lydiacambron.com/index.php/project/2020-an-isolation-odyssey/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://lydiacambron.com/index.php/project/2020-an-isolation-odyssey/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><em>2020: an isolation odyssey</em> is a reenactment of the iconic finale of <em>2001: A Space Odyssey</em> (Stanley Kubrick, 1968). Restaged in the context of home quarantine, the journey through time adapts to the mundane dramas of self-isolation–poking fun at the navel-gazing saga of life alone and indoors.</p>

<p>This project began in late March and was completed in late May, spanning the height of the pandemic in New York City. Staged in a one bedroom Brooklyn apartment, <em>2020</em> presents an obvious similarity to the domestic setting of <em>2001</em>. The stacked videos and synced movements also reveal parallels in emotion. The narrowness of daily life in a single space, transitioning from confusion to acceptance, a distorted sense of time, and ‘returning’ after a transformational event–all experiences analogous to quarantine. </p>

<p>The adapted version delineates the passing of time through wardrobe rather than age, identifying each phase of the character’s journey with a product of self care or PPE. Tools of private entertainment or self betterment are also used as props, questioning our confidence in products and productivity as anchors during times of uncertainty. Multitasking while #wfh, conjuring guilt or longing with unused exercise equipment, your entire being reduced to a measure of time–these scenes all illustrate the absurd comedy of trying to maintain control during this unprecedented and unpredictable time.<br>
</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://lydiacambron.com/index.php/project/2020-an-isolation-odyssey/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24250068</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 06:37:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Problem-Solving Techniques That Work for All Types of Challenges (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24249449">thread link</a>) | @wyclif
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>A lot of people don’t realize that there are general purpose problem solving techniques that cut across domains. They can help you deal with thorny challenges in work, your personal life, startups, or even if you’re trying to prove a new theorem in math.</p>



<p>Below are the 26 general purpose problem solving techniques that I like best, along with a one-word name I picked for each, and hypothetical examples to illustrate what sort of strategy I’m referring to.</p>



<p>Consider opening up this list whenever you’re stuck solving a challenging problem. It’s likely that one or more of these techniques can help!</p>



<h4>General Purpose Techniques for Solving Challenging Problems of All Kinds</h4>



<p>1. <strong>Clarifying</strong> – try to define the problem you are facing as precisely as you can, maybe by writing down a detailed description of exactly what the problem is and what constraints exist for a solution, or by describing it in detail to another person, which may lead to you realizing the problem is not quite what you had thought, or that it has a more obvious solution than you thought.</p>



<p>Life Example: <em>“I thought that I needed to find a new job, but when I thought really carefully about what I don’t like about my current job, I realized that I could likely fix those things by talking to my boss or even, potentially, just by thinking about them differently.”</em></p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“we thought we had a problem with users not wanting to sign up for the product, but when we carefully investigated what the problem really was, we discovered it was actually more of a problem of users wanting the product but then growing frustrated because of bad interface design.”</em></p>



<p>2. <strong>Subdividing</strong> – break the problem down into smaller problems in such a way that if you solve each of the small problems, you will have solved the entire problem.</p>



<p>Startup Example:<em> “My goal is to get company Z to become a partner with my company, and that seems hard, so let me break that goal into the steps of (a) listing the ways that company Z would benefit from becoming a partner with us, (b) finding an employee at company Z who would be responsive to hearing about these benefits, and (c) tracking down someone who can introduce me to that employee.”</em></p>



<p>Math Example:<em> “I want to prove that a certain property applies to all functions of a specific type, so I start by (a) showing that every function of that type can be written as a sum of a more specific type of function, then I show that (b) the property applies to each function of the more specific type, and finally I show that (c) if the property applies to each function in a set of functions then it applies to arbitrary sums of those functions as well.”</em></p>



<p>3. <strong>Simplifying </strong>– think of the simplest variation of the problem that you expect you can solve that shares important features in common with your problem, and see if solving this simpler problem gives you ideas for how to solve the more difficult version.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I don’t know how to hire a CTO, but I do know how to hire a software engineer because I’ve done it many times, and good CTOs will often themselves be good software engineers, so how can I tweak my software engineer hiring to make it appropriate for hiring a CTO?”</em></p>



<p>Math Example: <em>“I don’t know how to calculate this integral as it is, but if I remove one of the free parameters, I actually do know how to calculate it, and maybe doing that calculation will give me insight into the solution of the more complex integral.”</em></p>



<p>4. <strong>Crowd-sourcing</strong> – use suggestions from multiple people to gain insight into how to solve the problem, for instance by posting on Facebook or Twitter requesting people’s help, or by posting to a Q&amp;A site like Quora, or by sending emails to 10 people you know explaining the problem and requesting assistance.</p>



<p>Business Example: <em>“Do you have experience outsourcing manufacturing to China? If so, I’d appreciate hearing your thoughts about how to approach choosing a vendor.”</em></p>



<p>Health Example: <em>“I have trouble getting myself to stick to doing exercise daily. If you also used to have trouble getting yourself to exercise but don’t anymore, I’d love to know what worked to make it easier for you.”</em></p>



<p>5. <strong>Splintering</strong> – if the problem you are trying to solve has special cases that a solution to the general problem would also apply to, consider just one or two of these special cases as examples and solve the problem just for those cases first. Then see if a solution to one of those special cases helps you solve the problem in general.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I want to figure out how to improve employee retention in general, let me examine how I could have improved retention in the case of the last three people that quit.”</em></p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I want to figure out how to convince a large number of people to become customers, let me first figure out how to convince just Bill and John to become customers since they seem like the sort of customer I want to attract, and see what general lessons I learn from doing that.”</em></p>



<p>6. <strong>Reading</strong> – read the books or textbooks that seems most related to the topic, and see whether they provide a solution to the problem, or teach you enough related information that you can now solve it yourself. </p>



<p>Economics Example: <em>“Economists probably have already figured out reasonable ways to estimate demand elasticity, let’s see what an econometrics textbook says rather than trying to invent a technique from scratch.”</em></p>



<p>Mental Health Example: <em>“I’ve been feeling depressed for a long time, maybe I should read some well-liked books about depression, such as ‘Feeling Good.'”</em></p>



<p>7. <strong>Searching </strong>– think of a similar problem that you think practitioners, bloggers or academics might have already solved and search online (e.g., via google, Q&amp;A sites, or google scholar academic paper search) to see if anyone has done a write-up about how they solved it.</p>



<p>Advertising Example: <em>“I’m having trouble figuring out the right advertising keywords to bid on for my specific product, I bet someone has a blog post describing how to approach choosing keywords for other related products.”</em></p>



<p>Machine Learning Example:<em> “I can’t get this neural network to train properly in my specific case, I wonder if someone has written a tutorial about how to apply neural networks to related problems.”</em></p>



<p>8. <strong>Unconstraining</strong> – list all the constraints of the problem, then temporarily ignore one or more of the constraints that make the problem especially hard, and try to solve it without those constraints. If you can, then see if you can modify that unconstrained solution until it becomes a solution for the fully constrained problem.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“I need to hire someone who can do work at the intersection of machine learning and cryptography, let me drop the constraint of having cryptography experience and recruit machine learning people, then pick from among them a person that seems both generally capable and well positioned to learn the necessary cryptography.”</em></p>



<p>Computer Science Example: <em>“I need to implement a certain algorithm, and it needs to be efficient, but that seems very difficult, so let me first figure out how to implement an inefficient version of the algorithm (i.e., drop the efficiency constraint), then at the end I will try to figure out how to optimize that algorithm for efficiency.”</em></p>



<p>9. <strong>Distracting</strong> – fill your mind with everything you know about the problem, including facts, constraints, challenges, considerations, etc. and then stop thinking about the problem, and go and do a relaxing activity that requires little focus, such as walking, swimming, cooking, napping or taking a bath to see if new ideas or potential solutions pop into your mind unexpectedly as your subconscious continues to work on the problem without your attention.</p>



<p>Example: <em>“For three days, I’ve been trying to solve this problem at work, but the solution only came to me when I was strolling in the woods and not even thinking about it.”</em></p>



<p>Example from mathematician Henri Poincaré: <em>“The incidents of the travel made me forget my mathematical work. Having reached Coutances, we entered an omnibus to go someplace or other. At the moment when I put my foot on the step, the idea came to me, without anything in my former thoughts seeming to have paved the way for it, that the transformations I had used to define the Fuchsian functions were identical with those of non-Euclidean geometry.”</em></p>



<p>10. <strong>Reexamining</strong> – write down all the assumptions you’ve been making about the problem or about what a solution should look like (yes – make an actual list). Then start challenging them one by one to see if they are actually needed or whether some may be unnecessary or mistaken.</p>



<p>Psychology Example: <em>“We were assuming in our lab experiments that when people get angry they have some underlying reason behind it, but there may be some anger that is better modeled as a chemical fluctuation that is only loosely related to what happens in the lab, such as when people are quick to anger because they are hungry.”</em></p>



<p>Math Example: <em>“I need to construct a function that has this strange property, and so far I’ve assumed that the function must be smooth, but if it doesn’t actually need to be then perhaps I can construct just such a function out of simple linear pieces that are glued together.”</em></p>



<p>11.<strong> Reframing</strong> – try to see the problem differently. For instance, by flipping the default, analyzing the inverse of the problem instead, thinking about how you would achieve the opposite of what you want, or shifting to an opposing perspective.</p>



<p>Startup Example: <em>“If we were building this company over again completely from scratch, what would we do differently in the design of our product, and can we pivot the product in that direction right now?”</em></p>



<p>Life Example: <em>“Should move to New York to take a job that pays $20,000 more per year? Well, if I already lived in New York, the decision to stay there rather than taking a $20,000 pay cut to move here would be an easy one. …</em></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/">https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.spencergreenberg.com/2017/06/1514/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24249449</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 04:10:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Six Tools for Clearer Communication]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24248902">thread link</a>) | @AlexDReeve
<br/>
August 22, 2020 | https://reeve.blog/blog/five-tools-for-clearer-communication/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://reeve.blog/blog/five-tools-for-clearer-communication/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><main id="genesis-content"><article itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div itemprop="text">
<p>We live in a noisy world.</p>



<p>To cut through this noise and create clarity for those around us, we all need to communicate effectively every day. Our work doesn’t speak for itself; we need to collaborate, inspire, and build relationships. To do this, we need to be able to communicate clearly.</p>



<p>As a shy child and introverted adult, externalizing my perspective never came naturally to me. It still doesn’t. In high school, I had the dubious honor of being cast in the only non-speaking role in drama class. Despite this, today, I spend the majority of my day, every day, communicating with people. In some ways, my day job&nbsp;<em>is</em>&nbsp;communication.</p>



<p>Communication is a learned skill. I’m certainly no Obama, but over time, I’ve collected a set of tools that have helped me communicate more effectively.</p>



<h3>Contents</h3>



<ol><li><a href="#rule-of-three">Rule of Three</a></li><li><a href="#answer-explain-example">Answer, Explain, Example</a></li><li><a href="#structure-say-summarize">Structure, Say, Summarize</a></li><li><a href="#feelings-last">Feelings Last Longer Than Words</a></li><li><a href="#pause-context">Pause and Give Context</a></li><li><a href="#so-what">“So What” Is Your One Key Takeaway</a></li></ol>



<h3 id="rule-of-three">Rule of Three</h3>



<p>Three is a magic number in communication. From stories, like The Three Musketeers, Three Blind Mice, and Three Little Pigs, to colloquialisms like “blood, sweat, and tears,” <em>three</em> is everywhere. There’s even a Latin phrase, omne trium perfectum, or <em>everything that comes in threes is perfect</em>.</p>



<p>Why is this? Humans beings seek both patterns and simplicity. We’re pattern-recognition machines, always looking for signals among the noise. Simultaneously, we have limited working memory. We can’t remember a list of fifteen things or even a list of five. But we can remember three, which is the minimum number of objects needed to make a pattern. Three is concise, persuasive, and memorable.</p>



<p>When you say, “there are three reasons we should do this,” people pay attention. They know that three is easy to digest and remember. And you, the speaker, are forced to structure your argument succinctly and compellingly. When you put seven bullet-points in a document or slide, people’s eyes glaze over. When you put a concise list of three, they digest it. Within reason, in verbal or written communication, distill what you have to say down to three.</p>



<h3 id="answer-explain-example">Answer, Explain, Example</h3>



<p>I heard this from a former LinkedIn executive. The premise is simple but powerful. When answering a question, give the answer, then elaborate, then provide an example. That’s it.</p>



<p>By answering the question immediately, you’re getting to the point and giving the person who asked a concise answer. Then you’re supporting it with your rationale. Finally, you’re backing it up with a real example.</p>



<h3 id="structure-say-summarize">Structure, Say, Summarize</h3>



<p>“Structure, Say, Summarize” is a tool I use when communicating something nuanced. The basis is this: First, structure how you’re going to make the statement. Second, make the statement. Third, summarize your position and the “<a href="#so-what">so what</a>.”</p>



<ul><li>Structure: It’s a risk, but there are three reasons we should do this.</li><li>Say: The first reason is X, the second is Y, the third reason is Z.</li><li>Summarize: I know nothing is guaranteed. But, given these reasons, we’re missing an opportunity to grow by not doing this.</li></ul>



<p>This structure is akin to a Dale Carnegie quote: “Tell the audience what you’re going to say, say it; then tell them what you’ve said.”</p>



<p>Verbal communication is messy, and it’s difficult for people to follow spoken paragraphs. Even when you don’t have a tidy list of three, starting with “there are a few reasons,” making stating a few points, then summarizing your view is a powerful way to communicate more clearly.</p>



<p>But don’t use this all the time, or you’ll seem like a robot.</p>



<h3 id="feelings-last">Feelings Last Longer Than Words</h3>



<p>People will often forget what you said, but they’ll never forget how you made them feel. You might have made a logically sound argument, but if the recipient didn’t feel enthused, inspired, or understood, it probably won’t stick.</p>



<p>Feelings are why the world’s most iconic brands are so effective. We don’t remember every detail, every line of copy, or every number. But they make us feel a certain way, and feelings are sticky.</p>



<p>If you want to inspire action or lead a team, logic is important, but so is ensuring people are inspired when they walk away from an interaction. People won’t remember everything you said, but they’ll remember how you made them feel.</p>



<h3 id="pause-context">Pause and Give Context</h3>



<p>Never assume that everyone has the same context that you do. There’s a magical and straightforward sequence of words for this: “Let me give some context to make sure we’re on the same page.”</p>



<p>In any given conversation, everyone has a perspective formulated from a different set of inputs. The more closely aligned you can get these inputs, the more effective your communication will be. Shared context helps avoid “talking past each other” situations.</p>



<p>One of the tenets of effective communication is <em>over-communication</em>. Most people associate this with being annoying or spam. In my experience, that isn’t true. Over-communication is about never assuming that people have the same context that you do.</p>



<h3 id="so-what">“So What” Is Your One Key Takeaway</h3>



<p>For every piece of communication that you create, find the “so what.” Whether a presentation, document, or slide,&nbsp;if someone asked, “so what?”, what would you say? </p>



<p>Whatever the answer to that question is, make sure it comes across clearly. The answer to “so what?” usually involves articulates the implication for the audience.</p>



<p>An easily applicable tip here is to title your slides or headers with the “so what” for that particular slide or section. Hone in on the most important takeaway and the implication for the audience — why should they care?</p>

			</div></article></main></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://reeve.blog/blog/five-tools-for-clearer-communication/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24248902</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 01:53:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
