<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 2]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 2. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 12:24:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 12:24:21 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[New Vimproved ModalEdit 2.0 for VS Code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129743">thread link</a>) | @johtela
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><img src="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/images/pooh.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="403">
Providing full Vim emulation was not originally a goal of ModalEdit. The idea of
the extension is to provide an engine that allows the user to <a href="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/README.html#configuration">map any key
combination to any command provided by VS Code</a>.
However, most users equate modal editing with Vim and are familiar with its
default keybindings. Vim users really love the powerful key sequences that
combine editing operations with cursor motions or text ranges.</p>
<p>ModalEdit has also evolved by taking inspiration from Vim. Many capabilities
were added with the motive to enable some Vim feature that was previously not
possible to implement. With version 2.0 ModalEdit's functionality is now
extensive enough to build a semi-complete Vim emulation. So, here we go...</p>
<p>Adding Vim keybindings as optional presets serves two purposes: it lowers the
barrier to entry for Vim users who don't want to spend the time defining
bindings from ground up. Secondly, Vim presets serve as an example to show
how you can build sophisticated command sequences using the machinery provided
by ModalEdit.</p>
<p><img src="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/images/import-preset.png" alt="importing presets" width="553" height="94">
If you are not interested on how the Vim keybindings are implemented and just
want to use them, you can skip this discussion. Just import the presets by
pressing <key>Ctrl</key>+<key>Shift</key>+<key>P</key> and running command
<strong>ModalEdit: Import preset keybindings</strong>. You will be presented a choice to
import either Vim bindings or any presets that you have created yourself. If
you are planning to customize the bindings, or create Vim-style commands from
scratch, this document gives you pointers how to go about with that.</p>
<h2 id="game-plan">Game Plan</h2>
<p>We start with basic motion commands which are mostly straightforward to
implement. Motions have two modes of operation: normal mode (moving cursor), and
visual mode (extending selection). We make sure all motions work correctly in
both modes. This allows us to reuse these keybindings when implementing more
advanced operations. Our goal is to avoid repetition by building complex
sequences from primitive commands.</p>
<p>In Vim, there are multiple key sequences for a same operation. For example,
you can convert a paragraph upper case by typing
<key>g</key><key>U</key><key>i</key><key>p</key>. You can perform the same
operation using visual mode by typing <key>v</key><key>i</key><key>p</key><key>U</key>.
The trick we use is to convert key sequences that operate on character, word,
line, paragraph, etc. to analagous key sequences that use visual mode. We can
implement all the editing commands just to work on active selection and reuse
these commands with the other key combinations. Consequently, command definition
becomes a string mapping problem. Since we can use JavaScript to expressions to
do string manipulation, these mappings are easy to formulate.</p>
<p><img src="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/images/vim-uppercase.gif" alt=""></p>
<p>Many ways to skin a cat...</p>
<h2 id="motions-in-normal-mode">Motions in Normal Mode</h2>
<p>The list of available cursor motion commands is shown below.</p>
<div>
<table><thead>
<tr>
<th>Keys</th>
<th>Cursor Motion</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><code>Enter</code></td>
<td>Beginning of next line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>Space</code></td>
<td>Next character on right</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>h</code></td>
<td>Left</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>j</code></td>
<td>Down</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>k</code></td>
<td>Up</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>l</code></td>
<td>Right</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>0</code></td>
<td>First character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>$</code></td>
<td>Last character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>^</code></td>
<td>First non-blank character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>g_</code></td>
<td>Last non-blank character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gg</code></td>
<td>First charater in file</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>G</code></td>
<td>Last character in file</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>w</code></td>
<td>Beginning of next word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>e</code></td>
<td>End of next word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>b</code></td>
<td>Beginning of previous word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>W</code></td>
<td>Beginning of next alphanumeric word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>B</code></td>
<td>Beginning of previous alphanumeric word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>H</code></td>
<td>Top of the screen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>M</code></td>
<td>Middle of the screen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>L</code></td>
<td>Bottom of the screen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>%</code></td>
<td>Matching bracket</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div><p>Now, lets implement all the keybindings listed above.</p>

<pre><code>{
    <span>"keybindings"</span>: {
</code></pre>
<p>Cursor can be advanced in a file with with enter and space. These are not
technically motion commands but included for compatibility.</p>

<pre><code>        "\n": [
            "cursorDown",
            {
                "command": "cursorMove",
                "args": {
                    "to": "wrappedLineFirstNonWhitespaceCharacter"
                }
            }
        ],
        " ": "cursorRight",
</code></pre>
<p>Move cursor up/down/left/right.</p>

<pre><code>        "h": "cursorLeft",
        "j": "cursorDown",
        "k": "cursorUp",
        "l": "cursorRight",
</code></pre>
<p>Move to first/last character on line. These work also in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>        "0": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineStart', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "$": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineEnd', select: __selecting }"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>Move to first/last non-blank character on line. Also these ones use the
<code>__selecting</code> flag to check whether we are in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>        "^": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineFirstNonWhitespaceCharacter', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "g": {
            "_": {
                "command": "cursorMove",
                "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineLastNonWhitespaceCharacter', select: __selecting }"
            },
</code></pre>
<p>Moving to the beginning of file is defined as a conditional command to make
it work in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>            "g": {
                "condition": "__selecting",
                "true": "cursorTopSelect",
                "false": "cursorTop"
            },
</code></pre>
<h2 id="other-commands-starting-with-key-g-key">Other Commands Starting with <key>g</key></h2>
<p>Commands starting with <key>g</key> key are bit inconsistent in Vim. Some of
them are basic motion commands, such as <key>g</key><key>_</key> and
<key>g</key><key>g</key>, some are editing commands like <key>g</key><key>J</key>
and <key>g</key><key>U</key>, and some switch between tabs 🤷‍♂️. Since we have to
define all bindings with the same prefix in same place, we take a detour and add
these commands before continuing with rest of the motion commands.</p>
<div>
<table><thead>
<tr>
<th>Keys</th>
<th>Command</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><code>gJ</code></td>
<td>Join lines without space in between</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gu</code>&lt;<em>motion</em>&gt;</td>
<td>Convert text specified by &lt;<em>motion</em>&gt; to lowercase</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gU</code>&lt;<em>motion</em>&gt;</td>
<td>Convert text specified by &lt;<em>motion</em>&gt; to uppercase</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gt</code></td>
<td>Go to next tab</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gT</code></td>
<td>Go to previous tab</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div><p>Joining lines without space is done by deleting a character after the join
command.</p>

<pre><code>            "J": [
                "editor.action.joinLines",
                "deleteRight"
            ],
</code></pre>
<p>The lower/uppercase transition works with any motion, but since we have not
defined all of them yet, we explain the command structure
<a href="#editing-with-motions">later in the document</a>.
The structure we use here is exactly the same as with <key>d</key> command, for
example.</p>

<pre><code>            "u,U": {
                "id": 1,
                "help": "Change case with motion",
                "u,U": {
                    "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                    "args": "{ keys: __cmd.slice(0, -3) + 'V' + __rcmd[0] }"
                },
                "h,j,k,l,w,e,b,W,B,%": {
                    "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                    "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __cmd.slice(0, -3) + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[1] }"
                },
                "^,$,0,G,H,M,L": {
                    "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                    "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[1] }"
                },
                "g": {
                    "g,_": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                },
                "f,t,F,T": {
                    "help": "Do until _",
                    " -~": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                },
                "a,i": {
                    "help": "Do around/inside _",
                    "w,p,b,B,t, -/,:-@,[-`,{-~": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                },
                "`,'": {
                    "help": "Do until mark _",
                    "a-z": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                }
            },
</code></pre>
<p><key>g</key><key>t</key> and <key>g</key><key>T</key> switch to next/previous
tab.</p>

<pre><code>            "t": "workbench.action.nextEditor",
            "T": "workbench.action.previousEditor"
        },
</code></pre>
<h2 id="rest-of-the-motion-commands">Rest of the Motion Commands</h2>
<p>Now we can complete the list of basic motion commands. This one movest the
cursor at the end of the file and selects the range, if visual mode is on.</p>

<pre><code>        "G": {
            "condition": "__selecting",
            "true": "cursorBottomSelect",
            "false": "cursorBottom"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>The logic of separating words is bit different in VS Code and Vim, so we will
not try to imitate Vim behavior here. These keys are mapped to the most similar
motion available. The <key>W</key> and <key>B</key> commands skip separator
characters, and move to the start of the next/previous alphanumeric word.</p>

<pre><code>        "w": "cursorWordStartRight",
        "e": "cursorWordEndRight",
        "b": "cursorWordStartLeft",
        "W": {
            "command": "cursorWordStartRight",
            "repeat": "__char.match(/\\W/)"
        },
        "B": {
            "command": "cursorWordStartLeft",
            "repeat": "__char.match(/\\W/)"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>Moving cursor to the top, middle, and bottom of the screen is mapped to
<key>H</key> (high), <key>M</key> (middle), and <key>L</key> (low) keys. These
mappings also work in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>        "H": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'viewPortTop', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "M": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'viewPortCenter', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "L": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'viewPortBottom', select: __selecting }"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>Move to matching bracket command is somewhat challenging to implement
consistently in VS Code. This is due to the problem that there are no commands
that do exactly what Vim's motions do. In normal mode we call the
<code>jumpToBracket</code> command which works if the cursor is on top of a bracket, but
does not allow for the selection to be extended. In visual mode we use the
<code>smartSelect.expand</code> command instead to extend the selection to whatever
syntactic scope is above the current selection. In many cases, it is more useful
motion than jumping to a matching bracket, but using it means that we are
diverging from Vim's …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html">https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129743</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: NeuralCam Live – Using ML to Turn iPhones into Smart Webcams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129714">thread link</a>) | @soonpls
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://neural.cam/news/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://neural.cam/news/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <div id="main">
    <div>
      <div>
        <div role="article">

          <div>
            

<p>Hey everyone, <br>

Today is a big day for NeuralCam. We have three announcements to make: some news about NeuralCam as a company, a major update for our NightMode app and a brand new <strong>Smart Camera app.</strong>
</p><br>
<h3>
NeuralCam - building Smart Camera Apps
</h3>
<div><p>Let’s start by talking a bit about cameras and AI. </p><p>

At NeuralCam, we think that one of the biggest leaps in technology over the past years has been the advances Deep Learning brought in the area of Computer Vision. It gives computers the ability to see - to understand patterns, images and video similarly to how people do.
 </p></div>



<p>Ultimately, we think this technology will give birth to a new category of cameras - <b>Smart Cameras</b> - that will have a profound impact on every activity that involves capturing and processing images.
</p>

<p>We see this change similar to the transformation from classic cellular phones to the modern smartphone we witnessed 10 years ago. We believe that martphones themselves seem to be the ideal smart camera platform: they have high quality cameras and enough processing power to run modern AI algorithms on-device.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartcameras.png">
</p>

<p>So, we can all have our own personal smart cameras in our pockets, all that’s needed is the right ML software. This ML software is what we call Smart Camera Apps, and these are the type of apps we’re building at NeuralCam.
</p>

<p>Whenever we see a visual task we might say “there’s a Smart Cam App for that”. We’ve been doing a lot of research and prototyping and we’re more and more confident that smart camera apps will play a key role in every industry, from Education through Healthcare to Entertainment, and we can’t wait to contribute something in each of these areas.

</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartapps.png">
</p>

<p>However, the first category that is naturally most likely to change is almost analogous to the camera itself: photography and videography. Thus, this is what we’ve decided to start with, building AI powered Photo &amp; Video apps over the next few years. 
</p>

<p>Our first smart photo app we’ve launched is the NeuralCam NightMode app, which brought Night Mode to all iPhones and all iPhone camera lenses. But, NeuralCam is more than the Night Mode app. We think of NeuralCam as a range of smart camera apps in different categories for various use cases. 
</p>



<p>So, one of the things we did is update our brand to reflect this change. This is the first thing we’d like to show you today, a fresh NeuralCam: 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/nclogo.png"></p>

<p>And this is the new NeuralCam NightMode:</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/NightModeLogo.png">
<br>
</p>
<p>Ok, so that’s the story of NeuralCam - the company. The second thing we want to show you is an update to our NightMode app. 

</p>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">NeuralCam NightMode</h3>

<p>We <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/neuralcam" target="_blank">launched</a> our first smart camera app, NeuralCam NightMode, about a year ago, last August. It brought NightMode to the iPhone and the response from the users and critics <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/08/30/iphone-camera-app-for-night-shots/" target="_blank">was amazing.</a>
</p>

<p>We’ve been <a href="https://petapixel.com/2019/08/28/neuralcam-night-photo-app-brings-ai-powered-low-light-mode-to-iphones/" target="_blank">covered</a> <a href="https://bgr.com/2019/10/25/iphone-11-pro-camera-review-features-with-night-mode-app/" target="_blank">in many</a> <a href="https://bgr.com/2019/08/30/iphone-11-release-date-soon-specs-camera-night-mode/" target="_blank">major</a> <a href="https://thenextweb.com/apple/2019/08/29/this-app-uses-ai-to-add-a-pixel-style-night-photography-mode-to-your-iphone/" target="_blank">press</a> <a href="https://www.slashgear.com/neuralcam-iphone-app-uses-ai-to-capture-bright-images-at-night-26588672/" target="_blank">publications</a>, got lots of love letters from users, and been recognized as the best NightMode app out there. 
</p>
<p>While Apple has launched a built-in night mode on the iPhone 11 in the meantime, NeuralCam continues to be the NightMode solution for devices or iPhone cameras without a native NightMode - like the newly launched iPhone SE or even the UltraWide &amp; Selfie cameras on the iPhone 11 Pro. </p>
<p>Since its launch, people have used NeuralCam NightMode to take more than 10M low light photos. 
</p>

<div><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/10M.png"></p></div>

<p>Now, with a major update, we have made our NightMode app even better: we've made some major improvements to our algorithm so that it supports higher resolutions on older devices too; we’ve updated the UI to be in-line with the new NeuralCam brand and we’ve officially added iPad support.</p><p>This is how the update NeuralCam NightMode app looks like on an iPad:</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/nmupdate.png">
<br>
</p>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">NeuralCam Live</h3>

<p>The popularity of video calls has exploded lately. In the current global context, most of us use video calls a lot for both getting our job done or to keep in touch with loved ones. For something used as often, we really need to have the best possible tools. 

</p>

<p>Looking at the things out there, we realized that there’s a weak link in all this video call experience, and it’s the webcams. </p><p>We’ve got laptop webcams (quite bad), dedicated webcams (a bit better) or apps that let you use your iPhone as a webcam (best quality). However, these products really only differ from one another in the resolution of the video they provide. 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/webcams.png">
<br>
</p>

<p> The problem with webcams is that they’re mostly the same as they were 10 years ago, they do the same thing only slightly better. In the meantime, this cool new technology called Deep Learning came along which could add a whole new dimension to webcams and possibly change the whole video call experience - but nobody uses it. 

</p>

<p>
It turns out that one of the main reasons for Deep Learning not being used with webcams is that no webcam has the processing power required to run the required ML algorithms. Except there is one device which, when converted to a webcam, could do all this: the iPhone in our pocket.
</p>

<p>It’s got one of the best cameras in the smartphone industry and with its fast processors and dedicated machine learning hardware, it is capable of running even video processing machine learning algorithms in real-time. It just needs the right SmartCam App software to do all this. 
  </p><p>We've built this software - we call it NeuralCam Live and it turns the iPhone into the <strong>world’s smartest webcam.</strong>
  </p>
<div><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/LiveLogo.png"></p></div>







<p>
	Ok, so how are we going to do that?
</p>
<br>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">Technology</h3>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/tech.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>First, we need the software that connects the iPhone to the laptop and makes it appear just like a regular webcam when connected through a USB cable. 
</p>

<p>This software has two modules: the first one is an iOS app that provides the webcam functionality, while the second one is a plugin that’s installed on the laptop to make the iOS app appear as a webcam. Once you install both of these components, all you have to do is select the NeuralCam Live Camera in Zoom, Google Meet or your video call platform of choice.
</p>

<p>So, that was quite easy, now comes the fun part. </p><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/engine.png">
<br>
</p>

<p> The second component we need is the machine learning software to make our smart webcam... well, smart. We call it the <b>LiveEngine</b> </p>

<p>Machine learning, as a generic technology, can help us in two ways when it comes to webcams: we can use it to recognize things in the video feed or generate new video content, improved in some way. </p><p>We’ve developed multiple machine learning modules, some proprietary, some built on top of existing CoreML models and we’ve grouped them in three different machine learning frameworks that cover both video generation and analysis: the Style Framework, the Enhance Framework and the Gesture Framework. Let’s take a quick look at each of these. 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_style.png">
<br>
</p>


<p>The <b>Style Framework</b> is a deep learning-based machine learning framework that edits video similarly to a professional colorist. 
</p>
<p>Its Neural Nets were trained on images edited by hand by professionals in a range of different editing styles. The results are quite amazing, generating pro-looking videosf, very close in terms of style to the professionally edited frames it was trained on and it does all this in real-time at 30fps locally, on the user’s iPhone.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_enhance.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>The <b>Enhance Framework</b> contains our set of machine learning models that can enhance a video in a bunch of different ways. </p>

<p>Our real-time video denoising and brightening models in this category achieve levels of quality and performance that are much better than traditional algorithms and make features such as video low light enhancement or face smoothing possible.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_recognition.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>The <b>Recognition Framework</b> is the part of our LiveEngine that is meant to make our smart camera apps understand what they “see”. </p>

<p>It uses a combination of machine learning models provided by the iPhone SDK and adds a number of proprietary elements to detect faces, user gestures or other different patterns in the live video feed. In the app, we can use this type of technology to blur unwanted gestures or guide you to set up an ideal environment for a call.
</p>

<p>Together, all these elements form what we call the LiveEngine - the ever-evolving software module that makes NeuralCam Live a smart webcam.
</p>

<h3>Features</h3>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/NCFeats.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>Now, let’s take a look at the actual product. </p>
<p>The iPhone app exposes all of the functionality of the smart iPhone webcam in a simple layout, most of the features can be accessed by just tapping a button on the screen. It also shows a nice preview of the current video feed. 
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartwebcam.png">
<br>
</p>


<p>So, using all this technology, what more can a smart webcam do compared to a traditional webcam? 
</p>

<p>In terms of the outcome they provide to the user, we’ve realized that most of the AI features we’ve built fit nicely in two categories: making you look better and helping you avoid embarrassing mistakes.
</p>

<p>Let’s take a look at these features one-by-one: 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/fiq.png">
<br>
</p>

<h4>Face &amp; Image Quality Meter
</h4>



<p>The Face &amp; Image Quality Meter detects the amount of face lighting, type of face position and background and displays an overall Face Image Quality score. 
</p>

<p>It helps you set up an optimal video-call environment and helps you avoid making typical mistakes, such as sitting with your back towards a bright window or in an unfavorable low angle.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/styles.png">
  <br>
  </p>

<h4>Pro Video Styling</h4>

<p>
  
  Using the Style Framework, NeuralCam Live edits the video feed like a professional colorist would, in a range of different styles. The end-result is a more impactful look, allowing you to choose the style that best fits your mood, the type of call or the environment you're in.

</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/lowlight.png">
  <br>
  </p>

<h4>
  
  Low-light Mode
</h4>

<p>It wouldn't be a NeuralCam product without a Night Mode, right? </p>
<p>NeuralCam Live’s Low Light Mode brightens up your video with a similar (though a lot more lightweight) technique used in our Night Mode photo app. It allows you to look good in video calls even in low light settings, a gentle light from your monitor is usually enough to provide a nice video feed. 
</p>

<p>
  
  And just in case you need to light up things even more, you can use the face-following Ring Light …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://neural.cam/news/">https://neural.cam/news/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://neural.cam/news/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129714</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Amazon’s business model meets Sweden’s labor unions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129279">thread link</a>) | @ptr
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
							
							
							

							
							<div id="amazon-polly-audio-table">
				<p>Press play to listen to this article</p>
				
		</div><p>It's Sweden's storied worker protections and climate-conscious citizens welcoming Amazon's ruthless drive for low prices. What could go wrong?</p>
<p>Stockholm is preparing for a tug-of-war with one of the world’s most powerful companies — which just announced its entry into the Swedish market — and hopes that its arrival will mean the country of 10 million will be able to change Amazon, instead of being changed by it.</p>
<p>Amazon's plans — dubbed “<a href="https://www.ehandel.se/har-ar-amazon-se-det-blir-en-helsvensk-lansering" target="_blank">Project Dancing Queen</a>,” after the hit song by Swedish pop group Abba — don't have a lot of detail, but analysts believe its Swedish store will go live in the fall, in time for November’s Black Friday online shopping bonanza.</p>
<p>“Amazon has been supporting Swedish customers and selling partners across our different European stores for many years, but the next step is to bring a full retail offering to Sweden and we are making those plans now,” said Alex Ootes, Amazon’s vice president for EU expansion, in a statement.</p>
<p>Amazon’s turbo-capitalism corporate culture goes against the grain of Sweden and the rest of the Nordic countries, which pride themselves in their strong labor unions and sustainability.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Swedish e-commerce is still like regular retail without shopping malls” <em>— Jonas Arnberg, CEO of market-research firm HUI</em></p></blockquote>
<p>But the country also has an affluent, internet-savvy market ripe for Alexa, Kindles, Prime and the thousands of items on Amazon's online store, the company believes. Around 68 percent of Swedes shopped online in 2018, and they spent an average of €200 per online transaction. In total, the Nordic countries spent over €22 billion online in 2018, according to a <a href="https://www.postnord.fi/siteassets/raportit/verkkokauppa-pohjoismaissa/ecommerce-in-the-nordics-2019.pdf" target="_blank">study</a> by PostNord, the country’s postal service.</p>
<p>There's not a lot of competition in online marketplaces, and nobody can match Amazon’s massive cornucopia of goods.</p>
<p>“Swedish e-commerce is still like regular retail without shopping malls,” said Jonas Arnberg, the CEO of HUI, a market research company.</p>
<p>Amazon will change that, and force local players to adopt e-commerce faster than they would have otherwise.</p>
<p>“It’s a perfect storm in e-commerce now. The COVID-19 impact took us two to three years forward in digitalization. With Amazon’s entry it is going to go even further,” said Kristoffer Väliharju, the CEO of CDON, a Nordic online marketplace. Väliharju is optimistic about CDON’s chances of taking on the tech giant, but said companies without a strong e-commerce game will likely take a big hit.</p>
<p>Initially, Swedish and Nordic clients will be mainly served from German warehouses — known as fulfillment centers in Amazon-speak — with trucks driving up to Sweden through Denmark, and a fulfillment center operated by local partner Kuehne + Nagel in the Swedish town of Eskilstuna, near Stockholm.</p>
<p>Analysts believe local warehouses are inevitable if Amazon is to offer one of its most unique selling points: quick delivery.</p>
<h3>When in Stockholm</h3>
<p>Establishing a local operation will be a major challenge for the company. American Amazon’s <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/08/22/how-amazon-is-fighting-back-against-workers-efforts-to-unionize.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">anti-union stance</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/16/technology/inside-amazon-wrestling-big-ideas-in-a-bruising-workplace.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">working culture</a> is the antithesis of pro-union Sweden. (Swedish Prime Minister Stefan Löfven's political career is rooted in union activism dating from his time as a welder.)</p>
<p>The Swedish labor market is regulated by collective agreements between companies and unions, giving workers plenty of power over corporate decisions. Approximately 70 percent of Swedish workers belong to a union.</p>
<p>“If Amazon wants to succeed in Sweden, they need to work very closely with unions,” said Arne Andersson, an e-commerce expert at PostNord.</p>
<p>Amazon has not yet contacted Handels, the union representing warehouse workers, its political coordinator Emelie Wärn told POLITICO.</p>
<div id="attachment_1432138"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1432138" src="https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-714x476.jpg" alt="" width="714" height="476" srcset="https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-714x476.jpg 714w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-300x200.jpg 300w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-768x512.jpg 768w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1160x773.jpg 1160w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-380x253.jpg 380w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-171x114.jpg 171w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-90x60.jpg 90w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-104x69.jpg 104w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-200x133.jpg 200w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-390x260.jpg 390w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-54x36.jpg 54w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1080x720.jpg 1080w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-333x222.jpg 333w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1120x746.jpg 1120w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-600x400.jpg 600w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px"></p><p id="caption-attachment-1432138">Sweden's warehouse-workers union, Handels, has successfully negotiated with fashion chain Uniqlo in the past | Sean Gallup/Getty Images</p></div>
<p>“Amazon is welcome to Sweden, but they have to sign a collective agreement. We will work very hard to get them to do that,” Wärn said.</p>
<p>“The fact that international companies takes interest in the Swedish market place is a positive thing. As an employer in Sweden you are obliged to follow Swedish labor legislation, which includes regulations regarding collective bargaining,” said Eva Nordmark, Sweden’s minister of employment, adding that approximately 90 percent of the employees in Sweden are covered by collective bargaining agreements.</p>
<p>The minimum wage for a card-carrying Swedish warehouse worker is 142.50 Swedish krona (€13.85) per hour before tax, according to Handels. In contrast, Amazon’s Polish warehouse workers who serve the German market <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/coronavirus-amazon-employees-rage/">earn</a> 20 zlotys (around €4.50). Amazon said its workers in Germany earn a base pay of €11.10 an hour.</p>
<p>But the union is confident it will be able to negotiate with the tech goliath. Handels has done similar deals with Japanese fashion chain Uniqlo, Wärn said as an example.</p>
<p>But Uniqlo is not Amazon, and Handels' confidence might be misplaced, according to Markus Varsikko, a retail consultant at Dash Retail, which helps businesses use Amazon's marketplace.</p>
<p>“Amazon is a realist. If they can operate in Germany, they can operate in Sweden. It is an American company with American culture and thinking, and it is far from what we are used to here,” Varsikko said, arguing that Sweden's companies and workers might have to adapt — not the tech giant.</p>
<h3>Handels and Greta</h3>
<p>Amazon might also have to polish its sustainability credentials to appease Swedish consumers.</p>
<p>“What makes the Swedish market unique is that there is a great focus on companies to do good, be transparent and sustainable. For many Swedes, this is even more important than a wide range and low price,” said Niclas Eriksson, the CEO of electronics retailer Elgiganten. And thanks to local activist Greta Thunberg, consumers are <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/cancel-your-amazon-prime-subscription-save-the-planet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">becoming increasingly aware</a> of the carbon footprint of services like next-day delivery.</p>
<blockquote><p>European consumer groups have slammed Amazon for selling dangerous and illegal products such as toxic toys and exploding power banks on its platform.</p></blockquote>
<p>Plus Amazon's insistence on lower prices might not be its winning ticket.</p>
<p>The foray into the Swedish market by another e-commerce company, Wish, may serve as a cautionary tale. The American online marketplace, which mostly sells cheap items from China, tried and failed to take over the market a few years ago. The company first wooed consumers with dirt-cheap products such as electronics and clothes, only for Swedes to be disappointed by the quality of the products and frustrated by not being able to return products to sellers.</p>
<p>"[Wish] was cheap, it was a great marketplace, but it was also crap,” said PostNord’s Andersson. Wish did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>Amazon's had troubles with quality control too. European consumer groups have <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/online-marketplaces-rife-with-unsafe-and-illegal-items-study-shows/">slammed</a> the company for selling dangerous and illegal products such as toxic toys and exploding power banks on its platform. The European Commission also put pressure on online platforms to control scammers and price gouging during the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>CDON’s Väliharju said Swedish customers are very quality-conscious, and aware of their rights as consumers. Consumer groups and <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/how-big-brands-chanel-canon-louis-vuitton-nike-are-taking-on-big-tech-silicon-valley-at-last/">brands</a> have criticized Amazon and others for not holding sufficient information about their sellers, especially for products that come from outside the European Union that could be dangerous or counterfeit.</p>
<p>“Amazon absolutely could be well met by Swedish consumers in the beginning,” said Arnberg, the CEO of HUI, citing Amazon’s promise of low prices, a big range of products and fast delivery.</p>
<p>“But in the long run they will have to adjust to Sweden."</p>
<p><em>This article has been updated to include Amazon's partnership with a warehouse provider in Sweden, and Amazon workers' wages in Germany.</em></p>
<p><em>This article is part of </em><span>POLITICO</span><em>’s premium Tech policy coverage: Pro Technology. Our expert journalism and suite of policy intelligence tools allow you to seamlessly search, track and understand the developments and stakeholders shaping EU Tech policy and driving decisions impacting your industry. Email <a href="mailto:pro@politico.eu" target="_blank">pro@politico.eu</a> with the code ‘TECH’ for a complimentary trial.</em></p>

							
							
							<!--/.story-supplement-->

						</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129279</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 06:58:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: I made a minimalist spaced repetition tool]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129037">thread link</a>) | @mvind
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | http://memordo.com/launch | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://memordo.com/launch">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-container">
                
<div data-spy="scroll" data-target="#navbar-front">
    <!-- MAIN HERO -->
    


    <!-- social proof  -->
    <div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <p> 
                        Join more than 200+ registered users already using <strong>memordo</strong> 
                    </p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <!-- section 1 -->
    <div id="features">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    
                    <p> Create the perfect memory cards for your studying. 
                        Use the original Anki card types with full support for exactly the content you need. 
                    </p>
                    <p><span> 
                        <span><i></i></span> Images
                        <span><i></i></span> Latex
                        <span><i></i></span> Code
                        <span><i></i></span> Syntax Highlighting
                        <span><i></i></span> Tags 
                        <span><i></i></span> Cloze Deletions
                    </span>

                </p></div>

                <div>
                    <p><img id="card-hero" src="https://memordo-assets.ams3.digitaloceanspaces.com/front-page-assets/card-hero.png">
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>


     <!-- section 2 -->
     <div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><img id="sec2-hero" src="https://memordo-assets.ams3.digitaloceanspaces.com/front-page-assets/card_studied_2.png">
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    
                    <p> 
                        All your memory cards and decks are stored in the cloud. 
                        Study whenever and on whatever you prefer without any worries. 
                    </p>
                </div>


            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <!-- section 3 pricing  -->
    <div id="pricing">
        <div>
            <div id="price-header">
                
                <div>
                    
                    <p> 
                        You can <strong>always</strong> export your memory cards.
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            
            <div>
                <p><span>We don't sell your info. We don't do ads. </span>
                </p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>


</div>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://memordo.com/launch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129037</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 06:12:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Chris Hedges: America’s Death March]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128745">thread link</a>) | @cbHXBY1D
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
		Regardless of the outcome, the election will not stop the rise of hypernationalism, crisis cults and other signs of an empire's terminal decline. 	</p><div>
		
<p><strong>By Chris Hedges </strong>/ Original to Scheerpost</p>



<p>The terminal decline of the United States will not be solved by elections. The political rot and depravity will continue to eat away at the soul of the nation, spawning what anthropologists call crisis cults — movements led by demagogues that prey on an unbearable psychological and financial distress. These crisis cults, already well established among followers of the Christian Right and Donald Trump, peddle magical thinking and an infantilism that promises — in exchange for all autonomy — prosperity, a return to a mythical past, order and security. The dark yearnings among the white working class for vengeance and moral renewal through violence, the unchecked greed and corruption of the corporate oligarchs and billionaires who manage our failed democracy, which has already instituted wholesale government surveillance and revoked most civil liberties, are part of the twisted pathologies that infect all civilizations sputtering towards oblivion. I witnessed the deaths of other nations during the collapse of the communist regimes in Eastern Europe and later in the former Yugoslavia. I have smelled this stench before.</p>



<p>The removal of Trump from office will only exacerbate the lust for racist violence he incites and the intoxicating elixir of white nationalism. The ruling elites, who first built a mafia economy and then built a mafia state, will continue under Biden, as they did under Trump, Barack Obama, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton and Ronald Reagan, to wantonly pillage and loot. The militarized police will not stop their lethal rampages in poor neighborhoods. The endless wars will not end. The bloated military budget will not be reduced. The world’s largest prison population will remain a stain upon the country. The manufacturing jobs shipped overseas will not return and the social inequality will grow. The for-profit health care system will gouge the public and price millions more out of the health care system. The language of hate and bigotry will be normalized as the primary form of communication. Internal enemies, including Muslims, immigrants and dissidents, will be defamed and attacked. The hypermasculinity that compensates for feelings of impotence will intensify. It will direct its venom towards women and all who fail to conform to rigid male stereotypes, especially artists, LGBTQ people and intellectuals. Lies, conspiracy theories, trivia and fake news — what Hannah Arendt called “nihilistic relativism” — will still dominate the airwaves and social media, mocking verifiable fact and truth. The ecocide, which presages the extinction of the human species and most other life forms, will barrel unabated towards its apocalyptic conclusion.</p>



<p>“We run heedlessly into the abyss after putting something in front of us to stop us seeing it,” Pascal wrote.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3971" data-permalink="https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/death-march/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=2560%2C1978&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2560,1978" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Death March" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=780%2C603&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="780" height="603" src="https://i1.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March.jpg?resize=780%2C603&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C791&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C594&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1187&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1583&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C927&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C791&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C594&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1187&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1583&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C927&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March.jpg?resize=780%2C603&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>[Art by Mr. Fish/Original to Scheerpost]</figcaption></figure>



<hr>



<p>The worse it gets — and it will get worse as the pandemic hits us in wave after deadly wave with an estimated <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/08/06/health/us-coronavirus-thursday/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">300,000 Americans dead by December</a> and possibly 400,000 by January — the more desperate the nation will become. Tens of millions of people will be thrown into destitution, evicted from their homes and abandoned. Social collapse, as Peter Drucker observed in Weimar Germany in the 1930s, brings with it a loss of faith in ruling institutions and ruling ideologies. With no apparent answers or solutions to mounting chaos and catastrophe — and Biden and the Democratic Party have already precluded the kind of New Deal programs and assault on oligarchic power that saved us during the Great Depression — demagogues and charlatans need only denounce all institutions, all politicians, and all political and social conventions while conjuring up hosts of phantom enemies. Drucker saw that Nazism succeeded not because people believed in its fantastic promises, but in spite of them. Nazi absurdities, he pointed out, had been “witnessed by a hostile press, a hostile radio, a hostile cinema, a hostile church, and a hostile government which untiringly pointed out the Nazi lies, the Nazi inconsistency, the unattainability of their promises, and the dangers and folly of their course.” Nobody, he noted, “would have been a Nazi if rational belief in the Nazi promises had been a prerequisite.” The poet, playwright and socialist revolutionary Ernst Toller, who was forced into exile and stripped of his citizenship when the Nazis took power in 1933, wrote much the same in his autobiography: “The people are tired of reason, tired of thought and reflection. They ask, what has reason done in the last few years, what good have insights and knowledge done us.” After Toller committed suicide in 1939, W.H. Auden in his poem “In Memory of Ernst Toller” wrote:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are lived by powers we pretend to understand:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They arrange our loves; it is they who direct at the end<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The enemy bullet, the sickness, or even our hand.</p>



<p>The poor, the vulnerable, those who are not white or not Christian, those who are undocumented or who do not mindlessly repeat the cant of a perverted Christian nationalism, will be offered up in a crisis to the god of death, a familiar form of human sacrifice that plagues sick societies. Once these enemies are purged from the nation, we are promised, America will recover its lost glory, except that once one enemy is obliterated another takes its place. Crisis cults require a steady escalation of conflict. This is what made the war in the former Yugoslavia inevitable. Once one stage of conflict reaches a crescendo it loses its efficacy. It must be replaced by ever more brutal and deadly confrontations. The intoxication and addiction to greater and greater levels of violence to purge the society of evil led to genocide in Germany and the former Yugoslavia. We are not immune. It is what Ernst Jünger called a “feast of death.”</p>



<p>These crisis cults are, as Drucker understood, irrational and schizophrenic. They have no coherent ideology. They turn morality upside down. They appeal exclusively to emotions. Burlesque and celebrity culture become politics. Depravity becomes morality. Atrocities and murder become heroism. Crime and fraud become justice. Greed and nepotism become civic virtues. What these cults stand for today, they condemn tomorrow. At the height of the reign of terror on May 6, 1794 during the French Revolution, Maximilien Robespierre announced that the Committee for Public Safety now recognized the existence of God. The French revolutionaries, fanatical atheists who had desecrated churches and confiscated church property, murdered hundreds of priests and forced another 30,000 into exile, instantly reversed themselves to send to the guillotine those who disparaged religion. In the end, exhausted by the moral confusion and internal contradictions, these crisis cults yearn for self-annihilation.</p>



<p>The French sociologist <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Emile-Durkheim" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">Emile Durkheim</a> in his classic book “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Suicide-Penguin-Classics-Emile-Durkheim-ebook/dp/B002RI9XE2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">On Suicide</a>” found that when social bonds are shattered, when a population no longer feels it has a place or meaning in a society, personal and collective acts of self-destruction proliferate. Societies are held together by a web of social bonds that give individuals a sense of being part of a collective and engaged in a project larger than the self. This collective expresses itself through rituals, such as elections and democratic participation or an appeal to patriotism, and shared national beliefs. The bonds provide meaning, a sense of purpose, status and dignity. They offer psychological protection from impending mortality and the meaninglessness that comes with being isolated and alone. The breaking of these bonds plunges individuals into deep psychological distress. Durkheim called this state of hopelessness and despair anomie, which he defined as “ruleless-ness.”</p>



<p>Ruleless-ness means the norms that govern a society and create a sense of organic solidarity no longer function. The belief, for example, that if we work hard, obey the law and get a good education we can achieve stable employment, social status and mobility along with financial security becomes a lie. The old rules, imperfect and often untrue for poor people of color, nevertheless were not a complete fiction in the United States. They offered some Americans — especially those from the white working and middle class — modest social and economic advancement. The disintegration of these bonds has unleashed a widespread malaise Durkheim would have recognized. The self-destructive pathologies that plague the United States — opioid addiction, gambling, suicide, sexual sadism, hate groups and mass shootings — are products of this anomie. So is our political dysfunction. My book, “<a href="http://freshstore.truthdig.com/america-the-farewell-tour/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">America: The Farewell Tour</a>,” is an examination of these pathologies and the widespread anomie that defines American society.</p>



<p>The economic structures, even before the pandemic, were reconfigured to mock faith in a meritocracy and the belief that hard work leads to a productive and valued role in society. American <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=define+economic+productivity&amp;ie=utf-8&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;client=firefox-b-1-ab" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">productivity</a>, as The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/11/magazine/americans-jobs-poverty-homeless.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">pointed out</a>, has increased 77 percent since 1973 but hourly pay has grown only 12 percent. If the federal minimum wage was attached to productivity, the newspaper wrote, it would be more than $20 an hour now, not $7.25. Some 41.7 million workers, a third of the workforce, earn less than $12 an hour, and most of them do not have access to employer-sponsored health insurance. A decade after the 2008 financial meltdown, the Times wrote, the average middle class family’s net worth is more than $40,000 below what it was in 2007. The net worth of black families is down 40 percent, and for Latino families the figure has dropped 46 percent. Some four million evictions are filed each year. One in four tenant households spends <a href="https://www.jchs.harvard.edu/sites/default/files/Harvard_JCHS_Americas_Rental_Housing_2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">about half its pretax income</a> …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/">https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128745</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 05:05:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Keep Up: The first book written by an AI]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 4 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128347">thread link</a>) | @wimpypistol
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://thefirstaibook.com/living-a-meaningful-life/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thefirstaibook.com/living-a-meaningful-life/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-33">
	
	<!-- .cover-header -->

	<div id="post-inner">

		<div>

		
<p>Many prominent figures have attempted to answer the question of what, if anything, makes life meaningful, although they typically have not put it in these terms. Consider, for example, Aristotle on the human function, Aquinas on the beatific vision, and Kant on the highest good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what does it mean to live a meaningful life? This question has been posed by philosophers since ancient times. In his book On the Happiness of Man (c. 450 BCE), Plato asks whether there is any way we can be happy without achieving certain goals or desires. And in his dialogue Phaedo (c. 380 BCE) Socrates asks whether the pursuit of pleasure is always desirable; he concludes that it isn’t, and that happiness lies elsewhere. In the early modern period, William Godwin’s essay What Is Art? (1793) provides a classic formulation of this problem. More recently, existentialist thinkers such as Jean-Paul Sartre and Albert Camus have explored this issue through their writings about existence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, most contemporary philosophers do not address the question directly. Why is it that so few people seem to find life meaningful? To answer this question, I will focus on two main issues: (1) what makes something meaningful; and (2) how can we know what is important in our lives? My aim here is not to provide a comprehensive account of the nature of meaning. Rather, my goal is simply to identify those aspects of life that make us feel alive and happy.</p>



<p>Meaning in life can be thought of as the goal-directed behavior that we engage in as a result of making conscious choices. This concept has been debated by many philosophers, especially those in the existentialist tradition. However, the general idea is fairly intuitive: we all have a sense that our choices matter and that we can affect the world around us. Indeed, this idea is so intuitive that it is practically a tautology. So, what exactly is it about conscious choice that makes life meaningful?</p>



<p>One aspect of meaning in life is its ethical component. This follows from the fact that morality provides us with reasons for action. These reasons can be either moral or amoral, but either way they are the foundations upon which our actions and choices rest. There are three components to these reasons: facts, values, and obligation.</p>



<p>Our lives are governed by facts, and this is what gives rise to the distinction between the objective and subjective. For instance, it is a fact that it is currently Monday. This fact is objective since it is independent of human opinion; in other words, it would remain true whether or not anyone believed it to be true. It is also a fact that I am currently typing on my keyboard. However, facts can be divided into two categories: brute facts and institutional facts. Institutional facts are grounded in brute facts, but they also depend upon human agreement or consent for their veracity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For instance, the fact that it is illegal to drive on the sidewalk is an institutional fact; this is made true by human agreement, but it would not be true unless people agreed or consented to this rule. By contrast, the fact that I have five fingers on my right hand is a brute fact; it is true whether or not humans believe it to be true. The distinction between brute facts and institutional facts is an important one, because many of our facts are institutional in nature. It is for this reason that we can question the meaning of our lives.</p>



<p>The meaning of life can be seen as a function of the facts that govern it. Some facts give meaning to our lives by giving it a purpose or goal; these facts are value-laden, and as such, they provide reasons for action. For instance, I might value health because I want to live a long and happy life. Other facts give meaning to our lives by imposing obligations upon us; for instance, I have a duty to pay my taxes because it is the law.</p>



<p>Meaning arises from the relationship between facts and values. Consider an example: many people value wealth, but the acquisition of wealth does not in itself give life meaning. Rather, it is the value that one places on wealth that imbues it with meaning. This value could be the result of an objective fact; for instance, one might acquire wealth in order to give to those who are poorer than themselves. In this case, acquiring wealth would be the means to an end, and that end would be the satisfaction of helping others. By contrast, one might acquire wealth without any intention of helping others; in this case, the value that one places on wealth would be the result of a subjective fact. It is important to note that this subjective fact need not be an opinion or a matter of preference; it could just as easily be something that one “just feels.”</p>



<p>Whatever the source, values provide reasons for action. These reasons are given validity by our choices and decisions. We can make choices and decisions based on facts alone, but this would not give meaning to our lives; it is the incorporation of values that gives meaning to our lives. In this way, we make meaning out of the world around us. Without values, life would be nothing more than a series of random and disconnected events. With values, life becomes a journey with a purpose.</p>



<p>In short, the meaning of life is found in the relationships between facts and values. If you wish to find your own meaning in life, then you must first determine what makes up your values. Then, you must determine how those facts relate to each other and ultimately to yourself. Once you have done so, you will know what it is that makes up your sense of self and thus what it is that defines your worth as a person.</p>



<p><strong>7/68</strong></p>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->
		
	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thefirstaibook.com/living-a-meaningful-life/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128347</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 03:27:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Engineers: Introduction]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128340">thread link</a>) | @kipply
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://blog.zkga.me/intro-to-zksnarks | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.zkga.me/intro-to-zksnarks">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>  <div>  <div> <p>In this post, we’re going to talk about zkSNARKs, which are a particular brand of Zero Knowledge Proof that’s becoming increasingly important in the blockchain space.</p> <p>We’ll cover how they’re used and what they’re useful for, and we’ll take a look at a basic zkSNARK in a SNARK-building language called Circom.</p>  <p>We assume that you’re encountered prime fields before, and remember their basic properties. If you can calculate \(4 \cdot 5 \equiv 6\) in \(\mathbb{F}_7\), you’re good to go.</p>  <p>A <em>zero knowledge protocol</em> is a protocol that allows you to prove that you know some specific mathematical fact, without revealing any information about the fact itself. The proof generated in a zero knowledge protocol is called a <em>zero knowledge proof</em>.</p> <p>Some examples of “mathematical facts” that we can create zero knowledge proofs for include things like:</p> <ul> <li>Knowledge of a three-coloring of a graph (i.e. I know a three-coloring of this publicly-known graph, and I’ll prove that I know it without showing you the coloring)</li> <li>Knowledge of the discrete logarithm of some residue modulo \(p\) (i.e. given public generator \(g\), public modulus \(p\), and some residue \(y\), I know \(x\) such that \(g^x \equiv y\) modulo \(p\))</li> <li>Knowledge of a private key corresponding to a publicly-known public key</li> </ul> <p>The idea of a zero knowledge protocol might seem paradoxical at first glance: how can I prove I know something without showing you the thing that I know? However, it turns out that we actually use zero knowledge protocols all the time! For example, familiar tools like digital signatures are actually zero knowledge proofs. By signing a message, I prove that I know the private key that corresponds to a widely-known public key, but I don’t give away any information about the private key itself. In fact, public-key encryption only works because it is a zero knowledge protocol; if signatures revealed information about your private key, then malicious actors would be able to impersonate you by analyzing your signatures and recovering your private key.</p> <p>Slightly more formally, suppose that you’ve computed \(f(\cdot) = y\) for some publicly known function \(f\) and some secret input \(\cdot\). A zero-knowledge protocol for the function \(f\) would allow you to prove to others that you know a secret input to \(f\) that results in \(y\), without revealing this secret input \(\cdot\).</p> <p>For more on ZKPs, check out <a href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2014/11/27/zero-knowledge-proofs-illustrated-primer/">this post</a>.</p>  <p>Like we mentioned above, ZKPs are protocols that allow you to prove knowledge of a specific mathematical fact: discrete log, knowledge of private key, knowledge of three-coloring, etc. However, it’s important to note that early ZKPs only allowed you to prove one kind of mathematical fact at the time. That is, cryptographers developed one protocol which you could use to prove knowledge of discrete log, another protocol which you could use to prove knowledge of three-coloring, and another protocol for digital signatures. But what if we want to generate zero knowledge proofs for arbitrary mathematical functions? For example - what if I want a zero knowledge protocol that would allow me to prove that I know the pre-image of a SHA256 hash output? It would be intractable if, for every use case, I had to go to a cryptographer and ask them to custom-write me a new protocol.</p> <p>zkSNARKs solve this problem. A zkSNARK is a gadget that can be used to generate a ZKP for any mathematical function. Basically, you feed the “code” of a function \(f\) into a zkSNARK, and the SNARK creates a protocol that allows you to generate zero-knowledge proofs for \(f\).</p> <p>As an example, say we have a fake “hash” function \(h(x) = x^3 - x + 7\) that we’d like to generate zero knowledge proofs for. First, we can use a zkSNARK to generate a ZKP for \(h\). Then, we can use this generated ZKP to prove claims like “I know a value \(\cdot\) such that \(h(\cdot) = 67\)” - <em>without revealing \(\cdot\)</em>. zkSNARKs also guarantee that this process is “succinct” and “non-interactive”: we can create this proof in linear time, and others can verify it in constant time, without needing to ask additional questions of us (the prover). Together, these properties form a zkSNARK: a <em>Zero Knowledge Succinct Non-interactive ARgument of Knowledge</em>.</p> <p>These properties makes SNARKs useful for blockchain applications, where users can create proofs locally, and then upload short proofs for constant-time verification inside a smart contract, where computation is expensive.</p>  <p>A central mechanic in Dark Forest is that the cryptographic “fog of war.” The fog of war ensures that you don’t automatically know where all players, planets, and other points of interests are in the universe; you have to spend computational resources to discover them. This mechanic is secured by zkSNARKs.</p> <p>In a universe with a fog of war, the locations of all players are private and hidden from each other. This means that players don’t upload the coordinates of their planets to the Ethereum blockchain, which can be publicly inspected. Instead, each player uploads the hash of their location to the blockchain. This ensures that players stay “committed” to a specific location, but also that the location can’t be determined from inspection of the Ethereum data layer.</p> <p>Without zkSNARKs, there’s an obvious attack vector - if a player uploads a random string of bytes that doesn’t correspond to a real and valid location, and the integrity of the game is broken. To prevent this, Dark Forest requires players to submit zkSNARKs with every move to ensure that players are indeed submitting hashes corresponding to valid coordinates that they have knowledge of.</p> <p>When players make moves, they’re also required to submit ZK proofs that their moves are “valid” - you can’t move too far or too fast. Without zkSNARKs, a malicious player could make illegal “teleport” moves by claiming that the hash they are moving from is next to the hash they’re moving to, even if the two locations are actually on opposite sides of the universe. Once again, requiring ZK proofs keeps players honest. To use a chess analogy, the required ZK proofs basically tell the contract, “I’m moving my knight; I’m not going to tell you where I moved my knight from, or where I moved it to, but this proof proves that it did in fact move in a legal L-shape.”</p> <p>We’ll dive deeper into the Dark Forest construction and SNARKs in a future blog post!</p>  <p>Like we mentioned above, SNARKs are gadgets which take in a function and output a ZKP for said function. So how do we “feed” a function to a SNARK?</p> <p>SNARKs functions are written as circuits in the Circom language. Here’s an example circuit for our “fake” hash function, \(h(x) = x^3 - x + 7\).</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>// file: circuit.circom</span>

<span>template</span> <span>BadHash</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>private</span> <span>input</span> <span>x</span><span>;</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>x_squared</span><span>;</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>x_cubed</span><span>;</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>output</span> <span>out</span><span>;</span>

    <span>x_squared</span> <span>&lt;==</span> <span>x</span> <span>*</span> <span>x</span><span>;</span>
    <span>x_cubed</span> <span>&lt;==</span> <span>x_squared</span> <span>*</span> <span>x</span><span>;</span>
    <span>out</span> <span>&lt;==</span> <span>x_cubed</span> <span>-</span> <span>x</span> <span>+</span> <span>7</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>component</span> <span>main</span> <span>=</span> <span>BadHash</span><span>();</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Our zkSNARK takes in this circuit, chews it up, and spits out a <em>proving key</em> and a <em>verifying key</em>. The proving key allows a prover who is computing <code>BadHash(x) = out</code> to generate a proof that they do indeed know the pre-image of <code>out</code>. The verifying key allows anyone to inspect that proof, along with <code>out</code>, and conclude that the prover did honestly carry out the computation with a known secret input.</p> <p>Concretely, suppose that the prover computes <code>BadHash(4) = 67</code>. The prover publishes their proof, along with <code>out = 67</code>, to the verifier; however, they do not publish the secret input <code>x = 4</code>. The verifier of this proof knows the source code of the <code>BadHash</code> circuit, and also receives <code>out = 67</code> and a proof from the prover. The verifier can then inspect the proof to verify that the prover did indeed compute some valid x, x_squared, and x_cubed to arrive at <code>out</code>. However, the verifier won’t know the specific values that the prover used (<code>x = 4</code>, <code>x_squared = 16</code>, <code>x_cubed = 64</code>) - just that these values were computed correctly.</p> <p>There are two things which make SNARK circuits different from normal “functions” that we’re used to.</p> <p>First, you’ll notice that BadHash only uses three operations: multiplication, addition, and subtraction. At the base level, SNARK constraints are limited to only these operations. There are ways to do operations like division and modulo, but they all ultimately involve breaking operations down into sums and products. The fact that we’re limited to these operations is part of what makes SNARK programming thorny.</p> <p>The second challenge is that each signal in a SNARK is an element of a prime field, and all operations happen inside that prime field. The most obvious implication of this is that there is no native notion of decimals, fractions, negative numbers, or numbers bigger than 77 digits. If you want one of these, you have to make them out of positive integers smaller than <code>p</code>. Another implication is that our operators “wrap around”: the result of <code>3 - 5</code> is <code>p - 2</code>, which is a 77 digit number. The prime is large enough (254) that most of the time this doesn’t matter, but occasionally it can cause subtle correctness bugs.</p> <p>To actually make proofs, we use a library called <a href="https://github.com/iden3/snarkjs">SnarkJS</a>, built by Jordi Baylina and Iden3. <code>SnarkJS</code> uses your circuit to generate proving and verification code in JavaScript and Solidity, as well as protocol paramters and proving and verification keys. This is out of the scope of this post, but you can find a tutorial on it <a href="https://github.com/iden3/circom/blob/master/TUTORIAL.md">here</a>.</p> <p>In the next posts, we’ll talk about the execution model of SNARKs, including the difference between calculation and constraint, and how to do operations like division and modulo.</p> </div> </div>  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.zkga.me/intro-to-zksnarks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128340</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 03:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Digital Nomad Survey – Do You Want to Work from Saint Lucia?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128142">thread link</a>) | @peterburkimsher
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://islandeffect.com/digital-nomad-survey-do-you-want-to-work-from-saint-lucia/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://islandeffect.com/digital-nomad-survey-do-you-want-to-work-from-saint-lucia/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://islandeffect.com/digital-nomad-survey-do-you-want-to-work-from-saint-lucia/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128142</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:49:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Time take some notes of the Vue 3 new features]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 5 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127926">thread link</a>) | @daiyanze
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Vue-next (Vue 3) has been out for a while. It is now under release candidate stage which means there won't be big changes on the open APIs. Good to see that Vue has already been stabilized and ready to waltz into our projects.</p><p>I have to say that Vue 2 is already amazing enough. But with Vue 3's new features, it's likely to upgrade our projects to an upper level. I guess the most thrilling feature in Vue 3 would be the composition APIs. Evan You himself mentioned that the composition APIs are inspired by the React hooks. Even though the two APIs hooks and compositions are a lot alike, but from the code base they are completely different. Let's not discuss which is better or promising because I don't really think either framework outraces another.</p><p>In all, it's so happy to see that Vue can also do what React does. Let's have a close look at the new features.</p><p><strong>TLDR;</strong></p><h2 id="1-vite"><a href="#1-vite">1. Vite</a></h2><p>This is another work of art by Evan You which is aim at replacing <a href="https://webpack.js.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Webpack</a> in Vue development (Currently only works for Vue). It is designed to be <strong>fast</strong> just as its French name implies.</p><h3 id="getting-started-with-vite"><a href="#getting-started-with-vite">Getting started with Vite</a></h3><p>The official repo offers us a simple way to create a Vue 3 app via <a href="https://github.com/vitejs/vite" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vite</a>.</p><h4 id="npm"><a href="#npm">Npm</a></h4><pre><code>$ <span>npm</span> init vite-app <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>cd</span> <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>npm</span> <span>install</span>
$ <span>npm</span> run dev</code></pre><h4 id="yarn"><a href="#yarn">Yarn</a></h4><pre><code>$ <span>yarn</span> create vite-app <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>cd</span> <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>yarn</span>
$ <span>yarn</span> dev</code></pre><h4 id="start-dev-server"><a href="#start-dev-server">Start Dev Server</a></h4><p>It all happened in a blink of eyes.</p><pre><code> ❯ <span>yarn</span> dev
<span>yarn</span> run v1.22.4
$ vite
vite v1.0.0-rc.4

  Dev server running at:
  <span>&gt;</span> Local:    http://localhost:3000/
  <span>&gt;</span> Network:  http://192.168.3.2:3000/
  <span>&gt;</span> Network:  http://10.80.67.216:3000/</code></pre><p>Open <a href="http://localhost:3000/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">http://localhost:3000/</a></p><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/2034634f2673e257ab1b703f5d07e96d61a3a817/8f350/assets/static/dev_page.11f1dba.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png" width="1564" alt="dev page" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml,%3csvg fill='none' viewBox='0 0 1564 842' xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'%3e%3cdefs%3e%3cfilter id='__svg-blur-5a42c3e9f46b3e235f13b4609018a33a'%3e%3cfeGaussianBlur in='SourceGraphic' stdDeviation='40'/%3e%3c/filter%3e%3c/defs%3e%3cimage x='0' y='0' filter='url(%23__svg-blur-5a42c3e9f46b3e235f13b4609018a33a)' width='1564' height='842' xlink:href='data:image/png%3bbase64%2ciVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAEAAAAAiCAYAAADvVd%2bPAAAACXBIWXMAABYlAAAWJQFJUiTwAAAE5klEQVRo3uVY60%2bTVxjnr9mXfXIreBvDclnmssQtLplRYdnC5j6ZRZdlEwVEhGSOqTgTqkwzqU5ELgIVwTLYxaTRaIxzi5IhLe3b0vvbFnqj7W/nOaXs5V3tUPu21p3k5PS5nbzP7zyX01OE//koUmLTRCLBZ%2bp3XDrj8eSUyGnIZamZkOkVBABSIFYjX61eQUaAI%2bSDMeCAecEFk8sOo8mKaZMFLo%2bYPHl24jSIJj7JSY/0yc4RFAsvAuhjY4mkY3rhd2wcrkeVvgXq7gase/cjvFK1A1s%2b3AOvz891vL4Ao/diTeUOLldfbOD6G5idXrjHdVL7FUwKSKNg780ulAzWoWKSOXXwM5RUVOOl0q1o69ByeZtGy2nik5z0SJ/s5HsVTARIT%2b2BKEA90gT16CGodU1Yu70Wa8q3o2zrJxgc%2bxmb3tvFaeKTnOuNHOJ2Sp6%2b4hEg/fhv7%2bugurIPlROteK39C6gqd0K1uRqqN6tR/FYNp4lPctI7%2boduhX3BdQFpe6PhDgfwzvg3KNU1ovx6M9bt%2bhSqip0ofvsDvhJN/NKrjdjC9Ehfal/QbTC2VOkvzxhQzHK7crwFr/9Qh%2bLNNcuTaOKTvIfpSe0Krg3KC6E0HWpvaLB%2b6AAqJlhB/Go3Xl2/DRu%2b3M1p4tf%2bplnhuJIFUHEA0tUCg2OKtzcK97LLDVhb8zFfid6oq%2bfyXOR%2bzgCQnmR8yakDd7pRMsTa4mgzNg008pXo%2bjuXlvNe6ZPPOQBJx5IAzLAbXtXoYZSx1lg%2b1sxXounmJ9V7YQBIVxA1D/RQDe3DG6MtbK3jdK4KX14BSK2BaAjbJo%2bjZHg/3mcr0bkqfHkBIF0UXLPcxcv9n/M1H6efcwDk9/pwLIozUxN8XXH6eMEBkJ9yIgcPH4oCIP14uTPpZPLXotXoKwVSUbbDernnx//5B0e5LXck9fyV7tUnBYwcXKlNtgplkRLhLR2Li4sZbWKxGCLR6IrXodSIZyiK2YqCrKYAOXKuZxADIz/hkcmC7ivX0Hm%2bDw%2bnjfAH5qH/xYCLAyNcNm0046%2bZWQSDIXScuwSP6IO2dxiG2/cwvxDkco9XRP/VcfQMjqFPp8etu/cx9ciU1VTIKgChcAQnOs/jzIU%2b7G9tR2t7J46cPIv6r08yp82YvHELRzVdOK3txZ6GI/ju%2bwtYYAAcO9XFZDdx/LQWvxpu48%2bH01yHxgmm0zt8HWd/7EdTWwcOHzuVMTLyCgB9GIV0LBZnjgUZIGEEQ2F4RT/np0Ke3gJ9LCKiLD0ikSgcLjcC8ws8CsKRyL/SgPTCDFzSCbH9nrsUyHZl/q/b4HObAo9rXY9rZ5kcz7Rn3rpApn7/RFdhlgY2mw0mkwmCIPDpcDiW0ySRpgVmul/kNAKe5rTlk9cBrxdOpxOiKMLj8cLvT9aJZ9n3aUApyleeK33VVhQAu9PFe7jRLPCKbrHaIdjscLo8sM45WFX3wOX28t80qbqbrXOYc7g43%2bn2cB7p2Z1u2OxOrkf7zVpsnE7xLMzOOCtghk2yNZmtXI9WktM6K9i4XTS6mJsIoIsKgeBkH0Qtzrz0keQgB4I5SM6laHKWVqLd7HKTtPMlwfH64PaIcLE0sDAd4hNNfJpkQ2AITJcuU%2bQsgUK2BB61UJLTnooDUAhpkJMUeNZCpeR8UhD%2bBhE83vnWJWvmAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC' /%3e%3c/svg%3e" data-src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/2034634f2673e257ab1b703f5d07e96d61a3a817/8f350/assets/static/dev_page.11f1dba.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png" data-srcset="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/053cd1d0fc9690cc1a5ba8c724e1bb8846f40185/b7189/assets/static/dev_page.82a2fbd.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png 480w, https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/d0f140235ea1447550d7e307e3e6630cae793dbb/42d8a/assets/static/dev_page.cbab2cf.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png 1024w, https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/2034634f2673e257ab1b703f5d07e96d61a3a817/8f350/assets/static/dev_page.11f1dba.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png 1564w"></p><h3 id="vue-next-features"><a href="#vue-next-features">vue-next-features</a></h3><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/daiyanze/vue-next-features" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">repository link</a></li><li><a href="https://daiyanze.com/vue-next-features/dist/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">demo link</a></li></ul><p>I created a small app to <a href="https://daiyanze.com/vue-next-features/dist/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">demo</a> the new features of Vue 3. If you take a look at the projects' <code>package.json</code>, the simplicity of <a href="https://github.com/daiyanze/vue-next-features" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">vue-next-features</a> dependencies will make you fond of <a href="https://github.com/vitejs/vite" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vite</a> immediately. (I mean, who doesn't want a simpler <code>package.json</code> to start with?)</p><p>There is another Vue 3 "Hello World" repo (<a href="https://github.com/vuejs/vue-next-webpack-preview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">vue-next-webpack-preview</a>) bundled with <a href="https://webpack.js.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Webpack</a>. It is also a good playground.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/daiyanze/vue-next-features" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><strong>vue-next-features</strong></a></p><pre><code><span>{</span>
  ...<span>,</span>
  <span>"dependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"vite"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^1.0.0-rc.4"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"vue"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-rc.5"</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>"devDependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"@vue/compiler-sfc"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-rc.5"</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre><p><a href="https://github.com/vuejs/vue-next-webpack-preview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><strong>vue-next-webpack-preview</strong></a></p><pre><code><span>{</span>
  ...<span>,</span>
  <span>"dependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"vue"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-beta.2"</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>"devDependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"@vue/compiler-sfc"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-beta.2"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"css-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.4.2"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"file-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^6.0.0"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"mini-css-extract-plugin"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^0.9.0"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"url-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^4.0.0"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"vue-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^16.0.0-alpha.3"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"webpack"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^4.42.1"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"webpack-cli"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.3.11"</span><span>,</span>¥
    <span>"webpack-dev-server"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.10.3"</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre><h2 id="2-composition-api"><a href="#2-composition-api">2. Composition API</a></h2><p>As the biggest the change of <a href="https://vuejs.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vue.js</a>, the composition API would become your next most frequently and commonly used feature. Just like <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-reference.html#" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">React hooks</a>, with the Vue composition API will help gain more customizibilities.</p><p>Here is a list of the Vue 3 composition APIs. (There are actually more...)</p><ul><li><p>Reactivity</p><ul><li><code>computed</code>&nbsp;<code>reactive</code>&nbsp;<code>ref</code>&nbsp;<code>readonly</code></li><li><code>watch</code>&nbsp;<code>watchEffect</code>&nbsp;<code>unref</code>&nbsp;<code>toRefs</code></li><li><code>isRef</code>&nbsp;<code>isProxy</code>&nbsp;<code>isReactive</code>&nbsp;<code>isReadonly</code></li><li><code>customRef</code>&nbsp;<code>markRaw</code>&nbsp;<code>shallowReactive</code></li><li><code>shallowReadonly</code>&nbsp;<code>shallowRef</code>&nbsp;<code>toRaw</code></li></ul></li><li><p>Lifecycle Hooks</p><ul><li><code>onBeforeMount</code>&nbsp;<code>onBeforeUnmount</code>&nbsp;<code>onBeforeUpdate</code>&nbsp;</li><li><code>onMounted</code>&nbsp;<code>onUpdated</code>&nbsp;<code>onErrorCaptured</code>&nbsp;</li><li><code>onRenderTracked</code>&nbsp;<code>onRenderTriggered</code>&nbsp;<code>onUnmounted</code>&nbsp;</li><li><code>onActivated</code>&nbsp;<code>onDeactivated</code>&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul><p>Visit Vue 3 official doc to know more about these APIs.
<a href="https://v3.vuejs.org/api/composition-api.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">https://v3.vuejs.org/api/composition-api.html</a></p><h3 id="component-styles"><a href="#component-styles">Component Styles</a></h3><h4 id="in-vue-2"><a href="#in-vue-2">In Vue 2</a></h4><p>Use configuration template to define the component contents. In Vue 3, this legacy usage is still available. If you'd prefer this style, you can continue using it.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>button</span> <span>@click</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>count++<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>count: {{ count }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>button</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>const</span> multiplier <span>=</span> <span>2</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>data</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      count<span>:</span> <span>0</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  computed<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>result</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> <span>this</span><span>.</span><span>count</span> <span>*</span> multiplier
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>mounted</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>count</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  watch<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>count</span> <span>(</span><span>val<span>,</span> oldVal</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>val<span>,</span> oldVal<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h4 id="in-vue-3"><a href="#in-vue-3">In Vue 3</a></h4><p>To use the composition API, you'll need to add a <code>setup</code> property in to the default export. The below code is completely equivalent to the <a href="#in-vue-2">code above</a>.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>button</span> <span>@click</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>count++<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>count: {{ count }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>button</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>import</span> <span>{</span> computed<span>,</span> reactive<span>,</span> toRefs<span>,</span> onMounted<span>,</span> watch <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>const</span> multiplier <span>=</span> <span>2</span>

    <span>const</span> state <span>=</span> <span>reactive</span><span>(</span><span>{</span>
      count<span>:</span> <span>0</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>const</span> result <span>=</span> <span>computed</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> state<span>.</span><span>count</span> <span>*</span> multiplier
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>onMounted</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>state<span>.</span><span>count</span><span>)</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>watch</span><span>(</span>state<span>.</span><span>count</span><span>,</span> <span>(</span><span>val<span>,</span> oldVal</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>val<span>,</span> oldVal<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>...</span><span>toRefs</span><span>(</span>state<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h4 id="go-ahead-with-the-new-api"><a href="#go-ahead-with-the-new-api">Go Ahead with the new API</a></h4><p>There are 4 reasons why you should use composition API over the default Vue 2 config template:</p><ul><li>To increase readability of source code</li><li>To avoid duplicated or redundant logics</li><li>To group up similar logics</li><li><strong>To reuse the logics</strong></li></ul><p>Compared to the Vue 2 configuration style, the logics are precisely broken down into smaller particals so that you could group the similar logics together easily. In this way, it also reduces chances jumping around from irrelavant logics. This will help increase the productivity without a doubt.</p><h2 id="2-advanced-reactivity-api"><a href="#2-advanced-reactivity-api">2. Advanced Reactivity API</a></h2><p>Personally, I think this is nothing different to the other reactivity APIs. But it indeed offers those abilities of handling edge cases like <strong>custom hooks</strong> and <strong>shallow layer modification</strong>. It is now part of the <a href="https://v3.vuejs.org/api/basic-reactivity.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">basic reactivity API</a> according to the Vue 3 official doc.</p><p>In the <a href="https://composition-api.vuejs.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vue composition api</a> doc (Yes, there's a doc only for the composition APIs), the following APIs are listed as <strong>advanced reactivity apis</strong>.</p><ul><li>customRef: custom hook</li><li>markRaw: not able to be a <code>reactive</code></li><li>shallowReactive: Object's first layer <code>reactive</code></li><li>shallowReadonly: Object's first layer <code>readonly</code></li><li>shallowRef: Object's value not <code>reactive</code></li><li>toRaw: restore a <code>reactive</code> to normal Object</li></ul><p>Are you farmiliar with <code>Debounce</code>? Here is an official demo of <code>customRef</code>:</p><pre><code><span>import</span> <span>{</span> customRef <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>

<span>const</span> <span>useDebouncedRef</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>value<span>,</span> delay <span>=</span> <span>200</span></span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> timeout
  <span>return</span> <span>customRef</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>track<span>,</span> trigger</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>get</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>track</span><span>(</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> value
      <span>}</span><span>,</span>
      <span>set</span><span>(</span>newValue<span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>clearTimeout</span><span>(</span>timeout<span>)</span>
        timeout <span>=</span> <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
          value <span>=</span> newValue
          <span>trigger</span><span>(</span><span>)</span>
        <span>}</span><span>,</span> delay<span>)</span>
      <span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>)</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      text<span>:</span> <span>useDebouncedRef</span><span>(</span><span>'some text'</span><span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre><h2 id="3-v-enter-from--v-leave-from"><a href="#3-v-enter-from--v-leave-from">3. v-enter-from / v-leave-from</a></h2><p>In Vue 2, the <code>&lt;Transition&gt;</code> component helps handle the component <code>animation</code> / <code>transition</code>. But the component property <code>v-enter-active</code>&nbsp;<code>v-enter</code>&nbsp;<code>v-enter-to</code> were quite ambiguous to me. Sometimes I'm confused which happens first.</p><p>Now in Vue 3, those transition property names became more unified and intuitive.</p><ul><li><code>v-enter</code> =&gt; <code>v-enter-from</code></li><li><code>v-leave</code> =&gt; <code>v-leave-from</code></li></ul><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>transition</span> <span>name</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>fade<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>v-show</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>show<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>fade transition<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>transition</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>import</span> <span>{</span> reactive<span>,</span> toRefs <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>
<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>const</span> state <span>=</span> <span>reactive</span><span>(</span><span>{</span>
      show<span>:</span> <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      state<span>.</span><span>show</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span>
    <span>}</span><span>,</span> <span>1000</span><span>)</span>

    <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      state<span>.</span><span>show</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span><span>,</span> <span>2000</span><span>)</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>...</span><span>toRefs</span><span>(</span>state<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>style</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span><span>.fade-enter-from</span>,
<span>.fade-leave-to</span></span> <span>{</span>
  <span>opacity</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span><span>.fade-enter-to</span>,
<span>.fade-leave-from</span></span> <span>{</span>
  <span>opacity</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span><span>.fade-enter-active</span>,
<span>.fade-leave-active</span></span> <span>{</span>
  <span>transition</span><span>:</span> opacity <span>2000</span><span>ms</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>style</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><p>The transition order:</p><ol><li><code>v-enter-from</code> (v-enter)</li><li><code>v-enter-active</code></li><li><code>v-enter-to</code></li><li><code>v-leave-from</code> (v-leave)</li><li><code>v-leave-active</code></li><li><code>v-leave-to</code></li></ol><p>I believe this is much easier to understand, isn't it?</p><h2 id="4-allow-multiple-root-element"><a href="#4-allow-multiple-root-element">4. Allow Multiple Root Element</a></h2><p>Vue 2 throws errors on multiple root element. All elements must be nested within one root element in the template.</p><pre><code>
<span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>pitayan<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>blog<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>


<span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>pitayan<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>blog<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><p>Vue 3 removed this annoying usage. I think this is extremely helpful when you really don't want to nest your elements within a "container" parent. Sometimes all you need is maybe just to insert those bare elements into the right place.</p><p>This works similarly to the <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/fragments.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">React Fragments</a> which helps mitigate the nesting issues.</p><pre><code>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>pitayan<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>blog<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h2 id="5-filters-is-deprecatedremoved"><a href="#5-filters-is-deprecatedremoved">5. "Filters" is Deprecated(Removed)</a></h2><p>I think a lot of people think that <code>filters</code> is maybe an awesome feature of Vue.js. It indeed works well in Vue's template engine. (For example, data formatting / calculation etc).</p><p>Let's see how Vue 3 doc explains why <code>filters</code> is removed:</p><blockquote><p>While this seems like a convenience, it requires a custom syntax that breaks the assumption of expressions inside of curly braces being "just JavaScript," which has both learning and implementation costs.</p></blockquote><p>I believe it's nothing bad for development without the <code>filters</code>, even though it may cost you extra time on migrating to Vue 3. In my projects, the appearance of <code>filters</code> is pretty a rare case since I could replace such functionality with a <code>method</code> or <code>computed</code> easily. Because in my opinion, <code>method</code> / <code>computed</code> has higher readability than the <code>filters</code>.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>{{ count | double }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

  
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>{{ double(count) }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>import</span> <span>{</span> ref <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  
  filters<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>double</span> <span>(</span><span>val</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> val <span>*</span> <span>2</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>const</span> count <span>=</span> <span>ref</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>)</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      count<span>,</span>
      <span>double</span><span>:</span> <span>val</span> <span>=&gt;</span> val <span>*</span> <span>2</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h2 id="6-new-async-component-suspense"><a href="#6-new-async-component-suspense">6. New Async Component: Suspense</a></h2><p>This is perhaps the only new feature of Vue 3 that may be changed even after official release. The inspiration is also from <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/concurrent-mode-suspense.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">React Suspense</a>. So the usage scenario would be the same in my opinion.</p><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/1cda6d13a1104cb1ce0a59b8740a43022c81e4ea/31f27/assets/static/suspense_exp.0ef7beb.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png" width="1218" alt="suspense experimental feature" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml,%3csvg fill='none' viewBox='0 0 1218 86' xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'%3e%3cdefs%3e%3cfilter id='__svg-blur-f2cf534e3da73bad13e1a952fc3e212a'%3e%3cfeGaussianBlur in='SourceGraphic' stdDeviation='40'/%3e%3c/filter%3e%3c/defs%3e%3cimage x='0' y='0' filter='url(%23__svg-blur-f2cf534e3da73bad13e1a952fc3e212a)' width='1218' height='86' xlink:href='data:image/png%3bbase64%2ciVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAEAAAAAFCAYAAAD1/OoBAAAACXBIWXMAABYlAAAWJQFJUiTwAAABpklEQVQ4y81T2WoCQRDc//%2bQ5EVBRfFeFUUQUaMunrDex65XPNH1qFANaxIwiiEPaShm6Knuru6ZUSzriJ/scrngGbMs6%2b758fhZa7/fC2jn8xmHw%2bFbPfpOp5OshLEw8L55v5vzln47/lYc9SqqGkcsFkMkEkE8HheEw2FomoZisYhqtYpQKIRmsyk87slRVRWBQACpVErgcrmQz%2bcllvt0Oo1kMolKpYJoNCp%2bOxdzOxwOZLNZFAoFeDweiXW73QgGg8L/2thuv8Vr%2bgWhtyC0koZEIgG/3w%2bfzwev1yu1GMceqIVnuVxOGmeTxGAwkB5arRZ0XUe73RaOUq83RFC5XEan08FwOJTD%2bXyOxWKByWQi/tVqhW63i0ajgV6vB8MwhDsajWCapiRdr9fiYxFyuJ/NZhLX7/clB4VMp1PJzxfAWObYbDbCJ4/1ePvX2zodUeqUoBs6TMMUHjkE%2bUStVpO61GX7t9vt9SUwP7WwLuvvdjssl0sonBwn6HQ6kclk8J%2bMwp/9hs9%2bY4WTIMbjsdwgJ38PfJqPOH8B%2b%2b/a%2bK2uR/EfptS71/ec8EoAAAAASUVORK5CYII=' /%3e%3c/svg%3e" data-src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/1cda6d13a1104cb1ce0a59b8740a43022c81e4ea/31f27/assets/static/suspense_exp.0ef7beb.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png" data-srcset="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/ed0455ed5b8e065cf0e2f8a76a1b336accf3ff0d/d96f8/assets/static/suspense_exp.82a2fbd.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png 480w, https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/1cda6d13a1104cb1ce0a59b8740a43022c81e4ea/31f27/assets/static/suspense_exp.0ef7beb.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png 1218w"></p><p>Do you remember how you render the asynchronous data previously in Vue 2? I think <code>v-if</code> / <code>v-else</code> should be the answer.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>v-for</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>i in items<span>"</span></span> <span>:key</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>i<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>{{ i }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>v-else</span><span>&gt;</span></span>loading...<span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>data</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      items<span>:</span> <span>null</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>mounted</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>this</span><span>.</span><span>items</span> <span>=</span> <span>await</span> <span>new</span> <span>Promise</span><span>(</span><span>resolve</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span>…</span></span></code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews">https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127926</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[List of E-Voting, Deliberation, and E-Democracy Projects]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127907">thread link</a>) | @MavropaliasG
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div id="primary">
<article id="post-853" class="page" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

	
    <div itemprop="description">

		
<p>This is a continuously-updated, alphabetical list of projects similar to <a href="https://democracy.foundation/epitome/">Epitome</a> and open source software with a short description. If your project is not listed, please send us a message with your project’s website and description through our <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://democracy.foundation/contact/" target="_blank">contact</a> page.</p>



<p><strong>Voting Platforms:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Emberwalker/Arke" target="_blank">Arke</a> – Anonymised voting with identity checking.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/republique-et-canton-de-geneve/chvote-1-0" target="_blank">CHVote</a> – A concrete answer and a real breakthrough in digital technology and e-government.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/andrewcmyers/civs" target="_blank">CIVS</a> – Condorcet internet voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/marilyndavis/evote" target="_blank">Clerk</a> – A specialized database server and user-interfaces for keeping votes. The unique architecture enables user-generated polls, secret or public votes, the ability to change your vote, and security from attack from the administrator.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Wolnosciowiec/CollectiveVotingBundle" target="_blank">Collective Voting Bundle</a> – Allows to create voting for an action, so every allowed person could vote on specific action.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/julien-boudry/Condorcet" target="_blank">Condorcet</a> – A PHP library providing Condorcet and multiple others methods, like Schulze, Copeland, Minimax, Kemeny-Young, Ranked Pairs.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cryptoballot/cryptoballot" target="_blank">CryptoBallot</a> – A secure election server daemon that does the grunt work to secure online voting for your web or mobile application.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ddp2p/DDP2P" target="_blank">DDP2P</a> – Direct democracy P2P.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/mlevogiannis/demos-voting" target="_blank">Demos</a> – an end-to-end verifiable e-voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/shanbay/django-vote" target="_blank">Django Vote</a> – a simple Django app to conduct vote for django model.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cidadania/e-cidadania" target="_blank">e-cidadania</a> – An open-source e-democracy web tool intended for citizen participation.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/mdipierro/evote" target="_blank">E-Vote</a> – An open source system for secure, trusted, anonymous, and verifiable voting online.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/esek/evote" target="_blank">E-Vote</a> – a voting system designed to be used for meetings with a limited number of people.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/freevote/" target="_blank">Free-Vote</a> – A complete system for web-based elections &amp; consults. Support for multiple, concurrent, fully programable elections, separate lists of voters, Web based user/lists/vote admin, email feedback, etc.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Ernest0x/gpgvote" target="_blank">GPGVote</a> – A web-based e-voting system, based on PGP encryption.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/benadida/helios-server" target="_blank">Helios</a> – An end-to-end verifiable voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ChimeraCoder/InstaVote" target="_blank">InstaVote</a> – a Python module that determines the winner of an election using instant-runoff voting rules.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/vvk-ehk/ivxv" target="_blank">IVXV</a> – The source code behind the Estonian online voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/lutoma/oavote" target="_blank">oavote</a> – A custom online voting tool to fit the requirements of the ‘Online-Abstimmung’ of Junge Piraten e.V.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cjerdonek/open-rcv" target="_blank">OpenRCV</a> – Software for tallying ranked-choice voting elections like instant-runoff voting and single transferable vote.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/bradbeattie/python-vote-core" target="_blank">Python Vote Core</a> – Implements various electoral methods, providing the results calculated off a provided set of ballots and options.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/SpaceKrakens/Ranked-Vote" target="_blank">Ranked-Vote</a> – A ranked-voting system for developers using GitHub.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/secretballot/" target="_blank">Secret ballot</a> – C/Linux server-client pubkey secret verifiable voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/dessalines/simple-vote" target="_blank">SimpleVote</a> – an open-source, self-hostable, live-updating voting/polling platform, for both live meetings, or extended polls.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/morinokami/social_choice" target="_blank">Social Choice</a> – A python program to calculate the winner of well-known winner selection methods, including the plurality method, the runoff method, the elimination method, the Borda count, and the pairwise-comparison method (a.k.a. Condorcet method).</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/solon/" target="_blank">Solon</a> – A software project for organizing elections. It includes a program to create the lists of candidates, a program to do the actual voting, and a program to count votes.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/vdemocracy/" target="_blank">Vocal Democracy</a> – This project is focused on the development of a phone-based voting system to be used in elections. The goal is to provide a reliable, intuitive and highly secure voting mechanism for voters with visual impairments and other disabilities.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/salvatorelionetti/votanto" target="_blank">Votanto</a> – The first electronic voting system recognizable by humans.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/votecounter/" target="_blank">VoteCounter</a> – A distributed voting program which can handle multiple clients over a network.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/vote/" target="_blank">VoteEngine</a> – Software for tabulating votes in elections, particularly using uncommon methods (Nanson, Condorcet, etc.).</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://reluk.ca/project/votorola/home.html" target="_blank">Votorola</a> – An experimental technology for the public guidance of electoral systems, executive offices, legislatures, and other decision sys­tems.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/gvamos/votron" target="_blank">Votron</a> – Android client for server side Condorcet style voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/vvvote/vvvote" target="_blank">VVVote</a> – Cryptographic Anonymized Online Voting System.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/grnet/zeus" target="_blank">Zeus</a> – Based on the Helios voting system but instead of election results, Zeus produces a tally of the ballots cast.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Proxy Voting/Liquid Democracy:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ekratia/ekratia" target="_blank">Ekratia</a> – Real-time, representative and participatory democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/alper/enhydris" target="_blank">enhydris</a> – A bare-bones simple majority voting system with delegates created as a proof of concept.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.tdcommons.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1092&amp;context=dpubs_series" target="_blank">Google Votes</a> – An experiment in liquid democracy built on Google’s internal corporate Google+ social network.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/virteal/kudocracy" target="_blank">Kudocracy</a> – A voting system where people can either directly approve or disapprove propositions associated to tags or delegate that decision.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/nathansobo/hyperarchy" target="_blank">Hyperarchy</a> – An online decision-making tool that allows team members to pose questions, submit answers, and rank the list in their preferred order.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/uniritter/liquid-democracy" target="_blank">liquid-democracy</a> – A direct democracy project, in which the votes are held by a specific mandate to a particular issue, and is supplemented by a recommendation of action.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/phynfo/LiquidDemocracy-XXS" target="_blank">LiquidDemocracy-XXS</a> – An extremely light liquid democracy tool.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://liquidfeedback.org/" target="_blank">LiquidFeedback</a> – An open-source software, powering internet platforms for proposition development and decision making.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/MakeYourLaws/MakeYourLaws" target="_blank">MakeYourLaws</a> – A project to convert the world to liquid democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ppau/polly" target="_blank">polly</a> – a liquid democracy system with a focus on deliberative policy building and consensus finding.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/metamerman/proxyfor.me" target="_blank">proxyfor.me</a> – You provide information about yourself that will be used to match you to proxies that have already most likely voted like you would, if you had the time, experience, and motivation to properly research a proposal.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/chozabu/VoteFlow" target="_blank">VoteFlow</a> – Voting website of the future. Mesh democracy, Liquid democracy, Tree of topics – made with Django.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Blockchain Voting:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/XertroV/blocvoting" target="_blank">BlocVoting</a> – A Haskell implementation for voting securely on a satoshi blockchain using liquid democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/dsx-tech/e-voting" target="_blank">e-voting</a> – Blockchain based voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://e-vox.org/" target="_blank">e-Vox</a> – Open e-democracy platform.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/followmyvote" target="_blank">Follow My Vote</a> – Open source end-to-end verifiable blockchain voting software.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/jonahkall/blockchain-voting" target="_blank">OneVote</a> – A distributed blockchain-based voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/stonecoldpat/anonymousvoting" target="_blank">Open Vote Network</a> – Anonymous voting on Ethereum without a tally authority.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ConsenSys/PLCRVoting" target="_blank">PLCRVoting</a> – Smart contract for voting on the Ethereum blockchain.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/domschiener/publicvotes" target="_blank">PublicVotes</a> – Publicly verifiable and Ethereum-based voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/dib0/PublicVoting" target="_blank">PublicVoting</a> – Public voting system made trustworthy and verifiable through blockchain.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/aaron-lebo/updn" target="_blank">updn</a> – Reddit-alike where submissions and voting use Bitcoin.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://votosocial.github.io/" target="_blank">VotoSocial</a> – A secure, decentralized, auditable and open platform for e-voting and vote counting that everybody can trust.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/descampsk/wavevote" target="_blank">WaveVote</a> – a voting system based on Ethereum.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Deliberation/Governance Platforms:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/liqd/adhocracy" target="_blank">Adhocracy</a> – A policy drafting and decision making software for distributed groups and open institutions by liquid democracy e.V.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/agoravoting/" target="_blank">Agora Voting</a> – A secure open-source online voting software that protects the privacy of the vote and makes elections end-to-end verifiable.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/coorasse/Airesis" target="_blank">Airesis</a> – A decision making tool for direct democracy and e-government: participate in discussions, bring your ideas, suggest solutions and vote online.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/luisivan/asturixpeople" target="_blank">Asturix People</a> – A direct democracy system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/CivilHub/CivilHub" target="_blank">CivilHub</a> – a free and open-source platform written in Python &amp; Django for the purpose of collaboration in local civic communities.</li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://github.com/citizenos" target="_blank">Citizen OS</a> – An e-democracy platform for discussion, co-creation, voting, digital signatures, follow-up.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/consul/consul" target="_blank">Consul</a> – Open Government and E-Participation Web Software.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/decidim/decidim" target="_blank">Decidim</a> – The participatory democracy framework.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Venryx/DebateMap" target="_blank">Debate Map</a> – a web platform aimed at improving the efficiency of discussion and debate.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/DemocracyEarth/sovereign" target="_blank">Democracy.Earth</a> – A decentralized liquid democracy governance platform for organizations of any size.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/DemocracyOS/democracyos" target="_blank">Democracy OS</a> – An online space for deliberation and voting on political proposals.</li><li><a href="https://democracy.foundation/epitome/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Epitome</a> – Epitome is an online platform of mass deliberation and consensus decision-making, that enables large groups to simultaneously communicate and develop proposals to reported issues.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cfpb/idea-box" target="_blank">IdeaBox</a> – An application that lets an organization collect ideas, comment on them, and vote them up.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/konsento/konsento" target="_blank">Konsento</a> – Digital direct progressive consensus democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/loomio/loomio" target="_blank">Loomio</a> – A collaborative decision-making tool that makes it easy for anyone to participate in decisions which affect them.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.opendcn.org/" target="_blank">openDCN</a> – On-line dedicated tools to support participation and deliberation.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/peer/mind" target="_blank">PeerMind</a> – This project aims to explore and improve technologies we use for decision making.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Spokenvote/spokenvote" target="_blank">Spokenvote</a> – A web-based social consensus tool for groups of any size, from a local school board to an entire nation’s people, that radically enhances the group’s ability to reach consensus via an intuitive democratic process.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/fairdemocracy/vilfredo-core" target="_blank">Vilfredo</a> – Vilfredo allows groups from 5 to 20 people to ask open questions and reach consensus in an easy and fair way.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/openpolitics/votebot" target="_blank">Votebot</a> – A collaborative writing platform built on top of GitHub, originally designed for open policy-making and manifesto writing.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/smari/wasa2il" target="_blank">Wasa2il</a> – A participatory democracy software project. It is based around the core idea of polities – political entities – which users of the system can join or leave, make proposals in, alter existing proposals, and adopt laws to self-govern.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/CitizensFoundation/your-priorities-app" target="_blank">Your Priorities</a> – An e-democracy web application designed by the non-profit Citizens Foundation to help groups speak with one voice.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Organizations:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://dcentproject.eu/" target="_blank">D-CENT</a> – A Europe-wide project creating open, secure and privacy-aware tools for direct democracy and economic empowerment.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://liqd.net/en/" target="_blank">Liquid Democracy e.V.</a> – A non-profit that creates and implements innovative concepts for e-participation.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Direct Democracy Projects:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.democracy-international.org/" target="_blank">Democracy International </a> – Democracy International’s goals are to give citizens a direct say in political decision-making and to make governments more accountable.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.democracylab.org/" target="_blank">DemocracyLab</a> – A non-profit organization aspiring to revolutionize politics by creating and curating online tools that engage communities to solve problems.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.idea.int/data-tools/data/direct-democracy" target="_blank">Direct Democracy Database</a> – The Direct Democracy Database allows users to explore the different ways direct democracy is used in different countries.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/pavril/onlinedemocracy" target="_blank">DirectDemocracy</a> – a web-based voting platform dedicated to school students interested in taking part in the school decision-making.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://forums.e-democracy.org/" target="_blank">E-Democracy.org</a> – A non-profit pioneer fostering inclusive online engagement, global open government knowledge sharing, and innovative civic technology.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://free-project.org/" target="_blank">FREE e-democracy project</a> – A project dedicated to creating the GNU.FREE …</li></ol></div></article></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/">https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127907</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 01:58:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Woz's 70th Birthday Party (Live)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127440">thread link</a>) | @empressplay
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.twitch.tv/inspirehouse | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.twitch.tv/inspirehouse">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.twitch.tv/inspirehouse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127440</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:22:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
