<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:25:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 08:25:33 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Laser-Guided Lightning May Help Prevent Wildfires]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25103339">thread link</a>) | @kposehn
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
				
				<div>
				
				
				<p><h2>Small, portable laser pointers could be used to guide lightning strikes, with a study suggesting the technology may prevent bolts from sparking wildfires, a researcher told AFP Thursday.</h2></p>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<div><p>A team of international scientists have shown storm clouds could be “short-circuited” by using a hollow laser — like a pipe of light — to deliver particles into the clouds and draw lightning strikes, research co-author Professor Andrey Miroshnichenko from the University of New South Wales in Canberra told AFP.</p>
<p>In lab tests, the team — which also included scientists from the Australian National University (ANU) — successfully used a laser tractor beam to direct the path of an electrical discharge to specific targets, Miroshnichenko said.</p>
<p>In the past, high-powered lasers were needed to achieve similar results, making the technique dangerous, costly and inaccurate.<span>&nbsp;</span></p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<p><iframe title="Bushfires in Australia: What ignited the deadly crisis" width="1080" height="608" src="about:blank" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-l28KQ8dJDM?feature=oembed" data-no-lazy="1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
				
			</div><div>
				
				
				<div><p>But the new research suggested that small, hand-held lasers could be used in the field within the next decade, he said.</p>
<p>“It turns out that to deliver particles, you do not need high-intensity lasers, even low intensity like your laser pointer will be already enough,” Miroshnichenko said.</p>
<p>Using a tractor beam with a hollow centre, micro-particles in the air could be heated up and delivered to a specific point and trigger an electrical discharge.</p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><p><span><img src="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg" data-src="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg" alt="Electrical Discharge Induce by Microparticle" title="Electrical Discharge Induce by Microparticle" height="auto" width="auto" data-srcset="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg 800w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-768x427.jpg 768w" data-sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" srcset="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg 800w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-768x427.jpg 768w"></span>
			</p><div>
				
				
				<p>The electrical discharge induced by a heated microparticle.</p>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<div><p>Although it is yet to be tested outside a lab, the technique could potentially be used to control dry lightning strikes, infamous for sparking large blazes including several major <a href="https://www.breakingasia.com/trending/social-media-fakes-australia-bushfire-disinformation/">bushfires in Australia</a> and the western US in the past year, Miroshnichenko added.</p>
<p>“We can imagine a future where this technology may induce electrical discharge from passing lightning, helping to guide it to safe targets and reduce the risk of <a href="https://www.breakingasia.com/trending/makeshift-hospital-saving-dozens-of-koalas-injured-in-bushfires/">catastrophic fires</a>,” co-researcher Vladlen Shvedov, from the ANU Research School of Physics, said.</p>
<p>The research, published in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-19183-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nature Communications last month</a>, also involved Texas A&amp;M University in Qatar and the University of California in Los Angeles.<span>&nbsp;</span></p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25103339</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Create Vintage Videos Using FFmpeg in 4 Simple Steps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 273 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25102401">thread link</a>) | @ponderingfish
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><strong>It’s time for the holidays and what better way to share love and memories with your family than to create an old-school, vintage movie? You don’t need a time-machine to go back to the 50s or 60s to rmake your homevideo look like a vintage movie. All you need is FFmpeg, some imagination, and perhaps the rest of this guide 🙂 </strong></p>



<p>Let’s take a look at how you can use FFmpeg to make your videos look like old-school/vintage/retro-styled movies, shall we?</p>



<hr>



<h2>What’s Do I Mean By A Vintage Movie?</h2>



<p>Well, good question! </p>



<p><strong>My definition of an old-school movie is a movie with a low frame-rate (like 15 fps), lots of scratches and film-grain to give an aged look, and a sepia tint to it!</strong></p>



<p>Let’s see how we can achieve all of this using FFmpeg.</p>



<p>For this tutorial, I shall be using the “Touchdown Pass” sequence from <a href="https://media.xiph.org/video/derf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xiph</a> to illustrate the steps. It’s a 20 second video, but for the sake of this tutorial, I’ll be cutting it to 10 seconds using FFmpeg (<a href="https://ottverse.com/trim-cut-video-using-start-endtime-reencoding-ffmpeg/">here’s how to do that</a>).</p>



<p>Let’s get started! </p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 1: Changing the Frame Rate using FFmpeg</h2>



<p>The first step is to “speed” up the video. Let’s take the video back to pre-30fps or pre-60fps days and take it all the way down to 10 fps. This gives the video an old-school look right off the bat! </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i td-10sec.mp4 \
-filter:v fps=fps=10 \
td-fast.mp4</code></pre>



<p>Here is the sped-up video. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479524704" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 2: Give The Video a Vintage Look using FFmpeg’s filters</h2>



<p>Next, let’s change the rich, wonderful colors and bring a sepia-link tint to the entire video. This can be done using FFmpeg’s in-built <code>curves</code> filter. You can use the <code>curves</code> filter to change the amount of R, G, B in a frame and specify the “curves” that govern the change or shift in colors. </p>



<p>Luckily for us, FFmpeg has a pre-defined <code>vintage</code> filter that works pretty well, I must say! Here is the commandline to convert our sped-up video into a “vintage” looking video. Simple, right?</p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i td-fast.mp4 \
-vf curves=vintage \
td-vintage-fast.mp4</code></pre>



<p>Here’s the result of the <code>curves=vintage</code> filter on our footall video.</p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479525304" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 3: Getting a Film Grain Overlay and Resizing It</h2>



<p>As the final step, let’s add a lot of film-grain and “scratches” to make our video look like something that was shot on film, stored in a dusty old cupboard, and discovered 40 years later! </p>



<p>I found a fantastic “old school” film overlay on YouTube (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J_MZb7qTenE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">source link</a>) with a download link. </p>



<figure><div>
<p><span><iframe width="1200" height="675" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J_MZb7qTenE?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-US&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></span></p>
</div></figure>



<p>The video’s size is <code>1440x1080</code> pixels and so I had to resize it to <code>1920x1080</code> to match the size of my input video. </p>



<p>Here is the command to resize a video using FFmpeg using the the <code>scale</code> filter. I’ve stored the output video as <code>oldFilm1080.mp4</code>.</p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg -i old-film-grain.wmv \
-vf scale=1920:1080,setsar=1:1 \
oldFilm1080.mp4</code></pre>



<hr>



<h2>Step 4: Add the Overlay To Your Video</h2>



<p>Now we have two videos with us – </p>



<ol><li>our old-school film-grain-scratchy video</li><li>our vintage-looking, sped-up football video. </li></ol>



<p>Now all that’s left to do is to overlay them on each other and enjoy the fruits of <s>our</s> FFmpeg’s labor! </p>



<p>Here’s the commandline to achieve that. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe \
-i oldFilm1080.mp4 \
-i td-vintage-fast.mp4 \
-filter_complex "[0]format=rgba,colorchannelmixer=aa=0.25[fg];\
[1][fg]overlay[out]" \
-map [out] \
-pix_fmt yuv420p -c:v libx264 -crf 18 \
touchdown-vintage.mp4</code></pre>



<p>So, what’s going on here? </p>



<ul><li>we provide two input videos to FFmpeg </li><li>using <code>filter_complex</code>, we use <code>colorchannelmixer</code> to overlay by modifying the alpha channel of the film-grain video that is referred to as <code>[0]</code> and and let’s call the output <code>[fg]</code>. It’s black and white, so modifying only the alpha is good enough for our use case. The syntax is as follows <code>colorchannelmixer=rr:rg:rb:ra:gr:gg:gb:ga:br:bg:bb:ba:ar:ag:ab:aa</code>. </li><li>we are modifying only the alpha, and so, we modify only the <code>aa</code> (output’s alpha) to <code>0.25</code>.</li><li>then, we use the vintage-looking football video (referred to as <code>[1]</code>) and overlay them both using the <code>overlay</code> filter to create an interim output stored in a variable called <code>[out]</code>. This is shown in the commands –&gt; <code>[1][fg]overlay[out]</code></li><li>then, we encode the interim output to give us the final video using H.264 with <code>crf=18</code> which should give us a good quality video.</li></ul>







<p><strong>Here is what the final output looks like! Cool, isn’t it? </strong></p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479529512" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>







<p>And, here’s how it looks side-by-side the original video. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479529447" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>







<p>Now you can change the opacity of the alpha channels, use a different film grain video, or use a different <code>curves</code> function, but, the process won’t change much. </p>



<p>Hope you all have a lot of fun making “<strong>vintage</strong>” videos this holiday season and please let me know in the comments how it went! Please create some fun videos, share them with your loved ones, and have a few laughs 🙂 </p>



<p>Thank you! </p>



<p>If you enjoyed this post, do check out the rest of<a href="https://ottverse.com/category/ffmpeg/"> <strong>OTTVerse’s FFmpeg tutorials</strong></a> to learn more about how to use FFmpeg to improve your video editing, compression, and processing skills!</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25102401</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:33:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Moving my serverless project to Ruby on Rails]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 329 | Comments 170 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25100397">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://frantic.im/back-to-rails | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://frantic.im/back-to-rails">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <header>
    
    
  </header>
  <p>I have a small side project: <a href="https://hacker.gifts/">digital gift cards for hackers</a>. It uses Shopify for all the store-related stuff: frontend, payments, refunds, reports, etc.</p>

<p>But unlike regular digital products (ebooks, videos) I wanted each card that the user purchases from the store to be unique. So I made a  script that generates personalized images and ran it manually for every order.</p>

<p>The next logical step was automating this process. I started with serverless AWS Lambda. At the time it was the hot new tech and I wanted to learn more. It seemed very fitting for my use-case: single-responsibility functions that can run at any time and don’t require server maintenance.</p>

<p><img src="https://frantic.im/assets/back-to-rails/simple-lambda.png" alt=""></p>

<p>It was super easy to get started. I built a JavaScript function and deployed it to AWS Lambda, added Shopify web hook and it all worked!</p>

<p>Early benefits of serverless (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Easy to get started</li>
  <li>Don’t have to configure or maintain servers</li>
  <li>Free for small loads</li>
</ul>

<p>In reality, writing the simple Lambda functions turned out to be only 10% of the work.</p>

<p>Time passed and my backend started getting more complex: I needed to store some state for each <a href="https://hacker.gifts/products/space-invaders">puzzle</a>, send confirmation emails, show an order details page. What started as a simple function, grew into a bunch of serverless functions, SNS topics, S3 buckets, DynamoDB tables. All bound together with plenty of YAML glue, schema-less JSON objects passed around and random hardcoded configs in AWS console.</p>

<p>I think it’s just a typical software development lifecycle: things grow organically, become a mess, and require some refactoring. Make it run first (discover market fit), then make it right (refactor to integrate the new discoveries).</p>

<p>But this time it was different. I couldn’t refactor things as easily as I used to in traditional monolithic apps. Here’s why:</p>

<p>When the building blocks are too simple, the complexity moves into the interaction between the blocks.</p>

<p>And the interactions between the serverless blocks happen <em>outside</em> my application. A lambda publishes a message to SNS, another one picks it up and writes something to DynamoDB, the third one takes that new record and sends an email…</p>

<p>I could test every single block in that flow, but I didn’t have confidence in the overall process. What if publishing fails, how would I know that? How would system recover? Can I rollback and try again? Where do the logs go?</p>

<p>Another swarm of problems was hiding in my configuration: bad Route 53 record, typos in SNS topics, wrong S3 bucket region. Tracing errors was a challenge, there’s no single log output I can look into.</p>

<p>With serverless, I was no longer dealing with my project's domain, I was dealing with the distributed system's domain.</p>

<p>At this point I felt fooled.</p>

<p>I came for the easy way to deploy code and not think about servers, but in the end had to design my system around the platform’s limitations.</p>

<p>Drawbacks of serverless (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hard to follow information flow</li>
  <li>Impossible to replicate production environment locally</li>
  <li>Slow iteration speed</li>
  <li>Lack of end-to-end testing</li>
  <li>Immature documentation (dominated by often outdated Medium posts)</li>
  <li>No conventions (have to make hundreds of unessential decisions)</li>
</ul>

<p>—</p>

<p>I was clearly not enjoying the serverless. So I decided to rewrite it. After all, it is a side project I’m doing for fun. The tech stack of choice — Ruby on Rails.</p>

<p>I haven’t used Rails since 2013, and for the last 8 years at Facebook I’ve been mostly doing JavaScript.</p>

<p><img src="https://frantic.im/assets/back-to-rails/logo.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>The experience of picking Rails back up was really nice but… uneventful. Not much had really changed. A few things got added, a few small things moved around.</p>

<p>Of course I did <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/issues/38060">hit some magical Ruby issues</a>. But unlike my typical experience with JavaScript, I was quickly able to find the solution.</p>

<p>Rails comes with so many things built-in and configured. Over the years, without Rails, I used to gluing random JavaScript libraries together to roll my own routing, file storage wrappers, email preview pipeline, managing secrets, test setup with fixtures, database migrations, logging, performance reporting, deployment scripts. With Rails I didn’t have to think about all these details and could simply focus on making product-visible changes.</p>

<p>It was like driving a Tesla after years of making my own scrappy cars. Similar components, but all configured and aligned to work well together.</p>

<p>Benefits of Rails (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Conventions</li>
  <li>Tooling, libraries</li>
  <li>Documentation</li>
  <li>Monolith is easy to understand and test</li>
</ul>

<p>Drawbacks of Rails (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Feels heavyweight in the beginning</li>
  <li>Hurts if your opinions differ from Rails conventions</li>
  <li>Have to host on a server</li>
  <li>Doesn’t sound cool in 2020 (anymore and maybe yet)</li>
</ul>

<p>—</p>

<p>Serverless is like a black hole. It promised exciting adventures, but gravity sucked me in and I spent most of my efforts dealing with its complexity, instead of focusing on my product.</p>

  
  






  <div>
  <div>
    <p>Hi! My name is Alex. I’m a software engineer at Facebook, where I work on React&nbsp;Native, Oculus and Messenger. I love thinking about development experience.</p>
    <p>I write about programming, software design and side projects <a href="https://frantic.im/subscribe/" target="_blank"><svg viewBox="0 0 800 800"><path d="M493 652H392c0-134-111-244-244-244V307c189 0 345 156 345 345zm71 0c0-228-188-416-416-416V132c285 0 520 235 520 520z"></path><circle cx="219" cy="581" r="71"></circle></svg> Subscribe</a></p>
  </div>
</div>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://frantic.im/back-to-rails</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25100397</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 11:40:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Open Source does not mean “Includes Free Support”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 295 | Comments 247 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25099862">thread link</a>) | @alexellisuk
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
      We need to talk.
    </p><div>

<p>Here’s a paraphrased conversation I’m having way to often, costing me way too much time, keeping me from doing things that are way more important:</p>

<pre>User: Hi, I'd like to report a bug in your application.
Me:   Great! Please open a support ticket, then.
User: But, it looks like I need to pay for that?
Me:   So?
User: I just want to tell you that your app is broken, so you can fix it.
Me:   Yes, that's a support request, please open a ticket.
User: ...
</pre>

<figure>
  <a href="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/bugreport.png">
    <img src="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/bugreport.png">
  </a>
  
</figure><p>
                             
                             
From there it typically derails into a whiny tirade about me being a crappy two bit developer who doesn’t give a shit about his code (which is ridiculous, since, professional pride aside, I have every incentive to fix bugs, to prevent my inbox from getting flooded) and just wants to rip off his users.</p>

<p>In the past, I sometimes gave in (when it sounded like something might be wrong). I looked at the issue and almost always found that nothing was broken, just didn’t work as expected (which is actually to be expected for every reasonably complex piece of software). The user just didn’t bother reading the docs and tried to bypass the fee by masquerading the support request as a bug report. So, nowadays my policy simply is: no support ticket, no service. Any such request goes straight to the trash folder without even being looked at.</p>

<h2 id="why-am-i-such-an-asshole">Why am I such an asshole?</h2>

<p>Here’s the thing: I write open source software to solve <strong>my problem</strong>. I let you use my solutions because that comes at zero cost for me (well, almost, I still have to pay for the website, you are downloading from. You are welcome, by the way). I also provide the source code, so you can fix things yourself, should my solution turn out to be unsuitable. However, once you come to me with a “bugreport” that doesn’t also include a patch (or at least very precisely pinpoints the problem), then you are basically asking me to <strong>look at your problem</strong>. At this point, it is no longer zero cost for me and that’s the reason for why I am charging you money: you are asking me to spent time on your behalf. That is commonly called <strong>work</strong>. And surprisingly enough, work is what people expect to be paid for.</p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong. I’m happy to help. Selling support is what keeps the lights on here (did I mention the cost of running a webserver?). But coming to me under false pretense and/or expecting that I <strong>must</strong> provide free service on top of a software I gave away without charge is not going to win you any favours.</p>

<p>It stops being free, when it starts costing me! My time is valuable. If you want a piece of it, I want money in return. Period.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Seems like this post has struck a nerve and caused a few misunderstandings. <a href="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/reactions-bugreport-free-support/">Clarification on my position here</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25099862</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:12:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Ripped Out a £6k Lighting System]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 218 | Comments 286 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25099615">thread link</a>) | @iamflimflam1
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25099615</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 09:24:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On Taking Criticism]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25098585">thread link</a>) | @WoodenChair
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-4608430843265935994">
<p>I am what I would call a non-famous public person. What do I mean by that? I mean that I have jobs where people publicly review my work. As a college instructor, I receive student reviews. Some of them get read internally at our school, and some of them get posted publicy. And they’re attached to my name. They’re not some product where people might just know my company or my brand. They know <em>me</em>, and they’re reviewing <em>me</em>. As an author, my books get reviewed. Some of those reviews are by editors and official reviewers internal to the publisher. Some of those reviews are by email. But most of those reviews are posted online. As a software developer and hobbyist podcaster I also get public reviews.</p>

<p>To anyone in a personalized creative field who cares deeply about their work, bad reviews hurt. It’s not just about being sensitive (although I am sensitive and that doesn’t help). It’s that when you really pour your heart into something, as I do my teaching for example, then the product is an extension of you. Nobody would deny that the way a class or a book turns out is an extension of the personality, knowledge, and ability of the teacher/author. And when the product is criticized, it’s like you are being criticized. </p>

<p>My dad, who was also a college instructor, and the producer of nine books and nine instructional videos among many other public creative ventures, had a very thin skin. He couldn’t stand me reading him a bad review. That stuck with me. This very accomplished man, couldn’t stand even a little criticism. When I get too sensitive, I try to remember how his inability to accept criticism hurt some of his products. He was much more about getting things done than doing them perfectly. If he had a little bit more of a perfectionist streak in him, he would have done even better. But maybe he would have done less…</p>

<p>It doesn’t matter if I receive eighteen great reviews for a class. It’s the words of the two bad reviews that stick with me. And do you know why? <em>Because almost always there’s a kernel of truth to those reviews.</em> Does that mean we should listen to them? Well if I only listened to the bad reviews, I would never produce anything. I would just stay in bed. The fact is the people who are getting no bad reviews, are the people who are not taking the risk of putting themselves out there. So, we have to not let ourselves get so discouraged that we stop producing. And we have to remember that while we may not have served those two students well, we may have served those other eighteen students better than they would have been served in a world without us teaching them. </p>

<p>We can’t please every student or every customer. Nothing that gets watched/read by more than a few people is going to be liked by all of them. Even Mother Theresa would get a downvote on YouTube. So, if we’re serving the majority, we don’t want to let the critiques of a few steer us in the wrong direction.</p>

<p>On the other hand, being like my dad is dangerous too. <strong>No, the customer is not always right. But usually the customer has a point. We have to always be working to get better.</strong> Because we’re not perfect, and there’s always room for improvement. <strong>And we need to read those bad reviews to find those spaces for improvement.</strong> It doesn’t mean they’re right, but it does mean we need to think about them.</p>

<p>My dad accomplished an amazing amount. If he let those bad reviews slow him down too much, it’s very possible he would have not accomplished as much. But if he could have found a few tweaks, a few changes, to serve a few customers better, well then he could have grown through them. I want to grow, but I also don’t want to stop. So, I can’t let the reviews get me too down, but I have to read them.</p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25098585</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 05:39:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I teach vim]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 158 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25097788">thread link</a>) | @amichlin
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-124">

	

	
	<div>
		
<figure><a href="https://xkcd.com/378/"><img data-attachment-id="133" data-permalink="https://blog.ceos.io/real_programmers/" data-orig-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png" data-orig-size="740,406" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="real_programmers" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=740" src="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=740" alt="" srcset="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png 740w, https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=150 150w, https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"></a></figure>



<p>The why of why people use vim has been <a href="https://dev.to/iggredible/why-i-use-vim-2f40">covered fairly extensively</a>, so I thought I would spend a little time explaining why I <em>teach</em> vim to my high school students, even in 2020.</p>



<p>It all began when I was assigned a mixed class of ninth through twelfth grade students in computer science just after the financial collapse on 2008. Well, the financial collapse first brought me to teach Intro to Programming using VB 6.0 and Windows thin clients, which was an experience unto itself (thanks in part to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conficker">Conficker virus</a>). That experience is worth a separate blog post and is a good part of why one of my specialties is teaching computer security.</p>



<p>So here I am with all levels of student, including AP CS A (read: AP CS Java), and obsolete Windows PCs (at least the thin clients were gone). I couldn’t install any software, wanted to teach C, had to teach Java, and had very few options (these were the days before online web based IDEs).</p>



<p>I had experience with the UNIX command line, primarily Sun Workstations, thanks to my wonderful education at <a href="https://www.soe.ucsc.edu/departments/computer-science-and-engineering">UCSC</a>, so that wasn’t an issue. I had played with Linux in the 1990s to a bit of success, but hadn’t touched it for almost a decade. So I found an old Pentium 2 carcass in the the garbage outside my condo complex, installed a hard drive, and tried this new (to me) flavor of Linux called, strangely, <a href="https://ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu</a>.</p>



<p>I quickly realized this machine could have all the students coding at one, discovered the wonder that is <a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/latest.html">putty.exe</a> (it doesn’t require any installation to run!) to connect the obsolete PCs to the server and soon my students were off and coding.</p>



<p>Why did I teach them vim? I wish I could say I agonized over all the options at the time and decided vim was the best pedagogical solution, but the reality of the situation was that vi was what I used in college because my father taught me vi. You see, I am lucky to have a father who worked in the industry and is even somewhat of a <a href="https://www.bell-labs.com/usr/dmr/www/qed.html">footnote in text editor history</a>. So I taught vi (later vim) because it is what I knew. A running theme in many computer science teacher’s trials by fire… teaching something because it is what they know. I will go as far as to argue that it is more important that the teacher knows the editor, and especially the programming language, rather than assigning any importance to one correct editor or one correct language that all teachers should teach.</p>



<p>Years later, though, I still teach vim and the command line. So here is how I justify my decision, even if only to myself.</p>



<p>It just works. Every time I go to a new school, it takes time to get the software installed necessary to run IDEs. I remember walking into one school in which the AP CS A class was flailing away with Eclipse on Mac OS X because the students needed, and didn’t have, administrator access. I have an amazing tech department at my current job, but even here it took us weeks to figure out how to deploy Visual Studio Code on the student’s MacBook Airs and then we had to figure out how to deploy Python3 and Java. So there’s no confusion, I teach vim along with many IDEs and I fully believe it is my responsibility to teach multiple platforms and multiple IDEs, but the CLI and vim are always my safety net.</p>



<p>My students can program in any number of of languages on a now cloud based CLI Linux machine (thank you <a href="https://www.linode.com/">Linode</a> and <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> – both of whom offer a $5/month plan – just. happy customer!). By using the CLI, I can support literally any type of computer connecting (including iPads, although the lack of a virtual esc key drives me batty as a vim user, and <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/secure-shell-app/pnhechapfaindjhompbnflcldabbghjo?hl=en">ChromeBooks</a>). Students can connect from anywhere in the world and things just work. All of this became infinitely important in the remote and hybrid learning experience of the pandemic. And this is all possible because the students use vim.</p>



<p>I keep track of as many of my students that major in CS and a running theme is they all profusely thank me for teaching them vim and the CLI. Too many colleges start CS1 with an IDE and then throw the CS2 students into the deep end with the CLI. Not everyone is as lucky as I was in regards to having a father well versed in the CLI.</p>



<p>And yes, there are online IDEs these days, but I’ve found those to be full of their own pitfalls, privacy issues, and costs and find doing any advanced work using them to be very difficult if not impossible.</p>



<p>Also, to be clear, both nano and Emacs work quite well in the context of CLI Linux and I don’t make any claim that teachers should use vim over those equally acceptable command line text editors except for one small argument. Most people agree, computer security pretty much requires knowledge of the command line and a text editor. I always tell my students that the one editor they are likely to find already installed on a machine is vim and it is a bad day when you have to install another editor. Maybe just an issue for students interested in ethical penetration testing…</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25097788</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 02:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ask HN: Are you depressed?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 395 | Comments 461 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25096877">thread link</a>) | @pcbro141
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
        
    
      
    
<section>
    
        <span>Asked</span>
    
    <span>
        <abbr title="11 15 2020 00:09:57 UTC" data-epoch="1605398997">Nov 15, 2020</abbr>
    </span>
    <p>
        <span>IP Duplication Checking</span>
        
    </p>
</section>  
    
   

    


    
   

    
      
    

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25096877</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:12:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
