<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 08:31:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 08:31:12 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Review of Consensus Protocols]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 114 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24768971">thread link</a>) | @tcgv
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://thomasvilhena.com/2020/10/a-review-of-consensus-protocols | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thomasvilhena.com/2020/10/a-review-of-consensus-protocols">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>The consensus problem is a fundamental problem in multi-agent systems which requires a group of processes (or agents) to reliably and timely agree on a single data value. Although extensively discussed in the context of distributed computing it’s not exclusive to this field, also being present in our society in a variety of situations such as in democratic elections, the legislative process, jury trial proceedings, and so forth.</p>

<p>It’s solved through the employment of a consensus protocol governing how processes (agents) interact with one another. It may seem redundant but, to solve the consensus problem, first all processes agree to follow the same consensus protocol.</p>

<p>Some of these processes may fail or be unreliable in other ways (such as in a conflict of interest situation) so consensus protocols must be fault tolerant or resilient. The processes must somehow propose their candidate values, communicate with one another, and decide on a single consensus value.</p>

<p>In this post I review four major consensus protocols for solving the consensus problem based on my implementation of them, namely:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Chandra–Toueg</li>
  <li>Ben-Or</li>
  <li>Basic Paxos</li>
  <li>Nakamoto Consensus</li>
</ol>

<p>You can find supporting code for this analysis in this GitHub repository: <a href="https://github.com/TCGV/ConsensusKit">ConsensusKit</a></p>

<p>Before getting started let’s recap the three key properties of consensus protocols and take a quick look at relevant terminology for this discussion.</p>



<p>Formally a consensus protocol must satisfy the following three properties:</p>

<p><b>Termination</b></p>

<ul>
  <li>Eventually, every correct process decides some value.</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Integrity</b></p>

<ul>
  <li>If all the correct processes proposed the same value “v”, then any correct process must decide “v”.</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Agreement</b></p>

<ul>
  <li>Every correct process must agree on the same value.</li>
</ul>

<p>These requirements are rather straight forward. “Termination” certifies the protocol is resilient to halting failures. “Agreement” deters any two correct processes from deciding on different values which would break consensus. Lastly “Integrity”, which is in fact flexible and may vary depending on application requirements, assures the protocol behaves in an expected and unbiased way.</p>



<p>These terms are used throughout this post as well within the provided support source code.</p>

<h4>Protocol</h4>

<p>The official set of rules (“algorithm”) governing the behavior of processes for solving the consensus problem.</p>

<h4>Process</h4>

<p>An individual agent belonging to a larger group of agents collectively interested in reaching consensus. Processes can be “correct”, meaning they strictly adhere to the protocol and are not subject to failures, or “faulty”, meaning we cannot rely on them following the protocol at all times.</p>

<h4>Instance</h4>

<p>A well-defined round of interactions among processes under a consensus protocol. Depending on the underlying protocol one or multiple intances are required for reaching consensus.</p>

<h4>Proposer</h4>

<p>A process role. Processes under this role are entitled for proposing values. Any value agreed upon by all correct processes must have originated in a proposer.</p>

<h4>Decider</h4>

<p>A process role. Processes under this role are entitled for deciding on a value. Any value agreed upon by all correct processes must have been voted by at least one decider.</p>

<h4>Archiver</h4>

<p>An application or a subsystem that is responsible for persisting decided values and implementing a protocol’s specific data constraints.</p>

<h4>Failure detector</h4>

<p>An application or a subsystem that is responsible for the detection of node failures or crashes.</p>

<h4>Majority</h4>

<p>A protocol’s specific threshold requiring at least half of available votes, more when faulty processes are taken into account.</p>

<h4>Quorum</h4>

<p>A protocol’s specific threshold which ensures that a minimum number of participants (or votes) is met for taking an action.</p>

<p>With these definitions in place let’s move on to the implementation and review of each consensus protocol.</p>



<p>My main goal has been to implement these four protocols in code to be able to run and evaluate them in a controlled environment. I was also interested in trying to spot structural similarities among them that could be extracted into a common base structure, promoting code reuse.</p>

<p>The result of my first coding iteration is displayed in the simplified class diagram below:</p>

<p>
  <img src="https://thomasvilhena.com/images/p22/main-classes.PNG" alt="Main Clasees">
</p>

<p>Three main classes are depicted in the diagram:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The <b>Procotol</b> class has a collection of processes that will interact among each other according to the protocol rules for reaching consensus. Each execution of the protocol, through the <code>Execute</code> method, creates a new Instance (not to be confused with the conventional meaning of “instance” in object oriented programming).</li>
  <li>The <b>Instance</b> class represents one round of interactions among processes potentially resulting in a consensus, as indicated by the <code>Consensus</code> and <code>Value</code> properties. It’s responsible for managing the interaction between processes exercicing proposer and/or decider roles, providing methods for message delivery (<code>Send</code>) and retrieval (<code>WaitMessage</code> and <code>WaitQuorum</code>).</li>
  <li>The <b>Process</b> class is responsible for implementing proposer and/or decider roles. Behavior is defined in the <code>Bind</code> method just before the instance starts since, as well see, some protocols require processes to play different roles according the the current instance.</li>
</ul>

<p>The <code>Process.Propose</code> virtual method is called at the start of an instance execution for all proposer processes in that instance to kick off communication and has the following default implementation:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>
<span>protected</span> <span>virtual</span> <span>void</span> <span>Propose</span><span>(</span><span>Instance</span> <span>r</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>var</span> <span>v</span> <span>=</span> <span>Proposer</span><span>.</span><span>GetProposal</span><span>();</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>Archiver</span><span>.</span><span>CanCommit</span><span>(</span><span>v</span><span>))</span>
        <span>Broadcast</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Propose</span><span>,</span> <span>v</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It first generates a proposal based on the underlying proposer logic (ex: random boolean proposer), then verifies against an archiver if the generated value passes custom application requirements and finally broadcasts it to all sibling processes.</p>

<p>Processes that bind to the <code>Instance.WaitQuorum</code> event will wait for the protocol specific amount of messages (for each message type) required for taking an action. The specific amounts are defined in each protocol implementation when deriving the Instance class.</p>

<p>All four consensus protocols were implemented using this base structure, as presented in the following sections. Rather than performing an extensive code analysis I will focus on presenting each theoretical algorithm and key points of my implementation.</p>



<p>The Chandra–Toueg consensus algorithm was first published by Tushar Deepak Chandra and Sam Toueg in 1996 and introduced the concept of failure detectors as means for solving the consensus problem. The algorithm assumes a number of faulty processes denoted by <b>f</b> that’s less than <b>n/2</b> (i.e. less than simple majority).</p>

<p>In each instance one process acts as the decider (rotating coordinator) and all other processes act as proposers. The actions carried out in each instance are<sup>1</sup>:</p>

<ol>
  <li>All processes send (r, preference, timestamp) to the coordinator.</li>
  <li>The coordinator waits to receive messages from at least half of the processes (including itself).
    <ol>
      <li>It then chooses as its preference a value with the most recent timestamp among those sent.</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li>The coordinator sends (r, preference) to all processes.</li>
  <li>Each process waits (1) to receive (r, preference) from the coordinator, or (2) for its failure detector to identify the coordinator as crashed.
    <ol>
      <li>In the first case, it sets its own preference to the coordinator’s preference and responds with ack(r).</li>
      <li>In the second case, it sends nack(r) to the coordinator.</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li>The coordinator waits to receive ack(r) or nack(r) from a majority of processes.
    <ol>
      <li>If it receives ack(r) from a majority, it sends decide(preference) to all processes.</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li>Any process that receives decide(preference) for the first time relays decide(preference) to all processes, then decides preference and terminates.</li>
</ol>

<p>Let’s take a look at the code. The following code snippet defines the proposer process behavior:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>
<span>private</span> <span>void</span> <span>BindAsProposer</span><span>(</span><span>Instance</span> <span>r</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>WaitQuorum</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Select</span><span>,</span> <span>msgs</span> <span>=&gt;</span>
    <span>{</span>
        <span>var</span> <span>m</span> <span>=</span> <span>msgs</span><span>.</span><span>Single</span><span>();</span>
        <span>SendTo</span><span>(</span><span>m</span><span>.</span><span>Source</span><span>,</span> <span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Ack</span><span>,</span> <span>m</span><span>.</span><span>Value</span><span>);</span>
    <span>});</span>

    <span>WaitQuorum</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Decide</span><span>,</span> <span>msgs</span> <span>=&gt;</span>
    <span>{</span>
        <span>var</span> <span>v</span> <span>=</span> <span>msgs</span><span>.</span><span>Single</span><span>().</span><span>Value</span><span>;</span>
        <span>Terminate</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>v</span><span>);</span>
    <span>});</span>
<span>}</span>

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>On instance start proposers broadcast their values. Then they wait for a quorum to select a value from the pool of proposals. Since the protocol defines only a single decider per round this quorum is met when the decider process broadcasts his selection. Upon receiving this selection the proposer node will acknowledge it and wait for the decider’s decision, and then decide on the same value and terminate execution.</p>

<p>Now let’s see the code defining the complementary decider processes behavior:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>
<span>private</span> <span>void</span> <span>BindAsCoordinator</span><span>(</span><span>Instance</span> <span>r</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
    <span>WaitQuorum</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Propose</span><span>,</span> <span>msgs</span> <span>=&gt;</span>
    <span>{</span>
        <span>var</span> <span>v</span> <span>=</span> <span>PickMostRecentValue</span><span>(</span>
            <span>msgs</span><span>.</span><span>Where</span><span>(</span><span>m</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>Archiver</span><span>.</span><span>CanCommit</span><span>(</span><span>m</span><span>.</span><span>Value</span><span>))</span>
        <span>);</span>

        <span>Broadcast</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Select</span><span>,</span> <span>v</span><span>);</span>
    <span>});</span>

    <span>WaitQuorum</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Ack</span><span>,</span> <span>msgs</span> <span>=&gt;</span>
    <span>{</span>
        <span>var</span> <span>v</span> <span>=</span> <span>PickMostRecentValue</span><span>(</span><span>msgs</span><span>);</span>
        <span>Broadcast</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>MessageType</span><span>.</span><span>Decide</span><span>,</span> <span>v</span><span>);</span>
        <span>Terminate</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>,</span> <span>v</span><span>);</span>
    <span>});</span>
<span>}</span>

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It first waits for a quorum of proposals, i.e, for a simple majority of proposers to submit their values. Then the decider picks the most recent message value, possibly validating the value with the archiver, and broadcasts the selected value back to all processes.</p>

<p>After broadcasting the selected value the decider waits for a quorum of proposers to acknowledge it, in which case it decides on that value and broadcasts its decision to all processes before terminating.</p>

<p>Notice that this simplified implementation doesn’t take failures into account, even though the Chandra–Toueg protocol is fault-resilient.</p>



<p>Ben-Or is a decentralized consensus protocol, i.e., it doesn’t assign the decider role to any specific process. Curiously the algorithm correctness proof was only provided in a paper 15 years after its original publication<sup>2</sup>.</p>

<p>Because it lacks a decider for solving tie-break …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://thomasvilhena.com/2020/10/a-review-of-consensus-protocols">https://thomasvilhena.com/2020/10/a-review-of-consensus-protocols</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thomasvilhena.com/2020/10/a-review-of-consensus-protocols</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24768971</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 19:03:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Norway officially accuses Russia for cyberattacks on parliament]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 190 | Comments 104 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24768344">thread link</a>) | @lknik
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://www.regjeringen.no/en/aktuelt/datainnbruddet-i-stortinget/id2770135/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.regjeringen.no/en/aktuelt/datainnbruddet-i-stortinget/id2770135/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

        <header>
            

            

            



 
        </header>


<div>
    <p>
            <span>Press release |</span>
                    <span>Date: 13/10/2020</span>
            <span>
        | <a href="https://www.regjeringen.no/en/dep/ud/id833/">Ministry of Foreign Affairs</a>
    </span>

    </p>
    
    


</div>
        


            <p>
                    On 24 August, the Storting (Norwegian parliament) disclosed that its email systems had been hacked. ‘This is a very serious incident, affecting our most important democratic institution. The security and intelligence services are cooperating closely to deal with this matter at the national level. Based on the information the Government has, it is our view that Russia is responsible for these activities,’ said Minister of Foreign Affairs Ine Eriksen Søreide.
                </p>

        <div>

            



            
<p>The incident management is coordinated through the Norwegian Joint Cyber Coordination Centre.</p>
<p>This incident demonstrates the importance of good security measures. The increasing use of digital solutions means that the threats against us have also shifted to the digital arena. The Government will continue its efforts to strengthen national cyber security and expand international cooperation in this field.</p>
<p>Businesses, organisations, and private individuals must all participate in preventive security efforts if we are to prevent breaches of digital security. All types of organisations are advised to follow the recommendations of the Norwegian National Security Authority (NSM) regarding passwords and the basic guidelines for ICT security.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://nsm.no/home/">Read more about the NSM here.</a>&nbsp;</li>
</ul>





                        
            
        </div>


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.regjeringen.no/en/aktuelt/datainnbruddet-i-stortinget/id2770135/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24768344</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:21:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[SEO mistakes I've made and how I fixed them]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 283 | Comments 115 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24766682">thread link</a>) | @MaximeHeckel
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://blog.maximeheckel.com/posts/seo-mistakes-i-have-made-and-how-i-fixed-them/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.maximeheckel.com/posts/seo-mistakes-i-have-made-and-how-i-fixed-them/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>From 0 to 90k impressions in about a year, following <strong>S</strong>earch <strong>E</strong>ngine <strong>O</strong>ptimization good practices was key to help to grow my blog and my audience. However, when I started it, <strong>I made terrible mistakes</strong> that some SEO literate people could almost qualify as self-sabotage.</p><p>Thus, I want to dedicate this blog post <strong>to look back at 3 issues</strong> that caused me, and many others, countless headaches when dealing with SEO and Gatsby and <strong>the steps I took to fix them</strong>. I hope that this will help to fix some issues you might currently have on your awesome blog or portfolio without even being aware of them, kick-off your audience growth, and get discovered online 🚀.</p><section id="why-seo-is-so-important-section"><h2 id="why-seo-is-so-important"><a href="#why-seo-is-so-important" aria-label="why seo is so important permalink"><svg style="width:0px;height:0px"></svg></a>Why SEO is so important?</h2><p>You might know very little about what SEO does behind the scenes. To me, at least, it looked like an obscure, inconsistent, pseudo-science that only marketing people could understand (spoiler alert, it still kind of is).
However, after getting <a href="https://twitter.com/monicalent">@monicalent</a>'s awesome course <a href="https://bloggingfordevs.com/">bloggingfordevs</a>, it made the inner workings and good practices related to SEO a bit clearer to me. To quote her from her first newsletter</p><blockquote><p>SEO is a way of making sure that search engines can understand what your page is about, that it contains quality up-to-date information from an authoritative source, and will answer the question that the searcher had in mind.</p></blockquote><p>With good SEO, search engines can know what your content is about, discover all the blog posts you've written and, if you're lucky, catapult you to the top search result for a given set of keywords. Moreover, where <strong>sharing my newest articles on Twitter and Reddit would just cause a spike in traffic for a few days</strong>, <strong>SEO helps you get a more consistent traffic</strong> on your website, and for a longer time. The latter is what I was lacking for the longest time, despite having set up my Gatsby website and SEO component properly (or at least I thought so).</p><p>Gatsby's documentation has an incredibly well-written section on <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.com/tutorial/seo-and-social-sharing-cards-tutorial/">how to build an SEO component</a> to help you get started. However, that alone wasn't enough to make my blog discoverable early on, as you can see in the chart below representing the number of daily impressions I got since starting this blog:</p><figcaption>Chart representing the number of impressions per day of this blog on Google Search from August 2019 to the October 2020 (hover to see the data)</figcaption><p>For most of its first year, my blog was getting less than 50 daily impressions. <strong>Today</strong>, after fixing the issues I'm about to talk about, <strong>I get over 1000 daily impressions and it's still growing!</strong>
Of course, SEO is not the only component here, I also created more content this year and choose a better way to promote them, but it is still a significant driver to the growth you can see above.</p></section><section id="trailing-slashes-chaos-section"><h2 id="trailing-slashes-chaos"><a href="#trailing-slashes-chaos" aria-label="trailing slashes chaos permalink"><svg style="width:0px;height:0px"></svg></a>Trailing slashes chaos</h2><p>The blog you're reading this article on is built with Gatsby and hosted on Netlify. Sadly, using these two tools together without taking care of inconsistent trailing slash <code>/</code> at the end of your URLs can result in some undesirable outcomes.</p><p>One of these outcomes was that I was seeing a lot of <code>301</code> redirects logged in my analytics as readers were navigating to my articles. On my blog, a link to one of my blog posts would typically look like this: <code>/posts/learning-in-public</code> but when a reader clicked on it Netlify would append a trailing slash at the end of it thus redirecting the user.</p><p>That, my friends, is extremely bad for SEO. It impacted several unrelated areas of my website, such as:</p><ul><li><strong>Opengraph images or Twitter cards not being rendered consistently</strong>: readers would share a link sometimes with or without the trailing slash which would make it hard for some services to get the proper metadata and thus render a simple link instead of a proper preview card.</li><li><strong>Invalid URLs in sitemap</strong>: my sitemap is generated automatically at build time with a Gatsby plugin based on the URLs and pages of my website. Since I did not have trailing slashes at the end of my URLs it would generate my sitemap without them which once uploaded to Google Search Console would result in tons of warnings about invalid URLs since Google referenced the ones with the trailing slashes.</li></ul><section><h3 id="how-i-fixed-this"><a href="#how-i-fixed-this" aria-label="how i fixed this permalink"><svg style="width:0px;height:0px"></svg></a>How I fixed this</h3><p>I could have fixed this in two different ways:</p><ol><li>Disable the "Pretty URLs" option in Netlify's asset optimization settings. (see screenshot below)</li><li>Add a trailing slash to all my URLs on my blog.</li></ol><figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://blog.maximeheckel.com/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/cf0be/netlify-settings.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Image showcasing the asset optimizations options available in the Netlify project settings. Here you can see that I have the pretty URL option turned on which will add a trailing slash at the end of my URLs on this project." title="Image showcasing the asset optimizations options available in the Netlify project settings. Here you can see that I have the pretty URL option turned on which will add a trailing slash at the end of my URLs on this project." src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/a49ac35b34bbcb6cdb4c6c7231100040bfff6131/0ac3c/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/1cfc2/netlify-settings.png" srcset="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/6ecc8f818785e47dae754d6941f54b35e54483a0/2278b/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/3684f/netlify-settings.png 225w,https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/dfb54cd67b3f94f8b56b8cf33e5f62a5b5034aae/12f10/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/fc2a6/netlify-settings.png 450w,https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/a49ac35b34bbcb6cdb4c6c7231100040bfff6131/0ac3c/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/1cfc2/netlify-settings.png 900w,https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/f385f4210359f67c56540de380449c638338b608/b31c7/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/21482/netlify-settings.png 1350w,https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/d5b9f2320b291280ba1e429d1a0bb154e3b69bc5/ca35e/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/d61c2/netlify-settings.png 1800w,https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/2b7014b28c0153cfa30292e719454682f084965c/f77ac/static/5e9051d4443b042704a15079eaac2993/cf0be/netlify-settings.png 1994w" sizes="(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption>Image showcasing the asset optimizations options available in the Netlify project settings. Here you can see that I have the pretty URL option turned on which will add a trailing slash at the end of my URLs on this project.</figcaption>
  </figure><p>As Google already referenced my blog posts with a trailing slash, I decided to go with option number 2.</p><p>That change might look insignificant, but it resulted in a lot of weird issues suddenly disappearing. Additionally, it was essential for me to fix this before addressing the issue I'm just about to start talking about 😄!</p></section></section><section id="canonical-links-section"><h2 id="canonical-links"><a href="#canonical-links" aria-label="canonical links permalink"><svg style="width:0px;height:0px"></svg></a>Canonical links</h2><p>If you've been following me for a while, you might have started reading my content on <a href="https://medium.com/@MaximeHeckel">Medium</a>. I started blog.maximeheckel.com just about a year ago as of the time I'm writing these words. All the content on this site that dates back to before August 2019, was originally published on Medium.</p><p>On top of that, I did not edit the articles when migrating them to this website, nor did I delete the Medium ones. This resulted in <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/duplicate-content">duplicated content</a>, which meant that my newly deployed blog was in competition with Medium on the same keyword, the same content, from the same author when it comes to ranking on Google.</p><p>Thankfully there's a way to avoid this: <strong>setting canonical URLs</strong>. These URLs are placed in the <code>&lt;head&gt;</code> of your blog posts source code and designate that this post is the "original" post with that given content.</p><p>There are 2 steps to add valid canonical URLs to your website:</p><ol><li>You need to add them to the <code>&lt;head&gt;</code> of your post. For example: <code>&lt;link rel="canonical" href="https://blog.maximeheckel.com/posts/learning-in-public/" /&gt;</code></li><li>Head over to any third party platform you used in the past that has the content and add this canonical URL into the setting page of your post. I followed <a href="https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/360033930293-Set-a-canonical-link">this guide</a> on Medium to update my old blog post.</li></ol><p>Of course, you cannot do the first step until you've fixed any potential trailing slashes issues you may have like the ones I shared just above.</p><div><p>If like me you're a Gatsby user, you might be tempted to use <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.com/plugins/gatsby-plugin-canonical-urls/">gatsby-plugin-canonical-urls</a> which adds canonical URLs to your site's HTML pages at build time. </p><p><strong>I do not recommend this plugin</strong> for complex setups.</p><p>I tried it and it would consistently fail to put the proper URL, especially since my website as offline support it would sometimes write the offline fallback url in the <code>&lt;head/&gt;</code> of my HTML pages.
You'll be safer to add your canonical links programmatically in your own SEO component. See the code snippet below for an example. </p></div><div><div><p data-testid="codesnippet-title">Simplied version of the SEO component I built with support for canonical URLs</p></div><pre title="Simplied version of the SEO component I built with support for canonical URLs"><div data-testid="line"><p>1</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">import</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line"> graphql</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">StaticQuery</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">from</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">'gatsby'</span><span data-testid="content-line">;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>2</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line"></span><span data-testid="content-line">import</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">React</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">from</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">'react'</span><span data-testid="content-line">;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>3</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line"></span><span data-testid="content-line">import</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">Helmet</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">from</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">'react-helmet'</span><span data-testid="content-line">;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>13</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">        defaultDescription: description</span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>20</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line"></span><span data-testid="content-line">const</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">SEO</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">(</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line"> title</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"> desc</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"> image</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"> pathname</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"> date </span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line">)</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">=&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">(</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>36</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">        description</span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> desc </span><span data-testid="content-line">||</span><span data-testid="content-line"> defaultDescription</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>37</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">        image</span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">`</span><span data-testid="content-line">${</span><span data-testid="content-line">siteUrl</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line">${</span><span data-testid="content-line">image</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line">`</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>38</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">        date</span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> date </span><span data-testid="content-line">?</span><span data-testid="content-line"> date </span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">''</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>39</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">        title</span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> title </span><span data-testid="content-line">||</span><span data-testid="content-line"> defaultTitle</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>40</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">        url</span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">`</span><span data-testid="content-line">${</span><span data-testid="content-line">siteUrl</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">${</span><span data-testid="content-line">pathname </span><span data-testid="content-line">?</span><span data-testid="content-line"> `posts</span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">$</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">pathname</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line">` </span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">''</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line">`</span><span data-testid="content-line">,</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>44</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">        </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">Helmet</span><span data-testid="content-line"> title</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">title</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> defer</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">false</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>46</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"description"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">description</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>47</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"image"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">image</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="highlight-line"><p>48</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">link rel</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"canonical"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> href</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">url</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>49</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta property</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"og:url"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">url</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>50</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta property</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"og:type"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"article"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>53</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">            content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">keywords </span><span data-testid="content-line">&amp;&amp;</span><span data-testid="content-line"> keywords</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">length</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">0</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">?</span><span data-testid="content-line"> keywords</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">join</span><span data-testid="content-line">(</span><span data-testid="content-line">`</span><span data-testid="content-line">, </span><span data-testid="content-line">`</span><span data-testid="content-line">)</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">:</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">''</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>55</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta property</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"og:title"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">title</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>56</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta property</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"og:description"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">description</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>57</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta property</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"og:image"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">image</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>58</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"twitter:card"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"summary_large_image"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>59</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"twitter:creator"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">twitter</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>60</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"twitter:site"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">twitter</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>61</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"twitter:title"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">title</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>62</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"twitter:description"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">description</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div><div data-testid="line"><p>63</p><p><span><span data-testid="content-line">          </span><span data-testid="content-line">&lt;</span><span data-testid="content-line">meta name</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">"twitter:image"</span><span data-testid="content-line"> content</span><span data-testid="content-line">=</span><span data-testid="content-line">{</span><span data-testid="content-line">seo</span><span data-testid="content-line">.</span><span data-testid="content-line">image</span><span data-testid="content-line">}</span><span data-testid="content-line"> </span><span data-testid="content-line">/</span><span data-testid="content-line">&gt;</span><span data-testid="content-line"></span></span></p></div></pre></div></section><section id="server-side-rendering-and-missing-meta-tags-section"><p>In this part, we'll look at the one instance where Gatsby's server-side rendering mixed with my carelessness completely broke my SEO. By completely I mean all my custom SEO meta tags that I carefully put in my SEO component were gone from the server-side rendered version of the website making it almost invisible to any search engine.</p><section><h3 id="how-it-happened"><a href="#how-it-happened" aria-label="how it happened permalink"><svg style="width:0px;height:0px"></svg></a>How it happened</h3><p>This issue stemmed from what I would qualify as an <strong>interrupted static HTML build</strong>. </p><p>When building your Gatsby site the last steps of the build process involve building your production JS files and also generating the HTML for each page. If you're looking for more details you can check out <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/overview-of-the-gatsby-build-process/">this section of the Gatsby documentation about the build process</a>.</p><p>However, I wrote a <code>ThemeProvider</code> that wrapped the whole application. Thus any component or page can know which theme (dark or light) is currently enabled and the colors to use. This component was added to the <code>gatsby-ssr</code> and <code>gatsby-browser</code> files.</p><p>Under the hood, this <code>ThemeProvider</code> worked as follow:</p><ul><li>the state of the theme (dark or light) was injected via a React Provider to the whole app, that's how I can allow users to toggle between each theme.</li><li>that same state was also saved in the local storage to make sure revisiting the website would keep the previous theme enabled. When a reader loads this blog, the ThemeProvider will check for the presence of a specific variable in <code>localStorage</code> before setting the theme accordingly.</li></ul><p>I dedicated a blog post for this: <a href="https://blog.maximeheckel.com/posts/switching-off-the-lights-adding-dark-mode-to-your-react-app-with-context-and-hooks-f41da6e07269/">Switching off the lights - Adding dark mode to your React app</a>
and it actually contains the mistake that triggered the missing meta tags:</p><ul><li>Getting the variable set to the current theme from local storage was done in a React <code>useEffect</code>. Thus, …</li></ul></section></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.maximeheckel.com/posts/seo-mistakes-i-have-made-and-how-i-fixed-them/">https://blog.maximeheckel.com/posts/seo-mistakes-i-have-made-and-how-i-fixed-them/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.maximeheckel.com/posts/seo-mistakes-i-have-made-and-how-i-fixed-them/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24766682</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:45:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Virginia voter registration down on last day to register before election]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 80 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24766452">thread link</a>) | @gkop
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://www.wusa9.com/article/news/local/virginia/virginia-voter-registration-site-down-on-last-day-to-register-to-vote-officials-say/65-3e5b390b-3e47-4a22-a440-6afddf770f3a | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.wusa9.com/article/news/local/virginia/virginia-voter-registration-site-down-on-last-day-to-register-to-vote-officials-say/65-3e5b390b-3e47-4a22-a440-6afddf770f3a">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Officials say that a cut cable is to blame for the "temporary" system shutdown.</p><div>
                            <p>RICHMOND, Va. — A Virginia judge has granted a request to extend voter registration for 48 hours following technical issues that caused the commonwealth's voter registration portal to shut down for hours on Tuesday.</p>
                    <p>U.S. District Judge John A. Gibney, Jr. in Richmond gave the order Wednesday. The shutdown of the state’s website caused “a tremendous harm” to the people who want to register to vote, Gibney said.&nbsp;</p>
                        
                    <p>The deadline to register to vote is now 11:59 p.m. on Thursday Oct. 15. It includes both online and in-person registration.</p>
                    <p>“Today’s agreement to extend the voter registration deadline is a big win for democracy. Any eligible Virginian who was not able to register to vote yesterday can now do so,” said Attorney General Herring<strong>.&nbsp;</strong>“I have made it a top priority over the last several months to protect Virginians’ right to vote by making it as easy, safe and secure as possible, and this agreement is no different. I will continue to fight to make sure that every eligible Virginian can vote in this crucial election and that their vote will count.”</p>
                                <div>
                                    <blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">🚨BREAKING🚨 Judge says he will GRANT our request to extend voter registration deadline until 11:59pm on Thursday, October 15. Register to vote now!!</p>— Mark Herring (@MarkHerringVA) <a href="https://twitter.com/MarkHerringVA/status/1316369056019218432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 14, 2020</a></blockquote>

                                </div>
                    <p>An accidentally cut cable caused the entire Virginia voter registration system to go down for hours on the last day to register to vote before election day, according to the Virginia Information Technology Agency (VITA). Just before 3:30 p.m., the Virginia Department of Elections tweeted out that the <a href="https://vote.elections.virginia.gov/VoterInformation" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">registration portal</a> was back up and functioning properly.&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>Virginians are once again able to register to vote online with identification, or in-person at their voter registrar's offices.</p>
                    <p>VITA &nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/vaELECT/status/1316012911031017482?s=20" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">tweeted that a fiber cut</a> near Route 10 in Chester, Virginia was to blame for Tuesday's outage.&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>"Technicians learned that a Verizon fiber had been inadvertently struck as part of activities related to a Chesterfield County roadside utilities project, located off of Route 10 in Chester, Virginia," VITA said in a statement.&nbsp;</p>
                    <p>There was no time estimate given on when the problem would be fixed.</p>
                    <p>"Due to a network outage, the Citizen Portal is temporarily unavailable," the Virginia Department of Elections posted on their registration website Tuesday morning. "We are working with our network providers to restore service as quickly as possible."&nbsp;</p>
                                
                                <div>
                                    <blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thank you everyone for your patience! The citizen portal is back up, you can go to <a href="https://t.co/8vK06RBLHl">https://t.co/8vK06RBLHl</a> to register to vote, update information or check your registration status.</p>— VA Dept of Elections (@vaELECT) <a href="https://twitter.com/vaELECT/status/1316097971721773056?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2020</a></blockquote>

                                </div>
                    <p>Tuesday is the deadline to register to vote across Virginia, D.C. and Maryland.</p>
                    <div>
<p>You can check if you're already registered at <a href="https://vote.elections.virginia.gov/VoterInformation" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">vote.elections.virginia.gov</a>. You may register to vote at your local Division of Motor Vehicles (DMV) office or request an application <a href="https://vote.elections.virginia.gov/VoterInformation/PublicContactLookup" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">from your local general registrar</a>.</p>                                            </div>
                    <p>Additional information about registering to vote in Virginia <a href="https://www.elections.virginia.gov/registration/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">can be found here</a> or at your local registrar's website.</p>
                                <div>
                                    <blockquote><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Virginia election officials say *this* accidentally cut wire in Chesterfield County is likely why Virginia’s entire voter registration system is down...</p><p>On the final day to register to vote.<a href="https://twitter.com/wusa9?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WUSA9</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/CBSNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CBSNews</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/VOTE?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#VOTE</a> <a href="https://t.co/J7axn996jQ">https://t.co/J7axn996jQ</a></p></div>— Mike Valerio (@MikevWUSA) <a href="https://twitter.com/MikevWUSA/status/1316015529228865536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2020</a></blockquote>

                                </div>
                    <p>Northam said during his Tuesday afternoon coronavirus briefing how he does not appear to have the authority to extend the voter registration deadline, according to state code, and this would come from the courts. However, the governor expressed support for a court order to extend the deadline.</p>
                    <p>“I look forward to [the courts] assisting us and making sure we can extend the deadline,” Northam said.</p>
                                <div>
    <div data-module="video" data-stream="https://video.tegna-media.com/assets/WUSA/videos/c7a72fcc-3073-46d1-8e02-bcef97b72970/c7a72fcc-3073-46d1-8e02-bcef97b72970.m3u8" data-float="false" data-thumbnail="https://media.wusa9.com/assets/WUSA/images/157ee226-8fa6-4eab-bf92-e2e453f6631e/157ee226-8fa6-4eab-bf92-e2e453f6631e_1920x1080.jpg" data-title="Gov. Northam speaks about voter registration deadline in Virginia" data-description="Northam said during his Tuesday briefing how he does not appear to have the authority to extend the voter registration deadline, according to state code." data-site="65" data-id="c7a72fcc-3073-46d1-8e02-bcef97b72970" data-dfpposition="" data-mute="false" data-autoplay="false" data-link="https://www.wusa9.com/video/news/local/virginia/virginia-voter-registration-deadline/65-c7a72fcc-3073-46d1-8e02-bcef97b72970" data-origin="clipping" data-section="news" data-subsection="local" data-topic="virginia" data-subtopic="" data-captions="" data-related-playlist-id="tSIkxFyA" data-related-media-id="RRI79RaE" data-use-trending="true" data-ugc-preroll-disabled="false" data-duration="46" data-disable-preroll-at-duration="0">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p><img data-asset-fallback="default" src="https://media.wusa9.com/assets/WUSA/images/157ee226-8fa6-4eab-bf92-e2e453f6631e/157ee226-8fa6-4eab-bf92-e2e453f6631e_1920x1080.jpg"></p>
                        
                    </div>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
                            
        </div>
                                </div>
                    <p>Virginia Secretary of Administration Keyanna Conner mentioned during Tuesday's coronavirus briefing that she hopes services will be re-instated this afternoon.</p>
                    <p>“We hope to have a temporary solution in place by 4 p.m. that will bring our services back online," Conner said.</p>
                                <div>
                                    <blockquote><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>NEW &gt;&gt; Virginia voter registration system is DOWN for the entire state... on the final day to register.</p><p>Officials feared this would happen.</p><p>They told us over the system, called VERIS, is still “insufficiently reliable”<br>STORY:<a href="https://twitter.com/wusa9?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@WUSA9</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EarlyVoting?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#EarlyVoting</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/CBSNews?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CBSNews</a><a href="https://t.co/kCop0GhmQG">https://t.co/kCop0GhmQG</a></p></div>— Mike Valerio (@MikevWUSA) <a href="https://twitter.com/MikevWUSA/status/1316009339463835648?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2020</a></blockquote>

                                </div>
                    <p>Lt. Governor Justin Fairfax wrote on Twitter calling for Virginia's voter registration deadline to be extended given the statewide outage.</p>
                    <p>"I am officially calling for Virginia's Registration Deadline to be extended beyond today due to the service outages impacting voters' ability to register statewide," Fairfax said. "We will work with the Administration to resolve this issue and ensure all voters have access to vote."</p>
                                <div>
                                    <blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">VA <a href="https://twitter.com/LGJustinFairfax?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@LGJustinFairfax</a> calls for Virginia's voter registration deadline to be extended after the statewide system is down <a href="https://t.co/roHCtgZteh">https://t.co/roHCtgZteh</a></p>— Laura Geller TV (@LauraGellerTV) <a href="https://twitter.com/LauraGellerTV/status/1316025155999551489?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2020</a></blockquote>

                                </div>
                    <p>If you've already received your mail-in ballot, your ballot must be postmarked by Nov. 3 and must be received to the Virginia Board of Elections by Nov. 6 at noon.</p>
                    <p>Before mailing your ballot in, make sure that you've signed everywhere that needs to be signed. If not, your ballot could be thrown out. This includes the voter's oath or your return envelope, and anything pertaining to your witness requirements. &nbsp;</p>
                    
                                
                    
                    
                    
                                <div>
    <div data-module="video" data-stream="https://video.tegna-media.com/assets/WUSA/videos/6b5dcfb4-3870-4615-acc9-74ab309bf1f9/6b5dcfb4-3870-4615-acc9-74ab309bf1f9.m3u8" data-float="false" data-thumbnail="https://media.wusa9.com/assets/WUSA/images/5803acd9-ce44-4112-8a65-1e23bde50b15/5803acd9-ce44-4112-8a65-1e23bde50b15_1920x1080.jpg" data-title="Officials fear parts of Virginia election system labeled 'unreliable' in 2018 may slow or crash on Election Day" data-description="Virginia’s election commissioner expressed full confidence in the critical computer system, known as VERIS. It is slated to be replaced in July 2022, documents show." data-site="65" data-id="6b5dcfb4-3870-4615-acc9-74ab309bf1f9" data-dfpposition="" data-mute="false" data-autoplay="false" data-link="https://www.wusa9.com/video/news/local/virginia/virginia-election-system-labeled-unreliable-in-2018-election-day/65-6b5dcfb4-3870-4615-acc9-74ab309bf1f9" data-origin="clipping" data-section="news" data-subsection="local" data-topic="virginia" data-subtopic="" data-captions="" data-related-playlist-id="tSIkxFyA" data-related-media-id="rHOsaz7J" data-use-trending="true" data-ugc-preroll-disabled="false" data-duration="236" data-disable-preroll-at-duration="0">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <p><img data-asset-fallback="default" src="https://media.wusa9.com/assets/WUSA/images/5803acd9-ce44-4112-8a65-1e23bde50b15/5803acd9-ce44-4112-8a65-1e23bde50b15_1920x1080.jpg"></p>
                        
                    </div>
                    
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
                            
        </div>
                                </div>
                    
                    
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.wusa9.com/article/news/local/virginia/virginia-voter-registration-site-down-on-last-day-to-register-to-vote-officials-say/65-3e5b390b-3e47-4a22-a440-6afddf770f3a</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24766452</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:22:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Plug’nPwn – Connect to Jailbreak]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 165 | Comments 62 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24765461">thread link</a>) | @clashmeifyoucan
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://blog.t8012.dev/plug-n-pwn/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.t8012.dev/plug-n-pwn/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
<div>
<article>

<figure>
<img srcset="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w300/2020/10/T2-PortOpen.jpeg 300w,
                            https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/T2-PortOpen.jpeg 600w,
                            https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/T2-PortOpen.jpeg 1000w,
                            https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w2000/2020/10/T2-PortOpen.jpeg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w2000/2020/10/T2-PortOpen.jpeg" alt="Plug'nPwn - Connect to Jailbreak">
</figure>
<section>
<div>
<p>For those just joining us, news broke last week about the jailbreaking of <a href="https://www.apple.com/euro/mac/shared/docs/Apple_T2_Security_Chip_Overview.pdf" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Apple’s T2 security processor in recent Macs</a>. If you haven't read it yet, <a href="https://blog.t8012.dev/on-bridgeos-t2-research/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">you can catch up on the story here</a>, and try this out yourself at home <a href="https://checkra.in/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">using the latest build of checkra1n</a>. So far we’ve stated that you must put the computer into DFU before you can run checkra1n to jailbreak the T2 and that remains true, however today we are introducing a demo of replacing a target Mac's EFI and releasing details on the T2 debug interface.</p><p>In order to build their products unlike app developers Apple has to debug the core operating system. This is how firmware, the kernel and the debugger itself are built and debugged. From the earliest days of the iPod, Apple has built specialized debug probes for building their products. <a href="https://bgr.com/2019/03/08/iphone-hack-what-dev-fused-iphones-are-and-why-theyre-important/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">These devices are leaked</a> from Apple headquarters and their factories and have traditionally had monkey related names such as the “<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Kong_Cable" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Kong</a>”, “<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Kanzi_Cable" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Kanzi</a>” and “<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Chimp_Cable" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Chimp</a>”. They work by allowing access to special debug pins of the CPU, (which for <a href="https://developer.arm.com/architectures/cpu-architecture/debug-visibility-and-trace/coresight-architecture/serial-wire-debug" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">ARM devices is called Serial Wire Debug</a> or SWD), as well as other chips via JTAG and UART. <a href="https://blog.senr.io/blog/jtag-explained" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">JTAG is a powerful protocol</a> allowing direct access to the components of a device and access generally provides the ability to circumvent most security measures. Apple has even spoken about their debug capabilities <a href="https://www.blackhat.com/docs/us-16/materials/us-16-Krstic.pdf" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">in a BlackHat talk</a> describing the security measures in effect. Apple has <a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/05/31/internal-usb-c-diagnostic-tool/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">even deployed versions of these</a> to their retail locations allowing for repair of their iPads and Macs.</p><h2 id="the-bonobo-in-the-myst">The Bonobo in the Myst</h2><p>Another hardware hacker and security researcher <a href="http://ramtin-amin.fr/#tristar" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">Ramtin Amin did work last year</a> to create an effective <a href="https://shop.lambdaconcept.com/home/37-bonobo-debug-cable.html" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">clone of the Kanzi cable</a>. This combined with the checkm8 vulnerability from <a href="https://twitter.com/axi0mX" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">axi0mX</a> allows iPhones 5s - X to be debugged. </p><p>One of the interesting questions is how does the Macs <a href="https://support.apple.com/guide/apple-configurator-2/revive-or-restore-mac-firmware-apdebea5be51/mac" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">share a USB port </a>with both the Intel CPU (macOS) and the T2 (bridgeOS) for DFU. &nbsp;These are essentially separate computers inside of the case sharing the same pins. &nbsp;Schematics of the MacBook leaked from Apple’s vendors (a quick search with a part number and “schematic”), and analysis of the USB-C firmware update payload show that there is a component on each port which is tasked with both multiplexing (allowing the port to be shared) as well as terminating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USB_hardware#PD" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">USB power delivery (USB-PD)</a> for the charging of the MacBook or connected devices. &nbsp;Further analysis shows that this port is shared between the following:<br></p><ul><li>The Thunderbolt controller which allows the port to be used by macOS as Thunderbolt, USB3 or DisplayPort</li><li>The T2 USB host for DFU recovery</li><li>Various UART serial lines</li><li>The debug pins of the T2</li><li>The debug pins of the Intel CPU for debugging EFI and the kernel of macOS</li></ul><p><br>Like the above documentation related to the iPhone, the debug lanes of a Mac are only available if enabled via the T2. &nbsp;Prior to the checkm8 bug this required a specially signed payload from Apple, meaning that Apple has a <a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/2/17/11031902/apple-encryption-fbi-san-bernardino-backdoor" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">skeleton key to debug any device</a> including production machines. &nbsp;Thanks to checkm8, any T2 can be demoted, and the debug functionality can be enabled. &nbsp;Unfortunately Intel has placed large amounts of <a href="https://thunderbolttechnology.net/developer-application">information about the Thunderbolt controllers</a> and <strong>protocol under NDA</strong>, meaning that it has not been properly researched leading to a <a href="https://www.kaspersky.com/blog/thunderstrike-mac-osx-bootkit/7164/" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">string</a> of <a href="https://www.trendmicro.com/vinfo/tr/security/news/vulnerabilities-and-exploits/thunderstrike-2-rootkit-can-now-infect-macs-remotely" rel="noreferrer nofollow noopener">vulnerabilities</a> over the years.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/2020/10/USB_Type-C_Receptacle_Pinout.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/USB_Type-C_Receptacle_Pinout.png 600w, https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/USB_Type-C_Receptacle_Pinout.png 1000w, https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/size/w1600/2020/10/USB_Type-C_Receptacle_Pinout.png 1600w, https://blog.t8012.dev/content/images/2020/10/USB_Type-C_Receptacle_Pinout.png 2292w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Given that the USB-C port on the Mac does many things, it is necessary to indicate to the multiplexer what device inside the Mac you’d like to connect too. &nbsp;The USB-C port specification provides pins for this exact purpose (CC1/CC2) as well as detecting the orientation of the cable allowing for it to be reversible. &nbsp;On top of the CC pins runs another low speed protocol called USB-PD or USB power delivery. &nbsp;It is primarily used to negotiate power requirements between chargers(sources) and devices (sinks). &nbsp;USB-PD also allows for arbitrary packets of information in what are called “Vendor Defined Messages” or VDMs.</p><h2 id="apple-s-usb-pd-extensions">Apple’s USB-PD Extensions</h2><p>The VDM allows Apple to trigger actions and specify the target of a USB-C connection. &nbsp;We have discovered USB-PD payloads that <strong>cause the T2 to be rebooted and for the T2 to be held into a DFU state</strong>. &nbsp;Putting these two actions together, we can cause the T2 to restart ready to be jailbroken by checkra1n without any user interaction. &nbsp;While we haven’t tested a Apple Serial Number Reader, we suspect it works in a similar fashion, allowing the devices ECID and Serial Number to be read from the T2’s DFU reliably. &nbsp;The Mac also speaks USB-PD to other devices, such as when an iPad Pro is connected in DFU mode. &nbsp;<br><strong>Apple needs to document the entire set of VDM messages</strong> used in their products so that consumers can understand the security risks. &nbsp;The set of commands we issue are unauthenticated, and even if they were they were undocumented and thus un-reviewed. &nbsp;<strong>Apple could have prevented this scenario</strong> by requiring that some physical attestation occurs during these VDMs such as holding down the power button at the same time.</p><p>Taking all this information into account, we can string it together to reflect a real world attack. &nbsp;By creating a specialized device <strong>about the size of a power charger</strong>, we can place a T2 into DFU mode, run checkra1n, replace the EFI and upload a key logger to capture all keys. &nbsp;This is possible even though macOS is un-altered (the logo at boot is for effect but need not be done). &nbsp;This is because in Mac portables <strong>the keyboard is directly connected to the T2</strong> and passed through to macOS.</p><p>PlugNPwn is the entry into DFU directly from connecting a cable to the DFU port (if it doesn't show, it may be your AdBlock: <a href="https://youtu.be/LRoTr0HQP1U">https://youtu.be/LRoTr0HQP1U</a>)</p><figure><iframe width="612" height="344" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LRoTr0HQP1U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><figcaption>PlugN'Pwn Automatic Jailbreak</figcaption></figure><p>In the next video we use <code>checkra1n</code> to modify the <code>MacEFI</code> payload for the Intel processor (again, AdBlock may cause it not to show <a href="https://youtu.be/uDSPlpEP-T0">https://youtu.be/uDSPlpEP-T0</a>)</p><figure><iframe width="612" height="344" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uDSPlpEP-T0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><figcaption>Replacing the T2 MacEFI with SecureBoot on</figcaption></figure><p>In order to facilitate further research on the topic of USB-PD security, and to allow users at home to perform similar experiments we are pleased to announce pre-ordereing of our USB-PD screamer. &nbsp;It allows a computer to directly "speak" USB-PD to a target device. &nbsp;Get more info here:</p><figure>


</figure>
</div>
</section>
</article>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.t8012.dev/plug-n-pwn/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24765461</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 13:41:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[14,000x Speedup (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 406 | Comments 223 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24764605">thread link</a>) | @signa11
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | http://james.hiebert.name/blog/work/2015/09/14/CS-FTW.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://james.hiebert.name/blog/work/2015/09/14/CS-FTW.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>In my job as a scientific software developer, I tend to write a lot of code. And most people who haven’t been through a Computer Science degree tend to think that CS is “just” about slinging code at the screen and then running it. I have a good working relationship with many of my colleagues and co-workers with other backgrounds… Physics, Climate Science, Biology, etc. But when it comes to developing software, I get the distinct impression that people think, “Hey, how hard could this be?! We just write down a few instructions about what we want the computer to do, hit the execute button and the, ‘Blamo!’, we get our answer!”</p>

<p>The problem with that line of thinking is that it’s incredibly easy to write instructions that don’t mean what you think they mean. For example, your program could be completely uninterpretable by the computer. Furthermore, there is literally <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halting_problem">no way to tell whether your program will ever actually terminate</a> without actually executing it. And there are many, many, <em>many</em>, ways to write a program which make it “slow” to execute. “Slow” being… like <em>really</em> slow. Like it would take your entire lifetime or more to actually execute it. This final problem is one that I see most often when reading software written by people without a CS education. And fixing that is my job.</p>

<p>The thing about CS that people don’t realize is that it teaches you about the theory of computation, computability (i.e. can we actually compute something? We often take for granted that we can!), algorithm complexity, and all of the knowledge, logic and analysis techniques and help you compose a program that will run in the minimum amount of time or using the minimum amount of space.</p>

<p>Allow me to show you an example of a huge optimization that I made to a simple script written by a colleague.</p>

<p>In climate science we do a lot of downscaling. We take temperature and precipitation readings from a coarse scale Global Climate Model grid and map them to a fine scale local grid. Let’s say the global grid is 50x25 and the local grid is 1000x500. For each grid cell in the local grid, we want to know to which grid cell in the global grid it corresponds.</p>

<p>A simple way to think about this is that we want to minimize the distance between L[n] and G[n]. So a simple way to do the search would be:</p>

<pre><code>for each Local cell L[i]:
  for each Global cell G[j]:
     compute distance between L[i] and G[j]
  find the minimum distance in the set L[i] * G
  return the index of the minimum
</code></pre>

<p>It seems simple enough. However, if you look closely, you’ll notice that you have to do a <em>lot</em> of extra work. Look at the algorithm in terms of the size of the input.</p>

<pre><code>for each Local cell L[i]:                        # Do this L times
  for each Global cell G[j]:                     # Do this L x G times
     compute distance (d) between L[i] and G[j]  # Do this L x G times
  find the minimum distance in the set d[i*j]    # Read G cells L times (cost L x G)
  find the index whose cell matches the minimum  # Read G cells L times (cost L x G)
</code></pre>

<p>The code for this looked something like this:</p>

<pre><code>obs.lon &lt;- ncvar_get(nc.obs, 'lon')
obs.lat &lt;- ncvar_get(nc.obs, 'lat')
n.lon &lt;- length(obs.lon)
n.lat &lt;- length(obs.lat)

obs.lats &lt;- matrix(obs.lat, nrow=n.lon, ncol=n.lat, byrow=TRUE)
obs.lons &lt;- matrix(obs.lon, nrow=n.lon, ncol=n.lat)
obs.time &lt;- netcdf.calendar(nc.obs)

gcm.lon &lt;- ncvar_get(nc.gcm, 'lon')-360
gcm.lat &lt;- ncvar_get(nc.gcm, 'lat')
gcm.lats &lt;- matrix(gcm.lat, ncol=length(gcm.lat), nrow=length(gcm.lon),
                   byrow=TRUE)
gcm.lons &lt;- matrix(gcm.lon, ncol=length(gcm.lat), nrow=length(gcm.lon))
gcm.lons.lats &lt;- cbind(c(gcm.lons), c(gcm.lats))

# Figure out which GCM grid boxes are associated with each fine-scale grid point
# Confine search to 10 deg. x 10 deg. neighbourhood

dxy &lt;- 10
mdist &lt;- function(x, y)
    apply(abs(sweep(data.matrix(y), 2, data.matrix(x), '-')), 1, sum)
nn &lt;- list()
for (i in seq_along(obs.lons)) {
    if((i %% 500)==0) cat(i, '')
    gcm.lims &lt;- ((gcm.lons.lats[,1] &gt;= (obs.lons[i]-dxy)) &amp;
                 (gcm.lons.lats[,1] &lt;= (obs.lons[i]+dxy))) &amp;
                ((gcm.lons.lats[,2] &gt;= (obs.lats[i]-dxy)) &amp;
                 (gcm.lons.lats[,2] &lt;= (obs.lats[i]+dxy)))
    gcm.lims &lt;- which(gcm.lims)
    nn.min &lt;- which.min(mdist(c(obs.lons[i], obs.lats[i]),
                        gcm.lons.lats[gcm.lims,]))
    nn[[i]] &lt;- gcm.lims[nn.min]
}
nn &lt;- unlist(nn)
</code></pre>

<p>So, it seems like a simple algorithm. “Just” compute the distances and then find the minimum. But the way it was written, as the size of the number of local cells grows, our cost of computation grows by its product with the number of global grid cells. For Canadian ANUSPLIN data, there are 1068 x 510 cells (for a total of 544,680) and let’s say that our GCM has 50 x 25 cells (for a total of 1,250 cells). So the cost of the inner loop in “some computational unit” is:</p>



<p>where the  terms are constants that correspond to the cost of computing a distance between two points, finding the minimum point, and finding an array index. Really, we don’t care (much) about the constant terms, because they are not affected by the size of the input. So we can just clump them together and call the cost;</p>



<p>So for this set of input, our cost is </p>

<p>680 million.</p>

<p>That <em>seems</em> like a lot, but is it? Computers are fast, right? If we run the naive implementation that’s something like this:</p>

<p>it ends up taking 1668 seconds which is a little less than half an hour.</p>

<pre><code>&gt; source('BCCA/naive.implementation.R')
500 1000 1500 2000 2500 3000 ... 543000 543500 544000 544500 [1] "Elapsed Time"
    user   system  elapsed 
1668.868    8.926 1681.728 
</code></pre>

<p>But do we <em>need</em> for it to take 30 minutes? Here’s the thing. We’re comparing two grids together, both of which have tons of structure that we haven’t taken advantage of. For example the latitudes and longitudes in both the coarse and the fine grid are in sorted order. So if you want to search for a number, you don’t have to look at every single number. You can use a bisect algorithm where you look at the point in the middle and then decide which half of the array you want to search. Then searching the full space only costs you the log (base 2) of the search space.</p>

<p>The other major structure that we haven’t taken advantage of is the fact that the latitudes repeat themselves in the  dimension and the longitudes repeat themselves in the  dimension. So instead of doing an operation  times, we can do it  times. That’s a <em>huge</em> optimization.</p>

<p>What does that look like in pseudo-code?</p>

<pre><code>For each local[x]:
    bisect_search(local[x], Global[x])

For each local[y]:
    bisect_search(local[y], Global[y])

return a 2d grid of the search results for each dimension
</code></pre>

<p>In code:</p>

<pre><code>## Perform a binary search on the *sorted* vector v
## Return the array index of the element closest to x
find.nearest &lt;- function(x, v) {
    if (length(v) == 1) {
        return(1)
    }
    if (length(v) == 2) {
        return(which.min(abs(v - x)))
    }
    mid &lt;- ceiling(length(v) / 2)
    if (x == v[mid]) {
        return(mid)
    } else if (x &lt; v[mid]) {
        return(find.nearest(x, v[1:mid]))
    }
    else {
        return((mid - 1) + find.nearest(x, v[mid:length(v)]))
    }
}

regrid.one.dim &lt;- function(coarse.points, fine.points) {
    return(sapply(fine.points, find.nearest, coarse.points))
}

## Take a fine scale (e.g. ANUSPLINE) grid of latitudes and longitudes
## and find the indicies that correspond to a coarse scale (e.g. a GCM) grid
## Since the search is essentially a minimizing distance in 2 dimensions
## We can actually search independently in each dimensions separately (which
## is a huge optimization, making the run time x + y instead of x * y) and
## then reconstruct the indices to create a full grid
regrid.coarse.to.fine &lt;- function(coarse.lats, coarse.lons, fine.lats, fine.lons) {
    xi &lt;- regrid.one.dim(gcm.lon, obs.lon)
    yi &lt;- regrid.one.dim(gcm.lat, obs.lat)
    ## Two dimensional grid of indices
    xi &lt;- matrix(xi, ncol=length(fine.lats), nrow=length(fine.lons), byrow=F)
    yi &lt;- matrix(yi, ncol=length(fine.lats), nrow=length(fine.lons), byrow=T)
    return(list(xi=xi, yi=yi))
}

</code></pre>

<p>The cost for every bisection search is the log of the input size. Our input size is divided into X and Y space this time, so we’ll use , and  for Global, Local, X and Y.</p>



<p>Plugging in our numbers this gives us a cost estimate of 553,076. 553 thousand sounds a lot better than 680 million. Do we see that in the run time?</p>

<pre><code>&gt; ptm &lt;- proc.time(); rv &lt;- regrid.coarse.to.fine(gcm.lat, gcm.lon, obs.lat, obs.lon); print('Elapsed Time'); print(proc.time() - ptm)[1] "Elapsed Time"
   user  system elapsed 
  0.117   0.000   0.117 
&gt; str(rv)
List of 2
 $ xi: num [1:1068, 1:510] 15 15 15 15 15 15 15 15 15 15 ...
 $ yi: num [1:1068, 1:510] 13 13 13 13 13 13 13 13 13 13 ...
&gt; 
</code></pre>

<p>0.117 seconds. What took us almost half an hour before, now takes us a little over  of a second.</p>

<pre><code>&gt; 1668.868 / .117
[1] 14263.83
</code></pre>

<p>Soooooo… I know that I’m trained to do this kind of work and it’s my job to know how to do these types of things. But even <em>I’m</em> surprised and self-impressed at how significant that speedup is. That’s a <em>14 thousand times</em> speedup.</p>

<p>This script used to take so long that it had to save its output to disk and be manually checked by a scientist before proceeding. Now you can compute it in the blink of an eye. This is a computation that we have to do hundreds of times, and this saves us days to weeks of computation time. And it increases the ability to interact with the system, helping us to get more value out of our scientists’ time… they’re not sitting around waiting for a computation to finish. It just does it.</p>

<p>I should emphasize that these epic performance improvements come without buying any larger computer systems, no parallelization or increase in complexity… in fact the code for the faster algorithm is actually simpler and more reusable! It’s pretty much an all around win, just by reading the code and having …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://james.hiebert.name/blog/work/2015/09/14/CS-FTW.html">http://james.hiebert.name/blog/work/2015/09/14/CS-FTW.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://james.hiebert.name/blog/work/2015/09/14/CS-FTW.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24764605</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 11:49:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Low-Level Academy, an explorable systems programming course]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 346 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24764589">thread link</a>) | @nbaksalyar
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://lowlvl.org/tcp-ip-fundamentals/exchanging-messages | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lowlvl.org/tcp-ip-fundamentals/exchanging-messages">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="__next"><div><div id="content-container"><div id="headbar"><div id="logo-block"><a href="https://lowlvl.org/"><img id="sign" src="https://lowlvl.org/images/animation_1.svg" alt="Low-Level Academy"></a></div></div><div><div><p>When you opened this page in your web browser, your computer exchanged data with quite a few servers on the internet,
almost unnoticeably to you. In this lesson, we’ll build a network client application, which does something similar to
your browser in this situation.</p><p>It all starts with an <em>address</em>: you want to send a message to your friend Alice, but your computer needs to know
<em>where</em> these messages should be sent for the message to be delivered to the right computer—just like you need to
provide a recipient address when you send an email.</p><p>We are used to one kind of address system: <em>domain names</em>, like <code>lowlvl.org</code> or <code>duckduckgo.com</code>. However, these
addresses are intended to be used by human beings; machines use another addressing system.
Internet protocol (or <em>IP</em>) addresses look like <code>192.168.0.1</code>. In order to find out which IP address we should use
for a domain name like <code>lowlvl.org</code>, we ask a <em>name server</em>, a computer with a well-known IP address like
<code>1.2.3.4</code>. A name server understands DNS, or the domain name service <em>protocol</em>. Protocols are languages in
which computers can talk to each other.</p><p>So why don't we give it a try? Let's translate a domain name into an IP address:</p><p>Below you see a code example written in Rust (if you are not familiar with the Rust syntax, you can refer to
<a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/">The Rust Book</a> and learn by example).</p><p>This should give you a taste of what it's like to work with computer networks. Now let's start looking into
what makes this code tick!</p></div></div><div><div><p>We have now seen how IP addresses are used in a small, imaginary network of two computers.
But just knowing an address isn’t enough to do something useful: machines need to follow a well-known
protocol to make sure they can communicate with each other in a predictable way. This is what the
Internet protocol suite, also known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_protocol_suite">TCP/IP</a>,
is about: it's a standard collection of protocols used on the Internet.</p><p>The protocol suite consists of several protocols, of which we are interested in two: IP and UDP (later
we will also cover TCP and other protocols).</p><p>​<abbr title="Internet Protocol">IP</abbr> is the bread and butter of networking.
It serves as a foundation for high-level protocols. When computers exchange
messages, they encode them into IP <em>packets</em>, which you can view as individual
message units of up to 65 kilobytes in size. Usually, the operating system takes
care of the encoding for us and we don't need to do it manually, but it's still
good to know how it works under the hood, so let's see what a typical IP packet
looks like:</p><p>When you run this code, you see the destructured IP packet in a table. Each table cell contains an
individial field of the packet header. The header fields we set in code are highlighted in green—we
can skip the rest of them, for now.</p><p>On the right side, you can see the exact same packet represented in the
<em>hexadecimal</em> numerical system which is often used
to represent bytes because of its compactness (each single byte can be encoded by a hexadecimal
number ranging from <code>0x00</code> to <code>0xFF</code>, which <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/?q=0xFF+in+decimal&amp;t=hk&amp;ia=answer">corresponds to decimal</a>
<code>0</code> to <code>255</code>). This demonstrates that the IP header is just a sequence of numbers that we can interpret
and represent in different ways. If you are not comfortable with hexadecimal numbers, you can refer to
the <a href="https://lowlvl.org/prerequisites/binary-and-hexadecimal-numbers">prerequisite lesson on number encoding</a>.</p><h2>User Datagram Protocol</h2><p>​<abbr title="User Datagram Protocol">UDP</abbr>, or User Datagram Protocol, is a
thin layer above IP which adds some more contextual information for a message. A
UDP <abbr title="a word combination of data + telegram">datagram</abbr>
is also divided into a header and a payload. The fun thing about it is that an
entire UDP datagram is the <em>payload</em> of an IP packet! This is called
<em>encapsulation</em> and it's one of the core ideas in networking. A single layer of
the network stack like IP doesn’t know and doesn’t care about its payload, which
can be a protocol from the Internet protocol suite like TCP and UDP or even a
protocol defined by you.</p><p>UDP headers are only 8 bytes long. They contain source and destination <em>port numbers</em> which help to identify
different services running on the same computer—it's very common for a server to have many functions. Usually,
we designate a specific port number for a given service by convention. For example, name servers commonly use
the port number 53.</p><p>A UDP header also includes the total size of a datagram in bytes and a <em>checksum</em> which is used to verify
that the original network packet is not corrupted during transmission. And that's all it adds to the IP header!</p><p>Let's construct a UDP datagram header and add it to the previous example:</p><p>Now we are ready to move onto sending messages we have constructed
over the network!</p></div></div><div><div><p>Now we know how UDP datagrams and IP packets are constructed, but we
don't have to do this ourselves all the time. Instead, we can use
tools and functions provided by the operating system and the
standard library of our programming language. In Rust, these
functions are part of the <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/std/net/index.html"><code>std::net</code></a>
module.</p><p>We can use the <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/std/net/struct.UdpSocket.html#method.bind"><code>UdpSocket::bind</code></a>
function to construct <em>sockets</em>, which are virtual files that associate your program with a given port number.
All UDP datagrams incoming to this port will be redirected to your program by the operating system.</p><p><a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/std/net/struct.UdpSocket.html#method.send_to"><code>UdpSocket::send_to</code></a> can be used
to construct UDP datagrams from a given payload and send them over the network. We can wait for a response by using
the <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/stable/std/net/struct.UdpSocket.html#method.recv_from"><code>UdpSocket::recv_from</code></a>
function, which returns an IP address and a port number of a sender along with the message payload. In the case of
the name server request, we can interpret the payload as an IP address. If we send a request for Alice’s address to
the name server, we should get it back in this response!</p><p>Let's give it a try:</p><p>When you run this code, you can find a list of all IP packets you send and receive on the right. You can browse the
contents of IP packet headers and UDP datagrams. You can also find contents of an original message represented in
hexadecimal format below the packet browser.</p><p>With everything we have learned, you should be ready for a final test. In this test, you need to send a message to
your friend Alice. You know that she uses the port number <code>1000</code>—but you don't know her IP address yet! Maybe the
name server can help?</p><p>Congratulations, you have finished this lesson!</p><p>In the next one, we will cover the topic of fragmentation. So far we have been dealing with small messages only,
but what if you want to send a larger file, like a photo to share with your friend? We will learn how to break
large messages into small parts and how to reconstruct original files in the next lesson.</p><p><span>If you would like to follow updates, you can<!-- --> <a href="https://eepurl.com/haHQUn">subscribe to our mailing list</a>.</span></p></div></div><div><div id="lesson-navigation"><ol><li data-step="1">Exchanging Messages</li><li data-step="2">Sockets and Datagrams</li><li data-step="3">Sockets API</li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lowlvl.org/tcp-ip-fundamentals/exchanging-messages</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24764589</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 11:47:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Grand Unified Theory of Product Ideation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 78 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24764467">thread link</a>) | @jakobgreenfeld
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://jakobgreenfeld.com/gut | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jakobgreenfeld.com/gut">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>In short, effective methods to come up with product ideas can be categorized along two dimensions:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/startupideas.html">Organic ↔ Inorganic</a>. While organic ideas are solutions to problems you noticed in your own life, inorganic ideas are related to other people’s problems. Formulated differently, organic ideas grow out of the founders’ own experiences, while inorganic ideas don’t.</li>
  <li><a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/eriktorenberg/status/1243820706116198403">Bottom-up ↔ Top-down</a>. When you start only with a category in mind, you’re following a top-down approach, while if your ideation efforts start at some smaller scale you’re doing bottom-up ideation.</li>
</ul>

<p>We’ll discuss these distinctions in much more tangible terms in a moment. But first, just one more high-level observation. With the two dimensions at hand, we’re left with four distinct categories:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Organic, Bottom-Up Ideation. (“Scratch your own itch”)</li>
  <li>Organic, Top-Down Ideation. (“Live in the future, then build what’s missing”)</li>
  <li>Inorganic, Bottom-Up Ideation. (“Idea extraction”)</li>
  <li>Inorganic, Top-Up Ideation. (“Idea safaris”)</li>
</ul>

<p>Different entrepreneurs swear by different ideation methods. But what they all have in common is that they focus on finding problems over ideas.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Customers don’t pay for ideas; they pay for their problems to be solved.” - Nathan Barry</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Focusing on ideas is dangerous because it often leads to clever products that no one wants.</p>

<p><img src="https://jakobgreenfeld.com/images/gut.svg" alt=""></p>

<p>My humble opinion is that you should try all ideation methods at least once. Doing this will equip you with a broad arsenal of ideas that you can later put through the metaphorical <a href="https://tylertringas.com/business-ideas-meat-grinder/">“meat grinder”</a> (i.e. <a href="https://productideas.co/evaluation">evaluate</a> and <a href="https://productideas.co/validation">validate</a>).</p>

<p>In this essay I will not judge the different approaches (they’re all amazing!). My goal is merely to organize them within a common framework.</p>

<p>With that out of the way, let’s dive in. (I discuss the different ideation methods in the order recommended by <a href="https://training.kalzumeus.com/newsletters/archive/validating_product_ideas">Patrick McKenzie</a>. However, feel free to approach them in any order you like.)</p>

<h2 id="organic-bottom-up-ideation">Organic, Bottom-Up Ideation</h2>

<p>Organic, bottom-up ideation is all about solving problems that you currently have yourself or had in the past. It’s a great method because the best ideas are often things that you notice rather than things that you purposefully come up with during a brainstorming session.</p>

<p>While “<a href="https://tylertringas.com/finding-micro-saas-business-ideas/">scratching your own itch</a>” might sound easy, it requires a lot of effort if you want to do it right. We all develop a certain blindness to our routines and daily processes. Hence, we need to actively turn the spotlight on and scrutinize all areas of our lives.</p>

<p>This includes your current job, your hobbies and all jobs you had in the past. For each of them ask yourself:</p>

<ul>
  <li>What frictions did you encounter?</li>
  <li>What suboptimal processes did you notice?</li>
  <li>Did you found yourself wondering: “Why doesn’t someone make x?”</li>
  <li>What did you find frustrating? What made you think: “I shouldn’t have to x.”</li>
  <li>What would you spend money on without thinking if it existed?</li>
</ul>

<p>It makes a lot of sense to make it a habit to ask yourself this kind of questions regularly. With ideas, it’s like with radio frequency. You have to tune in to receive them and questions like the ones listed above will help you do that.</p>

<p>The biggest advantage of organic, bottom up ideation is that <a href="https://levels.io/startups/">you’re an expert on your own problems</a> and hence in an ideal position to navigate the corresponding <a href="https://cdixon.org/2013/08/04/the-idea-maze">idea maze</a>.</p>

<p>However, the usefulness of organic, bottom-up ideation depends heavily on the kind of life you’re living. If you’re living an interesting life, full of intellectual adventures, you’ll have no problem spotting opportunities.</p>

<p>But if your life is more mundane, the ideas you’ll be able to come up with organically will be less promising.</p>

<p>For example, most college students will only be able to usual problems:</p>

<ul>
  <li>I don’t know what I should do next Friday.</li>
  <li>It’s difficult to find a sexual partner.</li>
</ul>

<p>Only if you’re doing things that others don’t, you’ll be able to see what everyone else is missing.</p>

<p>An obvious solution to the “boring life”-problem is to start living a more interesting life and being more curious. This is what organic, top-down ideation is all about.</p>

<h2 id="organic-top-down-ideation">Organic, Top-Down Ideation</h2>

<p>A very poetic way to describe organic, top-down ideation was coined by Paul Graham: “Live in the future, then build what’s missing.” Formulated differently, if no promising ideas grow out of your own experiences, it’s time to become the kind of person who has more interesting product ideas.</p>

<p>This means that you purposefully pick a field (ideally one that will have a large impact in the future) and then immerse yourself in it. Hence, instead of starting with a specific problem you pick a new field and then try to get to the edge of it.</p>

<p>The most common way to do this is to get a job at a company in the space. Alternatively, you can, of course, also spend your free time dabbling in the field. For example, if you’re convinced that soon everyone will use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things">IoT devices</a>, you could start by <a href="https://github.com/HannahMitt/HomeMirror">building a smart mirror</a> to get your feet wet and then move on to more ambitious projects.</p>

<p>If you pick a promising field, the organic, top-down approach will allow you to spot many new problems worth solving. Ideally, you pick a field that is on the verge of becoming the next big thing. After all, <a href="http://jakobgreenfeld.com/trends">everything is easier when you’re riding a wave</a>. Then the problems you want to be solved, a few years later, millions of other people will want to be solved.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“[S]ince the most successful startups generally ride some wave bigger than themselves, it could be a good trick to look for waves and ask how one could benefit from them. Looking for waves is essentially a way to simulate the organic method. If you’re at the leading edge of some rapidly changing field, you don’t have to look for waves; you are the wave.” - <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/startupideas.html">Paul Graham</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>An interesting method to find industries and professions you could start to immerse yourself in is <a href="https://escapefromcubiclenation.libsyn.com/how-do-i-choose-which-business-to-start-">Pamela Slim’s month-long ideation exercise</a>. Each day you write down in a notebook how you respond to different things that occur in your life. After a while this will allow you to observe yourself like a scientist would observe an ant. Ideally, you’ll then be able to find patterns in the things that excite you. These are the things you should spend more time on.</p>

<p>A related useful method is to apply the principles of “curiosity overload” (h/t Daniel Priestley). Attend every event, listen to every sales pitch and subscribe to as much marketing material as you can find. If you bombard your brain this way, you’ll eventually notice interesting themes. As with Pamela Slim’s exercise, curiosity overload allows you to find out what kind of ideas get you excited. Moreover, it’s very likely that you stumble upon interesting inefficiencies and suboptimal processes. After all, if you fill your cup for a while it will eventually start pouring over.</p>

<p>Alternatively or supplementary, follow <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/hs.html">Paul Graham’s advice:</a> “Look for smart people and hard problems. Smart people tend to clump together, and if you can find such a clump, it’s probably worthwhile to join it.”</p>

<p>The biggest downside of organic, top-down ideation is that it takes a lot of time. You can’t expect to get to the edge of a new field in just a few weeks. More realistically, we’re talking about years. This may only be viable if you’re young. Hence, inorganic ideation methods can be invaluable.</p>

<h2 id="inorganic-bottom-up-ideation">Inorganic, Bottom-Up Ideation</h2>

<p>Rather than focusing on problems that you know from your own experiences, you can also focus on other people’s problems.</p>

<p>If you talk to people to find their specific pains, we call this inorganic, bottom-up ideation since we’re again starting with specific problems of a single person. It’s just that this person is no longer you. As with organic, bottom-up ideation, the goal is to discover the most painful problems (processes) that you can then put through the “<a href="https://productideas.co/validation">meat grinder</a>”.</p>

<p>However, while it is already difficult to become aware of suboptimal processes and problems in your own life, it’s even harder to do this for other people. Everyone becomes to some extent numb to the pain they experience in their daily lives.</p>

<p>In theory, you make a list of all the people you could talk to, reach out, and then just ask them questions like:  “What’s tedious or annoying about your work?”</p>

<p>However, in practice it’s usually a lot more difficult than that. Proper <a href="https://nathanbarry.com/finding-ideas-project/">idea extraction</a> is a skill and an art. <a href="http://momtestbook.com/">Whole books</a> have been written about how to do it right. The main problem is that if you ask the wrong kind of questions, the answers you’re getting will either be not very helpful or even lead you astray.</p>

<p>For example, when someone tells you about a problem it’s essential to ask them: “What have you already tried to solve it?” If the answer is: “Nothing.” the problem is not painful enough. Your solution would merely be “nice to have”. A hallmark of good product ideas is that the problem is currently solved through awkward workarounds.</p>

<p>A cautionary tale that exemplifies how difficult it is to learn something by talking to people is what happened to anthropologist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margaret_Mead">Margaret Mead</a>. She lived with the villagers in Samoa, and tried to learn everything she could about the life of teenagers there by talking to them. Years later other scientists discovered that most of her findings were based on stories that were completely made up by her teenage subjects. The teenagers admitted that they had made up stories just for fun.</p>

<p>Hence, instead of talking to individual people it can make a lot of sense to observe what happens within a whole industry. In that case, we’re talking again about top-down ideation.</p>

<h2 id="inorganic-top-down-ideation">Inorganic, top-down ideation</h2>

<p>The key idea is, as with, organic, top-down ideation, to start with a specific industry in mind. But instead of immersing yourself in it, you observe it from the outside like a scientist.</p>

<p>The first task is to find out where the people in your industry hang out (“<a href="https://stackingthebricks.com/cant-find-audience/">watering holes</a>”). This could be, for example, online forums, Slack channels, Subreddit, or Facebook groups. Once you’ve discovered these places, you go there and start observing what is happening. You’ll have to learn the …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jakobgreenfeld.com/gut">https://jakobgreenfeld.com/gut</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jakobgreenfeld.com/gut</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24764467</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 11:28:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[CSS Layout – Grid vs. Flexbox]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 63 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763958">thread link</a>) | @xxlcloudinc
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://codecoda.com/en/blog/entry/css-layout-grid-vs-flexbox | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://codecoda.com/en/blog/entry/css-layout-grid-vs-flexbox">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="description">
<p>A good layout makes users stay on a site because it makes important stuff easily accessible and intuitive to find. A lousy layout frustrates users, who leave because they can’t find what they are looking for.</p>
<div><p>In web design, <em>a layout</em> is a term that explains how a website is displayed on the screen. HTML 5 has quite a few elements that define parts of a web page: <em>header, nav, section, aside, article</em>, and <em>footer</em> are the significant distinctions in creating a layout. They constitute the four major sections of a webpage - <em>header/banner, navigation, content</em>, and <em>footer</em>.</p><p>Programming languages make websites feel alive, but at the core of every web page stands the good old HTML. When we discuss layouts, we must consider factors that make <em>a good</em> layout: responsiveness, viewing ports, display devices, browsers, and users’ screen sizes. A great layout not only looks great but can preserve the original intent by fitting in every possible display ratio. This correction is produced through CSS. In this article, we will examine two powerful properties: <em>CSS Flexbox and CSS Grid</em>.</p></div>
<figure><img src="https://cdn.codecoda.com/img/pixel.gif" data-plugin-lazyload="" data-plugin-options="{'effect' : 'fadeIn', 'speed' : 'fast'}" data-original="https://cdn.codecoda.com/themes/user/site/default/asset/img/blog/CSS-layout-1.png" alt="Generic Web Layout">
<figcaption><small>Generic Web Layout</small></figcaption>
</figure>
<h2>WHAT IS CSS FLEXBOX LAYOUT?</h2>
<div><p>The Flexible Box Module, commonly shortened to ‘flexbox,’ is a one-dimensional layout model. This means it deals with either row or column at a time but never both together. Flexbox is efficient when in aligning, distributing, and directing elements in a page.</p><p>Two key terminologies in Flexbox are the <strong>main axis</strong> and the <strong>cross axis</strong>. A flex container's main axis is the primary axis along which these flex items are laid out, and the cross-axis is perpendicular to it.</p><p>To start, we will wrap our HTML <em>divs</em> in a <em>flex-wrapper</em>.&nbsp;</p></div>
<pre><code>&lt;div class="flex-wrapper"&gt;
  &lt;div id="one"&gt;Header&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id="two"&gt;Nav&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div id="three"&gt;Content&lt;/div&gt;  
  &lt;div id="four"&gt;Footer&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>In CSS, our parent container, "flex-wrapper" will be converted to a flexbox with a simple line of code. </p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper { 
  display: flex; 
} 
</code></pre>
<p>I'll be adding a few elements and properties with bright colors and margins to make our <i>containers</i> and <i>divs</i> stand out.</p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper{ 
  display: flex; 
  background-color: beige; 
} 
.flex-wrapper &gt; div { 
  background-color: green; 
  height: 100px; 
  width: 100px; 
  margin: 10px; 
} 
</code></pre>
<p>You can see how nicely the div elements position itself horizontally. But if you notice, it doesn’t entirely take up all the space within the container. There’s a gap at the end. We can change this by adding <b>flex-grow</b>.</p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper &gt; div { 
  flex-grow: 1; 
}</code></pre>
<p>The flex-grow element distributes each item in a flex container. The default is 0, and by assigning a unit number to any of the <em>divs</em>, you can make it grow more massive than the rest. The opposite of this is <b>flex-shrink</b>.</p>
<pre><code>#one{ 
  flex-grow: 10;
} 
/* this gives the first div ten more units than the others */
</code></pre>
<h3>Flex-direction</h3>
<p>Flex-direction controls the direction in which items in a flex container should face. You can make the <em>divs</em> go up, down, left, and right. You can also have them in reverse order. By default, items in a flex-container are ordered from left to right, horizontally, within the main axis.</p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper{ 
  display: flex; 
  flex-direction: row; /* default direction */ 
}
.flex-wrapper{ 
  display: flex; 
  flex-direction: row-reverse;  
}</code></pre>
<p>Here, the items are displayed from left to right, but in reverse order. The fourth <em>div</em> now becomes the first and the first — the last.</p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper{ 
  display: flex; 
  flex-direction: column; 
} 
</code></pre>
<p>The <em>divs</em> are ordered from in a vertical manner - from up to down.</p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper{ 
  display: flex; 
  flex-direction: column-reverse; 
}</code></pre>
<p>The <em>divs</em> are ordered vertically, but in reverse, where the fourth <em>div</em> is at the top, and the first one is at the bottom.</p>
<h3>Flex Basis</h3>
<p>Flex basis defines the size of an item or a div inside the flex-container. This size value can be in <em>em, px,</em> or <em>percentage</em>. Flex-basis is different from flex-grow because it doesn’t equally share the space between items in a container.</p>
<pre><code>#three { 
  flex-basis: 200px; 
}</code></pre>
<h3>Flex</h3>
<p>Flex is a shorthand property that combines flex-shrink, flex-grow and flex-basis. It is recommended that you use this property instead of writing each individual property and its value. The order to set the values for the property is this: flex-grow, flex-shrink, flex-basis.</p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper { 
  display: flex; 
  flex: 0 0 200px; 
} 
</code></pre>
<h3>Justify-content and align-self</h3>
<p>Justify-content and align-self is the perfect solution to centralize a <em>div</em> or a container on a browser using flexbox.</p>
<pre><code>.flex-wrapper { 
  display: flex; 
  flex: 0 0 200px; 
  justify-content: center; 
  align-items: center; 
} 
</code></pre>
<h2>CSS Layout GRID</h2>
<p>CSS grid is a powerful 2-dimensional layout. This means <b>it can handle both the rows and columns of the layout</b>. CSS grid works with a 12-grid arrangement, where the screen is (invisibly) divided into 12 parts, and items must fit into this arrangement.<br <br=""><b>CSS grid's advantage over flexbox and other layout models is its two-dimensional quality</b>. It also makes positioning more straightforward, and the container’s elements can be set to overlap and overlap each other.</p>
<h3>Defining a grid in CSS grid</h3>
<p>A simple CSS line will transform an HTML structure to a CSS grid.</p>
<pre><code>&lt;div class="container"&gt; 
  &lt;div id="one"&gt;Header&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div id="two"&gt;Nav&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div id="three"&gt;Content&lt;/div&gt;  
  &lt;div id="four"&gt;Aside&lt;/div&gt;   
  &lt;div id="five"&gt;Section&lt;/div&gt;  
  &lt;div id="six"&gt;Footer&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
</code></pre>
<pre><code>.container { 
  display: grid; 
} 
</code></pre>
<h3>Grid template-columns and grid-template-rows</h3>
<p>The grid-template-columns and grid-template-row define the size of a column or row. It assigns a <i>div</i> a size depending on what is assigned. When you set the size of a template-column and template-grid size, you use <i>px, fr, percentage, or em</i>.</p>
<pre><code>.container { 
  display: grid; 
  grid-template-columns:  40px 1fr 20%;  
  grid-template-rows: 200px; 
  background-color: beige;   
}
.container &gt; div { 
  background-color: green; 
  margin: 10px; 
} 
</code></pre>
<div><p><b>grid-template-columns:</b> 40px 1fr 20%; - this line of code tells the browser to assign the first div a width of 40px. The second takes one fraction of the assigned space and the third 20%. Automatically, <em>divs</em> 4 to 6 move below the first 3, and takes on the values assigned in the same order. This means <em>div</em> 4 is assigned 40px, <em>div</em> 5 one fraction and <em>div</em> 6, 20%.</p><p>To place all six <em>divs</em> on one line, we must assign six values to the grid-template-column. We do not have to give different measurements to the grid-columns. We could use only <em>percentages, fr,</em> or <em>px</em>.</p><p>
<b>grid-template-rows:</b> 200px; - this assigns all the divs a height of 200px;</p></div>
<h3>FR</h3>
<pre><code>.container { 
  display: grid; 
  grid-template-columns: 16.7% 16.7% 16.7% 16.7% 16.7% 16.7%;  
} 
</code></pre>
<div><p>By assigning 16.7% in 6 places, I have successfully divided the six divs in the container into six equal parts on the screen. I used 16.7 because 16.7 times 6 gives 100% of the screen width.</p><p>Using percentage and px works perfectly, but it lacks adequate flexibility and belies the most useful resource - <b>a fraction of the CSS grid</b>.</p><p><b>Fr</b> is a fractional unit. It assigns each item one fraction of available space. The fractional space can be increased to accommodate each div according to how much space they need.</p><p>Our grid-template-columns now becomes</p></div>
<pre><code>grid-template-columns: 1fr 1fr 1fr 1fr 1fr 1fr; 
</code></pre>
<p>This divides each div equally on the screen.</p>
<pre><code>grid-template-columns: 1fr 2fr 1fr 2fr 1fr 1fr; 
</code></pre>
<p>This new value makes the second and fourth div twice the size of the rest. Most importantly, it is still distributed evenly on the browser and very much responsive.</p>
<h3>Repeat Function</h3>
<p>Rather than write down the values repeatedly, we can take advantage of the repeat function to assign values once.</p>
<pre><code>.container { 
  display: grid; 
  grid-template-columns: repeat(6, 1fr);
}</code></pre>
<p>The syntax is relatively straightforward. We need to use the word ‘repeat’ and then assign how many times we want the size repeated, which is 6, and then give the measurement value. This repeat function works with <em>fr, em, px</em> as well as <em>percentage</em>. This works for template-row as well.</p>
<h3>Gap</h3>
<p>Gap, also called <em>gutter</em> is a CSS grid property that allows you to specify the gap-space between <em>divs</em> in a CSS grid container. It works just like the margin property and is calculated mainly in <em>px</em>.</p>
<pre><code>gap: 10px;</code></pre>
<h3>Grid-column-start/grid-column-end and grid-row-start/grid-row-end</h3>
<p>The grid-column-start and grid-column-end place a grid item in a particular location within the column by referring to specific grid lines. The grid-row-start and grid-row-end also do the same to the row. By assigning a value to this property, grid items can be conveniently manipulated to start and end within the specified areas.</p>
<pre><code>.container { 
  display: grid; 
  grid-template-columns: repeat (3, 1fr); 
  grid-template-rows: repeat(4, 200px); 
}
#one { 
  grid-column-start: 1; 
  grid-column-end: 3; 
  grid-row-start: 1; 
  grid-row-end: 4; 
}</code></pre>
<div><p>When you assign these values to the first div, you’ll notice it pushes the second div one unit away, and it occupies the first two positions, pushing div 3 below. Row-wise, it now occupies three positions giving it a longer height.</p><p>There is a rule when indexing in programming because we generally count from 0, which applies here. The last value is usually mentioned, but not put into effect. For example, the grid-column-end is 3, but it stops at 2 just like the grid-row-end, which ends at 3 and not 4.</p></div>
<h3>Grid-columns and grid-row</h3>
<p>Gap, also called <em>gutter</em> is a CSS grid property that allows you to specify the gap-space between <em>divs</em> in a CSS grid container. It works just like the margin property and is calculated mainly in <em>px</em>.</p>
<pre><code>#one { 
  grid-column: 1/3; 
  grid-row: 1/4; 
}</code></pre>
<h3>Creating galleries using CSS grid</h3>
<p>CSS grid is the perfect model to create galleries. With little code and manipulation, you could make perfect, responsive gallery layouts.</p>
<h4>A Mosaic Gallery Layout</h4>
<p>A mosaic gallery layout creates even tiles of images distributed evenly over a page/container.</p>
<pre><code>&lt;div class="container"&gt; 
  &lt;div id="one"&gt;Image One&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div id="two"&gt;Image Two&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div…</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://codecoda.com/en/blog/entry/css-layout-grid-vs-flexbox">https://codecoda.com/en/blog/entry/css-layout-grid-vs-flexbox</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://codecoda.com/en/blog/entry/css-layout-grid-vs-flexbox</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24763958</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 09:58:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cockney Rhyming Slang History]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763872">thread link</a>) | @BerislavLopac
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://romanroadlondon.com/cockney-rhyming-slang-history/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://romanroadlondon.com/cockney-rhyming-slang-history/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
			
<div><p>Ever fallen down the ‘apples and pears’? Have you had your ‘barnet’ chopped recently? Called a mate on the old ‘dog and bone’? Or, ‘aven’t you a scooby’ about what all of that means?</p><p>Sit back, grab a nice cuppa ‘Rosy Lee’, and all will be explained.&nbsp;</p></div>



<p>These phrases belong to the vernacular of Cockney rhyming slang, a code-like way of speaking that originated in mid-19th century East London. You may remember your grandparents speaking it growing up, or perhaps you’ve heard a phrase or two being thrown about as you walk down <a href="https://romanroadlondon.com/roman-road-market-history/">Roman Road Market</a>, hunting for a bargain.</p>



<div><p>Leanne, who works in <a href="https://romanroadlondon.com/g-kelly-pie-mash-shop-working-class-food/">G Kelly</a>, said that hearing rhyming slang in the East End ‘isn’t as common these days’. ‘Pie and liquor is the Cockney rhyming slang for vicar’, she smilingly told us as she ladled the legendary parsley sauce. </p><p>Despite being less popular today, its old prevalence can still be heard, or seen, on our local streets. ‘<a href="https://romanroadlondon.com/bottlejob-craft-off-licence-shop-opens-globe-road/">BottleJob</a>‘, the bottle shop and craft off-licence in Globe Town, takes its name from a Cockney rhyming slang expression used to mean ‘coward’, which owner Alex Dehayen recalls as his grandfather’s affectionate nickname for him.&nbsp;</p></div>



<p>Due to its largely spoken nature, there are very few written records of its roots, but it was supposedly the language of stallholders and criminals. Thieves and vagabonds could use this type of ‘cryptolect’, a secretive language, to keep their liaisons well kept from eavesdropping authorities. A type of ‘in-the-know’ jargon, aiming to exclude or mislead anyone from outside of the Cockney bubble.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A sense of pride and nostalgia transpired from our Facebook call out about Cockney rhyming slang memories, particularly from the children that can remember their parents and grandparents using it. Mary Demmel remembers her aunt Mag leaving her house to get the bus saying “let me get me ole grey mare out”, meaning ‘fare’. Carol Legg’s nan ‘used to talk of the Artful that lived up the road’, referring to the lodger (Artful Dodger).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Pete Bailey, who comes from Hackney, recalled, ‘Growing up on the market, I used to hear everyone speaking it. Now it’s just a rare thing. I was at a football match last season and was standing with our captain’s girlfriend. She was shivering so I handed her my scarf and said, “Get that round your Gregory”. She looked at me funny and said, “What are you talking about?”. I’m trying to keep the Cockney language alive by teaching my godchildren.’</p>



<p>More commonly used today to describe a working class London accent, the term ‘Cockney’ actually has a specific geographical radius. It is officially defined as someone born within earshot of the chiming bells of Cheapside’s St Mary-le-Bow Church.</p>



<div><p>So, how exactly does this old-school lingo work? And, how on earth does a word like ‘plates’ come to mean ‘feet’? In its simplest form, a common word (feet) is typically replaced by a rhyming phrase of two or three words (plates of meat). The most proficient Cockney would usually shorten this back down to one word (plates). And, there you have it. Suddenly the expression ‘me plates are killing me’ translates as ‘my feet hurt’.</p><p>Don’t be fooled by the off-the-tongue ease at which it is most authentically delivered. These sayings can get confusingly cryptic. ‘Double slang’ is even harder to unscramble; this is how the name of a Greek philosopher came to mean one’s derrière. Aris is short for Aristotle. Aristotle rhymes with bottle. Bottle and glass rhymes with…you might want to have a go at working that one out yourself.</p></div>



<p>Marian Peck commented on our Facebook call out explaining her recollections of ‘backslang’. She said, ‘<strong>I</strong> think there were a couple of versions, but the one Cyril used was to take off the first letter of the word and put an ‘a’ on the end. So cat would be ‘ata’, television would be ‘elevisiona’.He came from Poplar, but worked as a bell boy in a London Hotel in the 1920s. Apparently a lot of staff could speak it and so the guests would not know what they were saying if they wanted to have a private conversation. My sister had go at it and tried to teach me, but I never had the patience!’</p>



<p>Some terms were born out of the summers that Cockneys spent hop picking. Whole families from the poorer parts of London would migrate ‘down to Kent’ to work on the fields, providing the surge of manual labour needed at harvest time. ‘Cherry’ is slang for ‘dog’, relating to the ‘cherry hog’ container that was used to collect crops. East Ender, Kim West, recalls, ‘I remember as a child in the hop fields, the adults would use slang and us kids would pick it up. The farmer would not understand a word’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other older examples relate to London locations. ‘Peckham Rye’ meaning ‘tie’, ‘Hampstead Heath’ meaning ‘teeth’ and ‘Tilbury Docks’ meaning ‘socks’. An all time favourite, first recorded in the 1850s, has to be ‘Barnet (fair)’, relating to one’s hair.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the 20th century, celebrity names began to influence these linguistic inventions. Musician Hank Marvin’ came to mean ‘starving’, singer Ruby Murray morphed into a synonym for ‘curry’, and racing driver Ayrton Senna was the new way of saying ‘tenner’.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the 2012 Olympics, an ATM on Commercial Street gave customers the language option of ‘Cockney rhyming slang’. To withdraw a bit of ’sausage and mash’ (cash), you were first asked to enter your ‘Huckleberry Finn’ (pin). This led to monetary prompts such as ‘Lady Godiva’ (£5) and ‘Horn of Plenty’ (£20).&nbsp;</p>



<div><p>In 1987, Mile End born record producer Paul Oakenfold coined the slang phrase ‘It’s all gone Pete Tong’, meaning ‘a bit wrong’. He wrote it in an article about acid house called ‘Bermondsey Goes Balearic’ for ‘Boy’s Own’ fanzine. Radio 1 DJ Pete Tong adopted it as the name for his Ibiza club night set and his nightly radio programme in the United States.&nbsp;</p><p>Whether from Del Boy or Danny Dyer, you have probably heard a bit of Cockney rhyming slang when watching the custard (telly – from ‘custard and jelly’). Some phrases even made it to DisneyLand via the lamplighters and chimney sweepers of ‘Mary Poppins’.</p></div>



<p>From <a href="https://romanroadlondon.com/knees-up-mother-brown-song-history/">old cockney classics</a>, like ‘My Old Man’s a Dustman’, to the lyrics of The Kinks and The Streets, you may have heard some rhyming slang sing from your record player or through your speakers.</p>



<p>Although it comes from the East End, the use of Cockney rhyming slang spreads far beyond the Bow Bells. The East Midlands accent has substituted ‘Derby Road’ for ‘cold’ and, down under, the name of Australian businessman Reg Grundy created ‘grundies’ (an Aussie word for ‘undies’).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite their travels, these phrases are undoubtedly heard most satisfyingly from the buoyant vocal box of a true, old-school, Cockney. In fact, some terms won’t make sense in any other accent. ‘Joanna’ means piano, relying on the ‘piannah’ pronunciation.&nbsp; Bawdy, bolshy and cheeky, the organically East End intonations perfectly capture the lingo’s playful charm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is the tradition dying out? A study carried out by the Museum of London in 2012 surveyed 2000 people, half of them Londoners, about their understanding and use of Cockney rhyming slang. It emerged that just 8% used the terms in everyday speech. The changing face of society, with new multi-cultural influences and the rise of virtual communication, is more aptly reflected in the contemporary slang of today’s youth.</p>



<p>However, that’s not to say that Cockney rhyming slang is a distant memory. New references to popular culture have been updating the canon since Victoria sat on the throne.&nbsp; The famous cartoon dog ‘Scooby Doo’ even managed to make the cut when ‘not a scooby’ came to mean ‘not a clue’.</p>



<div><p>Some phrases have become obsolete, but some are here to stay. Just as Shakespeare’s plays gave us terms like ‘a laughing stock’ and ‘a pound of flesh’, the old rhymes of East End folk have seeped right into the heart of the English Language. So, despite change and time, maybe it’ll never really be ‘brown bread’.</p><p>To find out more about Cockney rhyming slang, you can watch this <a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=299871854075637" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">archive footage</a> about how it was used.</p></div>








<div><div>			<div>
<hr>
<h3>Can you help us?</h3>
<p>As a not-for-profit media organisation using journalism to strengthen communities, we have not put our digital content behind a paywall or membership scheme as we think the benefits of an independent, local publication should be available to everyone living in our area.</p>

<p>If a fraction of the local 40,000 residents donated two pounds a month to <em>Roman Road LDN</em> it would be enough for our editorial team to serve the area full time and be beholden only to the community. A pound at a time, we believe we can get there.</p>
<h5>Support <em>Roman Road LDN</em> from as little as £2 and enjoy the benefits of being a Patron.</h5>

<h4><a href="https://romanroadlondon.com/support-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Become a Patron from as little as £2 per month ⇒</a></h4>
</div>
		</div></div><!-- AddThis Advanced Settings above via filter on the_content --><!-- AddThis Advanced Settings below via filter on the_content --><!-- AddThis Advanced Settings generic via filter on the_content --><!-- AddThis Share Buttons above via filter on the_content --><!-- AddThis Share Buttons below via filter on the_content --><!-- AddThis Share Buttons generic via filter on the_content -->		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://romanroadlondon.com/cockney-rhyming-slang-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24763872</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 09:43:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Improve Bluetooth Audio Quality on Linux]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 149 | Comments 62 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763593">thread link</a>) | @kn100
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://kn100.me/improving-bluetooth-audio-linux/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kn100.me/improving-bluetooth-audio-linux/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> <p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763593">Hacker News Discussion</a> | <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Ubuntu/duplicates/ja9kch/improving_bluetooth_audio_quality_on_ubuntu_linux/">Reddit Discussion</a></p>
<p>Bluetooth Audio is generally considered convenient, but not ‘audiophile’. Any self respecting audiophile is probably connecting their fancy headphones to some Digital to Analog Converter/Amp combo which might be connected to their computer using some fancy gold plated USB Cable. More power to them, I am not self respecting. I made a decision a few months ago to switch entirely to Bluetooth Audio as the convenience and tidiness of having a wireless headset just appealed to me so much.</p>
<p>I purchased the M-Pow H21s - which are a fairly budget noise cancelling pair of Bluetooth headphones. They appealed to me because they weren’t enormously expensive, and other M-Pow stuff I’d purchased in the past was of good enough quality for me to trust these would be too. I wasn’t wrong. The noise cancelling is reasonably good, and the sound profile, while not ‘neutral’ - is totally fine for me to use while working.</p>
<p>One thing that really did annoy me about these headphones (and I’m not sure if the fault lies with Bluetooth Audio on Linux or with the headphones themselves) is that if I walked away from my desk and then returned, the audio quality would perceptibly drop, but never quite recover. It seemed to get ‘stuck’ at a lower quality, until the headset was rebooted. One day, I got tired of this, so decided to research what was going on.</p>

<p>In the beginning, there was A2DP - or the Advanced Audio Distribution Profile. This is a Bluetooth profile - which describes a method by which audio can be transmitted between a sender and a receiver. The profile mandates that all Bluetooth devices support a codec called SBC - or Low Complexity Subband Codec. A codec defines exactly how the device that is sending the audio should compress it. SBC is what’s known as a Low Complexity codec. Low Complexity codecs have the design goal of being easy to encode for the sender and being easy to decode for the receiver. It’s a fairly old codec, being the precursor to MP2 - itself the precursor of MP3. When consumers started demanding better quality audio out of their Bluetooth hardware, various other codecs were added to hardware. Some hardware added MP3 encoding and decoding - which was a small improvement in two ways. Firstly, if the source material was already MP3, and the encoder was smart enough, the MP3 data could directly be sent to the receiver, meaning that no encoding step was necessary. Secondly, MP3 is generally considered to be a better codec in terms of the resulting audio quality, so even if there was an encoding step, the results were generally better. Apple added AAC support to their hardware - which itself is a far superior codec to MP3 lends much the same benefits. The freshest codec which seems to be available is from a company that Qualcomm gobbled up - aptX. This codec is interesting in the sense that it only offers the second advantage talked about above. Nobody has music in aptX format, which meant that all source material must be re-encoded on the device sending the audio.</p>

<p>The first step to identifying if improvements can be made to your own Bluetooth Audio is to figure out which codecs your Bluetooth Headset supports. You can generally find this out by finding the manufacturers information. My particular headset, the h21 - is dumb as rocks, and only supports SBC. If your headset supports a better codec, especially if it supports a codec called LDAC - you should very much consider trying that before trying to do what we’ll be doing in this article, which is improving the quality available to us using the SBC codec. <a href="https://www.nextpit.com/bluetooth-audio-codecs">This article does a reasonably good job of covering all the codecs.</a></p>
<p>No matter what your headphones support, the next thing you’re going to want to do is install a custom PulseAudio module which both enables support for a bunch of more fancy codecs, and also allows you to configure the codecs. Go grab <a href="https://github.com/EHfive/pulseaudio-modules-bt/wiki/Packages">EHfive/pulseaudio-modules-bt</a> and restart PulseAudio. You should already see in your systems sound settings you can now actually select between AAC, APTX, APTX HD, and LDAC - if your headset supports it. You can probably stop here if you’re able to switch to APTX or LDAC. If not, it’s time to configure SBC to be less sucky.</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://kn100.me/bt-audio-cli.png"> <figcaption>
<h4>default.pa, with the changes</h4>
</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>So, a quick review of the options the SBC encoder has that we likely care about. Firstly, the Stereo mode. Generally in audio the two stereo modes we have are.. well Stereo and Joint Stereo. Stereo transmits two distinct channels of audio in the same stream, but completely distinct from one another. Joint stereo makes the assumption that the left and right channels are probably similar enough that just encoding how the right channel differs from the left will result in a more efficient packing of data. Your headset is likely already using one of these two modes. SBC actually supports a third mode, called dual - which essentially sends two audio streams to your headset, completely independently of one another. This effectively doubles the bit-rate your headset can operate at, since you now will have two separate streams of audio being encoded, rather than just one. If your headset supports this dual mode, and it most likely does, you definitely want it. In fact, this unofficial feature has been added to a popular custom Android OS - called LineageOS, <a href="https://www.lineageos.org/engineering/Bluetooth-SBC-XQ/">and they describe the benefit of this very well here</a>.</p>
<p>The next option we likely care about is the bitpool. The bitpool effectively determines the bitrate the audio will be encoded at. The higher, the better. <a href="https://btcodecs.valdikss.org.ru/sbc-bitrate-calculator/">A calculator is available here</a> but what is shows is that at the default highest available Bitpool value (53) in Joint Stereo mode - the maximum available bitrate is 328kbps. If we do nothing else, and just switch to Dual Channel mode - the bitrate predictably roughly doubles to 617.4kbps. Some headsets, like my H21s, actually seem to do fine at higher bitpool values. Through experimentation, I found that around 70 was as much as my headset could manage without hearing the audio equivalent of a buffer overflow. At a bitpool value of 70, in dual channel mode, the bitrate now gets to 804.8kbps!</p>
<p>If you are experimenting with a different headset, I suggest starting with a bitpool value of 53 and dual stereo enabled. You can then experiment with increasing the bitpool value, as described below.</p>
<p>To modify these values, you’ll need to edit <code>/etc/pulse/default.pa</code>. Firstly, find the lind that begins <code>load-module module-bluetooth-discover</code>. Modify it to add these flags, like so:</p>
<p><code>load-module module-bluetooth-discover a2dp_config="sbc_cmode=dual sbc_min_bp=53 sbc_min_bp=53 sbc_freq=44k"</code></p>
<p>This will lock your SBC encoder to work at a bitpool size of 53 - in dual stereo mode. Restart PulseAudio by doing <code>pulseaudio -k</code> - and reconnect your Bluetooth headset. Hopefully, you’ll perceive a large improvement in quality, as I did. You can now experiment by changing that value of 53 for a higher value. <a href="https://btcodecs.valdikss.org.ru/codec-compatibility/">There’s a list of known compatibility available here</a>.</p>
<p>The one downside of this approach of locking the encoder to work at a particular bitpool is that you lose graceful degredation of quality as the link quality reduces. You could experiment with having a lower value for the <code>sbc_min_bp</code> so that the encoder can reduce quality.</p>
<p>Let me know if this helps you!</p>
<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763593">Hacker News Discussion</a> | <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Ubuntu/duplicates/ja9kch/improving_bluetooth_audio_quality_on_ubuntu_linux/">Reddit Discussion</a></p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kn100.me/improving-bluetooth-audio-linux/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24763593</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 08:51:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Automatically sending Webmentions from a static website]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 73 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763587">thread link</a>) | @chrislo
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | https://jamesmead.org/blog/2020-10-13-sending-webmentions-from-a-static-website | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jamesmead.org/blog/2020-10-13-sending-webmentions-from-a-static-website">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
      <p>A few months back I wrote about <a href="https://jamesmead.org/blog/2020-06-27-indieweb-ifying-my-personal-website">indieweb-ifying this website</a>. I attempted to follow the excellent <a href="https://indiewebify.me/">indiewebify.me guide</a>, but I skipped step 2 of Level 2, i.e. <a href="https://indiewebify.me/#send-webmentions">adding the ability to send Webmentions to other IndieWeb sites</a>. My <a href="https://jamesmead.org/blog/2020-06-27-indieweb-ifying-my-personal-website#publishing-on-the-indieweb">excuse</a> at the time was:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I decided to skip this step for now given that it's relatively easy to <a href="https://indieweb.org/webmention-implementation-guide#One-liner_webmentions">send a Webmention manually using <code>curl</code></a> and it's not as if I currently blog that frequently!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Anyway a couple of recent discoveries led me to fix this omission…</p>

<h3 id="webmentionapp">webmention.app</h3>

<p>This lovely little <a href="https://webmention.app/">service</a> built by <a href="https://remysharp.com/">Remy Sharp</a>, not to be confused with <a href="https://webmention.io/">webmention.io</a> which is used for <em>receiving</em> incoming <a href="https://indieweb.org/Webmention">Webmentions</a>, makes it easy to <em>send</em> outgoing webmentions for all the links on a given page:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This is a platform agnostic service that will check a given URL for links to other sites, discover if they support webmentions, then send a webmention to the target.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Fortunately I still have an <a href="http://feeds.jamesmead.org/floehopper-blog">RSS feed</a> for my blog and in this case the documentation <a href="https://webmention.app/docs#using-ifttt-to-trigger-checks">suggests using IFTTT</a> to automate doing this each time you publish an article.</p>

<h3 id="actionsflow">Actionsflow</h3>

<p>Somewhat serendipitously I recently came across <a href="https://actionsflow.github.io/docs/">Actionsflow</a> which is a free Zapier/IFTTT alternative for developers to automate workflows based on GitHub Actions.</p>

<p>I have to admit that I was initially quite confused by the Actionsflow documentation and I tried to add my Webmention-sending workflow to <a href="https://github.com/floehopper/jamesmead.org">the repo for this website</a>. However, once I realised the idea was to <a href="https://github.com/actionsflow/actionsflow-workflow-default/generate">create a new repo</a> based on a template, things became a little clearer.</p>

<h3 id="workflow-to-send-webmentions">Workflow to send Webmentions</h3>

<p>I created <a href="https://github.com/floehopper/send-webmentions">this repo</a> and added <a href="https://github.com/floehopper/send-webmentions/blob/main/workflows/send-webmentions.yml">this workflow</a> to poll my RSS feed and send an HTTP POST request to the webmention.app API for every new item. I was pleasantly surprised by how simple this was:</p>

<pre><code>name: Send webmentions for new blog posts
on:
  rss:
    url: http://feeds.jamesmead.org/floehopper-blog
    config:
      logLevel: debug
      limit: 1
jobs:
  send_webmentions:
    name: Send webmentions
    runs-on: ubuntu-latest
    steps:
      - name: 'Send webmentions for RSS item link'
        uses: actionsflow/axios@v1
        with:
          url: https://webmention.app/check/
          method: 'POST'
          params: '{ "url": "${{on.rss.outputs.link}}", "token": "${{ secrets.WM_TOKEN }}" }'
          is_debug: true
</code></pre>

<p>It took me a while to realise that the underlying Actionsflow GitHub Action was running every 5 minutes and <em>polling</em> my RSS feed. It seems to use the GitHub Action cache to "remember" which items it has seen before. Since I don't publish blog posts very often, polling every 5 minutes seemed a bit excessive and so I decided to <a href="https://github.com/floehopper/send-webmentions/commit/eb5a9cb573b1c532c92143b7fb2aed260c5fa552">reduce the frequency to hourly</a>.</p>

<h3 id="observations">Observations</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>I'm not sure I like the design of Actionsflow which means creating a new repo, but perhaps this would make more sense to me if I had more than one workflow. I suppose this repo is roughly equivalent to a single IFTTT account.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Over the course of the last year I've automated some backup jobs for <a href="https://gofreerange.com/">Go Free Range</a> using the <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cdk/api/latest/typescript/api/aws-ecs-patterns/scheduledfargatetask.html#aws_ecs_patterns_ScheduledFargateTask"><code>ScheduledFargateTask</code> class</a> in the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cdk/">AWS CDK</a> to fire up a container and run a script on a cron schedule. This has worked really well, but it's quite tempting to port these over to Actionsflow so we don't have to maintain anything other than the <code>Dockerfile</code> and associated shell scripts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>webmention.app is really nicely implemented with good documentation; it's a classic example of an elegant solution to a tightly scoped problem. Since I'll be making use of the API on a regular basis, I decided to <a href="https://jamesmead.org/blog/paypal.me/rem">buy Remy a drink</a> to say thank you!</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I'd also like to find a way to say thank you to <a href="https://aaronparecki.com/">Aaron Parecki</a> who built webmention.io and <a href="https://snarfed.org/">Ryan Barrett</a>, <a href="https://kylewm.com/">Kyle Mahan</a>, et al who built <a href="https://brid.gy/">brid.gy</a>. However, I can't see a way to do either and, indeed, the latter <a href="https://brid.gy/about#cost">explicitly say</a> "We don't need donations, promise."</p>
  </li>
</ul>


    </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jamesmead.org/blog/2020-10-13-sending-webmentions-from-a-static-website</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24763587</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 08:50:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Niche I am Looking to Fill]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763209">thread link</a>) | @DoreenMichele
<br/>
October 13, 2020 | http://www.eclogiselle.com/2020/10/the-niche-i-am-looking-to-fill.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.eclogiselle.com/2020/10/the-niche-i-am-looking-to-fill.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div id="post-body-206541096419142738"><p>
Eclogiselle is intended to be a compendium of free resources for small communities with paid services available below $5000. In fact, I hope to be able to offer some services for well under a thousand dollars.

</p><p>


I am looking to serve small communities that would have trouble hiring someone at all to do planning and economic development work for them. I am hoping to find creative ways to provide useful resources for communities who often either cannot afford paid staff or cannot find someone willing to work for them for what they can afford to pay.

</p><hr><p>
The small town I live in made an offer to a candidate for their city manager position and the candidate turned them down and took a higher paying job elsewhere. That seems to be par for the course.

</p><p>

Years ago when I was looking to become a professional planner, I haunted the online job listings. A lot of small communities kept the same job openings available for months at a time because of the challenges they face in filling such positions at all.

</p><p>
I have first-hand experience with my local <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CitizenPlanners/comments/duf6ae/main_street_america/">Main Street America</a> program. This is the leading voice for preservation-based economic development and community revitalization across the US. 
</p><p>
It is aimed at revitalizing small towns. In order to be an accredited Main Street program, you need to have an executive director: 

</p><ul><li>0-2500 people = half time volunteer Executive Director</li>

  <li>2500-5000 = half time paid Executive Director</li>

  <li>5000+ = full time paid Executive Director</li></ul><p>

So this well-established program doesn't expect a town of less than 2500 people to be able to pay their economic development director <i>at all</i>. It's a part-time, volunteer position for such communities. It's basically a labor of love. 
</p><p>
For towns between 2500 and 5000 people, they only expect them to be able to pay for a part-time director. It's only for communities above 5000 that they expect you to have a full-time paid executive director for this non-profit economic development entity.

</p><p>
Please note that if they have a full-time executive director, this is probably their only paid employee. There will also be a board running the non-profit and those are all unpaid positions.

</p><p>
So all the evidence suggests that small communities have trouble hiring planning and economic development staff <i>at all</i>, whether it is a city job or a job at a local non-profit trying to fill in the gaps in their small town. And when <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/urbanplanning/comments/j5a0vr/dark_side_question_typical_services_and_prices_at/">I asked around</a>, the answers I got suggest small communities face additional challenges when they look to contract out services instead of hiring paid staff to serve them.
</p><p>
In one reply to my query, I was given a link to <a href="https://patch.com/new-jersey/triboro/kinnelon-council-members-fear-environmental-resource-e348f325fc">an article</a> from 2012 where The Land Conservancy of New Jersey was offering to do an Environmental Resources Inventory (ERI) for Kinnelon, a burrough in New Jersey. They were offering it at a discount and the price was expected to be $10,000 (back in 2012 -- no doubt, prices have gone up since then).
</p><p>
<a href="https://tlc-nj.org/">The Land Conservancy of New Jersey</a> is apparently a <i>non-profit</i> land trust that has a goal of protecting open space. The person who left the link implied that this is probably a typical fee for non-profits and universities serving this space for small communities.

</p><p>

Non-profits and universities are supposed to be the good guys, the affordable option, the folks doing it out of idealism and not to make a quick buck. But it doesn't take much digging to be suspicious of this $10,000 ERI and why it is being pushed.
</p><p>
In the article, one person objecting to paying for the ERI said, in part, <i>All we do is keep spending money and no ones giving us money.</i> so I pulled up the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinnelon,_New_Jersey">Wikipedia page for Kinnelon</a>, New Jersey and, unsurprisingly, this is a wealthy suburb.
</p><p>
According to Wikipedia, in 2012 they were among the top 500 most expensive zip codes in the US. It lists them as at number 462.
</p><p>
A quick search tells me there are nearly 42,000 zip codes in the US. If you pull out a calculator and divide 462 by 42,000, the result is 0.011. So we are talking about people who are just outside of the One Percent. 
</p><p>
I read this article and I see vague, hand-wavy claims that this ERI is "useful for planning efforts" and I also see people complaining about a pattern of being bled for money over the years without getting results. I can readily believe they are being taken advantage of. 

</p><p>
I can believe that people keep going to Kinnelon burrough, selling them services "at a discount" (because "we are the good guys") for thousands of dollars -- because these people can come up with the money -- and the services aren't actually useful for development.
</p><p>
The other thing I was told was that most for-profit, private planning firms do not actively seek out projects that are below about $5k. If you approach them, they might do a small project for you, but chasing it down isn't worth it. It doesn't pay well enough.

</p><p>

Before life got in the way, I wanted to be a professional planner. I've spent years around online planning forums and attending local meetings and what not and I think I would have trouble finding a private planning firm. 
</p><p>
They seem to me to not be very visible. I'm not exactly an insider because I never got the career I wanted, but you would think this would be less opaque to me.
</p><p>

So my impression is that planning firms are hard to identify by small communities, aren't actively seeking business from small communities because it doesn't pay well enough and may not even take a bid from you even if you approach them. If it's only a few thousand dollars, they seem to feel like they are doing you some kind of favor if they are willing to work with you.

</p><p>

I am in Aberdeen, Washington. It is in a region I have dubbed The Pacific Coastal Region of Washington State or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CoastalWA/">CoastalWA</a>. 

</p><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bGDP0jo2muo/X4Tk73UfcOI/AAAAAAAAGyU/ng7YAFlb8jEcNG137qzgwJx-WcKRulB5QCLcBGAsYHQ/s0/CoastalWA256sq.png"><img alt="" data-original-height="256" data-original-width="256" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-bGDP0jo2muo/X4Tk73UfcOI/AAAAAAAAGyU/ng7YAFlb8jEcNG137qzgwJx-WcKRulB5QCLcBGAsYHQ/s0/CoastalWA256sq.png"></a></p><p>



This is a region with a sparse number of small towns and a large number of unincorporated communities. There is at least a half million people, two or three dozen incorporated small towns and probably upwards of 200 unincorporated communities.

</p><p>
And most likely an influx of people will be coming here in the next few years because it is a relative safe haven from things like climate change. So I think the many small communities in this region need to begin preparing for growth if they don't want a bunch of well-heeled outsiders to come in and run rough-shod over the people who are already here.

</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CoastalWA/comments/j4u0by/welcome/">
  Welcome to CoastalWA</a></li><li>
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CoastalWA/comments/izecag/counties_of_coastal_wa/">Counties of CoastalWA</a></li><li>
<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CoastalWA/comments/iztsji/coastal_wa_is_a_relative_safe_haven_in_2020/">CoastalWA is A Relative Safehaven</a></li></ul><p>

So I think there is tremendous need for free and low cost economic development and planning resources and services that would work well for small communities. The only question in my mind is if I can figure out how to package up offerings that make sense for both me and them and find a way to connect with the people who need it.





</p><blockquote>The
  Map on this page is by <a href="http://stamen.com/">Stamen Design</a> and is being used under <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0">CC BY 3.0</a>. Map Data by <a href="http://openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap</a>, under <a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/copyright">ODbL</a>. It has been edited by <a href="https://doreenmichele.blogspot.com/">Doreen Traylor</a>.</blockquote>


<p>
<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24763209">Hacker News Discussion</a></p></div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.eclogiselle.com/2020/10/the-niche-i-am-looking-to-fill.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24763209</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 07:40:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Custom Allocators Demystified]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 62 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24762840">thread link</a>) | @deafcalculus
<br/>
October 12, 2020 | https://slembcke.github.io/2020/10/12/CustomAllocators.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://slembcke.github.io/2020/10/12/CustomAllocators.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Have you ever wondered why people write their own memory allocators? Are they masochists? Do they think they can write a better memory allocator than the OS? Shouldn’t they just use a garbage collected language instead?</p>

<h2 id="why-bother-with-custom-allocators">Why bother with custom allocators?</h2>

<p>Around 2010 or so when Chipmunk2D was new(ish), it didn’t use any custom allocators. Even temporary data was allocated when needed, tracked, and freed when I was done with it. At the time I was developing it, I was using OS X, and this was more or less fine. I even have some old stress test videos on YouTube with tens of thousands of colliding objects in real time on an old Core 2 Duo laptop. Running the same code on Windows XP wasn’t so great however. Had somebody suggested using a custom allocator, I probably would have turned my nose up at the idea and said something like “That’s dumb, I can do something simpler.” Besides, looking at sampling profiler data on OS X was telling me that memory functions weren’t even 1% of the CPU time after all. Why bother trying to make the allocator more efficient? On the other hand I knew what I had really wanted to do was to try and pack all of my collision data together to make it cache friendly. So what I did was to keep pools of various types of structs. If I needed a collision pair struct, I could just grab one from the pool. If the pool was empty, I’d allocate a few more kilobytes of them in a big block first. I did something similar for contact data, but since it only needed to be kept for a single frame I could release entire blocks of it back to the pools all at once. This solved my Windows performance problem, and the locality made for a very nice performance bump on other platforms too!</p>

<p>The astute reader is probably performing a face palm right now as I’ve just described a slab allocator and a zone allocator. :)</p>

<h3 id="no-need-for-a-better-malloc">No need for a better <code>malloc()</code></h3>

<p>So what does <code>malloc()</code> give us anyway?</p>

<ul>
  <li>Access to nearly unlimited amounts of virtual memory</li>
  <li>Create or free individual allocations of any size</li>
  <li>Safe, transparent access to allocations from any thread</li>
</ul>

<p>These are all great features, and it would be difficult to implement a reasonably generic replacement. On the other hand, many programs and systems within them have unique memory requirements. For Chipmunk2D’s collision system what I needed was completely different:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Memory locality</li>
  <li>Predictable performance</li>
  <li>Simplified memory ownership</li>
</ul>

<p>So while I didn’t know it at the time, I had several reasons to want a custom allocator, and I accidentally implemented several! The last item in particular is interesting to me because it’s completely antithetical to what I used to think custom allocators were all about. I had a model in my head where custom allocators were about performance, and garbage collection to be about simplifying ownership, but it turns out the two are not so mutually exclusive. Using some custom allocator techniques in a garbage collected language can improve performance, and using them in a traditional language can give many of the same benefits as if you had garbage collection.</p>

<h3 id="more-reasons-to-bother-with-custom-allocators">More reasons to bother with custom allocators</h3>

<p>Over the years, I’ve wasted <em>many</em> hours debugging memory issues. With just a hash table and a set of linked lists, you can track the history of all your allocations. That makes it pretty easy to track down use after free errors, double free errors, and memory leaks. Using guard pages around your allocations, you can detect overflows. Techniques like this can be a nice complement to external tools like Valgrind or AddressSanitizer. Between the simplified memory ownership, having tools to help detect errors, and tools to debug issues when they do occur, I can happily say I haven’t spent a lot of time debugging memory issues for years. :)</p>

<h2 id="common-allocators">Common Allocators</h2>

<p>Several of the common allocators you hear people talk about are so simple, you can describe them in a paragraph! (Though I’m going to cheat and use diagrams too.)</p>

<h3 id="1-slab-allocator">1) Slab Allocator</h3>

<p><img src="https://slembcke.github.io/images/SlabAllocator.svg" alt="Slab Allocator Diagram"></p>

<p>The collision pair example from Chipmunk2D is basically a slab allocator. The idea is that your allocator just needs to keep a list of large blocks of memory (slabs) that you have allocated, and break those into little fixed sized blocks of memory for your objects that you store in a linked list of free allocations. The trick is to use the allocations themselves as linked list nodes so you don’t have to waste any extra memory for tracking. Allocating memory becomes as fast as pushing or popping nodes onto a linked list, and you only have to talk to the OS when you run out of space in your existing slabs. Additionally, all of the memory is packed together which helps play nice with the CPU cache. As a bonus, you know for sure that you are packing small, short lived allocations together and minimizing fragmentation of your main memory space.</p>

<p><strong>When to use it:</strong> When you need to keep a pool of short lived allocations that are all the same size.</p>

<h3 id="2-linear-allocator">2) Linear Allocator</h3>

<p><img src="https://slembcke.github.io/images/LinearAllocator.svg" alt="Linear Allocator Diagram"></p>

<p>Linear allocators (sometimes called bump allocators) are one of the simplest and most useful custom allocators. The short version: Given a block of memory, start at the beginning and make allocations one after another. When you are done with all the allocations, free or reuse the block. Generally speaking you also need to deal with alignment, overflow, and out of memory issues, but none of that is particularly complicated. Linear allocators are great when you need scratch memory to build a temporary data structure, or otherwise know that all the data you are allocating has a finite lifespan. This works well when processing a user input event in a GUI, or a frame in a game. Not only does your data end up well packed for the CPU cache, but the actual cost of the allocation is just a tiny bit of arithmetic, and deallocation is basically free! The biggest downside of linear allocators is that you need to know the worst case memory usage up front.</p>

<p><strong>When to use it:</strong> When you need fast temporary memory with a finite lifespan.</p>

<h3 id="3-zone-allocator">3) Zone Allocator</h3>

<p><img src="https://slembcke.github.io/images/ZoneAllocator.svg" alt="Zone Allocator Diagram"></p>

<p>Zone allocators (sometimes called arena allocators) make linear allocators more flexible by relaxing the upfront memory allocation. Instead of a single block of memory, you make a series of linear allocators. Whenever one runs out of space, allocate another block and switch to it. Then all you need to do is keep a list of the blocks you allocate so they can be freed (or returned to a pool) when you are done with the zone.</p>

<p>Zone allocators are pretty simple to extend to be thread safe as well. Instead of a single linear allocator you can make one per thread as needed. Only the list of blocks shared by the zone’s linear allocators needs to be protected by a mutex.</p>

<p><strong>When to use it:</strong> When you need fast temporary memory with a finite lifespan, but don’t know how much you’ll need.</p>

<h3 id="4-buddy-block-allocator">4) Buddy Block Allocator</h3>

<p>The buddy block allocator is the fanciest allocator I’ve personally implemented. It’s pretty generic, and is exactly the sort of thing I thought would be a waste of time all those years ago. On the other hand it’s not particularly complicated, and my own implementation is barely 200 sloc. The basic idea is that you start with a large block of memory that you want to split up, and when you make allocations you recursively break the block into halves until you have the size you need. Since sub-blocks are always broken into pairs (buddies), it’s easy to figure out the location of any given block’s buddy with a little math. When freeing a block, you can easily check if the buddy is free and join them back together into a larger block.</p>

<p>While I can’t succinctly describe the whole algorithm in a paragraph, there are plenty of articles on the internet if you want a clearer picture. Also, keep in mind that while this is a pretty generic algorithm that you really <em>could</em> replace malloc() with, you might want to have a pretty good idea of why you’d want to. Maybe you have some strong latency constraints (audio, graphics, etc), or maybe you are allocating something that isn’t regular memory (ex: Vulkan memory). I’ve only used my implementation in a real-time audio synthesizer, but it would have been fine without it too. It was for a hobby project, and it was fun. :)</p>

<p><strong>When to use it:</strong> When you need a general purpose allocator with predictable performance.</p>

<h2 id="why-not-bother-with-custom-allocators">Why not bother with custom allocators!</h2>

<p>Hopefully I’ve convinced somebody that custom allocators aren’t a terrible idea after all, and given them some terms to search for more information.</p>

<p>Happy allocating! :)</p>

  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://slembcke.github.io/2020/10/12/CustomAllocators.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24762840</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 06:28:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Predict a Reddit user's Myers-Briggs type from their profile]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 111 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24762449">thread link</a>) | @ragnarkar
<br/>
October 12, 2020 | https://gimmeserendipity.com/mbtimodel/reddit/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gimmeserendipity.com/mbtimodel/reddit/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  

<title>Predict a Reddit User's MBTI Personality</title>

<form method="POST" action="/mbtimodel/reddit/" enctype="multipart/form-data">



<br>
<label for="message"><h4>Enter username here: </h4></label>


</form>
<p>Please be patient, this could take up to a minute to process.</p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gimmeserendipity.com/mbtimodel/reddit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24762449</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 05:05:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
