<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 13:11:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 13:11:21 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bitcoin Core Lead Maintainer Steps Back, Encourages Decentralization]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 121 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25880727">thread link</a>) | @runeks
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://laanwj.github.io/2021/01/21/decentralize.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://laanwj.github.io/2021/01/21/decentralize.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Recent events have made me reflect on a few things in my life I was already thinking about for a while. Also, responses on social media have made me realize that people have <em>strange</em> expectations from me, and what my role in the Bitcoin Core project is.</p>

<h2 id="growth">growth</h2>

<p>Bitcoin has grown a lot since I started contributing to it in 2011. Some arrangements that were acceptable for a small scale FOSS project are no longer so for one runing a 600 billion dollar system. Market cap is famously deceptive, but my point is not about specific numbers here.</p>

<p>One thing is clear: this is a serious project now, and we need to start taking decentralization seriously.</p>

<h2 id="moving-on">moving on</h2>

<p>I realize I am myself somewhat of a centralized bottleneck. And although I find Bitcoin an extremely interesting project and believe it’s one of the most important things happening at the moment, I also have many other interests. It’s also particularly stressful and I don’t want it, nor the bizarre spats in the social media around it, to start defining me as a person.</p>

<h2 id="spreading-out">spreading out</h2>

<p>I will start by delegating my own tasks, and decreasing my involvement. I do not intend to stop contributing to Bitcoin, or even to the Bitcoin Core project, but I would like to remove myself from the critical path and take (even more) of a background role.</p>

<p>Note that we had a nice growth in development activity, and that maintenance of the code itself has already been spread over multiple people for a while. I’m not the most active maintainer. Looking at the number of git merges</p>

<div><div><pre><code>bitcoin<span>$ </span>git log <span>--pretty</span><span>=</span><span>"format:%cn"</span> <span>--merges</span> <span>--since</span><span>=</span>2020-01-01 | <span>sort</span>| <span>uniq</span> <span>-c</span>
    313 fanquake
     51 Jonas Schnelli
    727 MarcoFalke
      7 Pieter Wuille
     65 Samuel Dobson
    363 Wladimir J. van der Laan
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Only about 24% of the merges were done by me, last year.</p>

<h2 id="plans">plans</h2>

<p>But there’s plenty of things left to figure out, from the top of my head:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Decentralize distribution.</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>In the short run, transfer bitcoincore.org to an organization instead of private ownership. Reduce the “bus factor”.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>I think it would be good if some other organizations set up mirrors, so there is less incentive to try to take bitcoincore.org down.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>In the long run, move away from a website for code distribution completely. No matter who owns it, a website on the clearnet can be shut down with the press of a button, and it seems that the global internet is gearing up to make censorship increasingly easy. We need a decentralized web. For us, one option would be IPFS, which is starting to catch on. For the binaries themselves there’s already the option of downloading through torrents.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Decentralize the release process, and release signing.</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Delegate more parts of the release process. Other maintainers should be able to do a release without my involvement.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Rename the GPG key used to sign <code>SHA256SUMS.asc</code> to “Bitcoin Core release signing key”, instead of having it in my personal title. Make some construct so that N of M (minimally) trusted gitian signers doing a succesful build automatically results in a signed distribution.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Same for the native code signing for Windows and MacOS.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Even better in the long run would be to split up the keys, e.g. though RSA threshold signing, so that the whole process is geographically distributed.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Decentralize the development hub.</p>

    <ul>
      <li>It’s not clear whether github can be trusted to act in our interest in the long run. Although issues and PRs are backed up through the API, having to move somewhere else could give significant interruption in development. And hopping from provider to provider would be awful—ideally the whole thing would not rely on a central server <em>at all</em>. For this I’ve been watching the <a href="https://radicle.xyz/">radicle</a> project, a P2P distributed code collaboration platform. It’s not quite there yet, but seems promising.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Bitcoin is quite different in some of the requirements here from other FOSS projects, so we’ll have to develop some tools as we go. We could also, definitely, use some help here.</p>

<p>Some smaller things to consider:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Find someone else who wants to do the IRC meeting chair instead of me. Or maybe rotate it between multiple people.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Release (and release candidate) mails to the <code>bitcoin-dev</code> and <code>bitcoin-core-dev</code> lists will no longer be necessarily signed and sent by me.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There’s some development specific tooling hosted by me (e.g. the PR notification bots on IRC and mastodon). As they are non-critical and only little time goes into maintaining them, I’m fine with this for now.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>As for decentralizing Bitcoin’s node software itself:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Carl Dong’s <code>libbitcoin_kernel</code> work. Bitcoin Core is a large monolithic project which includes the consensus code, which is much more critical than the other parts. The kernel would be an isolated part with well-defined interface, and at some point, its own review flow for changes. The difference with previous <code>libbitcoin_consensus</code> plans is that the kernel is stateful: it includes UTXO management and validation. It however does not include P2P, mempool policy, wallet, GUI, and RPC code. It could be re-used in different clients, to have more diversity in clients, but without the risks of a deviating consensus implementation.</li>
</ul>

<p>Over the course of 2021 this will be my focus with regard to Bitcoin Core.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://laanwj.github.io/2021/01/21/decentralize.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25880727</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 08:45:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Rysolv – Fix open source issues, get paid]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 128 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25879238">thread link</a>) | @themanmaran
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://rysolv.com/issues | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rysolv.com/issues">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rysolv.com/issues</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25879238</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 03:14:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Analog Computer Inside Prime Minister]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25877102">thread link</a>) | @homarp
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | http://www.insidegmt.com/2021/01/the-analog-computer-inside-prime-minister/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.insidegmt.com/2021/01/the-analog-computer-inside-prime-minister/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="657" height="217" src="http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner2.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner2.jpg 657w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner2-300x99.jpg 300w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner2-518x171.jpg 518w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner2-82x27.jpg 82w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner2-600x198.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 657px) 100vw, 657px"></figure></div>



<p><span title="G">G</span>lance at <em>Prime Minister</em>’s game board and player mats, and the first thing you’ll notice are all the numbers. The most important one is 330: the number of seats you need for a majority in the House of Commons. In this article, we’ll take a look at <em>Prime Minister</em>’s numerical side, with a focus on its measurement of public opinion.</p>



<p>At the heart of the game is an analog computer simulating the Victorian-era British political system. It tracks and links about 30 different political factors, including Parliament’s confidence in each player, each party’s popular support in eight key sectors of the electorate, current election projections, the number of government MPs and their “moderate” or “partisan” inclinations, projected votes on the government’s bills, the “uncertainty” factor in elections and Parliamentary votes, and Queen Victoria’s support for different players. By reducing these factors to numerical values and structuring their relationships, this analog computer decides who gets to lead each party, which party controls the government, and what bills the government can pass. Whoever does the best job of manipulating the factors controls the system and gets an edge in the game.</p>



<div><figure><a href="http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1.png"><img loading="lazy" width="977" height="550" src="http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1.png" alt="" srcset="http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1.png 977w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1-300x169.png 300w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1-768x432.png 768w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1-760x428.png 760w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1-518x292.png 518w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1-82x46.png 82w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PM_1-600x338.png 600w" sizes="(max-width: 977px) 100vw, 977px"></a></figure></div>



<p>Here you can see a partial snapshot of <em>Prime Minister</em>’s game board, showing the most detailed part of its analog computer: the eight key sectors of the electorate. They include a mix of geographic, social, and ideological groups: Conservatives, Farmers, the Gentry, Ireland, Liberals, the Middle Class, Scotland, and Workers. You’ll track support for each party in each sector, moving wooden markers up and down the numerical tracks. The side with the blue rosette tracks support for the Conservative Party, and the side with the orange rosette does the same for the Liberal Party. The green circles indicate each party’s starting position in the game’s standard setup. During the game, you’ll encounter icons from bills, events, and actions that tell you when to move the markers up and down a track. By moving a marker up one step, you earn one to three popularity points, depending on the sector and your current position. The popularity points that each party earns in the different sectors are added up, and the total relative point difference between the parties determines projections for the next election.</p>



<p>The eight sectors overlap so that one voter might belong to several different sectors at once. For example, a landowner in Scotland might belong to the Conservatives, Gentry, Farmer, and Scotland sectors. The Conservative Party might win his vote by appealing to his ideological identity as a Conservative, or the Liberal Party might win his vote by appealing to his geographic Scots identity. A sector’s significance in each election varies depending on the parties’ respective strategies. If both parties neglect Farmers, then Farmers will have no significance. But if the Conservative Party maxes out its popularity among Farmers while the Liberal Party earns nothing there, the Farmers sector will weigh heavily in the next election–not only because Farmers prefer the Conservative Party, but because they have been motivated to vote according to their economic interests.</p>



<p>Different sectors have different point spreads, reflecting their importance in the Victorian-era electorate. In this era, most British subjects didn’t have the right to vote, so the point spreads aren’t simply based on population distribution. They’re based on the number of voters and each sector’s overall impact on the election results, factoring in the value of campaign contributions, endorsements, and other means of influence. This is why the Gentry sector has more points than Workers, despite being a much smaller slice of the population.</p>



<p>As the game progresses, parties will reach maximum or minimum values in some sectors. These maximums and minimums affect the game’s strategy and evoke real-life political effects. No matter how strongly Scotland prefers one party over another, Scotland’s impact is limited by the number of voters in Scotland. Once the Conservative Party has maxed out its popularity in Scotland, it can gain nothing more there; it must look for additional points in other sectors while being careful not to rock the boat in Scotland. Conversely, once the Conservative Party has bottomed out in Ireland, it has nothing more to lose there and incurs no further penalty for continuing to neglect the Irish–a circumstance which may become useful. As in real life, the parties and politicians in <em>Prime Minister </em>can’t please everyone all the time. When faced with hard choices, they favor their political patrons and write off sectors that are unimportant to them. If there’s a rail disaster in Scotland, a Conservative Prime Minister (PM) will be forced to deal with it if he wants to retain his party’s support there. But if a problem surfaces in Ireland, the same PM might choose to ignore it and focus on something else, knowing that his party can’t do any worse in Ireland.</p>



<p>In addition to tracking popular support, the sectors also track the public’s mood for partisanship, which in turn can result in “partisan” MPs who support more radical bills. The game board measures public partisanship through “red points” that are printed side-by-side next to the total points for some sectors. Not every sector produces red points. For example, the Middle Class–not known for favoring radicalism–doesn’t generate any red points. At the other end of the spectrum, the ideological sectors (Conservatives and Liberals) produce only red points. Red points are always party-specific. If a sector offers red points, it offers them to one party only. By appealing to Workers, the Liberal Party can earn up to 7 red points, reflecting the support of radical Workers who favor partisan Liberal MPs. The Conservative Party can also earn popularity points in the Workers sector, but can’t earn any red points there because Workers who support the Conservative Party prefer moderate MPs.</p>



<p>Each sector has its own flavor and strategic impact. Both parties are free to pursue popularity in any sector–the Conservative Party may pursue a limited number of points in the Liberals sector, for example–but some sectors have a natural affinity or resistance to a particular party. In pursuing popular support in the different sectors, players have to think not only about the raw number of points they earn, but also the difficulty of holding particular sectors. Scotland has the fewest points, but it’s the most stable sector. Scotland’s interests aren’t directly implicated in the hot-button political issues of the day, so there are no bills that upset the Scots. The Middle Class is equally open to both parties and offers more points than Scotland, but is somewhat harder to hold owing to its more sensitive economic and moral preferences. Players also need to think about maintaining a coherent moderate or partisan strategy. The sectors for Conservatives and Liberals are the richest in points, making them tempting targets early in the game. But appealing to voters’ partisanship results in partisan MPs who favor divisive bills that could come back to haunt you. And if your government is equally split between moderate and partisan MPs, you may have a hard time getting them to agree on legislation.</p>



<p>In standard games, <em>Prime Minister</em>’s framework supports an open-ended format in which players strive to control government, win elections, and pass bills. Different politician abilities and about 200 unique cards ensure that no two games are the same. The same framework also supports specific scenarios that simulate historical problems, like home rule for Ireland or the repeal of the Corn Laws. Automated “Clockwork” politicians can readily function within the game’s system, opening the door to solitaire play.</p>



<p>Players have a wide variety of ways to interact with the game, starting with an action point system that allows you to perform a variable number of actions per turn. Depending on your current player mat and your politician’s fixed abilities, you can campaign to increase your party’s popularity in particular sectors, debate for or against bills, flatter Her Majesty to gain her favor, or influence MPs to make them more moderate or partisan. You can also draw “supporter” cards featuring influential Victorians who perform actions on your behalf. You’ll always have many things to do and not enough action cubes to spend, forcing you to prioritize your actions while anticipating future events. The PM’s response to random events and Parliament’s enactment of important bills have consequences that ripple through the system. The players and parties are in a constant tug of war. Collecting the right supporters, unleashing them at the right moment, and coordinating your actions with other players can help you achieve a breakthrough. But the game is not all about numbers. Relationships between players also factor heavily in the game, particularly in its 3- or 4-player mode. We’ll take a look at the players’ roles and relationships in the next <em>InsideGMT</em> article for <em>Prime Minister</em>.</p>



<hr>



<div><figure><a href="https://www.gmtgames.com/p-906-prime-minister.aspx"><img loading="lazy" width="657" height="217" src="http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner3.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner3.jpg 657w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner3-300x99.jpg 300w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner3-518x171.jpg 518w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner3-82x27.jpg 82w, http://www.insidegmt.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/PrimeMinister_banner3-600x198.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 657px) 100vw, 657px"></a></figure></div>

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.insidegmt.com/2021/01/the-analog-computer-inside-prime-minister/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25877102</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 22:29:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Weak Men Are Superweapons (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 247 | Comments 148 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25876554">thread link</a>) | @skinkestek
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/Weak-Men-Are-Superweapons | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/Weak-Men-Are-Superweapons">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wikitext">

<p><span>May 12, 2014</span>
</p>
<h3>I</h3>
<p>There was an argument on Tumblr which, like so many arguments on Tumblr, was terrible. I will rephrase it just a little to make a point.
</p>
<p>Alice said something along the lines of “I hate people who frivolously diagnose themselves with autism without knowing anything about the disorder. They should stop thinking they’re ‘so speshul’ and go see a competent doctor.”
</p>
<p>Beth answered something along the lines of “I diagnosed myself with autism, but only after a lot of careful research. I don’t have the opportunity to go see a doctor. I think what you’re saying is overly strict and hurtful to many people with autism.”
</p>
<p>Alice then proceeded to tell Beth she disagreed, in that special way only Tumblr users can. I believe the word “cunt” was used.
</p>
<p>I notice two things about the exchange.
</p>
<p>First, why did Beth take the bait? Alice said she hated people who <em>frivolously</em> self-diagnosed <em>without knowing anything about the disorder</em>. Beth clearly was not such a person. Why didn’t she just say “Yes, please continue hating these hypothetical bad people who are not me”?
</p>
<p>Second, why did <em>Alice</em> take the bait? Why didn’t she just say “I think you’ll find I wasn’t talking about you?”
</p>
<h3>II</h3>
<p>One of the cutting-edge advances in fallacy-ology has been the <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/getting-duped/" rel="nofollow">weak man</a>, a terribly-named cousin of the straw man. The straw man is a terrible argument nobody really holds, which was only invented so your side had something easy to defeat. The weak man is a terrible argument that only a few unrepresentative people hold, which was only <em>brought to prominence</em> so your side had something easy to defeat.
</p>
<p>For example, “I am a proud atheist and I don’t like religion. Think of the terrible things done by religion, like the actions of the Westboro Baptist Church. They try to disturb the funerals of heroes because they think God hates everybody. But this is horrible. Religious people can’t justify why they do things like this. That’s why I’m proud to be an atheist.”
</p>
<p>It’s not a straw man. There really is a Westboro Baptist Church, for some reason. But one still feels like the atheist is making things just a little too easy on himself.
</p>
<p>Maybe the problem is that the atheist is indirectly suggesting that Westboro Baptist Church is typical of religion? An implied falsehood?
</p>
<p>Then suppose the atheist posts on Tumblr: “I hate religious people who are rabidly certain that the world was created in seven days or that all their enemies will burn in Hell, and try to justify it through ‘faith’. You know, the sort of people who think that the Bible has all the answers and who hate anyone who tries to think for themselves.”
</p>
<p>Now there’s practically no implication that these people are typical. So that’s fine, right?
</p>
<p>On the other side of the world, a religious person is writing “I hate atheists who think morality is relative, and that this gives them the right to murder however many people stand between them and a world where no one is allowed to believe in God”.
</p>
<p>Again, not a straw man. The Soviet Union contained several million of these people. But if you’re an atheist, would you just let this pass?
</p>
<p>How about “I hate black thugs who rob people”?
</p>
<p>What are the chances a black guy reads that and says “Well, good thing I’m not a thug who robs people, he’ll probably <em>love</em> me”?
</p>
<h3>III</h3>
<p>What is the problem with statements like this?
</p>
<p>First, they are meant to re-center a category. Remember, people think in terms of categories with central and noncentral members – a sparrow is a central bird, an ostrich a noncentral one. But if you live on the Ostrich World, which is inhabited only by ostriches, emus, and cassowaries, then probably an ostrich seems like a pretty central example of ‘bird’ and the first sparrow you see will be fantastically strange.
</p>
<p>Right now most people’s central examples of religion are probably things like your local neighborhood church. If you’re American, it’s probably a bland Protestant denomination like the Episcopalians or something.
</p>
<p>The guy whose central examples of religion are Pope Francis and the Dalai Lama is probably going to have a different perception of religion than the guy whose central examples are Torquemada and Fred Phelps. If you convert someone from the first kind of person to the second kind of person, you’ve gone most of the way to making them an atheist.
</p>
<p>More important, if you convert a culture from thinking in the first type of way to thinking in the second type of way, then religious people will be unpopular and anyone trying to make a religious argument will have to spend the first five minutes of their speech explaining how they’re not Fred Phelps, honest, and no, they don’t picket any funerals. After all that time spent apologizing and defending themselves and distancing themselves from other religious people, they’re not likely to be able to make a very rousing argument for religion.
</p>
<h3>IV</h3>
<p>In <a href="https://slatestarcodex.com/2014/04/15/the-cowpox-of-doubt/" rel="nofollow">Cowpox of Doubt</a>, I mention the inoculation effect. When people see a terrible argument for an idea get defeated, they are more likely to doubt the idea later on, even if much better arguments show up.
</p>
<p>Put this in the context of people attacking the Westboro Baptist Church. You see the attacker win a big victory over “religion”, broadly defined. Now you are less likely to believe in religion when a much more convincing one comes along.
</p>
<p>I see the same thing in atheists’ odd fascination with creationism. Most of the religious people one encounters are not young-earth creationists. But these people have a dramatic hold on the atheist imagination.
</p>
<p>And I think: well, maybe if people see atheists defeating a terrible argument for religion enough, atheists don’t <em>have to</em> defeat any of the others. People have already been inoculated against religion. “Oh, yeah, that was the thing with the creationism. Doesn’t seem very smart.”
</p>
<p>If this is true, it means that all religious people, like it or not, are in the same boat. An atheist attacking creationism becomes a deadly threat for the average Christian, even if that Christian does not herself believe in creationism.
</p>
<p>Likewise, when a religious person attacks atheists who are moral relativists, or communists, or murderers, then all atheists have to band together to stop it somehow or they will have successfully poisoned people against atheism.
</p>
<h3>V</h3>
<p>This is starting to sound a lot like <a href="http://squid314.livejournal.com/329171.html" rel="nofollow">something I wrote on my old blog about superweapons</a>.
</p>
<p>I suggested imagining yourself in the shoes of a Jew in czarist Russia. The big news story is about a Jewish man who killed a Christian child. As far as you can tell the story is true. It’s just disappointing that everyone who tells it is describing it as “A Jew killed a Christian kid today”. You don’t want to make a big deal over this, because no one is saying anything objectionable like “And so all Jews are evil”. Besides you’d hate to inject identity politics into this obvious tragedy. It just sort of makes you uncomfortable.
</p>
<p>The next day you hear that the local priest is giving a sermon on how the Jews killed Christ. This statement seems historically plausible, and it’s part of the Christian religion, and no one is implying it says anything about the Jews today. You’d hate to be the guy who barges in and tries to tell the Christians what Biblical facts they can and can’t include in their sermons just because they offend you. It would make you an annoying busybody. So again you just get uncomfortable.
</p>
<p>The next day you hear people complain about the greedy Jewish bankers who are ruining the world economy. And really a disproportionate number of bankers are Jewish, and bankers really do seem to be the source of a lot of economic problems. It seems kind of pedantic to interrupt every conversation with “But also some bankers are Christian, or Muslim, and even though a disproportionate number of bankers are Jewish that doesn’t mean the Jewish bankers are disproportionately active in ruining the world economy compared to their numbers.” So again you stay uncomfortable.
</p>
<p>Then the next day you hear people complain about Israeli atrocities in Palestine (what, you thought this was past czarist Russia? This is future czarist Russia, after Putin finally gets the guts to crown himself). You understand that the Israelis really do commit some terrible acts. On the other hand, when people start talking about “Jewish atrocities” and “the need to protect Gentiles from Jewish rapacity” and “laws to stop all this horrible stuff the Jews are doing”, you just feel worried, even though you personally are not doing any horrible stuff and maybe they even have good reasons for phrasing it that way.
</p>
<p>Then the next day you get in a business dispute with your neighbor. Maybe you loaned him some money and he doesn’t feel like paying you back. He tells you you’d better just give up, admit he is in the right, and apologize to him – because if the conflict escalated everyone would take his side because he is a Christian and you are a Jew. And everyone knows that Jews victimize Christians and are basically child-murdering Christ-killing economy-ruining atrocity-committing scum.
</p>
<p>You have been boxed in by a serious of individually harmless but collectively dangerous statements. None of them individually referred to you – you weren’t murdering children or killing Christ or owning a bank. But they ended up getting you in the end anyway.
</p>
<p>Depending on how likely you think this is, this kind of forces Jews together, makes them become strange bedfellows. You might not like what the Jews in Israel are doing in Palestine. But if you think someone’s trying to build a superweapon against you, and you don’t think you can differentiate yourself from the Israelis reliably, it’s in your best interest to defend them anyway.
</p>
<h3>VI</h3>
<p>I wrote the superweapon post to address some of my worries about feminism, so it would not be surprising at all if we found this dynamic there.
</p>
<p>Feminists tend to talk about things like “Men tend to silence women and not respect their opinions” or “Men treat women like objects …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/Weak-Men-Are-Superweapons">https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/Weak-Men-Are-Superweapons</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/Weak-Men-Are-Superweapons</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25876554</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 21:26:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[.NET GC Internals mini-series]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 161 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25876087">thread link</a>) | @GordonS
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://tooslowexception.com/net-gc-internals-mini-series/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tooslowexception.com/net-gc-internals-mini-series/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-625">
	
		
	
	<div itemprop="articleBody">
				<p>I’ve decided to make a series of at least <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLpUkQYy-K8Y-wYcDgDXKhfs6OT8fFQtVm" target="_blank">8 free weekly-based webinars</a> about<strong> in-depth implementation details of the .NET GC</strong> and… I’m super happy with it! Why the idea? Many <strong>my other activities are about more practical “.NET memory management”</strong>, like <a href="https://prodotnetmemory.com/" target="_blank">my book</a> or <a href="https://workshop.prodotnetmemory.com/" target="_blank">workshops/trainings/consultancy</a> I gave. But during all this practical-oriented events t<strong>here is always not enough time</strong> to explain in details how .NET GC is implemented. Obviously, I always explain some concepts and algorithms, to the level that helps in understanding the whole concept. But not with the level of details that I am satisfied.</p>
<p>Hence the idea – make a separate <strong>content that will be just as deep as I like</strong> 🙂 So, I will cover details on the level of bits, bytes and source code, not only on the level of the overall algorithm description.</p>
<p>The first episode was yesterday, feel invited to watch:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8i1Nv7wGsjk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>

<p>The topics I’ve covered in the first module:</p>
<ul>
<li>the whole series roadmap</li>
<li>some fundamentals like reference counting (including more modern algorithms) and tracing GC</li>
<li>.NET GC types and its history</li>
<li>first dive into the .NET 5 runtime source code, including the first breakpoints in the famous 40 kLOC gc.cpp</li>
</ul>
<p>And the whole <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLpUkQYy-K8Y-wYcDgDXKhfs6OT8fFQtVm" target="_blank">playlist is also available on YouTube</a>.</p>
<p>The topics I will cover during the whole series are as follows:</p>
<p><a href="https://tooslowexception.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/gcwebinar02.png"><img src="https://tooslowexception.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/gcwebinar02-1024x535.png" alt="gcwebinar02" width="720" height="376" srcset="https://tooslowexception.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/gcwebinar02-1024x535.png 1024w, https://tooslowexception.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/gcwebinar02-300x157.png 300w, https://tooslowexception.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/gcwebinar02-768x401.png 768w, https://tooslowexception.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/gcwebinar02.png 1402w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px"></a></p>
<p>And we will see whethere it ends after eight episodes, or maybe a new interesting topics will emerge (including, from your questions).</p>
<p>Have a nice watch!</p>
							</div>
		</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tooslowexception.com/net-gc-internals-mini-series/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25876087</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 20:39:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How hard should I push myself?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 260 | Comments 175 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25874374">thread link</a>) | @dshipper
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://superorganizers.every.to/p/how-hard-should-i-push-myself | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://superorganizers.every.to/p/how-hard-should-i-push-myself">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F3d2ebce7-e447-49bf-a6b4-f78c21198041_1400x934.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F3d2ebce7-e447-49bf-a6b4-f78c21198041_1400x934.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/3d2ebce7-e447-49bf-a6b4-f78c21198041_1400x934.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:934,&quot;width&quot;:1400,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:181814,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>How hard should I push myself?</p><p>It’s a question I ask myself a lot, and I bet you do too. On the one hand I really want to push myself. I’m ambitious, I want to leave it all out on the field—some of my peak work moments have come from times when I’ve pushed myself to a place where I didn’t think I could go. We all have more ability to adapt to stress and pressure than we think we do.</p><p>On the other hand, I want to be kind to myself. I wonder how much the drive to push myself is really just a drive to make up for something that I feel is missing or inadequate—and whether pushing myself will actually fill the hole. I also sometimes wonder whether letting myself off the hook is just laziness masquerading as self-care. It’s hard to tell.</p><p>But importantly, I wonder whether pushing myself might, in fact, kill me. Constant pressure creates chronic stress, and there’s all sorts of scientific studies that show that chronic stress is really bad for you. It makes you more susceptible to heart disease, it makes it harder to recover from illnesses, it can affect your sleep, and it can even affect your working memory.</p><p>There’s also all sorts of literature (and conversations on Twitter) that says that stress is actually good for you.&nbsp;</p><p>What gives? How much stress is good, and how much is bad?&nbsp;</p><p>I think that in order to understand the question we posed at the top—how much we should be pushing ourselves—we have to better understand stress. We need to understand what the stress of pushing ourselves does to our bodies, how much we can take of it, and how we can, hopefully, learn to cope with it better.</p><p>That’s what <a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780805073690">Why Zebra's Don't Get Ulcers</a> by Robert M. Sapolsky is about. Robert's a stress researcher, and as far as I can tell he's one of the good ones. He's the kind of intellectual who's smart, but also smart enough to know what he doesn't know. He's written a book, but he doesn't come across as trying to sell it to you—he's kind of like your zany self-aware smart-as-hell uncle who happens to study the stress responses of baboons for a living.</p><p>In the book Dr. Sapolsky harnesses his own research, as well as a wide array of animal and human studies to figure out the answer to a fairly simple question: how does stress work, and why do humans get stress-related diseases?&nbsp;</p><p>It’s an interesting question—you can understand why a human body might react poorly to not being fed enough. But why would psychological stress have dangerous consequences? The basic gist is this:&nbsp;</p><p>The stress response is built to get us out of danger. If you're an animal in the Serengeti and you're being chased by a lion you really, really want to have a stress response. Being stressed means you’re preparing your muscles to move—a lot. Your heart rate rises and pushes blood to your extremities. Glucose is released into your bloodstream to help run your muscles as fast as possible.&nbsp;</p><p>The stress response pushes certain parts of your body into high gear—but it also turns certain parts of your body off. For example, when you’re stressed digestion is inhibited. What’s the point of wasting energy on digesting food for later when you might not even survive for 10 more minutes? Reproduction is also inhibited. Same reason.&nbsp;</p><p>This is all well and good in the wild—you don't need to reproduce if a lion is eating your face off. But humans, and some more intelligent animals, have evolved the stress response from an unqualified Good Thing into...well, something that might kill you.</p><p>What’s different about our stress response? Well, we have the ability to <em>anticipate</em> danger. Other animals have this ability too: it’s a good thing to get stressed seeing the lion all the way across the savannah, instead of only when it mauls your intestines out. But humans have evolved this anticipation ability to extend far beyond other animals. We anticipate bad things months, years, or even decades out. And when we do this, the very same stress response gets turned on—even though there is no immediate danger, and there is no immediate way to avoid it.&nbsp;</p><p>Suddenly, you aren’t just activating the stress response for a few minutes when you’re running for your life. Instead, it’s activated all the time—chronically. And this is where the problems start.&nbsp;</p><p>Remember we mentioned earlier that the stress response amps some parts of your body into high gear, and turns off others? If you’re doing that chronically, you start to have problems. Suddenly, your digestive system isn’t just inhibited for a few minutes while you’re escaping danger. It’s chronically inhibited. The same thing happens with your immune system—chronic stress tamps it down, and makes it harder for you to fight off diseases. Stress is bad for your heart too—if you’re pumping blood as if you need to run from something all the time, you’re going to get high blood pressure.&nbsp;</p><p>In these cases, according to Sapolsky, “the stress response can become more dangerous than the stressor itself, especially when the stress is purely psychological.”</p><p>To be clear, stress doesn’t actually make you sick. But it does leave you more vulnerable to disease and illnesses than you otherwise would be—and those <em>can</em> make you very sick.</p><h3><strong>So is stress bad?</strong></h3><p>Stress isn’t good or bad. It’s a tool. In small doses it’s good, but too much of a good thing becomes a bad thing pretty quickly.</p><p>When your stress response is working properly it makes you run faster, your memory gets better, you’re able to focus better. But when your stress response is over-activated, or chronically activated—you get ulcers and heart disease. It’s bad!&nbsp;</p><p>A good analogy is exercise. Too little exercise and you open yourself up to a whole host of diseases, both physical and psychological. Too much, and you can actually kill yourself.&nbsp;</p><h3><strong>What do we do about it?</strong></h3><p>The answer to the question we posed at the top, then, is that it’s great to push yourself—but you should be paying attention to the signs that tell you that you need a break. And it’s to give yourself plenty of ways to manage stress while you’re going through it, so that it doesn’t affect you as badly as it could.</p><p>This is the really interesting nugget: stress isn’t mathematical. Expose the same person to the same stressor and they will have different stress responses based on their coping strategies. Which means if you want to live a life where you’re pushing yourself, it’s best to develop a variety of coping strategies to help you manage it.&nbsp;</p><p>Here’s what Sapolsky recommends:</p><h4><strong>Increase your sense of control</strong>.&nbsp;</h4><p>If you put a human in a room where loud noises are going off, you’ll activate their stress response. If you give the human a button to reduce the volume of the loud noises they’ll be less stressed—regardless of whether they even use the button.&nbsp;</p><p>What that means is, just knowing you have the <em>option</em> to reduce stress is enough to make something less stressful—even if you’re not actually controlling the stressors at all.&nbsp;</p><p>It’s why the first few sessions of therapy are often so powerful for patients. You’ve finally found a way to manage how you’re feeling, even though you probably haven’t changed too much about your life.</p><p>When you’re facing mild to moderate stressors, ask yourself, <em>How can I increase my sense of control in this situation?</em> You might find there are simple answers that will make you feel a lot better.</p><h4><strong>Increase your sense of predictability.</strong></h4><p>Rats that are exposed to repeated electric shocks are more likely to get ulcers. But if you ring a bell before you administer the shock—making the shock more predictable—the rats are less likely to get ulcers. If you make the stressor predictable, you only have to get stressed right before it happens. That means you’re not stressed the rest of the time, and therefore the stress response doesn’t wreak as much havoc on your body.</p><p>Making the stressors in your life more predictable can have a similar effect. When you see CEOs that keep their calendars clear and never do phone calls—you’re seeing the benefit of predictability in action.</p><p>Of course, we can’t make our lives totally predictable (and in fact that wouldn’t be desirable.) But the more you can expose yourself to stressors in a predictable way the better off you’ll be. For example, maybe only doomscroll on Twitter once a week. Or only check email a couple of times a day.</p><h4><strong>Create outlets for frustration.</strong></h4><p>When rats that are exposed to repeated stressors are given a piece of wood to gnaw on, they are far less likely to develop ulcers. Outlets for frustration are another important coping mechanism for stress.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>There are many unproductive outlets—for example, taking things out on your partner or a co-worker. But there are also many productive ones, like exercise or journaling. Making a list of outlets and making sure to return to them again and again can reduce the havoc that chronic stress can wreak on your body.</p><h4><strong>Increase social support.</strong></h4><p>Social support is the last coping strategy on the list, and it’s perhaps my favorite one.</p><p>If you give a primate a stressor in the lab, you’ll find elevated markers of stress in its behavior and in its blood. But give the primate a stressor when it’s surrounded by friends—its stress markers will be lower, even for the same level of stressor.</p><p>The same thing happens in humans. For example, in one study parents of children who have been killed in war were no more likely to get disease or die—except if they were already widowed or divorced.</p><p>Creating a vibrant sense of social support can put an unmanageable stressor into perspective and help keep it under control. Without social support, even small things can set us off in ways that are unproductive and unhealthy.</p><h2><strong>What did you think of this article?</strong></h2><p><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeMqlgyA7pSRFgxvzNkEFFqsPIvmkxtZ81IiGD0LQzYFL5-AA/viewform?usp=pp_url&amp;entry.1276325438=Amazing">Amazing</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeMqlgyA7pSRFgxvzNkEFFqsPIvmkxtZ81IiGD0LQzYFL5-AA/viewform?usp=pp_url&amp;entry.1276325438=Good">Good</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeMqlgyA7pSRFgxvzNkEFFqsPIvmkxtZ81IiGD0LQzYFL5-AA/viewform?usp=pp_url&amp;entry.1276325438=Meh">Meh</a>&nbsp;-&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeMqlgyA7pSRFgxvzNkEFFqsPIvmkxtZ81IiGD0LQzYFL5-AA/viewform?usp=pp_url&amp;entry.1276325438=Bad">Bad</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://superorganizers.every.to/p/how-hard-should-i-push-myself</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25874374</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 18:16:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Dissecting the Apple M1 GPU, Part II]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 517 | Comments 173 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25873887">thread link</a>) | @dddddaviddddd
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://rosenzweig.io/blog/asahi-gpu-part-2.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rosenzweig.io/blog/asahi-gpu-part-2.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
<header><p>22 Jan 2021</p></header><p>Less than a month ago, I began <a href="https://rosenzweig.io/blog/asahi-gpu-part-1.html">investigating the Apple M1 GPU</a> in hopes of developing a free and open-source driver. This week, I’ve reached a second milestone: drawing a triangle with my own open-source code. The vertex and fragment shaders are handwritten in machine code, and I interface with the hardware via the IOKit kernel driver in an identical fashion to the system’s Metal userspace driver.</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://rosenzweig.io/M1HelloTriangle.png" alt=""><figcaption>A triangle rendered on the M1 with open-source code</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The bulk of the new code is responsible for constructing the various command buffers and descriptors resident in shared memory, used to control the GPU’s behaviour. Any state accessible from Metal corresponds to bits in these buffers, so understanding them will be the next major task. So far, I have focused less on the content and more on the connections between them. In particular, the structures contain pointers to one another, sometimes nested multiple layers deep. The bring-up process for the project’s triangle provides a bird’s eye view of how all these disparate pieces in memory fit together.</p>
<p>As an example, the application-provided vertex data are in their own buffers. An internal table in yet another buffer points each of these vertex buffers. That internal table is passed directly as input to the vertex shader, specified in another buffer. That description of the vertex shader, including the address of the code in executable memory, is pointed to by another buffer, itself referenced from the main command buffer, which is referenced by a handle in the IOKit call to submit a command buffer. Whew!</p>
<p>In other words, the demo code is not yet intended to demonstrate an understanding of the fine-grained details of the command buffers, but rather to demonstrate there is “nothing missing”. Since GPU virtual addresses change from run to run, the demo validates that all of the pointers required are identified and can be relocated freely in memory using our own (trivial) allocator. As there is a bit of “magic” around memory and command buffer allocation on macOS, having this code working at an early stage gives peace of mind going forward.</p>
<p>I employed a piecemeal bring-up process. Since my IOKit wrapper exists in the same address space as the Metal application, the wrapper may modify command buffers just before submission to the GPU. As an early “hello world”, I identified the encoding of the render target’s clear colour in memory, and demonstrated that I could modify the colour as I pleased. Similarly, while learning about the instruction set to bring up the disassembler, I replaced shaders with handwritten equivalents and confirmed I could execute code on the GPU, provided I wrote out the machine code. But it’s not necessary to stop at these “leaf nodes” of the system; after modifying the shader code, I tried uploading shader code to a different part of the executable buffer while modifying the command buffer’s pointer to the code to compensate. After that, I could try uploading the commands for the shader myself. Iterating in this fashion, I could build up every structure needed while testing each in isolation.</p>
<p>Despite curveballs, this procedure worked out far better than the alternative of jumping straight to constructing buffers, perhaps via a “replay”. I had used that alternate technique to bring-up Mali a few years back, but it comes with the substantial drawback of fiendishly difficult debugging. If there is a single typo in five hundred lines of magic numbers, there would be no feedback, except an error from the GPU. However, by working one bit at a time, errors could be pinpointed and fixed immediately, providing a faster turn around time and a more pleasant bring-up experience.</p>
<p>But curveballs there were! My momentary elation at modifying the clear colours disappeared when I attempted to allocate a buffer for the colours. Despite encoding the same bits as before, the GPU would fail to clear correctly. Wondering if there was something wrong with the way I modified the pointer, I tried placing the colour in an unused part of memory that was already created by the Metal driver – that worked. The contents were the same, the way I modified the pointers was the same, but somehow the GPU didn’t like my memory allocation. I wondered if there was something wrong with the way I allocated memory, but the arguments I used to invoke the memory allocation IOKit call were bit-identical to those used by Metal, as confirmed by <code>wrap</code>. My last-ditch effort was checking if GPU memory had to be mapped explicitly via some side channel, like the <code>mmap</code> system call. IOKit does feature a device-independent memory map call, but no amount of fortified tracing found any evidence of side-channel system call mappings.</p>
<p>Trouble was brewing. Feeling delirious after so much time chasing an “impossible” bug, I wondered if there wasn’t something “magic” in the system call… but rather in the GPU memory itself. It was a silly theory since it produces a serious chicken-and-egg problem if true: if a GPU allocation has to be blessed by another GPU allocation, who blesses the first allocation?</p>
<p>But feeling silly and perhaps desperate, I pressed forward to test the theory by inserting a memory allocation call <em>in the middle</em> of the application flow, such that every subsequent allocation would be at a different address. Dumping GPU memory before and after this change and checking for differences revealed my first horror: an auxiliary buffer in GPU memory tracked all of the required allocations. In particular, I noticed values in this buffer increasing by one at a predictable offset (every <code>0x40</code> bytes), suggesting that the buffer contained an array of handles to allocations. Indeed, these values corresponded exactly to handles returned from the kernel on GPU memory allocation calls.</p>
<p>Putting aside the obvious problems with this theory, I tested it anyway, modifying this table to include an extra entry at the end with the handle of my new allocation, and modifying the header data structure to bump the number of entries by one. Still no dice. Discouraging as it was, that did not sink the theory entirely. In fact, I noticed something peculiar about the entries: contrary to what I thought, not <em>all</em> of them corresponded to valid handles. No, all but the <em>last</em> entry were valid. The handles from the kernel are 1-indexed, yet in each memory dump, the final handle was always <code>0</code>, nonexistent. Perhaps this acts as a sentinel value, analogous to NULL-terminated strings in C. That explanation begs the question of why? If the header already contains a count of entries, a sentinel value is redundant.</p>
<p>I pressed on. Instead of adding on an extra entry with my handle, I copied the last entry <code>n</code> to the extra entry <code>n + 1</code> and overwrote the (now second to last) entry <code>n</code> with the new handle.</p>
<p>Suddenly my clear colour showed up.</p>
<p>Is the mystery solved? I got the code working, so in some sense, the answer must be yes. But this is hardly a satisfying explanation; at every step, the unlikely solution only raises more questions. The chicken-and-egg problem is the easiest to resolve: this mapping table, along with the root command buffer, is allocated via a special IOKit selector independent from the general buffer allocation, and the handle to the mapping table is passed along with the submit command buffer selector. Further, the idea of passing required handles with command buffer submission is not unheard of; a similar mechanism is used on mainline Linux drivers. Nevertheless, the rationale for using 64-byte table entries in shared memory, as opposed to a simple CPU-side array, remains totally elusive.</p>
<p>Putting memory allocation woes behind me, the road ahead was not without bumps (and potholes), but with patience, I iterated until I had constructed the entirety of GPU memory myself in parallel to Metal, relying on the proprietary userspace only to initialize the device. Finally, all that remained was a leap of faith to kick off the IOKit handshake myself, and I had my first triangle.</p>
<p>These changes amount to around 1700 lines of code since the last blog post, available on <a href="https://github.com/AsahiLinux/gpu">GitHub</a>. I’ve pieced together a simple demo animating a triangle with the GPU on-screen. The window system integration is effectively nonexistent at this point: XQuartz is required and detiling the (64x64 Morton-order interleaved) framebuffer occurs in software with naive scalar code. Nevertheless, the M1’s CPU is more than fast enough to cope.</p>
<p>Now that each part of the userspace driver is bootstrapped, going forward we can iterate on the instruction set and the command buffers in isolation. We can tease apart the little details and bit-by-bit transform the code from hundreds of inexplicable magic constants to a real driver. Onwards!</p>
<p><a href="https://rosenzweig.io/">Back to home</a></p>
</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rosenzweig.io/blog/asahi-gpu-part-2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25873887</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 17:34:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The strange economics of open-source software (2015)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25873194">thread link</a>) | @alexrustic
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://www.philipotoole.com/the-strange-economics-of-open-source-software/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.philipotoole.com/the-strange-economics-of-open-source-software/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p><a href="https://www.maynardkeynes.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="John Maynard Keynes" src="https://www.philipotoole.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/keynes-150x150.png" alt="John Maynard Keynes" width="150" height="150"></a>I always use the names of economists for my machines’ <a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1034" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">hostnames</a>. <a href="http://www.econlib.org/library/Enc/bios/Keynes.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>keynes</em></a>, <a href="http://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/economic-sciences/laureates/1976/friedman-bio.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>friedman</em></a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Marx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>marx</em></a>, <em><a href="https://fraser.stlouisfed.org/docs/meltzer/fisdeb33.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fisher</a>, </em><em><a href="http://www.britannica.com/biography/David-Ricardo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ricardo</a></em>.</p>
<p>So every so often the strange economics of open-source software hits me.</p>
<p><span id="more-2749"></span><br>
Today it is almost taken for granted that the source code for most software is freely available. This is a profound and remarkable change, given how different it was only 15 years ago. From a certain point of view our industry is “giving away” its product, and yet the industry <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/20/opinion/is-big-tech-too-powerful-ask-google.html?_r=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">is richer and more powerful than ever</a>.&nbsp; So where is the value? What are the implications?</p>
<h2>Where has all the closed-source software gone?</h2>
<p>Of course, it’s not <strong>gone</strong>. It’s there at the banks, within embedded devices, and companies such as <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft</a> and <a href="https://www.oracle.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Oracle</a> remain among the most powerful companies in the world, but almost all the innovation — and most importantly most of the excitement —&nbsp; is happening within open-source.</p>
<p>Within our industry it is becoming apparent that services — <a href="http://searchcloudcomputing.techtarget.com/definition/Software-as-a-Service" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaaS</a>&nbsp; and companies such as <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Airbnb </a>— are the future.&nbsp; And in fact, it sometimes seems to be that the only way to write really valuable closed-source software nowadays is within the context of a service. Behind all the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">REST</a> endpoints, the&nbsp; <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS ELBs</a>, and the<a href="http://www.haproxy.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> HAProxy systems</a>, sits some of most closely-guarded software in the world.</p>
<h2>The ever-increasing dominance of open-source</h2>
<p>The increasing dominance of open-source software seems particularly true with respect to infrastructure software.&nbsp; While security software has often been open-source through necessity — no-one would trust it otherwise — infrastructure is becoming the dominant category of open-source. Look at databases — <a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/internals/en/guided-tour.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MySQL</a>, <a href="https://www.mongodb.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MongoDB</a>, <a href="https://www.rethinkdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RethinkDB</a>, <a href="https://github.com/apache/couchdb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CouchDB</a>, <a href="https://influxdb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">InfluxDB</a> (of which I am part of the <a href="https://github.com/influxdata/influxdb/graphs/contributors" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">development team</a>), or <a href="http://www.cockroachlabs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cockroachdb</a>. Is there anyone today that would even consider developing a new closed-source database? Or take search technology — <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">elasticsearch</a>, <a href="http://lucene.apache.org/solr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Solr</a>, and <a href="http://www.blevesearch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">bleve</a> — all open-source. And <a href="https://www.linux.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Linux</a> is so obvious, it is almost pointless to mention it.<br>
If you want to create a closed-source infrastructure solution, you better have an enormously compelling story, or be delivering it as part of a bigger package such as a software appliance.</p>
<h2>So where is the value?</h2>
<p>Compared to when I first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nortel" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">started programming,</a> that some of the most valuable companies in software now give away their product is astounding, when you actually think about it. So where is the real value within a such a company, when its product is free? It’s where it’s always been — just more so.</p>
<p>The real value is within the development team and its ideas, that the team behind the software are, and remain, innovative, execute well, and produce quality software. And that they remain so is key — so that it does not matter that what they produce is freely available.&nbsp; It is of little benefit to a competitor that the source is freely available, when the team behind the project is probably six months ahead — and often more — conceptually in terms of design, development and process.</p>
<h2>The economics of recruitment</h2>
<p>And the implications go far beyond how software is developed.<br>
It is generally accepted these days within <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Silicon_Valley">The Valley</a> that large, older, firms find it particularly hard to hire. The excitement, and latitude for creativity, within a start-up has always appealed, and even more so now with the outstanding <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2014-10-28/facebook-s-22-billion-whatsapp-deal-buys-10-million-in-sales" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">commercial success of some</a>.</p>
<p>But a second-order effect is also prevalent — many developers baulk at the idea that their work may never be seen by their peers in the open-source community, and therefore may never help them progress in their careers. And it is at larger, older firms, that the least amount of open-source software is written — what <a href="http://paulgraham.com/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Paul Graham</a> calls <a href="http://paulgraham.com/ideas.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">downwind jobs</a>.</p>
<p>But Services remain part of the future — because while the code that Service software developers write may not be visible, the functionality is visible to the world and with the advent of cloud-computing, the power accruing to these developers is significant and growing. Services can hire, unlike the traditional firms.</p>
<h2>Possibilities for our grandchildren</h2>
<p>The rise of open-source has been a remarkable development in the history of economics and production. I often wonder what <a href="http://www.econ.yale.edu/smith/econ116a/keynes1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Keynes</a>, Marx, and even Ricardo, would think of it all.</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.philipotoole.com/the-strange-economics-of-open-source-software/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25873194</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 16:40:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pidgin – A Universal Chat Client]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 619 | Comments 420 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25872525">thread link</a>) | @smusamashah
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://www.pidgin.im/plugins | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.pidgin.im/plugins">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/awslabs/pidgin-chime/">Amazon Chime</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Community">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Online meeting and video conferencing
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Amazon Web Services - Labs
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/nmbook/pidgin-libbnet/">Battle.net Classic</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Community">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Blizzard’s gaming network: notably for StarCraft, Diablo II, and WarCraft III
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                nmbook
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol" istrusted="true">
                            <td>
                                <img src="https://github.com/EionRobb/purple-battlenet/raw/master/battlenet48.png" alt="Battle.net v2 logo">
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/EionRobb/purple-battlenet#readme">Battle.net v2</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Trusted">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Blizzard’s gaming network for WoW, Overwatch and others
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                EionRobb
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol">
                            <td>
                                <img src="https://github.com/jrfoell/campfire-libpurple/raw/master/campfire48.png" alt="Campfire logo">
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/jrfoell/campfire-libpurple/">Campfire</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Community">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol plugin for Basecamp’s Campfire IM
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                jrfoell
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/ccpp/deltachat-purple/">Deltachat</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Community">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                IM over email
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                ccpp
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol" istrusted="true">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/EionRobb/purple-discord/#readme">Discord</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Trusted">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Text chat for gamers
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                EionRobb
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/samuelkarp/purple-docker/">Docker</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Community">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Send stdin commands to Docker containers
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                samuelkarp
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/fchat-pidgin/fchat-pidgin#readme">F-List</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Community">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                F-List roleplaying community
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                fchat-pidgin
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol" istrusted="true">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/dequis/purple-facebook/wiki/">Facebook</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Trusted">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Facebook chat
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                dequis
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol" istrusted="true">
                            <td>
                                <img src="https://github.com/EionRobb/purple-gammu/raw/master/icons/48/gammu.png" alt="Gammu logo">
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/EionRobb/purple-gammu/#readme">Gammu</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Trusted">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Send SMS through your feature phone via usb/serial/bluetooth/irda
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                EionRobb
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol" istrusted="true">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://notabug.org/alyssa/groupme-purple/">GroupMe</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Trusted">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                GroupMe group messaging
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Alyssa Rosenzweig
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol" istrusted="true">
                            <td>
                                <img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/1063865/87138135-18131780-c2f2-11ea-9579-3dfbb7d858fb.png" alt="Hangouts logo">
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/EionRobb/purple-hangouts#readme">Hangouts</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Trusted">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Alternative plugin for Google Hangouts
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                EionRobb
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol">
                            <td>
                                <img src="https://github.com/theli-ua/honpurple/raw/master/data/pixmaps/pidgin/emblems/16/hon_ingame.png" alt="Heroes of Newerth logo">
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/theli-ua/honpurple/">Heroes of Newerth</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Community">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Online video game
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                theli-ua
                            </td>
                        </tr>
                        <tr data-type="Protocol" istrusted="true">
                            <td>
                                &nbsp;
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <a href="https://github.com/EionRobb/icyque/">ICQ WIM (IcyQue)</a>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                <span aria-label="Trusted">
                                    <i></i>
                                </span>
                            </td>
                            <td>
                                Protocol
                            </td>
              …</tr></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.pidgin.im/plugins">https://www.pidgin.im/plugins</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.pidgin.im/plugins</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25872525</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 15:37:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A story about pivots]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 123 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25871629">thread link</a>) | @james_impliu
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://posthog.com/blog/story-about-pivots | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://posthog.com/blog/story-about-pivots">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><div><p>PostHog has pivoted <em>a lot</em>.</p>
<p>After 5 pivots in 6 months, we got into <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/">YCombinator</a> last year, pivoted again whilst we were there and have now gone from the first commit to thousands of deployments, a team across 10 countries and $12M raised, in well under a year. We've a long way to go, but we're delighted at how it has gone so far.</p>
<p>This is that story and what we learned from it.</p>
<h2 id="youll-feel-silly"><a href="#youll-feel-silly" aria-label="youll feel silly permalink"></a>You'll feel silly</h2>
<p>It goes something like this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Convince yourself then your family, friends and colleagues you have some great idea.</li>
<li>Quit your job.</li>
<li>Build it. Listen to the soundtrack from <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1285016/">The Social Network</a> way too much.</li>
<li>Everyone thinks your thing is terrible. Hopefully you realize.</li>
</ol>
<p>The nature of a startup is that you have to <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/library/6g-how-to-talk-to-users">talk to users</a>. Or so we've heard.</p>
<p>My sole focus for weeks on end was just to get meetings with people that we felt may have the same problem we were trying to solve.</p>
<h2 id="it-got-good-eventually-right"><a href="#it-got-good-eventually-right" aria-label="it got good eventually right permalink"></a>It got good eventually, right?</h2>
<p>In 9 months, we built 6 products and did more than 100 meetings with potential users.</p>
<p>The range of ideas we tried to solve looks broad, but the thing that connected all of them was that we tackled problems we'd experienced in our previous professional lives.</p>
<p>So, what did we build?</p>
<h3 id="1-sales-territory-management-tool"><a href="#1-sales-territory-management-tool" aria-label="1 sales territory management tool permalink"></a>1. Sales Territory Management Tool</h3>
<p>At one stage in my life, I was the VP of Sales at an enterprise software company. On paper, it looked like a glamorous job - I used to fly around the world with the sales team, and met with huge enterprise clients in fancy skyscrapers, like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Commerce_Centre">ICC in Hong Kong</a>:</p>
<p><a href="https://posthog.com/static/international-commerce-centre-44dfcde59997db42043f10c44a88f782.jpg">
                    <img src="https://posthog.com/static/international-commerce-centre-44dfcde59997db42043f10c44a88f782.jpg" srcset="https://posthog.imgix.net/static/international-commerce-centre-44dfcde59997db42043f10c44a88f782.jpg?w=175 175w, https://posthog.imgix.net/static/international-commerce-centre-44dfcde59997db42043f10c44a88f782.jpg?w=350 350w, https://posthog.imgix.net/static/international-commerce-centre-44dfcde59997db42043f10c44a88f782.jpg?w=700 700w, https://posthog.imgix.net/static/international-commerce-centre-44dfcde59997db42043f10c44a88f782.jpg?w=1000 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" title="International Commerce Center - a big skyscraper in Hong Kong" alt="International Commerce Center - a big skyscraper in Hong Kong" loading="lazy">
                </a></p>
<p>Despite this, the <em>majority</em> of your time in sales is spent getting nowhere. All those hotels, flights, calls, fastidiously wearing a suit in inappropriately warm weather - very few of those things result in anything.</p>
<p>Sidenote: this is why <a href="https://posthog.com/handbook/growth/strategy">product led growth</a> is so much better.</p>
<p>If you're not getting anywhere with a potential customer after a few weeks or months of trying, your time is better spent elsewhere. Yet systems that are the core products of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salesforce">$17.1Bn revenue companies</a> come with a manually selected arbitrary number for the percentage probability that doesn't vary with time.</p>
<p>We pulled pipeline data from Hubspot or Salesforce, then used predictive analytics to work out how this curve looked based on historic data, then applied it to the current pipeline. Once a deal dropped below a certain threshold, we'd recommend you swap out that target company and pull a new one into the pipeline.</p>
<p>We confused a lot of people with this idea, because we were confused with whom we were targeting.</p>
<p>We got 15 sales leaders to agree to trying this out, sent them a link, then waited...</p>
<p>and waited...</p>
<p>just <em>one</em> person even clicked the sign up link. The rest didn't even try it.</p>
<p>With hindsight, it was way overpowered for tiny teams and we'd only have had a great fit for huge ones with a lot of data.</p>
<p>The only people interested in smaller teams were enthusiasts, but there wasn't an easy jump from that to a bigger market. We could have just worked on selling the product to big companies, but that would be <a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/library/3O-why-big-deals-are-bad-for-startups">tough</a>.</p>
<h3 id="2-crm-with-predictive-analytics"><a href="#2-crm-with-predictive-analytics" aria-label="2 crm with predictive analytics permalink"></a>2. CRM with Predictive Analytics</h3>
<p>One of our friends who ran a small sales team was a clear outliter. He had been using our first product a lot. We asked ourselves - why?</p>
<p>He had used it to <em>replace</em> his CRM. </p>
<p>Could we just do the whole lot in one place, and reimagine the CRM - would that make things feel simpler?</p>
<p>We positioned the product as a CRM for small companies, with predictive analytics for an even simpler experience managing everything. We tweaked the functionality to have more control over deals and contacts.</p>
<p>It suddenly got really hard to get anyone to talk to us.</p>
<p>There are many lightweight CRMs out there, and predictive analytics make more sense for those with more data, not startups with hardly any.</p>
<p>This was around the time that <a href="https://superhuman.com/">Superhuman</a> was getting pretty popular; we got overexcited, and kept using words like "blazing", "gorgeous", "brilliant". I blame too much time wasted reading <a href="https://sifted.eu/articles/vc-brags-twitter/">VC Twitter</a>.</p>
<p>We didn't think through who we were building for. The market we were working on was very busy, so if I went back in time, I would have focused more on our differentiation - a product could make more sense than a platform. Tim and I also just weren't strong enough at design to differentiate on that alone.</p>
<p>After hundreds of messages to potential users, we eventually got a single customer for $20/month, who then didn't actually pay the invoice. If you're pushing this hard and getting nowhere, you don't have the magic of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l-vfn97QTr0">product market fit</a>.</p>
<h3 id="3-11-tool-with-predictive-analytics"><a href="#3-11-tool-with-predictive-analytics" aria-label="3 11 tool with predictive analytics permalink"></a>3. 1:1 Tool with Predictive Analytics</h3>
<p>Back to basics - what was the actual problem we were solving?</p>
<p>It was the prioritization of where to focus your sales efforts. If 90% of your deals deals won't close, you need to get good at not spending time on those that aren't going to close.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andrew_Grove">Andrew Grove</a> has an excellent book, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/High-Output-Management-Andrew-Grove/dp/0679762884/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;keywords=high+output+management&amp;qid=1610712757&amp;s=books&amp;sr=1-1">High Output Management</a>. The premise is that your 1:1 meetings with your direct reports are your most leveraged time.</p>
<p>Yet, many managers in practise don't prepare, at all.</p>
<p><a href="https://posthog.com/static/amazing-team-9b6c9c9a4eaaf13acd63fc7243e975f9.jpg">
                    <img src="https://posthog.com/static/amazing-team-9b6c9c9a4eaaf13acd63fc7243e975f9.jpg" srcset="https://posthog.imgix.net/static/amazing-team-9b6c9c9a4eaaf13acd63fc7243e975f9.jpg?w=175 175w, https://posthog.imgix.net/static/amazing-team-9b6c9c9a4eaaf13acd63fc7243e975f9.jpg?w=350 350w, https://posthog.imgix.net/static/amazing-team-9b6c9c9a4eaaf13acd63fc7243e975f9.jpg?w=700 700w, https://posthog.imgix.net/static/amazing-team-9b6c9c9a4eaaf13acd63fc7243e975f9.jpg?w=1000 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" title="A team that look a little bit like their happiness is staged" alt="A team that look a little bit like their happiness is staged" loading="lazy">
                </a></p>
<p>We changed the UX completely, and made an app that looked a bit like google docs, where you and your reports could each create an agenda in advance and take notes. The twist? The product would interpret your sales pipeline and would use predictive analytics to suggest specific deals to discuss that could be worth replacing or that had changed dramatically since the previous week.</p>
<p>We managed to get lots of meetings easily with this idea, and everyone reported not preparing to the standard they wanted. Did we have a silver bullet?</p>
<p>Despite giving out logins, only one team out of around 10 started using the tool. </p>
<p>We were flumoxed. This tool was simple, people were excited, but no one used it.</p>
<p>For those that haven't read it, <a href="http://momtestbook.com/">The Mom Test</a>, which I wish I'd read sooner, explains our downfall here perfectly:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>If they haven't solved the problem, ask why not. Have they tried searching for solutions and found them wanting? Or do they not even care enough to have Googled for it?

Rule of thumb: Anything involving the future is an over-optimistic lie.</code></pre></div>
<p>If we'd have asked this question, we'd have saved a couple more weeks.</p>
<p>By this stage, we were thinking we just wanted to work with people that would at least try our stuff. These pesky heads of sales were just too capricious and we needed a break.</p>
<p>Software engineers, surely they'd be more willing to try something that we built. We moved on to a different idea we'd had. Voilà:</p>
<h3 id="4-technical-debt-monitoring-tool-using-surveys-after-each-pull-request"><a href="#4-technical-debt-monitoring-tool-using-surveys-after-each-pull-request" aria-label="4 technical debt monitoring tool using surveys after each pull request permalink"></a>4. Technical Debt Monitoring Tool using Surveys after each Pull Request</h3>
<p>We'd seen the impact of technical debt not being paid off at the right rate in our past, and had the perspective that automation isn't key to solving it. We believed that engineers knew when it was worth tackling.</p>
<p>I spoke with every developer or engineering leader I'd ever worked with, and many I hadn't. They all said this problem was a huge pain point.</p>
<p>So we built a survey tool that integrated with git repositories. After each pull request, it would ask the developer to answer a few quick questions - did anything slow them down, what type of problem was it, and roughly how much time was wasted. The tool would then visualize the code base against time lost to help surface where to start.</p>
<p>We got quite a lot of users, and we got into YCombinator with this idea. Three weeks into the batch, we had reached 600 users, with a 50% response rate to the surveys.</p>
<p>We had started trying to charge people for the product. But we kept getting feedback that although it was a nice way to log issues, it just wasn't helping solve the problem. A few teams converted at very low order values with a lot of pushing, but it was clear we had a problem.</p>
<p>It turns out everyone has problems with technical debt, but solving it involves changing how teams prioritize. Product teams weren't using the tool, and they were often dictating what people built.</p>
<p>After a meetup with our YC friends at a cool <a href="http://sparksocialsf.com/">food truck spot</a>, we took a long walk back to our house in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castro_District,_San_Francisco">Castro</a>. We were thinking about how to solve our product woes. Could it turn into a piece of roadmapping software? Would it need to integrate with the roadmap software already in use? We just didn't feel excited about building these things out.</p>
<p><a href="https://posthog.com/static/about-to-run-out-of-product-ideas-31f3a4983d29ab835ee25c87a04dcb56.jpeg">
            <img src="https://posthog.com/static/about-to-run-out-of-product-ideas-31f3a4983d29ab835ee25c87a04dcb56.jpeg" title="James and Tim at a group ycombinator meetup about to walk home" alt="James and Tim at a group ycombinator meetup about to walk home" loading="lazy">
        </a></p>
<p>A couple of days later, driving between Mountain View and San Francisco, we realized that we just weren't the right people to run this business.</p>
<p>Although Tim had struggled with technical debt first hand, neither of us had solved it. If one of us had managed an engineering team before, we'd have perhaps been better placed to understand things. Our basic skills were good enough to get quite far with the idea, but we didn't have the belief to take it further.</p>
<p>Along the way, we learned a lot about how developers and product managers work together. We'd also created a big list of future ideas we'd had whilst building all the above things out. If you can't stop thinking of other ideas, you probably are building something you don't like. This all came into play for idea 6 later on (the good one).</p>
<p>So what did we do next?</p>
<h3 id="5-engineering-retention-tool-using-surveys-after-each-pull-request"><a href="#5-engineering-retention-tool-using-surveys-after-each-pull-request" aria-label="5 engineering retention tool using surveys after each pull request permalink"></a>5. Engineering Retention Tool using Surveys after each Pull Request</h3>
<p>Those fickle engineers joining companies and leaving them whenever they want to ;)</p>
<p>This idea didn't come from us, which doomed it before it even really started.</p>
<p>This lasted all of 5 days. We had a bunch of meetings left over from (4) to validate it. Amusingly we had to do a YCombinator demo day dry run for this in front of 500 people who made up the YC batch.</p>
<p>We had a wildly unenthusiastic response from prospective users. The lowlight was during one of the meetings that we resorted to asking the CTO of an 80 person start up what his biggest problem was, "I've not really got any". Noice, noice.</p>
<p><a href="https://gfycat.com/discover/andy-samberg-gifs">from Andy Samberg GIFs</a></p>
<h3 id="6-open-source-product-analytics-platform"><a href="#6-open-source-product-analytics-platform" aria-label="6 open source product analytics platform permalink"></a>6. Open Source Product Analytics Platform</h3>
<p>Things got meta.</p>
<p>Along our journey (/series of failed ideas), we got frustrated having to send all our user data to 3rd parties to understand our product usage. It felt wrong and it meant we'd …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://posthog.com/blog/story-about-pivots">https://posthog.com/blog/story-about-pivots</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://posthog.com/blog/story-about-pivots</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25871629</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 13:53:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[B2B SaaS marketplaces with opportunities for indie hackers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 153 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25870899">thread link</a>) | @khuknows
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://rocketgems.com/blog/saas-marketplaces/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rocketgems.com/blog/saas-marketplaces/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div>
            <p>Although <a href="https://rocketgems.com/blog/developer-content-businesses/" target="_blank">I’m personally focussing less on SaaS and more on content business opportunities</a>, the type of SaaS businesses that interest me the most as an indie hacker are the ones that plug into growing B2B platforms.</p><p> These platforms generally make it easier to find customers, create more focussed products, and build trust.</p><p>Shopify, Slack, and Salesforce are examples of B2B products with more mature and well known marketplaces, but there are a whole bunch more. They range from more fully featured marketplaces that have integrated user reviews and payment handling, to more basic "integration directories."</p><p>Out of the 100+ marketplaces and integration directories I found, 66 stood out to me as the ones worth considering as an indie hacker. The ones that have user reviews built in have a (*) next to their names.</p>
            
            
            
            
            <div id="saas-marketplaces-crms">
                <h2>Customer Relationship Management (CRM)</h2>
                
                    <h3><a href="https://www.salesforce.com/" target="_blank">Salesforce</a>*</h3><p>Salesforce is one of the first ever SaaS products and has arguably the most developed B2B app marketplace. Listings include user reviews, live chat, pricing details, and more.</p><p><a href="https://appexchange.salesforce.com/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://www.hubspot.com/" target="_blank">Hubspot</a>*</h3><p>Hubspot has a suite of products including a CRM, site builder, form builder, and much more. Their app marketplace has user reviews, app install numbers, videos, and pricing details.</p><p><a href="https://ecosystem.hubspot.com/marketplace/apps" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://www.pipedrive.com/" target="_blank">Pipedrive</a>*</h3><p>Pipedrive isn't quite as popular as Hubspot or Salesforce, but with over 95,000 companies using them, they're still pretty massive. Their app marketplace listings include ratings, reviews, and optional videos.</p><p><a href="https://marketplace.pipedrive.com/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.zoho.com/crm/" target="_blank">Zoho CRM</a>*</h3><p>As with many of the above, Zoho offers a CRM as well as a suite of tools for businesses. Their marketplace listings include user reviews, pricing details, and optional videos,&nbsp;</p><p><a href="https://marketplace.zoho.com/home" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p>
                
            </div>
            
            <div id="saas-marketplaces-customer-support">
                <h2>Customer support</h2>
                
                    <h3><a href="https://www.zendesk.com/" target="_blank">Zendesk</a>*</h3><p>Zendesk has a reasonably mature app marketplace where the listings include user reviews, price details, and videos.</p><p><a href="https://www.zendesk.com/apps/directory" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://freshdesk.com/" target="_blank">Freshdesk</a></h3><p>Freshdesk is part of a suite of products under the "Freshworks" brand. Their marketplace seems quite mature and includes helpful features like search, but the listings don't include user reviews or pricing details.</p><p><a href="https://www.freshworks.com/apps/freshdesk/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="http://intercom.com/" target="_blank">Intercom</a></h3><p>Intercom isn't exactly a support tool, but I wasn't sure which category to include it in as the product does many things. They're best known for their live chat widget. The Intercom marketplace listings do include pricing details and optional videos, but don't have user reviews.</p><p><a href="https://www.intercom.com/app-store" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://www.helpscout.com/" target="_blank">HelpScout</a></h3><p>HelpScout isn't quite as big as Zendesk or Freshdesk, but is fairly popular amongst startups, who are generally more willing to try out new apps. Their app directory is quite basic and doesn't include things like user reviews or pricing details.</p><p><a href="https://www.helpscout.com/help-desk-integration/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://frontapp.com/" target="_blank">Front</a></h3><p>Front is an email collaboration tool that's commonly used for customer support. Like HelpScout, their app directory is fairly basic.</p><p><a href="https://frontapp.com/integrations" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://www.liveagent.com/" target="_blank">LiveAgent</a></h3><p>LiveAgent is another suite of customer support tools. Their integration directory is a more simple one, similar to Front and HelpScout.</p><p><a href="https://www.liveagent.com/integrations/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p>
                
            </div>
            
            
            
            <div id="saas-marketplaces-website-builders">
                <h2>Website builders</h2>
                
                    <h3><a href="https://www.shopify.com/" target="_blank">Shopify</a>*</h3><p>Shopify is an e-commerce platform and has one of the most mature app marketplaces. The marketplace listings include user reviews, payments, videos, and more. App makers can even use paid ads within the marketplace to get in front of more potential customers. This is a marketplace with plenty of opportunity and plenty of competition.</p><p><a href="https://apps.shopify.com/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Wordpress</a>*</h3><p>Wordpress powers a huge percentage of all websites. It's the most popular website builder (or content management system). Their plugin marketplace has user reviews, download numbers, and more. Most plugins are free, and most of the paid ones charge one time fees. This is another marketplace with plenty of opportunity and plenty of competition.</p><p><a href="https://wordpress.org/plugins/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.squarespace.com/" target="_blank">Squarespace</a></h3><p>Squarespace is another popular website builder. If you listen to podcasts, you'll likely have heard one of their ads. Their marketplace is quite tiny and less advanced then a lot of the above. It doesn't have user reviews, but does have pricing information.</p><p><a href="https://www.squarespace.com/extensions/home" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://webflow.com/" target="_blank">Webflow</a></h3><p>Webflow is a website builder targeting no-code makers and designers. It seems to be growing rapidly, but their marketplace is still super basic.</p><p><a href="https://university.webflow.com/integrations" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.wix.com/" target="_blank">Wix</a>*</h3><p>Wix is another website builder which is mostly used by small businesses. Their marketplace includes user reviews, videos, pricing details, and more.</p><p><a href="https://www.wix.com/app-market" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://magento.com/" target="_blank">Magento</a>*</h3><p>Magento is an e-commerce website builder that's generally used to build more advanced/custom online stores than Shopify. Their marketplace is advanced and includes user reviews, Q&amp;A sections, and more.</p><p><a href="https://marketplace.magento.com/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://woocommerce.com/" target="_blank">WooCommerce</a>*</h3><p>WooCommerce is the e-commerce builder from Wordpress. I think WooCommerce plugins are kinda Wordpress plugins that are packaged specifically for WooCommerce, but there is a separate marketplace for WooCommerce plugins that has reviews, pricing, etc. I assume there's also more willingness to pay for WooCommerce plugins because it's more likely that websites built with it are earning revenue.</p><p><a href="https://woocommerce.com/products/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.bigcommerce.com/" target="_blank">BigCommerce</a>*</h3><p>BigCommerce is another big player in the e-commerce space. Their marketplace includes payments, user reviews, videos, and more.</p><p><a href="https://www.bigcommerce.co.uk/apps/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.volusion.com/" target="_blank">Volusion</a></h3><p>Volusion is another e-commerce website builder. I don't really hear of it much so I have no idea how big it is, but they do have a basic plugin marketplace that does include pricing details.</p><p><a href="https://www.volusion.com/v1/marketplace" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p>
                
            </div>
            
            <div id="saas-marketplaces-marketing-automation">
                <h2>Marketing</h2>
                
                    <h3><a href="https://marketo.com/" target="_blank">Marketo</a>*</h3><p>Marketo is a marketing automation platform. Their marketplace is quite advanced and includes user reviews, videos, and more.</p><p><a href="https://launchpoint.marketo.com/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="http://mailchimp.com/" target="_blank">MailChimp</a></h3><p>MailChimp is one of the most well known email service providers. The marketplace is one of the more basic ones.</p><p><a href="https://mailchimp.com/integrations/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://segment.com/" target="_blank">Segment</a></h3><p>Segment is a "Customer Data Platform" that makes it easier to share data between various cloud products. Their marketplace, which they call an "integrations catalog" is exactly that, more of a catalog than a marketplace with reviews and what not.</p><p><a href="https://segment.com/catalog/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://www.drip.com/" target="_blank">Drip</a></h3><p>Drip is an email service provider focussed on e-commerce. Their integration marketplace is another example of a more basic one. The listings don't have user reviews or pricing details.</p><p><a href="https://www.drip.com/integrations" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.activecampaign.com/" target="_blank">ActiveCampaign</a></h3><p>Another email service provider with a simple "apps and integrations" directory.</p><p><a href="https://www.activecampaign.com/apps/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p>
                
            </div>
            
            
            
            <div id="saas-marketplaces-other">
                <h2>Other</h2>
                
                    <p>Here are a whole bunch of other B2B products that include app/plugin/extension marketplaces that I couldn't place into any of the above categories. A lot of them fit into some sort of "productivity" or "collaboration" category.</p><h3><a href="https://zoom.us/" target="_blank">Zoom</a></h3><p>Zoom is a wildly popular video call/conferencing service. They recently launched "Zapps" which are apps that enhance the zoom experience. As their marketplace is brand new, and isn't fully launched yet. I have no clue how popular Zapps will become, but I'd bet there are some great opportunities here.</p><p><a href="https://zoom.us/docs/en-us/zoom-apps.html" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://slack.com/" target="_blank">Slack</a></h3><p>Slack is a live chat app for teams. Their app marketplace doesn't include user reviews, but it is fairly mature. Most Slack teams use a few apps and there are features built into the Slack service that helps people discover apps. As with Shopify, this is a marketplace with plenty of opportunity and plenty of competition.</p><p><a href="https://slack.com/apps" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en/microsoft-teams/group-chat-software" target="_blank">Microsoft Teams</a>*</h3><p>Microsoft Teams is the live chat product from Microsoft. It's very quickly become super popular with large companies and enterprises.</p><p><a href="https://appsource.microsoft.com/en-us/marketplace/apps?product=teams" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://workspace.google.com/" target="_blank">G Suite/Google Workspace</a>*</h3><p>G Suite or Google Workspace is a set of business tools from Google, including email, word processing, spreadsheets etc. The marketplace includes user ratings, install numbers, and more. Personally, I wouldn't put too much trust into any of the Google marketplaces as they have a history of being less friendly to their app developers when compared to other B2B app marketplaces.</p><p><a href="https://gsuite.google.com/marketplace/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://airtable.com/" target="_blank">Airtable</a></h3><p>Airtable is a powerful spreadsheet type tool with a newer marketplace. The marketplace is fairly basic at the moment, but it's very new and I imagine it will become more advanced in the future.</p><p><a href="https://airtable.com/marketplace" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://zapier.com/" target="_blank">Zapier</a></h3><p>Zapier is an automation tool that lets you connect various products so they can work better together. Their marketplace doesn't include user reviews or usage numbers, but lets customers discover apps through workflows and guides.</p><p><a href="https://zapier.com/apps" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.integromat.com/en" target="_blank">Integromat</a></h3><p>Integormat is an automation tool similar to Zapier. Their app directory is also fairly basic, but it does let you visualise how the apps can be used together really well.</p><p><a href="https://www.integromat.com/en/integrations" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://bubble.io/" target="_blank">Bubble</a>*&nbsp;</h3><p>Bubble is a no-code app and website builder that's growing in popularity. Their plugin marketplace does include user reviews and pricing details.</p><p><a href="https://bubble.io/plugins" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://rapidapi.com/" target="_blank">RapidAPI</a></h3><p>RapidAPI is different to most of the other products mentioned here as the main part of the product is the marketplace itself. It's an API marketplace that makes it easier for developers to integrate and pay for many APIs. The marketplace doesn't have reviews, but listings have an area for discussions, popularity ratings, and more comparable features.</p><p><a href="https://rapidapi.com/marketplace" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/" target="_blank">SurveyMonkey</a></h3><p>SurveyMonkey is a super popular form and survey builder. They have a fairly basic app directory.</p><p><a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/apps/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a><br></p><h3><a href="https://www.typeform.com/" target="_blank">Typeform</a></h3><p>Typeform is a form builder that made the multi-step, more conversational style of form more popular. They have a basic app directory.</p><p><a href="https://www.typeform.com/connect/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://www.jotform.com/" target="_blank">JotForm</a></h3><p>JotForm is another form builder. Their marketplace is fairly simple, but there are plenty of opportunities for simple apps that can enhance forms.</p><p><a href="https://www.jotform.com/apps/" target="_blank">Marketplace →</a></p><h3><a href="https://monday.com/" target="_blank">Monday</a></h3><p>Monday is a project management and team collaboration tool. Their app marketplace doesn't have …</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://rocketgems.com/blog/saas-marketplaces/">https://rocketgems.com/blog/saas-marketplaces/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rocketgems.com/blog/saas-marketplaces/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25870899</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 12:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Secure Messaging App Conundrum: Signal vs. Telegram [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 79 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25870133">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://cqi.inf.usi.ch/publications/telegram_vs_signal.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cqi.inf.usi.ch/publications/telegram_vs_signal.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cqi.inf.usi.ch/publications/telegram_vs_signal.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25870133</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 09:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Upgrade Your SSH Keys]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25870060">thread link</a>) | @hackmin
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://blog.g3rt.nl/upgrade-your-ssh-keys.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.g3rt.nl/upgrade-your-ssh-keys.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
            
<p>Whether you're a software developer or a sysadmin, I bet you're using SSH keys.
Pushing your commits to Github or managing your Unix systems, it's best practice to do this over SSH with public key authentication rather than passwords.
However, as time flies, many of you are using older keys and not aware of the need to generate fresh ones to protect your privates much better.
In this post I'll demonstrate how to transition to an Ed25519 key smoothly, why you would want this and show some tips and tricks on the way there.</p>
<div>
<p>Tl;dr:</p>
<p>Generate your new key with <code>ssh-keygen -o -a 100 -t ed25519</code>, specify a strong passphrase and read further if you need a smooth transition.</p>
</div>
<p>I'm planning to publish some more posts on SSH tips &amp; tricks, so keep an eye on my blog for more.
This post will focus on about SSH keys as user public key authentication.</p>
<h2 id="dsa-and-rsa-1024-bit-are-deprecated-now">DSA and RSA 1024 bit are deprecated now<a href="#dsa-and-rsa-1024-bit-are-deprecated-now" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>If you've created your key more than about four years ago with the default options it's probably insecure (RSA &lt; 2048 bits).
Even worse, I've seen tweeps, colleagues and friends still using DSA keys (<code>ssh-dss</code> in OpenSSH format) recently.
That's a key type similar to RSA, but limited to 1024 bits size and therefore <a href="https://security.stackexchange.com/a/5100/12948">recommended against</a> for a long time.
It's plainly insecure and refused for valid reasons in recent OpenSSH versions (see also the <a href="http://www.openssh.com/txt/release-7.0">changelog for 7.0</a>).</p>
<p>The sad thing about it is that I see posts on how to re-enable DSA key support rather than moving to a more secure type of key.
Really, it's unwise to follow instructions to change the configuration for <code>PubkeyAcceptedKeyTypes</code> or <code>HostKeyAlgorithms</code> (host keys are for a later post).
Instead, upgrade your keys!</p>
<p><img alt="Picture of an ancient key" src="https://blog.g3rt.nl/images/20160923_old_key_picture.jpg"></p>
<p>Compare DSA with the technology of locks using keys like this one.
You wouldn't want this type of key to unlock your front door, right?</p>

<h2 id="determine-your-current-situation">Determine your current situation<a href="#determine-your-current-situation" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>List all your keys:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>$</span> <span>for</span> keyfile in ~/.ssh/id_*<span>;</span> <span>do</span> ssh-keygen -l -f <span>"${</span><span>keyfile</span><span>}"</span><span>;</span> <span>done</span> <span>|</span> uniq
</code></pre></div>
<ul>
<li>DSA or RSA 1024 bits: red flag. Unsafe.</li>
<li>RSA 2048: yellow recommended to change</li>
<li>RSA 3072/4096: great, but Ed25519 has some benefits!</li>
<li>ECDSA: depends. Recommended to change</li>
<li>Ed25519: wow cool, but are you brute-force safe?</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="a-smooth-transition-i-promise">A smooth transition, I promise.<a href="#a-smooth-transition-i-promise" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>You're probably thinking… "I'm using my key for a long time, I don't want to change them everywhere now."
Valid point, but you don't have to! It's good to know you can have multiple keys on your system and your SSH client will pick the right one for the right system automatically.</p>
<p>It's part of the SSH protocol that it can offer multiple keys and the server picks the one your client will have to prove it has possession of the private key by a challenge.
See it in action adding some verbosity to the SSH connect command (<code>-vvv</code>).
Also if you're using an SSH agent you can load multiple keys and it will discover them all.
Easy as that.</p>
<h2 id="youll-like-the-twisted-edwards-curve">You'll like the Twisted Edwards curve<a href="#youll-like-the-twisted-edwards-curve" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>Most common is the RSA type of key, also known as <code>ssh-rsa</code> with SSH.
It's very compatible, but also slow and potentially insecure if created with a small amount of bits (&lt; 2048).
We just learned that your SSH client can handle multiple keys, so enable yourself with the newest faster elliptic curve cryptography and enjoy the very compact key format it provides!</p>
<p>Ed25519 keys are short. Very short. If you're used to copy multiple lines of characters from system to system you'll be happily surprised with the size. The public key is just about 68 characters. It's also much faster in authentication compared to secure RSA (3072+ bits).</p>
<p>Generating an Ed25519 key is done using the <code>-t ed25519</code> option to the ssh-keygen command.</p>
<p>Ed25519 is a reference implementation for EdDSA using Twisted Edward curves (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twisted_Edwards_curve">Wikipedia link</a>).</p>
<h2 id="increase-resistance-to-brute-force-password-cracking">Increase resistance to brute-force password cracking<a href="#increase-resistance-to-brute-force-password-cracking" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>When generating the keypair, you're asked for a passphrase to encrypt the private key with.
If you will ever lose your private key it should protect others from impersonating you because it will be encrypted with the passphrase.
To actually prevent this, one should make sure to prevent easy brute-forcing of the passphrase.</p>
<p>OpenSSH key generator offers two options to resistance to brute-force password cracking: using the new OpenSSH key format and increasing the amount of key derivation function rounds.
It slows down the process of unlocking the key, but this is what prevents efficient brute-forcing by a malicious user too.
I'd say experiment with the amount of rounds on your system.
Start at about 100 rounds.
On my system it takes about one second to decrypt and load the key once per day using an agent.
Very much acceptable, imo.</p>
<p>With <code>ssh-keygen</code> use the <code>-o</code> option for the new RFC4716 key format and the use of a modern key derivation function powered by bcrypt.
Use the <code>-a &lt;num&gt;</code> option for <code>&lt;num&gt;</code> amount of rounds.</p>
<p>Actually, it appears that when creating a Ed25519 key the <code>-o</code> option is implied.</p>
<p>The OpenSSH manpages are not really explanatory about the 'new' format.
I found this article pretty useful: <a href="http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/new-openssh-key-format-and-bcrypt-pbkdf">"new openssh key format and bcrypt pbkdf" on www.tedunangst.com</a>.</p>
<h2 id="generate-your-new-sexy-ed25519-key">Generate your new sexy Ed25519 key<a href="#generate-your-new-sexy-ed25519-key" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>

<div><pre><span></span><code><span><span>$</span> ssh-keygen -o -a <span>100</span> -t ed25519
</span><span>Generating public/private ed25519 key pair.</span>
<span>Enter passphrase (empty for no passphrase):</span>
<span>Enter same passphrase again:</span>
<span>Your identification has been saved in /home/gert/.ssh/id_ed25519.</span>
<span>Your public key has been saved in /home/gert/.ssh/id_ed25519.pub.</span>
<span>The key fingerprint is:</span>
<span>SHA256: [...] gert@hostname</span>
<span>The key's randomart image is: [...]</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>Note the line 'Your identification has been saved in /home/gert/.ssh/id_ed25519'.
Your current RSA/DSA keys are next to it in the same <code>~/.ssh</code> folder.
As with any other key you can copy the public key in <code>~/.ssh/id_ed25519.pub</code> to target hosts for authentication.</p>
<h2 id="multi-key-aware-ssh-client">Multi-key aware SSH client<a href="#multi-key-aware-ssh-client" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>All keys available on default paths will be autodetected by SSH client applications, including the SSH agent via ssh-add.
So, if you were using an application like ssh/scp/rsync before like...</p>

<p>it will now offer multiple public keys to the server and the server will request proof of possession for a matching entry for authentication.
And your daily use of the <code>ssh-add</code> command will not change and autodiscover the Ed25519 key:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span><span>$</span> ssh-add
</span><span>Enter passphrase for /home/gert/.ssh/id_rsa:</span>
<span>Identity added: /home/gert/.ssh/id_rsa (gert@hostname)</span>
<span>Identity added: /home/gert/.ssh/id_ed25519 (gert@hostname)</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>It not only discovered both keys, it also loaded them by entering a single passphrase (because it's the same)!</p>
<p>We've reached a very important goal now.
Without any change to your daily routine we can slowly change the existing configuration on remote hosts to accept the Ed25519 key.
In the meantime the RSA key will still work.
Great, right!?</p>
<h2 id="change-or-set-a-passphrase">Change or set a passphrase<a href="#change-or-set-a-passphrase" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>If you're afraid this will change your key, don't worry.
The private part of your keypair is encrypted with a passphrase which only exists locally on your machine.
Change it as often as you like.
This is recommended to prevent abuse in case the key file gets into the wrong hands.
Repeat for all your key files to ensure a new key format with 100 bcrypt KDF rounds:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>$</span> ssh-keygen -f ~/.ssh/id_rsa -p -o -a <span>100</span>
</code></pre></div>
<h2 id="upgrade-your-current-rsa-key">Upgrade your current RSA key<a href="#upgrade-your-current-rsa-key" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>Using Ed25519 will (and should) work in most situations by now, but legacy systems may not support them as of yet.
The best fallback is a strong RSA keypair for this.</p>
<p>While the OpenSSH client supports multiple RSA keys, it requires configuration/command line options to specify the path so it's rather error-prone.
Instead, I'd recommend upgrading your existing key in-place to keep things simple once this is done.
Depending on the strength (key size) of your current RSA key you can migrate urgently or comfortably.</p>
<p>In case you have a weak RSA key still, move it out of the way from the standard path and generate a new one of 4096 bits size:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>$</span> mv ~/.ssh/id_rsa ~/.ssh/id_rsa_legacy
<span>$</span> mv ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub ~/.ssh/id_rsa_legacy.pub
<span>$</span> ssh-keygen -t rsa -b <span>4096</span> -o -a <span>100</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>If you are using an agent, manually point it to all your keys:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>$</span> ssh-add ~/.ssh/id_rsa ~/.ssh/id_rsa_legacy ~/.ssh/id_ed25519
</code></pre></div>
<p>Once you are finished the transition on all remote targets you can go back to convenience and let it autodiscover your new RSA and Ed25519 keys; simply omit the keyfile arguments.</p>
<h2 id="software-support-for-ed25519">Software support for Ed25519<a href="#software-support-for-ed25519" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>Support is available since OpenSSH 6.5 and well adopted in the Unix world OSs for workstations.
Ubuntu 14.04+, Debian 8+, CentOS/RedHat 7+ etc. all support it already.
(If you have details about Mac OS X please drop a line, couldn't find it with a quick search).
Some software like custom desktop key agents may not like the new keys for several reasons (see below <a href="#my-gnome-keyring-doesnt-work-anymore">about the Gnome-keyring</a> for example).</p>
<p>Github works pretty well too, by the way.
Launchpad and Gerrit code review however, seem to require RSA keys unfortunately.
PuTTY on Windows? See below.</p>
<h2 id="my-gnome-keyring-doesnt-work-anymore">My Gnome-keyring doesn't work anymore<a href="#my-gnome-keyring-doesnt-work-anymore" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>The Gnome-keyring, as used in Ubuntu Unity at least, fails to read the new RFC4716 format keys but reports success.
It's bugged.
More details here in <a href="https://askubuntu.com/q/564821/88802">my AskUbuntu Q&amp;A post</a>.
I'd recommend disabling the Gnome keyring for SSH agent use and use the plain OpenSSH agent instead.</p>
<h2 id="im-using-windows-with-putty">I'm using Windows with PuTTY<a href="#im-using-windows-with-putty" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>Sorry, I'm not using PuTTY, but make sure to upgrade first.
This page suggests Ed25519 support since a late-2015 version according to a <a href="http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/wishlist/ed25519.html">wishlist item</a>.
Generally speaking, I'm not too excited with the speed of implementation of security features in it.</p>
<h2 id="is-this-the-ultimate-secure-ssh-keypair">Is this the ultimate secure SSH keypair?<a href="#is-this-the-ultimate-secure-ssh-keypair" title="Permanent link"> </a></h2>
<p>We've taken some steps, important ones, but it's far from ultimate security.
When dealing with high assurance environments I would strongly discourage key usage like described in this post as this holds the unencrypted private key in memory.
Instead, use hardware security (smart cards) to avoid leaking keys even from memory dumps.
It's not covered in this post, mainly because it requires a hardware device you need to buy and secondly because the limitations are device dependent.
A nice cute solution would be to make use of your TPM already …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.g3rt.nl/upgrade-your-ssh-keys.html">https://blog.g3rt.nl/upgrade-your-ssh-keys.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.g3rt.nl/upgrade-your-ssh-keys.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25870060</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 09:42:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ownCloud Infinite Scale: Go instead of PHP, microservices instead of LAMP]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 100 | Comments 105 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25869798">thread link</a>) | @veddox
<br/>
January 22, 2021 | https://www.heise.de//news/ownCloud-Infinite-Scale-Go-statt-PHP-Microservices-statt-LAMP-5029244.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.heise.de//news/ownCloud-Infinite-Scale-Go-statt-PHP-Microservices-statt-LAMP-5029244.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        





<a-collapse has-indicator="">
  
  
  
</a-collapse>


      

      <p>Im stillen KÃ¤mmerlein arbeitet ownCloud seit Ã¼ber einem Jahr an der neuen Version seiner Software und zeigt nun zum ersten Mal sein neues Projekt Infinite Scale â€“ allerdings sind die Entwickler nicht langsam, sondern haben sich viel vorgenommen. Bis einschlieÃŸlich ownCloud X ist die Software eine klassische LAMP-Applikation: Im Hintergrund werkelt MySQL, Apache serviert PHP-Seiten und das gesamte Konstrukt lÃ¤uft Ã¼blicherweise auf einer Linux-Installation.</p>

<a-paternoster height="360" media="(min-width: 320px) and (max-width: 767px)">
  


  


  <a-ad height="600" instant="" layout="fixed" media="(min-width: 320px) and (max-width: 767px)" preload-distance="200" safeframe="" sizes="300x600,300x50,300x75,300x100,300x150,300x250,320x50,320x75,320x100,320x250" targeting="{&quot;kw&quot;:[&quot;Cloud Computing&quot;,&quot;Google Go&quot;,&quot;Linux und Open Source&quot;,&quot;Microservices&quot;,&quot;Nextcloud&quot;,&quot;OwnCloud&quot;,&quot;PHP&quot;,&quot;Server &amp; Storage&quot;,&quot;Systemverwaltung&quot;],&quot;mpos&quot;:[&quot;understitial&quot;,&quot;top&quot;],&quot;themenhub&quot;:&quot;yes&quot;}" type="gpt" unit="/6514/www.heise.de/ix/ix-inhalt" width="300"></a-ad>

</a-paternoster>


<p>Im Laufe der Jahre sind die ownCloud-Entwickler allerdings an immer mehr Performance- und Skalierbarkeitsgrenzen gestoÃŸen, deren Ursache zumeist in entsprechenden Limitierungen in PHP liegt. Wer groÃŸe ownCloud-Installationen betreibt, kennt das: Je mehr Nutzer und Dateien die Instanz verwaltet, desto trÃ¤ger wird sie mit der Zeit. RegelmÃ¤ÃŸig sehen Admins sich zudem mit Speicherplatzmangel konfrontiert, denn bisher speichert ownCloud die Dateien seiner Nutzer lokal auf einem normalen Dateisystem ab. Wird der Platz dort knapp, ist das Problem gar nicht so leicht zu umschiffen.</p>
<h3 id="nav_goodbye_php_0">Goodbye, PHP</h3>
<p>Alle <a href="https://www.heise.de/thema/OwnCloud">diese alten ZÃ¶pfe</a> planen die Entwickler in ownCloud Infinite Scale endgÃ¼ltig abzuschneiden. Dabei handelt es sich mehr Revolution denn Evolution: Ihren alten Code treten die Entwickler fast vollstÃ¤ndig in die Tonne und ersetzen ihn durch einen kompletten Rewrite in Go. oCIS folgt einem Modell aus drei Schichten: Die unterste Schicht kÃ¼mmert sich um das Speichern von Dateien, die mittlere Schicht umfasst alle Kern-Dienste und die dritte Schicht ist das ebenfalls vollstÃ¤ndig neu geschriebene Webinterface.</p>





  

<a-lightbox tabindex="1">
  
    

<figure>

  <div>
      <a href="https://www.heise.de/imgs/18/3/0/4/1/5/0/0/ocis5-b5dab7c1ceae5a77.png">
      

<a-img alt="" height="887" high-dpi-quality="70" layout="responsive" quality="85" src="/imgs/18/3/0/4/1/5/0/0/ocis5-b5dab7c1ceae5a77.png" width="1250"></a-img>



      </a>
    

  </div>
    

<figcaption>    <p>Ein erster Test des neuen ownCloud Infinite Scale und des ebenfalls neuen Webinterface, geschrieben in Vue.js.</p>
      
    
</figcaption>

</figure>

  
</a-lightbox>




<p>Der Kern von ownCloud besteht kÃ¼nftig aus verschiedenen Microservices, die einander per gRPC Befehle und Anweisungen zusenden. Die Entwickler bÃ¼ndeln die MESH-Software Traefik fest mit oCIS, um sich um Themen wie Loadbalancing und sichere Kommunikation innerhalb des Service-Netzwerks keine Gedanken machen zu mÃ¼ssen. Was im Umkehrschluss bedeutet: Reichen die laufenden Instanzen eines bestimmten ownCloud-Dienstes nicht mehr aus, lassen sich zusÃ¤tzliche Instanzen desselben Dienstes ad hoc starten.</p>
<p>Architektonisch nutzt oCIS diverse Vorteile von Go zur Beschleunigung. Fordert der Nutzer kÃ¼nftig eine spezielle Aktion per API oder Webinterface an, kÃ¼mmern die einzelnen oCIS-Microservices sich im Hintergrund darum. Der Anwender muss nicht warten, bis die jeweilige Aktion erfolgreich ausgefÃ¼hrt ist, bevor er den nÃ¤chsten Befehl absenden kann. Der Effekt findet sich auch auf der Code-Ebene wieder, wo Go anders als PHP echte NebenlÃ¤ufigkeit beherrscht und damit mehrere Operationen zur selben Zeit ausfÃ¼hren kann.</p>
<p>Obendrein reduziert der Umstieg auf Microservices den administrativen Aufwand von ownCloud. Eine externe Datenbank wie MySQL benÃ¶tigt die Software kÃ¼nftig nicht mehr â€“ um ihre Datenhaltung kÃ¼mmern sich eigene Microservices.</p>






  


  <a-ad height="250" instant="" layout="responsive" media="(min-width: 320px) and (max-width: 767px)" preload-distance="200" safeframe="" sizes="300x50,300x75,300x100,300x150,300x250,320x50,320x75,320x100,320x250,fluid" targeting="{&quot;kw&quot;:[&quot;Cloud Computing&quot;,&quot;Google Go&quot;,&quot;Linux und Open Source&quot;,&quot;Microservices&quot;,&quot;Nextcloud&quot;,&quot;OwnCloud&quot;,&quot;PHP&quot;,&quot;Server &amp; Storage&quot;,&quot;Systemverwaltung&quot;],&quot;mpos&quot;:[&quot;2&quot;],&quot;themenhub&quot;:&quot;yes&quot;}" type="gpt" unit="/6514/www.heise.de/ix/ix-inhalt" width="300"></a-ad>




      <!-- RSPEAK_STOP -->

      

      

     

      

      <!-- RSPEAK_STOP -->

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.heise.de//news/ownCloud-Infinite-Scale-Go-statt-PHP-Microservices-statt-LAMP-5029244.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25869798</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 09:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why isn't differential dataflow more popular?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 220 | Comments 105 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25867693">thread link</a>) | @jamii
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/why-isnt-differential-dataflow-more-popular/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/why-isnt-differential-dataflow-more-popular/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <p><a href="https://github.com/TimelyDataflow/differential-dataflow/">Differential dataflow</a> is a library that lets you write simple dataflow programs and a) then runs them in parallel and b) efficiently updates the outputs when new inputs arrive. Compared to competition like <a href="https://spark.apache.org/">spark</a> and <a href="https://kafka.apache.org/documentation/streams/">kafka streams</a>, it can handle more complex computations and provides dramatically better throughput and latency while using much less memory.</p>
<p>But I'm only aware of a few companies that use it in production, even though it's been around for 5 years. </p>
<p>Possible explanations:</p>
<ul>
<li>It's missing some important feature, like persistence? </li>
<li>It's had very little advertising?</li>
<li>The api is too hard to use?</li>
<li>The docs / tutorials are not good enough?</li>
<li>Rust is intimidating?</li>
<li>No company to provide paid support?</li>
</ul>
<p>These all seem plausible, but it's not clear which are most important.</p>
<p>Even more surprising is that noone has copied the ideas into some enterprise friendly java monstrosity - despite the fact that differential dataflow is open source and is explained in depth in many papers and blog posts.</p>
<p>I'm interested because <a href="https://materialize.com/">materialize</a> is expending a huge amount of effort adding a SQL layer on top of differential dataflow. That's all very well for people who like SQL, but I'm curious whether there are also potential users who would have been perfectly happy with javascript/python/R bindings and a good tutorial? There are probably multiple niches to be served here.</p>
<p>If you considered using differential dataflow and decided against, please <a href="mailto:jamie@scattered-thoughts.net">let me know</a> why.</p>
<hr>
<p>I got feedback in the form of ~20 emails and ~100 comments on <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25867693">hn</a> and <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/7zeb3x/why_isn_t_differential_dataflow_more">lobsters</a>. Thanks to everyone who took the time to reach out - it was very helpful.</p>
<p>(To clarify for many fine but confused commenters - I did not make differential dataflow. I'm just trying to find out what more needs to be done to be useful in that niche.)</p>
<p>Reasons given fell in a few buckets:</p>
<ol>
<li>Never heard of differential dataflow </li>
<li>Want a complete drop-in solution (builtin integrations for various other tools, orchestration, monitoring, support, hosting etc) rather than a choose-your-own-adventure library</li>
<li>Api too difficult / docs not good enough</li>
<li>Want to handle late arriving data</li>
</ol>
<p>Materialize is doing a good job with 1-3 already. </p>
<p>I think differential dataflow actually can handle 4, since it can handle bitemporal timestamps, but this isn't something that has been well tested or advertised. That might be worth experimenting with. UPDATE: Frank McSherry posted a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0WijjN0LiZ4">video demo</a>.</p>
<p>All of the people in group 2 talked about typical data processing tasks, but people in group 3 had a much wider range of tasks including large-scale code analysis and monitoring systems with strong latency/consistency requirements. </p>
<p>Group 3 includes many people who seriously evaluated DD but couldn't get past the hello world stage, but also several people who <em>are</em> using DD because nothing else can handle their requirements, but still complain that the api is difficult to use.</p>
<p>Api complaints included:</p>
<ul>
<li>where is all the state? where do all these map/reduce calls actually end up living?</li>
<li>which operators are internally stateful? how much memory will this use? how can I monitor how much memory each operator is using?</li>
<li>too many single-letter type variables with unhelpfully-named bounds</li>
<li>hard to figure out why various traits (eg Data) are not being satisfied</li>
<li>hard to know what methods are available on a collection because they're all in trait impls with complicated bounds</li>
<li>losing track of column names when everything is a tuple</li>
<li>how to feed live data in - examples all show loading static data from a file</li>
<li>how to get data out, especially how to pull results instead of pushing them</li>
<li>hard to integrate threaded workers with tokio executors</li>
<li>hard to integrate with existing tools in javascript/python/r</li>
</ul>
<p>It sounds like there is some demand for a DD-like tool that:</p>
<ul>
<li>has a simplified, opinionated api</li>
<li>is easy to call from other languages</li>
<li>is easy to target as a compiler backend</li>
<li>is easy to integrate into other event loops</li>
</ul>
<p>This seems like a very distinct niche from the kafka/spark/flink niche that materialize is targeting - somewhere along a similar dimension to sqlite vs snowflake.</p>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/why-isnt-differential-dataflow-more-popular/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25867693</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 02:45:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[C++ Anti-Patterns]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25867068">thread link</a>) | @Foe
<br/>
January 21, 2021 | https://martin-ueding.de/posts/cpp-antipatterns/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://martin-ueding.de/posts/cpp-antipatterns/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody text">
    <div>
<p>This is a list of C++ anti-patterns that I have seen in various codes.</p>
<!-- END_TEASER -->

<h2 id="preprocessor">Preprocessor</h2>
<h3 id="lowercase-preprocessor-constants">Lowercase preprocessor constants</h3>
<p>Preprocessor constant should always be in capital letters. Otherwise you will
get the weirdest of bugs that take hours to days to track down. Say there is
some feature that you want to switch on/off during compile time. One way to do
it would be using <code>#ifdef</code> like this:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>int</span> <span>make_query</span><span>(</span><span>Query</span> <span>const</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>q</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// Do some query stuff here.</span>

<span>#ifdef VERIFY_RESULT</span>
    <span>// Perform some verification.</span>
<span>#endif</span>

    <span>// Some other tasks and return statement.</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre>


<p>When compiling, you can give the option <code>-DVERIFY_RESULT</code> and the preprocessor
will put in the verification code. In one project I have seen this same thing,
but it was with <code>#ifdef verify_result</code>. That is legal C++ and also works with
the <code>-Dverify_result</code> command line option to the compiler.</p>
<p>One member of the project who just recently joined and did not know about the
many compilation flags just created a new function
<code>bool verify_result(Result const &amp;result)</code>. The compiler did not say that the
name was not in use. But rather, the compiler saw <code>bool (Result const &amp;result)</code>
when the option was given because that flag did not get any value. GCC
complained that it did not expect the <code>(</code> there.</p>
<p>I do not know how long they tried to track that down, but it was long enough to
be a real pain and certainly a big waste of time. This would not have happened
if the preprocessor constants had been uppercase all the time.</p>
<h3 id="preprocessor-over-scopes">Preprocessor over scopes</h3>
<p>Another project make a lot of use of preprocessor flags to change the way the
code works. This in itself is not a problem. However, there are pieces of code
like this:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>#ifdef FLAG</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>#endif</span>
</code></pre>


<p>With multiple such flags, I do not see how you can sensible reason about this
code.</p>
<h3 id="including-source-files">Including source files</h3>
<p>This was in one of the header files:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>#include</span> <span>"other.cpp"</span><span></span>
</code></pre>


<p>Including source files in header files usually is just wrong. One edge case are
unity builds or template specializations. Said project just did it for no
apparent reason.</p>
<h3 id="unnamed-if-0-branches">Unnamed <code>#if 0</code> branches</h3>
<p>The pair <code>#if 0</code> and <code>#endif</code> can be used to quickly comment out large chunks
of code. Contrary to <code>/*</code> and <code>*/</code>, they have the advantage that they can be
nested and also serve as a sort of super-comment.</p>
<p>When there are multiple of those blocks around, it becomes a bit hard to
understand why some are enabled and others are not enabled:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>#if 0</span><span></span>
<span>// ...</span>
<span>#endif</span>

<span>// ...</span>

<span>#if 1</span>
<span>// ...</span>
<span>#endif</span>

<span>// ...</span>

<span>#if 0</span><span></span>
<span>// ...</span>
<span>#endif</span>
</code></pre>


<p>Is the middle one the negation of the first one? Is the first and third one
actually the same; do they have to be enabled at the same time?</p>
<p>Here I like it better to introduce some named constant for that. The above
could look like the following:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>#ifdef POLISH_WIDGETS</span>
<span>// ...</span>
<span>#endif</span>

<span>// ...</span>

<span>#ifndef POLISH_WIDGETS</span>
<span>// ...</span>
<span>#endif</span>

<span>// ...</span>

<span>#ifdef POLISH_WIDGETS</span>
<span>// ...</span>
<span>#endif</span>
</code></pre>


<p>Then it would be easy to understand what is going on. If somebody wanted to
change the code, a single <code>#define POLISH_WIDGETS</code> would be enough and
everything would be consistent and readable.</p>

<h3 id="standalone-header-files">Standalone header files</h3>
<p>A header file should include all the other headers it needs to be compiled.
Something I have seen a couple times is this here:</p>
<p><code>f.hpp</code>:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>#pragma once</span>

<span>void</span> <span>f</span><span>(</span><span>MyClass</span> <span>x</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre>


<p>Notice that the type <code>MyClass</code> is not defined here. It is defined in this
header, but that is not included in <code>f.hpp</code> at all.</p>
<p>It is defined in <code>myclass.hpp</code>:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>#pragma once</span>

<span>class</span> <span>MyClass</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>public</span><span>:</span>
        <span>int</span> <span>member</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>
</code></pre>


<p>The implementation of the function <code>f</code> is in <code>f.cpp</code>. <em>There</em> the header for
<code>MyClass</code> is included:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>#include</span> <span>"myclass.hpp"</span><span></span>
<span>#include</span> <span>"f.hpp"</span><span></span>

<span>void</span> <span>f</span><span>(</span><span>MyClass</span> <span>x</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>x</span><span>.</span><span>member</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre>


<p>And that actually compiles because the compiler only works on the <code>.cpp</code> files.
And given the ordering of the <code>#include</code> statements, the C++ compiler sees
this:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>class</span> <span>MyClass</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>public</span><span>:</span>
        <span>int</span> <span>member</span><span>;</span>
<span>};</span>

<span>void</span> <span>f</span><span>(</span><span>MyClass</span> <span>x</span><span>);</span>

<span>void</span> <span>f</span><span>(</span><span>MyClass</span> <span>x</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>x</span><span>.</span><span>member</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre>


<p>This will work as long as that header <code>f.hpp</code> is always included after
<code>myclass.hpp</code>. It will start to fail when you use <code>f.hpp</code> somewhere else. There
should be an <code>#include "myclass.hpp"</code> in <code>f.hpp</code>.</p>

<p>The order of the header files in <code>f.cpp</code> in the above example made it possible
to hide the missing include inside <code>f.hpp</code> such that it still compiles. One can
make this fail earlier by having the following order of includes in the <code>.cpp</code>
files:</p>
<ol>
<li>"Own" header file, for <code>X.cpp</code> that would be <code>X.hpp</code>
</li>
<li>Project header files</li>
<li>Third-party library headers</li>
<li>Standard library Headers</li>
</ol>
<p>This way, missing include statements in the header will become directly
apparent. You might find a bug in a third-party library this way.</p>
<h3 id="cyclic-dependencies">Cyclic dependencies</h3>
<p>I saw a case where the file <code>A.hpp</code> provides the classes <code>A1</code> and <code>A2</code>. The
file <code>B.hpp</code> provided <code>B1</code>. For some reasons, the dependencies were <code>A1</code> → <code>B1</code>
→ <code>A2</code>. That is not directly a cyclic dependency of the types but of the header
files. This was "solved" in the project like this in file <code>A.hpp</code>:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>class</span> <span>A1</span> <span>{</span> <span>...</span> <span>};</span>

<span>#include</span> <span>"B.hpp"</span><span></span>

<span>class</span> <span>A2</span> <span>{</span> <span>...</span> <span>};</span>
</code></pre>


<p>Sure, that compiled just fine. But again, header <code>B.hpp</code> is not a standalone
header and can only be used in this sandwich. I have resolved this by creating
the files <code>A1.hpp</code> and <code>A2.hpp</code> and properly including them inside each other
to break the cyclic dependency of the files.</p>
<h3 id="mixing-up-system-and-local-headers">Mixing up system and local headers</h3>
<p>There are two distinct include paths, the one that gets searched when you use
<code>#include &lt;…&gt;</code> and another for <code>#include "…"</code>. The former is for system and
third-party library headers that are installed globally. You can add to that
path using <code>-I</code>. The latter is for your project and can be amended with <code>-i</code>.
One should not mix the two and use <code>-I.</code> in order to include the local headers
with <code>#include &lt;…&gt;</code>.</p>

<p>One can argue about the usage of <code>using namespace</code>. In most cases I will not
use it to keep the global namespace somewhat clean. Using
<code>using namespace std;</code> in a <code>.cpp</code> file is okay because the namespace <code>std</code> is
just dumped out in a single compilation unit. I do not have to worry about it
in other files.</p>
<p>It becomes a totally different story once you put that <code>using namespace std;</code>
into a header file. Then every other header or source file that includes it
will have that namespace dumped out. Even other projects using that library
will suffer from the attempt to save some typing of the library programming.</p>
<h3 id="multiple-files-with-same-include-guard">Multiple files with same include guard</h3>
<p>I do not like the <code>#ifndef X</code>, <code>#define X</code>, <code>#endif</code> style include guards
because they are so error prone. They are hard to read but even worse, one can
choose the same include guard twice in a project. One could even have the same
include guard that some other library already has used.</p>
<p>If that is the case, the errors will be painfully subtle. Depending on the
order if inclusion, the last header file will just not be included. Then you
get errors about undefined types and undefined functions and might pull out
your hair before you realize what is going on.</p>
<p><code>#pragma once</code> is a good alternative except if you are working with IBM XL 12.
But that compiler cannot do C++11, so it is not that interesting for me anyway.</p>
<h3 id="include-guards-do-not-match-the-filename">Include guards do not match the filename</h3>
<p>If you have <code>#ifndef FOO_H</code> in <code>bar.h</code>, bad things will happen when you create
another <code>foo.h</code>. Therefore the include guard should always be derived from the
path, or use <code>#pragma once</code>.</p>

<p>Using C functions in C++ might be a reasonable thing to do. If you do that, do
not include <code>X.h</code> but rather <code>cX</code>. So instead of <code>&lt;stdint.h&gt;</code> use <code>&lt;cstdint&gt;</code>.
This way the C functions will be properly in the <code>std</code> namespace.</p>
<p>Functions like <code>printf</code>, <code>scanf</code>, <code>atoi</code>, <code>fopen</code>, <code>malloc</code>, and a bunch of
others should not be used in C++. There are so much better ways.</p>
<h3 id="include-inside-namespaces">
<code>include</code> inside namespaces</h3>
<p>For reason unknown to me, there are a few includes of standard library headers
inside of namespaces. The only reason I can think of is that writing <code>::std::</code>
instead of <code>std::</code> seemed too much work.</p>
<p>GCC 6.0 has changed the standard headers such that they do not work when you
include them inside a namespace. This way one can catch this anti-pattern.</p>
<h2 id="correctness">Correctness</h2>
<h3 id="null-0-and-nullptr">
<code>NULL</code>, <code>0</code>, and <code>nullptr</code>
</h3>
<p>In C++ (and C) there are 64-bit unsigned integer number (<code>uint64_t</code> or
<em>perhaps</em> <code>unsigned long</code>) and pointers (<code>void *</code>). In the machine, they are
exactly the same thing, 64-bit unsigned integer numbers. For the type system,
it still makes a great difference.</p>
<p>Although they are both just numbers to the computer, one should help the
programmers read the source code and write</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>uint64_t</span> <span>number</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>void</span> <span>*</span><span>pointer</span> <span>=</span> <span>NULL</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre>


<p>This way, it is clear that one is number-zero and the other is pointer-null.
The preprocessor constant <code>NULL</code> is just <code>0</code> or <code>0u</code>, so the compiler always
sees a plain 0 there. Still it is helpful for the programmer to read. In C++11
there even is <code>nullptr</code> which has the correct type, <code>nullptr_t</code>.</p>
<p>In some code you see horrible things like these:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>uint64_t</span> <span>number</span> <span>=</span> <span>NULL</span><span>;</span>
<span>void</span> <span>*</span><span>pointer</span> <span>=</span> <span>0x0</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre>


<h3 id="casting-pointers-to-integers">Casting pointers to integers</h3>
<p>For some reason in one project, pointers are casted to integers. And they are
converted to a special type of integer that you have to choose as a flag to
<code>configure</code> such that the length of that integer is the exact same as the
pointer length, otherwise the compiler would give you an error.</p>
<p>I still do not understand why one would do this sort of brittle code.</p>
<h3 id="subtle-dependence-on-operator-precedence">Subtle dependence on operator precedence</h3>
<p>What is the value of <code>x</code>?</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>uint32_t</span> <span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>1</span> <span>&lt;&lt;</span> <span>3</span> <span>-</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre>


<p>I would read it as $2^3 - 1$ and that is seven. The value actually is four.
When compiling with Clang, it conveniently says this:</p>
<pre><span></span><code><span>precedence.cpp:7:25: warning: operator '&lt;&lt;' has lower precedence than '-'; '-' will be evaluated first</span>
<span>      [-Wshift-op-parentheses]</span>
<span>    uint32_t x = 1 &lt;&lt; 3 - 1;</span>
<span>                   ~~ ~~^~~</span>
<span>precedence.cpp:7:25: note: place parentheses around the '-' expression to silence this warning</span>
<span>    uint32_t x = 1 &lt;&lt; 3 - 1;</span>
<span>                        ^</span>
<span>                      (    )</span>
</code></pre>


<p>What did the original author of that line really mean? Was he aware that the
<code>-</code> operation binds stronger than <code>&lt;&lt;</code>? Can I trust that code without
completely understand where all those magic numbers come from?</p>
<h3 id="not-using-raii">Not …</h3></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://martin-ueding.de/posts/cpp-antipatterns/">https://martin-ueding.de/posts/cpp-antipatterns/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://martin-ueding.de/posts/cpp-antipatterns/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25867068</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 01:26:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
