<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 08:33:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 08:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Tree That Owns Itself (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24884133">thread link</a>) | @panic
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://thetreeographer.com/2018/03/22/the-tree-that-owns-itself/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thetreeographer.com/2018/03/22/the-tree-that-owns-itself/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>No matter how famous or how ancient, all trees are ultimately owned by someone. It could be a government, a trust, or even just an individual caretaker. However, one white oak tree in Athens, Georgia was reportedly so beloved by its owner that upon his death, he gave the tree ownership of itself in his will.<span id="more-2706"></span></p>
<h2>The Legend of the Tree That Owns Itself</h2>
<p>The legend goes that a particularly large and beautiful white oak played a special role in the childhood of its owner, Colonel William Henry Jackson. When he died some time between 1820 and 1832, he deeded the tree and the soil around it to the tree itself. Here is the reported text of his will:</p>
<blockquote><p>I, W. H. Jackson, of the county of Clarke, of the one part, and the oak tree&nbsp;… of the county of Clarke, of the other part: Witnesseth, That the said W. H. Jackson for and in consideration of the great affection which he bears said tree, and his great desire to see it protected has conveyed, and by these presents do convey unto the said oak tree entire possession of itself and of all land within eight feet [2.4 m] of it on all sides.</p></blockquote>
<div data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_2712"><p><a href="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg"><img loading="lazy" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2712" data-attachment-id="2712" data-permalink="https://thetreeographer.com/2018/03/22/the-tree-that-owns-itself/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786/" data-orig-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg" data-orig-size="933,669" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="The_tree_that_owns_itself_(4987035786)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg?w=933" src="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg?w=674&amp;h=484" alt="The_tree_that_owns_itself_(4987035786)" width="674" height="484" srcset="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg?w=674&amp;h=484 674w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg?w=150&amp;h=108 150w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg?w=300&amp;h=215 300w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg?w=768&amp;h=551 768w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself_4987035786-e1521714786992.jpg 933w" sizes="(max-width: 674px) 100vw, 674px"></a></p><p id="caption-attachment-2712">The original Tree That Owns Itself in 1910</p></div>
<p>After that, the tree become known as the Tree that Owns Itself. However, there are a number of problems with the story’s validity. It originally ran as a front page story in the <em>Athens Banner Weekly</em> on August 12, 1890. That’s some 60 years after the supposed transaction took place, and there are no indications that anything special had happened to the tree before that (although it was known as Jackson’s Tree).</p>
<p>On top of that, the only witness to the will itself is the author of the article, and no one has been able to confirm that the statement above was ever made. However, the story became so popular that no one dared doubt the tree’s self-ownership. Effectively, the tree owned itself because everyone said it did.</p>
<p>Legally, of course, the tree isn’t able to own itself regardless of Jackson’s wishes. In fact, careful examination of property lines reveals that the tree isn’t even on his property. It’s officially part of the street (since it’s part of a median in the middle of the street), so its care falls to local authorities.</p>
<p>However, the tree is such a well respected landmark in the city that the Athens-Clarke County government has declared that in spite of the actual legality, the tree owns itself. Because they said so.</p>
<div data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_2713"><p><a href="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2713" data-attachment-id="2713" data-permalink="https://thetreeographer.com/2018/03/22/the-tree-that-owns-itself/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329/" data-orig-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg" data-orig-size="1500,941" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Exp10000XL10000&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg?w=1024" src="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg?w=1024&amp;h=642" alt="the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329" srcset="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg?w=1024&amp;h=642 1024w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg?w=150&amp;h=94 150w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg?w=300&amp;h=188 300w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg?w=768&amp;h=482 768w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/the_tree_that_owns_itself2c_athens2c_georgia_28834283897329.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></a></p><p id="caption-attachment-2713">A postcard from the 1930s commemorating the Tree That Owns Itself</p></div>
<h2>Can a tree have rights?</h2>
<p>It might seem strange that a tree can own anything, let alone itself, but there is actually some legal precedent. Although they usually take a back seat to animal rights, plant rights have been discussed in several countries around the world.</p>
<p>In the Netherlands, a party called <a href="https://in.reuters.com/article/us-dutch-election-plants/plant-rights-party-to-contest-next-dutch-election-idINTRE62S2HA20100329">the Party for the Plants</a> was created to try to snag a few seats in the 2010 parliamentary elections. Although they weren’t particularly successful, their platform focused exclusively on promoting biodiversity and protecting plants from being harvested for biofuels.</p>
<p>More success has been found in New Zealand, where for the first time anywhere a forest was granted legal personhood and ownership of itself. The&nbsp;Te Urewera Act of 2014 changed the legal status of Te Urewera, a forest sacred to the Maori people, from a Natural Park into <a href="http://maorilawreview.co.nz/2014/10/tuhoe-crown-settlement-te-urewera-act-2014/">its own legal entity</a>.</p>

<p>Obviously the forest can’t speak for itself, so a board was set up “to act on behalf of, and in the name of, Te Urewera”. In March 2017 a second act was passed granting similar rights to the Whanganui River, since the local Maori tribe consider the river itself to be their ancestor.</p>
<p>Although it doesn’t go as far as giving trees and other plants ownership of themselves, the Clean Water Act of 1972 in the United States effectively grants them some rights. Under the ‘natural resource damage’ provisions of the law, trees and other resources have some basic rights. It’s the government, however, that’s entrusted with protecting those rights, although any money earned through litigation must be spent on the resource itself. Essentially, the money <em>belongs</em> to the resource.</p>
<h2>The Son of The Tree That Owns Itself</h2>
<p>The Tree That Owns Itself might have been granted semi-legal status in Athens-Clarke County, but that didn’t protect it from the whims of Mother Nature. It was heavily damaged in an ice storm in 1907, and eventually fell down in 1942. Many suspected that the tree had died long before falling.</p>
<p>But if the tree owned land, surely it must pass on to its next of kin. A tree grown from an acorn of the Tree That Owns Itself was selected as the heir, an transplanted into its new home in 1946. It also inherited the name, although it’s also referred to as the Son of the Tree That Owns Itself.</p>
<div data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_2710"><p><a href="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2710" data-attachment-id="2710" data-permalink="https://thetreeographer.com/2018/03/22/the-tree-that-owns-itself/treethatownsitself/" data-orig-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg" data-orig-size="750,563" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;CYBERSHOT&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1097078702&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;9.7&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.008&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Treethatownsitself" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg?w=750" src="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg?w=1070" alt="Treethatownsitself" srcset="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg 750w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg?w=150 150w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/treethatownsitself.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px"></a></p><p id="caption-attachment-2710">The Son of The Tree That Owns Itself</p></div>
<p>It’s now been more than 70 years since the tree moved in to the quiet residential neighborhood on Finley Street, and it appears to be doing well. Despite its unknown legal status, the legend lives on with a plaque commemorating the words that started it all. Slightly edited to be more intelligible to modern readers, it reads:</p>
<blockquote><p>For and in consideration of the great love I bear this tree and the and the great desire I have for its protection for all time, I convey entire possession of itself and all land within eight feed of the tree on all sides<br>
-William M Jackson</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="2711" data-permalink="https://thetreeographer.com/2018/03/22/the-tree-that-owns-itself/forandinconsideration/" data-orig-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg" data-orig-size="693,563" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Forandinconsideration" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg?w=693" src="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg?w=1070" alt="Forandinconsideration" srcset="https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg 693w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg?w=150 150w, https://thetreeographer.files.wordpress.com/2018/03/forandinconsideration.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 693px) 100vw, 693px"></a></p>
<p>If you enjoyed this article about the Tree That Owns Itself, check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://thetreeographer.com/archive/">archive</a>&nbsp;for more amazing tree stories. Also check out the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheTreeographer/">Facebook page</a>, with a few extra tree goodies throughout the week. Subscribe below to receive notifications whenever a new tree story is published.</p>
<p>As always, feel free to drop a comment below. It’s always nice to hear from you!</p>

			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thetreeographer.com/2018/03/22/the-tree-that-owns-itself/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24884133</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 05:51:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No More Bold Visions of the Future]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24882565">thread link</a>) | @riverlong
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://jayriverlong.github.io/2020/10/24/future.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jayriverlong.github.io/2020/10/24/future.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" role="main"> <article role="article">  <p>What do I want the future to be like? What amazing inventions do I want to see, and help build in my lifetime? I realized this morning that I don’t know. I was shocked.</p> <p>I’ve been tinkering with technology since I was a child, and I’ve been investing in early-stage companies for the past five years. More than sixty bets on the future. I’m meant to have bold visions of a better world, theses I support, and capital that I allocate in a technologically optimistic way. I began investing in startups because I wanted to help shape the future. And while I still get excited talking to founders with bold ideas, I have none of my own.</p> <p>When I was a teen, growing up on a diet of Carl Sagan’s Cosmos and Alvin Toffler’s Futurism, I had plenty of big ideas: spaceflight, supersonic travel, mag-lev trains, geodesic domes, bio-nanotech for longevity, and social organization to provide maximum freedom for all. Cheesy, but optimistic.</p> <p>Now I am 29 and I have no big, optimistic ideas. I think of plenty of arbitrages and improvements in efficiency. And while I believe that better infrastructure enables more construction and innovation, closing an obscure pricing gap just isn’t like dreams of great adventure and exploration on the frontier of human experience and possibility.</p> <p>I spend much time thinking about solutions to existing problems – the incentive mismatch in mass media that is causing accelerating polarization, how to remedy the effects of climate change, and so on. But these are all <em>fixes</em>, reactions. It feels like I’m in the belly of the ship, frenetically plugging leaky holes, never even having the space of mind to think <em>where the ship should go</em>. Ostensibly, those decisions are made on the bridge of the ship, which, in October 2020, seems to be populated by well-intentioned individuals, but hamstrung in their ability to make good collective decisions.</p> <p>Recent years have shown me how difficult it is to make <em>any</em> meaningful public decision. Every debate is endlessly contentious, every subject has meaningful nuance, and every decision has exceedingly hard-to-predict second-order-effects. The world is much more complex than it was even twenty years ago, and the effects are paralyzing. This is clearly felt among policymakers, but I feel it even as a technologist: I understand that virtually all tools can be used – and more often than not, <em>will</em> be used – for both good and evil, and how hard the results are to predict over years in our dynamic world. I learned that technology can rarely solve fundamental social problems, and I’ve seen the public perception rollercoaster of “this technology/person/policy is good” to “this is evil” more times than I can count.</p> <p>This puts me in a real bind for having high-conviction views that aren’t microscopically focused. As an example, for the past few years I have struggled developing a long-term view on bitcoin. By network effect, I think it is clear that in the long term, we will have <em>either</em> fiat or crypto – either fully centralized or fully decentralized – not both. Which world do I want to live in? I’m not sure. On the one hand, it is clear that our existing US financial system is fragile with systemic risk, a playball exposed to potentially irresponsible governance. You might call its mechanics unfair to the masses, but you’d also need to point out that it has <em>actually worked</em> in creating prosperity over the past 110 years. (And, comparing the US to other countries, it has worked remarkably well!) I agree with need for overhaul of the system, but I’m not sure if it’s wise throw out the entire thing and open up the world’s largest power vacuum in the process. This rarely ends well. I cannot tell, with intellectual honesty, which avenue is best to pursue. I doubt that anyone does.</p> <p>Other arenas of big problems and changes yield similar dilemmas. Perhaps consequently, I have found myself not dreaming big anymore. I dream small, where the effects are predictable. On dreaming big, there is the paralysis of responsibility and effects, but there is also a level of cynicism that has come to me over the years, as big dreams turn out to be much more fraught and complicated as they move into reality. The nuance, complexity, difficulty, responsibility, and often <em>irreversibility</em> in effecting big changes has slowly removed the stars from my eyes as I look at technology. Maybe that’s a good thing as I come to appreciate the gravity of change.</p> <p>But at the same time, if we don’t take big, bold, bets, we’ll be forever stuck in the valleys of local optima. As Bezos says, the size of your risk-taking should increase with the size of your enterprise – at scale, we should be taking many daring gambles, all the time. But it doesn’t feel like that’s really happening. It feels like we spend lots of effort debating marginal nuance, sitting in the belly of the ship doing maintenance, rather than charting the course forward.</p> <p>It is difficult to be an optimist in 2020. I admire the few<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">1</a></sup> that still have the courage to dream big and to remind ourselves that there <em>is</em> a future that could be amazing and that is worth fighting for.</p>  <hr>  <br> </article> </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jayriverlong.github.io/2020/10/24/future.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24882565</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 22:57:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Boston Dynamics Spot Measured Background Radiation in Chernobyl Exclusion Zone]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 27 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24882438">thread link</a>) | @app4soft
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://www.ukrinform.ua/rubric-technology/3122689-robotpes-vid-boston-dynamics-zamirav-radiaciu-u-zoni-vidcuzenna.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ukrinform.ua/rubric-technology/3122689-robotpes-vid-boston-dynamics-zamirav-radiaciu-u-zoni-vidcuzenna.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Ð�Ð° Ñ‚ÐµÑ€Ð¸Ñ‚Ð¾Ñ€Ñ–Ñ— Ð·Ð¾Ð½Ð¸ Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ñ‡ÑƒÐ¶ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ� Ð²Ð¿ÐµÑ€ÑˆÐµ Ð¿Ñ€Ð¾Ð²ÐµÐ´ÐµÐ½Ð¾ Ð²Ð¸Ð¿Ñ€Ð¾Ð±ÑƒÐ²Ð°Ð½Ð½Ñ� Ð°Ð²Ñ‚Ð¾Ð½Ð¾Ð¼Ð½Ð¾Ð³Ð¾ Ñ€Ð¾Ð±Ð¾Ñ‚Ð° Boston Dynamics «SPOT».</p>

    <div>
         
        <p>ÐŸÑ€Ð¾ Ñ†Ðµ Ð£ÐºÑ€Ñ–Ð½Ñ„Ð¾Ñ€Ð¼Ñƒ Ð¿Ð¾Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ð¾Ð¼Ð¸Ð»Ð¸ Ð² Ð”ÐµÑ€Ð¶Ð°Ð²Ð½Ð¾Ð¼Ñƒ Ð°Ð³ÐµÐ½Ñ‚Ñ�Ñ‚Ð²Ñ– Ð· ÑƒÐ¿Ñ€Ð°Ð²Ð»Ñ–Ð½Ð½Ñ� Ð·Ð¾Ð½Ð¾ÑŽ Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ñ‡ÑƒÐ¶ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ� (Ð”Ð�Ð—Ð’).</p>

<p>Ð—Ð°Ð·Ð½Ð°Ñ‡Ð°Ñ”Ñ‚ÑŒÑ�Ñ�, Ñ‰Ð¾ Ð²Ð¸Ð¿Ñ€Ð¾Ð±ÑƒÐ²Ð°Ð½Ð½Ñ� Ð·Ð´Ñ–Ð¹Ñ�Ð½ÐµÐ½Ð¾ Ð´Ð¾Ñ�Ð»Ñ–Ð´Ð½Ð¸Ñ†ÑŒÐºÐ¾ÑŽ Ð³Ñ€ÑƒÐ¿Ð¾ÑŽ Ð‘Ñ€Ñ–Ñ�Ñ‚Ð¾Ð»ÑŒÑ�ÑŒÐºÐ¾Ð³Ð¾ ÑƒÐ½Ñ–Ð²ÐµÑ€Ñ�Ð¸Ñ‚ÐµÑ‚Ñƒ Ñ�Ð¿Ñ–Ð»ÑŒÐ½Ð¾ Ð· Ñ„Ð°Ñ…Ñ–Ð²Ñ†Ñ�Ð¼Ð¸ Ð”ÐµÑ€Ð¶Ð°Ð²Ð½Ð¾Ð³Ð¾ Ñ�Ð¿ÐµÑ†Ñ–Ð°Ð»Ñ–Ð·Ð¾Ð²Ð°Ð½Ð¾Ð³Ð¾ Ð¿Ñ–Ð´Ð¿Ñ€Ð¸Ñ”Ð¼Ñ�Ñ‚Ð²Ð° «Ð¦ÐµÐ½Ñ‚Ñ€Ð°Ð»ÑŒÐ½Ðµ Ð¿Ñ–Ð´Ð¿Ñ€Ð¸Ñ”Ð¼Ñ�Ñ‚Ð²Ð¾ Ð· Ð¿Ð¾Ð²Ð¾Ð´Ð¶ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ� Ð· Ñ€Ð°Ð´Ñ–Ð¾Ð°ÐºÑ‚Ð¸Ð²Ð½Ð¸Ð¼Ð¸ Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ñ…Ð¾Ð´Ð°Ð¼Ð¸» (Ð”Ð¡ÐŸ «Ð¦ÐŸÐŸÐ&nbsp;Ð’»).</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="840" src="https://static.ukrinform.com/photos/2020_10/1603468013-980.jpg" title="" width="630"></figure>

<p>ÐŸÑ–Ð´ Ñ‡Ð°Ñ� Ñ€Ð¾Ð±Ñ–Ñ‚ Ð²Ð¸ÐºÐ¾Ñ€Ð¸Ñ�Ñ‚Ð¾Ð²ÑƒÐ²Ð°Ð»Ð¸ Ð±ÐµÐ·Ð¿Ñ–Ð»Ð¾Ñ‚Ð½Ñ– Ð»Ñ–Ñ‚Ð°Ð»ÑŒÐ½Ñ– Ð°Ð¿Ð°Ñ€Ð°Ñ‚Ð¸, Ð½Ð°Ð·ÐµÐ¼Ð½Ñ– Ñ€Ð¾Ð±Ð¾Ñ‚Ð¸Ð·Ð¾Ð²Ð°Ð½Ñ– Ñ�Ð¸Ñ�Ñ‚ÐµÐ¼Ð¸, Ð´Ð°Ñ‚Ñ‡Ð¸ÐºÐ¸-Ñ�ÐºÐ°Ð½ÐµÑ€Ð¸ Ð´Ð»Ñ� Ð¾Ñ†Ñ–Ð½ÐºÐ¸ Ñ€Ð¾Ð·Ð¿Ð¾Ð´Ñ–Ð»Ñƒ Ñ€Ð°Ð´Ñ–Ð¾Ð°ÐºÑ‚Ð¸Ð²Ð½Ð¸Ñ… Ð¼Ð°Ñ‚ÐµÑ€Ñ–Ð°Ð»Ñ–Ð² Ð½Ð° Ð¿Ð»Ð¾Ñ‰Ñ– Ñ‚Ð° Ð² Ð¿Ñ€Ð¾Ñ�Ñ‚Ð¾Ñ€Ñ– (Ð³Ð°Ð¼Ð¼Ð°-Ñ�Ð¿ÐµÐºÑ‚Ñ€Ð¾Ð¼ÐµÑ‚Ñ€, Ð»Ñ–Ð´Ð°Ñ€, Ñ„Ð¾Ñ‚Ð¾Ð³Ñ€Ð°Ð¼Ð¼ÐµÑ‚Ñ€Ñ–Ñ�, Ð³Ñ–Ð¿ÐµÑ€Ñ�Ð¿ÐµÐºÑ‚Ñ€Ð°Ð»ÑŒÐ½Ð¸Ð¹ Ñ‚Ð° Ð½ÐµÐ¹Ñ‚Ñ€Ð¾Ð½Ð½Ð¸Ð¹ Ð´Ð°Ñ‚Ñ‡Ð¸ÐºÐ¸).</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="840" src="https://static.ukrinform.com/photos/2020_10/1603468013-913.jpg" title="" width="630"></figure>

<p>Ð—Ð¾ÐºÑ€ÐµÐ¼Ð°, Ð¿Ñ€Ð¾Ð²Ð¾Ð´Ð¸Ð»Ð¸Ñ�ÑŒ Ñ€Ð°Ð´Ñ–Ð¾Ð¼ÐµÑ‚Ñ€Ð¸Ñ‡Ð½Ñ– Ñ‚Ð° Ð³ÐµÐ¾Ñ„Ñ–Ð·Ð¸Ñ‡Ð½Ñ– Ñ€Ð¾Ð±Ð¾Ñ‚Ð¸ Ð½Ð° Ñ‚ÐµÑ€Ð¸Ñ‚Ð¾Ñ€Ñ–Ñ— Ð´Ð²Ð¾Ñ… Ñ�ÐµÐºÑ‚Ð¾Ñ€Ñ–Ð² Ð¿ÑƒÐ½ÐºÑ‚Ñƒ Ñ‚Ð¸Ð¼Ñ‡Ð°Ñ�Ð¾Ð²Ð¾Ñ— Ð»Ð¾ÐºÐ°Ð»Ñ–Ð·Ð°Ñ†Ñ–Ñ— Ñ€Ð°Ð´Ñ–Ð¾Ð°ÐºÑ‚Ð¸Ð²Ð½Ð¸Ñ… Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ñ…Ð¾Ð´Ñ–Ð² «Ð&nbsp;ÑƒÐ´Ð¸Ð¹ Ð»Ñ–Ñ�» Ñ‚Ð° Ð½Ð° Ñ‚ÐµÑ€Ð¸Ñ‚Ð¾Ñ€Ñ–Ñ�Ñ… Ð¿ÑƒÐ½ÐºÑ‚Ñ–Ð² Ð·Ð°Ñ…Ð¾Ñ€Ð¾Ð½ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ� Ñ€Ð°Ð´Ñ–Ð¾Ð°ÐºÑ‚Ð¸Ð²Ð½Ð¸Ñ… Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ñ…Ð¾Ð´Ñ–Ð² «ÐŸÑ–Ð´Ð»Ñ–Ñ�Ð½Ð¸Ð¹» Ñ– «Ð‘ÑƒÑ€Ñ�ÐºÑ–Ð²ÐºÐ°».</p>

<figure><img alt="" height="840" src="https://static.ukrinform.com/photos/2020_10/1603468013-197.jpg" title="" width="630"></figure>

<p>Ð—Ð° Ñ€ÐµÐ·ÑƒÐ»ÑŒÑ‚Ð°Ñ‚Ð°Ð¼Ð¸ Ñ€Ð¾Ð±Ñ–Ñ‚, Ð½Ð° «ÐŸÑ–Ð´Ð»Ñ–Ñ�Ð½Ð¾Ð¼Ñƒ» Ñ‚Ð° «Ð‘ÑƒÑ€Ñ�ÐºÑ–Ð²Ñ†Ñ–» Ð±ÑƒÐ´Ðµ Ð¾Ñ‚Ñ€Ð¸Ð¼Ð°Ð½Ð¾ Ð·Ð¾Ð±Ñ€Ð°Ð¶ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ� Ñƒ 3D-Ñ„Ð¾Ñ€Ð¼Ð°Ñ‚Ñ– Ñ– ÐºÐ°Ñ€Ñ‚Ð¸ Ñ€Ð¾Ð·Ð¿Ð¾Ð´Ñ–Ð»Ñƒ Ð°ÐºÑ‚Ð¸Ð²Ð½Ð¾Ñ�Ñ‚Ñ– Ñ€Ð°Ð´Ñ–Ð¾Ð½ÑƒÐºÐ»Ñ–Ð´Ñ–Ð². Ð¢Ð°ÐºÐ¾Ð¶ Ð´Ð¾Ñ�Ð»Ñ–Ð´Ð½Ð¸ÐºÐ¸ Ð¾Ð±Ñ–Ñ†Ñ�ÑŽÑ‚ÑŒ Ð½Ð°Ð´Ð°Ñ‚Ð¸ Ð·Ð¾Ð±Ñ€Ð°Ð¶ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ� Ð¿ÑƒÐ½ÐºÑ‚Ñƒ «Ð&nbsp;ÑƒÐ´Ð¸Ð¹ Ð»Ñ–Ñ�» Ñ–Ð· Ð´Ñ–Ð»Ñ�Ð½ÐºÐ°Ð¼Ð¸, Ñ�ÐºÑ– Ð¼Ð°ÑŽÑ‚ÑŒ Ð²Ð¸Ñ�Ð¾ÐºÑƒ Ð¿Ð¾Ñ‚ÑƒÐ¶Ð½Ñ–Ñ�Ñ‚ÑŒ Ð´Ð¾Ð·Ð¸.</p>

<section><b>Ð§Ð¸Ñ‚Ð°Ð¹Ñ‚Ðµ Ñ‚Ð°ÐºÐ¾Ð¶: </b><a href="https://www.ukrinform.ua/rubric-technology/3023941-u-singapuri-parki-patruluut-robotipsi-pilnuut-za-distancieu.html" target="_blank">Ð£ Ð¡Ñ–Ð½Ð³Ð°Ð¿ÑƒÑ€Ñ– Ð¿Ð°Ñ€ÐºÐ¸ Ð¿Ð°Ñ‚Ñ€ÑƒÐ»ÑŽÑŽÑ‚ÑŒ Ñ€Ð¾Ð±Ð¾Ñ‚Ð¸-Ð¿Ñ�Ð¸ – Ð¿Ð¸Ð»ÑŒÐ½ÑƒÑŽÑ‚ÑŒ Ð·Ð° Ð´Ð¸Ñ�Ñ‚Ð°Ð½Ñ†Ñ–Ñ”ÑŽ</a></section>

<p>Ð’Ð¸ÐºÐ¾Ð½Ð°Ð½Ñ– Ñ€Ð¾Ð±Ð¾Ñ‚Ð¸ Ð´Ð¾Ð·Ð²Ð¾Ð»Ñ�Ñ‚ÑŒ Ð”Ð¡ÐŸ «Ð¦ÐŸÐŸÐ&nbsp;Ð’» Ð¾Ð½Ð¾Ð²Ð¸Ñ‚Ð¸ ÐºÐ°Ñ€Ñ‚Ð¸ Ñ€Ð¾Ð·Ð¿Ð¾Ð´Ñ–Ð»Ñƒ Ñ€Ð°Ð´Ñ–Ð°Ñ†Ñ–Ð¹Ð½Ð¾Ð³Ð¾ Ð·Ð°Ð±Ñ€ÑƒÐ´Ð½ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ�.</p>

<p>Ð¯Ðº Ð¿Ð¾Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ð¾Ð¼Ð»Ñ�Ð² Ð£ÐºÑ€Ñ–Ð½Ñ„Ð¾Ñ€Ð¼, 20 Ð¶Ð¾Ð²Ñ‚Ð½Ñ� Ñƒ Ð”Ð�Ð—Ð’ Ð·Ð°Ñ�Ð²Ð¸Ð»Ð¸ Ð¿Ñ€Ð¾ Ð´ÐµÑ„Ñ–Ñ†Ð¸Ñ‚ ÐºÐ¾ÑˆÑ‚Ñ–Ð² Ð½Ð° Ð¿Ñ–Ð´Ð¿Ñ€Ð¸Ñ”Ð¼Ñ�Ñ‚Ð²Ð°Ñ… Ð·Ð¾Ð½Ð¸ Ð²Ñ–Ð´Ñ‡ÑƒÐ¶ÐµÐ½Ð½Ñ�, Ñ‰Ð¾ Ð²Ð¸Ð½Ð¸Ðº ÑƒÐ½Ð°Ñ�Ð»Ñ–Ð´Ð¾Ðº Ð½ÐµÐ´Ð¾Ñ�Ñ‚Ð°Ñ‚Ð½ÑŒÐ¾Ð³Ð¾ Ñ„Ñ–Ð½Ð°Ð½Ñ�ÑƒÐ²Ð°Ð½Ð½Ñ� Ñƒ 2020 Ñ€Ð¾Ñ†Ñ– Ð´Ð²Ð¾Ñ… Ð±ÑŽÐ´Ð¶ÐµÑ‚Ð½Ð¸Ñ… Ð¿Ñ€Ð¾Ð³Ñ€Ð°Ð¼. ÐŸÑ€Ð¾Ð±Ð»ÐµÐ¼Ð¸ Ð· Ñ„Ñ–Ð½Ð°Ð½Ñ�ÑƒÐ²Ð°Ð½Ð½Ñ�Ð¼ Ð¿Ð¾Ñ‚Ð¾Ñ‡Ð½Ð¸Ñ… Ð²Ð¸Ð´Ð°Ñ‚ÐºÑ–Ð² Ñ” Ð½Ðµ Ð»Ð¸ÑˆÐµ Ð½Ð° Ð§Ð�Ð•Ð¡, Ð° Ð¹ Ð½Ð° Ð”ÐŸ "Ð¦ÐžÐ¢Ð†Ð—", Ð”Ð¡ÐŸ "Ð•ÐºÐ¾Ñ†ÐµÐ½Ñ‚Ñ€", Ð”Ð¡ÐŸ "ÐŸÑ–Ð²Ð½Ñ–Ñ‡Ð½Ð° ÐŸÑƒÑ‰Ð°", Ð”Ð¡ÐŸ "Ð¦ÐŸÐŸÐ&nbsp;Ð’".</p>

                    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ukrinform.ua/rubric-technology/3122689-robotpes-vid-boston-dynamics-zamirav-radiaciu-u-zoni-vidcuzenna.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24882438</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 22:33:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My toothbrush streams gyroscope data]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 140 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24881729">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://blog.johannes-mittendorfer.com/artikel/2020/10/my-toothbrush-streams-gyroscope-data | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.johannes-mittendorfer.com/artikel/2020/10/my-toothbrush-streams-gyroscope-data">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
            <p>Since a few month I own an electrical toothbrush from Phillips called <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=Sonicare+HX992B">Sonicare HX992B</a>. It connects to <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.philips.cdp.ohc.tuscany" title="App">an mobile App</a> using Bluetooth that tells you how well you brushed your teeth, shows the orientation in real-time, and also notifies you when to change the brush for a new one.</p>
            <p><img src="https://blog.johannes-mittendorfer.com/assets/img/sonicare-image.jpeg" alt="Phillips Sonicare"></p>
            <p>I was curious how this exactly works. Since the application uses Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE), I used the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=no.nordicsemi.android.mcp">nRF Connect</a> app for Android to get a list of advertised services.</p>
            <p><img src="https://blog.johannes-mittendorfer.com/assets/img/whatsapp-image-2020-10-09-at-19-34-24.jpeg" alt="Screenshot of nRF connect" title="Screenshot of nRF connect"></p>
            <p>Now I had a list of 12 BLE services of which only four are <a href="https://www.bluetooth.com/de/specifications/gatt/" title="List of common services">standard services described on bluetooth.com</a>. In addition to well-known services like Generic Access, Generic Attribute, Device Information and Battery Service, also eight custom services exist, that were created by the manufacturer. Every one of the first seven service UUIDs starts with <code>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d5000</code> and ends with a number from 1 to 8 with number 3 missing. An additional eight service has a completely different prefix than the others.</p>
            <table>
              <thead>
                <tr>
                  <th>UUID</th>
                  <th>Service</th>
                </tr>
              </thead>
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>0x1800</td>
                  <td>Generic Access</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>0x1801</td>
                  <td>Generic Attribute</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>0x180a</td>
                  <td>Device Information</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>0x180f</td>
                  <td>Battery Service</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d50001</td>
                  <td>Unknown Service 1</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d50002</td>
                  <td>Unknown Service 2</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d50004</td>
                  <td>Unknown Service 4</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d50005</td>
                  <td>Unknown Service 5</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d50006</td>
                  <td>Unknown Service 6</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d50007</td>
                  <td>Unknown Service 7</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>477ea600-a260-11e4-ae37-0002a5d50008</td>
                  <td>Unknown Service 8</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>a651fff1-4074-4131-bce9-56d4261bc7b1</td>
                  <td>Unknown Other Service</td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table>
            <p>By switching the device on and off, changing the strength and mode and also by changing the brush back and forth, I was able to identify some of the characteristics of the six services. By reverse engineering the code of the Android app using <a href="https://github.com/skylot/jadx">jadx</a> I found information about the session storage and many other things.</p>
            <table>
              <thead>
                <tr>
                  <th>Service</th>
                  <th>Suffix</th>
                  <th>Actions</th>
                  <th>Description</th>
                </tr>
              </thead>
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>Handle (1)</td>
                  <td>4010</td>
                  <td>RWN</td>
                  <td>Handle State: Off(0), Standby(1), Run(2),Charge(3), Shutdown(4) Validate(6), LightsOut(7)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4020</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4022</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4030</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4040</td>
                  <td>RW-</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4050</td>
                  <td>RW-</td>
                  <td>Current Time (Unix Timestamp)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Brushing (2)</td>
                  <td>4070</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>Current session id</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4080</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>Mode (0x0=Clean, 0x2=White+, …)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4082</td>
                  <td>RWN</td>
                  <td>State (0=Ready, 1=Active, 2=Resume)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4090</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>Active time in seconds</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4091</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>Mode 2 (0x78=Clean, 0xa0=White+, 0xc8=Gum Health, 0xb4=Deep Clean+)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>40a0</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>40b0</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>Strength (0,1,2)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>40c0</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Session Storage (4)</td>
                  <td>40d0</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>Last session id (e.g. 0x2c05 = 1324)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>40d2</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>40d5</td>
                  <td>RW-</td>
                  <td>Session Type</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>40e0</td>
                  <td>-WN</td>
                  <td>Request session (write session id, write 0x00 to 4110, get notification with data here and at 4100)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4100</td>
                  <td>–N</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4110</td>
                  <td>-WN</td>
                  <td>Session Access Control Point</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Orientation (5)</td>
                  <td>4120</td>
                  <td>RW-</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4130</td>
                  <td>–N</td>
                  <td>Gyroscope Data</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4140</td>
                  <td>-WN</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>Brush (6)</td>
                  <td>4210</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>NFC Tag Version</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4220</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>? INT8</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4230</td>
                  <td>R-N</td>
                  <td>Brush Serial</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4240</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>Brush Manufacturing Date?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4250</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4254</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4260</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4270</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4280</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>Brush Lifetime (Seconds)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4290</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>Brush Usage (Seconds)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>42a0</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>Brush Type (None, Adaptive Clean, Adaptive White, Tongue Care, Adaptive Gums)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>42a2</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>42a4</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>42a6</td>
                  <td>RWN</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>42b0</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>NFC Payload (always phillips.com)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>42c0</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>? INT16</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>7</td>
                  <td>4310</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>? INT16</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4320</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>? INT16</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4330</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>?</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4360</td>
                  <td>R–</td>
                  <td>? (Only uses second byte)</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>8</td>
                  <td>4410</td>
                  <td>RW-</td>
                  <td>? INT16</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                  <td>&nbsp;</td>
                  <td>4420</td>
                  <td>RW-</td>
                  <td>? INT32</td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table>
            <p>According to the application sources, the last unknown service is called “Moonshine Streaming” and is used to update the firmware. I agreed with myself to not touch this one, since I could damage the firmware and would need to brush my teeth by hand again.</p>
            <p>Since I could see a very course orientation displayed in the app during a cleaning session, I expected orientation data somewhere in the characteristics. I found them in the service <code>5</code>. Once you enable notifications for the <code>4130</code> service, you get a data stream to byte arrays. It turns out, these are indeed the values of the gyroscope.</p>
            <p><img src="https://blog.johannes-mittendorfer.com/assets/img/sonicare-gyro.png" alt="Gyroscrope" title="Gyroscope"></p>
            <p>I created a python library to interface with the toothbrush in Python. Feel free to experiment, find the meaning of the missing services and submit pull requests: <a href="https://github.com/joushx/python-sonicare">https://github.com/joushx/python-sonicare</a></p>
          </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.johannes-mittendorfer.com/artikel/2020/10/my-toothbrush-streams-gyroscope-data</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24881729</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 20:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Implement a retro game in JavaScript with MakeCode Arcade style sprites]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24881012">thread link</a>) | @codeguppy
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://codeguppy.com/code.html?t=mars_attack&list=games | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://codeguppy.com/code.html?t=mars_attack&list=games">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://codeguppy.com/code.html?t=mars_attack&amp;list=games</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24881012</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 18:30:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Good Quality DOSBox Video Capture]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 43 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24880762">thread link</a>) | @headalgorithm
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://susam.in/blog/good-quality-dosbox-video-capture/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://susam.in/blog/good-quality-dosbox-video-capture/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p>By <b>Susam Pal</b> on 01 Sep 2020</p>
<h2 id="vintage-dos-programs"><a href="#vintage-dos-programs">Vintage DOS Programs</a></h2>

<p>
Once in a while, I fire up one of the vintage DOS games or language
interpreters in DOSBox for nostalgia's sake. I have archived these
vintage programs at <a href="https://github.com/susam/dosage">github.com/susam/dosage</a>.
DOSBox is an emulator program that emulates IBM PC compatible computers
running DOS. Trying my hands on these antiquated DOS programs now evokes
old memories from my childhood days days when I first came across
computers as part of our primary school curriculum.
</p>

<p>
Computers were much simpler in those days. The ones in our school were
IBM PC compatible computers with mostly monochrome displays. A couple of
them had support for a very limited number of colours provided by CGA or
EGA graphics cards. The ability to boot a computer using a
5¼-inch floppy disk containing MS-DOS, load a Logo or BASIC
interpreter, or a computer game from another floppy disk, and then write
some programs or play a few games without any distraction had its own
charm that I find missing from modern day computing.
</p>

<p>
Often while using old DOS programs with DOSBox in this day and age, I
want to take screenshot captures or video captures of the DOSBox
sessions and share them with my friends. In this article, I will explain
how I create good quality screenshot captures and video captures of
DOSBox sessions in formats that I can share with others.
</p>


<h2 id="contents"><a href="#contents">Contents</a></h2>
<ul>
  <li><a href="#vintage-dos-programs">Vintage DOS Programs</a></li>
  <li><a href="#software-versions">Software Versions</a></li>
  <li><a href="#ibm-pc-logo-in-dosbox">IBM PC Logo in DOSBox</a></li>
  <li><a href="#digger-in-dosbox">Digger in DOSBox</a></li>
  <li><a href="#dosbox-screenshot-capture">DOSBox Screenshot Capture</a></li>
  <li><a href="#dosbox-video-capture">DOSBox Video Capture</a></li>
  <li><a href="#dosbox-audio-video-capture">DOSBox Audio/Video Capture</a></li>
  <li><a href="#dosbox-gif-animation">DOSBox GIF Animation</a></li>
  <li><a href="#references">References</a></li>
</ul>


<h2 id="software-versions"><a href="#software-versions">Software Versions</a></h2>

<p>
Since this article involves several pieces of software, some of what is
written here may not hold good in future if the behaviour of any of
these software tools change in future. The list below contains the
versions of all software tools that were used to test the commands
provided in this article:
</p>

<ol>
  <li>macOS High Sierra 10.13.6</li>
  <li>DOSBox 0.74-3</li>
  <li>FFmpeg 4.3.1</li>
  <li>ImageMagick 7.0.10-28
  </li><li>IBM Personal Computer Logo Version 1.00</li>
  <li>Digger (Original PC booter version by Windmill Software)</li>
</ol>

<p>
Note that both Logo and Digger programs in the list above are DOS
programs that were released in 1983. They cannot be run directly on
modern computers but they can be run with DOSBox since it emulates old
IBM PC compatible computers.
</p>


<h2 id="ibm-pc-logo-in-dosbox"><a href="#ibm-pc-logo-in-dosbox">IBM PC Logo in DOSBox</a></h2>

<p>
IBM Personal Computer Logo developed by Logo Computer Systems Inc.
(LCSI) in 1983 was the first piece of software I got introduced to while
learning computers as a kid. I came across it at the age of 8 when I was
in Class 4 and our school had a 5¼-inch floppy disk with IBM PC
Logo on it. As a result, Logo was the first programming language I
learnt in my life. About 20 years later, I would realize that the first
programming language I learnt is a dialect of Lisp. How wonderful!
</p>

<figure id="logo-welcome-screenshot">
  <a href="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-logo-0.png"><img src="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-logo-0.png" alt="A screenshot of IBM Personal Computer Logo with copyright notices of IBM and LCSI, welcome message, and question mark prompt"></a>
  <figcaption>
    Welcome screen of IBM Personal Computer Logo
  </figcaption>
</figure>

<!--
Class Age Year
   KG   4   88
    1   5   89
    2   6   90
    3   7   91
    4   8   92
    5   9   93
    6  10   94
    7  11   95
    8  12   96
    9  13   97
   10  14   98
-->

<p>
If the Logo interpreter program <code>LOGO.COM</code> exists in the
current directory, it can be run with DOSBox using the following
command:
</p>

<pre><code>dosbox LOGO.COM</code></pre>

<p>
One of the things I enjoyed drawing with Logo was a grid of overlapping
circles like this:
</p>

<figure id="logo-program-screenshot">
  <a href="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-logo-1.png"><img src="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-logo-1.png" alt="A grid made with 20 circles along with Logo source code for it"></a>
  <figcaption>
    Grid of circles drawn with IBM Personal Computer Logo
  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
Here is the Logo source code for the above output:
</p>

<pre><code>REPEAT 20 [REPEAT 180 [FD 1 RT 2] RT 18]</code>
</pre>


<h2 id="digger-in-dosbox"><a href="#digger-in-dosbox">Digger in DOSBox</a></h2>

<p>
At around the same time I learnt Logo, I also came across Digger, a
computer game for IBM PC developed by Windmill Software in 1983.
</p>

<figure id="digger-welcome-screenshot">
  <a href="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-digger-0.png"><img src="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-digger-0.png" alt="A screenshot of Digger welcome screen with the names and pictures of various game characters with a copyright notice of Windmill Software"></a>
  <figcaption>
    Welcome screen of Digger
  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
If the Digger program <code>DIGGER.COM</code> exists in the directory,
it can be run using DOSBox with the following command:
</p>

<pre><code>dosbox DIGGER.COM -c "config -set cpu cycles=500" -machine cga</code>
</pre>

<p>
The <code>-machine cga</code> option emulates a machine with Color
Graphics Adapter (CGA) because Digger requires a machine of this type to
run correctly. The <code>cycles=500</code> configuration option slows
down the speed at which DOSBox emulates instructions in order to emulate
the slow machines of olden days. Without this option, Digger runs too
fast to be able to be conveniently playable.
</p>

<figure id="digger-game-screenshot">
  <a href="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-digger-1.png"><img src="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-digger-1.png" alt="A screenshot of underground maze in the game of Digger"></a>
  <figcaption>
    A game of Digger that has just begun
  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
Digger has an excellent gameplay where the player digs through
underground tunnels to pick up emeralds, drop gold bags to release the
gold or squash nobbins and hobbins, collect the released gold to earn
more points, and so on. It uses bright and attractive colours. The music
is great. When Digger was released in 1983, it was quite advanced for
its time.
</p>



<h2 id="dosbox-screenshot-capture"><a href="#dosbox-screenshot-capture">DOSBox Screenshot Capture</a></h2>

<p>
The screenshots above were obtained by running IBM PC Logo and the
original 1983 PC booter version of Digger on DOSBox and then resizing
the screenshots such that their aspect ratio matches the aspect ratio of
old CRT computer monitors.
</p>

<p>
To obtain the screenshots, we first press <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> +
<kbd>F5</kbd> while DOSBox is running. The paths of the screenshots
appear in the console output at the terminal where DOSBox was launched.
For example:
</p>

<pre><samp>Capturing Screenshot to /Users/susam/Library/Preferences/capture/logo_000.png
Capturing Screenshot to /Users/susam/Library/Preferences/capture/logo_001.png</samp>
</pre>

<pre><samp>Capturing Screenshot to /Users/susam/Library/Preferences/capture/digger_000.png
Capturing Screenshot to /Users/susam/Library/Preferences/capture/digger_001.png</samp>
</pre>

<p>
The screenshots obtained in this manner have an aspect ratio of 8:5
which makes the output look stretched horizontally. The old CRT computer
monitors for which these old DOS programs were written had an aspect
ratio of 4:3 instead. This stretched look can be fixed by resizing the
images to an aspect ratio of 4:3. Here are the commands used to fix the
aspect ratio and produce the images:
</p>

<pre><code>convert logo_000.png -sample '1920x1440!' dosbox-logo-0.png
convert logo_001.png -sample '1920x1440!' dosbox-logo-1.png</code>
</pre>
<pre><code>convert digger_000.png -sample '1920x1440!' dosbox-digger-0.png
convert digger_001.png -sample '1920x1440!' dosbox-digger-1.png</code>
</pre>

<!--
According to Screen Resolution Statistics for January 2020 by
w3schools.com, here are the statistics of browser resolutions:

Resolution   %age  Cumulative

Lower         9.0    9.0
1280 x  720   3.9   12.9
1024 x  768   1.4   14.3
1360 x  768   1.0   15.3
1366 x  768  27.6   42.9
1280 x  800   1.8   44.7
1536 x  864   9.8   54.5
1440 x  900   5.6   60.1
1600 x  900   4.1   64.2
1280 x 1024   2.4   66.6
1680 x 1050   2.6   69.2
1920 x 1080  20.3   89.5
1920 x 1200   1.5   91.0
2560 x 1440   1.7   92.7
Other High    7.3  100.0

1440 x 1080 is strictly larger than 55.3% displays.
1600 x 1200 is strictly larger than 66.6% displays.
1920 x 1440 is strictly larger than 91.0% displays.
x 1080 >= 89.5% displays
x 1200 >= 91.0% displays.
x 1440 >= 92.7% displays
-->

<p>
The <code>convert</code> program comes with ImageMagick. There are a few
things worth noting here:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    We use the <code>-sample</code> option here to resize the image as
    opposed to using <code>-resize</code> or <code>-scale</code>. The
    <code>-resize</code> or <code>-scale</code> option would smooth the
    jagged edges in the text and graphics by introducing additional
    colours. The <code>-resize</code> option is great for real world
    images where we do want the edges to be smooth while scaling up or
    down but in these screenshots we want to retain the crisp and jagged
    edges that is typical of DOSBox and the old CRT monitors. Therefore
    we use the <code>-sample</code> option that does not introduce any
    new colours. Instead it uses nearest-neighbour interpolation (point
    sampling) to decide the colours of the scaled image.
  </li>
  <li>
    The <code>!</code> flag is used to ignore the aspect ratio of the
    original image. Without this flag, the output files would be
    1920x1200 in size, that is, the largest size with an aspect ratio of
    8:5 that fits in a 1920x1440 box. With this flag, the original
    aspect ratio of 8:5 is ignored and the output is exactly 1920x1440
    in size.
  </li>
</ul>

<p>
By the way, I have donated these images above to Wikimedia Commons under
the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0) license:
</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:IBM_LCSI_Logo_Welcome_Screen.png">File:IBM_LCSI_Logo_Welcome_Screen.png</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:IBM_LCSI_Logo_Circles.png">File:IBM_LCSI_Logo_Circles.png</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Digger_Original_PC_Booter_Version_Welcome_Screen.png">File:Digger_Original_PC_Booter_Version_Welcome_Screen.png</a>
  </li><li><a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Digger_Original_PC_Booter_Version_Game.png">File:Digger_Original_PC_Booter_Version_Game.png</a></li>
</ul>

<p>
Having the images on Wikimedia Commons helps to include these
screenshots in the Wikipedia articles on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logo_(programming_language)#Implementations">Logo</a>
and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digger_(video_game)">Digger</a>.
</p>


<h2 id="dosbox-video-capture"><a href="#dosbox-video-capture">DOSBox Video Capture</a></h2>

<p>
To start capturing video of DOSBox, we press <kbd>Ctrl</kbd> +
<kbd>Alt</kbd> + <kbd>F5</kbd>. The same key combination stops capturing
video. The following output appears in the console output to show where
the video file is saved:
</p>

<pre><samp>Capturing Video to /Users/susam/Library/Preferences/capture/logo_000.avi
Stopped capturing video.</samp>
</pre>

<p>
Say, I want to share a video capture of DOSBox with Logo running on it
with my friends who might be on devices that do not support playing AVI
files. The following FFmpeg command converts the video to a format that
can be distributed widely and played on a wide range of devices and
players:
</p>

<pre><code>ffmpeg -i logo_000.avi -an -c:v libx264 -preset veryslow \
       -crf 17 -vf format=yuv420p,scale=1920:1440:flags=neighbor,fps=30 \
       dosbox-logo.mp4</code>
</pre>

<p>
Here is what the output looks like:
</p>

<figure id="logo-video">
  <video controls="">
    <source src="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-logo.mp4" type="video/mp4">
  </video>
  <figcaption>
    Video capture of IBM Personal Computer Logo
    [<a href="https://susam.in/files/blog/dosbox-logo.mp4">MP4</a>]
  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>
Let us briefly discuss the various FFmpeg options used here:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>
      <code>-i logo_000.avi</code>
    </p>
    <p>
      This, of course, specifies the input file.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <code>-an</code>
    </p>
    <p>
      The audio is silent in this video, so we reduce the file size a
      little by disabling the audio stream with this option. For
      example, without this option the output file size was 317 KB but
      with this option it turned out to be 282 KB.
    </p>
    <p>
      This option should not be specified if the audio stream needs to
      preserved, for example, with DOS games that have audio. We will
      see an example of this in the next section.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <code>-c:v libx264</code>
    </p>
    <p>
      This option selects the x264 encoder to encode the video stream
      into H.264 format. H.264 is also known as MPEG-4 Part 10, Advanced
      Video Coding (MPEG-4 AVC). Currently, it is the most popular
      format for recording, compression, and distribution of video
      content.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>
      <code>-crf 17</code>
    </p>
    <p>
      This option provides visually lossless output, that is, high
      quality output without any loss in quality that can be perceived
      by human eyes. For completely lossless output, we need to use the
      <code>-crf 0</code> option. However, this option sets the video
      profile to <code>High 4:4:4 Predictive</code> which prevents the
      video from playing in some video players. This issue is discussed
      in more detail in the point about <code>yuv420p</code> pixel
      format that comes later in this list. Since <code>-crf 0</code>
      cannot be used due to this issue, the next best option is
      <code>-crf 1</code> which while not completely lossless is much
      better than …</p></li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://susam.in/blog/good-quality-dosbox-video-capture/">https://susam.in/blog/good-quality-dosbox-video-capture/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://susam.in/blog/good-quality-dosbox-video-capture/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24880762</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 17:49:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The four dangerous animals of product development]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24880218">thread link</a>) | @ochronus
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://ochronus.online/four-dangerous-animals-of-product-development/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ochronus.online/four-dangerous-animals-of-product-development/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-233" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="itemscope">
<div>

<div itemprop="text">
<p>This is going to be a short walk in the product development zoo, I hope you’ll enjoy the ride!</p>
<p><em>Caveat</em>: what you’ll read about are (usually) not personality types but behaviors in a specific (type of) situation. Acting like a HIPPO, a WOLF, a RHINO or a ZEBRA doesn’t make anyone a bad person. You’re still a team, aim to understand where they are coming from, and, well, they might even be right, with the wrong communication style. </p>
<h2>The HIPPO – the Highest Paid Person’s Opinion</h2>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<figure><picture title="The four dangerous animals of product development 3">
<source type="image/webp" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hippo.png.webp 484w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hippo-300x300.png.webp 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hippo-150x150.png.webp 150w" srcset="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20484%20484'%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px">
<img width="484" height="484" src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20484%20484'%3E%3C/svg%3E" alt="hippo - Highest Paid Person's Opinion" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hippo.png 484w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hippo-300x300.png 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hippo-150x150.png 150w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px" data-lazy-src="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/hippo.png">
</picture>
</figure>
</div>
<div>
<p>It can be tempting to give in to the HIPPOs – founders or CEO or VPS who want to make all the decisions – but don’t let them steer you off course.</p>
<p>Bring everything back to your vision and objectives. If the HIPPOs aren’t aligned with those, you could be headed for dangerous waters.</p>
<p>Don’t let your HiPPO kill your ideas – inform them with data and make them a <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2017/10/26/data-driven-decision-making-beware-of-the-hippo-effect/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data-driven HiPPO</a>! </p>
<p>Read more about <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/derosetichy/2013/04/15/what-happens-when-a-hippo-runs-your-company/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">what happens when a HIPPO runs your company</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h2>The WOLF – Working On the Latest Fire</h2>
<div>
<div>
<p>The WOLF has a short attention span and a temptation to jump from one problem to the next. They tend to only enjoy fighting fires, This will disrupt your team’s focus and effectiveness, making you easy prey for your competitors.</p>
<p>Create a process for collecting feedback about problems, bugs and only consider these along with all other requests. Set up triaging and set clear priorities and a method for prioritization.</p>
<p>There’s a whole book on WOLF prioritization: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1942788290/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Phoenix Project</a></p>
</div>
<div>
<figure><picture title="The four dangerous animals of product development 4">
<source type="image/webp" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wolf.png.webp 484w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wolf-300x300.png.webp 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wolf-150x150.png.webp 150w" srcset="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20484%20484'%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px">
<img width="484" height="484" src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20484%20484'%3E%3C/svg%3E" alt="wolf - Working On the Latest Fire" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wolf.png 484w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wolf-300x300.png 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wolf-150x150.png 150w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px" data-lazy-src="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wolf.png">
</picture>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<h2>The RHINO – Really Here In Name Only</h2>
<div>
<div>
<figure><picture title="The four dangerous animals of product development 5">
<source type="image/webp" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/rhino.png.webp 478w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/rhino-300x300.png.webp 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/rhino-150x150.png.webp 150w" srcset="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20478%20478'%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px">
<img width="478" height="478" src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20478%20478'%3E%3C/svg%3E" alt="rhino - Reall Here In Name Only" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/rhino.png 478w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/rhino-300x300.png 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/rhino-150x150.png 150w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 478px) 100vw, 478px" data-lazy-src="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/rhino.png">
</picture>
</figure>
</div>
<div>
<p>The RHINO is just there to collect a paycheck without contributing much to the team. They might not be actively impeding your decision-making, but they are not helping much either. </p>
<p>Having a clearly defined prioritization process can help ensure all your team members understand how decisions are made and give them the confidence to actively participate. Hopefully, in this process, everyone is empowered to have a say and it doesn’t turn into “Well our process is that the boss tells you what’s important” – which is exactly how you end up with a team of disillusioned RHINOs.</p>
</div>
</div>
<h2>The ZEBRA – Zero Evidence But Really Arrogant</h2>
<div>
<div>
<p>ZEBRAs think they know it all but rely on their instinct rather than any actual evidence. To stave off the ZEBRAs in your midst, make sure that you’ve got data to back up your decisions.</p>
<p>Come up with quick experiments you can run to test ideas and gather evidence. Push for a data-driven culture.</p>
<p>An interesting article for the HIPPO vs. the ZEBRA: <a href="https://kromatic.com/blog/in-defense-of-the-hi-p-p-o/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">In defense of the HIPPO…fear the ZEBRA</a></p>
</div>
<div>
<figure><picture title="The four dangerous animals of product development 6">
<source type="image/webp" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/zebra.png.webp 484w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/zebra-300x300.png.webp 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/zebra-150x150.png.webp 150w" srcset="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20484%20484'%3E%3C/svg%3E" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px">
<img width="484" height="484" src="data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%20484%20484'%3E%3C/svg%3E" alt="zebra - Zero Evindence But Really Aggressive" data-lazy-srcset="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/zebra.png 484w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/zebra-300x300.png 300w, https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/zebra-150x150.png 150w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 484px) 100vw, 484px" data-lazy-src="https://ochronus.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/zebra.png">
</picture>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<h2>And one extra…. the RHINO again! This time, Really High value New Opportunity</h2>
<p>Usually, it’s a salesperson with an amazing value customer deal for an unplanned feature insisting re-allocating resources to build what’s required to win the deal. The results, sadly, are an ignored strategy and roadmap and resources allocated to serve a single customer.</p>
<p>There are two ways here:</p>
<p>1, Chase the RHINO away: Compare the opportunity cost and value and argue against signing the deal if you have customer insight supporting the roadmap.<br>2, Tame the RHINO: Adjust the roadmap if the opportunity includes features you already had planned for later in the year.</p>
<p>Read more here: <a href="https://www.productfocus.com/taming-the-rhino/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Taming the Rhino</a></p>

<p>There’s an amazing doc called <a href="https://www.productboard.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/The-Essential-Guide-to-Prioritization.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Essential Guide to Prioritization</a> which explains the above with more context and more detail.</p>
<hr>
<h4>You might be interested in these posts, too:</h4>
<p><a href="https://ochronus.online/goal-setting/">The 101 of effective goal setting</a></p>
<p><a href="https://ochronus.online/learning-at-work-is-work/">Learning at work is absolutely work</a></p>
<p><a href="https://ochronus.online/how-to-stop-winning-arguments/">How to stop winning arguments</a></p>
<p><a href="https://ochronus.online/stories-we-tell-ourselves/">The stories we tell ourselves</a></p>


</div>
</div>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ochronus.online/four-dangerous-animals-of-product-development/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24880218</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 16:34:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[/.bashrc VS –/.profile VS –/.bash_profile]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 128 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24880170">thread link</a>) | @keyboardman
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://leimao.github.io/blog/bashrc-VS-profile-VS-bash_profile/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://leimao.github.io/blog/bashrc-VS-profile-VS-bash_profile/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" role="main">
  <div>
    
	<p><img src="https://leimao.github.io/images//author_images/Lei-Bio-Medium.jpg" alt="Lei Mao bio photo"></p><h3>Lei Mao</h3>
<p>Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Science.</p>
<p>

<a href="http://facebook.com/dukeleimao" target="_blank"><i></i> Facebook</a>
<a href="http://linkedin.com/in/lei-mao" target="_blank"><i></i> LinkedIn</a>


<a href="http://github.com/leimao" target="_blank"><i></i> GitHub</a>
<a href="http://scholar.google.com/citations?user=R2VUf7YAAAAJ" target="_blank"><i></i>&nbsp; G. Scholar</a>






<a href="mailto:dukeleimao@gmail.com" target="_blank"><i></i> E-Mail</a>

<a href="https://leimao.github.io/feed.xml" target="_blank"> RSS</a>
  </p></div>
  <article>
    <!--/ .headline-wrap -->
    <div>
      <h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>

<p>Sometimes, when I remotely login to some Linux computers or use Docker containers, I would find the shell is plain black and white, different from the colorful shell I am used to dealing with on my local machine. This sometimes makes it difficult to look for libraries, executables, and folders. Sometimes, some executables could be called directly from a local shell but from a remote login shell they are not directly callable.</p>



<p>It turns out that the shell is an executable and it is “configured” by special shell scripts such as <code>~/.bashrc</code>, <code>~/.profile</code>, <code>~/.bash_profile</code>. In this blog post, I would like to briefly discuss the differences between these scripts.</p>

<h3 id="bashrc">~/.bashrc</h3>

<p>I modify the <code>~/.bashrc</code> file from time to time, because sometimes I would like to set some environment variables, including <code>PATH</code> which is an environmental variable in Linux and other Unix-like operating systems that tells the shell which directories to search when looking for executable files. But I have been ignoring the commented block at its beginning for decades.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ cat ~/.bashrc 
# ~/.bashrc: executed by bash(1) for non-login shells.
# see /usr/share/doc/bash/examples/startup-files (in the package bash-doc)
# for examples
...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This means that in a local shell where <code>bash</code> is being used, this shell script will be executed immediately after <code>bash</code> is executed. There are many other shell executable variants, such as <code>zsh</code>. <code>~/.bashrc</code> is only specific to <code>bash</code>.</p>



<p>There are many settings in the <code>~/.bashrc</code> that makes the shell look colorful. For example,</p>

<div><div><pre><code># enable color support of ls and also add handy aliases
if [ -x /usr/bin/dircolors ]; then
    test -r ~/.dircolors &amp;&amp; eval "$(dircolors -b ~/.dircolors)" || eval "$(dircolors -b)"
    alias ls='ls --color=auto'
    #alias dir='dir --color=auto'
    #alias vdir='vdir --color=auto'

    alias grep='grep --color=auto'
    alias fgrep='fgrep --color=auto'
    alias egrep='egrep --color=auto'
fi
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="profile">~/.profile</h3>

<p>The comment block found in the <code>~/.profile</code> explicitly tells us that it will be executed for the login shells. However, if <code>~/.bash_profile</code> or <code>~/.bash_login</code> exists, <code>~/.profile</code> will not be executed.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ cat ~/.profile 
# ~/.profile: executed by the command interpreter for login shells.
# This file is not read by bash(1), if ~/.bash_profile or ~/.bash_login
# exists.
# see /usr/share/doc/bash/examples/startup-files for examples.
# the files are located in the bash-doc package.

# the default umask is set in /etc/profile; for setting the umask
# for ssh logins, install and configure the libpam-umask package.
#umask 022

# if running bash
if [ -n "$BASH_VERSION" ]; then
    # include .bashrc if it exists
    if [ -f "$HOME/.bashrc" ]; then
	. "$HOME/.bashrc"
    fi
fi

# set PATH so it includes user's private bin if it exists
if [ -d "$HOME/bin" ] ; then
    PATH="$HOME/bin:$PATH"
fi

# set PATH so it includes user's private bin if it exists
if [ -d "$HOME/.local/bin" ] ; then
    PATH="$HOME/.local/bin:$PATH"
fi
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The default content of the <code>~/.profile</code> is simple. In most cases, it inherits whatever is in the <code>~/.bashrc</code>, and adds some user specific executable filepath to the environment variable <code>PATH</code>. So if there are commands that make the shell look colorful in the <code>~/.bashrc</code>, the login shell should also look colorful.</p>

<h3 id="bash_profile">~/.bash_profile</h3>

<p>Unfortunately, in most of my login trials, the shells were never colorful, and sometimes the environment variables did not match my expectation. In those cases, this is because there exists a <code>~/.bash_profile</code> and therefore <code>~/.profile</code> or <code>~/.bashrc</code> is never executed. Usually the <code>~/.bash_profile</code> will be empty, which means that we would not have the environment and appearance that we have in our local shell.</p>



<p>To make the login shell “back to normal”, we could either delete the <code>~/.bash_profile</code> or modify the <code>~/.bash_profile</code> by adding some commands like</p>



<h3 id="caveats">Caveats</h3>

<p>Sometimes, a non-color shell could be helpful. It can be used to indicate that you are not working in local shell, and that what you are seeing could either be a Docker shell or a remote login shell. When we know what shell we are dealing with, we will be more likely to avoid dangerous operations. For example, in a Docker shell, we could do almost anything, such as <code>rm -rf /</code> without sudo, without harming the local system.</p>

<h3 id="acknowledgement">Acknowledgement</h3>

<p>I would like to thank Liam Keane from Hacker News for correcting the grammars and polishing the words in the blog post.</p>

      <hr>
      
    </div><!-- /.article-wrap -->
  
    <!-- /#disqus_thread -->
  
  </article>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://leimao.github.io/blog/bashrc-VS-profile-VS-bash_profile/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24880170</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 16:28:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Microsoft Tilecode]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 399 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24879861">thread link</a>) | @Impossible
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://microsoft.github.io/tilecode/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://microsoft.github.io/tilecode/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://microsoft.github.io/tilecode/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24879861</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:42:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Genghis, Graphs and Middle Management]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24879825">thread link</a>) | @neophocion
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://middle-out.io/posts/genghis | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://middle-out.io/posts/genghis">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>You’re a developer working on the Foobar feature at company X. Unbeknownst to you, Genghis, the company CEO, just had dinner with other industry leaders and became excited about this new thing called Beezlyboo. Genghis mentions his excitement at Thursday’s executive council meeting, with the company’s top layer of middle management listening in.</p><p>Mandukhai, the middle manager two layers above you, was present. She conveys the takeaways in her regular Friday morning coffee catchup with the managers that report to her, including the Foobar team lead, your boss, Subotai.</p><p>Fighting for relevance after a bumpy year, Subotai grows convinced that working on this Beezlyboo thing might be his ticket back into Mandukhai's good graces.</p><p>You enter the office on Monday morning, unsheathe your sword, and balance it carefully on top of your monitor before sitting down and getting to work. <i>Little do you know that two weeks from now, half your time will be spent on this new thing called Beezlyboo.</i></p><div><h3>How Middle Management Emerges</h3><p>This is an unfortunately common description of how decisions are made in many of today’s <del>Khanates</del> companies. Why is that? Let’s take a look at how communication and decision making evolve as companies grow larger.</p><p>Here’s how many companies begin: <br><img src="https://middle-out.io/images/genghis/2company.png" alt="2 people companies"></p><p>Two founders, working closely to get their new startup off the ground.</p><p>A more mature company might look more like this:<br><img src="https://middle-out.io/images/genghis/k3company.png" alt="Small company"></p><p>That’s Google circa 1999. Individuals hold increasingly defined roles. Management and process are beginning to creep in, but all anyone really wants to do is get on with things, management be damned. Grabbing a colleague to discuss something is as easy as shouting across the office.</p><p>But as companies grow larger, the majority end up looking more like this:<img src="https://middle-out.io/images/genghis/3comp.png" alt="Large company"></p><p>This is of course an over-simplification as every organization maintains informal networks, cross-functional teams, and parallel networks. But it is a useful representation to understand how hierarchies simplify the sharing of information by creating highways for it. Additionally, we will assume that every team operates in a mesh (even if we were not skilled enough to draw those relations).</p><p>See those ‘o’ nodes? That’s middle management. Layers and layers of it. Its main purpose is to simplify decision making and communication by concentrating ownership of different parts of the business in the hands of a select few.</p><figure><d-figure id="boldify"><div svelte-1667065745=""><p>For the more mathematically inclined, middle management splits the previously shown complete graphs with <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><msub><mi>K</mi><mi>n</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi>n</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>n</mi><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn></mrow></mfrac></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">K_n = \frac{n(n-1)}{2}</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span> edges into multiple complete subgraphs with <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><msub><mi>M</mi><mi>n</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><msubsup><mo>∑</mo><mi>i</mi><mi>n</mi></msubsup><msub><mi>K</mi><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>i</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>+</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">M_n = \sum_i^nK_{m(i)+1}</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span> edges, where <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>i</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">i</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span> runs over managers and <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>i</mi><mo>)</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">m(i)</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span> is the number of people they manage. We assume that reporting edges correspond to lines of communication and that members of a team are fully connected in complete graphs.</p></div></d-figure></figure><p>The benefits are clear. When CEO Genghis or Kublai, another middle manager, want to figure out what’s going on with the Foobar team (highlighted above in Millenial pink), all they need do is call Subotai. By concentrating ownership of Foobar in Subotai’s hands, his team is shielded from unnecessary communication, allowing them to focus on their work.</p><figure><d-figure id="boldify"><div svelte-1667065745=""><p>To illustrate: <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><msub><mi>K</mi><mrow><mn>5</mn><mn>0</mn><mn>0</mn><mn>0</mn></mrow></msub><mo>=</mo><mn>1</mn><mn>2</mn><mo separator="true">,</mo><mn>4</mn><mn>9</mn><mn>7</mn><mo separator="true">,</mo><mn>5</mn><mn>0</mn><mn>0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">K_{5000} = 12,497,500</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span>, but introducing 556 managers<sup>1</sup> each with <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>i</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>=</mo><mn>1</mn><mn>0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">m(i) = 10</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span> reports gives <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><msub><mi>M</mi><mrow><mn>5</mn><mn>5</mn><mn>6</mn></mrow></msub><mo>=</mo><mn>3</mn><mn>0</mn><mo separator="true">,</mo><mn>5</mn><mn>8</mn><mn>0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">M_{556} = 30,580</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span>. That's only <span><span><span><math><semantics><mrow><mn>0</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">.</mi><mn>2</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">0.2\%</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span> of the original and a radically simpler org structure! </p></div></d-figure></figure><p>But there's also an obvious downside: poor decision making. While the ‘x’ nodes focus on the work at hand, the ‘o’ nodes are busy talking and aligning amongst themselves. This creates two problems: the ‘o’s lose touch with the actual work being done, while the ‘x’s cannot easily see, communicate, or influence beyond team boundaries. Which, remember, is why you’ll be surprised when Beezlyboo lands on your desk in two weeks' time.</p><h3>What Companies Are Doing About This Today</h3><p>So far we've been talking about idealized companies. In reality, there are informal networks that permeate company hierarchies. There are also good and bad ‘x’s and ‘o’s. We know a lot about what a good ‘o’ is (or should be). There’s an <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/vickyvalet/2019/03/19/americas-best-management-consulting-firms-2019/#656906003d00">entire industry out there dedicated to this</a>, complete with degrees (MBAs) and reading material (those management books you tend to find in airport bookshops).</p><p>One thing ‘o’s obsess over is how best to organize things, which is great. That's their job, after all. The problem is that their solutions are often clunky. Do any of these sound familiar?</p><ul><li><b>Culture stuff:</b> the ‘o’s realize the company’s formal and informal hierarchies are too strong, so they begin promoting things like guilds, societies, team building activities, random coffee catchups between senior leads and juniors, etc.</li><li><b>Reorgs:</b> featuring endless tweaks to the traditional hierarchical org structure (functional, divisional, matrix/cross-functional… you name it). Ironically, it’s the ‘o’s that instigate these —  often to the complete bewilderment of the ‘x’s.</li><li><b>Surveys:</b> because making the ‘x’s click through an annoying ten-page annual survey is a great way of discovering how they really feel. Right? Right. </li></ul><p>If these solutions sound drab and disengaging, it's because they are. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ronald_Coase">Ronald Coase</a>, the 1991 Nobel laureate in economics, published an <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1468-0335.1937.tb00002.x">influential essay in 1937</a> on why firms even appear, and mentions that the benefits of larger firms are quickly outweighed by the overheads of maintaining their complex hierarchies and the misallocations of resources which stem from this. In a more modern work, Gary Hammel and Michele Zanini demonstrate in <a href="https://www.humanocracy.com/">Humanocracy</a> -- another one of those airport books -- that:                </p><p>A <a href="https://www.gallup.com/workplace/236552/managers-engaged-jobs.aspx">2018 Gallup study</a> found two-thirds of US employees and 51 percent of US managers to be disengaged at work.</p><p>In 2018, there were 146 million employees in the US workforce. [...] Of these, 20.5 million were managers and supervisors. In addition, there were 6.4 million employed in administrative support functions. In total, then, the bureaucratic class comprises 26.9 million individuals or 18.4 percent of the US workforce. [...] claiming more than $3.2 trillion in compensation, or nearly a third of America’s total wage bill.</p><p>They argue that, if we could repurpose a fraction of this managerial bloat into more productive pursuits, we would free up a lot of unproductive excess wages and therefore raise productivity, overall compensation (for the rest of us), and employee engagement.</p><p><b>Genghis:</b> Okay, kiddo, that's great... but we're trying to run a Khanate company that stretches from eastern Europe to China. Maybe our team building activities are a little boring, and we do like a good reorg, especially after we invade acquire a new company, but what are you proposing? That we fire all our generals and officers and turn into those Valve hippies? <br><b>Ogedei (You):</b> Not at all. Hear me out.</p><h3>What the Future Might Look Like</h3><p>With everyone and <a href="https://www.itv.com/news/wales/2020-03-19/people-stuck-at-home-are-sharing-pictures-of-their-cat-and-dog-coworkers">their cat</a> — not to mention the <a href="https://www.oecd.org/future-of-work/">OECD</a> — talking about the Future of Work these days, isn’t it time we began trying to tackle company organization with more pizazz? You know, just throw some tech and AI at it.</p><p><b>Genghis:</b> Oh god, here we go again with your AI thing.<br></p><p>He's right: here we go.<sup>2</sup> One of the most significant transformations due to play out over the next decade is the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/06/20/slack-ceo-predicts-end-of-company-email-as-we-know-it-in-7-years.html">death of email</a> in within-company communications and its replacement by tools like Slack and Teams. Not only do Slack and Teams introduce a new medium for companies to communicate in, they also allow for modern third-party integrations via their APIs. That’s something email tools like Gmail or Outlook never quite got right.</p><p>On top of this, there's an unfolding generational shift. Millennials will continue to graduate to positions of power as the 2020s progress — and they’ve grown up using online chat protocols and social networks.</p><p><b>Ogedei:</b> So here’s the thing, Dad. The way we organize ourselves in companies will change because young people like me communicate in new and different ways.</p><p>The first wave of startups attempting to tackle this — like <a href="https://knowyourteam.com/">Know Your Team (KYT)</a>, <a href="https://www.ally.io/">Ally</a>, <a href="https://lattice.com/">Lattice</a>, <a href="https://www.donut.com/">Donut</a>, <a href="https://withcadence.io/">Cadence</a>, and a handful of others — are already well on their way.</p><p>Let's take KYT as an example. It's a fantastic tool that takes the magic of being a good 'o' and pours it into a suite of effective communication tools to help you manage your reports. Backed by years of research and a kick-ass CEO in <a href="https://clairelew.com/">Claire Lew</a>, KYT is a great example of a company pushing the envelope of how we think about management.</p><figure><d-figure id="boldify"><div svelte-1667065745=""><div><p>If middle managers in today’s corporations are obsessed with airport books and ways of organizing people, then the true organizational geeks are military commanders and theorists. Organizing militaries has been a thing since time immemorial, from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sun_Tzu">Sun Tzu</a> to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_von_Clausewitz">Clausewitz</a>.<sup>3</sup></p><p>The Mongols weren’t too shabby either. Instead of Slack, they used a system of postal relays called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yam_(route)">Yam</a>. Instead of executive councils, they had <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kurultai">Kurultais</a>. The Mongols adapted quickly and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religion_in_the_Mongol_Empire">didn't try to change the religious habits of conquered populations</a>. By virtue of necessity, they also had a <a href="https://www.britannica.com/place/Mongol-empire/Organization-of-Genghis-Khans-empire">pretty devolved leadership structure</a> — individual Khans ruled parts of the empire which were thousands of miles apart. We could learn a lot about how management can be done better from the Mongols.<sup>4</sup></p></div></div></d-figure></figure><h3>Rethinking How We Organize</h3><p>So if fully connected graphs don't scale, and if tight hierarchies are inefficient and soul-crushing, what else is there?</p><p>Say you're a middle manager. You report to someone, a few others report to you. A good chunk of your time is spent synthesizing information (mostly updates) flowing across your node in the graph, from the top down and from the bottom up. </p><p>This is where we come in. At Middle Out, we're working on a solution that analyses user conversations, summarizes important segments into updates, and proposes these updates to users for final editing and approval before making them visible to the rest of the company. We then take these updates and show each user the ones our model believes are most useful to them. This is tantamount to getting rid of the fog-of-war that shrouds parts of any company from individual employees. In short, you'd see Beezlyboo coming a mile away. </p><figure><d-figure id="boldify"><div svelte-1667065745=""><div><p>Why did this not exist before? Why do people still update each other …</p></div></div></d-figure></figure></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://middle-out.io/posts/genghis">https://middle-out.io/posts/genghis</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://middle-out.io/posts/genghis</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24879825</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA['changeme' is valid base64]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24879062">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://blog.3fx.ch/post/changeme-base64/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.3fx.ch/post/changeme-base64/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <article>
        <header>
            
        </header>

        


        <p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base64">Base64-encoding</a> is ubiquitous in our
modern world. Many programs communicate in base64-encoded messages, since these
have nice properties: They consist of a very limited subset of ASCII characters,
and can thus be displayed as text. E-Mails for example are commonly encoded in
base64 in transfer, which can be seen in the <code>Content-Transfer-Encoding</code> header.</p>

<p>Where I volunteer we have a tradition of putting <code>changeme</code> as a placeholder for
many template variables indicating that they should be overwritten later. Thus,
if we later still see <code>changeme</code> anywhere we know that somewhere somebody must
have forgotten to specify a variable<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Sometimes these template variables should correspond to base64-encoded content,
i.e. the base64-decoding of said variable should produce meaningful content. But
what happens if somebody forgets to define said variable, and it is substituted
with<code>changeme</code> instead? I always thought that it would fail to
decode the string since the probability that <code>changeme</code> is actually valid base64
encoding must be very low. But lo and behold, this is not the case:</p>

<pre><code>% echo changeme | base64 -d
r�[1m
</code></pre>

<p>Running <code>hexdump</code> on the output we can identify the characters:</p>

<pre><code>% echo changeme | base64 -d | hexdump -C
00000000  72 16 a7 81 e9 9e      |r.....|
00000006
</code></pre>

<p>Mostly nonsense, but the second byte is interesting: It is an ASCII control
character <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>, meaning trips up all sorts of programs which expect to read
printable ASCII characters, such as JSON deserializers.</p>

<p>This bug actually occurred when I was migrating some applications between
different Kubernetes clusters: In the old cluster the application ran without
problems, but I forgot to specify some variable in the new cluster, and it lead
to Go complaining about non-ASCII characters in a JSON string.</p>

<p>I guess the moral of the story is: If you use dummy values be sure that they
cannot be misinterpreted.</p>



        
    </article>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.3fx.ch/post/changeme-base64/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24879062</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 13:24:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[September 2020 least deadly month ever in Sweden]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 129 | Comments 132 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24878723">thread link</a>) | @ptr
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://cornucopia.cornubot.se/2020/10/september-2020-least-deadly-month-ever.html?m=1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cornucopia.cornubot.se/2020/10/september-2020-least-deadly-month-ever.html?m=1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-2414610535484946156" itemprop="articleBody"><p>
According to the state authority Statistics Sweden (SCB) data, september 2020 was the least deadly month per capita ever in Swedish history. So far the year 2020 has been the third least deadly year per capita ever in the country, despite the tragic and global Covid-19 pandemic.</p><table><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9FFnIABbac4/X5Pw8Wo0YFI/AAAAAAABB58/SHSv6ZYjdD0Vz6mP10Bp1YI3UlnpY_zBwCLcBGAsYHQ/s2048/1.png"><img data-original-height="1176" data-original-width="2048" height="160" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9FFnIABbac4/X5Pw8Wo0YFI/AAAAAAABB58/SHSv6ZYjdD0Vz6mP10Bp1YI3UlnpY_zBwCLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h366/1.png" width="280"></a></td></tr><tr><td>Deaths in September 1860 - 2020 in Sweden per 100 000 population. Data: SCB</td></tr></tbody></table><div><p>September 2020 was the least deadly month ever in Sweden, at least so far back as the data from SCB:s public database provides data. There were 63.07 deaths per 100 000 people in September 2020, and the previous record low was 64.24 in June 2019, and before that 65.13 in June 2018.</p><div><div><p>For the year 2020 so far, ie January - September, the number of deaths per capita is the third lowest ever.</p><table><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0S5HrrSJ-u4/X5Pw8Yv4K1I/AAAAAAABB6A/-sEnWALKjRAJy_5Z6GM4xDDZsYzg1QhFACLcBGAsYHQ/s2048/2.png"><img data-original-height="1176" data-original-width="2048" height="160" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-0S5HrrSJ-u4/X5Pw8Yv4K1I/AAAAAAABB6A/-sEnWALKjRAJy_5Z6GM4xDDZsYzg1QhFACLcBGAsYHQ/w640-h366/2.png" width="280"></a></td></tr><tr><td>Deaths January - September 1860 - 2020 in Sweden per 100 000 population. Data: SCB</td></tr></tbody></table><br></div></div></div><p>The number of deaths per 100 000 population in Sweden was 675 for January - September 2020. 2019 January - September have the record low at 636 and 2016 had the record before that at &nbsp;673. Data sources are the same as above.</p><p><b>Both 2017 and 2018 had a higher numer of deaths per capita January - September than Sweden have had for the same months in 2020, despite the Covid-19 pandemic.</b></p><p>Possible confounding factors might be demographic mix. However, the average age in Sweden (<a href="https://www.statistikdatabasen.scb.se/pxweb/sv/ssd/START__BE__BE0101__BE0101B/BefolkningMedelAlder/">SCB database table</a>) was 41.1 years in 2011, and had a plateau at 41.2 for the years 2012 - 2018, and increased to 41.3 years in 2019, so the average population age is increasing. There is no data for 2020 yet.&nbsp;</p><p><i>I am not an epidemiologist. It is not up to me to draw conclusions from this. The numbers above are simple facts, based on the high quality official statistics. My only merit is running the independent blog in economics and politics in Sweden with the highest traffic since the start 2008, and being used to crunch official statistics and data. As my Swedish language article on the subject got some international attention, I have published this article in bad English.</i></p><p><i>New visitors will be unable to comment, as my moderator robot deletes any comments made by non-listed accounts.&nbsp;</i></p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cornucopia.cornubot.se/2020/10/september-2020-least-deadly-month-ever.html?m=1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24878723</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 12:22:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Porting Firecracker to a Raspberry Pi 4 (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24878698">thread link</a>) | @k__
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://blog.cloudkernels.net/posts/firecracker-rpi4/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.cloudkernels.net/posts/firecracker-rpi4/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      

<p>Since we got our hands on the new Raspberry Pi 4, we started exploring how
various virtualization technologies behave on the board. First thing we tried is how to run <a href="https://cloudkernels.github.io/posts/rpi4-64bit-virt/">Nabla</a> on it and how it compares to native KVM.</p>

<p>Next thing we wanted to try is <a href="https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker">firecracker</a>, the notorious micro-VMM that
Amazon Lambda &amp; Fargate run on. To our disappointment, firecracker was not
<a href="https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker/issues/1196">yet</a> running on RPi4. So we started looking into coding in the necessary
changes :)</p>

<p>After a bit of investigation, we figured out that the key missing piece is
support for the GICv2 ARM interrupt controller. In fact, firecracker only
supports GIC version 3 since it was open-sourced, but not version 2, which is
the version appearing in the Raspberry Pi series, as well as in other popular
boards, like the Hikey 970 we got our hands on, or Khadas VIM3. A bit more
digging into the internals of firecracker and the Linux kernel, helped us
work out the details and open a <a href="https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker/pull/1235">pull-request</a> which adds support for the
missing parts.</p>

<h4 id="changes-in-firecracker">Changes in Firecracker</h4>

<p>The Generic Interrupt Controller (GIC) is the IP block in the ARM processors
that implements interrupt handling. The Linux kernel supports user- and
kernel-space emulation for GICv2 as well as GICv3 and v4. However, Firecracker
only handles the GICv3-related configuration of the virtual GIC (VGIC).
Similarly, setting up the FDT for the guest microVM from Firecracker only
handles GIC-v3 devices.</p>

<p>In terms of code organization, the GIC related code currently exposes a function
for setting up GICv3 performing the corresponding <code>ioctl</code> KVM commands. The
first part of our PR changes this by introducing a GIC Trait which defines the
common interface for all GIC implementations. Even though it is still under
discussion, what exactly will be in the Trait in its final form, it will be
something along the following lines:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rs"><span>/// Trait for GIC devices.
</span><span></span><span>pub</span><span> </span><span>trait</span><span> </span>GICDevice<span> </span>{<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>/// Returns the GIC version of the device
</span><span></span><span>    </span><span>fn</span> <span>version</span>(<span>&amp;</span><span>self</span>)<span> </span>-&gt; <span>u32</span>;<span>
</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>/// Returns the file descriptor of the GIC device
</span><span></span><span>    </span><span>fn</span> <span>device_fd</span>(<span>&amp;</span><span>self</span>)<span> </span>-&gt; <span>&amp;</span><span>DeviceFd</span>;<span>
</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>/// Returns an array with GIC device properties
</span><span></span><span>    </span><span>fn</span> <span>device_properties</span>(<span>&amp;</span><span>self</span>)<span> </span>-&gt; <span>&amp;</span>[<span>u64</span>];<span>
</span><span></span>}<span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>With this in place, we can define objects per GIC version, which implement this
Trait, and still have the rest of the code deal with the <code>GICDevice</code> Trait,
which is transparent to the GIC version.</p>

<p>The implementations for each version, implement the Trait and a <code>new</code> function
which is used to create the new object:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rs"><span>pub</span><span> </span><span>fn</span> <span>new</span>(vm: <span>&amp;</span><span>VmFd</span>,<span> </span>vcpu_count: <span>u64</span>)<span> </span>-&gt; <span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span><span>Box</span><span>&lt;</span>GICDevice<span>&gt;&gt;</span><span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>The differentiation between the two versions lays in the VGIC register
attributes that each device exposes. As a result, the work we need to do is essentially to <code>mmap</code> their addresses.</p>

<p>GICv2 relevant addresses include the <strong>distributor</strong> and <strong>cpu</strong> groups:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rs"><span>/* Setting up the distributor attribute.
</span><span> We are placing the GIC below 1GB so we need to substract the size of the distributor.
</span><span>*/</span><span>
</span><span></span>set_device_attribute(<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>vgic_fd,<span>
</span><span>    </span>kvm_bindings::KVM_DEV_ARM_VGIC_GRP_ADDR,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>u64</span>::from(kvm_bindings::KVM_VGIC_V2_ADDR_TYPE_DIST),<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>get_dist_addr()<span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u64</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>u64</span>,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span></span>)<span>?</span>;<span>
</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>/* Setting up the CPU attribute.
</span><span> */</span><span>
</span><span></span>set_device_attribute(<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>vgic_fd,<span>
</span><span>    </span>kvm_bindings::KVM_DEV_ARM_VGIC_GRP_ADDR,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>u64</span>::from(kvm_bindings::KVM_VGIC_V2_ADDR_TYPE_CPU),<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>get_cpu_addr()<span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u64</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>u64</span>,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span></span>)<span>?</span>;<span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>whereas the GICv3 includes the <strong>distributor</strong> and <strong>redistributor</strong> groups:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rs"><span>/* Setting up the distributor attribute.
</span><span> We are placing the GIC below 1GB so we need to substract the size of the distributor.
</span><span>*/</span><span>
</span><span></span>set_device_attribute(<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>vgic_fd,<span>
</span><span>    </span>kvm_bindings::KVM_DEV_ARM_VGIC_GRP_ADDR,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>u64</span>::from(kvm_bindings::KVM_VGIC_V3_ADDR_TYPE_DIST),<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>get_dist_addr()<span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u64</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>u64</span>,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span></span>)<span>?</span>;<span>
</span><span>
</span><span></span><span>/* Setting up the redistributors' attribute.
</span><span>We are calculating here the start of the redistributors address. We have one per CPU.
</span><span>*/</span><span>
</span><span></span>set_device_attribute(<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>vgic_fd,<span>
</span><span>    </span>kvm_bindings::KVM_DEV_ARM_VGIC_GRP_ADDR,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>u64</span>::from(kvm_bindings::KVM_VGIC_V3_ADDR_TYPE_REDIST),<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>&amp;</span>get_redists_addr(<span>u64</span>::from(vcpu_count))<span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u64</span><span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>u64</span>,<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span></span>)<span>?</span>;<span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Finally, for both versions of GIC we finalize the device initialization by
setting the number of supported interrupts and the <em>control_init</em> group.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rs"><span>/// Finalize the setup of a GIC device
</span><span></span><span>pub</span><span> </span><span>fn</span> <span>finalize_device</span>(fd: <span>&amp;</span><span>DeviceFd</span>)<span> </span>-&gt; <span>Result</span><span>&lt;</span>()<span>&gt;</span><span> </span>{<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>/* We need to tell the kernel how many irqs to support with this vgic.
</span><span>     * See the `layout` module for details.
</span><span>     */</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span>nr_irqs: <span>u32</span> <span>=</span><span> </span><span>super</span>::layout::IRQ_MAX<span> </span><span>-</span><span> </span><span>super</span>::layout::IRQ_BASE<span> </span><span>+</span><span> </span><span>1</span>;<span>
</span><span>    </span><span>let</span><span> </span>nr_irqs_ptr<span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>&amp;</span>nr_irqs<span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>*</span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>u32</span>;<span>
</span><span>    </span>set_device_attribute(<span>
</span><span>        </span>fd,<span>
</span><span>        </span>kvm_bindings::KVM_DEV_ARM_VGIC_GRP_NR_IRQS,<span>
</span><span>        </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span>        </span>nr_irqs_ptr<span> </span><span>as</span><span> </span><span>u64</span>,<span>
</span><span>        </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span>    </span>)<span>?</span>;<span>
</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>/* Finalize the GIC.
</span><span>     * See https://code.woboq.org/linux/linux/virt/kvm/arm/vgic/vgic-kvm-device.c.html#211.
</span><span>     */</span><span>
</span><span>    </span>set_device_attribute(<span>
</span><span>        </span>fd,<span>
</span><span>        </span>kvm_bindings::KVM_DEV_ARM_VGIC_GRP_CTRL,<span>
</span><span>        </span><span>u64</span>::from(kvm_bindings::KVM_DEV_ARM_VGIC_CTRL_INIT),<span>
</span><span>        </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span>        </span><span>0</span>,<span>
</span><span>    </span>)<span>?</span>;<span>
</span><span>
</span><span>    </span><span>Ok</span>(())<span>
</span><span></span>}<span>
</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Regarding the FDT creation, there are differences between v2 and v3 regarding
the interrupt controller <code>intc</code> node.</p>

<p>First, we need to define the GICv2 <code>compatible</code> property to be <code>arm,gic-400</code>,
since it is the GIC-400 chip which implements GICv2. Next is the <code>reg</code>
property of the FDT, which includes the addresses and the corresponding sizes of
the GIC registers, i.e. distributor and CPU for GICv2, distributor and
redistributor for GICv3. Finally, we fix the <code>interrupts</code> property which
determines the interrupt source of the VGIC maintenance interrupt. The
corresponding values for GICv2 were taken from the respective <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/blob/master/Documentation/devicetree/bindings/interrupt-controller/arm%2Cgic.yaml">Linux Kernel entries</a>.</p>

<h4 id="build-firecracker-with-rpi4-support">Build firecracker with RPi4 support</h4>

<p>While waiting for the patch to merge upstream you can go ahead and check out it
yourself.</p>

<p>Clone and build our fork of firecracker (keep in mind that while the PR review
is going on, we might force-update the branch).</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">$ git clone https://github.com/cloudkernels/firecracker.git
$ <span>cd</span> firecracker
$ ./tools/devtool build</code></pre></div>
<p>Next you need a kernel image and a root filesystem to run with your firecracker
build. You can grab the pre-built kernel image and rootfs here:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">$ wget https://s3.amazonaws.com/spec.ccfc.min/img/aarch64/ubuntu_with_ssh/kernel/vmlinux.bin
$ wget https://s3.amazonaws.com/spec.ccfc.min/img/aarch64/ubuntu_with_ssh/fsfiles/xenial.rootfs.ext4 </code></pre></div>
<p>Alternatively, you can build your own kernel and rootfs using the following
steps provided by the firecracker docs
<a href="https://github.com/cloudkernels/firecracker/blob/master/docs/rootfs-and-kernel-setup.md">here</a></p>

<h4 id="launch-our-image">Launch our image</h4>

<p>To launch our image we will use the <a href="https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firectl">firectl</a> tool. We need, to setup a tap
device for the networking or our firecracker microVM.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">$ sudo ip tuntap add dev tap0 mode tap
$ sudo ip addr add <span>172</span>.16.0.1/24 dev tap0
$ sudo ip link <span>set</span> tap0 up</code></pre></div>
<p>And we launch the microVM using firectl:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">firectl --firecracker-binary<span>=</span><span>${</span><span>PATH_TO_FC_BIN</span><span>}</span> --kernel<span>=</span>vmlinux.bin <span>\
</span><span></span>	--tap-device<span>=</span>tap0/aa:fc:00:00:00:01 <span>\
</span><span></span>	--kernel-opts<span>=</span><span>"console=ttyS0 reboot=k panic=1 pci=off ip=172.16.0.42::172.16.0.1:255.255.255.0::eth0:off"</span> <span>\
</span><span></span>	--root-drive<span>=</span>./nginx_fc.ext4</code></pre></div>
<p>Here, we used here the <code>ip</code> kernel boot parameter to give the <code>172.16.0.42</code>.</p>

<p>Finally, we try out our nginx server:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="html">curl 172.16.0.42
<span>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;</span>
&lt;<span>html</span>&gt;
&lt;<span>head</span>&gt;
&lt;<span>title</span>&gt;Welcome to nginx!&lt;/<span>title</span>&gt;
&lt;<span>style</span>&gt;
    <span>body</span> {
        <span>width</span>: <span>35</span><span>em</span>;
        <span>margin</span>: <span>0</span> <span>auto</span>;
        <span>font-family</span>: Tahoma, Verdana, Arial, <span>sans-serif</span>;
    }
&lt;/<span>style</span>&gt;
&lt;/<span>head</span>&gt;
&lt;<span>body</span>&gt;
&lt;<span>h1</span>&gt;Welcome to nginx!&lt;/<span>h1</span>&gt;
&lt;<span>p</span>&gt;If you see this page, the nginx web server is successfully installed and
working. Further configuration is required.&lt;/<span>p</span>&gt;

&lt;<span>p</span>&gt;For online documentation and support please refer to
&lt;<span>a</span> <span>href</span><span>=</span><span>"http://nginx.org/"</span>&gt;nginx.org&lt;/<span>a</span>&gt;.&lt;<span>br</span>/&gt;
Commercial support is available at
&lt;<span>a</span> <span>href</span><span>=</span><span>"http://nginx.com/"</span>&gt;nginx.com&lt;/<span>a</span>&gt;.&lt;/<span>p</span>&gt;

&lt;<span>p</span>&gt;&lt;<span>em</span>&gt;Thank you for using nginx.&lt;/<span>em</span>&gt;&lt;/<span>p</span>&gt;
&lt;/<span>body</span>&gt;
&lt;/<span>html</span>&gt;</code></pre></div>
      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.cloudkernels.net/posts/firecracker-rpi4/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24878698</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 12:15:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Understanding static single assignment forms]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 40 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24878421">thread link</a>) | @signa11
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/10/23/Understanding-static-single-assignment-forms | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/10/23/Understanding-static-single-assignment-forms">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">


<h2><em>Programming, philosophy, pedaling.</em></h2>

<ul>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/">Home</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags">Tags</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/favorites">Favorites</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/archive">Archive</a></li>
    
      <li><a href="https://yossarian.net/">Main Site</a></li>
    
</ul>

<hr>



<h2>
  <em>Oct 23, 2020</em>
</h2>

  <p>Tags:
  
    
    <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags#llvm">llvm</a>,
    
  
    
    <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/tags#programming">programming</a>
    
  
  </p>


<p><em>With thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/inventednight/">Niki Carroll</a>, winny, and kurufu for their
invaluable proofreading and advice.</em></p>

<h2 id="preword">Preword</h2>

<p>By <a href="https://twitter.com/8x5clPW2/status/1311316978703970307">popular demand</a>, I’m doing another
LLVM post. This time, it’s <strong>single static assignment</strong> (or SSA) form, a common feature
in the intermediate representations of optimizing compilers.</p>

<p>Like <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/09/19/LLVMs-getelementptr-by-example">the last one</a>, SSA is a
topic in compiler and IR design that I <em>mostly</em> understand but could benefit from some self-guided
education on. So here we are.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-represent-a-program">How to represent a program</h2>

<p>At the highest level, a compiler’s job is singular: to turn some source language <em>input</em>
into some machine language <em>output</em>. Internally, this breaks down into a sequence of clearly
delineated<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup> tasks:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Lexing</strong> the source into a sequence of tokens</li>
  <li><strong>Parsing</strong> the token stream into an <strong>abstract syntax tree</strong>, or AST<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup></li>
  <li><strong>Validating</strong> the AST (e.g., ensuring that all uses of identifiers are consistent with the
source language’s scoping and definition rules)<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup></li>
  <li><strong>Translating</strong> the AST into machine code, with all of its complexities (instruction selection,
register allocation, frame generation, &amp;c)</li>
</ol>

<p>In a <strong>single-pass</strong> compiler, (4) is monolithic: machine code is generated as the compiler walks
the AST, with no revisiting of previously generated code. This is extremely fast (in terms of
compiler performance) in exchange for some a few significant limitations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Optimization potential: because machine code is generated in a single pass, it can’t be revisited
for optimizations. Single-pass compilers tend to generate extremely slow and <em>conservative</em>
machine code.</p>

    <p>By way of example: the
  <a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/hjl-tools/x86-psABI/x86-64-psABI-1.0.pdf">System V ABI</a>
  (used by Linux and macOS) defines
  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_zone_(computing)">a special 128-byte region</a> beyond the
  current stack pointer (<code>%rsp</code>) that can be used by leaf functions whose stack frames fit within
  it. This, in turn, saves a few stack management instructions in the function prologue and
  epilogue.</p>

    <p>A single-pass compiler will struggle to take advantage of this ABI-supplied
  optimization: it needs to emit a stack slot for each automatic variable as they’re visited,
  and cannot revisit its function prologue for erasure if all variables fit within the red zone.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Language limitations: single-pass compilers struggle with common language design decisions, like
allowing use of identifiers before their declaration or definition. For example, the following
is valid C++:</p>

    <div><div><pre><code>  <span>class</span> <span>Rect</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>public:</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>area</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span> <span>return</span> <span>width</span><span>()</span> <span>*</span> <span>height</span><span>();</span> <span>}</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>width</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span> <span>return</span> <span>5</span><span>;</span> <span>}</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>height</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span> <span>return</span> <span>5</span><span>;</span> <span>}</span>
  <span>};</span>
</code></pre></div>    </div>

    <p>C and C++ <em>generally</em> require pre-declaration and/or definition for identifiers, but
  member function bodies may reference the entire class scope. This will frustrate a
  single-pass compiler, which expects <code>Rect::width</code> and <code>Rect::height</code> to already exist
  in some symbol lookup table for call generation.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Consequently, (virtually) all modern compilers are <strong>multi-pass</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.yossarian.net/assets/multipass.jpg" alt="Pictured: Leeloo Dallas from The Fifth Element holding up her multi-pass.">
<em>“multi-pass” — Leeloo Dallas</em></p>

<p>Multi-pass compilers break the <em>translation</em> phase down even more:</p>

<ol>
  <li>The AST is lowered into an <strong>intermediate representation</strong>, or IR</li>
  <li>Analyses (or passes) are performed on the IR, refining it according to some optimization
profile (code size, performance, &amp;c)</li>
  <li>The IR is either translated to machine code <em>or</em> lowered to <em>another</em> IR, for further target
specialization or optimization<sup id="fnref:4" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:4">4</a></sup></li>
</ol>

<p>So, we want an IR that’s easy to <em>correctly</em> transform and that’s amenable to optimization. Let’s
talk about why IRs that have the <strong>static single assignment</strong> property fill that niche.</p>

<h2 id="ssa-form">SSA form</h2>

<p>At its core, the SSA form of any program source program introduces only one new constraint:
all variables are assigned (i.e., stored to) <strong>exactly once</strong>.</p>

<p>By way of example: the following (not actually very helpful) function is <strong>not</strong> in a valid SSA form
with respect to the <code>flags</code> variable:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>helpful_open</span><span>(</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>fname</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>flags</span> <span>=</span> <span>O_RDWR</span><span>;</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>access</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>F_OK</span><span>))</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>flags</span> <span>|=</span> <span>O_CREAT</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>int</span> <span>fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>flags</span><span>,</span> <span>0644</span><span>);</span>

  <span>return</span> <span>fd</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Why? Because <code>flags</code> is stored to twice: once for initialization, and (potentially) again inside
the conditional body.</p>

<p>As programmers, we could rewrite <code>helpful_open</code> to only ever store once to each automatic variable:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>helpful_open</span><span>(</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>fname</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>access</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>F_OK</span><span>))</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>flags</span> <span>=</span> <span>O_RDWR</span> <span>|</span> <span>O_CREAT</span><span>;</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>flags</span><span>,</span> <span>0644</span><span>);</span>
  <span>}</span> <span>else</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>flags</span> <span>=</span> <span>O_RDWR</span><span>;</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>flags</span><span>,</span> <span>0644</span><span>);</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>But this is clumsy and repetitive: we essentially need to duplicate every chain of uses that
follow any variable that is stored to more than once. That’s not great for readability,
maintainability, or code size.</p>

<p>So, we do what we always do: make the compiler do the hard work for us. Fortunately there exists
a transformation from every valid program into an equivalent SSA form, conditioned on two simple
rules.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Rule #1: Whenever we see a store to an already-stored variable, we replace it with a brand
new “version” of that variable.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Using rule #1 and the example above, we can rewrite <code>flags</code> using <code>_N</code> suffixes to indicate versions:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>helpful_open</span><span>(</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>fname</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>flags_0</span> <span>=</span> <span>O_RDWR</span><span>;</span>

  <span>// Declared up here to avoid dealing with C scopes.</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>flags_1</span><span>;</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>access</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>F_OK</span><span>))</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>flags_1</span> <span>=</span> <span>flags_0</span> <span>|</span> <span>O_CREAT</span><span>;</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>int</span> <span>fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>flags_1</span><span>,</span> <span>0644</span><span>);</span>

  <span>return</span> <span>fd</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>But wait a second: we’ve made a mistake!</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>open(..., flags_1, ...)</code> is incorrect: it unconditionally assigns <code>O_CREAT</code>, which wasn’t in the
original function semantics.</li>
  <li><code>open(..., flags_0, ...)</code> is <strong>also</strong> incorrect: it <em>never</em> assigns <code>O_CREAT</code>, and thus
is wrong for the same reason.</li>
</ul>

<p>So, what do we do? We use rule 2!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Rule #2: Whenever we need to <em>choose</em> a variable based on control flow, we use the Phi function
(φ) to introduce a <strong>new</strong> variable based on our choice.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Using our example once more:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>helpful_open</span><span>(</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>fname</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>flags_0</span> <span>=</span> <span>O_RDWR</span><span>;</span>

    <span>// Declared up here to avoid dealing with C scopes.</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>flags_1</span><span>;</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>access</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>F_OK</span><span>))</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>flags_1</span> <span>=</span> <span>flags_0</span> <span>|</span> <span>O_CREAT</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>int</span> <span>flags_2</span> <span>=</span> <span>φ</span><span>(</span><span>flags_0</span><span>,</span> <span>flags_1</span><span>);</span>

    <span>int</span> <span>fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>flags_2</span><span>,</span> <span>0644</span><span>);</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>fd</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Our quandary is resolved: <code>open</code> <strong>always</strong> takes <code>flags_2</code>, where <code>flags_2</code> is a fresh SSA variable
produced applying φ to <code>flags_0</code> and <code>flags_1</code>.</p>

<p>Observe, too, that φ is a <strong>symbolic</strong> function: compilers that use SSA forms internally do not
emit real φ functions in generated code<sup id="fnref:5" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:5">5</a></sup>. φ exists <em>solely</em> to reconcile rule #1 with the
existence of control flow.</p>

<p>As such, it’s a little bit silly to talk about SSA forms with C examples (since C and other
high-level languages are what we’re translating from in the first place). Let’s dive into how
LLVM’s IR actually represents them.</p>

<h2 id="ssa-in-llvm">SSA in LLVM</h2>

<p>First of all, let’s see what happens when we run our very first <code>helpful_open</code> through <code>clang</code>
with no optimizations:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>define</span> <span>dso_local</span> <span>i32</span> <span>@helpful_open</span><span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*</span> <span>%fname</span><span>)</span> <span>#0</span> <span>{</span>
<span>entry:</span>
  <span>%fname.addr</span> <span>=</span> <span>alloca</span> <span>i8</span><span>*,</span> <span>align</span> <span>8</span>
  <span>%flags</span> <span>=</span> <span>alloca</span> <span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>%fd</span> <span>=</span> <span>alloca</span> <span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>store</span> <span>i8</span><span>*</span> <span>%fname</span><span>,</span> <span>i8</span><span>**</span> <span>%fname.addr</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>8</span>
  <span>store</span> <span>i32</span> <span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span><span>*</span> <span>%flags</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>%0</span> <span>=</span> <span>load</span> <span>i8</span><span>*,</span> <span>i8</span><span>**</span> <span>%fname.addr</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>8</span>
  <span>%call</span> <span>=</span> <span>call</span> <span>i32</span> <span>@access</span><span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*</span> <span>%0</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span> <span>#4</span>
  <span>%tobool</span> <span>=</span> <span>icmp</span> <span>ne</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%call</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span>
  <span>br</span> <span>i1</span> <span>%tobool</span><span>,</span> <span>label</span> <span>%if.end</span><span>,</span> <span>label</span> <span>%if.then</span>

<span>if.then:</span>                                          <span>; preds = %entry</span>
  <span>%1</span> <span>=</span> <span>load</span> <span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span><span>*</span> <span>%flags</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>%or</span> <span>=</span> <span>or</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%1</span><span>,</span> <span>64</span>
  <span>store</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%or</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span><span>*</span> <span>%flags</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>br</span> <span>label</span> <span>%if.end</span>

<span>if.end:</span>                                           <span>; preds = %if.then, %entry</span>
  <span>%2</span> <span>=</span> <span>load</span> <span>i8</span><span>*,</span> <span>i8</span><span>**</span> <span>%fname.addr</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>8</span>
  <span>%3</span> <span>=</span> <span>load</span> <span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span><span>*</span> <span>%flags</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>%call1</span> <span>=</span> <span>call</span> <span>i32</span> <span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*,</span> <span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>...)</span> <span>@open</span><span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*</span> <span>%2</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%3</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>420</span><span>)</span>
  <span>store</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%call1</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span><span>*</span> <span>%fd</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>%4</span> <span>=</span> <span>load</span> <span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span><span>*</span> <span>%fd</span><span>,</span> <span>align</span> <span>4</span>
  <span>ret</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%4</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><em>(View it on <a href="https://godbolt.org/z/6ea8Pq">Godbolt</a>.)</em></p>

<p>So, we call <code>open</code> with <code>%3</code>, which comes from…a <code>load</code> from an <code>i32*</code> named <code>%flags</code>?
Where’s the φ?</p>

<p>This is something that <em>consistently</em> slips me up when reading LLVM’s IR: only <em>values</em>,
<strong>not</strong> memory, are in SSA form. Because we’ve compiled with optimizations disabled, <code>%flags</code> is
just a stack slot that we can <code>store</code> into as many times as we please, and that’s <em>exactly</em> what
LLVM has elected to do above.</p>

<p>As such, LLVM’s SSA-based optimizations aren’t all that useful when passed IR that makes direct
use of stack slots. We want to <em>maximize</em> our use of SSA variables, whenever possible, to make
future optimization passes as effective as possible.</p>

<p>This is where <a href="https://llvm.org/docs/Passes.html#mem2reg-promote-memory-to-register"><code>mem2reg</code></a> comes in:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>This file (optimization pass) promotes memory references to be register references. It promotes
alloca instructions which only have loads and stores as uses. An alloca is transformed by using
dominator frontiers to place phi nodes, then traversing the function in depth-first order to
rewrite loads and stores as appropriate. This is just the standard SSA construction algorithm to
construct “pruned” SSA form.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>(Parenthetical mine.)</p>

<p><code>mem2reg</code> gets run at <code>-O1</code> and higher, so let’s do exactly that:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>define</span> <span>dso_local</span> <span>i32</span> <span>@helpful_open</span><span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*</span> <span>nocapture</span> <span>readonly</span> <span>%fname</span><span>)</span> <span>local_unnamed_addr</span> <span>#0</span> <span>{</span>
<span>entry:</span>
  <span>%call</span> <span>=</span> <span>call</span> <span>i32</span> <span>@access</span><span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*</span> <span>%fname</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span> <span>#4</span>
  <span>%tobool.not</span> <span>=</span> <span>icmp</span> <span>eq</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%call</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span>
  <span>%spec.select</span> <span>=</span> <span>select</span> <span>i1</span> <span>%tobool.not</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>66</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>2</span>
  <span>%call1</span> <span>=</span> <span>call</span> <span>i32</span> <span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*,</span> <span>i32</span><span>,</span> <span>...)</span> <span>@open</span><span>(</span><span>i8</span><span>*</span> <span>%fname</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%spec.select</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>420</span><span>)</span> <span>#4</span><span>,</span> <span>!dbg</span> <span>!22</span>
  <span>ret</span> <span>i32</span> <span>%call1</span><span>,</span> <span>!dbg</span> <span>!23</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Foiled again! Our stack slots are gone thanks to <code>mem2reg</code>, but LLVM has actually optimized
<em>too far</em>: it figured out that our flags value is wholly dependent on the return value of our
<code>access</code> call and erased the conditional entirely.</p>

<p>Instead of a φ node, we got this <code>select</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>%spec.select</span> <span>=</span> <span>select</span> <span>i1</span> <span>%tobool.not</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>66</span><span>,</span> <span>i32</span> <span>2</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>which the <a href="https://llvm.org/docs/LangRef.html#select-instruction">LLVM Language Reference</a>
describes concisely:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The ‘select’ instruction is used to choose one value based on a condition, without IR-level branching.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So we need a better example. Let’s do something that LLVM can’t trivially optimize into a
<code>select</code> (or sequence of <code>select</code>s), like adding an <code>else if</code> with a function that we’ve …</p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/10/23/Understanding-static-single-assignment-forms">https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/10/23/Understanding-static-single-assignment-forms</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.yossarian.net/2020/10/23/Understanding-static-single-assignment-forms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24878421</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 11:07:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Anki as Learning Superpower: Computer Science Edition]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 357 | Comments 214 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24878171">thread link</a>) | @Smaug123
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://www.gresearch.co.uk/article/anki-as-learning-superpower-computer-science-edition/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.gresearch.co.uk/article/anki-as-learning-superpower-computer-science-edition/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<div>
        <p><span>Life at G-Research</span>
          <span>23/10/2020</span>
        </p>
			</div>
    </div><div>
			<div>
        
        <p><em>Patrick Stevens is a Developer at G-Research.</em></p>
<p>TL;DR: <em>If you aren’t using <a href="https://apps.ankiweb.net/">Anki</a> or one of its siblings to remember what you learn, you are missing out on literal superpowers. There are specific techniques which I’ve found helpful for using it to learn maths and computer science in particular.</em></p>
<p>This post will discuss extremely briefly what Anki is, but is mainly aimed at helping the student of maths or computer science to squeeze out some extra droplets of productivity from it. If you aren’t already familiar with Anki, go and read Michael Nielsen’s post <a href="http://augmentingcognition.com/ltm.html">Augmenting Long-Term Memory</a> as well or instead of this one; if you’re short of time, the main value of the post to someone new to Anki is in the first one-eighth or so, up to but not including “Using Anki to thoroughly read a research paper in an unfamiliar field”. That essay gives a broad-strokes motivation for why one might want to use Anki at all. (Spoiler: it gives you a superhuman memory!)</p>
<h2 id="what-is-anki-">What is Anki?</h2>
<p><a href="https://apps.ankiweb.net/">Anki</a> is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaced_repetition">spaced repetition system</a>: essentially a program that shows you flashcards at intervals tailored to help you remember their contents. Such systems are based on the observation that while you can’t stop memories from decaying, repeated exposure makes the decay exponentially slower.</p>
<p>So while you need to rehearse a fact frequently when you first come to learn it, reviews can become very sparse very quickly without losing much of your hard-won memory.</p>
<p>Anki is only one such system; other implementations such as SuperMemo and Mnemosyne exist.<br>
There are also applications using the same principles for more specific goals; for example, Memrise is designed for language learning. This post is phrased in terms of Anki, because for historical reasons that’s the one I use.</p>

<p>I’ve placed this section at the start, because I believe that spaced repetition is genuinely a superpower that anyone can acquire. If I can’t hold your interest in this post, I encourage you to glance over these other resources in the hope that one of them does the trick!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://augmentingcognition.com/ltm.html">Augmenting Long-Term Memory</a> –&nbsp; a brief introduction to various memory systems with a particular focus on Anki. The money quote: “Anki makes memory a choice”. If you choose to remember something, you can.</li>
<li><a href="https://quantum.country/">Quantum Country</a> – an introduction to quantum computation with integrated spaced-repetition flashcards, which comes with emailed reminders to use the site at intervals. Even if you have no interest in quantum computation, I recommend skimming at least the first bits of the site, so that you can see what really good flashcards based on a text can look like. (Note that some of its cards are not ideal; the site does sometimes fall into the “yes/no” pattern, with flashcards whose answer is a bald “yes” or “no”. Cards of this form aren’t as good as cards which get you to reproduce actually content-based parts of a fact.)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.supermemo.com/en/archives1990-2015/articles/20rules">The Twenty Rules of Formulating Knowledge in Learning</a> – the creator of the spaced-repetition system SuperMemo discusses how to formulate knowledge so that it sticks. Again, even if you don’t use spaced repetition, definitely read this; the advice is absolutely foundational to my understanding of how to learn. A nontrivial amount of this very blog post is essentially specialising some of these rules to the case of maths and computer science.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/medicalschoolanki/">Reddit: Medical School Anki</a>, a subreddit with almost 55,000 subscribers at the time of writing. This link is here just to demonstrate that there are fields (such as medicine) in which Anki is very popular and nowhere near as niche as it is in most areas.</li>
</ul>

<p>Absolutely crucial to the effective use of Anki for even a moderate collection of cards is that answering a card should be a single mental motion.</p>
<p>What does this mean? We’ll demonstrate with some positive and negative examples.</p>
<ul>
<li>“What is the capital of France?” is probably answered with a single mental motion: it’s just “Paris”, obtained by a simple lookup in your memory.</li>
<li>“What is 367 times 399?” is many mental motions unless you are really unusually good at mental arithmetic. Almost everyone has to carry out some algorithm to get an answer to this question.</li>
<li>“What is the composition of air?” is probably many mental motions: for example, a lookup of “which gases are in air?” and a number of motions like “what proportion of air is this specific gas?”. Or it could be the various mental motions of “Which gas is the nth most common in air, and what is its proportion in air?” as n varies.</li>
<li>“What is the most common gas in air, and what is its proportion?” is very possibly a single mental motion despite the multiple components in its answer. For me, the knowledge that “nitrogen is the most common gas in air” is intimately bound up with “78% of air is nitrogen”; to answer one question is to access the same mental lump of storage as is required to answer the other question. Of course, for someone else, this may be two distinct facts and two distinct memory lookups.</li>
</ul>
<p>A card that is answered with one mental motion may be multiple motions for someone else; and a question answered with many mental motions may become one motion after you learn some additional fact or part of the model that ties the facts together. So it’s helpful if you personally keep track of what you’re doing to answer a given card, so that you can recognise some of this structure in your own mind.</p>
<p>Any card which is multiple mental motions should be broken down into smaller chunks.</p>
<p>If you’re doing too much work to answer a card, it’s important to notice, so that you can break the card down. And don’t worry that you might “break down a card too much”; if the cards are easy, Anki will exponentially decrease how often it shows them to you. The cost of creating a card that’s too easy is almost entirely in the time it takes you to create the card in the first place; a card that’s too difficult will sap your time and energy again and again.</p>

<p>As an example, recall the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ratio_test">ratio test for convergence</a>, likely to be covered in any first course in analysis:</p>
<p><em>Let$\sum_{n=1}^{\infty} a_n$ be a complex series, with each $a_i$ nonzero.<br>
Suppose that there is $a$ such that $|\frac{a_{n+1}}{a_n}| \to a$.<br>
Then, if $a &lt; 1$ then the series converges absolutely; if $a &gt; 1$ then the series diverges.</em></p>
<p>(We’ll discuss its proof in a later section.)</p>
<p>This statement has a number of moving parts, and is definitely much too large to appear as a single card. (Remember the rule of thumb: answering a single card should be a single mental motion.)<br>
How could we formulate this statement in an Anki-friendly way?</p>
<p>My own personal Anki collection contains the following cards. (Anki does allow LaTeX, though I often optimise for speed of card creation and just use plain text, however ugly it ends up. As long as it’s easily legible, it doesn’t need to be pretty.)</p>
<ul>
<li>What conditions exist on the ratio test? (answer: nonzero, sequence of ratios has a limit)</li>
<li>When does the ratio test let us conclude something? (answer: successive ratios converge to something not equal to 1)</li>
<li>Which cases exist on the ratio test? (answer: ratios converge to less than, or greater than, 1)</li>
<li>What can we say from the ratio test if the ratios converge to something less than 1? (answer: converges absolutely)</li>
<li>What can we say from the ratio test if the ratios converge to something greater than 1? (answer: diverges)</li>
<li>What can we say from the ratio test if the ratios converge to 1? (answer: nothing)</li>
<li>Give an example where the ratio test is inconclusive. (answer: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harmonic_series_(mathematics)">harmonic series</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>All these cards are very simple; perhaps they might look laughably simple. This is fine! Remember that Anki will rapidly stop showing you cards you already know. Crucially each card is really a single mental motion to answer.</p>
<p>Note also that information is duplicated between cards. For example, there are two cards saying in slightly different ways that the ratio test talks about when successive ratios converge to something not equal to 1. Again, it’s fine to repeat information, because cards are cheap. Here, the information is duplicated to better facilitate the links between the cards: one card is a general “when can we conclude anything”, and one card is the same information rephrased as “which cases do I need to consider to produce more information here”. Without the additional rephrasing, there’s more of a risk of developing “isolated” clusters of cards; the aim is that given just the prompt “ratio test”, I can reproduce the <em>entire</em> cluster without thinking any further.</p>
<p>And don’t forget to store key examples and counterexamples!</p>

<p>Remembering a definition is rather like remembering the statement of a theorem.<br>
Without further ado, here is my definition of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red-black_tree">red-black tree</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>What, imprecisely, are the colouring rules on a red-black tree? (“global; local; base-case”)</li>
<li>What are the leaves of a red-black tree? (“null, black”)</li>
<li>What is the base-case colouring rule of a red-black tree? (“leaves are black”)</li>
<li>What is the local colouring rule of a red-black tree? (“red node =&gt; black children”)</li>
<li>What is the global colouring rule of a red-black tree? (“black depth is well defined”)</li>
<li>What is the black depth of a node in a red-black tree? (“the number of black nodes encountered on a path from that node down to a leaf”)</li>
</ul>
<p>Again, there is some duplication (two cards note that the leaves of a red-black tree are coloured black), and all the cards are extremely simple. The point is to make sure not only that the actual <em>content</em> is remembered, but also that the content is interlinked enough that you can reproduce the entire definition from the single prompt “red-black tree”. Moreover, one card is explicitly structural and carries no actual content as such: the card that lists the three types of colouring rule. This card is there solely to allow me to remember which <em>cards</em> are relevant.</p>
<p>Naively, one might create instead a single card, “what is a red-black tree?”. But in my experience, this is too big. If you’re reviewing even 30 cards a day, and …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.gresearch.co.uk/article/anki-as-learning-superpower-computer-science-edition/">https://www.gresearch.co.uk/article/anki-as-learning-superpower-computer-science-edition/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.gresearch.co.uk/article/anki-as-learning-superpower-computer-science-edition/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24878171</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 10:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ungrammar]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 149 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24878098">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://rust-analyzer.github.io//blog/2020/10/24/introducing-ungrammar.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rust-analyzer.github.io//blog/2020/10/24/introducing-ungrammar.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>So, what exactly does “describing syntax trees” mean and why is it useful?
When writing an IDE, one of the core data structure is the concrete syntax tree.
It is a full-fidelity tree which represents the original source code in detail, including parenthesis, comments, and whitespace.
CSTs are used for initial analysis of the language.
They are also a vocabulary type for refactors.
Although the ultimate result of a refactor is a text diff, tree modification is a more convenient internal representation.</p>

<p>At the lowest level, the CST is typically unityped: there’s some <code>Node</code> superclass, which has a collection of <code>Node</code> children and an optional <code>Node</code> parent.
On top of this raw layer, a more AST-like API is provided: <code>Struct</code> has a <code>.name()</code> and a list of <code>.fields()</code>, etc.
This typed API is huge!
For rust-analyzer, it is comprised of more than 130 <em>types</em>!
And it is also more detailed than a typical AST: <code>Struct</code> also has <code>.l_curly()</code> and <code>.r_curly()</code>.</p>
<p>What’s worse, this API changes a lot, especially at the beginning.
You may start with nesting <code>.fields()</code> directly under the <code>Struct</code>, but then introduce a <code>StructFields</code> node for everything between the curly braces to share the code with enum variants.</p>
<p>In short, writing this by hand sucks :-)
Ungrammar is a notation to concisely describe the structure of the syntax tree, which can be used by a code generator to build an API in the target language.
If you’ve heard about <a href="https://www.oilshell.org/blog/2016/12/11.html">ASDL</a>, ungrammar is ASDL for concrete syntax trees.
For rust-analyzer’s case, that means taking the following input:</p>
<div>
<div>
<pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
3
4
</pre></td><td><pre>Module =
  Attr* Visibility?
  'mod' Name
  (ItemList | ';')
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<p>And generating the following output:</p>
<div>
<div>
<pre><code data-lang="rust"><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
</pre></td><td><pre><span>impl</span> <span>ast</span><span>::</span><span>AttrsOwner</span>      <span>for</span> <span>Module</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>impl</span> <span>ast</span><span>::</span><span>VisibilityOwner</span> <span>for</span> <span>Module</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>impl</span> <span>ast</span><span>::</span><span>NameOwner</span>       <span>for</span> <span>Module</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>impl</span> <span>Module</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>pub</span> <span>fn</span> <span>mod_token</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>)</span>       <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Option</span><span>&lt;</span><span>SyntaxToken</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>{</span> <span>...</span> <span>}</span>
    <span>pub</span> <span>fn</span> <span>item_list</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>)</span>       <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Option</span><span>&lt;</span><span>ItemList</span><span>&gt;</span>    <span>{</span> <span>...</span> <span>}</span>
    <span>pub</span> <span>fn</span> <span>semicolon_token</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Option</span><span>&lt;</span><span>SyntaxToken</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>{</span> <span>...</span> <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<p>In typical parser generators, something similar can be achieved by generating <em>both</em> the parser and the syntax tree from the same grammar.
This works to some extent, but has an inherent problem that the shape of the tree you want for the programmatic API, and the shape of the grammar you need to implement the parser are often different.
“Technical” transformations like left-recursion elimination don’t affect the language described by the grammar, but completely change the shape of the parse tree.
In contrast, ungrammar focuses solely on the second task, which radically reduces the complexity of the grammar.
In rust-analyzer, it is paired with a hand-written parser.</p>
<p>Treated as an ordinary (context free) grammar, ungrammar describes a superset of the language.
For example, for programmatic API it might be convenient to treat commas in comma-separate lists as a part of the list element
(rust-analyzer doesn’t do this yet, but it should).
This leads to the following ungrammar, which obviously doesn’t treat commas precisely:</p>
<div>
<div>
<pre><code><table><tbody><tr><td><pre>1
2
3
4
5
</pre></td><td><pre>FieldList =
  '{' Field* '}'

Field:
  Name ':' Type ','?
</pre></td></tr></tbody></table></code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<p>Similarly, ungrammar defines binary and unary expressions, but doesn’t specify their relative precedence and associativity.</p>
<p>An interesting side-effect is that the resulting grammars turn out to be pretty human readable.
For example, a full production ready Rust grammar takes about 600 short lines:<br></p>

<p>This might be a good fit for reference documentation!</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rust-analyzer.github.io//blog/2020/10/24/introducing-ungrammar.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24878098</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 09:55:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Composer 2.0 is now available]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24878068">thread link</a>) | @Y-bar
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://blog.packagist.com/composer-2-0-is-now-available/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.packagist.com/composer-2-0-is-now-available/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            


            <section>
                <div>
                    <h2 id="1-what-s-new">1/ What's new?</h2><p>The list of changes and improvements is long, check the <a href="https://github.com/composer/composer/releases/tag/2.0.0">complete changelog</a> if you are interested in reading it all. I will highlight a few key points here.</p><h3 id="performance-improvements">Performance improvements</h3><p>We overhauled pretty much everything from the protocol used between Composer and packagist.org to the dependency resolution, including downloading files in parallel using curl and constraint evaluation optimizations. This leads to massive improvements in terms of both speed and memory usage. The difference depends on your use case, so while I've seen reports of improvements of over 50% to both in some projects, I cannot put an exact number on it. But I am sure you will be positively surprised if you haven't tried Composer 2 yet.</p><p>As a side note to this, <code>require</code>/<code>remove</code> and partial updates are now much faster because Composer will now only load the metadata of the packages which are being changed.</p><figure><img src="https://blog.packagist.com/content/images/2020/10/image_2020-10-24_175318.png" alt="" srcset="https://blog.packagist.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/image_2020-10-24_175318.png 600w, https://blog.packagist.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/image_2020-10-24_175318.png 1000w, https://blog.packagist.com/content/images/2020/10/image_2020-10-24_175318.png 1455w" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1200px"><figcaption>Time for initial update + install (bootstrapped project, empty cache) shows roughly 60% less time used by Composer 2 with ext-curl enabled</figcaption></figure><h3 id="architectural-changes-and-determinism">Architectural changes and determinism</h3><p>The way dependency updates are done internally was refactored, which, for you, will result in more deterministic updates. The current local state of the vendor directory will not interfere in updates anymore. </p><p>After an update is complete, the install process is run automatically and it will now execute all network bound operations first - and in parallel if possible. This will avoid leaving you with a half-updated vendor directory if a network error occurs midway through installation.</p><h3 id="runtime-features">Runtime features</h3><p>We added a <a href="https://getcomposer.org/doc/07-runtime.md#platform-check">platform-check step</a> when <code>vendor/autoload.php</code> gets initialized which checks the current PHP version/extensions match what is expected by your dependencies and fails hard otherwise.</p><p>There is a new class, <code>Composer\InstalledVersions</code>, which is autoloaded in every project and is available at runtime. It allows you to check which packages/versions are present at runtime of your own project.</p><p>See the <a href="https://getcomposer.org/doc/07-runtime.md">runtime docs</a> for more details.</p><p>If your code relies on any of these runtime features, you should require <code>"composer-runtime-api": "^2.0"</code> in your composer.json. This is a virtual package which is provided by Composer and will make sure people have to use Composer 2.x to install your package.</p><h3 id="error-reporting-improvements">Error reporting improvements</h3><p>Because things don't always go the way they're supposed to, we made sure to improve the error reporting shown to you when dependencies cannot be resolved. It's hard to give concrete examples here as there are a million ways this can fail but you will hopefully notice that messages are now shorter, clearer and less repetitive.</p><h3 id="partial-updates-with-temporary-constraints">Partial updates with temporary constraints</h3><p>Sometimes it can be useful to upgrade or downgrade a single package to a specific version, perhaps temporarily to test something or wait for a bug fix. You can now run <code>composer update vendor/package:1.0.*</code> for example (or <code>1.0.12</code> or any other version constraint), to run an update of only <code>vendor/package</code> to a version matching this additional constraint. This will not update your require in composer.json, and it will not mark the lock file out of date.</p><p>If you want to add/restrict a constraint but still do a full update of all dependencies, you can use <code>update --with vendor/package:1.0.*</code> which will run the update with that additional constraint.</p><h2 id="2-how-easy-is-it-to-upgrade">2/ How easy is it to upgrade?</h2><p>Our goal is that every Composer user can upgrade smoothly and swiftly. The gains are huge and we want everyone to benefit from them. To achieve that we did a few things:</p><ul><li>Composer 2.0 still supports PHP 5.3 and above, much like Composer 1.x</li><li><code>composer.lock</code> files are interoperable between versions, so you can upgrade to 2.0 and roll back easily if needed.</li><li>Most commands and arguments remain the same, and largely what you know about Composer remains true in 2.0.</li></ul><p>If you run <code>composer self-update</code> from 1.x, it will warn you that a new stable major version of Composer is available, and you can use <code>composer self-update --2</code> to migrate to it.</p><p>Should you encounter issues, you can go back at any time by using <code>composer self-update --1</code>. Hopefully that will make everyone feel comfortable to experiment with the new release.</p><p>If you are <a href="https://getcomposer.org/doc/faqs/how-to-install-composer-programmatically.md">installing Composer automatically</a> from the installer script, and wish to remain on Composer 1.x for the time being, you can also pass it a <code>--1</code> argument to prevent it from installing Composer 2.0 by default. If you do this please remember and aim to upgrade in a timely manner, as Composer 1.x will not be maintained for very long.</p><h2 id="3-backwards-compatibility-breaks">3/ Backwards compatibility breaks?</h2><p>Here are the main things likely to cause trouble with the upgrade process:</p><ul><li><strong>Plugins</strong>: This is probably going to be the major source of problems for most people. Plugins need to be updated to support Composer 2, and some of them are not ready, yet. Composer 2 will complain and fail to resolve dependencies if a plugin does not support it, so no need to overthink it, you can try it out and see how it goes.</li><li>The new <strong>platform-check feature</strong> means that Composer checks the runtime PHP version and available extensions to ensure they match the project dependencies. If a mismatch is found, the autoloader exits with error details to make sure problems are not overlooked. To avoid issues when deploying to production it is recommended to run <code>composer check-platform-reqs --no-dev</code> with the production PHP process as part of your build or deployment process.</li><li><strong>Repository priority</strong>: If a package exists in a higher priority repository, it will now be entirely ignored in lower priority repositories. If you seem to be missing packages when using Composer 2, see <a href="https://getcomposer.org/repoprio">repository priorities docs</a> for details.</li><li><strong>Invalid PSR-0 / PSR-4 configurations</strong> will not autoload anymore in optimized-autoloader mode, as per the warnings introduced in Composer 1.10. Mostly these warnings were for classes that were not meant to autoload anyway so I don't expect major issues, but it's safer to clean these up before upgrading.</li></ul><p>If you want to know more, I would highly recommend reading the <a href="https://github.com/composer/composer/blob/master/UPGRADE-2.0.md">UPGRADE</a> guide which has multiple sections for end users, plugin authors and Composer repository implementors.</p><h2 id="4-what-s-next">4/ What's next?</h2><p>We don't have a very detailed feature roadmap anymore as 2.0 contains tons of new goodies, but one important thing I want to explain is our PHP version support going forward.</p><p>As I mentioned above, Composer 2.0 supports PHP 5.3+, which is at this point very outdated and makes the code quite hard to maintain in places. We went through the effort to make sure every Composer user can upgrade to Composer 2, but the plan is to drop support for EOL PHP versions in a future minor release.</p><p>Composer 2.1 might still come with PHP 5.3 support, depending on the timeline and which features end up being included, but then at the latest by Composer 2.2 we will drop support for everything older than PHP 7.1.3. According to our stats this allows over 90% of the Composer users to use the latest version, and for the others who are stuck on outdated PHP versions we will keep providing critical bug and security fixes in the 2.0.x or 2.1.x range.</p><p>As for Composer 1.x, it is now more or less EOL. It will also receive critical fixes if anything comes up but the goal for everyone should be to migrate to 2.x as soon as possible.</p><p>Finally I want to thank everyone who contributed and helped make this a reality. The 2.0 release represents over 1100 commits from 28 people, 150+ GitHub issues and pull requests, plus everyone who test it, reviewed PRs, etc. It has been a huge effort with the first commits made about two years ago.</p><p>I also want to thank all our <a href="https://packagist.com/">Private Packagist</a> customers who helped finance this effort and afforded us the time we spent on all this. We sincerely hope everyone will appreciate the result!</p>
                </div>
            </section>


            


        </article>

    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.packagist.com/composer-2-0-is-now-available/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24878068</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 09:46:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Faasd – Lightweight Serverless for Raspberry Pi]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 71 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24877846">thread link</a>) | @alexellisuk
<br/>
October 24, 2020 | https://blog.alexellis.io/faasd-for-lightweight-serverless/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.alexellis.io/faasd-for-lightweight-serverless/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
    <article>

        

        <section>
            <div><p>Kick the tires with faasd today, for a lightweight serverless experience that doesn't require Kubernetes. Instead it uses containerd and the existing OpenFaaS ecosystem.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Last updated: 24th October 2020 - upgraded faasd &amp; containerd versions. Added instructions for core components logs such as the gateway.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You can run <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faasd">faasd</a> anywhere, even on a <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/">Raspberry Pi</a>, but why would you want to do that? faasd offers many of the benefits of containers and <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faas">OpenFaaS</a>, but without the complexity and operational costs of Kubernetes. <a href="https://github.com/containerd/containerd">containerd</a> is a low-level tool for automating containers, and a <a href="https://landscape.cncf.io/">CNCF project</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.alexellis.io/content/images/2019/12/ofctr.png" alt="OpenFaaS and containerd logos"></p>
<p>The use-cases for <a href="https://blog.alexellis.io/introducing-functions-as-a-service/">Serverless / FaaS are fairly well-known</a>, but you could use faasd at the edge, in a smart-car, as part of an IoT device, for crunching data before uploading samples to the cloud, for webhook receivers/alerting, bots, webservices, API integrations or even providing your own APIs. Compute is compute, and OpenFaaS with containerd makes it easy to both consume and provide.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>🚀 Support the development of faasd - <a href="https://github.com/sponsors/openfaas">Sponsor OpenFaaS on GitHub</a><br>
⭐️ Star or fork <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faasd">faasd on GitHub</a></p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="beforewestart">Before we start</h2>
<p>Use Raspbian Lite (now called RaspiOS) for this tutorial. Do not install Docker on the same Raspberry Pi as it may cause conflicts with networking and the version of containerd we are using.</p>
<p>You should use RPi 2, 3 or 4. If you have only one Raspberry Pi, then you'll be able to deploy pre-built images from the OpenFaaS Function Store, but if you have a second Raspberry Pi, then you can use it to build new functions too.</p>
<p>You can also deploy to a PC or cloud VM:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.openfaas.com/blog/faasd-tls-terraform/">Deploy faasd to DigitalOcean with Terraform</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faasd/blob/master/docs/MULTIPASS.md">Deploy faasd to your laptop with Multipass</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>
<p>Installation only takes a few moments, and in the future should be quicker if we can secure binaries for containerd from the upstream project.</p>
<h3 id="getfaascli">Get <code>faas-cli</code></h3>
<p>The <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faas-cli/">faas-cli</a> can be used to build, deploy, manage, and invoke functions with OpenFaaS. OpenFaaS offers a REST API, asynchronous invocations, authentication, metrics, and a UI out of the box.</p>
<p>Install using the utility script, or alternatively the binaries are also available on the <a href="https://github.com/openfaas/faas-cli/releases">releases page</a>.</p>
<pre><code># Install to local directory
curl -sLfS https://cli.openfaas.com | sh
sudo mv faas-cli to /usr/local/bin

# Or run with sudo to move to /usr/local/bin in one step
curl -sLfS https://cli.openfaas.com | sudo sh
</code></pre>
<p>See also: <a href="https://docs.openfaas.com/">OpenFaaS docs</a></p>
<h3 id="getcontainerd">Get containerd</h3>
<p>Unfortunately the <a href="https://github.com/containerd/containerd">containerd</a> maintainers only provide binaries for <code>x86_64</code> (regular PCs), so we have to install Go and build containerd from source.</p>
<p>We'll install some dependencies that will help us in the tutorial and after installation</p>
<pre><code>sudo apt update \
  &amp;&amp; sudo apt install -qy \
    runc \
    bridge-utils \
    tmux \
    git
</code></pre>
<p>Pick option A or B.</p>
<h4 id="ausemycontainerdarmhfbinariesfast">A) Use my containerd armhf binaries (fast)</h4>
<p>I have compiled binaries for containerd, which you can use if you wish. <a href="https://github.com/alexellis/containerd-armhf/releases">alexellis/containerd/armhf</a>.</p>
<pre><code>curl -sSL https://github.com/alexellis/containerd-arm/releases/download/v1.3.5/containerd-1.3.5-linux-armhf.tar.gz | sudo tar -xvz --strip-components=1 -C /usr/local/bin/
</code></pre>
<h4 id="bbuildyourowncontainerdbinariesslow">B) Build your own containerd binaries (slow)</h4>
<p>Raspbian needs a few additional build-time dependencies for containerd:</p>
<pre><code>sudo apt update \
  &amp;&amp; sudo apt install -qy \
    build-essential \
    libbtrfs-dev \
    libseccomp-dev
</code></pre>
<p>You can use my utility script to build containerd now:</p>
<pre><code>export GOPATH=$HOME/go/
mkdir $GOPATH/src/github.com/openfaas
cd $GOPATH/src/github.com/openfaas
git clone https://github.com/openfaas/faasd

cd cd faasd

./hack/build-containerd-armhf.sh
</code></pre>
<p>This could take a few moments on RPi2 or 3, and is a little quicker on RPi4.</p>
<h3 id="configurecontainerdtostartonboot">Configure containerd to start on boot</h3>
<p>Install a systemd unit file for <code>containerd</code>:</p>
<pre><code>curl -SLfs https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containerd/containerd/v1.3.5/containerd.service | sudo tee /etc/systemd/system/containerd.service

sudo systemctl enable containerd
sudo systemctl start containerd
</code></pre>
<p>Check that <code>containerd</code> started with <code>sudo systemctl status containerd</code>, if not then you may need to <code>unmask</code> it and run the commands again. See <a href="https://blog.ruanbekker.com/blog/2017/12/09/unmask-a-masked-service-in-systemd/">unmasking a service</a>.</p>
<h3 id="installnetworking">Install networking</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Enable the Kernel's bridge module</p>
<pre><code># One-off
sudo modprobe br_netfilter &amp;&amp; \
sudo sysctl net.bridge.bridge-nf-call-iptables=1

# Make it permanent
echo "br_netfilter" | sudo tee -a /etc/modules-load.d/modules.conf

echo "net.bridge.bridge-nf-call-iptables=1" | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.conf
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>
<p>Install CNI plugins</p>
<p>Fortunately there are upstream ARM binaries available for the CNI plugins.</p>
<pre><code>sudo mkdir -p /opt/cni/bin

curl -sSL https://github.com/containernetworking/plugins/releases/download/v0.8.5/cni-plugins-linux-arm-v0.8.5.tgz | sudo tar -xz -C /opt/cni/bin
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>
<p>Enable NAT</p>
<p>Enable NAT between the container network and your wider network and the Internet:</p>
<pre><code>sudo /sbin/sysctl -w net.ipv4.conf.all.forwarding=1

echo "net.ipv4.conf.all.forwarding=1" | sudo tee -a /etc/sysctl.conf
</code></pre>
<p>Optional step - if you have Docker running on your system, then disable it and reboot at this point.</p>
<pre><code>sudo systemctl disable docker
sudo systemctl disable docker.sock # or docker.socket - You may also need this step
</code></pre>
<p>Docker's IP address range conflicts with the one chosen by netns, this will be resolved when moving to CNI.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="getfaasd">Get <code>faasd</code></h3>
<p>faasd is a Go binary that runs on your system and packages all of OpenFaaS, it's a similar tool to docker-compose.</p>
<p>One of faasd's commands <code>faasd provider</code> runs an OpenFaaS provider which implements the OpenFaaS "CRUD" API for functions.</p>
<p>Clean-up old versions, if required:</p>
<pre><code># Stop systemd services, if you have them
sudo systemctl stop faasd
sudo systemctl stop faasd-provider

# Remove old binaries if you have them
sudo rm -rf /usr/local/bin/faasd
</code></pre>
<p>Download the faasd binary:</p>
<pre><code>sudo curl -sSLf "https://github.com/openfaas/faasd/releases/download/0.9.5/faasd-armhf" \
    --output "/usr/local/bin/faasd" \
    &amp;&amp; sudo chmod a+x "/usr/local/bin/faasd"
</code></pre>
<p>Now run the installation:</p>
<pre><code>export GOPATH=$HOME/go/
mkdir -p $GOPATH/src/github.com/openfaas
cd $GOPATH/src/github.com/openfaas

git clone https://github.com/openfaas/faasd --depth=1

cd faasd

sudo faasd install
</code></pre>
<h2 id="postinstall">Post-install</h2>
<p>The <code>faasd install</code> command creates two systemd unit files which can be used to start/stop <code>faasd</code> and <code>faasd-provider</code>.</p>
<h3 id="checktheinstallation">Check the installation</h3>
<p>Check the services:</p>
<pre><code>sudo systemctl status faasd
sudo systemctl status faasd-provider
</code></pre>
<p>Find logs:</p>
<pre><code>sudo journalctl -u faasd --lines 40
sudo journalctl -u faasd-provider --lines 40
</code></pre>
<p>You'll find your login details for the gateway in <code>/var/lib/faasd/secrets</code>, the user is <code>admin</code> and the password is in <code>/var/lib/faasd/secrets/basic-auth-password</code></p>
<h3 id="checkthelogsfromtheopenfaascoreservices">Check the logs from the OpenFaaS Core Services</h3>
<p>You can access the logs from any of the core services deployed with faasd as follows:</p>
<pre><code>sudo journalctl -t default:gateway --lines 40
sudo journalctl -t default:nats --lines 40
sudo journalctl -t default:queue-worker --lines 40
sudo journalctl -t default:prometheus --lines 40
</code></pre>
<p>For more, see the <code>docker-compose.yaml</code> file in the current directory.</p>
<h3 id="accessopenfaasfromyourlaptop">Access OpenFaaS from your laptop</h3>
<p>faasd deploys OpenFaaS along with its core logic <code>faasd-provider</code>, which uses containerd instead of Kubernetes to start, stop, and manage functions.</p>
<p>The <code>faasd</code> process will proxy any incoming requests on HTTP port 8080 to the OpenFaaS gateway container, you can also find the IP of the container in your <code>hosts</code> file in the <code>faasd</code> directory.</p>
<p>You can also access the built-in Prometheus container by editing <code>docker-compose.yaml</code> to expose its ports, either to 127.0.0.1, or all your network adapters.</p>
<h3 id="deployafunctionfromthestore">Deploy a function from the store</h3>
<p>Obtain your OpenFaaS password. You need to run this command on your Raspberry Pi:</p>
<pre><code>sudo cat /var/lib/faasd/secrets/basic-auth-password
</code></pre>
<p>Log in to the gateway, either on your RPi, or from your own computer.</p>
<pre><code># If connecting remotely
export IP=192.168.0.101
export OPENFAAS_URL=http://$IP:8080
echo $PASSWORD | faas-cli login

# Or on device:

sudo cat /var/lib/faasd/secrets/basic-auth-password | faas-cli login --password-stdin
</code></pre>
<p>Look at what's available in the function store for the armhf platform, then deploy something:</p>
<pre><code>faas-cli store list --platform armhf

# Deploy figlet
faas-cli store deploy --platform armhf figlet

# Find the URLs for the function
faas-cli store inspect figlet

# Create some ASCII

echo "faasd" | faas-cli invoke figlet
</code></pre>
<p>Try a function that can generate an <code>identicon</code> like you may have seen for default avatar logos on GitHub.com</p>
<pre><code>faas-cli store deploy --platform armhf identicon

echo $USER | faas-cli invoke identicon &gt; avatar.png
</code></pre>
<p>Here's an example of the avatar for the user <code>pi</code>:</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.alexellis.io/content/images/2020/01/avatar.png" alt="avatar"></p>
<h3 id="runanasyncfunction">Run an async function</h3>
<p>You can also run your functions in the background or asynchronously.</p>
<p>Create a webhook receiver using a public service such as:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://requestbin.com/">https://requestbin.com/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://postb.in/">https://postb.in/</a></li>
</ul>
<pre><code>faas-cli store deploy --platform armhf nodeinfo

curl -d "verbose" \
  http://127.0.0.1:8080/async-function/nodeinfo \
  --header "X-Callback-Url: https://postb.in/1578562711776-8760500776115"
</code></pre>
<p>You'll be able to refresh your webhook receiver and see the value.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.alexellis.io/content/images/2020/01/Screenshot-2020-01-09-at-09.41.11.png" alt="Screenshot-2020-01-09-at-09.41.11"></p>
<h3 id="buildanewcontainerimage">Build a new container image</h3>
<p>You'll need a second Raspberry Pi for this step since we do not have <code>docker</code> installed on the device.</p>
<p>There are a couple of workarounds if you don't have a second device: use buildkit per as my post <a href="https://blog.alexellis.io/building-containers-without-docker/">Building containers without Docker</a>. Or build on your PC using <a href="https://github.com/alexellis/multiarch-templates">one of my multi-arch templates</a>.</p>
<p>You can also use one of my prebuilt functions such as <a href="https://github.com/alexellis/2020/">ascii-2020</a>, but you should only run the <code>faas-cli deploy</code> step.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Log into the Raspberry Pi with <code>ssh</code> and install the <code>faas-cli</code> and <code>docker</code>.</p>
<pre><code>curl -sLfS https://cli.openfaas.com | sudo sh
</code></pre>
<pre><code>curl -sLfS https://get.docker.com | sudo sh

sudo usermod -aG docker pi
newgrp
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>
<p>Log into the Docker Hub</p>
<pre><code>docker login
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>
<p>Create a Golang function</p>
<pre><code>export DOCKER_HUB_NAME="alexellis2"

faas-cli template store pull golang-middleware

faas-cli new --lang golang-middleware \
  hello-world \
  --prefix $DOCKER_HUB_NAME
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now build and push the image</p>
<pre><code>faas-cli push -f hello-world.yml
faas-cli deploy -f hello-world.yml
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="deployyournewcontainer">Deploy your new container</h3>
<p>You can set your OpenFaaS …</p></div></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.alexellis.io/faasd-for-lightweight-serverless/">https://blog.alexellis.io/faasd-for-lightweight-serverless/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.alexellis.io/faasd-for-lightweight-serverless/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24877846</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 08:48:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Language Design with Leo White]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24876465">thread link</a>) | @bshanks
<br/>
October 23, 2020 | https://signalsandthreads.com/language-design/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://signalsandthreads.com/language-design/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<h2 id="000000">00:00:00</h2>

<div><p>Welcome to Signals And Threads, in-depth conversations about every layer of the tech stack from Jane Street. I’m Ron Minsky. </p><p> Today, we’re going to have a conversation about programming language design with Leo White. Leo works in our compilers team here at Jane Street, and he works mostly on what’s called the frontend of the compiler, which means he spends a lot of time thinking about language features and about the type system that supports those language features, and in particular, he does that work in OCaml, which is the programming language we use on a day-to-day basis. </p><p> So, Leo, to get started, I’m curious, can you tell us a little bit about how you got involved in all of this? How you got involved in programming language design, in the first place?</p></div>

<h2 id="0000400">00:00:40.0</h2>

<div><p>I had some interest in programming languages from a young age. I started programming at 11 or something, and then I think I was fairly interested in how these mysterious things were created. The most formative thing I can think of in this regard, is between my first and second years at university, I remember reading Benjamin Pierce’s <a href="https://www.cis.upenn.edu/~bcpierce/tapl/"><em>Types and Programming Languages</em></a>. That really clicked. I just thought that stuff was great and I just really wanted work on it, and explore those ideas. </p><p> So, I think that’s kind of one of the main things that got me into it. I knew I wanted to do some programming language stuff, I started doing a PhD in that area. It was more about compilation than programming language design, and I was working on a source-to-source C compiler, and I was writing that compiler in OCaml, because OCaml had a good library for reading C files, and I already knew Standard ML, because it’s what they teach you in the first year at Cambridge. So, anyways, I was using OCaml to write this compiler, and I realized that there was a language feature that I wanted to have that would make it easier for me to write this C compiler, and since I kind of hated the work I was doing on the C compiler and was not that interested in it, I procrastinated by adding this feature to OCaml instead. And that’s kind of how I got into writing code for the OCaml compiler. So, I was writing, this language feature and went through the process of trying to upstream it, and whilst I was doing that and my PhD was coming to an end, Anil Madhavapeddy was looking around for people to join OCaml Labs, which was this new project to work on the OCaml compiler that Jane Street was kind of funding in Cambridge. So, he was trying to look for people to work on the OCaml compiler and suddenly this Cambridge address shows up with the implementing language features for OCaml and so he thought, well, I should go and see this person. So, he got in touch with me. And that’s kind of how I started working at OCaml Labs as an RA after having finished my PhD.</p></div>

<h2 id="0002195">00:02:19.5</h2>

<p>It’s by the way worth noting that most people have the wisdom to not immediately go and dive into adding features to languages that they’re just starting to use, and in particular, diving into the type system. I think when Anil saw someone who was willing to just going in and add a new type system feature, he was pretty excited.</p>

<h2 id="0002346">00:02:34.6</h2>

<p>Yes. I did not realize at the time that this wasn’t something that you just did. Yes, I was somewhat under-supervised in my PhD and clearly, no one told me that this is a terrible idea, and a bad way to spend your time. So, I just went ahead and did it instead, and I really enjoyed it. I mean, it’s quite a terrible…like, the type system is hard to dive into. I would not recommend doing it without some assistance.</p>

<h2 id="0002568">00:02:56.8</h2>

<p>The thing you mentioned about how you got involved in OCaml, is the thing that’s always worried me a little bit about how languages are designed, which is to say, languages are almost inevitably designed by people who write compilers, and so, they go around and look at the features they would like for writing compilers and go ahead and add them to the language, and I always wondered, like, how much of a bias is this in how our languages are designed?</p>

<h2 id="0003178">00:03:17.8</h2>

<p>I would say, not much of one mostly, because that is probably a fair accusation of OCaml, which is very nice for writing compilers and has all the things you would want for writing a compiler, but that is not true of most languages. Most languages are kind of horrible to write compilers in, so I don’t think it’s applying there.</p>

<h2 id="0003327">00:03:32.7</h2>

<p>So, you got excited about programming language design from reading <em>Types and Programming Languages</em>, which is Benjamin Pierce’s extremely famous book in this area, or at least extremely famous in an extremely narrow group of people, and you’ve been doing it now for quite a while. Some of that work during your PhD. Some at OCaml Labs, and a bunch of it here, in the intermediate time. What do you find exciting about language design? Why do you like it?</p>

<h2 id="0003550">00:03:55.0</h2>

<p>One of the main things I think I like about language design is that it sits at an interesting intersection between some very interesting pure mathematics, especially on the type system design side of things, and a more aesthetic, kind of, design style. A lot of it is about trying to find things that fit within the mathematical constraints, but are also a design that people like aesthetically and enjoy using.</p>

<h2 id="0004166">00:04:16.6</h2>

<p>And this is one of the real challenges of programming language design. It is really not, at its heart, a scientific enterprise, or at least, not at the end. This is a thing you often hear programming language people complain about, is the fact that they can’t do any proper studies, or rather, whether they can or can’t do it, that in practice, that is not how the field is driven.</p>

<h2 id="0004365">00:04:36.5</h2>

<p>Some people do try and do studies in how effective a programming language is, but it kind of hits up against all the things that make it hard to do experiments in the social sciences. It’s just seems like, in principle, you can manage it, but the experiments are just very hard to do, right? What you really need to do is get a load of professional programmers to agree to use all these different languages to solve the same problems for a prolonged period of time, and clearly this isn’t going to happen.</p>

<h2 id="0004566">00:04:56.6</h2>

<p>Yeah, it does seem completely and utterly hopeless to me because, if the things you care about are what you can do in a programming language, with large groups of people, solving hard problems, with significant amounts of time being devoted to it, which seems like, to me, at least, the interesting problem, and I think, a problem that a lot of programming languages are not even motivated by, you just have no hope. Like the kind of experiments people can run in practice, are like, they grab the thing they have at hand, which is usually a collection of sophomores, and then they study the thing that they can, which is something like how easy is it to understand the very first errors they see in their language or like, how well do they do when they try and do stuff in their first few weeks or maybe few months of working at it. And that just doesn’t get at the actual thing you care about when you think about what makes programming effective in the real world.</p>

<h2 id="0005434">00:05:43.4</h2>

<div><p>This kind of genuinely bothers quite a lot of people, I think, who work in programming languages. They really would much prefer that it were a proper science. It’s much better thought of as a kind of intersection between some mathematics and design. </p><p> And those are both things that we know how to study, right? The scientific method is not the only approach to knowledge. With mathematics, you can try to prove useful theorems and interesting properties, and people successfully do research in design disciplines like, my favorite example is really architecture, which I think is a very similar area to programming language design, in that it’s kind of constrained by mathematics. You know, you have to make sure the building stays up and also, is interesting from a design perspective. You know, you want to make buildings that people enjoy being in and looking at, and so on.</p></div>

<h2 id="0006249">00:06:24.9</h2>

<p>And there’s more than just the raw structural things you have to check. When you think about the design of a building, you think about what are transit times, and people do all sorts of studies to try get feels for how effective it is, but in the end, no one thinks that the final way to figure out whether a building is good is to do a randomized control trial, where you’re like, you make four different buildings and you have this, this and this. You have four equivalent businesses that you sit in the four different buildings and you see how it goes. And I think the scale of the economic investment required, I’m not sure if it’s not quite as absurd or a little more absurd to do the programming language equivalent, but it’s up there.</p>

<h2 id="0007013">00:07:01.3</h2>

<p>I think that that’s a better way of looking at programming language design, as a discipline.</p>

<h2 id="0007068">00:07:06.8</h2>

<p>You know, there are two ways of handling design problems. One is, you can solve them in the market, right? You can, you know, go off and have people go and design programming languages and see which are successful, and we have that down. There’s a whole system for doing that. And then there’s an academic equivalent of this, and a lot of the work on OCaml, in particular, happens in a context which includes a lot of academic staff. Do you have a feel for how you would make things like evaluation of papers different than it is now in order to accommodate for this?</p>

<h2 id="0007335">00:07:33.5</h2>

<div><p>I don’t have concrete suggestions. I’ve always wanted to, actually seriously, look into disciplines like architecture and so on, and look at how they, I mean they have journals. They have assessment of things. There must be mechanisms by which they do this, but I’ve never actually sat down and put serious time into seeing what that is. </p><p> I’m kind of more struck by the fact that when you’re at, say ICFP, which is the main functional …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://signalsandthreads.com/language-design/">https://signalsandthreads.com/language-design/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://signalsandthreads.com/language-design/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24876465</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 02:34:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
