<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 12:29:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 12:29:02 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Manufacturing in India vs. China]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108874">thread link</a>) | @hammadn
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.aliaworld.com/post/manufacturing-in-india-vs-china | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.aliaworld.com/post/manufacturing-in-india-vs-china">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-hook="post-description"><article><div><div data-rce-version="8.3.0"><div dir="ltr"><div><p id="viewer-foo"><span>For many importers, the end of profitable manufacturing in China may be near. Apart from a tenuous and vague “phase one” trade deal, any kind of truce in the ongoing China-U.S. trade war seems distant. And without a resolution in the next few weeks, nearly all goods traded between the U.S. and China will have tariffs by December 15.</span></p><p id="viewer-adua0"><span>Is it any wonder why many manufacturers are now considering leaving China, while others are accelerating earlier plans to exit.</span></p><p id="viewer-drn2j"><span>Manufacturing in India stands out as a cost-effective alternative to China. Companies like Hasbro have announced plans to limit their number of China-made products to half, choosing to relocate much of their production to India.</span></p><p id="viewer-3clqd"><span>And Taiwanese Foxconn, which manufacturers Apple’s iPhone and Amazon’s Echo, built their first plant in India in 2015 and plans to expand operations there.</span></p><p id="viewer-5a9o5"><span>But many other companies are either looking for solutions outside India or prefer to remain in China. They view India’s many challenges—a skills gap and inadequate infrastructure among them—as insurmountable barriers to their continued success.</span></p><p id="viewer-1kpog"><span>Let’s explore how manufacturing compares between India and China and whether India may be the right sourcing choice for you.</span></p><div id="viewer-4c75k"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.aliaworld.com/post/manufacturing-in-india-vs-china" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/3fccd7_b886c6ba02cb42f6ba3909c99634d44b~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_400%2Ch_256%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/3fccd7_b886c6ba02cb42f6ba3909c99634d44b~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><h2 id="viewer-68ao9"><span>WHAT DOES INDIA EXPORT TODAY?</span></h2><p id="viewer-9cbef"><span>India exported more than $323 billion worth of goods in 2018. Meanwhile, China exported goods valued at nearly eight times as much. China’s top exports included products such as electrical machinery, appliances and equipment. While raw materials and products requiring less sophisticated manufacturing composed the majority of India’s exports.</span></p><p id="viewer-f2041"><span><strong>Mineral products, chemical products and precious metals and stones</strong></span></p><p id="viewer-9sv1v"><span>India’s top exports are dominated by mineral products (16 percent), chemical products (14 percent) and precious metals (12 percent). Mineral products include mineral fuels and oils, such as Manufacturing in India vs. Chinapetroleum.</span></p><p id="viewer-4t78m"><span>Chemical products include various organic and inorganic chemicals, soaps, tanning dyes, fertilizers, explosives and, most notably, pharmaceuticals. India’s pharmaceutical industry now reportedly supplies:</span></p><ul><li id="viewer-947qg"><p>50 percent of the world’s demand for various vaccines</p></li><li id="viewer-2k7f4"><p>40 percent of U.S. demand for generic drugs; and</p></li><li id="viewer-ef5ro"><p>25 percent of all medicine in the UK</p></li></ul><p id="viewer-baho4"><span>Contributing seven percent of the country’s GDP, India’s precious metals and stones industry employs 4.6 million workers. Labor-intensive cutting, polishing and processing of small diamonds is a particularly strong sub-sector for India. Other gems, gold and jewelry are other major products in this category.</span></p><div id="viewer-inev"><div><div data-hook="imageViewer" role="button" tabindex="0"><div role="img"><p><img data-pin-url="https://www.aliaworld.com/post/manufacturing-in-india-vs-china" data-pin-media="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/3fccd7_9c904a6c67764948a1492d4f556b20e0~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_327%2Ch_324%2Cal_c%2Cq_80/file.png" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/3fccd7_9c904a6c67764948a1492d4f556b20e0~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_300,h_300,al_c,q_5/file.png"></p></div></div></div></div><p id="viewer-2i14b"><span><strong>Food and beverage</strong></span></p><p id="viewer-dror4"><span>Food and beverage products represent about 11 percent of India’s total exports, or $35 billion. Some of India’s leading exports in food and beverage include:</span></p><ul><li id="viewer-citq4"><p>Basmati rice</p></li><li id="viewer-8o9ls"><p>Carabeef or meat of bovine animals</p></li><li id="viewer-f7e4l"><p>Frozen shrimp and prawns; and</p></li><li id="viewer-bqua5"><p>Refined sugar</p></li></ul><p id="viewer-3737a"><span>India’s broader agricultural sector accounts for 17 percent of the country’s economy and employs more than 60 percent of the population.</span></p><p id="viewer-7ql2u"><span><strong>Garments and textiles</strong></span></p><p id="viewer-bcu8t"><span>The garment and textiles industry is one of India’s fastest growing. Overall textiles exports were valued at $39 billion in 2018 and are expected to more than double by 2021.</span></p><p id="viewer-9shou"><span>Part of the growth comes from various government initiatives, such as a 2018 increase in basic customs duties from 10 percent to 20 percent on more than 500 textile products. Another contributor is India’s robust production of relevant input materials, such as cotton, which lend supply chain and cost advantages.</span></p><p id="viewer-faukb"><span>These exports include knitted, woven and crocheted textiles and apparel, carpets and textile floor coverings and man-made filaments.</span></p><p id="viewer-7r4hg"><span>Despite China’s current dominance in export value, India’s government is making serious efforts to invest in the country’s manufacturing sector. Though the manufacturing sector now contributes only 16 percent to India’s gross domestic product (GDP), the “Make in India” initiative aims to boost that contribution to 25 percent by 2022.</span></p><p id="viewer-caorn"><span>And companies like Chinese smartphone maker OnePlus are investing heavily in R&amp;D in India. “Our success in India has proven to be a great model for our growth in other regions,” says OnePlus CEO Pete Lau. “…We are now closer to making India as our second headquarters.”</span></p><h2 id="viewer-6tjmf"><span>COST AND AVAILABILITY OF SKILLED LABOR IN INDIA AND CHINA</span></h2><p id="viewer-fp3rq"><span>Differences in manufacturing wages, size and skill level of the labor force should be at the forefront of your decision to move production from China to India. Depending on your product type, some of these factors may highlight clear advantages for remaining in China.</span></p><p id="viewer-6tdee"><span><strong>Manufacturing wages</strong></span></p><p id="viewer-7q1sj"><span>Labor represents one of the main costs of manufacturing goods. And importers have watched China’s labor costs soar in recent decades, often growing by 10-15 percent annually. China’s minimum wages, which now range from about US$140 to US$346 per month, are set at the provincial level.</span></p><p id="viewer-5u605"><span>India’s minimum wages similarly vary across states and range from about US$66 to US$202. Mounting U.S. tariffs on Chinese goods over the past year have only strengthened the case for India as a cost-effective manufacturing alternative. And importers of labor-intensive products, like garments and textiles, are in the best position to realize cost savings by moving to India.</span></p><p id="viewer-2dtbl"><span><strong>Labor force size and skill level</strong></span></p><p id="viewer-5d337"><span>Among the many manufacturing locations opposing China, India is unmatched in the size of its labor force. According to September 2019 data from the World Bank, India’s labor force numbers about 519 million. China’s labor force is still much larger with 783 million strong. But Indonesia’s labor force, with 134 million workers, is a distant third for the region.</span></p><p id="viewer-fh5j3"><span>India falls behind many of its neighbors with regard to factors the World Economic Forum use to rank countries in their human capital report. India ranks 103rd overall, while China ranks 34th.</span></p><p id="viewer-3umpt"><span>One area where India suffers a deficiency is in “know-how”, which includes the breadth and depth of specialized skills at work. We see this directly at play in the quality and complexity of the country’s top export products. This metric also measures employers’ perceived ease at filling job vacancies.</span></p><p id="viewer-8obvp"><span>India also has room to grow with regard to its labor development rank. This rank considers access to and enrollment in formal education, opportunities to upskill and how well the education system fits the needs of a competitive economy.</span></p><p id="viewer-6aqg0"><span>Some have attributed the low development rank to India’s shortage of vocational schools.</span></p><p id="viewer-crl8q"><span>The relatively low labor participation rate in India—just 67 percent among the 25-54 age group as of 2017—also hurt the country’s human capital rank. India’s employment gender gap, one of the world’s largest, was another major contributor. In contrast, China achieved a labor participation rate of 88 percent for the same age group.</span></p><p id="viewer-3r1pr"><span>On the positive side, India has performed relatively well in terms of quality of education, staff training and economic complexity.</span></p><p id="viewer-aa1e7"><span>Read further at <a href="https://www.intouch-quality.com/blog/manufacturing-in-india-vs-china" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.intouch-quality.com/blog/manufacturing-in-india-vs-china</u></a></span></p><p id="viewer-1hgbn"><span><em><strong>If you are looking forward to source high-quality metal jewelry then reach out to us at </strong></em><a href="mailto:info@aliajewelery.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em><strong><u>info@aliajewelery.com</u></strong></em></a><em><strong> &amp; we'll provide you with a free quote as per your requirement.</strong></em></span></p></div></div></div></div></article></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.aliaworld.com/post/manufacturing-in-india-vs-china</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25108874</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 06:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Short History of Romaji]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108455">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I recently created a tool called <a href="https://github.com/polm/cutlet">cutlet</a> for converting Japanese to romaji.
While working on cutlet I was surprised at the difficulty of finding a good
guide to the difference between romaji systems, particularly their history and
usage, so I wrote this up.</p>
<h2 id="a-romaji-refresher"> A Romaji Refresher</h2>
<p>There are three relatively well-defined romaji systems. For a quick overview of
some of their differences:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Japanese</th>
<th>新橋</th>
<th>お茶漬け</th>
<th>富士山</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Hepburn</td>
<td>Shinbashi (or Shimbashi)</td>
<td>ochazuke</td>
<td>Fujisan</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kunreisiki</td>
<td>Sinbasi</td>
<td>otyazuke</td>
<td>Huzisan</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Nipponsiki</td>
<td>Sinbasi</td>
<td>otyaduke</td>
<td>Huzisan</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Hepburn is the most widely used outside Japan, Kunreisiki is officially taught
to children in Japan. Nipponsiki is similar to Kunreisiki but older. Technically
Hepburn uses macrons for long vowels while Kunreisiki and Nipponsiki use
circumflexes, but usage isn't consistent and there's no difference in meaning
between them.</p>
<p>In recent years "wapuro" romaji, based on input when typing Japanese, are also
relatively common, but it's not systematized (except in as far as programs
either take or don't take certain sequences) and isn't used in any kind of
formal writing.</p>
<h2 id="particle-comparison"> Particle Comparison</h2>
<p>As another refresher, here's how non-phonetic particles are represented in the
various systems.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Japanese</th>
<th>は</th>
<th>を</th>
<th>へ</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Hepburn</td>
<td>wa</td>
<td>wo</td>
<td>e</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Kunreisiki</td>
<td>wa</td>
<td>o</td>
<td>e</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Nipponsiki</td>
<td>ha</td>
<td>wo</td>
<td>he</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Hepburn is phonetic except for <em>wo</em>, Kunreisiki is strictly phonetic, and
Nipponsiki is strictly orthographic.</p>
<h2 id="early-romaji"> Early Romaji</h2>
<p>Japanese was first written in the Latin alphabet in the 1600s, mainly by
Christian missionaries. It was used by the missionaries for recording and
learning the language, and also used in texts they produced to try to spread
Christianity. Since Christianity was later supressed in Japan, these forms of
romaji never had wide adoption, though they influenced later efforts.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-the-hepburn-system"> The Origins of the Hepburn System</h2>
<p>In 1867, missionary <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Curtis_Hepburn#Missionary_work_in_Japan">James Curtis Hepburn</a> published a
Japanese-English dictionary in Yokohama. Naturally he needed some way to write
Japanese words for people who couldn't read Japanese, so he devised a system of
representing Japanese that reflected the pronunciation of English consonants.
His system wasn't designed from the ground up, but developed based on his
knowledge of existing systems by other missionaries as well as his own
knowledge of Japanese.</p>
<p>Somewhat later, in 1885, an organization known as the
<a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%83%9E%E5%AD%97%E8%AB%96#%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%83%9E%E5%AD%97%E4%BC%9A">羅馬字会</a>
(Romajikai) was established. Mainly a society of Japanese academics, it was
interested in promoting the use of romaji as a replacement for kana and kanji.
Some motivations for getting rid of native writing systems included easier
international communication and improved domestic literacy. The principle
founders were <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ry%C5%8Dkichi_Yatabe">Ryoukichi Yatabe</a>, a botanist and the first Japanese graduate of Cornell, and <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A4%96%E5%B1%B1%E6%AD%A3%E4%B8%80">Masakazu Toyama</a>, a <a href="https://ii.umich.edu/cjs/history-of-cjs.html">graduate of the University of Michigan</a> who
later occupied a high post at what would eventually become Tokyo University.</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/4d041d6a/max-moritz-romaji.jpg"><img src="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/4d041d6a/img/max-moritz-romaji.jpg.l.jpg"></a><figcaption>The Romajikai published books to promote romaji, including this translation of Max and Moritz, titled "Wampaku Monogatari". This edition was reprinted in 1978. via <a href="https://www.wul.waseda.ac.jp/kotenseki/html/he22/he22_07214/index.html">Waseda University</a>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>In 1886 the Romajikai published <a href="https://dl.ndl.go.jp/info:ndljp/pid/862485">a romaji system</a>. Also in 1886
Hepburn published the third edition of his dictionary, which roughly used the
system.  I've had trouble finding the exact nature of the influence between
Hepburn's system and the Romajikai, but they were on friendly terms and
cooperating. Hepburn's dictionary's third edition took off, the romaji system
mainly came to be called by his name, and it became widely established,
particularly among foreigners dealing with Japan.</p>
<p>If you're interested in learning more about Hepburn's dictionaries, a <a href="http://www.meijigakuin.ac.jp/mgda/waei/">wealth
of information</a> is available via Meiji Gakuin University
Library, including a comparison of romaji in all published versions and
manuscripts.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-the-nipponsiki-system"> The Origins of the Nipponsiki System</h2>
<p>Around the time the Romajikai was established, one of the members, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tanakadate_Aikitsu">Aikitu
Tanakadate</a>, developed his
own romaji system, based on some existing informal conventions, that was
specifically designed to mirror the structure of Japanese kana without regard
to foreign pronunciation.</p>
<p>In 1885 Tanakadate proposed this new system to the Romajikai, but they
ultimately rejected his proposal in favor of keeping Hepburn. As a result
Tanakadate left the Romajikai and promoted Nipponsiki on his own. Before
becoming known as "Nipponsiki" this style of Romanization was known as
"Tanakadatesiki".</p>
<p>The disagreement between Tanakadate was only the first in a long series of
arguments between Hepburn and Nipponsiki proponents.</p>
<p>Tanakadate was around 30 when he invented this system, and most of his later
career was in physics. He worked with Lord Kelvin in Scotland and helped bring
about the adoption of the metric system in Japan. He used romaji in personal
writings and promoted it throughout his life. We'll be seeing him again later.</p>
<h2 id="standard-form-and-the-romaji-hirome-kai"> Standard Form and the Romaji Hirome Kai</h2>
<p>In 1905 the ローマ字ひろめ会 (Romaji Hirome Kai, "Society for the Advancement
of Romaji") was established. They published a magazine, called simply "Rômaji",
to create more reading material in romaji and spread its use within Japan.  By
this point Toyama and Yatabe had both passed away, and it's unclear if the
original Romajikai still existed in any capacity. An important early member of
the new society was <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E8%97%A4%E5%B2%A1%E5%8B%9D%E4%BA%8C">Katsuji Fujioka</a>, who wrote the
<a href="https://dl.ndl.go.jp/info:ndljp/pid/942994">羅馬字手引</a> (Romaji Tebiki), a kind of romaji dictionary.</p>
<p>Shortly after it was founded the Romaji Hirome Kai proposed a slightly modified
Hepburn and called it 標準式, or "Standard Form". Note that this is "Standard
Form" in general, not "Standard Hepburn", suggesting this was some kind of
official standard romanization system; this may have been a response to
Tanakadatesiki becoming known as "Nipponsiki", which could imply that other
romaji systems were "foreign". As we'll see in a bit, this rhetorical trick
ultimately didn't help official adoption.</p>
<p>I haven't been able to track down the original document with Standard Form, but
the Romaji Tebiki was already using it in 1906.</p>
<p>Standard Form replaced macrons with circumflexes and always romanized ん as
"n", rather than sometimes using "m" depending on the following consonant.</p>
<p>Tanakadate was still around and joined the Romaji Hirome Kai at some point, but
got fed up with their use of Hepburn, left, and founded his own organization in
1914.</p>
<h2 id="the-origins-of-kunreisiki"> The Origins of Kunreisiki</h2>
<p>In 1930 the government formed a committee to evaluate various romaji systems
for official government use. At this point Tanakadate was a member of the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_of_Peers_(Japan)">House of Peers</a>, and Romaji Hirome Kai member and Hepburn proponent
Fujioka was not a politician, but had political influence due to his long and
prominent career as a linguist. Both were involved with the government
committee.</p>
<p>While the system used at this point varied considerably by government agency,
Hepburn was more popular, so it seemed slated for official adoption.  However,
in 1935 Fujioka died of illness. In 1937, following a recommendation from the
committee, a slightly modified version of Tanakadate's Nipponsiki, dubbed
Kunreisiki, was established as the official government romaji system.</p>
<p>The main difference between Kunreisiki and Nipponsiki is that kana that are not
pronounced differently in standard modern Japanese are spelled as their more
common counterpart (づ and ず are both <em>zu</em>), though there are other
differences, like how particles are represented, and how ambiguous phonetic
boundaries are written.</p>
<h2 id="the-war"> The War</h2>
<p>Despite the recent official adoption of a government-approved romaji system,
around 1938 a number of more radical romaji proponents were arrested as
potential (or actual) anti-nationalists. One example was Esperantist and
language researcher <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E6%96%8E%E8%97%A4%E7%A7%80%E4%B8%80">Hidekatsu Saitou</a>, who contracted tuberculosis in
prison and died in 1940.</p>
<p>Following World War 2, the occupying American forces rescinded the law making
Kunreisiki official and ordered the use of Hepburn for public signage and
documents. During the occupation, an American educational commission
<a href="https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=pur1.32754081234191&amp;view=1up&amp;seq=28">recommended native Japanese writing be replaced with romaji</a>.
This never happened, though romaji became a standard component of post-war
education.</p>
<p>Post-war the development of romaji became less dramatic, as serious proponents
of replacing Japanese writing systems with romaji mostly disappeared. There
have been a number of laws and rules issued by the government over the years,
as well as a few special systems like the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSL_romanization">unique system</a> developed for a
textbook called "Japanese: The Spoken Language", but Hepburn and
Nipponsiki/Kunreisiki remain the major systems.</p>
<p>There is also much to be written about interaction of romaji with computers,
but that's best left for another time.</p>
<h2 id="what-about-revised-hepburn%3F"> What About Revised Hepburn?</h2>
<p>Sometimes you'll see references to "Revised Hepburn", but nobody knows what
this is. It is used to mean, variously:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hepburn's system in his third edition, in contrast to earlier editions</li>
<li>the 1905 version by the ローマ字ひろめ会 (properly 標準式 or "standard form")</li>
<li>a version introduced with Kenkyuusha's "New Japanese-English Dictionary" in 1954, subsequently <a href="https://www.loc.gov/catdir/cpso/romanization/japanese.pdf">adopted by the American Library of Congress</a></li>
<li>other minor variants proposed at different times</li>
</ul>
<p>While the Library of Congress is surely consistent in their romaji usage, their
choice of a particular 1954 dictionary is a bit odd, and distinguishing it from
the similar 1905 system is a source of confusion. At one point it seemed like
Hepburn might become an ANSI standard, but instead Kunreisiki was adopted, and
that standard (Z39.11-1972) has since been deprecated. This lack of an official
standard contributes to inconsistency in what "Revised Hepburn" means.</p>
<p>In contrast, "traditional Hepburn" is somewhat reliably used to refer to the
system used in Hepburn's third edition as opposed to later forms.</p>
<p>Another common variant, "passport Hepburn" refers to the system previously
mandated for names on Japanese passports, which included some exceptions to
normal Hepburn, but those requirements are <a href="https://www.mofa.go.jp/mofaj/toko/passport/pass_4.html#q17">no longer strictly in force</a>,
and you can use any romanization you want (such as "George" for what would be
"Jouji" in Hepburn) if you have …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html">https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dampfkraft.com/romaji-history.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25108455</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 05:39:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple Responds to macOS Privacy Concerns, Explains Why Apps Were Slow to Launch]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25108108">thread link</a>) | @svrma
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/mac/apple-responds-to-macos-privacy-concerns-explains-why-apps-were-slow-to-launch/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/mac/apple-responds-to-macos-privacy-concerns-explains-why-apps-were-slow-to-launch/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>


<!-- .entry-social-links -->
<div>
	
	
	
		
		
	
<!-- .entry-social-links -->	
		
		
	<div>
	<p><a href="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_.jpg" alt="" width="799" height="549" srcset="https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_.jpg 799w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-350x240.jpg 350w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-768x528.jpg 768w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-640x440.jpg 640w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-660x453.jpg 660w, https://cdn.iphoneincanada.ca/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Apple_macOS-catalina-available-today_100719_big.jpg.large_-560x385.jpg 560w" sizes="(max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/news/privacy-concerns-emerge-following-apple-ocsp-server-outage/">Following privacy concerns from Mac users after Apple’s Online Certificate Status Protocol (OCSP) server went down, </a>thus causing third-party applications unable to open on Macs, Apple has now responded to the situation,&nbsp; exacerbated by a recent blog post by Jeffrey Paul.</p>	
	
	
	
<p>An Apple spokesperson told<em> iPhone in Canada</em> it had updated its support document, ‘Safely open apps on your Mac’, to now further detail its privacy protections.</p>
<p>“Gatekeeper performs online checks to verify if an app contains known malware and whether the developer’s signing certificate is revoked,” <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202491">explains</a> Apple. “We have never&nbsp;combined data from these checks with information about Apple users or their devices. We do not use data from these checks to learn what individual users are&nbsp;launching or running on their devices,” clarified the company.</p>
<p>“Notarization checks if the app contains known malware using an encrypted connection that is resilient to server failures,” says Apple, further emphasizing, “These security checks have never included the user’s Apple ID or the identity of their device. To further protect privacy, we have stopped logging IP addresses&nbsp;associated with Developer ID certificate checks, and we will ensure that any collected IP addresses are removed from logs,” details Apple.</p>
<p>On top of this, Apple says “over the next year we will introduce several changes to our security checks,” specifically:</p>
<ul>
<li>a new encrypted protocol for Developer ID certificate revocation checks</li>
<li>strong protections against server failure</li>
<li>a new preference for users to opt out of these security protections</li>
</ul>
<p>Apple also gave some further technical information on the situation to <em>iPhone in Canada.</em> Certificate revocation checks occur to verify that Developer ID certificates used to sign an app have not been revoked by the company. The move is critical for security since a certificate may be pulled if a developer suspects it has been compromised by third parties, or is being used to sign malicious apps.</p>
<p>The industry-standard online certificate status protocol (OCSP) is used by macOS to verify that the Developer ID code signing certificate issued to an app developer has not been revoked. This OCSP request does not include the Apple ID of the user, or reveal a device or app being launched.</p>
<p>Apple says since OCSP is used to check other certificates, including those used to encrypted web connections, these requests happen over unencrypted HTTP, as normal throughout the industry.</p>
<p>HTTP is used to prevent&nbsp;situations where verifying the validity of the certificate that secures the connection to an OCSP server would potentially depend on the result of a request to that same&nbsp;OCSP server, creating a loop that would make it impossible to resolve the request, according to Apple.</p>
<p>Apple says on macOS Catalina and later, by default, all apps running are notarized by the company to note they have been checked by Apple for known malicious software. When an app launches, macOS will check to verify that the app has not been labeled as malicious by Apple since it was first notarized. These checks happen over an encrypted connection—and are resilient to server failures. Which is what happened the other day and users saw their apps hang and take forever to launch.</p>
<p>What caused the OCSP server problem? Apple says it was due to a server-side misconfiguration that specifically interfered with macOS being able to cache OCSP responses for Developer ID. This configuration error, along with an unrelated content delivery network (CDN) misconfiguration, is what caused the slow performance for apps to launch.</p>
<p>Apple explained to <em>iPhone in Canada</em> it has already fixed this performance issue through a server-side update, that will now allow macOS to cache Developer ID OCSP checks for a longer period. macOS users do not need to do anything to benefit from this Apple update.</p>
<p>App notarization checks are used to verify that apps being launched in macOS have not been found to be malicious by Apple, since they were first notarized. Apple says these checks take place over an encrypted connection and are immune to server failures. Notarization checks were not affected by the server-side issue that caused OCSP requests to fail.</p>

	</div>

</div><!-- .entry-inner -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.iphoneincanada.ca/mac/apple-responds-to-macos-privacy-concerns-explains-why-apps-were-slow-to-launch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25108108</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 04:44:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Improve ADS-B Reception with Your Software-Defined Radio]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25107487">thread link</a>) | @gp10
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.onesdr.com/2020/11/16/how-to-improve-ads-b-reception/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.onesdr.com/2020/11/16/how-to-improve-ads-b-reception/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>Automatic dependent surveillance–broadcast&nbsp;(ADS-B) technology enables aircraft to&nbsp;determine their position via satellite and periodically broadcast this location information. An ADS-B receiver system can be used to decode this broadcast signal to track airplanes. </p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-system-1024x576.png" alt="" width="473" height="266" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-system-1024x576.png 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-system-300x169.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-system-768x432.png 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-system-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-system.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 473px) 100vw, 473px"><figcaption>The ADS-B System</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Now let’s take a look at the various components of an ADS-B station, why they matter, and how to make improvements. </p>



<h2><strong>ADS-B Receiver</strong></h2>



<p>In <a href="https://www.onesdr.com/2020/10/21/the-best-ads-b-receiver-for-2020-2021/">this article we previously discussed the different ADS-B receivers</a> on the market today. Systems like the one from <a href="https://amzn.to/36E08h1">Garmin</a> are completely closed and fully integrated and there’s not much opportunity to understand how they work or improve them. The best you can do is use them as per the manufacturer’s recommendation and that should result in the best performance for this product.</p>







<p>On the other hand, there’s plenty of opportunity to learn from open systems based on  either the <a href="https://amzn.to/3f4pJUk">FlightAware</a> or the <a href="https://amzn.to/3kzQa59">Stratux ADS-B receivers</a>. </p>







<p>Both these systems use <a href="https://amzn.to/3f0RHjH">the RTL-SDR</a> as foundational building blocks. There’s a wealth of information online on the internal architecture and various experiments conducted on these products to understand their specifications, performance and how best to use them. There’s also a large online community to learn from and contribute to. </p>



<h2>How Much ADS-B Signal Do You Really Need?</h2>



<p>In general when a receiver processes signals, there is a range of optimal signal level over which it performs best. Anything lower will result in performance degradation – in other words, you will see fewer airplanes. Anything greater will have the same effect. </p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ADS-B-SIGNAL-LEVELS-1024x677.png" alt="" width="495" height="327" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ADS-B-SIGNAL-LEVELS-1024x677.png 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ADS-B-SIGNAL-LEVELS-300x198.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ADS-B-SIGNAL-LEVELS-768x508.png 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ADS-B-SIGNAL-LEVELS.png 1202w" sizes="(max-width: 495px) 100vw, 495px"><figcaption>Different ADS-B Signal Ranges </figcaption></figure></div>



<p>At the very extreme, signal levels higher than a certain level will damage the ADS-B receiver. The trick then is to optimize the signal level such that you can get to within the sweet spot of the ADS-B receiver. </p>



<h2><strong>A Note on Measuring Signals </strong></h2>



<p>In general, it is very difficult to predict actual wireless signal strengths received without making a measurement. Typically a spectrum analyzer is used to make signal measurements at any given frequency. However, not everyone can afford a spectrum analyzer or has access to one. Fortunately it is possible to use an application like SDR# with your receiver to determine how strong or weak various received signals actually are and the impact they might be having on performance.</p>



<p>Here is an example of signal measurement with <a href="https://amzn.to/3f0RHjH">the RTL-SDR</a> as viewed in SDR#. The two views shown are the FFT view and the waterfall or spectrogram below it.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="593" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FM-before-1024x593.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FM-before-1024x593.jpg 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FM-before-300x174.jpg 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FM-before-768x445.jpg 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/FM-before.jpg 1916w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>FM signals measured with <a href="https://amzn.to/3f0RHjH">the RTL-SDR</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>As you experiment with different antennas and other components below, tune across the frequency range of <a href="https://amzn.to/3f0RHjH">the RTL-SDR</a> to check out various signals and their strengths in the waterfall view. This will give you an idea of how your changes impact performance. It will for instance tell you approximately how much gain you need to add up front. It will also tell you if you actually need any amplification at all. In general avoid doing anything that increases the <strong><span>RED</span></strong> levels as these are very strong signals. </p>



<p>Now let’s take a look at the various parts of the ADS-B system and how they impact performance.</p>



<h2>Antennas</h2>



<p>The antenna is at the very front-end of your ADS-B system. You will need an effective <a href="https://amzn.to/3cyPXNr">antenna for ADS-B</a> as it is key to good signal reception. As is often said, garbage in, garbage out. If you use a lousy antenna, a good receiver isn’t going to compensate for it. You can read our complete <a href="https://www.onesdr.com/2020/04/19/best-antennas-for-ads-b-reception/">review of ADS-B antennas</a>. The best antenna requires some effort for installation and optimization but it’s well worth the time spent. </p>



<h2>RF Cables</h2>



<p>If you’re looking to mount your antenna on your rooftop or on a tower for better reception, you will need to take the length of the RF cable from the antenna to your ADS-B receiver into consideration. Why is that?</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Installing-an-antenna-on-rooftop-1024x576.png" alt="" width="553" height="311" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Installing-an-antenna-on-rooftop-1024x576.png 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Installing-an-antenna-on-rooftop-300x169.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Installing-an-antenna-on-rooftop-768x432.png 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Installing-an-antenna-on-rooftop-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Installing-an-antenna-on-rooftop.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 553px) 100vw, 553px"><figcaption>Installing an Antenna on your Rooftop</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>As the frequency of the signal increases, so do the signal losses or attenuation due to any given length of cable. For instance, if you were to use <a href="https://amzn.to/36DJJcj">LMR-400 cable</a>, the loss at 30 MHz is only 0.7 dB for every 100 ft of cable. For the same length of cable, the loss at 1090 MHz is around 4 dB. This signal loss directly impacts the sensitivity of the system by 4 dB and therefore reduces the range of your ADS-B receiver by more than half relative to if you were to use a very short length of cable. That is quite significant.</p>



<h2>Amplifiers</h2>



<p>Fortunately there is a way to compensate for this degradation in sensitivity due to cable loss. It involves the use of a low noise amplifier (LNA). In general, any LNA with sufficiently low noise figure (typically less than 1 dB) and the required amount of gain can be used. </p>



<p>So the first question is – what is the required gain? </p>



<p>The answer depends on several factors some of which are:</p>



<ul><li>Amount of cable loss at 1090 MHz</li><li>Other RF signals are present in your environment – in particular strong ones</li><li>The dynamic and operating range of your ADS-B receiver</li></ul>



<p>As discussed, cable loss can be overcome with the use of an LNA. However, an LNA will amplify everything within its range of operation. It will amplify AM, FM and other signals. Consider a situation where an FM signal is stronger than the ADS-B signal of interest. The amplified signal will saturate the receiver if it exceeds the dynamic range. The signal will also possibly damage the receiver if you’re operating at signal levels that exceed the range of the receiver. The receiver will not be able to process the ADS-B signal of interest in either case.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-1-1024x576.png" alt="Block diagram showing ADS-B signal amplified" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-1.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>Amplifying an ADS-B signal</figcaption></figure>



<p>A solution to this problem is to use a Filtered LNA. This is an LNA with a filter integrated along with it as shown in the picture below.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-2-1024x576.png" alt="Filtered LNA for ADS-B" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-2-1024x576.png 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-2-300x169.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-2-768x432.png 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-2-1536x864.png 1536w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/LNA-2.png 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>Filtered Low Noise Amplifier for ADS-B</figcaption></figure>



<p>The LNA is usually the first component and it is followed by a filter specific to the band of interest – in this case 1090 MHz for ADS-B. This product will reject all signals outside the ADS-B frequency range. For instance it will reject strong FM signals, 4G signals from cellular base stations, signals at 2.4 GHz from your Wi-Fi access point and more. </p>



<p>Here are a couple of ADS-B filtered LNAs that will work depending on your setup.</p>







<p>Use <a href="https://gpio.com/collections/filtered-low-noise-amplifier/products/ads-b-filtered-dual-low-noise-amplifier-lna-with-30-db-gain">this Filtered LNA with 30 dB gain</a> if you have a very long cable run and need to compensate for significant signal loss. Using the calculation for LMR400 above, this Filtered LNA can compensate for 700 ft of cable loss. </p>



<p>Use <a href="https://gpio.com/collections/filtered-low-noise-amplifier/products/ads-b-filtered-low-noise-amplifier-lna-with-15-db-gain">this Filtered LNA that provides 15 dB gain</a>, if you have a shorter cable run. </p>



<h3><strong>How to Install an LNA</strong></h3>



<p>It is best to place the LNA very close to the antenna. This will help minimize the noise figure and improve the sensitivity of your ADS-B receiver system. Since it’s difficult to get a power source or supply at the top of an antenna, <a href="https://www.onesdr.com/2020/01/19/what-is-a-bias-tee/">a bias tee system</a> can be used. A bias tee at the receiver is used to send the DC voltage up to the LNA over the RF cable connecting the two. At the LNA there is a reciprocal bias tee that splits the DC and RF signals. The DC is used to power the LNA. The block diagram below shows a situation where the SDR has a built-in bias tee. This is indeed the case with <a href="https://amzn.to/3f0RHjH">the RTL-SDR</a>.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/bias-tee-modules-1-1024x576.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/bias-tee-modules-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/bias-tee-modules-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/bias-tee-modules-1-768x432.png 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/bias-tee-modules-1.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"><figcaption>Use a Bias Tee to Power a Remote LNA</figcaption></figure>



<p>Sometimes when an LNA is connected the results look like in the following picture – amazing results with a tripling of the number of planes observed!</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="940" height="529" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-improvement.jpg" alt="" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-improvement.jpg 940w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-improvement-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ads-b-improvement-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px"><figcaption>Improvement in Number of Planes Tracked</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>At other times, the addition of an LNA degrades performance and you will not be able to see any airplanes. Why does this happen? Let’s assume that your LNA is connected properly with the RF input end connected to the antenna and that it is powered correctly. There are then two possibilities:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Too much cable loss</strong> and the amount of LNA gain cannot help overcome this degradation. In this situation more gain is required and you can simply add another LNA. Remember to place the first LNA as close to the antenna as possible so as to minimize noise figure. Remember also to check signal levels so you can adjust the amplitude to be within the optimal range. </li><li><strong>Too much gain </strong>and you are likely saturating your receiver with strong signals. Note that even when using a filtered LNA, if the FM signals in your area are very strong, the out-of-band attenuation due to the filter might not be adequate to prevent receiver saturation. Once again you can check what’s going on with the spectrum analyzer view in SDR#. </li></ul>



<h3><strong>How to Optimize the Signal Levels into the RTL-SDR</strong></h3>



<p>There are three methods by which you can optimize signal levels going into the RTL-SDR after the addition of a Filtered LNA.</p>



<p>In the event that you have strong out-of-band signals, they should be attenuated to a reasonable level. The easiest way to do this is by adding an additional <a href="https://www.tindie.com/products/gpio/ads-b-bandpass-filter-band-pass-1090-mhz-ads-b/">ADS-B bandpass filter</a> after the Filtered LNA.</p>



<p>Another way to optimize gain is to reduce the signal level across the band with an attenuator. Connect <a href="https://amzn.to/2K4a4IY">an inline fixed attenuator</a> to the output of the LNA. You can experiment with different values such as 30 dB, 20 dB, etc. until you start seeing output by way of planes. </p>







<p>The third method is to adjust the gain in the Flightaware stick digitally. The <a href="https://amzn.to/3f4pJUk">FlightAware</a> stick is essentially an <a href="https://amzn.to/3f0RHjH">RTL-SDR</a> and utilizes an R802T chipset. Below is a block diagram of the R802T.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/R820T-block-1024x689.png" alt="" width="540" height="363" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/R820T-block-1024x689.png 1024w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/R820T-block-300x202.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/R820T-block-768x517.png 768w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/R820T-block.png 1498w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px"><figcaption>R802T Architecture</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>As you can see the user has the ability to modify the Variable Gain Amplifier (VGA). The range over which this can be varied is nearly 50 dB. The <a href="https://amzn.to/3f4pJUk">FlightAware</a> powers up with maximum amplification in the system. So you essentially have to adjust it to a point where you get the best reception. <a href="https://discussions.flightaware.com/t/for-beginners-how-to-set-change-gain/30201">Here are instructions on how to modify the gain</a>. </p>



<p>Many experiments have been conducted and reported on the <a href="https://amzn.to/3f4pJUk">FlightAware</a> discussion site. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://discussions.flightaware.com/t/gain-adjustment/18376/7" target="_blank">Here is one such discussion</a>. In the plot below, user BartJr has reported an improvement in reception with increase in amplification.</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="777" height="392" src="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rtl-vga-inc.png" alt="" srcset="https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rtl-vga-inc.png 777w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rtl-vga-inc-300x151.png 300w, https://www.onesdr.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rtl-vga-inc-768x387.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 777px) 100vw, 777px"><figcaption>Reception Varies with VGA Gain</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>By contrast below are the results reported by user ieand who has …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.onesdr.com/2020/11/16/how-to-improve-ads-b-reception/">https://www.onesdr.com/2020/11/16/how-to-improve-ads-b-reception/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.onesdr.com/2020/11/16/how-to-improve-ads-b-reception/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25107487</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 02:59:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Super Creative Radio – nonstop curated music for creative work]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25104736">thread link</a>) | @URfejk
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.supercreative.design/radio | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.supercreative.design/radio">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-ix="super-move"><h2>Share good vibes 🌈</h2><p>Submit your track or artwork to make hundreds of other creatives vibe. We’ll review your submission and feature you in the radio and newsletter.</p><div><div><h6><span>s</span><span>u</span><span>p</span><span>e</span><span>r</span>&nbsp;</h6><p>&nbsp;your submission has been received!</p></div><div><p>Oops! Something went wrong while submitting the form.</p></div></div><p>or</p><div><div><h6><span>s</span><span>u</span><span>p</span><span>e</span><span>r</span>&nbsp;</h6><p>&nbsp;your submission has been received!</p></div><div><p>Oops! Something went wrong while submitting the form.</p></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.supercreative.design/radio</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25104736</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:55:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Laser-Guided Lightning May Help Prevent Wildfires]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25103339">thread link</a>) | @kposehn
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				
				
				<div>
				
				
				<p><h2>Small, portable laser pointers could be used to guide lightning strikes, with a study suggesting the technology may prevent bolts from sparking wildfires, a researcher told AFP Thursday.</h2></p>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<div><p>A team of international scientists have shown storm clouds could be “short-circuited” by using a hollow laser — like a pipe of light — to deliver particles into the clouds and draw lightning strikes, research co-author Professor Andrey Miroshnichenko from the University of New South Wales in Canberra told AFP.</p>
<p>In lab tests, the team — which also included scientists from the Australian National University (ANU) — successfully used a laser tractor beam to direct the path of an electrical discharge to specific targets, Miroshnichenko said.</p>
<p>In the past, high-powered lasers were needed to achieve similar results, making the technique dangerous, costly and inaccurate.<span>&nbsp;</span></p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<p><iframe title="Bushfires in Australia: What ignited the deadly crisis" width="1080" height="608" src="about:blank" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-l28KQ8dJDM?feature=oembed" data-no-lazy="1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
				
			</div><div>
				
				
				<div><p>But the new research suggested that small, hand-held lasers could be used in the field within the next decade, he said.</p>
<p>“It turns out that to deliver particles, you do not need high-intensity lasers, even low intensity like your laser pointer will be already enough,” Miroshnichenko said.</p>
<p>Using a tractor beam with a hollow centre, micro-particles in the air could be heated up and delivered to a specific point and trigger an electrical discharge.</p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><p><span><img src="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg" data-src="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg" alt="Electrical Discharge Induce by Microparticle" title="Electrical Discharge Induce by Microparticle" height="auto" width="auto" data-srcset="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg 800w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-768x427.jpg 768w" data-sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" srcset="https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle.jpg 800w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-300x167.jpg 300w, https://www.breakingasia.com/wp-content/uploads/Electrical-Discharge-Induce-by-Microparticle-768x427.jpg 768w"></span>
			</p><div>
				
				
				<p>The electrical discharge induced by a heated microparticle.</p>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text --><div>
				
				
				<div><p>Although it is yet to be tested outside a lab, the technique could potentially be used to control dry lightning strikes, infamous for sparking large blazes including several major <a href="https://www.breakingasia.com/trending/social-media-fakes-australia-bushfire-disinformation/">bushfires in Australia</a> and the western US in the past year, Miroshnichenko added.</p>
<p>“We can imagine a future where this technology may induce electrical discharge from passing lightning, helping to guide it to safe targets and reduce the risk of <a href="https://www.breakingasia.com/trending/makeshift-hospital-saving-dozens-of-koalas-injured-in-bushfires/">catastrophic fires</a>,” co-researcher Vladlen Shvedov, from the ANU Research School of Physics, said.</p>
<p>The research, published in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-020-19183-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nature Communications last month</a>, also involved Texas A&amp;M University in Qatar and the University of California in Los Angeles.<span>&nbsp;</span></p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.breakingasia.com/news/laser-guided-lightning-may-help-prevent-wildfires/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25103339</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 18:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Create Vintage Videos Using FFmpeg in 4 Simple Steps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 273 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25102401">thread link</a>) | @ponderingfish
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><strong>It’s time for the holidays and what better way to share love and memories with your family than to create an old-school, vintage movie? You don’t need a time-machine to go back to the 50s or 60s to rmake your homevideo look like a vintage movie. All you need is FFmpeg, some imagination, and perhaps the rest of this guide 🙂 </strong></p>



<p>Let’s take a look at how you can use FFmpeg to make your videos look like old-school/vintage/retro-styled movies, shall we?</p>



<hr>



<h2>What’s Do I Mean By A Vintage Movie?</h2>



<p>Well, good question! </p>



<p><strong>My definition of an old-school movie is a movie with a low frame-rate (like 15 fps), lots of scratches and film-grain to give an aged look, and a sepia tint to it!</strong></p>



<p>Let’s see how we can achieve all of this using FFmpeg.</p>



<p>For this tutorial, I shall be using the “Touchdown Pass” sequence from <a href="https://media.xiph.org/video/derf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Xiph</a> to illustrate the steps. It’s a 20 second video, but for the sake of this tutorial, I’ll be cutting it to 10 seconds using FFmpeg (<a href="https://ottverse.com/trim-cut-video-using-start-endtime-reencoding-ffmpeg/">here’s how to do that</a>).</p>



<p>Let’s get started! </p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 1: Changing the Frame Rate using FFmpeg</h2>



<p>The first step is to “speed” up the video. Let’s take the video back to pre-30fps or pre-60fps days and take it all the way down to 10 fps. This gives the video an old-school look right off the bat! </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i td-10sec.mp4 \
-filter:v fps=fps=10 \
td-fast.mp4</code></pre>



<p>Here is the sped-up video. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479524704" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 2: Give The Video a Vintage Look using FFmpeg’s filters</h2>



<p>Next, let’s change the rich, wonderful colors and bring a sepia-link tint to the entire video. This can be done using FFmpeg’s in-built <code>curves</code> filter. You can use the <code>curves</code> filter to change the amount of R, G, B in a frame and specify the “curves” that govern the change or shift in colors. </p>



<p>Luckily for us, FFmpeg has a pre-defined <code>vintage</code> filter that works pretty well, I must say! Here is the commandline to convert our sped-up video into a “vintage” looking video. Simple, right?</p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i td-fast.mp4 \
-vf curves=vintage \
td-vintage-fast.mp4</code></pre>



<p>Here’s the result of the <code>curves=vintage</code> filter on our footall video.</p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479525304" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2>Step 3: Getting a Film Grain Overlay and Resizing It</h2>



<p>As the final step, let’s add a lot of film-grain and “scratches” to make our video look like something that was shot on film, stored in a dusty old cupboard, and discovered 40 years later! </p>



<p>I found a fantastic “old school” film overlay on YouTube (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J_MZb7qTenE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">source link</a>) with a download link. </p>



<figure><div>
<p><span><iframe width="1200" height="675" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J_MZb7qTenE?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-US&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></span></p>
</div></figure>



<p>The video’s size is <code>1440x1080</code> pixels and so I had to resize it to <code>1920x1080</code> to match the size of my input video. </p>



<p>Here is the command to resize a video using FFmpeg using the the <code>scale</code> filter. I’ve stored the output video as <code>oldFilm1080.mp4</code>.</p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg -i old-film-grain.wmv \
-vf scale=1920:1080,setsar=1:1 \
oldFilm1080.mp4</code></pre>



<hr>



<h2>Step 4: Add the Overlay To Your Video</h2>



<p>Now we have two videos with us – </p>



<ol><li>our old-school film-grain-scratchy video</li><li>our vintage-looking, sped-up football video. </li></ol>



<p>Now all that’s left to do is to overlay them on each other and enjoy the fruits of <s>our</s> FFmpeg’s labor! </p>



<p>Here’s the commandline to achieve that. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe \
-i oldFilm1080.mp4 \
-i td-vintage-fast.mp4 \
-filter_complex "[0]format=rgba,colorchannelmixer=aa=0.25[fg];\
[1][fg]overlay[out]" \
-map [out] \
-pix_fmt yuv420p -c:v libx264 -crf 18 \
touchdown-vintage.mp4</code></pre>



<p>So, what’s going on here? </p>



<ul><li>we provide two input videos to FFmpeg </li><li>using <code>filter_complex</code>, we use <code>colorchannelmixer</code> to overlay by modifying the alpha channel of the film-grain video that is referred to as <code>[0]</code> and and let’s call the output <code>[fg]</code>. It’s black and white, so modifying only the alpha is good enough for our use case. The syntax is as follows <code>colorchannelmixer=rr:rg:rb:ra:gr:gg:gb:ga:br:bg:bb:ba:ar:ag:ab:aa</code>. </li><li>we are modifying only the alpha, and so, we modify only the <code>aa</code> (output’s alpha) to <code>0.25</code>.</li><li>then, we use the vintage-looking football video (referred to as <code>[1]</code>) and overlay them both using the <code>overlay</code> filter to create an interim output stored in a variable called <code>[out]</code>. This is shown in the commands –&gt; <code>[1][fg]overlay[out]</code></li><li>then, we encode the interim output to give us the final video using H.264 with <code>crf=18</code> which should give us a good quality video.</li></ul>







<p><strong>Here is what the final output looks like! Cool, isn’t it? </strong></p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479529512" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>







<p>And, here’s how it looks side-by-side the original video. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/479529447" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>







<p>Now you can change the opacity of the alpha channels, use a different film grain video, or use a different <code>curves</code> function, but, the process won’t change much. </p>



<p>Hope you all have a lot of fun making “<strong>vintage</strong>” videos this holiday season and please let me know in the comments how it went! Please create some fun videos, share them with your loved ones, and have a few laughs 🙂 </p>



<p>Thank you! </p>



<p>If you enjoyed this post, do check out the rest of<a href="https://ottverse.com/category/ffmpeg/"> <strong>OTTVerse’s FFmpeg tutorials</strong></a> to learn more about how to use FFmpeg to improve your video editing, compression, and processing skills!</p>

<!-- MOLONGUI AUTHORSHIP PLUGIN 4.2.9 -->
<!-- https://www.molongui.com/authorship/ -->

<div id="mab-2475982632" data-plugin-release="4.2.9" data-plugin-version="free" data-box-layout="slim" data-box-position="below" data-multiauthor="false" data-author-type="user" itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person">

	
    <!-- Author headline -->
    <p>
        <h3>
            <span>About The Author</span>
        </h3>
    </p>

    <div>

        <div data-profile-layout="layout-1" data-author-ref="user-194568617">
            
<!-- End of .m-a-box-content-top -->

<div>

    <!-- Author picture -->
    
	<p><a href="https://ottverse.com/author/vkr2020/">
                    <img src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1b73140b34f836d184d53fbb00f406dd?s=150&amp;d=mp&amp;r=g" width="150" height="150" alt="Avatar" data-lazy-src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1b73140b34f836d184d53fbb00f406dd?s=150&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;d=mp&amp;r=g" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7">                </a>
                	</p>

    <!-- Author social -->
    
    <!-- Author data -->
    <div>

        <!-- Author name -->
        

        <!-- Author metadata -->
        

        <!-- Author bio -->
        
<div itemprop="description">
	<p>I’m Dr. Krishna Rao Vijayanagar, and I am the Founder and Editor of OTTVerse.com. I've spent several years working hands-on with Video Codecs (AVC, HEVC, MultiView Plus Depth), ABR streaming, and Video Analytics (QoE, Content &amp; Audience, and Ad). I hope to use my experience and love for video streaming to bring you information and insights into the OTT universe. Please use the Contact Page to get in touch with me.</p>
</div>

        
            <!-- Author related posts -->
            <!-- End of .m-a-box-related -->

        
    </div><!-- End of .m-a-box-data -->

</div><!-- End of .m-a-box-content-middle -->

<!-- End of .m-a-box-content-bottom -->        </div><!-- End of .m-a-box-profile -->

        
    </div><!-- End of .m-a-box-container -->

	
</div><!-- End of .m-a-box -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ottverse.com/create-vintage-videos-using-ffmpeg/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25102401</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:33:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Case for Properties: Programming Language Design]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25102163">thread link</a>) | @WillBAnders
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
                <div>
                    
                    <div>
                        <div>
                            <p><span>November 15, 2020</span><br>
                                <span><em>~12m read time</em></span>
                            </p>
                            <p><span>November 15, 2020</span><br>
                                <span><em>~12m read time</em></span>
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <p>Properties are a really nice feature of modern languages, and I've recently
                    gotten attached to them in Kotlin. For a while
                    I wasn't comfortable with the idea of 'fields' performing arbitrary computation,
                    but having used them for a few months now I'm really enjoying the simplicity -
                    <em>especially</em> when moving back to Java!</p>
                <p>Having given it some thought, I wanted to lay out a case in support of
                    properties which highlights their benefits over directly accessing fields (which
                    is mostly about getters/setters, but nonetheless), and how we can establish some
                    guidelines on when properties should not be used to avoid the issue of
                    arbitrary computation causing side effects or other unexpected behavior.</p>
                
                <p>In short, a property is <abbr title="Features which aid readability or ease of use but do not impact semantics.">syntax sugar</abbr> for getter/setter methods that look
                    like fields. Instead of having to use the methods <code>item.getQuantity()</code> and
                    <code>item.setQuantity()</code>, we can access the property <code>item.quantity</code> and set it
                    using <code>item.quantity = 1</code>, exactly like a field. The compiler transforms property
                    access and assignment to use the appropriate getters/setters (hence, syntax sugar).
                </p>
                <p>The most noteworthy consequence of this is, in my opinion, allowing <em>validation
                    on assigment</em>. For example, <code>item.quantity</code> may be defined as follows (in Kotlin):</p>
<pre><span>class</span> <span>Item</span> {
    <span>var</span> <span>quantity</span>: <span>Int</span> = <span>0</span>
        <span>set</span>(value) {
            require(value &gt;= <span>0</span>) <span>//throws if negative</span>
            <span>field</span> = value
        }
}
</pre>
<pre><span>
  <i onclick="openDemo('item-property', this)"></i>
</span>item.<span>quantity</span> = <span>-10</span>;
</pre>
                
                <p>The largest benefit of properties is replacing field use, which has a massive
                    amount of drawbacks, with methods instead. In languages like C++ and Java that
                    don't have properties, the best practice is to keep all fields private and
                    manually create getters and setters. More modern languages, like C# and Kotlin,
                    use properties for this instead which can do that automatically.</p>
                <p>Most of the following points are also benefits of using getters/setters over
                    fields, and then properties step in to provide the extra bit of syntax sugar icing on
                    the cake.</p>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <h3 id="api-safety-and-compatibility">
                            <span>
                                <a href="#api-safety-and-compatibility">
                                    <i></i>
                                </a>
                            </span>
                            <span>API Safety and Compatibility</span>
                        </h3>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <ol>
                    <li>Property getters/setters can have different <abbr title="public/private and friends">access modifiers</abbr>, allowing for
                        fields which are read-only for external use but still mutable within the class.
                        <ul>
                            <li>Example: In Kotlin, <code>val&nbsp;counter&nbsp;=&nbsp;0&nbsp;private&nbsp;set</code>
                                defines a <code>counter</code> field that can be publicly accessed but not modified (unless within the class).
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>Getters/setters can be used to maintain <abbr title="A (mathematical) property which is expected to hold true in all cases

For example, a unit vector (3D) has the invariant x² + y² + z² == 1.">invariants</abbr> and perform other
                        validation work, such as <code>quantity&nbsp;&gt;=&nbsp;0</code> in the opening example.
                    </li>
                    <li>Since getters/setters are methods, the implementation can be changed without
                        breaking either <abbr title="Application Programming Interface

The interface of the *source* code">API</abbr> or <abbr title="Application Binary Interface

The interface of the *compiled* code">ABI</abbr> compatibility.
                        <ul>
                            <li>Example: A <code>Vector</code> class could have <code>x/y/z</code> properties, but
                                change the implementation to use a component array <code>[x, y, z]</code> instead without issue.
                            </li>
                            <li>Additionally, getters/setters can be inlined during optimization to speed up performance at the cost of ABI compatibility.
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                </ol>
                
                <ol>
                    <li>Properties can be used in interfaces since they're backed by methods, while fields require getters/setters to be defined for them. Notably, these getters/setters would still need to have fields defined in the implementing class to handle their values, while a property can handle that automatically.
                    </li>
                    <li>Properties can be used for methods which often behave like fields, but
                        cannot be implemented with one due to subtypes requiring computation or
                        other restrictions.
                        <ul>
                            <li>Example: <code>List#size()</code> generally doesn't need computation and returns the
                                value of a field, but some implementations (such as a <abbr title="A form of linked list which doesn't track its size, comes from Lisp

Honestly google it, this text box can't do it justice">cons list</abbr>) might.
                            </li>
                            <li>Whether <code>List#size()</code> should be a property is certainly debatable, but with how frequently collections are used I think it's almost a necessity.
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                </ol>
                
                <ol>
                    <li>Properties are a <em>single unit</em>. Getters/setters are located in the same
                        location in the source code as the property declaration, making it easier to
                        fully understand a field as opposed to having them defined in separate locations.
                    </li>
                    <li>Properties almost always have syntax sugar for providing default
                        implementations of <code>get/set</code> (if it's not already done automatically). In Kotlin, <code>val property</code> provides a default
                        getter while <code>var property</code> provides both a getter and setter.
                    </li>
                    <li>Debugging properties is possible without a dedicated debugger by using
                        getters/setters. This may be minor for large languages, but if your language
                        doesn't have an IDE or still in development this is <em>extremely</em> useful.
                    </li>
                    <li>Readability is often increased, albeit debatable. I personally find <code>item.quantity&nbsp;=&nbsp;1</code> to
                        be more readable than <code>item.setQuantity(1)</code>, especially in large chains.
                    </li>
                    <li>Generally, properties imply 'simple' behavior, like fields, as opposed to complex
                        computation that some methods may perform. We'll talk about this in detail soon.
                    </li>
                </ol>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <h2 id="so-what-are-the-downsides">
                            <span>
                                <a href="#so-what-are-the-downsides">
                                    <i></i>
                                </a>
                            </span>
                            <span>So what are the downsides?</span>
                        </h2>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <p>I think there are two notable downsides to having properties. First, the
                    performance difference between field access and method calls can be significant,
                    especially in low level languages. Second, field access has clear, well-defined
                    behavior while a method call could effectively do anything, thus making it
                    harder to reason about code. Let's dig in to both of these.</p>
                
                <p>Field access is almost always language primitive, and is therefore faster than
                    doing the work of a method call (which then has to access <em>something</em> anyways).</p>
                <p>That said, compiler optimizations like <abbr title="Replacing a method call with it's implementation">inlining</abbr> can easily resolve this for
                    simple properties. In more complex cases, this is actually where properties are
                    most useful - a field itself wasn't sufficient, so the alternative would have
                    been a method call or sacrificing validation anyways.</p>
                <p>In low level languages where memory layout is often important, knowing a field
                    access corresponds to a memory lookup (and not arbitrary computation) can be
                    important. In higher level languages, particularly Object Oriented ones that
                    often encapsulate fields behind methods anyways, I don't believe this
                    distinction is as necessary.</p>
                <div>
                    <div>
                        <h3 id="problem-2-arbitrary-computation">
                            <span>
                                <a href="#problem-2-arbitrary-computation">
                                    <i></i>
                                </a>
                            </span>
                            <span>Problem 2: Arbitrary Computation</span>
                        </h3>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <p>Finally, we've made our way to what I believe is the core issue: since
                    properties can perform arbitrary computation, it is unclear what potential
                    behavior getting/setting a property may have. The extreme example here, of
                    course, is deleting the entire file system. Fields on the other hand have
                    clearly defined behavior - get or set the value, nothing more.</p>
                <p>However, these type of assumptions are not unique to properties. We apply the
                    same assumptions to methods (and honestly everything) as well. I often presume
                    that <code>getX()</code> and <code>setX(x)</code> have 'simple' behavior, but they could use lazy
                    initialization, have unexpected validation checks, or cause side-effects and
                    other unexpected behavior
                    like a database <code>getConnection()</code>. Naming is one of the two hard problems in computer science,
                    likely because we carry assumptions with us that may not always fit.</p>
                <p>That said, these assumptions …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html">https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.willbanders.dev/articles/a-case-for-properties.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25102163</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 16:04:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[New Trend: Data-Infrastructure-as-a-Service]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 10 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25102046">thread link</a>) | @randrews543
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://talkinsaasy.com/blog/data-infrastructure-as-a-service | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://talkinsaasy.com/blog/data-infrastructure-as-a-service">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div data-layout-label="Post Body" data-type="item" id="item-5f73b31b98869d427835f0db"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3f09a85ee918fc7ad2a2"><div><p>Entrepreneurs and investors are continually looking towards the horizon to see what new challenges and shortcomings are in the market and what solutions can emerge to help solve them. The scale and complexity of data within different industries was already complex and the complexity and scale of it is only increasing every single day. How do we take all this data, wrangle it, and make it more manageable to use, enter Data-Infrastructure-as-a-Service. </p><p>Data-Infrastructure-as-a-Service is an emerging category of startups that bring together functional data from across specific industries and makes it more easily available with strong documentation so startups, developments teams and technology providers can more easily integrate industry data from other products and service providers within their industry.</p><p>Think of these services as the “pipes” that help ensure the data is flowing, you just need to turn on the spigot on your end and it should all come flowing out. Each human on earth  creating 1.7 megabytes of data EACH SECOND! In the time you read this post you will have create 204 new megabytes of data, the sheer volume of it is massive and if we don’t maintain good pipes, everything will clog.</p><p>Startups like <a href="https://withleaf.io/" target="_blank">Leaf Agriculture</a> (Farming and AgTech), <a href="https://www.noyo.com/" target="_blank">Noyo</a> (Healthcare and Insurance), and <a href="https://truelayer.com/" target="_blank">TrueLayer</a> (Banking) are all building industry specific data infrastructure platforms. These tools are helping simplify data and system integration. Shortening innovation cycles, increasing access for developers, enabling integrations, and increasing the overall satisfaction of customers when their disparate tools and systems all work together harmoniously. As both an entrepreneur and investor, keep your eyes peeled for new opportunities on the horizon for industry specific Data Infrastructure platforms.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://talkinsaasy.com/blog/data-infrastructure-as-a-service</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25102046</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 15:49:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Moving my serverless project to Ruby on Rails]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 329 | Comments 170 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25100397">thread link</a>) | @pcr910303
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://frantic.im/back-to-rails | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://frantic.im/back-to-rails">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <header>
    
    
  </header>
  <p>I have a small side project: <a href="https://hacker.gifts/">digital gift cards for hackers</a>. It uses Shopify for all the store-related stuff: frontend, payments, refunds, reports, etc.</p>

<p>But unlike regular digital products (ebooks, videos) I wanted each card that the user purchases from the store to be unique. So I made a  script that generates personalized images and ran it manually for every order.</p>

<p>The next logical step was automating this process. I started with serverless AWS Lambda. At the time it was the hot new tech and I wanted to learn more. It seemed very fitting for my use-case: single-responsibility functions that can run at any time and don’t require server maintenance.</p>

<p><img src="https://frantic.im/assets/back-to-rails/simple-lambda.png" alt=""></p>

<p>It was super easy to get started. I built a JavaScript function and deployed it to AWS Lambda, added Shopify web hook and it all worked!</p>

<p>Early benefits of serverless (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Easy to get started</li>
  <li>Don’t have to configure or maintain servers</li>
  <li>Free for small loads</li>
</ul>

<p>In reality, writing the simple Lambda functions turned out to be only 10% of the work.</p>

<p>Time passed and my backend started getting more complex: I needed to store some state for each <a href="https://hacker.gifts/products/space-invaders">puzzle</a>, send confirmation emails, show an order details page. What started as a simple function, grew into a bunch of serverless functions, SNS topics, S3 buckets, DynamoDB tables. All bound together with plenty of YAML glue, schema-less JSON objects passed around and random hardcoded configs in AWS console.</p>

<p>I think it’s just a typical software development lifecycle: things grow organically, become a mess, and require some refactoring. Make it run first (discover market fit), then make it right (refactor to integrate the new discoveries).</p>

<p>But this time it was different. I couldn’t refactor things as easily as I used to in traditional monolithic apps. Here’s why:</p>

<p>When the building blocks are too simple, the complexity moves into the interaction between the blocks.</p>

<p>And the interactions between the serverless blocks happen <em>outside</em> my application. A lambda publishes a message to SNS, another one picks it up and writes something to DynamoDB, the third one takes that new record and sends an email…</p>

<p>I could test every single block in that flow, but I didn’t have confidence in the overall process. What if publishing fails, how would I know that? How would system recover? Can I rollback and try again? Where do the logs go?</p>

<p>Another swarm of problems was hiding in my configuration: bad Route 53 record, typos in SNS topics, wrong S3 bucket region. Tracing errors was a challenge, there’s no single log output I can look into.</p>

<p>With serverless, I was no longer dealing with my project's domain, I was dealing with the distributed system's domain.</p>

<p>At this point I felt fooled.</p>

<p>I came for the easy way to deploy code and not think about servers, but in the end had to design my system around the platform’s limitations.</p>

<p>Drawbacks of serverless (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hard to follow information flow</li>
  <li>Impossible to replicate production environment locally</li>
  <li>Slow iteration speed</li>
  <li>Lack of end-to-end testing</li>
  <li>Immature documentation (dominated by often outdated Medium posts)</li>
  <li>No conventions (have to make hundreds of unessential decisions)</li>
</ul>

<p>—</p>

<p>I was clearly not enjoying the serverless. So I decided to rewrite it. After all, it is a side project I’m doing for fun. The tech stack of choice — Ruby on Rails.</p>

<p>I haven’t used Rails since 2013, and for the last 8 years at Facebook I’ve been mostly doing JavaScript.</p>

<p><img src="https://frantic.im/assets/back-to-rails/logo.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>The experience of picking Rails back up was really nice but… uneventful. Not much had really changed. A few things got added, a few small things moved around.</p>

<p>Of course I did <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/issues/38060">hit some magical Ruby issues</a>. But unlike my typical experience with JavaScript, I was quickly able to find the solution.</p>

<p>Rails comes with so many things built-in and configured. Over the years, without Rails, I used to gluing random JavaScript libraries together to roll my own routing, file storage wrappers, email preview pipeline, managing secrets, test setup with fixtures, database migrations, logging, performance reporting, deployment scripts. With Rails I didn’t have to think about all these details and could simply focus on making product-visible changes.</p>

<p>It was like driving a Tesla after years of making my own scrappy cars. Similar components, but all configured and aligned to work well together.</p>

<p>Benefits of Rails (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Conventions</li>
  <li>Tooling, libraries</li>
  <li>Documentation</li>
  <li>Monolith is easy to understand and test</li>
</ul>

<p>Drawbacks of Rails (for hobby projects):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Feels heavyweight in the beginning</li>
  <li>Hurts if your opinions differ from Rails conventions</li>
  <li>Have to host on a server</li>
  <li>Doesn’t sound cool in 2020 (anymore and maybe yet)</li>
</ul>

<p>—</p>

<p>Serverless is like a black hole. It promised exciting adventures, but gravity sucked me in and I spent most of my efforts dealing with its complexity, instead of focusing on my product.</p>

  
  






  <div>
  <div>
    <p>Hi! My name is Alex. I’m a software engineer at Facebook, where I work on React&nbsp;Native, Oculus and Messenger. I love thinking about development experience.</p>
    <p>I write about programming, software design and side projects <a href="https://frantic.im/subscribe/" target="_blank"><svg viewBox="0 0 800 800"><path d="M493 652H392c0-134-111-244-244-244V307c189 0 345 156 345 345zm71 0c0-228-188-416-416-416V132c285 0 520 235 520 520z"></path><circle cx="219" cy="581" r="71"></circle></svg> Subscribe</a></p>
  </div>
</div>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://frantic.im/back-to-rails</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25100397</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 11:40:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A framework for offline and decentralised web apps]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 33 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25100313">thread link</a>) | @dgellow
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://concords.app/blog/what-is-concords | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://concords.app/blog/what-is-concords">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><p>Concords is an MVP framework for building offline &amp; decentralised web apps, with a file-based approach to storing data. It has no servers or databases and is a static app built with Javascript and HTML, all code is written to run in a browser and nothing is stored outside of the browser or downloaded files.</p> <p>The full MVP is available to try at <a href="https://alpha.concords.app/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">alpha.concords.app</a></p> <h2 id="why">Why?</h2> <p>SAAS applications run on servers with databases. Each interaction with the UI sends information from the browser to a server, which then likely writes something or fetches something from a centralized database.</p> <p>Maintaining servers and databases is expensive, complex and time-consuming and I'm not really interested in that side of software. I don't want the responsibility to look after data that is depended upon, that's neither my skill-set nor passion. I like to focus my attention on the front-end experience.</p> <p>I set out to build a framework for file-based SAAS apps. Multi-user collaborative apps, with data-driven user flows and advanced UI. But apps that run offline and save state to the filesystem, not send it off to a cloud-based database. Giving users full ownership and visibility of their data, with no dependency on an internet connection. Taking a progressive approach to connectivity, using it to enrich the experience, but not depend on it.</p> <h2 id="technical-steps">Technical Steps</h2> <ul> <li><p>Functional blockchain library in Typescript.</p> </li> <li><p><a href="https://svelte.dev/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Svelte</a> &amp; <a href="https://sapper.svelte.dev/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Sapper</a> for all things UI.</p> </li> <li><p>Blockchain sync with IndexedDB and reactivity hook.</p> </li> <li><p>Created <a href="https://1.0.0.concords.app/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">some mini-apps</a> to refine and test the core functionality.</p> </li> <li><p>User Authentication flow.</p> </li> <li><p><a href="https://alpha.concords.app/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">MVP: Kanban app</a>.</p> </li> </ul> <h2 id="concords-mvp-board-app">Concords MVP: Board App</h2> <p>This MVP serves to demonstrate a basic solution to a truly offline and decentralized experience in a collaborative web app. It's a static app, so just Javascript and HTML, with no servers or databases running in the background. It's a progressive web app with a service worker, that runs entirely in the browser. So once the initial load has been performed, the rest of the experience can work completely offline, where data is stored in files, downloaded and uploaded through the UI.</p> <p>A boards app covers a lot of functionality commonly found in SAAS applications, I figured it's a great benchmark to prove out the technology.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/add-task.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h3 id="authentication">Authentication</h3> <p>With Concords, authentication is all done in the browser, without any communication to a server or external resource.</p> <p>In the Concords authentication system, we issue a downloadable public profile which includes your public key and some basic user info. I keep mine for the MVP on my personal domain. <a href="https://ternent.dev/concords/sam-ternent.profile.concords.json" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">https://ternent.dev/concords/sam-ternent.profile.concords.json</a></p> <p>Anyone with access to my public key is able to encrypt data for me, that only I can read with my private key. I just have that stored on my personal machine. It’s never been online and no-one else knows it.</p> <p>This key is used to log the user into the app and only a valid key combination can login and access the software.</p> <p>For my MVP, this is more than sufficient to complete and decent authentication flow. We can have a recognisable UX of profile/password combination to build a login system, whilst setting us up for an encrypted, multi-user, data flow.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/signup.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <p>I know it's a pain to ask users to store both parts of their encryption keys themselves. If the private key is lost, it's unrecoverable and so is any encrypted data to that key. But I couldn't compromise here, it has to be this way to keep things decentralized. But it's a problem that can be fixed through software, it doesn't have to be my software - we're decentralizing things here, but key management software will fix this problem.</p> <h3 id="the-app">The App</h3> <p>Knowing roughly what I needed to build to prove out the concept, and having already implemented User Profile and the authentication flow, the key features I chose to implement were:</p> <ul> <li>Create new and multiple boards</li> <li>Downloadable app files</li> <li>Load any board, from any user</li> <li>Assign tasks to users</li> <li>Editable tasks</li> <li>Timestamped actions</li> <li>Drag to sort columns</li> <li>Draggable tasks across columns</li> <li>Soft delete tasks to the trash, with restore and remove</li> <li>Activity log with an immutable history of the board</li> </ul> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/create-board.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h4 id="multiple-users">Multiple Users</h4> <p>By default, a new user doesn't have edit access to a document. For the purpose of the MVP, we've got a "Join" button in the left-hand sidebar. Clicking this will add the user as an entry to the data store and unlock editing. This covers the concept enough for now, but we are able to achieve direct encryption with the public/private key authentication, so that's going to be an interesting avenue to explore further outside of the MVP context.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/third-user.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h3 id="core-library">Core Library</h3> <p>The core of the framework is written in Typescript. It's a collection of functional utilities which cover the data side of the application. It runs an internal blockchain for writing data, mapped with an IndexDB instance for reading.</p> <h4 id="blockchain">Blockchain</h4> <p>At the heart of the library is the <a href="https://hackernoon.com/merkle-tree-what-is-it-and-why-use-it-8m2a63xjd" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">Merkel Tree</a> solution. Our Merkle Tree (as used in Blockchain and git), is a functional library to act as a blockchain node, from a JSON object structure, in the browser.</p> <p>Built on top of that is a CRUD API which the application will interface with. When an action is performed in the app, a timestamped transaction is created for the blockchain. Once commit, all pending transactions are then added to a block on the chain. Once a block has been added to the blockchain, the hash-based data structure ensures the integrity of the app state.</p> <pre><code>{
 "type": "tasks",
 "action": "create",
 "data": {
   "title": "Task Name",
   "description": "Task Description",
   "completed": false,
   "due_date": "2020-11-02",
   "assigned_to": "a72e75a898db9247be59d1aaf9d4c54459e1d24faa43d9f5da0a5a9611a19eb",
   "column": "2bb6a2b737381377fd962b1bda0771d084abd3cab270648c78b7e06566e6b5",
   "id": "d2e25d4d6c77b34fbe87da5f387cf8c3bec25ffc76673e84bf76dbf2aa15754f",
   "timestamp": 1604144654690
 },
 "user": {
   "firstName": "Sam",
   "lastName": "Ternent",
   "avatarUrl": "https://ternent.dev/concords/avatar.jpeg",
   "organisation": "Team Concords",
   "id": "a72e75a898db9247be59d1aaf9d4c54459e1d24faa43d9f5da0a5a9611a19eb"
 },
 "signature": "NOT RELEASED"
}</code></pre><hr> <h4 id="database">Database</h4> <p>Sitting on the other side of the blockchain is the DB layer. When a transaction it accepted onto the blockchain, we parse the event and perform an operation on an IndexedDB instance in the browser. Transactions are recorded as they go in, so we don’t duplicate transactions and minimise the number of write operations to the database.</p> <p>As long as we have the blockchain data object, we have a full picture of our app and data state. We can drop and recreate a database with complete accuracy, based on secured transactional history. This is a <strong>read only</strong> layer.</p> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/flows/recreate-db.gif?raw=true"></p> <hr> <h4 id="architecture-overview">Architecture Overview</h4> <p><img alt="" src="https://concords.app/images/architecture.svg"></p> <hr> <h2 id="next-steps">Next Steps</h2> <h3 id="desktop-app">Desktop App</h3> <p>A quick leap here is to build this out into a desktop app using electron. Little things like saving the hash to a keychain, directly reading and writing to the filesystem. I'm excited to try running the <a href="https://dat.foundation/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank">DAT</a> project to enable P2P connectivity to give a realtime collaborative experience.</p> <h3 id="intergrations">Intergrations</h3> <p>My primary goal is decentralization. I'm not against storing data on the cloud, I just want to be able to make my own choice as to where. The initial standout integration I want to try is with Dropbox, syncing a folder in your filesystem to dropbox will give us the ability to introduce the "push/pull" aspect found in git.</p> <h3 id="conflict-resolution">Conflict resolution</h3> <p>I need to do further research around conflict resolution. I have the basics for a complete blockchain, which includes proof of work and consensus to ensure the validity of the underlying data structure, but it doesn't secure or handle in-app data conflicts. Visual diffs and conflicts are problems solved in various other applications, with plenty of research available. I'm not sure how it will look yet, but it should be a fun one to solve.</p> <h3 id="user-roles--permissions">User roles &amp; permissions</h3> <p>Using our data structure user roles and permissions are achievable. With the use of application-level permission keys, we can encrypt the access key for a specific user. They will then have access to any data under that permission level.</p> </section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://concords.app/blog/what-is-concords</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25100313</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 11:26:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Open Source does not mean “Includes Free Support”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 295 | Comments 247 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25099862">thread link</a>) | @alexellisuk
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
      We need to talk.
    </p><div>

<p>Here’s a paraphrased conversation I’m having way to often, costing me way too much time, keeping me from doing things that are way more important:</p>

<pre>User: Hi, I'd like to report a bug in your application.
Me:   Great! Please open a support ticket, then.
User: But, it looks like I need to pay for that?
Me:   So?
User: I just want to tell you that your app is broken, so you can fix it.
Me:   Yes, that's a support request, please open a ticket.
User: ...
</pre>

<figure>
  <a href="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/bugreport.png">
    <img src="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/bugreport.png">
  </a>
  
</figure><p>
                             
                             
From there it typically derails into a whiny tirade about me being a crappy two bit developer who doesn’t give a shit about his code (which is ridiculous, since, professional pride aside, I have every incentive to fix bugs, to prevent my inbox from getting flooded) and just wants to rip off his users.</p>

<p>In the past, I sometimes gave in (when it sounded like something might be wrong). I looked at the issue and almost always found that nothing was broken, just didn’t work as expected (which is actually to be expected for every reasonably complex piece of software). The user just didn’t bother reading the docs and tried to bypass the fee by masquerading the support request as a bug report. So, nowadays my policy simply is: no support ticket, no service. Any such request goes straight to the trash folder without even being looked at.</p>

<h2 id="why-am-i-such-an-asshole">Why am I such an asshole?</h2>

<p>Here’s the thing: I write open source software to solve <strong>my problem</strong>. I let you use my solutions because that comes at zero cost for me (well, almost, I still have to pay for the website, you are downloading from. You are welcome, by the way). I also provide the source code, so you can fix things yourself, should my solution turn out to be unsuitable. However, once you come to me with a “bugreport” that doesn’t also include a patch (or at least very precisely pinpoints the problem), then you are basically asking me to <strong>look at your problem</strong>. At this point, it is no longer zero cost for me and that’s the reason for why I am charging you money: you are asking me to spent time on your behalf. That is commonly called <strong>work</strong>. And surprisingly enough, work is what people expect to be paid for.</p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong. I’m happy to help. Selling support is what keeps the lights on here (did I mention the cost of running a webserver?). But coming to me under false pretense and/or expecting that I <strong>must</strong> provide free service on top of a software I gave away without charge is not going to win you any favours.</p>

<p>It stops being free, when it starts costing me! My time is valuable. If you want a piece of it, I want money in return. Period.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Seems like this post has struck a nerve and caused a few misunderstandings. <a href="https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/reactions-bugreport-free-support/">Clarification on my position here</a>.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://raccoon.onyxbits.de/blog/bugreport-free-support/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25099862</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 10:12:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Ripped Out a £6k Lighting System]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 218 | Comments 286 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25099615">thread link</a>) | @iamflimflam1
<br/>
November 15, 2020 | https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


  <p>Back in 2012 my wife and I started a house renovation project in Edinburgh (Scotland) having moved to that great city the previous year. In our previous London abode we’d installed a wireless lighting system from a company called Rako and it worked well enough to convince us that wireless was the way to go. Now, having installed and maintained a system with over 150 wireless lighting control circuits over the past 7 years I’ve finally had to admit that my technology choice was wrong. The Z-Wave wireless lighting system I installed just doesn’t work for a home like mine. I have now ripped out almost all of the Z-Wave units I installed – which had cost me more than £6k to buy and install. Read on to see the 10 reasons I finally kicked it out and what I have now replaced it with.</p>
<h2>My career in Wireless</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Actixlogohires-300x224.jpg" alt="" width="205" height="153" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Actixlogohires-300x224.jpg 300w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Actixlogohires-100x75.jpg 100w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Actixlogohires.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 205px) 100vw, 205px">Firstly let me explain that I spent most of my career in the wireless (mobile phone) industry and consider myself to have a reasonable degree of expertise in the field. The company I founded (<a href="http://www.actix.com/">http://www.actix.com</a>) has been a leading specialist in planning and optimising new wireless technologies for the past 25 years and has developed solutions for measurement and optimisation of everything from Analog to 5G.</p>
<p>Wireless technology is behind some of the most amazing developments of the last 50 years – things like the iPhone and satellite TV. So you may find it strange that I would be doubting the ability of a leading home-automation wireless technology to do something as straightforward as turning a light on and off. But unfortunately my experience has been exactly that.&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Z-Wave – The system I chose in 2012</h2>
<p>Back in 2012 I asked for recommendations from the people I knew who were Home Automation pioneers – not least <a href="https://www.devicepilot.com/about">Pilgrim Beart</a> (the founder of the Hive product <a href="https://www.hivehome.com/">https://www.hivehome.com</a> now owned by BG) and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quentin_Stafford-Fraser">Quentin Stafford-Fraser</a> (co-inventor of the webcam). The consensus around the time was that one of the wireless technologies already on the market would become the de-facto standard for domestic lighting control. That seemed pretty compelling as companies like <a href="https://aeotec.com/">AeoTech,</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.fibaro.com/en/">Fibaro</a>, Philips and LightwaveRF were already producing wireless lighting systems including (in the first two instances) control modules that could be retro-fitted into the pattress (wall-box) behind a light switch.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-14-190552.png" alt="" width="172" height="145" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-14-190552.png 172w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-14-190552-100x84.png 100w" sizes="(max-width: 172px) 100vw, 172px"><img loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-14-190703-300x210.png" alt="" width="231" height="162" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-14-190703-300x210.png 300w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-14-190703-100x70.png 100w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screenshot-2020-11-14-190703.png 753w" sizes="(max-width: 231px) 100vw, 231px"></p>
<p>At that time there were essentially three main choices of wireless technology: <a href="https://www.z-wave.com/">Z-Wave</a>, <a href="https://lightwaverf.com/">LightwaveRF</a> and <a href="https://zigbeealliance.org/">ZigBee</a>. I discounted LightwaveRF as it was (still is?) very range limited and my house is an old one built almost entirely from large stone blocks (even internally) that are very good at blocking RF signals. Between Z-Wave and ZigBee there wasn’t much to choose from a wireless perspective but the decision was made for me when I looked at the manufacturer support for each technology. As mentioned above companies like AeoTech and Fibaro already had modules (devices that turn on/off or dim a circuit) on the market that I thought would be ideal for my lighting control system whereas such support for ZigBee was pretty much completely absent save a few hobbyist-level companies.</p>
<p>So I found a supplier (<a href="https://www.vesternet.com/">Vesternet</a> – who have been great by the way) and started ordering Z-Wave modules to try out. Fast-forward 18 months or so and I’d installed (with the help of a great electrician called Lorenzo) over 150 circuits with Z-Wave control. Many of the modules I installed in that period were Fibaro generation 1 dimmer and switch (relay) units. They had a few quirks but I found that if I bought the right LED lamps (mainly Philips ones) and used the balun that you can buy to compliment a Fibaro dimmer then I could get (relatively) flicker-free dimming wirelessly.</p>
<div id="attachment_1799"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1799" loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="397" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-300x225.jpg 300w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-768x576.jpg 768w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-100x75.jpg 100w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/20201114_201934-house-1184x888.jpg 1184w" sizes="(max-width: 529px) 100vw, 529px"></p><p id="caption-attachment-1799">Lorenzo is the guy on the roof harnessing the lightning. Picture by Rab (Ian or Yanny) Gamble.</p></div>
<p>Since Lorenzo was replacing most of the wiring in the house I managed to get him to bring a lot of the control cables together in around five separate locations. This simplified the task of adding devices and also helped me to keep track of the actual units. To this day I have a spreadsheet with around 500 lines (around 3 lines per circuit) which details all of the lighting circuits in the house, the circuit breaker they are connected to, the type of device that controls the circuit and its location. Unfortunately I wasn’t 100% successful in getting the control point of all the lighting circuits in one of these five locations and there are actually at least three units lost in the walls somewhere which respond to Z-Wave commands but don’t seem to control anything I can find!</p>
<h2>Z-Wave Hubs</h2>
<p>Having chosen a technology and the modules to turn things on and off (or dim them) the next step is to decide on a central hub or controller as all Z-Wave networks need one of those. At the time a popular one was called <a href="https://www.vesternet.com/pages/vera-controller-comparison">Vera</a> and I initially opted for that. It had a reasonably good way of overcoming one of the problems of Z-Wave (adding a new module requires the hub and the module to be close together) which came in the form of a battery box that could power the hub while you moved it around to add modules (the AeoTech Z-Stick has a similar feature). Unfortunately Vera also had a number of downsides – a limited API to allow it to be controlled by other systems, a non-working backup system that forgot what modules had been added and a slow processor which meant adding multiple modules took a stupidly long time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/FIB_HC2_01-300x78.png" alt="" width="300" height="78" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/FIB_HC2_01-300x78.png 300w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/FIB_HC2_01-768x201.png 768w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/FIB_HC2_01-100x26.png 100w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/FIB_HC2_01.png 795w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"><img loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/MCV_VERA_L-300x275.png" alt="" width="221" height="203" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/MCV_VERA_L-300x275.png 300w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/MCV_VERA_L-100x92.png 100w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/MCV_VERA_L.png 496w" sizes="(max-width: 221px) 100vw, 221px"></p>
<p>So began a waltz through a significant part of the available hub-landscape, taking in <a href="https://www.vesternet.com/products/z-wave-fibaro-home-center-2-system">Fibaro’s HC2 hub</a>, a Mac-based home automation app called <a href="https://www.indigodomo.com/">Indigo</a>, an open-source system called <a href="https://www.domoticz.com/">Domoticz</a> and finally <a href="https://www.home-assistant.io/">Home Assistant</a> (recommended by Quentin who I mentioned previously – did I tell you he co-invented the web-cam – I did – but I guess that’s cool enough to be mentioned twice – right?). Each has their own strengths and weaknesses but ultimately a lot of the problems I found with any of these systems came down to issues with Z-Wave itself and while my sashays from one to another sometimes gave me the impression of progress they generally just shifted the shadows around and left the underlying issues unresolved.</p>
<p>What did prove to be significant though was the hardware on which these systems are based. The Vera and Fibaro HC2 have their own hardware platforms which are not open and this gave me quite a bit of trouble as I tried to work though the failure concentration problem that I will attempt to explicate later. The Mac-based system was good in the sense that it was based on Mac hardware which I have found to be relatively reliable. However, it was, ironically, the failure of a Mac Mini which ultimately precipitated another switch that I had been mulling due to a lack of Z-Wave diagnostics.</p>
<p>The systems I moved to (Domoticz and then Home Assistant) were based on Raspberry Pi hardware and that has resulted in quite a few more problems – SD card corruption due to brown-outs, reboots at unfortunate times due to me attempting to automate system updates and hardware failure initiated by some circuit breaker issues I experienced.</p>
<h2>Reason 1: Z-Wave Pairing</h2>
<p>The process of adding a module to a Z-Wave network is to put the hub into “include” mode and then press a button on the module while it is close to the hub. That sounds simple enough but now imagine doing this for 150 modules scattered around a house, some behind wall-plates, others in waterproof boxes, concealed in ceilings, etc.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/z-wave-protocol-hacking-300x157.png" alt="" width="300" height="157" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/z-wave-protocol-hacking-300x157.png 300w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/z-wave-protocol-hacking-100x52.png 100w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/z-wave-protocol-hacking.png 728w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"></p>
<p>It was quite onerous to do it once but I think I’ve probably done it on average three times for every module in the house plus quite a few more times for modules that I’ve moved around, or have failed and had to be replaced. That’s getting on for 500 include processes. And that’s just to get the module visible to the system. Once it is included you generally have to locate the specific function(s) of the module you want to use (e.g. a motion sensor might have a temperature reading, a light-level and an alarm setting in addition to the motion detection function), then you give each function a name, then you need to indicate what room it is in, then you might want to group it with other module functions (so, for instance, a mood setting in the dining room sets the light levels on five different modules via a scene or group). All of that needs to be typed in and you will generally be doing this while wandering around, so you will do it on a laptop or tablet and sometimes up a ladder or in a cupboard.</p>
<p>I have now gotten to the stage where I dread some modules failing. The one that controls a water-feature in the garden is in a sealed box, the one that controls an out-door heater is in a small loft area that can only be accessed by a rickety ladder, the one for the guest-room extractor fan is in a crawl space, etc. This can’t be the right way to do things can it?</p>
<p>When I compare this to the way IT operations used to be compared to the way dev-ops is now I think it is fair to say that we are just at the start and that things must change. It used to be normal that an IT person would have to physically sit at a computer for hour on end to install OSes, applications and security. Now it is done remotely and automatically on predominantly virtualized hardware. Furthermore, most apps are now in the cloud and the management of the servers that run them are automated to the Nth degree. Home automation and IoT have a long way to go!</p>
<h2>Reason 2: Z-Wave Healing After Adding a Module</h2>
<p>As mentioned a common challenge with Z-Wave is that introducing a new module to the network requires the module and hub to be close together. This actually creates a lot of work. There are two main ways to handle this:</p>
<ol>
<li>bring the hub to the module once it is in-situ and operating</li>
<li>power the module up when it is close to the hub and then move it later</li>
</ol>
<p>Both options are problematic if you are relying on the mesh network capabilities to extend the range of the network because the mesh works by finding routes from one module to another so that it can communicate at distance.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ZWaveNetworkInfo-300x130.jpg" alt="" width="487" height="211" srcset="https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ZWaveNetworkInfo-300x130.jpg 300w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ZWaveNetworkInfo-100x43.jpg 100w, https://secureservercdn.net/160.153.137.170/onv.491.myftpupload.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ZWaveNetworkInfo.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 487px) 100vw, 487px"></p>
<p>In …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/">https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://robdobson.com/2020/11/the-10-reasons-i-ripped-out-a-6k-lighting-system/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25099615</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 09:24:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Git blame sucks for understanding WTF code (and what to use instead)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25098994">thread link</a>) | @stefanjudis
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://tekin.co.uk/2020/11/patterns-for-searching-git-revision-histories | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tekin.co.uk/2020/11/patterns-for-searching-git-revision-histories">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
    <p>You’re happily working your way through a codebase when you happen upon some code that makes you stop and think: What the…!? Maybe it’s a method that’s doing something surprising. Or perhaps it’s doing something completely unsurprising, it’s just doing it in a surprising way.</p>

<p><img src="https://tekin.co.uk/images/20201113/math-lady.jpg" alt=""></p>

<h2 id="git-blame-to-the-rescue">Git blame to the rescue?</h2>

<p>When this happens you might instinctively reach for <code>git blame</code> to help you figure out what’s going on. After all, <code>git blame</code> gives you the commit that most recently touched the line, and often that’s enough to point you in the right direction. But often it isn’t and you’re none the wiser. That’s because:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>git blame is too coarse</strong>: it reports against the whole line. If the most recent change isn’t related to the part of the line you’re interested, you’re out of luck.</li>
  <li><strong>git blame is too shallow</strong>: it only reports a single change; the most recent one. The story of the particular piece of code you’re interested in may have evolved over several commits.</li>
  <li><strong>git blame is too narrow</strong>: it only considers the file you are running blame against. The code you are interested in may also appear in other files, but to get the relevant commits on those you’ll need to run blame several times.</li>
</ul>

<p>If you only use <code>git blame</code> you’re limiting yourself to a one-dimensional perspective of the code you’re trying to understand. Wouldn’t it be better to view things in 3D!?</p>

<h2 id="a-more-powerful-way-to-trace-the-history-of-wtf-code">A more powerful way to trace the history of WTF code</h2>

<p>Thankfully Git has some pretty powerful search tools built right in. Let’s take a closer look at some of the tools at our disposal.</p>

<h2 id="find-all-commits-containing-a-particular-piece-code">Find all commits containing a particular piece code</h2>

<p>If <code>git blame</code> is entry-level history search, <code>git log -S</code> (also known as “the pickaxe”) is how you take things to the next level. It lets you search for all commits that contain a given string:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>git log <span>-S</span> <span>"method_name"</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This will return all the commits that contain <code>method_name</code> across the entire repository, giving you a bespoke history of a piece of code across both multiple commits and files. You can use the pickaxe to examine the entire history of a particular snippet: all the places it’s been used; how it’s usage has changed; if it’s moved file; when it was first introduced, and more.</p>

<h2 id="see-the-diffs-alongside-the-commit-messages">See the diffs alongside the commit messages</h2>

<p>If you include the <code>-p</code> option (short for <code>--patch</code>) you get the full diff alongside the commit messages, giving you even more context and making it easier to spot the relevant changes:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ git log -S "method_name" -p
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="find-the-commit-that-first-added-some-code">Find the commit that first added some code</h2>

<p>Say you want to find the first commit that introduced a particular class, method or snippet of code. You can use the pickaxe combined with the <code>--reverse</code> option to get the commits in reverse-chronological order so the commit where the code first appears is listed at the top:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ git log -S "method_name" -p --reverse
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="find-when-a-piece-of-code-was-deleted">Find when a piece of code was deleted</h2>

<p>Because the pickaxe search finds both additions and deletions, you can even use it to find code that has since been deleted:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ git log -S "deleted code" -p
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Assuming the snippet no longer exists in the codebase the first commit returned will be the one where it was removed.</p>

<h2 id="limit-the-scope-of-the-search">Limit the scope of the search</h2>

<p>Because we’re using <code>git log</code> you can also provide a path to focus the search to a given file or folder:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ git log -S "some code" -p app/models/user.rb
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="search-deeper-with-a-regular-expression">Search deeper with a regular expression</h2>

<p>I mostly stick to the pickaxe because I find working with regular expressions cumbersome, but if you want to perform a more advanced search using a regular expression you can do so with <code>-G</code> instead:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ git log -G "REGEX HERE"
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It’s also worth noting that searching with <code>-S</code> has a subtle limitation that <code>-G</code> does not: <code>-S</code> only shows commits that either added or removed the search string. If the string you are searching for moved within the same file but was otherwise unchanged, <code>-S</code> won’t include that commit, whereas <code>-G</code> will.</p>

<h2 id="search-the-commit-messages-themselves">Search the commit messages themselves</h2>

<p>Sometimes searching for literal code is too narrow, or the information you’re after isn’t actually in the code but in the commit messages themselves. In which case you can use <code>--grep</code> to search commit messages instead:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ git log --grep "commit message search"
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="in-summary">In summary</h2>

<p>Next time some code has you puzzled and you want to understand more about it, look beyond <code>git blame</code> and dig deeper into the history using the pickaxe and friends:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Find the entire history of a snippet of code with <code>git log -S</code></li>
  <li>Include <code>-p</code> to see the diff as well as the commit messages</li>
  <li>Include <code>--reverse</code> to see the commit that introduced the code listed first</li>
  <li>Scope search to specific folders or files by including a path</li>
  <li>Search with a regular expression using <code>git log -G</code></li>
  <li>Search commit messages using <code>git log --grep</code></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="epilogue">Epilogue</h2>

<p>Of course searching a codebase’s history will only be fruitful if the history itself is helpful. If the history hasn’t been constructed with atomic commits that have useful commit messages, searching it will likely be a frustrating and unhelpful experience.</p>

<p>To learn more about the how and why of putting together more useful histories, check out <a href="https://tekin.co.uk/2019/02/a-talk-about-revision-histories">A Branch in Time (a talk about revision histories)</a>.</p>


  </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tekin.co.uk/2020/11/patterns-for-searching-git-revision-histories</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25098994</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 07:08:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Exercise Reduces Tumour Growth – and Now We Know the Cellular Basis for It]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25098779">thread link</a>) | @pvsukale3
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/cancer-recovery-exercise-cellular-basis-lactates-cd8-t-cells/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/cancer-recovery-exercise-cellular-basis-lactates-cd8-t-cells/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
										                <p><em>A superresolution image of a group of killer T-cells (green and red) surrounding a cancer cell (blue, centre). Image: US NIH.</em></p>
<p>On World Cancer Day this year, Tata Memorial Hospital in Mumbai, known in India for its cancer care facilities, <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/mumbai/exploring-new-options-in-cancer-care/article30729911.ece">announced</a> that it would study the <a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02161900">effects of yoga</a> on breast cancer patients. While the association between <a href="https://www.the-scientist.com/features/regular-exercise-helps-patients-combat-cancer-67317">exercise and recovery</a> in cancer patients has been known since the 1990s, we know little about how this works on a molecular level.</p>
<p>A <a href="https://elifesciences.org/articles/59996">new study</a> shows that the key might lie in activating certain immune cells. The study, conducted by Randall Johnson and his team from the Karolinska Institute in Stockholm, Sweden, and the University of Cambridge, was the culmination of three years of research on what makes exercise good for cancer patients.</p>


<p>They first established that exercise could indeed decrease the growth of tumours. They induced tumours in mice, mimicking breast cancer in humans, and separated them into two groups: one exercised on running wheels and one did not. After a few days, the tumours had shrunk in the group that exercised but not in the sedentary group.</p>
<p>When the researchers examined blood samples from the mice, two things had dramatically increased after exercise: immune cells known as CD8+ T-cells and a compound called lactic acid.</p>
<p>The team first looked into CD8+ T-cells, which <a href="https://www.the-scientist.com/news-analysis/the-ever-expanding-t-cell-world-a-primer-31123">defend against</a> tumours and infections. Did increased levels after exercise mean that the cells were involved in reducing tumour growth? To test this, the team removed CD8+ T-cells from tumour-bearing mice and then made them exercise. This time, exercising could not shrink the tumours: removing the T-cells also removed the positive effects of exercise.</p>
<p>“Then we did what, to my mind, is the coolest experiment in the paper,” said Johnson. They made mice exercise, carefully took CD8+ T-cells from them, and transplanted the cells into another set of mice that had tumours but didn’t exercise. To the scientists’ delight, simply transplanting CD8+ T-cells from mice that had exercised could shrink tumours in sedentary mice.</p>
<p>“The T-cells themselves are coming in ‘trained,’ making them better anti-tumour T-cells,” Johnson said.</p>
<p>What was ‘training’ the T-cells, though? That’s when the team turned their attention to lactic acid. After an intense bout of exercise, lactic acid is what makes your muscles feel like they’re burning. In the bloodstream, it circulates as lactate, its ionic form.</p>
<p>To mimic this form and the levels attained after exercise, the researchers injected sodium lactate into sedentary mice that had tumours. As with the T-cells, they found that daily injections of sodium lactate could shrink tumours and improve survival in these mice.</p>
<p>The team now knew that, through exercise, both lactate and CD8+ T-cells could reduce tumour growth. But this still didn’t explain how the two effects were linked.</p>
<p>To answer this, the scientists first checked whether lactate could independently activate CD8+ T-cells – and found that it could. Next, they again injected mice with lactate, only this time they removed the CD8+ T-cells from the mice. Without the T-cells, lactate injections could no longer lessen tumour growth.</p>
<p>“This shows that it’s really the lactate affecting the T-cells and helping them achieve a better anti-tumour effect,” Johnson said.</p>
<p><ins>Also read: <a href="https://science.thewire.in/health/why-everyone-around-you-seems-to-be-getting-cancer/">Why Everyone Around You Seems to Be Getting Cancer</a></ins></p>
<p>The study fills an important gap in our understanding of how exercise and the related metabolite changes boost anti-tumour the activities of our immune cells.</p>
<p>This said, “My main concern is that people should not think that only exercise can cure cancer,” S.V. Chiplunkar, a former director of the Advanced Centre for Treatment, Research and Education in Cancer, Mumbai, and current head of its Cancer Immunology and Immunotherapy division, cautioned.</p>
<p>“A combination of immunotherapy with supervised exercise or yoga regimens may yield significant benefits, but this needs to be tested in a randomised clinical trial.” Chiplunkar wasn’t involved in the study.</p>
<p>And as with any good study, this one spawned more questions than it answered. “Future studies should address how lactate levels are modulated in cancer patients/mice models in response [to] exercise,” Rajender Motiani, an assistant professor and DBT/Wellcome Trust India fellow at the Regional Centre for Biotechnology, Faridabad, said.</p>
<p>“A <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41591-019-0485-4">recent study</a> in elite athletes showed that lactate is utilised by a unique class of gut microbiome, enhancing endurance and performance. It would be worth examining gut microbiota changes in cancer patients in response to exercise.”</p>
<p>Johnson’s team is now working out how much exercise is needed to boost T-cell activity. For example, one question they’re asking is if one hour of intense exercise could be better than two hours of light exercise.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Helene Rundqvist, the study’s lead author, has been involved in a <a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02522260?term=exercise&amp;cond=Breast+Cancer&amp;cntry=SE&amp;city=Stockholm&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1">clinical trial</a> assessing the effects of exercise on breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. The trial is still active and expected to be completed in 2022.</p>
<p><em>Sruthi Balakrishnan is a Bangalore-based science writer who is intrigued by all things biological.</em></p>
<!-- AI CONTENT END 1 -->
																												              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://science.thewire.in/the-sciences/cancer-recovery-exercise-cellular-basis-lactates-cd8-t-cells/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25098779</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 06:23:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On Taking Criticism]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25098585">thread link</a>) | @WoodenChair
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-4608430843265935994">
<p>I am what I would call a non-famous public person. What do I mean by that? I mean that I have jobs where people publicly review my work. As a college instructor, I receive student reviews. Some of them get read internally at our school, and some of them get posted publicy. And they’re attached to my name. They’re not some product where people might just know my company or my brand. They know <em>me</em>, and they’re reviewing <em>me</em>. As an author, my books get reviewed. Some of those reviews are by editors and official reviewers internal to the publisher. Some of those reviews are by email. But most of those reviews are posted online. As a software developer and hobbyist podcaster I also get public reviews.</p>

<p>To anyone in a personalized creative field who cares deeply about their work, bad reviews hurt. It’s not just about being sensitive (although I am sensitive and that doesn’t help). It’s that when you really pour your heart into something, as I do my teaching for example, then the product is an extension of you. Nobody would deny that the way a class or a book turns out is an extension of the personality, knowledge, and ability of the teacher/author. And when the product is criticized, it’s like you are being criticized. </p>

<p>My dad, who was also a college instructor, and the producer of nine books and nine instructional videos among many other public creative ventures, had a very thin skin. He couldn’t stand me reading him a bad review. That stuck with me. This very accomplished man, couldn’t stand even a little criticism. When I get too sensitive, I try to remember how his inability to accept criticism hurt some of his products. He was much more about getting things done than doing them perfectly. If he had a little bit more of a perfectionist streak in him, he would have done even better. But maybe he would have done less…</p>

<p>It doesn’t matter if I receive eighteen great reviews for a class. It’s the words of the two bad reviews that stick with me. And do you know why? <em>Because almost always there’s a kernel of truth to those reviews.</em> Does that mean we should listen to them? Well if I only listened to the bad reviews, I would never produce anything. I would just stay in bed. The fact is the people who are getting no bad reviews, are the people who are not taking the risk of putting themselves out there. So, we have to not let ourselves get so discouraged that we stop producing. And we have to remember that while we may not have served those two students well, we may have served those other eighteen students better than they would have been served in a world without us teaching them. </p>

<p>We can’t please every student or every customer. Nothing that gets watched/read by more than a few people is going to be liked by all of them. Even Mother Theresa would get a downvote on YouTube. So, if we’re serving the majority, we don’t want to let the critiques of a few steer us in the wrong direction.</p>

<p>On the other hand, being like my dad is dangerous too. <strong>No, the customer is not always right. But usually the customer has a point. We have to always be working to get better.</strong> Because we’re not perfect, and there’s always room for improvement. <strong>And we need to read those bad reviews to find those spaces for improvement.</strong> It doesn’t mean they’re right, but it does mean we need to think about them.</p>

<p>My dad accomplished an amazing amount. If he let those bad reviews slow him down too much, it’s very possible he would have not accomplished as much. But if he could have found a few tweaks, a few changes, to serve a few customers better, well then he could have grown through them. I want to grow, but I also don’t want to stop. So, I can’t let the reviews get me too down, but I have to read them.</p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.observationalhazard.com/2020/11/on-taking-criticism_15.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25098585</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 05:39:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[VMAF, PSNR, SSIM calculation using FFmpeg]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25098434">thread link</a>) | @ponderingfish
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://ottverse.com/calculate-psnr-vmaf-ssim-using-ffmpeg/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ottverse.com/calculate-psnr-vmaf-ssim-using-ffmpeg/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><strong>In this article, let’s learn to compute VMAF, PSNR, and SSIM using FFmpeg. While working on videos (compression or post-processing), it is common to compute objective metrics in addition to doing subjective Visual Quality testing. If you are using FFmpeg in your workflow, it is very easy to compute these metrics instead of purchasing expensive tools. </strong></p>



<p>Let’s go ahead and take a look at these metrics and how they are computed, shall we?</p>



<hr>



<h2>What is VMAF?</h2>



<p><strong><a href="https://github.com/Netflix/vmaf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VMAF from Netflix</a></strong>&nbsp;stands for Video Multi-method Assessment Fusion, and it is a video quality metric that combines human vision modeling with machine learning. It’s become very popular as it succeeds (not fully) at automating subjective quality testing that usually requires humans to watch and score videos.</p>



<p>FFmpeg and Netflix’s VMAF are now part of every video processing and compression engineer’s toolbox. To understand how to install VMAF, please read our “<a href="https://ottverse.com/vmaf-ffmpeg-ubuntu-compilation-installation-usage-guide/">VMAF Installation</a>” article.</p>



<hr>



<h2>How to Compute VMAF using FFmpeg</h2>



<p>Let’s look at a couple of ways of computing VMAF. </p>



<p><strong>If your source and destination videos are of the same dimensions (height and width)</strong>, then you can directly compute the VMAF value using the command line below. </p>



<p>All you need to do is point FFmpeg to the location of the VMAF model file and it will do the rest. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i videoToCompare.mp4 -i originalVideo.mp4 -lavfi libvmaf="model_path=vmaf_v0.6.1.pkl":log_path=vmaf_logfile.txt -f null -</code></pre>



<p><strong>However, in case the source and destination videos are not of the same resolution, then you have to ensure that the destination is brought to the same resolution as the source video before computing VMAF</strong>.</p>



<p>Here is a simple one-liner that uses the <code>filter_complex</code> to do the resolution change and then computes the VMAF value. I have used the <code>bicubic</code> filter to do the up/down scaling. </p>



<pre><code><code>bin/ffmpeg -i test_720p30.mp4 -i test_1080p30.mp4 -filter_complex "[0:v]scale=1920x1080:flags=bicubic[main]; [1:v]scale=1920x1080:flags=bicubic,format=pix_fmts=yuv420p,fps=fps=30/1[ref]; \</code>
<code>[main][ref]libvmaf=psnr=true:log_path=vmaflog.json:log_fmt=json" \</code>
<code>-f null -</code></code></pre>



<p>The log file that is produced by the VMAF computation is very comprehensive. It provides a frame-wise score of VMAF and its constituent metrics, along with the aggregate score (if that’s all you are looking for). </p>



<p>Here is an example of the VMAF file. </p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="205" src="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1024%2C205&amp;ssl=1" alt="VMAF using FFMpeg" srcset="https://889329.smushcdn.com/2063466/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?size=240x48&amp;lossy=1&amp;strip=1&amp;webp=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=300%2C60&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://889329.smushcdn.com/2063466/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?size=480x96&amp;lossy=1&amp;strip=1&amp;webp=1 480w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=768%2C154&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://889329.smushcdn.com/2063466/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?size=960x192&amp;lossy=1&amp;strip=1&amp;webp=1 960w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1024%2C205&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1200%2C240&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1536%2C307&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?w=1771&amp;ssl=1 1771w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-srcset="https://889329.smushcdn.com/2063466/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?size=240x48&amp;lossy=1&amp;strip=1&amp;webp=1 240w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=300%2C60&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://889329.smushcdn.com/2063466/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?size=480x96&amp;lossy=1&amp;strip=1&amp;webp=1 480w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=768%2C154&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://889329.smushcdn.com/2063466/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?size=960x192&amp;lossy=1&amp;strip=1&amp;webp=1 960w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1024%2C205&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1200%2C240&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1536%2C307&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?w=1771&amp;ssl=1 1771w" data-src="https://i2.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/vmaf-1.png?resize=1024%2C205&amp;ssl=1" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></figure>



<hr>



<h2>What is PSNR and How Is It Calculated?</h2>



<p>From Wikipedia, </p>



<p><em><strong>Peak signal-to-noise ratio, often abbreviated&nbsp;PSNR, is an engineering term for the ratio between the maximum possible power of a&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Signal_(information_theory)" target="_blank" rel="noopener">signal</a>&nbsp;and the power of corrupting&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noise" target="_blank" rel="noopener">noise</a>&nbsp;that affects the fidelity of its representation.&nbsp;</strong></em></p>



<p>So, for a video, you are essentially trying to compute how much noise or pixel corruption has been introduced due to the video compression process which is essentially lossy (mainly due to Quantization). </p>



<p>The first step is to compute the Mean Squared Error or MSE. The formula is shown below where I and K represent the original and destination images respectively and <code>m</code> and <code>n</code> are the height and width of the images respectively. </p>



<p><img src="https://wikimedia.org/api/rest_v1/media/math/render/svg/3a34719b4f391dba26b3e8e4460b7595d62eece4" alt="{\mathit  {MSE}}={\frac  {1}{m\,n}}\sum _{{i=0}}^{{m-1}}\sum _{{j=0}}^{{n-1}}[I(i,j)-K(i,j)]^{2}"></p>



<p>Once you have the MSE, you can compute the PSNR using the formula shown below. </p>



<p><img src="https://wikimedia.org/api/rest_v1/media/math/render/svg/fc22801ed1232ff1231c4156b589de5c32063a8a" alt="{\begin{aligned}{\mathit  {PSNR}}&amp;=10\cdot \log _{{10}}\left({\frac  {{\mathit  {MAX}}_{I}^{2}}{{\mathit  {MSE}}}}\right)\\&amp;=20\cdot \log _{{10}}\left({\frac  {{\mathit  {MAX}}_{I}}{{\sqrt  {{\mathit  {MSE}}}}}}\right)\\&amp;=20\cdot \log _{{10}}\left({{\mathit  {MAX}}_{I}}\right)-10\cdot \log _{{10}}\left({{{\mathit  {MSE}}}}\right)\end{aligned}}"></p>



<p>Here,&nbsp;<em>MAX<sub>I</sub></em>&nbsp;is the maximum possible pixel value of the image. When the pixels are represented using 8 bits per sample, this is 255. </p>



<h2>How to Calculate PSNR using FFmpeg?</h2>



<p>You don’t have to go through all those calculations while using FFmpeg. All you need to do use the filter module <code>lavfi</code> and tell it to compute the PSNR. That’s it. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i videoToCompare.mp4 -i originalVideo.mp4 -lavfi psnr=stats_file=psnr_logfile.txt -f null -</code></pre>



<p>FFmpeg will print the average PSNR on the console while the log file will contain a frame-wise list of the MSE and the PSNR for the Luma and Chroma planes (y, u, and v). An example is shown below – </p>



<pre><code>n:1 mse_avg:54.96 mse_y:72.51 mse_u:27.98 mse_v:11.74 psnr_avg:30.73 psnr_y:29.53 psnr_u:33.66 psnr_v:37.43 
 n:2 mse_avg:69.70 mse_y:93.80 mse_u:31.01 mse_v:12.02 psnr_avg:29.70 psnr_y:28.41 psnr_u:33.22 psnr_v:37.33 
 n:3 mse_avg:72.74 mse_y:98.37 mse_u:31.02 mse_v:11.96 psnr_avg:29.51 psnr_y:28.20 psnr_u:33.21 psnr_v:37.35 
 n:4 mse_avg:73.11 mse_y:98.94 mse_u:31.14 mse_v:11.76 psnr_avg:29.49 psnr_y:28.18 psnr_u:33.20 psnr_v:37.43 </code></pre>



<hr>



<h2>How to Calculate SSIM using FFmpeg?</h2>



<p>Finally, let’s take a look at computing SSIM using FFmpeg. Again looking at the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Structural_similarity" target="_blank" rel="noopener">definition of SSIM</a>, </p>



<p><em><strong>The&nbsp;structural similarity&nbsp;index measure&nbsp;(SSIM) is a method for predicting the perceived quality of digital television and cinematic pictures, as well as other kinds of digital images and videos. SSIM is used for measuring the similarity between two images. The SSIM index is a&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Video_quality#Classification_of_objective_video_quality_metrics" target="_blank" rel="noopener">full reference metric</a>; in other words, the measurement or prediction of&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image_quality" target="_blank" rel="noopener">image quality</a>&nbsp;is based on an initial uncompressed or distortion-free image as reference.</strong></em></p>



<p>Calculating SSIM using FFmpeg is very similar to calcuating PSNR. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg.exe -i videoToCompare.mp4 -i originalVideo.mp4 -lavfi ssim=stats_file=ssim_logfile.txt -f null -</code></pre>



<p>The output of this command is going to look like this – </p>



<pre><code>[Parsed_ssim_0 @ 0000029c82894300] SSIM Y:0.926845 (11.357537) U:0.876798 (9.093807) V:0.860658 (8.559193) All:0.907472 (10.337287)</code></pre>



<p>And the log file will give you information on the SSIM values for each of the planes (Y, U, and V) along with the aggregate for each of the frames of the video. </p>



<pre><code> n:1 Y:0.930033 U:0.926453 V:0.913508 All:0.926682 (11.347897)
 n:2 Y:0.919140 U:0.915343 V:0.910900 All:0.917134 (10.816226)
 n:3 Y:0.922417 U:0.915795 V:0.910959 All:0.919404 (10.936853)
 n:4 Y:0.920077 U:0.916443 V:0.912994 All:0.918291 (10.877300)
 n:5 Y:0.926438 U:0.927597 V:0.917905 All:0.925209 (11.261518)
 n:6 Y:0.920619 U:0.919988 V:0.918780 All:0.920207 (10.980375)</code></pre>



<hr>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>That’s it folks – now you know how to calculate three very important objective metrics for video quality evaluation — PSNR, VMAF, and SSIM. By computing all three and using them for analysis, it’s hard to be thrown off by artifacts that one metric can catch and the other can’t. </p>



<p>And like always, do spend a few minutes doing some visual testing (subjective) after you’re done with the objective scores! </p>



<p>If you enjoyed this post, do check out the rest of<a href="https://ottverse.com/category/ffmpeg/"> <strong>OTTVerse’s FFmpeg tutorials</strong></a> to learn more about how to use FFmpeg to improve your video editing, compression, and processing skills!</p>

<!-- MOLONGUI AUTHORSHIP PLUGIN 4.2.9 -->
<!-- https://www.molongui.com/authorship/ -->

<div id="mab-8281560925" data-plugin-release="4.2.9" data-plugin-version="free" data-box-layout="slim" data-box-position="below" data-multiauthor="false" data-author-type="user" itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person">

	
    <!-- Author headline -->
    <p>
        <h3>
            <span>About The Author</span>
        </h3>
    </p>

    <div>

        <div data-profile-layout="layout-1" data-author-ref="user-194568617">
            
<!-- End of .m-a-box-content-top -->

<div>

    <!-- Author picture -->
    
	<p><a href="https://ottverse.com/author/vkr2020/">
                    <img src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1b73140b34f836d184d53fbb00f406dd?s=150&amp;d=mp&amp;r=g" width="150" height="150" alt="Avatar" data-lazy-src="https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/1b73140b34f836d184d53fbb00f406dd?s=150&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;d=mp&amp;r=g" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7">                </a>
                	</p>

    <!-- Author social -->
    
    <!-- Author data -->
    <div>

        <!-- Author name -->
        

        <!-- Author metadata -->
        

        <!-- Author bio -->
        
<div itemprop="description">
	<p>I’m Dr. Krishna Rao Vijayanagar, and I am the Founder and Editor of OTTVerse.com. I've spent several years working hands-on with Video Codecs (AVC, HEVC, MultiView Plus Depth), ABR streaming, and Video Analytics (QoE, Content &amp; Audience, and Ad). I hope to use my experience and love for video streaming to bring you information and insights into the OTT universe. Please use the Contact Page to get in touch with me.</p>
</div>

        
            <!-- Author related posts -->
            <!-- End of .m-a-box-related -->

        
    </div><!-- End of .m-a-box-data -->

</div><!-- End of .m-a-box-content-middle -->

<!-- End of .m-a-box-content-bottom -->        </div><!-- End of .m-a-box-profile -->

        
    </div><!-- End of .m-a-box-container -->

	
</div><!-- End of .m-a-box -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ottverse.com/calculate-psnr-vmaf-ssim-using-ffmpeg/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25098434</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 05:11:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why I teach vim]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 158 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25097788">thread link</a>) | @amichlin
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-124">

	

	
	<div>
		
<figure><a href="https://xkcd.com/378/"><img data-attachment-id="133" data-permalink="https://blog.ceos.io/real_programmers/" data-orig-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png" data-orig-size="740,406" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="real_programmers" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=740" src="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=740" alt="" srcset="https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png 740w, https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=150 150w, https://blogceosio.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/real_programmers.png?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"></a></figure>



<p>The why of why people use vim has been <a href="https://dev.to/iggredible/why-i-use-vim-2f40">covered fairly extensively</a>, so I thought I would spend a little time explaining why I <em>teach</em> vim to my high school students, even in 2020.</p>



<p>It all began when I was assigned a mixed class of ninth through twelfth grade students in computer science just after the financial collapse on 2008. Well, the financial collapse first brought me to teach Intro to Programming using VB 6.0 and Windows thin clients, which was an experience unto itself (thanks in part to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conficker">Conficker virus</a>). That experience is worth a separate blog post and is a good part of why one of my specialties is teaching computer security.</p>



<p>So here I am with all levels of student, including AP CS A (read: AP CS Java), and obsolete Windows PCs (at least the thin clients were gone). I couldn’t install any software, wanted to teach C, had to teach Java, and had very few options (these were the days before online web based IDEs).</p>



<p>I had experience with the UNIX command line, primarily Sun Workstations, thanks to my wonderful education at <a href="https://www.soe.ucsc.edu/departments/computer-science-and-engineering">UCSC</a>, so that wasn’t an issue. I had played with Linux in the 1990s to a bit of success, but hadn’t touched it for almost a decade. So I found an old Pentium 2 carcass in the the garbage outside my condo complex, installed a hard drive, and tried this new (to me) flavor of Linux called, strangely, <a href="https://ubuntu.com/">Ubuntu</a>.</p>



<p>I quickly realized this machine could have all the students coding at one, discovered the wonder that is <a href="https://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/latest.html">putty.exe</a> (it doesn’t require any installation to run!) to connect the obsolete PCs to the server and soon my students were off and coding.</p>



<p>Why did I teach them vim? I wish I could say I agonized over all the options at the time and decided vim was the best pedagogical solution, but the reality of the situation was that vi was what I used in college because my father taught me vi. You see, I am lucky to have a father who worked in the industry and is even somewhat of a <a href="https://www.bell-labs.com/usr/dmr/www/qed.html">footnote in text editor history</a>. So I taught vi (later vim) because it is what I knew. A running theme in many computer science teacher’s trials by fire… teaching something because it is what they know. I will go as far as to argue that it is more important that the teacher knows the editor, and especially the programming language, rather than assigning any importance to one correct editor or one correct language that all teachers should teach.</p>



<p>Years later, though, I still teach vim and the command line. So here is how I justify my decision, even if only to myself.</p>



<p>It just works. Every time I go to a new school, it takes time to get the software installed necessary to run IDEs. I remember walking into one school in which the AP CS A class was flailing away with Eclipse on Mac OS X because the students needed, and didn’t have, administrator access. I have an amazing tech department at my current job, but even here it took us weeks to figure out how to deploy Visual Studio Code on the student’s MacBook Airs and then we had to figure out how to deploy Python3 and Java. So there’s no confusion, I teach vim along with many IDEs and I fully believe it is my responsibility to teach multiple platforms and multiple IDEs, but the CLI and vim are always my safety net.</p>



<p>My students can program in any number of of languages on a now cloud based CLI Linux machine (thank you <a href="https://www.linode.com/">Linode</a> and <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a> – both of whom offer a $5/month plan – just. happy customer!). By using the CLI, I can support literally any type of computer connecting (including iPads, although the lack of a virtual esc key drives me batty as a vim user, and <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/secure-shell-app/pnhechapfaindjhompbnflcldabbghjo?hl=en">ChromeBooks</a>). Students can connect from anywhere in the world and things just work. All of this became infinitely important in the remote and hybrid learning experience of the pandemic. And this is all possible because the students use vim.</p>



<p>I keep track of as many of my students that major in CS and a running theme is they all profusely thank me for teaching them vim and the CLI. Too many colleges start CS1 with an IDE and then throw the CS2 students into the deep end with the CLI. Not everyone is as lucky as I was in regards to having a father well versed in the CLI.</p>



<p>And yes, there are online IDEs these days, but I’ve found those to be full of their own pitfalls, privacy issues, and costs and find doing any advanced work using them to be very difficult if not impossible.</p>



<p>Also, to be clear, both nano and Emacs work quite well in the context of CLI Linux and I don’t make any claim that teachers should use vim over those equally acceptable command line text editors except for one small argument. Most people agree, computer security pretty much requires knowledge of the command line and a text editor. I always tell my students that the one editor they are likely to find already installed on a machine is vim and it is a bad day when you have to install another editor. Maybe just an issue for students interested in ethical penetration testing…</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.ceos.io/2020/11/14/why-i-teach-vim/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25097788</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 02:50:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Going Bark: A Furry’s Guide to End-to-End Encryption]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25097177">thread link</a>) | @ciarannolan
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			
<p>Governments are back on their anti-encryption bullshit again.</p>



<p>Between the <a href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2020/03/06/earn-it-is-an-attack-on-encryption/">U.S. Senate’s “EARN IT” Act</a>, the <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/10/orders-top-eus-timetable-dismantling-end-end-encryption">E.U.’s slew of anti-encryption proposals</a>, and <a href="https://fee.org/articles/australia-s-unprecedented-encryption-law-is-a-threat-to-global-privacy/">Australia’s new anti-encryption law</a>, it’s become clear that the authoritarians in office view online privacy as a threat to their existence.</p>



<p>Normally, when the governments increase their anti-privacy sabre-rattling, technologists start talking more loudly about Tor, Signal, and other privacy technologies (usually only to be drowned out by paranoid people who think Tor and Signal are government backdoors or something stupid; conspiracy theories ruin everything!).</p>



<p><strong>I’m not going to do that.</strong></p>



<p>Instead, I’m going to show you how to add end-to-end encryption to any communication software you’re developing. (Hopefully, I’ll avoid making <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/10/28/bizarre-design-choices-in-zooms-end-to-end-encryption/">any bizarre design decisions</a> along the way.)</p>



<p>But first, some important disclaimers:</p>



<ol><li><strong>Yes, you should absolutely do this.</strong> I don’t care how banal your thing is; if you expect people to use it to communicate with each other, you should make it so that you can never decrypt their communications.</li><li>You should absolutely NOT bill the thing you’re developing as an <em>alternative</em> to Signal or WhatsApp.</li><li>The goal of doing this is to increase the amount of end-to-end encryption deployed on the Internet that the service operator cannot decrypt (even if compelled by court order) and make E2EE normalized. The goal is NOT to compete with highly specialized and peer-reviewed privacy technology.</li><li>I am not a lawyer, I’m some furry who works in cryptography. The contents of this blog post is not legal advice, nor is it endorsed by any company or organization. Ask the <a href="https://eff.org/">EFF</a> for legal questions.</li></ol>



<p>The organization of this blog post is as follows: First, I’ll explain <a href="#symmetric-key-encryption">how to encrypt and decrypt data between users</a>, assuming you have a key. Next, I’ll explain <a href="#key-agreement">how to build an authenticated key exchange</a> and <a href="#session-key-management">a ratcheting protocol to determine the keys used in the first step</a>. Afterwards, I’ll explore <a href="#identity-key-management">techniques for binding authentication keys to identities and managing trust</a>. Finally, I’ll discuss <a href="#backdoor-resistance">strategies for making it impractical to ever backdoor your software (and impossible to silently backdoor it)</a>, just to piss <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_Eyes">the creeps and tyrants of the world</a> off even more.</p>



<p>You don’t have to implement the full stack of solutions to protect users, but the further you can afford to go, the safer your users will be from privacy-invasive policing.</p>







<h2 id="preliminaries">Preliminaries</h2>



<h3 id="choosing-a-cryptography-library">Choosing a Cryptography Library</h3>



<p>In the examples contained on this page, I will be using the <a href="https://libsodium.gitbook.io/doc/">Sodium cryptography library</a>. Specifically, my example code will be written with the <a href="https://github.com/paragonie/sodium-plus">Sodium-Plus</a> library for JavaScript, since it strikes a good balance between performance and being cross-platform.</p>


<pre title="">const { SodiumPlus } = require('sodium-plus');

(async function() {
     // Select a backend automatically
     const sodium = await SodiumPlus.auto();
     
     // Do other stuff here
})();
</pre>


<p>Libsodium is <a href="https://latacora.micro.blog/2018/04/03/cryptographic-right-answers.html">generally the correct choice for developing cryptography features in software</a>, and is available in most programming languages,</p>



<p>If you’re prone to choose a different library, you should consult your cryptographer (and yes, you should have one on your payroll if you’re doing things different) about your design choices.</p>



<h3>Threat Modelling</h3>



<p>Remember above when I said, “You don’t have to implement the full stack of solutions to protect users, but the further you can afford to go, the safer your users will be from privacy-invasive policing”?</p>



<p>How far you go in implementing the steps outlined on this blog post should be informed by <a href="https://adamcaudill.com/2016/07/20/threat-modeling-for-applications/">a threat model</a>, not an ad hoc judgment.</p>



<p>For example, if you’re encrypting user data and storing it in the cloud, you probably want to pass <a href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2012/04/05/icloud-who-holds-key/">the Mud Puddle Test</a>:</p>



<blockquote><div><p>1. First, drop your device(s) in a mud puddle.<br>2. Next, slip in said puddle and crack yourself on the head. When you regain consciousness you’ll be perfectly fine, but<em>&nbsp;won’t for the life of you&nbsp;</em>be able to&nbsp;recall your device passwords or keys.<br>3. Now try to get your cloud data back.</p><p>Did you succeed? If so, you’re screwed. Or to be a bit less dramatic, I should say: your cloud provider has access to your ‘encrypted’ data, as does the government if they want it, as does any rogue employee who knows their way around your provider’s internal policy checks.</p></div><cite>Matthew Green describes the Mud Puddle Test, which Apple products <a href="https://sneak.berlin/20201112/your-computer-isnt-yours/">definitely don’t pass</a>.</cite></blockquote>



<p>If you must fail the Mud Puddle Test for your users, make sure you’re clear and transparent about this in the documentation for your product or service.</p>







<h2 id="symmetric-key-encryption">I. Symmetric-Key Encryption</h2>



<p>The easiest piece of this puzzle is to encrypt data in transit between both ends (thus, satisfying the loosest definition of end-to-end encryption).</p>



<p>At this layer, you already have some kind of symmetric key to use for encrypting data before you send it, and for decrypting it as you receive it.</p>



<p>For example, the following code will encrypt/decrypt strings and return hexadecimal strings with a version prefix.</p>


<pre title="">const VERSION = "v1";

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function encryptData(message, key, assocData = null) {
    const nonce = await sodium.randombytes_buf(24);
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': VERSION,
      'nonce': await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce),
      'extra': assocData
    });

    const encrypted = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_encrypt(
        message,
        nonce,
        key,
        aad
    );
    return (
       VERSION +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce) +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(encrypted)
    );
}

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function decryptData(encrypted, key, assocData = null) {
    const ver = encrypted.slice(0, 2);
    if (!await sodium.sodium_memcmp(ver, VERSION)) {
        throw new Error("Incorrect version: " + ver);
    }
    const nonce = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(2, 50));
    const ciphertext = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(50));
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': ver,
      'nonce': encrypted.slice(2, 50),
      'extra': assocData
    });
    
    const plaintext = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_decrypt(
        ciphertext,
        nonce,
        key,
        aad
    );
    return plaintext.toString('utf-8');
}
</pre>


<p>Under-the-hood, this is using <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/07/12/comparison-of-symmetric-encryption-methods/#aes-gcm-vs-xchacha20poly1305">XChaCha20-Poly1305</a>, which is less sensitive to timing leaks than AES-GCM. However, like AES-GCM, this encryption mode doesn’t provide <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/016">message- or key-commitment</a>.</p>



<p>If you want key commitment, you should derive two keys from <code>$key</code> using a KDF based on hash functions: One for actual encryption, and the other <a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1153">as a key commitment value</a>.</p>



<p>If you want message commitment, you can use AES-CTR + HMAC-SHA256 or XChaCha20 + BLAKE2b-MAC.</p>



<p>If you want both, ask <a href="https://mumble.net/~campbell/">Taylor Campbell</a> about his BLAKE3-based design.</p>



<p>A modified version of the above code with key-commitment might look like this:</p>


<pre title="">const VERSION = "v2";

/**
 * Derive an encryption key and a commitment hash.
 * @param {CryptographyKey} key
 * @param {Uint8Array} nonce
 * @returns {{encKey: CryptographyKey, commitment: Uint8Array}}
 */
async function deriveKeys(key, nonce) {
    const encKey = new CryptographyKey(await sodium.crypto_generichash(
        new Uint8Array([0x01].append(nonce)),
        key
    ));
    const commitment = await sodium.crypto_generichash(
        new Uint8Array([0x02].append(nonce)),
        key
    );
    return {encKey, commitment};
}

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function encryptData(message, key, assocData = null) {
    const nonce = await sodium.randombytes_buf(24);
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': VERSION,
      'nonce': await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce),
      'extra': assocData
    });
    const {encKey, commitment} = await deriveKeys(key, nonce);

    const encrypted = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_encrypt(
        message,
        nonce,
        encKey,
        aad
    );
    return (
       VERSION +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(nonce) +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(commitment) +
       await sodium.sodium_bin2hex(encrypted)
    );
}

/**
 * @param {string|Uint8Array} message
 * @param {Uint8Array} key
 * @param {string|null} assocData
 * @returns {string}
 */
async function decryptData(encrypted, key, assocData = null) {
    const ver = encrypted.slice(0, 2);
    if (!await sodium.sodium_memcmp(ver, VERSION)) {
        throw new Error("Incorrect version: " + ver);
    }
    const nonce = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(2, 50));
    const ciphertext = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(114));
    const aad = JSON.stringify({
      'version': ver,
      'nonce': encrypted.slice(2, 50),
      'extra': assocData
    });
    const storedCommitment = await sodium.sodium_hex2bin(encrypted.slice(50, 114));
    const {encKey, commitment} = await deriveKeys(key, nonce);
    if (!(await sodium.sodium_memcmp(storedCommitment, commitment))) {
        throw new Error("Incorrect commitment value");
    }
    
    const plaintext = await sodium.crypto_aead_xchacha20poly1305_ietf_decrypt(
        ciphertext,
        nonce,
        encKey,
        aad
    );
    return plaintext.toString('utf-8');
}
</pre>


<p>Another design choice you might make is to encode ciphertext with base64 instead of hexadecimal. That doesn’t significantly alter the design here, but it does mean your decoding logic has to accommodate this.</p>



<p>You SHOULD version your ciphertexts, and include this in the AAD provided to your AEAD encryption mode. I used “v1” and “v2” as a version string above, but you can use your software name for that too.</p>



<h2 id="key-agreement">II. Key Agreement</h2>



<p>If …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/">https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://soatok.blog/2020/11/14/going-bark-a-furrys-guide-to-end-to-end-encryption/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25097177</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 01:12:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ask HN: Are you depressed?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 395 | Comments 461 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25096877">thread link</a>) | @pcbro141
<br/>
November 14, 2020 | http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
        
    
      
    
<section>
    
        <span>Asked</span>
    
    <span>
        <abbr title="11 15 2020 00:09:57 UTC" data-epoch="1605398997">Nov 15, 2020</abbr>
    </span>
    <p>
        <span>IP Duplication Checking</span>
        
    </p>
</section>  
    
   

    


    
   

    
      
    

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.strawpoll.me/22152225</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25096877</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:12:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
