<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 04:33:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 04:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A visual guide to SSH tunnels]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 66 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26053323">thread link</a>) | @brendanfalk
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="app"><section data-v-4fc16f31="" id="introduction"><div data-v-4fc16f31=""><nav data-v-4fc16f31=""><ul data-v-4fc16f31=""><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#introduction">Introduction</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#port-forwarding">Port forwarding</a><ul data-v-4fc16f31=""><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#local-port-forwarding">Local</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#remote-port-forwarding">Remote</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#dynamic-port-forwarding">Dynamic</a></li></ul></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#jump-hosts">Jump hosts</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#reliable-ssh-tunnels">Reliable SSH tunnels</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#more-examples">More examples</a></li><li data-v-4fc16f31=""><a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="#resources">Resources</a></li></ul></nav><p data-v-4fc16f31="">This page explains use cases and examples of SSH tunnels while visually presenting
the traffic flows. For example, here's a reverse tunnel that allows only users from
IP address 1.2.3.4 access to port 80 on the SSH client through an SSH server.</p><p data-v-4fc16f31="">SSH tunnels are encrypted TCP connections between SSH clients and servers
that allows traffic entering one side of the tunnel to transparently exit
through the other. While the term originally referred to tunnels using TUN/TAP virtual
network interfaces, it's commonly used to refer to SSH port forwarding nowadays.
Use cases include:</p><ul data-v-4fc16f31=""><li data-v-4fc16f31="">Providing encrypted channels for protocols that use plaintext</li><li data-v-4fc16f31="">Opening backdoors into private networks</li><li data-v-4fc16f31="">Bypassing firewalls</li></ul><p data-v-4fc16f31="">This page is a work-in-progress. Feel free to&nbsp;<a data-v-4fc16f31="" href="https://github.com/linrock/ssh-tunnels">suggest examples or corrections on Github</a></p></div></section><section data-v-47beec60="" id="port-forwarding"><div data-v-47beec60=""><header data-v-47beec60=""><h2 data-v-47beec60="">Port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-47beec60="">Forwards a port from one system (local or remote) to another</h3></header><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Local port forwarding</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">Local port forwarding allows you to forward traffic on the SSH client
to some destination through an SSH server. This lets you access
remote services over an encrypted connection as if they were local services.
Example use cases:</p><ul data-v-47beec60=""><li data-v-47beec60="">Accessing a remote service (redis, memcached, etc.) listening on internal IPs</li><li data-v-47beec60="">Locally accessing resources available on a private network</li><li data-v-47beec60="">Transparently proxying a request to a remote service</li></ul></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Remote port forwarding</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">Remote port forwarding allows you to forward traffic on an SSH server
to a destination through either the SSH client or another remote host.
This gives users on public networks access to resources on private networks.
Example use cases:</p><ul data-v-47beec60=""><li data-v-47beec60="">Making a local development server available over a public network</li><li data-v-47beec60="">Granting IP-restricted access to a remote resource on a private network</li></ul></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Dynamic port forwarding</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">Dynamic port forwarding opens a SOCKS proxy on the SSH client that lets
you forward TCP traffic through the SSH server to a remote host.</p></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">Forwarding from privileged ports</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">If you want to open a privileged port (ports 1-1023) to forward traffic, you'll
need to run SSH with superuser privileges on the system that opens the port.</p><p><code data-v-47beec60="">sudo ssh -L 80:example.com:80 ssh-server</code></p></div><div data-v-47beec60=""><h4 data-v-47beec60="">SSH command-line flags</h4><p data-v-47beec60="">These are some useful SSH command-line flags when establishing tunnels</p><p><code data-v-47beec60="">-f
  # forks the ssh process into the background<br data-v-47beec60="">-n
  # prevents reading from STDIN<br data-v-47beec60="">-N
 # do not run remote commands. Used when only forwarding ports<br data-v-47beec60="">-T
 # disables TTY allocation</code></p><p data-v-47beec60="">Here's an example of a command you would run to create an SSH tunnel
in the background that forwards a local port through the ssh server.</p><p><code data-v-47beec60="">ssh -fnNT -L 127.0.0.1:8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-47beec60="">For brevity, the examples below will leave out these command-line
flags.</p></div></div></section><section data-v-42eeae9a="" id="local-port-forwarding"><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><header data-v-42eeae9a=""><h2 data-v-42eeae9a="">Local port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections from a port on a local system to a port on a remote host</h3></header><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L 127.0.0.1:8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections to 127.0.0.1:8080 on your local system
to port 80 on example.org through ssh-server. The traffic between your
local system and ssh-server is wrapped in an SSH tunnel,
but the traffic between ssh-server and example.org is not.
From the perspective of example.org the traffic originates from
ssh-server.</p></div><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L 8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L *:8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections to port 8080 on all interfaces on your local system
to example.org:80 through a tunnel to ssh-server.</p></div><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">ssh -L 192.168.0.1:5432:127.0.0.1:5432 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Forwards connections to 192.168.0.1:5432 on your local system to
127.0.0.1:5432 on ssh-server. Note that 127.0.0.1 here is localhost
from the viewpoint of ssh-server.</p></div><div data-v-42eeae9a=""><h4 data-v-42eeae9a="">SSH configurations</h4><p data-v-42eeae9a="">Make sure that TCP forwarding is enabled on the SSH server. By default it should be.</p><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">AllowTcpForwarding yes</code></p><p data-v-42eeae9a="">If you're forwarding ports on interfaces other than 127.0.0.1 then you'll
need to enable GatewayPorts on your local system, either within ssh_config or as
a command-line option</p><p><code data-v-42eeae9a="">GatewayPorts yes</code></p></div><h4 data-v-42eeae9a="">Use cases</h4><p data-v-42eeae9a="">If you want to use a secure connection to access a remote service
that communicates over plaintext. For example, redis and memcached
all use plaintext protocols. If you securely access one of these services
on a remote server over public networks, you can tunnel a connection
from your local system to the remote server instead of having it listen
over the public internet.</p></div></section><section data-v-63ab32db="" id="remote-port-forwarding"><div data-v-63ab32db=""><header data-v-63ab32db=""><h2 data-v-63ab32db="">Remote port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards a port on a remote system to another system</h3></header><div data-v-63ab32db=""><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">ssh -R 8080:localhost:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards traffic to all interfaces on port 8080 on ssh-server to
localhost port 80 on your local computer. If one of these interfaces is available
to the public internet, traffic connecting to port 8080 will be forwarded to your
local system.</p></div><div data-v-63ab32db=""><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">ssh -R 1.2.3.4:8080:localhost:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards traffic to ssh-server:8080 to localhost:80 on your local system
while only allowing access to the SSH tunnel entrance on ssh-server
from IP address 1.2.3.4. Use The GatewayPorts clientspecified directive
with this.</p></div><div data-v-63ab32db=""><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">ssh -R 8080:example.org:80 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Forwards traffic to all interfaces on ssh-server:8080 to localhost:80
on your local system. From your local system, traffic is then forwarded
to example.org:80. From the perspective of example.org the traffic
is originating from your local system.</p></div><div data-v-63ab32db=""><h4 data-v-63ab32db="">SSH server configuration</h4><p data-v-63ab32db="">By default, forwarded ports are not accessible to the public internet.
You'll need to add this to your sshd_config on your remote server to forward
public internet traffic to your local computer.</p><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">GatewayPorts yes</code></p><p data-v-63ab32db="">Or if you'd like to specify which clients are allowed access, you can use
the following in your sshd_config instead</p><p><code data-v-63ab32db="">GatewayPorts clientspecified</code></p></div></div></section><section data-v-7fa32086="" id="dynamic-port-forwarding"><div data-v-7fa32086=""><header data-v-7fa32086=""><h2 data-v-7fa32086="">Dynamic port forwarding</h2><h3 data-v-7fa32086="">Forward traffic from a range of ports to a remote server</h3></header><div data-v-7fa32086=""><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">ssh -D 3000 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-7fa32086="">Opens a SOCKS proxy on port 3000 of all interfaces on your local system.
This allows you to forward traffic sent through the proxy to the ssh-server
on any port or destination host. By default, SSH will use the SOCKS5 protocol,
which forwards TCP and UDP traffic.</p></div><div data-v-7fa32086=""><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">ssh -D 127.0.0.1:3000 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-7fa32086="">Opens a SOCKS proxy on 127.0.0.1:3000 on your local system.</p></div><p data-v-7fa32086="">When you have a SOCKS proxy running, you can configure your web browser
to use the proxy to access resources as if connections were originating
from ssh-server. For example, if ssh-server had access to other servers
within a private network, by using using a SOCKS proxy you could access
those other servers locally as if you were on the network, without needing
to set up a VPN.</p><div data-v-7fa32086=""><p data-v-7fa32086="">When you have a SOCKS proxy running, you can test it like so</p><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">curl -x socks5://127.0.0.1:12345 https://example.org</code></p></div><div data-v-7fa32086=""><h4 data-v-7fa32086="">SSH client configuration</h4><p data-v-7fa32086="">If you want the SOCKS proxy to be available to more interfaces than just
localhost, make sure to enable GatewayPorts on your local system.</p><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">GatewayPorts yes</code></p><p data-v-7fa32086="">Since GatewayPorts is being configured on the SSH client here, you can also 
configure it with a command-line option instead of ssh_config.</p><p><code data-v-7fa32086="">ssh -o GatewayPorts=yes -D 3000 ssh-server</code></p></div></div></section><section data-v-8405b8ce="" id="jump-hosts"><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><header data-v-8405b8ce=""><h2 data-v-8405b8ce="">Jump hosts and proxy commands</h2><h3 data-v-8405b8ce="">Transparently connecting to a remote host through intermediate hosts</h3></header><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -J user1@jump-host user2@remote-host</code><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -o "ProxyJump user1@jump-host" user2@remote-host</code></p><p data-v-8405b8ce="">Establishes an SSH connection with jump-host and forwards TCP traffic
to remote-host. Connecting to remote-host through an intermediate jump-host.
The above command should work out of the box if jump-host already has
SSH access to remote-host. If it does not, you can use agent forwarding
to forward the SSH identity of your local computer to remote-host.</p></div><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -J jump-host1,jump-host2 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-8405b8ce="">You can specify multiple comma-separated jump hosts.</p></div><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh -o ProxyCommand="nc -X 5 -x localhost:3000 %h %p" user@remote-host</code></p><p data-v-8405b8ce="">Connecting to a remote server through a SOCKS5 proxy using netcat.
From the perspective of the server, the originating IP is from proxy-host.
However, the SSH connection itself is end-to-end encrypted so proxy-host
only sees an encrypted stream of traffic between the local system
and remote-host.</p></div><div data-v-8405b8ce=""><h4 data-v-8405b8ce="">SSH client configuration</h4><p data-v-8405b8ce="">To enable agent forwarding, you can use ssh-add to add your local SSH
identity to your local ssh agent.</p><p><code data-v-8405b8ce="">ssh-add</code></p></div></div></section><section data-v-61bcd1b8="" id="reliable-ssh-tunnels"><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><header data-v-61bcd1b8=""><h2 data-v-61bcd1b8="">Reliable SSH Tunnels</h2><h3 data-v-61bcd1b8="">How to keep SSH tunnels open through network failures</h3></header><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">The commands listed above work on an ad-hoc basis, but if
you want to maintain SSH tunnels through network outages or
unreliable connections, you'll have to do some additional setup.</p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">By default, the TCP connection used to establish an SSH tunnel
may time out after a period of inactivity. To prevent timeouts,
you can configure the server to send heartbeat messages.</p><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">ServerAliveInterval 15<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">ServerAliveCountMax 4</code></p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">You can also configure the client to send heartbeat messages.</p><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">ClientAliveInterval 15<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">ClientAliveCountMax 4</code></p></div><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><h4 data-v-61bcd1b8="">Using AutoSSH</h4><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">While the above options may prevent a connection from dropping
due to inactivity, they will not re-establish dropped connections.
To ensure that an SSH tunnel will be re-established, you can use
autossh, which builds an SSH tunnel and monitors its health.</p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">AutoSSH accepts the same arguments for port forwarding as SSH.</p><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">autossh -R 2222:localhost:22 ssh-server</code></p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">This establishes a reverse tunnel that comes back after network failures.
By default, AutoSSH will open extra ports on the SSH client and server for
health checks. If traffic appears to no longer pass between the health check
ports, AutoSSH will restart the SSH tunnel.</p></div><div data-v-61bcd1b8=""><p><code data-v-61bcd1b8="">autossh -R 2222:localhost:22 \<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">&nbsp;&nbsp;-M 0 \<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">&nbsp;&nbsp;-o "ServerAliveInterval 10" -o "ServerAliveCountMax 3" \<br data-v-61bcd1b8="">&nbsp;&nbsp;remote-host</code></p><p data-v-61bcd1b8="">Using the -M 0 flag disables the health check ports and allows the SSH client
to handle the health checks. In this example, the SSH client expects the server
to send a heartbeat every 10 seconds. If 3 heartbeats fail in a row, the SSH client
exits, and AutoSSH will re-establish a new connection.</p></div></div></section><section data-v-c0e61440="" id="more-examples"><div data-v-c0e61440=""><header data-v-c0e61440=""><h2 data-v-c0e61440="">More examples and use cases</h2></header><div data-v-c0e61440=""><h4 data-v-c0e61440="">Transparent access to remote resource on a private network</h4><p data-v-c0e61440="">Let's say there's a git repository on a private network that's only accessible
through a private server on the network. This server is not accessible to the public
internet. You have direct access to the server, but don't have VPN access to the
private network.</p><p data-v-c0e61440="">For convenience, you'd …</p></div></div></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/">https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://robotmoon.com/ssh-tunnels/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26053323</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 07:22:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Scientists develop transparent wood that is stronger and lighter than glass]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 145 | Comments 72 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26051883">thread link</a>) | @lazycrazyowl
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/1.5902739 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/1.5902739">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Bob McDonald's blog: A simple backyard procedure results in see-through wood with enormous potential as a building material.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902788.1612553036!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A flower is visible behind a piece of the transparent material.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Researchers at the University of Maryland have turned ordinary sheets of wood into <a href="https://advances.sciencemag.org/content/7/5/eabd7342" target="_blank"><u>transparent material</u></a> that is nearly as clear as glass, but stronger and with better insulating properties. It could become an energy efficient building material in the future.</p>  <p>Wood is made of two basic ingredients: cellulose, which are tiny fibres, and lignin, which bonds those fibres together to give it strength.</p>  <p>Tear a paper towel in half and look closely along the edge. You will see the little cellulose fibres sticking up. Lignin is a glue-like material that bonds the fibres together, a little like the plastic resin in fibreglass or carbon fibre. The lignin also contains molecules called chromophores, which give the wood its brown colour and prevent light from passing through.</p>  <p>Early attempts to make transparent wood involved removing the lignin, but this involved hazardous chemicals, high temperatures and a lot of time, making the product expensive and somewhat brittle. The new technique is so cheap and easy it could literally be done in a backyard.</p>  <p>Starting with planks of wood a metre long and one millimetre thick, the scientists simply brushed on a solution of hydrogen peroxide using an ordinary paint brush. When left in the sun, or under a UV lamp for an hour or so, the peroxide bleached out the brown chromophores but left the lignin intact, so the wood turned white.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902789.1612553066!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Researchers demonstrated after brushing a coat of hydrogen peroxide on the opaque wood material, and exposing it to one hour of sunlight, it turns transparent.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Next, they infused the wood with a tough transparent epoxy designed for marine use, which filled in the spaces and pores in the wood and then hardened.&nbsp;This made the white wood transparent.</p>  <p>You can see a similar effect by taking that same piece of paper towel, dip half of it in water and place it on a patterned surface.&nbsp;The white paper towel will become translucent with light passing through the water and cellulose fibres without being scattered by refraction.</p>  <p>The epoxy in the wood does an even better job, allowing 90 per cent of visible light to pass through. The result is a long piece of what looks like glass, with the strength and flexibility of wood.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902790.1612552994!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-usda-forest-service-jpg.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A researcher holds up a square of transparent wood material against a green leaf.<!-- --> <!-- -->(USDA Forest Service)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>As window material, it would be much more resistant to accidental breakage. The clear wood&nbsp;is lighter than glass, with better insulating properties, which is important because windows are a major source of heat loss in buildings. It also might take less energy to manufacture clear wood because there are no high temperatures involved.</p>  <p>Transparent wood could become an alternative to glass in energy efficient buildings, or perhaps coverings for solar panels in harsh environments. There could be no end of uses.</p>      <p>Many different types of wood, from balsa to oak, can be made transparent, and it doesn't matter if it is cut along the grain or against it. If the transparent wood is made a little thicker, it would be strong enough to become part of the structure of a building, so there could be entire transparent wooden walls.</p>  <p>While this technology has yet to&nbsp; be scaled up to industrial levels, the researchers say it has great potential as a new building material. In fact, they say that theoretically, an entire house could be made transparent. It is not clear why anyone would want to live in a transparent house, but for people who do, it would be OK to throw stones…</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5902787.1612553101!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/transparent-wood-qinqin-xia-university-of-maryland.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A researcher holds up a 10-centimetre long slab of the see-through wood.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Qinqin Xia, University of Maryland/Science Advances)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Images copyright Xia et al.&nbsp;<a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/" rel="license">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial license</a>,&nbsp;</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/1.5902739</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26051883</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:48:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Mediocre Programmer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26051600">thread link</a>) | @celadevra_
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | http://themediocreprogrammer.com/what-is-the-mediocre-programmer.html#what-is-the-mediocre-programmer | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://themediocreprogrammer.com/what-is-the-mediocre-programmer.html#what-is-the-mediocre-programmer">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>The Mediocre Programmer? What's that?</p>
<p>The Mediocre Programmer is a book about the journey of becoming a better programmer. But before we can become better programmers we have to pass through being mediocre programmers. Mediocre doesn't mean a bad programmer --- far from it. It means lacking skill. As beginners we start our journey full of fresh ideas of how we'll be great programmers, but as we learn more we realize that the gap between being a beginner and an expert programmer requires us to be mediocre for a time. And that period of mediocrity can be frustrating. As beginning programmers we're given all the encouragement to explore and make mistakes. As we move to the intermediate and mediocre stages of programming that encouragement fades. Instead of encouragement we are faced with expectations, both from ourselves and from others. We start to question our abilities. Why do we have to keep looking things up? Shouldn't we already know this? Why does programming feel like a struggle? Am I ever going to be good at this? </p>
<p>This book is about helping you along on the journey of being a mediocre programmer. Together we'll uncover some of common misconceptions we have about programming, failure, and growth and come to understand that the act of programming and development is something we undertake each day and improve in small ways. It's these small changes that over time transform us from being mediocre programmers into better programmers.</p>
<p>There are plenty of books on how to become a better programmer out there. Books like this tend to have checklists and other advice that the author deems important enough for you to do in order to become a better programmer. They tend to focus on specific improvements like choosing a better editor, writing better test cases, or drinking lots of water. Those books have lots of useful advice, but they read like a laundry list of things that you must do all at once in order to succeed. This book will try not to saddle you with more work (you likely have enough as it is). Rather, we'll discuss what it feels like to be a programmer. We'll talk about the emotions in being a programmer; the feelings of frustration, guilt, anger, and inadequacy. We'll cover the struggles in learning new things and keeping your skills current. We'll talk about those times when you feel like giving up and walking away from computing and whether those feelings come from a place of love or a worry that you're not keeping up.</p>
<p>This book is a personal journey for both of us. It's a memoir of my time as a programmer and my feelings along the way. I've thought many times about giving up and finding a different career path but doing anything other than being a computer programmer scares me even more. Does that mean I'm stuck in a perverse ouroboros of self-pity and self-doubt? Hardly. It means that I need to dig deeper to understand why I chose the path of being a programmer and realize that it took a lot to get here and it's going to take a lot more to get where I want to be. It's a commitment to seeing things as they are now and moving forward from wherever I'm standing.</p>
<p>I hope you'll join me on this journey.</p>
<p>(The book is released under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike license (CC-BY-SA)</a>. You are encouraged to read it, share it, and use it to help others through their struggle).</p>  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://themediocreprogrammer.com/what-is-the-mediocre-programmer.html#what-is-the-mediocre-programmer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26051600</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:46:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I bought 200 Raspberry Pi Model B’s and I’m going to fix them: Part 5]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26049470">thread link</a>) | @techscoop_xyz
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://james.li/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-5/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://james.li/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-5/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-3722">

	

	<div>
		
<h2>Introduction</h2>



<p>Back in <a href="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-4/">Part 4 </a>I continued the repairs and donated the money from the first batch of the repaired Pis to the Raspberry Pi Foundation. <br></p>



<p>In this post I will be covering what the money went towards and go over the current repair status.</p>



<blockquote><p>I’ve confirmed that your donation has been allocated to Pi Drop. It should fund approximately three deployments of Pi 400+monitor+webcam to disadvantaged young people in the UK. Thanks again for the donation (and for putting more Pi 1 units back in the field).</p><cite>Eben Upton – Founder Raspberry Pi Foundation</cite></blockquote>



<p>The money donated so far has funded three computers for disadvantaged young people that require a computer to learn from home. Whilst this might not seem like a lot from selling 27 Raspberry Pi 1’s please keep in mind this includes a Raspberry Pi 400 or a Raspberry Pi 4 with keyboard, mouse, monitor and SD card. </p>



<p>In terms of continuing the repairs and donations I have a goal in my head that I would like to meet and I will be listing a further 30 repaired  Model B’s for sale today!</p>



<p>I will also be listing 10 “Model A’s” – More about these below.</p>



<h2>Salvaging dead Pis by removing components</h2>



<p>I came across a fair amount of Pis with dead Ethernet and/or dead USB ports. This issue was caused by a failed Ethernet IC.</p>



<p>Eben Upton did offer to see if they had any spare Ethernet IC’s for the Pi 1. I could have used them to restore full functionality to these devices however I had already started converting them to Model As and the chance of spare IC’s for such an old device laying around seemed slim. </p>



<blockquote><p>&nbsp;was thinking perhaps we might have some 9512 chips lying around, but it’s been so long since we transitioned to 9514 that we almost certainly don’t.</p><cite>Eben Upton – Founder Raspberry Pi Foundation</cite></blockquote>



<p>Instead I removed the Ethernet IC and associated circuitry – More of this can be seen in <a href="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Part 3</a>.</p>



<p>I have completed 10 of these so far and they will also be listed for sale today! </p>



<p>These devices are almost identical to the original Model A with the missing Ethernet port, IC and top USB port. <br></p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3724" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1654/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?fit=2560%2C1695&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2560,1695" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1612607901&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;25&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.025&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1654" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C199&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C497&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="750" height="497" src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654.jpg?resize=750%2C497&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654.jpg?resize=750%2C497&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C678&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C199&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C509&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C1059&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=2200%2C1457&amp;ssl=1 2200w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?w=2250&amp;ssl=1 2250w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-old-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654.jpg?resize=750%2C497&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C678&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C199&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C509&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C1059&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?resize=2200%2C1457&amp;ssl=1 2200w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?w=2560&amp;ssl=1 2560w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w, https://i1.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654-scaled.jpg?w=2250&amp;ssl=1 2250w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1654.jpg?resize=750%2C497&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>Some of these boards might have residual flux left over from the repairs although I have cleaned them up as best as I can! </p>



<p>They also have a mixture of 256MB and 512MB of RAM meaning some of them are an upgrade over the original model A!</p>



<h2>Replacing damaged SD card slots</h2>



<p>I already went over this in<a href="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-4/"> part 4</a> however I’m further along with the repairs. 30 of these have been repaired in total so far and I also re-enforced the slots with a small amount of Epoxy Resin to stop them being snapped from the board. <br></p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3721" data-permalink="https://blog.jmdawson.co.uk/img_1650/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?fit=2123%2C2560&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2123,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone 8 Plus&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1612606643&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.083333333333333&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="img_1650" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?fit=249%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?fit=750%2C905&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="750" height="905" src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650.jpg?resize=750%2C905&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650.jpg?resize=750%2C905&amp;ssl=1" alt="" data-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=849%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 849w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=249%2C300&amp;ssl=1 249w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C926&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C1930&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?w=2123&amp;ssl=1 2123w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-sizes="(max-width: 750px) 100vw, 750px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-old-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650.jpg?resize=750%2C905&amp;ssl=1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=849%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 849w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=249%2C300&amp;ssl=1 249w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C926&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?resize=1600%2C1930&amp;ssl=1 1600w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?w=2123&amp;ssl=1 2123w, https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650-scaled.jpg?w=1500&amp;ssl=1 1500w" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/blog.jmdawson.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/img_1650.jpg?resize=750%2C905&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>Repaired Pi’s with new upgraded SD card slots. </figcaption></figure>



<p>Please keep in mind when purchasing these – Not all of the Pi’s listed for sale today will include a new SD card slot. Some of the Pis literally had the SD card slots ripped off damaging the pads and a small amount of the devices have had trace wires added to the board to repair the missing pads. These are small and almost unnoticeable but please keep this in mind! </p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<div><p>These devices are now listed for sale – as with the last batch the Model Bs will be sold in pairs with one device having been repaired previously and the other working but not repaired. Although both devices have been tested and proved to work I will only guarantee one of the Pis. </p><p>Model Bs x2 for £15: https://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/Raspberry-pi-model-b-x2/274673808835</p><p>Model As x1 for £7: https://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/Raspberry-pi-model-A/274673810787</p><p>All money raised from these will be donated to the Raspberry Pi Foundation. </p><p>If you have any thoughts on this please let me know below! </p></div>





	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

				
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://james.li/i-bought-200-raspberry-pi-model-bs-and-im-going-to-fix-them-part-5/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26049470</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:08:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Architecture.md]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1028 | Comments 135 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26048784">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://matklad.github.io//2021/02/06/ARCHITECTURE.md.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://matklad.github.io//2021/02/06/ARCHITECTURE.md.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <article>
  
  <p>Feb 6, 2021</p>
  <p>If you maintain an open-source project in the range of 10k-200k lines of code, I strongly encourage you to add an <code>ARCHITECTURE</code> document next to <code>README</code> and <code>CONTRIBUTING</code>.
Before going into the details of why and how, I want to emphasize that this is not another “docs are good, write more docs” advice.
I am pretty sloppy about documentation, and, eg, I often use just “simplify” as a commit message.
Nonetheless, I feel strongly about the issue, even to the point of pestering you:-)</p>
<p>I have experience with both contributing to and maintaining open-source projects.
One of the lessons I’ve learned is that the biggest difference between an occasional contributor and a core developer lies in the knowledge about the physical architecture of the project.
Roughly, it takes 2x more time to write a patch if you are unfamiliar with the project, but it takes 10x more time to figure out <em>where</em> you should change the code.
This difference might be hard to perceive if you’ve been working with the project for a while.
If I am new to a code base, I read each file as a sequence of logical chunks specified in some pseudo-random order.
If I’ve made significant contributions before, the perception is quite different.
I have a mental map of the code in my head, so I no longer read sequentially.
Instead, I just jump to where the thing should be, and, if it is not there, I move it.
Mental map is the source of truth.</p>
<p>I find <code>ARCHITECTURE</code> file to be a low-effort high-leverage way to bridge this gap.
As the name suggest, this file should describe the high-level architecture of the project.
Keep it short: every recurring contributor will have to read it.
Additionally, the shorter it is, the less likely it will be invalidated by some future change.
This is the main rule of thumb for <code>ARCHITECTURE</code> — specify only things which are unlikely to frequently change.
Don’t try to keep it synchronized with code.
Instead, revisit it a couple of times a year.</p>
<p>Start with a bird’s eye overview of the problem being solved.
Then, specify a more-or-less detailed codemap.
Describe coarse-grained modules and how they relate to each other.
Codemap should answer “where’s the thing that does X?”.
It should also answer “what does the thing that I am looking at do?”.
Avoid going into details of <em>how</em> each module works, pull this into separate documents or (better) inline documentation.
Codemap is a map of a country, and not an atlas of maps of its states.
Use this as a chance to reflect on the project structure.
Are the things you want to put near each other in the codemap adjacent in <code>exa -TD</code>?</p>
<p>Do name important files, modules, and types.
Do not directly link them (links go stale).
Instead, encourage the reader to use symbol search to find the mentioned entities by name.
This doesn’t require maintenance, and will help to discover related, similarly named things.</p>
<p>Explicitly call-out architectural invariants.
Often, important invariants are expressed as an <em>absence</em> of something, and it’s pretty hard to divine that from reading the code.
Nothing in the model layer specifically doesn’t depend on the views.</p>
<p>Point out boundaries between layers and systems as well.
A boundary implicitly contains information about the implementation of the system behind it.
It even constraints all <em>possible</em> implementations.
But finding a boundary by just randomly looking at the code is hard — good boundaries have measure zero.</p>
<p>After finishing the codemap, add a separate section on cross-cutting concerns.</p>
<p>A good example of <code>ARCHITECTURE</code> document is the one from rust-analyzer:
<a href="https://github.com/rust-analyzer/rust-analyzer/blob/d7c99931d05e3723d878bea5dc26766791fa4e69/docs/dev/architecture.md">architecture.md</a>.</p>
</article>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://matklad.github.io//2021/02/06/ARCHITECTURE.md.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26048784</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:46:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nevada bill would allow tech companies to create governments]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 142 | Comments 128 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26046053">thread link</a>) | @waynekerr
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://www.techregister.co.uk/nevada-bill-would-allow-tech-companies-to-create-governments/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.techregister.co.uk/nevada-bill-would-allow-tech-companies-to-create-governments/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <!-- hearst/article/types/story_body_r2.tpl -->


<p>CARSON CITY, Nev. (AP) — Planned legislation to establish new business areas in Nevada would allow technology companies to effectively form separate local governments.</p>

<p>Democratic Gov. Steve Sisolak announced a plan to launch so-called Innovation Zones in Nevada to jumpstart the state’s economy by attracting technology firms, Las Vegas Review-Journal reported  Wednesday.</p>

<p>The zones would permit companies with large areas of land to form governments carrying the same authority as counties, including the ability to impose taxes, form school districts and courts and provide government services.</p>


<p>The measure to further economic development with the “alternative form of local government” has not yet been introduced in the Legislature.</p>

<p>Sisolak pitched the concept in his State of the State address delivered Jan. 19. The plan would bring in new businesses at the forefront of “groundbreaking technologies” without the use of tax abatements or other publicly funded incentive packages that previously helped Nevada attract companies like Tesla Inc.</p>


<p>Sisolak named Blockchains, LLC as a company that had committed to developing a “smart city” in an area east of Reno after the legislation has passed.</p>


<p>The draft proposal said the traditional local government model is “inadequate alone” to provide the resources to make Nevada a leader in attracting and retaining businesses and fostering economic development in emerging technologies and industries.</p>

<p>The Governor’s Office of Economic Development would oversee applications for the zones, which would be limited to companies working in specific business areas including blockchain, autonomous technology, the Internet of Things, robotics, artificial intelligence, wireless, biometrics and renewable resource technology.</p>


<p>Zone requirements would include applicants owning at least 78 square miles (202 square kilometers) of undeveloped, uninhabited land within a single county but separate from any city, town or tax increment area. Companies would have at least $250 million and plans to invest an additional $1 billion in their zones over 10 years.</p>

<p>The zones would initially operate with the oversight of their location counties, but would eventually take over county duties and become independent governmental bodies.</p>

<p>The zones would have three-member supervisor boards with the same powers as county commissioners. The businesses would maintain significant control over board membership.</p>

<p>The governor’s economic development office did not respond to questions about the zones Wednesday.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.techregister.co.uk/nevada-bill-would-allow-tech-companies-to-create-governments/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26046053</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 12:17:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What data on myself I collect and why (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 173 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26045797">thread link</a>) | @karlicoss
<br/>
February 6, 2021 | https://beepb00p.xyz/my-data.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://beepb00p.xyz/my-data.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <article>
    
    <section id="post-title">
    
    <p>How I am using 50+ sources of my personal data
    </p></section>
    <!-- are sections appropriate for that? -->

    <section id="post-content">
    <p>
This is the list of personal data sources I use or planning to use with rough guides on how to get your hands on that data if you want it as well.
It's still incomplete and I'm going to update it regularly.
</p>
<p>
My goal is collecting almost all of my digital trace, <b>automating data collection to the maximum extent possible</b> and making it work in the background, so one can set up pipelines once and hopefully never think about it again.
</p>
<p>
This is kind of a follow-up on my previous post on the <a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/sad-infra.html">sad state of personal data</a>, and part of my personal way of getting around this sad state.
</p>
<p>
If you're terrified by the long list, you can jump straight into <a href="#consumers">"Data consumers"</a> section to find out how I use it.
In addition, check out <a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/myinfra.html">my infrastructure map</a>, which might explain it better!
</p>

<div>
<h2 id="why"><a href="#why">¶</a><span>1</span> Why do you collect X? How do you use your data?</h2>
<div>
<p>
All things considered, I think it's a fair question!
Why bother with all this <a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/tags.html#infra">infrastructure</a> and hoard the data if you never use it?
</p>
<p>
In the next section, I will elaborate on each specific data source, but to start with I'll list the rationales that all of them share:
</p>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="backup"><a href="#backup">¶</a>backup</h3>
<p>
It may feel unnecessary, but shit happens. What if your device dies, account gets suspended for some reason or the company goes bust?
</p>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="lifelogging"><a href="#lifelogging">¶</a><a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/tags.html#lifelogging">lifelogging</a></h3>
<div>
<p>
Most data in digital form got timestamps, so automatically, without manual effort, constitutes data for your timeline.
</p>
<p>
I want to remember more, be able to review my past and bring back and reflect on memories. Practicing lifelogging helps with that.
</p>
<p>
It feels very wrong that things can be forgotten and lost forever.
It's understandable from the neuroscience point of view, i.e. the brain has limited capacity and it would be too distracting to remember everything all the time.
That said, I want to have a <b>choice</b> whether to forget or remember events, and I'd like to be able to potentially access forgotten ones.
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="qs"><a href="#qs">¶</a><a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/tags.html#quantifiedself">quantified self</a></h3>
<p>
Most collected digital data is somewhat quantitative and can be used to analyze your body or mind.
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h2 id="what"><a href="#what">¶</a><span>2</span> What do I collect/want to collect?</h2>
<div>
<p>
As I mentioned, most of the collected data serve as a means of backup/lifelogging/quantified self, so I won't mention them again in the 'Why' sections.
</p>
<p>
All my data collection pipelines are <b>automatic unless mentioned otherwise</b>.
</p>
<p>
Some scripts are still private so if you want to know more, let me know so I can prioritize sharing them.
</p>
</div>

<div>
<h3 id="arbtt"><a href="#arbtt">¶</a>Arbtt (desktop time tracker)</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: <a href="https://arbtt.nomeata.de/">arbtt-capture</a>
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>haven't used it yet, but it could be a rich source of lifelogging context</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="bitbucket"><a href="#bitbucket">¶</a>Bitbucket (repositories)</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: <a href="https://github.com/samkuehn/bitbucket-backup">samkuehn/bitbucket-backup</a>
</p>
<p>
Why: 
</p>
<ul>
<li><p>
proved especially useful considering Atlassian is going to <a href="https://bitbucket.org/blog/sunsetting-mercurial-support-in-bitbucket"><b>wipe</b></a> mercurial repositories
</p>
<p>
I've got lots of private mercurial repositories with university homework and other early projects, and it's sad to think of people who will lose theirs during this wipe.
</p></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="bluemaestro"><a href="#bluemaestro">¶</a><a href="https://bluemaestro.com/products/product-details/bluetooth-environmental-monitor-and-logger">Bluemaestro</a> (environment sensor)</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: sensor syncs with phone app via Bluetooth, <samp>/data/data/com.bluemaestro.tempo_utility/databases/</samp> is regularly copied to grab the data.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>temperature during sleep data for the <a href="#dashboard">dashboard</a></li>
<li><p>
lifelogging: capturing weather conditions information
</p>
<p>
E.g. I can potentially see temperature/humidity readings along with my photos from hiking or skiing.
</p></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="blood"><a href="#blood">¶</a>Blood</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: via <a href="https://thriva.co/">thriva</a>, data imported manually into an org-mode table (not doing too frequently so wasn't worth automated scraping)
</p>
<p>
Also tracked glucose and ketones (with <a href="https://freestylediabetes.co.uk/freestyle-libre">freestyle libre</a>) for a few days out of curiosity, also didn't bother automating it.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>contributes to the <a href="#dashboard">dashboard</a>, could be a good way of establishing your baselines</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

<div>
<h3 id="emfit"><a href="#emfit">¶</a><a href="https://shop-eu.emfit.com/products/emfit-qs">Emfit QS</a> (sleep tracker)</h3>
<div>
<p>
Emfit QS is kind of a medical grade sleep tracker. It's more expensive than wristband ones (e.g. <a href="#fitbit">fitbit</a>, <a href="#jawbone">jawbone</a>) but also more reliable and gives more data.
</p>
<p>
How: <a href="https://github.com/karlicoss/backup-emfit">emfitexport</a>.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>sleep data for the <a href="#dashboard">dashboard</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

<div>
<h3 id="facebook"><a href="#facebook">¶</a>Facebook</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: manual archive export.
</p>
<p>
I barely use Facebook, so don't even bother doing it regularly.
</p>
</div>
</div>



<div>
<h3 id="fitbit"><a href="#fitbit">¶</a>Fitbit</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: manual CSV export, as I only used it for few weeks. Then the sync stopped working and I had to return it.
However, it seems <a href="https://dev.fitbit.com/build/reference/web-api/intraday-requests">possible</a> via API.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>activity data for the <a href="#dashboard">#dashboard</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="foursquare"><a href="#foursquare">¶</a>Foursquare/Swarm</h3>
<p>
How: via API
</p>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="github_repos"><a href="#github_repos">¶</a>Github (repositories)</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: <a href="https://github.com/josegonzalez/python-github-backup">github-backup</a>
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>capable of exporting starred repositories as well, so if the authors delete them I will still have them</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>



<div>
<h3 id="takeout"><a href="#takeout">¶</a>Google takeout</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: semi-automatic. 
</p>
<ul>
<li>only manual step: enable scheduled exports (you can schedule 6 per year at a time), and choose to keep it on Google Drive in export settings</li>
<li>mount your Google Drive (e.g. via <a href="https://github.com/astrada/google-drive-ocamlfuse">google-drive-ocamlfuse</a>)</li>
<li>keep a script that checks mounted Google Drive for fresh takeout and moves it somewhere safe</li>
</ul>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Google collects lots of data, which you could put to some good use. However, old data is getting <a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/takeout-data-gone.html">wiped</a>, so it's important to export Takeout regularly.</li>
<li><a href="#promnesia">better browsing history</a></li>
<li>(potentially) search history for <a href="#promnesia">promnesia</a></li>
<li><a href="#search">search</a> in youtube watch history</li>
<li>location data for lifelogging and the <a href="#dashboard">dashboard</a> (activity)</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="hackernews"><a href="#hackernews">¶</a><span>STRT</span>Hackernews</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: haven't got to it yet. It's going to require:
</p>
<ul>
<li>extracting upvotes/saved items via web scraping since Hackernews doesn't offer an API for that. Hopefully, there is an existing library for that.</li>
<li><p>
I'm also using <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=io.github.hidroh.materialistic">Materialistic</a> app that has its own 'saved' posts and doesn't synchronize with Hackernews. 
</p>
<p>
Exporting them is going to require copying the database directly from the app private storage.
</p></li>
</ul>
<p>
Why: same reasons as <a href="#reddit">Reddit</a>.
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="hsbc"><a href="#hsbc">¶</a>HSBC bank</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: manual exports of monthly PDFs with transactions. They don't really offer API, so unless you want to web scrape and deal with 2FA, it seems it's the best you can do.
</p>
<p>
Why
</p>
<ul>
<li>personal finance; used it with <a href="https://github.com/karlicoss/hsbc-parser">karlicoss/hsbc-parser</a> to feed into <a href="https://hledger.org/">hledger</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>


<div>
<h3 id="jawbone"><a href="#jawbone">¶</a>Jawbone</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: via API.
Jawbone is dead now, so if you haven't exported it already, likely your data is lost forever.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>sleep data for the <a href="#dashboard">dashboard</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="kindle"><a href="#kindle">¶</a>Kindle</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: manually exported <samp>MyClippings.txt</samp> from Kindle. Potentially can be automated similarly to <a href="#kobo">Kobo</a>.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#search">better search</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>



<div>
<h3 id="nomie"><a href="#nomie">¶</a><a href="https://nomie.app/">Nomie</a></h3>
<div>
<p>
How: regular copies of <samp>/data/data/io.nomie.pro/files/_pouch_events</samp> and <samp>/data/data/io.nomie.pro/files/_pouch_trackers</samp>
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>could be a great tool for detailed lifelogging if you're into it</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="nutrition"><a href="#nutrition">¶</a>Nutrition</h3>
<div>
<p>
I tracked almost all nutrition data for stuff I ingested over the course of a year.
</p>
<p>
How: I found most existing apps/projects clumsy and unsatisfactory, so I developed my own system.
Not even a proper app, something simpler, basically a domain-specific language in Python to track it.
</p>
<p>
Tracking process was simply editing a python file and adding entries like:
</p>
<div>
<pre>
<span>july_09</span> = F(
  [  
       spinach * bag,
       tuna_spring_water * can,       
       beans_broad_wt    * can * 0.5, 
       onion_red_tsc     * gr(115)  , 
       cheese_salad_tsc  * 100,       
       lime, 
  ],
  [
     
  ],
  tea_black * 10,     
  wine_red * ml * 150, 
)

<span>july_10</span> = ... 
</pre>
</div>
<p>
Comments added for clarity of course, so it'd be more compact normally.
</p>
<p>
Then some code was used for processing, calculating, <a href="https://postimg.cc/bdSVc43Y">visualizing</a>, etc.
</p>
<p>
Having a real programming language instead of an app let me make it very flexible and expressive, e.g.:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p>
I could define composite dishes as Python objects, and then easily reuse them.
</p>
<p>
E.g. if I made four servings of soup on 10.08.2018, ate one immediately and froze other three I would define something like <samp>soup_20180810 = [...]</samp>, and then I can simply reuse <samp>soup_20180810</samp> when I eat it again.
(date was easy to find out as I label food when put it in the freezer anyway)
</p></li>
<li>I could make many things implicit, making it pretty expressive without spending time on unnecessary typing</li>
<li>I rarely had to in nutrient composition manually, I just pasted the product link to supermarket website and had an automatic script to parse nutrient information</li>
<li>For micronutrients (that usually aren't listed on labels) I used the <a href="https://github.com/alyssaq/usda-sqlite">USDA sqlite database</a></li>
</ul>
<p>
The hard thing was actually not entering, but rather not having nutrition information if you're eating out. That year I was mostly cooking my own food, so tracking was fairly easy.
</p>
<p>
Also I was more interested in lower bounds, (e.g. "do I consume at least recommended amount of micronutrients"), so not having logged food now and then was fine for me.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p>
I mostly wanted to learn about food composition and how it relates to my diet, and I did
</p>
<p>
That logging motivated me to learn about different foods and try them out while keeping dishes balanced.
I cooked so many different things, made my diet way more varied and became less picky.
</p>
<p>
I stopped because cooking did take some time and I actually realized that as long as I actually vary
food and try to eat everything now and then, I hit all recommended amounts of micronutrients, so I stopped.
It's kind of an obvious thing that everyone recommends, but one thing is hearing it as a common wisdom
and completely different is coming to the same conclusion <b>from your data</b>.
</p></li>
<li>nutritional information contributes to <a href="#dashboard">dashboard</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="photos"><a href="#photos">¶</a>Photos</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: no extra effort required if you sync/organize your photos and videos now and then.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li>obvious source of lifelogging, in addition comes with GPS data</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h3 id="pdfs"><a href="#pdfs">¶</a>PDF annotations</h3>
<div>
<p>
As in, <a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/annotating.html#pdfs">native PDF annotations</a>. 
</p>
<p>
How: nothing needs to be done, PDFs are local to your computer. You do need <a href="https://github.com/karlicoss/my/blob/master/my/pdfs.py">some tools</a> to crawl your filesystem and extract the annotations.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p>
experience of using your PDF annotations (e.g. searching) is <a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/annotating.html#comparison"><b>extremely poor</b></a>
</p>
<p>
I'm improving this by using <a href="#orger">orger</a>.
</p></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

<div>
<h3 id="notes"><a href="#notes">¶</a>Plaintext notes</h3>
<div>
<p>
Mostly this refers to org-mode files, which I use for notekeeping and logging.
</p>
<p>
How: nothing needs to be done, they are local. 
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="#search">search</a> comes for free, it's already local</li>
<li><a href="#promnesia">better browsing history</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>


<div>
<h3 id="rtm"><a href="#rtm">¶</a>Remember the Milk</h3>
<div>
<p>
How: ical export from the API.
</p>
<p>
Why:
</p>
<ul>
<li><p>
<a href="#search">better search</a>
</p>
<p>
I stopped using RTM in favor of org-mode, but I can still easily find my old task and notes, which allowed for a smooth transition.
</p></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>

</div></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://beepb00p.xyz/my-data.html">https://beepb00p.xyz/my-data.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://beepb00p.xyz/my-data.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26045797</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 11:13:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Write Readable Code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26043509">thread link</a>) | @piinbinary
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | http://jeremymikkola.com/posts/2021_02_02_how_to_write_readable_code.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://jeremymikkola.com/posts/2021_02_02_how_to_write_readable_code.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
        <div>
          

          <p>
    Posted on February  2, 2021
    
</p>


<p>These are some of the things I think about when trying to write clean, readable code.</p>
<h2 id="prioritize-clarity">Prioritize Clarity</h2>
<p>There are many ways to write any piece of code. Some will run faster, some will take less memory, some will be easier to test. And some will be more clear.</p>
<p>The first step to writing clear code is to make it a priority.</p>
<p>This means you have to deprioritize other aspects, like speed. There’s no such thing as prioritizing one thing without deprioritizing something else (when everything is a priority, nothing is).</p>
<h2 id="develop-a-sense-for-clarity">Develop a sense for clarity</h2>
<p>Writing well requires knowing what good writing looks like, and creating clear code requires knowing what clear code looks like. Reading well-regarded code can give you a sense of what good can look like.</p>
<p>A good sense for clear code won’t keep you from writing unreadable code, but it will tell you what parts don’t smell right.</p>
<h2 id="edit">Edit</h2>
<p>Your first idea for how to write the code will rarely be the most clear.</p>
<p>It’s often easier to find a readable way to write code after you’re finished with the mental work of getting the first version written down. Reading back over what you just wrote will help give ideas for how to improve it.</p>
<h2 id="start-by-explaining">Start by explaining</h2>
<p>If you’re not sure how to organize the code, start by explaining what needs to be done as though you are telling it to another person (or rubber duck). Write it down: “Well, we need to skip it if the user is deleted, or if the order is already in progress…” Take that explanation and transform it into code.</p>
<p>When laying out the code, it’s better to be thinking in terms of human communication rather than machine abstractions.</p>

<p>Add comments that explain why the code is doing what it is doing, or is structured the way that it is structured.</p>
<p>Just reading the logic won’t tell you why the author thought that was the right logic. There might be some business reason you don’t know about - perhaps users outside the US sometimes put the street number at the end of the first line of the address. Or maybe there is some little technical detail - this query is structured in this weird way to convince Postgres to optimize it correctly. These are added bits of context that don’t exist in the code itself.</p>
<p>Code can’t self-document if it isn’t there. If you decide to not write some code and don’t leave a comment explaining why, there will be nothing left to explain what you were thinking!</p>
<p>Even if it is possible to understand the reasoning from just reading the code, it’s hard mental work that can be very easily prevented.</p>
<h2 id="dont-mix-levels">Don’t mix levels</h2>
<p>Don’t mix levels of abstraction within a method.</p>
<p>This mixes levels of abstraction:</p>

<p>This doesn’t:</p>

<p>Mixing levels of abstraction makes the reader jump between thinking about what is being done and how it is implemented.</p>
<p>When you talk about what code does, you are talking about the current level of abstraction. When you talk about how the code does it, you are talking about the next level of abstraction down.</p>
<p>In the <code>welcome</code> method, what it does is send a welcome email if it has not already been sent. How it determines if the email was already sent is to query the database of past email records. Notice that the second version of <code>welcome</code> moves the ‘how’ to a separate method. It’s only concerned with the ‘what’, meaning it stays at one level of abstraction.</p>
<p>Make each function live at one level of abstraction, and delegate lower-level details to methods at lower levels of abstraction. Methods with a single level of abstraction tend to read like a story about what is going on.</p>
<h2 id="break-out-functions">Break out functions</h2>
<p>Big functions can (sometimes!) be made more readable by breaking them up into smaller functions.</p>
<p>Sometimes that function acts like a series of steps, in which case it works well to extract a function for each step. Other times, there are different decisions to be made, each of which could be made in a different function. Perhaps there’s parts of the function that act like making a decision and parts that act like taking action. There’s a lot of different dimensions you can use to split up a function. It takes practice to get good at seeing the right one to use.</p>
<p>Smaller functions have some advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>Each bit of logic is given a name. This makes it easier to know what each bit of logic is for and helps you find where a bit of logic lives.</li>
<li>There are fewer variables in scope.</li>
<li>It’s easier to tell what the program was “thinking” when you look at a stack trace or run a debugger.</li>
<li>The small functions can be tested separately.</li>
</ul>
<p>Computers would work fine with no functions at all. Functions exist for the sake of programmers, so make good use of them.</p>
<h2 id="dont-break-out-functions">Don’t break out functions</h2>
<p>The Don’t Repeat Yourself (DRY) idea is often taken too far.</p>
<p>Now, it’s a very good idea to extract magic numbers to constants and have one copy of the logic for making a particular decision. Repeating those bits of code is a bad idea.</p>
<p>DRY starts to go too far when two functions that happen to share a handful of lines become a target for deduplication. Completely avoiding duplicated lines means that you’ll end up with confusing, nonsense abstractions that exist only to hold those few shared lines. This makes the code weirdly hard to change because the structure of two unrelated pieces of code will be tied together.</p>
<p>The test for whether some pieces of code should be deduplicated is simple: would anything bad happen if one was changed without also changing the other? If the answer is yes, then make a single source of truth for it. If not, consider leaving it alone.</p>
<p>The point of DRY isn’t to run a manual compression process on the codebase, it’s to avoid a dependency where two parts of the code need to be manually kept in sync. Remember, deduplicating code is not the same thing as creating an abstraction.</p>
<h2 id="avoid-configurable-functions">Avoid configurable functions</h2>
<p>Prefer many functions to a few, configurable functions.</p>
<p>I’m sure you’ve seen stories like this one: you start off with a clean function that’s called in three different places. You want to use it in a fourth place, but it needs to do something slightly different, so you add a configuration parameter. Then the first caller gets a new feature, requiring two more configuration parameters. A fifth use case is added with its own special parameter. Caller #2 is too slow, so you add yet another parameter for skip part of the work.</p>
<p>Somehow, your clean function that started life doing one thing now has 5 configuration parameters and does potentially 2^5 = 32 different things (or more)!</p>
<p>It’s much better to have multiple functions, each of which does just one thing.</p>
<p>Once you have separate functions, there will of course be duplication. When those shared parts need to be kept in sync, apply DRY and extract them to shared functions. This is easier if the function is already broken down into subfunctions for decisions and steps.</p>
<p>Remember, a few duplicated lines is fine! If each of the separate functions has its own for-loop over a list, that’s very acceptable duplication.</p>
<p>One advantage of this approach is that when one use-case goes away, you can easily delete the relevant function. You don’t have to dig around in the logic of a complicated function to tease out the parts that were for that particular set of options.</p>
<p>Readers of a special-purpose function will find it much easier to understand what it does.</p>
<p>(Note that this is only the right approach if you control all the callers of the function. If you function is part of a public API, then the reasoning here doesn’t apply because you don’t know what all the usecases are or will be.)</p>
<h2 id="dont-prematurely-optimize">Don’t prematurely optimize</h2>
<p>Race cars go faster than normal cars, but at the expense of having hard seats, making lots of noise, and lacking A/C. If you don’t know that your function is going to need to be a race car, don’t strip out the A/C yet. Leave the creature comforts in - focus on writing code that is easy for humans to read instead of easy for computers to run.</p>
<p>The same is true about premature generalization. You wouldn’t buy a dump truck if you don’t need to haul huge loads of things, so you also shouldn’t make your code able to serve all kinds of needs that may never happen.</p>

        </div>
      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://jeremymikkola.com/posts/2021_02_02_how_to_write_readable_code.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26043509</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 02:08:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Netflix's Annual Reports (10-Ks) used to be a work of art. What happened?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 237 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26043294">thread link</a>) | @singhkays
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>Annual reports are part and parcel of every public company’s life. It is a document that the public corporations must provide annually to shareholders that describes their operations and financial conditions. In the U.S., companies typically file the Form 10-K with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).
One fine day, as I was following the internet rathole, I landed myself on the Netflix investor page for some reason. One thing to understand about these 10-K forms is that these are …. pretty basic. Imagine being transported back in time from the current beautifully designed web interfaces back to a text-based interface. This is what I was dealing with, and all the reports looked like these fine specimens from Facebook and Amazon.</p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/Facebook-Amazon-Apple-SEC-10-K-Annual-Report.jpg" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/Facebook-Amazon-Apple-SEC-10-K-Annual-Report_hu13535cc2fca097282ae3d4c789949a54_1009075_480x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/Facebook-Amazon-Apple-SEC-10-K-Annual-Report_hu13535cc2fca097282ae3d4c789949a54_1009075_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/Facebook-Amazon-Apple-SEC-10-K-Annual-Report_hu13535cc2fca097282ae3d4c789949a54_1009075_1200x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/Facebook-Amazon-Apple-SEC-10-K-Annual-Report_hu13535cc2fca097282ae3d4c789949a54_1009075_1500x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/Facebook-Amazon-Apple-SEC-10-K-Annual-Report_hu13535cc2fca097282ae3d4c789949a54_1009075_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg" alt="Apple Mac Mini M1 without any support for billions of colors"> </a><figcaption>
<p>Facebook and Amazon 10-K Annual Report filings</p>
</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><strong>Then 2002 happened!</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/dayum.gif" alt="2002"></p>
<p>I landed on an Annual Report unlike any I had seen before. And it was not just the 2002 Annual Report - <em>the reports from 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006 were similar</em>! <strong>Somebody had actually put a lot of time into designing these</strong> ‼️</p>
<p>Here are my favorite examples.</p>

<p>What I love about this report is the play on introducing the report as an opening sequence of a movie.</p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-10k-2002.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-10k-2002_hu2d114347833df5514aac7ee085b9d5d4_71770_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-10k-2002_hu2d114347833df5514aac7ee085b9d5d4_71770_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-10k-2002_hu2d114347833df5514aac7ee085b9d5d4_71770_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-10k-2002_hu2d114347833df5514aac7ee085b9d5d4_71770_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2002"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2002-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2002-1_hu274467ef5cbd2e24fd63077a7db5d26f_64715_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2002-1_hu274467ef5cbd2e24fd63077a7db5d26f_64715_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2002-1_hu274467ef5cbd2e24fd63077a7db5d26f_64715_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2002-1_hu274467ef5cbd2e24fd63077a7db5d26f_64715_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2002"> </a>
</figure>

<p>2003 report begins with a <em>Netflix-DVD-in-the-mail</em> envelope design - very on-brand! It then plays on movie titles like Edward Scissorhands to explain benefits and features. Then, it ends with an infographic that makes it very easy to digest the annual numbers.</p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-1_hu8724731d856b29a67207f1bf3fbfef97_112561_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-1_hu8724731d856b29a67207f1bf3fbfef97_112561_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-1_hu8724731d856b29a67207f1bf3fbfef97_112561_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-1_hu8724731d856b29a67207f1bf3fbfef97_112561_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-1_hu8724731d856b29a67207f1bf3fbfef97_112561_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2003"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-2.jpg" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-2_hua0d4d4b24f4da3a102e4452ac738b95f_1474183_480x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-2_hua0d4d4b24f4da3a102e4452ac738b95f_1474183_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 800w,
            
                   
            
                   
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-2_hua0d4d4b24f4da3a102e4452ac738b95f_1474183_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg" alt="Netflix annual report 2003"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-3.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-3_hu055393f3f5f2f1634733d0661cc54e8a_251051_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-3_hu055393f3f5f2f1634733d0661cc54e8a_251051_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-3_hu055393f3f5f2f1634733d0661cc54e8a_251051_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-3_hu055393f3f5f2f1634733d0661cc54e8a_251051_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2003-3_hu055393f3f5f2f1634733d0661cc54e8a_251051_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2003"> </a>
</figure>

<p>The 2004 report continues the tradition of a grand opening. It then uses direct integrations with famous movie characters like Spiderman, Austin Powers, and Frankenstein. This is my favorite report!</p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-1_hu3676cb8e64e37d29454e3b3b697788bb_274427_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-1_hu3676cb8e64e37d29454e3b3b697788bb_274427_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-1_hu3676cb8e64e37d29454e3b3b697788bb_274427_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-1_hu3676cb8e64e37d29454e3b3b697788bb_274427_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-1_hu3676cb8e64e37d29454e3b3b697788bb_274427_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2004"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-2.jpg" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_2064285_480x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_2064285_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_2064285_1200x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_2064285_1500x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_2064285_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg" alt="Netflix annual report 2004"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-3.jpg" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-3_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1757568_480x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-3_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1757568_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-3_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1757568_1200x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-3_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1757568_1500x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-3_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1757568_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg" alt="Netflix annual report 2004"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-4.jpg" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-4_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1491359_480x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-4_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1491359_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-4_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1491359_1200x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-4_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1491359_1500x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2004-4_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_1491359_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg" alt="Netflix annual report 2004"> </a>
</figure>

<p>For the 2005 report, the focus seems to have been on the subscribers. I’m not sure if the profile pics are of the subscribers to Netflix at the time, but it’s very likely.
The now-defunct star-based rating system shows up as a way to represent horizontal bar charts. Somebody really put some serious thought into this design!</p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-1_hu67b4416ebcd408b8922d2faf2e554718_83298_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-1_hu67b4416ebcd408b8922d2faf2e554718_83298_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-1_hu67b4416ebcd408b8922d2faf2e554718_83298_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-1_hu67b4416ebcd408b8922d2faf2e554718_83298_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-1_hu67b4416ebcd408b8922d2faf2e554718_83298_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2005"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-2.jpg" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_5553635_480x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_5553635_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_5553635_1200x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_5553635_1500x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-2_hu322d2d6e2c1db2da0ec1bf30df36bb57_5553635_800x0_resize_q75_lanczos.jpg" alt="Netflix annual report 2005"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-3.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-3_hub8731d1f7aa26d60a5e88ac3cb324573_400197_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-3_hub8731d1f7aa26d60a5e88ac3cb324573_400197_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-3_hub8731d1f7aa26d60a5e88ac3cb324573_400197_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-3_hub8731d1f7aa26d60a5e88ac3cb324573_400197_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2005-3_hub8731d1f7aa26d60a5e88ac3cb324573_400197_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2005"> </a>
</figure>

<p>2006 is the first year when the design was toned down and only a couple of pages worth calling out. This report’s theme seems to be the mailbox and a mailbox bar chart that I can only describe as “atrocious.” What are they trying to do with the shadows? 🧐👀</p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-1_huf2298265da57c94e59634446caf4f4af_302193_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-1_huf2298265da57c94e59634446caf4f4af_302193_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-1_huf2298265da57c94e59634446caf4f4af_302193_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-1_huf2298265da57c94e59634446caf4f4af_302193_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-1_huf2298265da57c94e59634446caf4f4af_302193_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2006"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-2.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-2_hu3255779762a9eea70fcadd17fda20b7a_206264_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-2_hu3255779762a9eea70fcadd17fda20b7a_206264_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-2_hu3255779762a9eea70fcadd17fda20b7a_206264_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-2_hu3255779762a9eea70fcadd17fda20b7a_206264_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2006-2_hu3255779762a9eea70fcadd17fda20b7a_206264_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2006"> </a>
</figure>

<p>2007, 2008, and 2009 are basically clones of each other. The design has been reduced to bare bones with only a couple of “designed” pages before the 10-K form. There are only a few pages worth calling out, but at least the bar charts are sensible and easily readable. 🎉</p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2007-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2007-1_hu3e6efb30cc4a0f3c3a2a43acd64d2521_120726_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2007-1_hu3e6efb30cc4a0f3c3a2a43acd64d2521_120726_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2007-1_hu3e6efb30cc4a0f3c3a2a43acd64d2521_120726_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2007-1_hu3e6efb30cc4a0f3c3a2a43acd64d2521_120726_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2007-1_hu3e6efb30cc4a0f3c3a2a43acd64d2521_120726_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2007"> </a>
</figure>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2008-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2008-1_hu1d1f0bb29adfdde5be77cf8971777f23_133517_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2008-1_hu1d1f0bb29adfdde5be77cf8971777f23_133517_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2008-1_hu1d1f0bb29adfdde5be77cf8971777f23_133517_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2008-1_hu1d1f0bb29adfdde5be77cf8971777f23_133517_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2008-1_hu1d1f0bb29adfdde5be77cf8971777f23_133517_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2008"> </a>
</figure>

<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2009-1.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2009-1_hu43f0aa86e85aa96ddbd233495374a4b4_83991_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2009-1_hu43f0aa86e85aa96ddbd233495374a4b4_83991_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2009-1_hu43f0aa86e85aa96ddbd233495374a4b4_83991_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2009-1_hu43f0aa86e85aa96ddbd233495374a4b4_83991_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report 2009"> </a>
</figure>

<p>From 2010 onwards, we’re basically back to the SEC template without any “designed” pages. Not sure what happened to the design team in 2010. 🤷</p>
<p><strong>If anybody knows the answer, please reach out.</strong></p>
<figure><a href="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2010-2021.png" target="_blank">
<img sizes="(min-width: 35em) 1200px, 100vw" srcset="
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2010-2021_hub6cbaa4dbd26830c1288c892b16c75d7_703155_480x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 480w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2010-2021_hub6cbaa4dbd26830c1288c892b16c75d7_703155_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 800w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2010-2021_hub6cbaa4dbd26830c1288c892b16c75d7_703155_1200x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1200w,
            
                   https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2010-2021_hub6cbaa4dbd26830c1288c892b16c75d7_703155_1500x0_resize_lanczos_2.png 1500w,
            " src="https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/media/netflix-annual-report-2010-2021_hub6cbaa4dbd26830c1288c892b16c75d7_703155_800x0_resize_lanczos_2.png" alt="Netflix annual report post-2010"> </a>
</figure>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/2002AR-print.pdf">2002</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/2003AR_print.pdf">2003</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/2004AR_print.pdf">2004</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/2005ar.pdf">2005</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/NFLX.pdf">2006</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/AR_10K_final_2007.pdf">2007</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/Final_AR_10K.pdf">2008</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/2009-AR.pdf">2009</a></li>
<li><a href="https://s22.q4cdn.com/959853165/files/doc_financials/annual_reports/132054ACL.PDF">2010</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ir.netflix.net/financials/annual-reports-and-proxies/default.aspx">Others</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Reach out if you have any questions! Feel free to follow me on</p>
<ul>
<li>Twitter - <a href="https://twitter.com/singhkays">@singhkays</a></li>
<li>LinkedIn - <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/singhkays/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/singhkays/</a></li>
</ul>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/netflix-annual-reports-work-of-art/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26043294</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 01:28:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Some Arabic and Persian accounts of the export of tin from Cornwall]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26043133">thread link</a>) | @Thevet
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
The aim of the following piece is simply to share some interesting accounts of the tin-trade in the thirteenth and fourteenth centuries, particularly one written in Arabic and another in Persian. Taken together, these two accounts suggest that tin from southwestern England (<i>i.e.&nbsp;</i>Cornwall and Devon) was exported via southern France to both Egypt and ultimately Iran in this period, with it being used by potters in the latter area to make tin-opacified ceramic glazes.</p><div><div><p>The first account to be considered here is a short but intriguing section from the early fourteenth-century&nbsp;<i>Taqwīm al-buldān</i>, 'Survey of the countries' (1321), of Abū l-Fidāʾ, a Syrian prince of the Ayyūbid family, which offers both a general description of England and a short but intriguing section detailing the export of tin from England to Alexandria, Egypt, via southern France. The section that deals generally with England is explicitly derived from the earlier work of&nbsp;Ibn Saʿīd al-Maghribī, who was born born near Granada in 1213, lived for a time in Egypt, and died in 1286, and runs as follows:&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>And the islands of Britain are eleven islands. Of the famous islands is the island of England (<i>Inkiltarah</i>). Ibn Saʿīd said: And the ruler of this island is called <i>al-Inkitār</i> in the <i>History of Salāḥ&nbsp;ad-Dīn (Saladin) in the wars of ʿAkkā (Acre)</i>. His capital in this island is the city of <i>Lundras </i>(London). He continued: And the length of this island from south to north, with a slight inclination, is 430 miles. Its width in the middle is about 200 miles. He continued: <b>And in this island are mines of gold, silver, copper, and tin</b>. There are no vines because of the sharpness of the frost. <b>Its inhabitants bring the precious metals of these mines to the land of France, and exchange them for wine.</b> The ruler of France has plentiful gold and silver from that source. In their country (sc. England) is made the fine scarlet wool of their sheep, which is fine like silk. They place coverings over the animals, to protect them from rain, sun, and dust. In spite of the wealth of <i>al-Inkitār</i> and the extent of his kingdom, he admits the sovereignty of <i>al-Farans</i><i>īs</i>&nbsp;(the French king), and when there is an assembly, he performs his service by presenting before (the ruler of France) a vessel of food, by ancient custom.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn1">1</a>)</p></blockquote><p>The mention here of mines that produce tin is noteworthy. The tenth-century Persian <i>Ḥudūd al-ʿĀlam</i>, written for a prince of Gūzgan in northern Afghanistan in <i>c.&nbsp;</i>982, intriguingly describes Britain as an 'emporium' (<i>bārgāh</i>) of Spain (<i>Andalus</i>) and also makes mention of 'numerous mountains, rivers, villages, and different mines' in Britain, but doesn't specify the nature of these mines, unlike Ibn Saʿīd and Abū l-Fidāʾ.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn2">2</a>) Interestingly, the above description of the specific characteristics of the mines of England seems to have been picked up fairly rapidly by other authors aside from Abū l-Fidāʾ. For example, its influence can be seen in the&nbsp;<i>Jāmiʿ al-tawārīkh</i> of Rashīd al-Dīn (completed in&nbsp;Īlkhānate-era Iran,&nbsp;<i>c.</i>&nbsp;1307–16), and in Banākatī's derivative&nbsp;<i>Rawżat ūli’l-albāb</i>,&nbsp;written in 1317 at Banākaṯ, Transoxiana (in present-day Tajikistan, Central Asia), although their description is expanded slightly to say that in <i>Anglater</i>—England—there are 'many remarkable mountains, innumerable mines of gold, silver, copper, tin, and iron, and different kinds of fruit.'(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn3">3</a>)&nbsp;</p><p>After the above general description of England, Abū l-Fidāʾ offers brief discussions of Ireland and of another Atlantic island where gyrfalcons and polar bears are said to be found (the former reportedly being popular with the Sultan of Egypt and the latter being said to have skin that is soft to the touch). Later on, however, he returns to the question of the export of metals from England when discussing Toulouse, France, in another section that is explicitly derived from the work of Ibn Saʿīd al-Maghribī:</p><blockquote><p>Ibn Said said: And to the east of Bordeaux is the city of Toulouse... The river (sc. Garonne) is south of it, and ships from the Encircling Ocean ascend it, with tin and copper, which they bring from the island of England and the island of Ireland. It is carried on pack-animals to Narbonne, and taken from there on the ships of the Franks to Alexandria.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn4">4</a>)</p></blockquote><p>Needless to say, this statement is undoubtedly interesting, offering, as it does, good evidence for the long-distance export of tin from southwestern England during the thirteenth and fourteenth centuries. The first half of the route described here is certainly an ancient one, bearing a striking similarity to the tin route described by Diodorus Siculus in the first century BC (probably drawing on the lost account of Pytheas, a fourth-century BC traveller from Marseille). He says that those who dwell in southwestern Britain 'work the tin into pieces' and sell it to merchants who 'carry it from there across the Straits of Galatia or Gaul; and finally, making their way on foot through Gaul for some thirty days, they bring their wares on horseback to the mouth of the river Rhone'. Although the route described by the above Arabic account is slightly more detailed than that recorded by Diodorus, and obviously has an additional stage from France to Egypt, the coincidence is notable, and a find of a sixth-century cruciform brooch from eastern England in south-eastern France near to Castelnaudary, Aude (about midway along the route from Toulouse to the Mediterranean), arguably offers some confirmation that the same overland route from England to the Mediterranean was indeed in use in the intervening period too.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn5">5</a>)</p><table><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LA9ShHsnFc8/X8AbV7cybxI/AAAAAAADMBg/VR4mW-G9pEA_OTBQhJZpo5bDgwkm8meAgCLcBGAsYHQ/s2048/14thC-Persian-tin-Jug-large.jpg"><img data-original-height="597" data-original-width="500" height="478" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jSQfeF5o0L8/X8AbVPJ2gwI/AAAAAAADMBc/jB-Be7EM_08qt5oLNuogahanX57kC3IYwCLcBGAsYHQ/s16000/14thC-Persian-tin-Jug-500.jpg" width="400"></a></td></tr><tr><td><i>A fourteenth-century, tin-glazed jug decorated with lustre and cobalt, made at Ray, Iran, and now in the Royal Cornwall Museum, Truro; click the image for a larger view (image: Caitlin Green).<br></i></td></tr></tbody></table><p>The second, Persian account of the medieval tin trade is less specific about the source of the tin than this, but is nonetheless important. In particular, it offers us some idea of where a portion, at least, of the tin from southwestern England was transported to after it reached thirteenth-/fourteenth-century Egypt, as well as the purposes to which it might be put. The account itself is from a treatise on ceramics by Abū l-Qāsim Qāshānī of Kashan, Iran, that was written in <i>c.</i>&nbsp;1300–01, based on the date of the earliest, autograph manuscript. This treatise mentions the importation of tin to Iran from Western Europe or <i>Farangistān</i>, a name strictly meaning the land of the Franks (the French) that was applied generally to Western Europe north of the Iberian Peninsula:&nbsp;</p><blockquote><p>The vessels, ingredients and materials which serve as raw materials for these people [manufacturers of tiles and other ceramic objects] are many... One of these is the form of tin called <i>raṣāṣ</i>. <u>Its mines are known in many places. The first is that from Farangistān.</u> In Farangistān it is cast in the form of pieces and stamped with a Farangī stamp <u>as prevention against adulteration</u>...(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn6">6</a>)</p></blockquote><p>The account then goes on to list two other sources of tin, one to the north of Iran (in the middle Volga area of modern Russia) and another to the east in 'China' (possibly Malaysia), before including details on how such tin could be used in the making of white and turquoise ceramic glazes.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn7">7</a>) Suffice to say, in the present context this account is of considerable interest. The tin from&nbsp;<i>Farangistān</i>&nbsp;mentioned here must have almost certainly originated in southwestern England, based on both what we know of tin production in this era and the above Arabic account of Abū l-Fidāʾ/Ibn Saʿīd al-Maghribī, with its reference to French merchants transporting English tin to Alexandria. Furthermore, it is worth noting that the tin from the middle Volga in Russia may also have ultimately come from England too, as there were no medieval native sources of tin in that region and tin does, in fact, seem to have been imported into Russia from England via Germany earlier in the medieval period.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn8">8</a>)&nbsp;</p><table><tbody><tr><td><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9KT_vElMz1k/X8AcRscMyAI/AAAAAAADMB0/-tSBWeTbGMYi-3SWIDhx77h9oy7OzBvJQCLcBGAsYHQ/s2159/Two13thCBowlFrags-large.jpg"><img data-original-height="209" data-original-width="500" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UFD0U70naiA/X8AcRBf2k_I/AAAAAAADMBw/bE_2YVlhlkQTiUbO68Q_Jjw22whtXN5QgCLcBGAsYHQ/s16000/Two13thCBowlFrags-500.jpg"></a></td></tr><tr><td><i>Two fragments of mina'i bowls probably made in the city of Kashan in the early thirteenth century, both featuring a tin-opacified glaze, now in the Royal Cornwall Museum, Truro; click the image for a larger view. The left bowl, TRURI 900.479, seems to show a young prince sitting cross-legged, whilst the right bowl, TRURI 900.478, shows a male equestrian figure (image: Caitlin Green).<br></i></td></tr></tbody></table><p>In consequence, it can be said that the two main accounts under consideration here seem, when taken together, to suggest that tin from Cornwall and Devon was very probably making its way across to Iran in the late thirteenth and early fourteenth centuries, where it was used to create tin-opacified white and turquoise ceramic glazes by manufacturers of pottery and tiles. In this context, it is worth observing that Cornish or Devonshire tin was definitely used for a similar purpose in sixteenth-century Italy, and&nbsp;Anna McSweeney has recently argued that it was probably used for making opaque ceramic glazes in medieval Iberia too.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn9">9</a>) So, for example, in 1417 a potter named Hacen Muça was paid by a French merchant from Montpellier, Joan Lorenç, in lead, tin and cobalt to undertake work that he was to deliver to the port of Valencia in two months, presumably using tin obtained by this French merchant from southwestern England, and in 1325 another contract specifies that the potter Mahomet Bensuleyman and another <i>saracen&nbsp;</i>from Manises, eastern Spain, would be paid in advance with lead and tin for the kiln loads that they were to supply.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn10">10</a>)&nbsp;</p><p>Whether earlier Islamic ceramics using tin-opacified glazes similarly depended on tin from southwestern England is a matter of speculation, but it is interesting to observe that the earliest such glazes seem to have their origins in Egypt in the eighth century AD, which is perhaps suggestive, given that tin seems to have been known as 'the Brittanic metal' in Egypt only a century earlier.(<a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html#fn11">11</a>) Finally, it should be noted that the tin imported into Iran from medieval England was almost certainly used for purposes other than the creation of ceramic …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html">https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.caitlingreen.org/2020/11/arabic-and-persian-accounts-of-cornish-tin-trade.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26043133</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 01:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Resignation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 143 | Comments 93 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26041401">thread link</a>) | @mpweiher
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://www.andymills.work/resignation | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.andymills.work/resignation">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-content-field="main-content">
            
            <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1612552823625" id="page-601d7a506f42587aa4d93797"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-601d7a506f42587aa4d93798"><div><div><p>Today I’m resigning from The New York Times. Those are not words I ever wanted to write.</p><p>Growing up, I never even imagined that I would get the chance to live in New York City or to work in media -- let alone at the paper of record. I’m from a tiny town of a thousand people in the middle of the corn fields of Illinois. I paid my way through Christian College working as a groundskeeper, a dishwasher, a roofer, and at summer jobs in factories and on farms.</p></div><p>And yet, I ended up having the chance to work for the most important news organization in the world. And I have loved it. I have been able to collaborate with some of the most talented, passionate and creative journalists in the world. I’ve been so proud and grateful for what we’ve been able to accomplish together.&nbsp;</p><p>When I was hired as the first full-time audio producer at The Times, the audio department was just an idea, nurtured in an old closet with grey foam panels glued to the walls on the 16th floor. Now it is a pillar of The Times’ journalism and a model for the industry.&nbsp;</p><p>Together with Lisa Tobin, Theo Balcomb, and Michael Barbaro, I helped create The Daily in 2017. Since then I’ve gone on to help create and develop series like Rabbit Hole with Kevin Roose and The Field with The Times’ politics team. And, of course, in 2018 I helped create and produce the most ambitious project I’ve ever worked on: Caliphate.</p><p>While I remain proud of our team and what we were able to accomplish with Caliphate, getting any aspect of any story wrong, by any degree, is a journalist’s worst nightmare. After Caliphate was corrected, in print and in audio, peers of mine in the audio industry, from outside of The Times, began to raise questions about why I had been allowed to remain in my position.&nbsp;</p><p>There are answers to these questions: When it came to fact-checking support for the project, the Times’ leadership told us that they had their own internal system in place for stories of this nature. That system broke down. And they did not blame us. In fact, throughout The Times’ reexamination of Caliphate, they told our production team that we’d engaged in rigorous and careful journalism. One masthead editor even made it a point to tell me: “I won’t let you blame yourself.”</p><p>But in the meantime, another story emerged online: that my lack of punishment came down to entitlement and male privilege. That accusation gave some the opportunity to resurface my past personal conduct.</p><p>Like all human beings, I have made mistakes that I wish I could take back. Nine years ago, when I first moved to New York City, I regularly attended monthly public radio meet up parties where I looked for love and eventually earned a reputation as a flirt. Eight years ago during a team meeting, I gave a colleague a back rub. Seven years ago I poured a drink on a coworker’s head at a drunken bar party. I look back at those actions with extraordinary regret and embarrassment.&nbsp;</p><p>All of this happened while I was working at WNYC. When my managers there confronted me with how my unprofessional behavior was making people feel, I was ashamed. I apologized to the individuals that I’d learned I had upset or made uncomfortable. And I was punished. I received a warning from WNYC’s HR department that I needed to be more professional or look for work elsewhere. I was told to meet with a professional work-place trainer. I was a production assistant at the time, and the promotion to producer that I had been working toward was denied.&nbsp;</p><p>I took this reckoning seriously and I continued to work at WNYC for nearly two more years without further incident.&nbsp;</p><p>When I started working at The Times, in 2016, I was open with my bosses and colleagues about this experience and what I’d learned from it. They said that they appreciated my candor and defended me publicly, including in New York Magazine in 2018.</p><div><p>At The Times, I have strived to continue to grow and be a better co-worker and person, and not repeat the mistakes of my 20s. All of my reviews have reflected that. Each year as the team grew, I was promoted to higher levels of leadership. In December, my latest promotion was finalized: I was to become our audio department’s director of development. “Ride or die baby! I’m thrilled about this. You are a treasured colleague and an insane talent. So much to come! Looking forward to toasting,” wrote the assistant managing editor who oversees The New York Times’s audio report.&nbsp;</p><p>But that was not to be. The allegations on Twitter quickly escalated to the point where my actual shortcomings and past mistakes were replaced with gross exaggerations and baseless claims. Several people have even alleged that I am a predator and a dangerous threat to my colleagues. I have been transformed into a symbol of larger societal evils. As a journalist, it has been especially discouraging and upsetting to see fellow journalists make such claims or retweet them.&nbsp;</p></div><p>The entire experience has been extraordinarily painful. I know I’m not supposed to say that because people will claim that I’m trying to make myself the victim. I know that I still have a lot of room to grow as a person - I can be overly zealous and talk over people, making them feel unheard. I know that this whole letter opens me up to more public shaming and ridicule. But public shaming is very painful. That is the truth. So is leaving the job you love.</p><p>And yet, that’s what I feel I need to do. As the pressure of this online campaign has grown to encompass some staffers of The Times, it has led to a climate where, even though I still love the mission of this important institution, I feel it is in the best interest of both myself and my team that I leave the company at this time. I do this with no joy and a heavy heart.</p><p>To the journalists, editors, colleagues and friends who’ve reached out with words of encouragement and support over the past several weeks, thank you from the bottom of my heart. Your calls and notes have meant more to me than you can know.</p><p>To all my colleagues with whom I’ve had the chance to collaborate on such important and ambitious journalism projects throughout these last several years, I will miss working with you dearly. I wish you all the very best. I will keep cheering you on.</p><p>At some point, maybe I’ll tell this story more fully, but I got into this work to tell other people’s stories. And for now, I’m going to get back to that.</p><p>Andy</p></div></div></div></div></div>
          </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.andymills.work/resignation</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26041401</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 21:24:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Notes on My Chemotherapy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26041001">thread link</a>) | @whatrocks
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://www.charlieharrington.com/chemotherapy | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.charlieharrington.com/chemotherapy">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Nobody likes an addendum.</p>
<p>Appendices are great (ask any Tolkien fan). P.S.'s are <em>the best</em> (especially if they're from a penpal).</p>
<p>But addendums. Nope. They change the rules, after you've started playing. After the game's over, even.</p>
<p>I recently got dropped with this whopper of an addendum:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>Orcein stains performed on blocks A3 and A5 highlight elastic fibers
wrapping around nests of tumor cells, consistent with vascular invasion</code></pre></div>
<h2>A lil' background</h2>
<p>Previously, on "Halt and Catch Cancer", I thought I was in the clear. Sure, I'd been <a href="https://www.charlieharrington.com/colon-cancer">diagnosed with Stage II colon cancer at age 34</a>. But the neato robotic surgery to remove my sigmoid colon (and my grisly barnacle of a tumor) was successful, with no signs of the cancer spreading to the nearby lymph nodes (which are essentially the Information Superhighway of your body's immune system).</p>
<p>Officially, we're talking a PT3N0 pathology, where N means the number of lymph nodes with tumor cells (zero, in my case, of the 21 that were removed and inspected) and T means the levels of colon wall that the tumor "broke through." N0 is awesome and T3 is not-so-awesome. My tumor was pretty darn close to breaking through the colon wall. But the fact that I had no lymph nodes affected was a good sign -- a good enough sign that no chemotheraphy was being recommended by my USCF doctor crew.</p>
<p>Now, after my blog post on this whole "cancer sitch," I'd been in touch with friends and other wood-workers who were, unfortunately, familiar with this process. One, in particular, has been highly tuned into the research and literature around colon cancer, and he pushed me to make sure I fully understood my pathology. He also mentioned that he's seen folks with my PT3N0 pathology do chemotherapy on a preventative basis. Given that my big missive in my last post was about "becoming your own health advocate," his advice hit hard, because I was already lapsing in my attentiveness. Frankly, I was exhausted from the surgery, relieved by the results, ready to move on, and the pathology report itself was confusing af.</p>
<p>Actually, you know what? I'm just going to paste it here:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>FINAL PATHOLOGIC DIAGNOSIS
Sigmoid colon, sigmoid colectomy:
1. Adenocarcinoma, moderately-differentiated, invasive through
muscularis propria into pericolic adipose tissue, negative margins; see
comment.
2. No tumor in twenty-one lymph nodes (0/21).
COMMENT:
COLON CARCINOMA SYNOPTIC COMMENT
- Procedure: Sigmoid colectomy.
Result Information
All Reviewers List
Pathology PDF Report
Narrative &amp; Impression
Harrington, Charles
- Location of tumor: Sigmoid colon.
- Tumor size: 3.3 x 2.5 x 1 cm.
- Macroscopic tumor perforation: Not identified.
- Histologic Type: Adenocarcinoma.
- Histologic Grade: Moderately-differentiated (low grade).
- Microscopic depth of invasion: Tumor invades through the muscularis
propria into pericolic soft tissue (pT3).
- Margins: Negative.
 - Proximal margin: Negative (tumor is &gt; 4 cm from margin).
 - Distal margin: Negative (tumor is &gt; 4 cm from margin).
 - Circumferential (radial) margin: Negative (tumor is &gt; 3 cm from
margin).
- Treatment effect (modified Ryan score, scale 0-3): No known
presurgical therapy.
- Lymphovascular invasion: Not identified on H&amp;E (orcein stains will
be performed on blocks A3 and A5, and the results will be reported as an
addendum).
- Perineural invasion: None.
- Tumor Deposits: Not identified.
- Lymph node status: Negative (number of lymph nodes examined: 21).
- Other pathologic findings: None identified.
- AJCC Pathologic Stage: pT3N0.
- Ancillary studies: Immunohistochemistry for DNA mismatch repair
proteins will be reported in an addendum.

Addendum Comment
Immunohistochemistry was performed to evaluate the status of DNA
mismatch repair protein expression on block A3. The results in the tumor
cell nuclei are:
MLH1 expression: Present.
PMS2 expression: Present.
MSH2 expression: Present.
MSH6 expression: Present.
Expression for all four markers, in most cases, indicates that the DNA
mismatch repair proteins are intact. This result should be correlated
with the clinical presentation and family history to determine the need
for further work up for Lynch syndrome</code></pre></div>
<p>Probably TMI, but this will actually be easier for me to find later, instead of spelunking through the oh-so-painful EPIC MyChart software. Am I allowed to share this? I DON'T KNOW AND I DON'T CARE.</p>
<p>As you can see, this plaintext nightmare is full of strange and wonderous medical terms. Yes, the doctors walk you through it but still... it's a lot. I did push them to explain the terms, like what negative margins mean and why they're a good thing, although I kind of forget already so I won't try to explain.</p>
<p>After this walk-through with the docs, I felt good about my plan. No chemo needed. Just ongoing tests and CT scans and blood work and colonoscopies over the next five years to make sure that the cancer wasn't back, led by the UCSF Cancer Survivorship Clinic. Sure, that wasn't nothing, but it also isn't that bad, considering how lucky I am to have caught this thing and gotten it removed ASAP. The idea was, after five years, I'd be back in the general population for risk of colon cancer. <em>Cured</em>.</p>
<p>But then, during my first Survivorship Clinic convo in November, I recalled that one line from the pathology... the one mentioning the addendum that I hadn't yet seen. I ask about it. We dig in, and we find this:</p>
<div data-language="text"><pre><code>Addendum Comment
Orcein stains performed on blocks A3 and A5 highlight elastic fibers
wrapping around nests of tumor cells, consistent with vascular invasion</code></pre></div>
<p><code>Consistent with vascular invasion</code>. Welp, that can't be good.</p>
<p>At this point, I'm immediately whisked off the UCSF Oncology Department.</p>
<h2>New faces and new tests and new plans</h2>
<p>A hospital is a series of interconnected rings, all slightly Venn Diagramming each other, kind of like the Olympics logo. As a patient, you tend to orbit one of the rings. But sometimes you'll Three Body Problem your way over to another ring.</p>
<p>In my entire diagnosis and surgery process, I'd never made it over to the Oncology (aka cancer) ring -- I was stuck in Surgery World. But, after this addendum, I'm now squarely in their circle.</p>
<p>So, what's our goal now? Well, now that we've noticed that my cancer has slightly spread into the vascular system, we need to figure out what to do about it. First, let's remember the good stuff - the rest of the pathology is relatively awesome. Next, let's get some more data!</p>
<p>We do these tests:</p>
<ul>
<li>Signatera - looks in your blood for tumor cells</li>
<li>Oncotype - looks at your tumor and rates the likelihood of recurrence</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Let me reiterate that my explanations of these tests (and anything medical-related) is entirely my random-dudeman-laymen's explanation. I hope to provide one person's context and interpretation of these confusing and scary things. I'm open to feedback and information on what I can do better.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Insurance aside</h3>
<p>Insurance didn't want to cover the Oncotype test, because, of course. Insurance doesn't want to cover a lot of things, especially brand new "cutting edge" stuff, like the Oncotype test.</p>
<p>Instead, insurance wants to make sure that you really-super-duper-need whatever it is they're going to give you, to the point where there's basically no way they can say no. My doctors have been amazing advocates for me, helping make sure that insurance knows how important these tests and treatments are for my health. THANK YOU, UCSF.</p>
<p>Insurance is frustrating and scary. I do not understand it. I do not want to understand it. I wish it was simpler. I wish I didn't have to make sure that I was "covered" for things related to my health and my family's health. I also know that I'm incredibly lucky to have good insurance. I took a screenshot from my insurance app back in December:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/c27e7/bill.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="insurance bill" title="insurance bill" src="https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/a6d36/bill.png" srcset="https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/222b7/bill.png 163w,
https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/ff46a/bill.png 325w,
https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/a6d36/bill.png 650w,
https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/e548f/bill.png 975w,
https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/3c492/bill.png 1300w,
https://www.charlieharrington.com/static/b7291d13e21492cbff924ada73137851/c27e7/bill.png 2144w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>WTF. That's an insane amount of money. But my life was saved, sooo...? The insurance company even assigned me a nurse to "check in on me" as a resource back in November and December, which sadly was more of a nuisance than anything else. And, then, when my company switched insurance providers at the beginning of 2021, this nurse service stopped abruptly. The whole thing's odd. But I can say again that I am extremely grateful to have had good insurance during my cancer treatment.</p>
<h3>Make a new plan</h3>
<p>The Signatera is clear, which is great. No circulating tumor cells in my blood. I ask the question, "Doesn't this mean I'm, like, good for life now?" And apparently no. They can't say that. They can only say, "We don't see anything right now." It's the balance sheet of cancer. Just cause things look good right now doesn't mean that next year or next quarter's gonna be the same. Past performance is no indication of future something-something.</p>
<p>Oncotype's pretty good, too. From what the doc explains, this test suggests that my tumor has a 12% recurrence rate. This is a low number and I should be happy about it. And I am. But I want it to be zero, obviously. Also, recurrence isn't talking about new polyps growing in my butt and starting cancers -- that can still happen. Recurrence is about whether cells from my now-removed cancer tumor are going rear their awful heads again, somewhere else in my body.</p>
<p>It's at this point that we get into the discussion around chemo. There's evidence that chemo can help reduce the recurrence rate even further. My oncology team brings my data to this cool-sounding UCSF "Tumor Board" meeting, and they advise a chemo treatment. The evidence suggests that we can bring down my recurrance rate from 12% to 6%.</p>
<p>But they also reiterate that it's my choice. I can say no. As my aforementioned friend said, "You don't do chemo recreationally." In fact, the doctors explain that if I were an old man, they might not advise treatment. But since I'm young and restless, it makes more sense for me to do whatever I can to improve my chances.</p>
<p>Duh, let's do this thing.</p>
<h2>So, what's chemotherapy like?</h2>
<p>Well, first of all, there's all different kinds of chemo. I didn't know that. I'm on a combo …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.charlieharrington.com/chemotherapy">https://www.charlieharrington.com/chemotherapy</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.charlieharrington.com/chemotherapy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26041001</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 20:49:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Balthazar Personal Computing Device, a 13” RISC-V laptop]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26040427">thread link</a>) | @SamWhited
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://balthazar.space/wiki/Balthazar | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://balthazar.space/wiki/Balthazar">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://balthazar.space/wiki/Balthazar</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26040427</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 19:50:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Remarkbox – Hosted comments without ads or tracking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 226 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26038501">thread link</a>) | @foxhop
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://www.remarkbox.com/remarkbox-is-now-pay-what-you-can.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.remarkbox.com/remarkbox-is-now-pay-what-you-can.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p><span>


<p>I reject big tech's monopoly on moderation. </p>
<p>In these strange times during 2021 I have found myself longing for an Internet controlled by the people and <em>not powered</em> by a global dragnet on the common person (often mislabelled as advertisement). These "advertisements" are <a href="https://www.stuartmcmillen.com/comic/supernormal-stimuli/#page-1">superhuman stimuli</a> which track and follow <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shadow_profile" target="_blank">all humans</a>.
</p>

<p>
I consider these sorts of "advertisements" to be a form digital stalking (an outlawed, mentally and emotionally abusive action). </p>
<p>Big tech nudges YOU for attention and nudges YOU to spend. Big tech uses computers to track and profile preferences, tolerances, sex, geo-location, race, political affiliation, and more with the aim of to exploring and exploiting you, your family, your friends... everyone.</p>

<p>
We must demand updates to our laws to prevent big tech from hiding behind their terms of service and corporate protections while claiming it is legal to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyberstalking" target="_blank">cyberstalk</a> all humans. </p>
<p>Get yourself out of the loop! We are all absolutely addicted to this stuff. These psychic manipulations work on the subconscious of all animals; no one is immune.</p>
<p>The future doesn't have to be doom and gloom. We can build a better way. We may not be able to compete with their datacenters or balance sheets, but perhaps we don't need to. </p>
<p>We must keep the conversation going and we must not shut down speech. We must not be afraid to talk, otherwise we will lose our ability to find compromise and a healthy path forward. </p>
<p><strong>Starting today, Remarkbox is free.</strong></p>
<p>If this resonates with you, follow this two-minute <a href="https://my.remarkbox.com/setup" target="_blank">guided setup</a> to use the software anywhere that supports HTML (web pages, static blogs). </p>
<p>We already have our own platforms, it's about time we start using them! </p>
<p>Most of the groundwork has already been laid out. Let's roll up our sleeves and build! </p>
<p>If you have ideas, software, or tech which could be operationalized to help build a new social cloud, please reach out to me, I would like to hear from you. </p>
<p><a href="https://russell.ballestrini.net/contact/" target="_blank">https://russell.ballestrini.net/contact/</a></p>
<p>I leave you with this: be good to one another, use your speech to move people positively and follow the virtuous path, stay civil and moderate your own online discourse. </p>
<p>Those who control the narrative control history, and the future. Let us not stand idle during these times. We must not allow the powerful to have a monopoly on the moderation of speech. </p>
<p>Regardless of the labels and stereotypes tossed my way (even by friends), I choose freedom, and I choose to speak. I hope you do too. </p>
<p>We must not accept the old normal or the new normal. We have not been defeated, we must not be domesticated by the powerful. Let's build a better future together.</p>
<p>As always, please act civil when you speak your mind in the comments box below. I'd like to hear you, but I will moderate the discourse if things go sour.</p>
<p> After all I have that power, and so do you. </p>

<p>Russell Ballestrini
<br>
Remarkbox Founder
<br>
Wed Feb  3 09:06:21 EST 2021
</p>

<!-- Remarkbox - Your readers want to communicate with you -->



</span></p>



  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.remarkbox.com/remarkbox-is-now-pay-what-you-can.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26038501</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 17:06:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Will India Ban Twitter?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26037336">thread link</a>) | @laurex
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://www.platformer.news/p/will-india-ban-twitter | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.platformer.news/p/will-india-ban-twitter">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><article><div><h3>After a dramatic escalation in tensions, tweets risk going the way of TikToks</h3><table><tbody><tr><td><div><a href="https://www.platformer.news/people/241262-casey-newton"><p><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_90,h_90,c_fill,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F248e369b-4a49-4f75-90c9-a56e773cdaad_869x1303.jpeg" alt=""></p></a></div></td><td><div><div><p><a href="https://www.platformer.news/people/241262-casey-newton">Casey Newton</a></p></div><table><tbody><tr><td><svg role="img" style="height:20px;width:20px;" width="20" height="20" viewBox="0 0 18 18" fill="none" stroke-width="0.9" stroke="#000" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><g><title></title><rect x="6.5" y="4.5" width="5" height="11" rx="2.5" stroke="#B6B6B6"></rect><rect x="4.5" y="9.5" width="9" height="6" rx="0.5" fill="#B6B6B6" stroke="#B6B6B6"></rect></g></svg></td><td>Feb 4</td><td><span><span><svg role="img" width="15" height="20" viewBox="0 0 15 20" fill="none" stroke-width="1" stroke="#000" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><g><title></title><path d="M1.73624 5.1145C2.43974 4.37137 3.37095 4 4.3036 4C5.23626 4 6.16745 4.37137 6.87097 5.1145L7.49949 5.77892L8.1227 5.11986C9.52973 3.63357 11.8557 3.6336 13.2627 5.11986C14.6698 6.60612 14.6698 8.98642 13.2627 10.4727C11.4639 12.3728 9.66583 14.2737 7.86703 16.1738C7.81927 16.2242 7.76183 16.2643 7.6982 16.2918C7.63456 16.3192 7.56606 16.3333 7.49683 16.3333C7.42761 16.3333 7.3591 16.3192 7.29547 16.2918C7.23184 16.2643 7.1744 16.2242 7.12664 16.1738L5.77904 14.7472L3.08384 11.8939L1.73624 10.4673C0.331003 8.98011 0.329213 6.60074 1.73624 5.1145Z" stroke="#999999"></path></g></svg><svg role="img" style="height:20px;width:15px;" width="15" height="20" viewBox="0 0 15 20" fill="none" stroke-width="1" stroke="#000" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><g><title></title><path d="M1.73624 5.1145C2.43974 4.37137 3.37095 4 4.3036 4C5.23626 4 6.16745 4.37137 6.87097 5.1145L7.49949 5.77892L8.1227 5.11986C9.52973 3.63357 11.8557 3.6336 13.2627 5.11986C14.6698 6.60612 14.6698 8.98642 13.2627 10.4727C11.4639 12.3728 9.66583 14.2737 7.86703 16.1738C7.81927 16.2242 7.76183 16.2643 7.6982 16.2918C7.63456 16.3192 7.56606 16.3333 7.49683 16.3333C7.42761 16.3333 7.3591 16.3192 7.29547 16.2918C7.23184 16.2643 7.1744 16.2242 7.12664 16.1738L5.77904 14.7472L3.08384 11.8939L1.73624 10.4673C0.331003 8.98011 0.329213 6.60074 1.73624 5.1145Z" stroke="#999999"></path></g></svg> 11</span></span></td><td><a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/will-india-ban-twitter/comments"><svg role="img" style="height:20px;width:14px;" width="14" height="20" viewBox="0 0 14 20" fill="none" stroke-width="1" stroke="#000" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><g><title>Comment</title><path d="M7.47092 13.7982L7.32727 13.6656H7.13176H2.14118C1.22171 13.6656 0.5 12.944 0.5 12.0679V6.09766C0.5 5.22165 1.22171 4.5 2.14118 4.5H11.8588C12.7783 4.5 13.5 5.22165 13.5 6.09766V12.0679C13.5 12.944 12.7783 13.6656 11.8588 13.6656H10.5412H10.0412V14.1656V16.1657C10.0392 16.1649 10.0339 16.1625 10.0255 16.1565L7.47092 13.7982Z" stroke="#999999"></path></g></svg> 1</a></td><td><span><span><svg role="img" style="height:20px;width:11px;" width="11" height="20" viewBox="0 0 11 20" fill="none" stroke-width="1" stroke="#999999" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"><g><title>Share</title><path d="M4.125 6H1.6875C1.13522 6 0.6875 6.44772 0.6875 7V13.6667C0.6875 14.219 1.13522 14.6667 1.6875 14.6667H9.3125C9.86478 14.6667 10.3125 14.219 10.3125 13.6667V7C10.3125 6.44772 9.86478 6 9.3125 6H6.875"></path><path d="M2.75 4.33333L5.5 2L8.25 4.33333"></path><path d="M5.5 2V10"></path></g></svg></span></span></td></tr></tbody></table></div></td></tr></tbody></table></div><div><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F0f22d31a-5095-47a7-bd7a-17ef3c28b5f1_1024x683.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F0f22d31a-5095-47a7-bd7a-17ef3c28b5f1_1024x683.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/0f22d31a-5095-47a7-bd7a-17ef3c28b5f1_1024x683.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:683,&quot;width&quot;:1024,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:159647,&quot;alt&quot;:&quot;People in India protesting attacks on farmers and a partial internet ban. The protests are at the heart of a conflict between India and Twitter. (Pradeep Gaur / Getty Images)&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt="People in India protesting attacks on farmers and a partial internet ban. The protests are at the heart of a conflict between India and Twitter. (Pradeep Gaur / Getty Images)"></a><figcaption>People in India protesting attacks on farmers and a partial internet ban. The protests are at the heart of a conflict between India and Twitter. (Pradeep Gaur / Getty Images)</figcaption></figure></div><p>Today, let’s talk about a crackdown on free speech and what it portends for the future of the global internet.</p><p>A thing that happens to large technology platforms over time is that go…</p></div><div><h2>This post is for paying subscribers</h2><div></div><div><p><a href="https://www.platformer.news/account/login?redirect=%2Fp%2Fwill-india-ban-twitter&amp;email=&amp;with_password=" native="">Already a paying subscriber? <b>Sign in</b></a></p></div></div></article><div><p><a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/andy-jassys-platform-problems">← Previous</a><a href="https://www.platformer.news/p/a-top-trump-critic-leaves-the-oversight">Next →</a></p></div></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.platformer.news/p/will-india-ban-twitter</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26037336</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:28:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AWS Cheat Sheets]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 99 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26036772">thread link</a>) | @totaldude87
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://tutorialsdojo.com/aws-cheat-sheets/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tutorialsdojo.com/aws-cheat-sheets/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Our <strong>AWS cheat sheets</strong> were created to give you a bird’s eye view of the important AWS services that you need to know by heart to be able to pass the different <strong>AWS certification exams</strong> such as the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, as well as the other Associate, Professional, and Specialty certification exams. It’s presented mostly in bullet points to provide you with easy-to-digest and easy-to-remember notes that will help you gain a better understanding of the different AWS services.</p><p>While these AWS cheat sheets will save you from going through all the AWS documentations, we still highly recommend that you read those as well as the whitepapers to supplement your exam preparations. Also, check out these helpful <strong><span><a href="https://tutorialsdojo.com/aws-study-path-notes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS exam study guides</a></span></strong> which contain tips and resources that you can use while reviewing for your AWS certification exam.</p><p>We also recommend that you answer as many <strong><a href="https://portal.tutorialsdojo.com/all-courses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span>AWS practice test questions</span></a></strong> as you can to further increase your chances of passing the exam. And if you want to access only the <span><strong>relevant</strong></span> cheat sheets for the specific AWS exams that you are preparing for then check out the <a href="https://portal.tutorialsdojo.com/product-category/aws-ebooks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong><span>Tutorials Dojo Study Guide and Cheat Sheets eBooks</span></strong></a>.</p><p>All the best!</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tutorialsdojo.com/aws-cheat-sheets/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26036772</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 14:44:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Modifying Telegram's “People Nearby” feature to pinpoint people's homes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 227 | Comments 65 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26036613">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://owlspace.xyz/cybersec/tg-nearby/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://owlspace.xyz/cybersec/tg-nearby/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><article><header></header><p>One morning I woke up and found that Telegram implemented a new feature called “People Nearby”. If you choose to share your location publicly on Telegram, you’ll appear in a list for users who are physically close to you. Not only that, but they’ll also see just how far away you are down to the meter. However, you don’t need to share your own location in order to see where people around you are located. These are perfect prerequisites to find out just how accurate this feature really is and, more importantly, whether or not it can be used to find out where nearby Telegram users live.</p><h3 id="privacy-101-your-location-isnt-anyones-business">Privacy 101: Your location isn’t anyone’s business</h3><p>If you’ve never heard of this feature and you suddenly feel the urge to delete your Telegram account forever, let me stress something very important: <strong>“People Nearby” is opt-in</strong>. By default, no one can see how far away you are on Telegram. You’ll only ever end up in other people’s lists by pressing the “Make Myself Visible” button. If you choose to try it out, remember to disable it once you’re done.</p><figure><img src="https://owlspace.xyz/images/tg-nearby/share-publicly.png" alt="Telegram's prompt to share your location using the &quot;People Nearby&quot; feature"><figcaption><p>JUST DON’T PRESS THIS BUTTON OKAY?</p></figcaption></figure><p>Once you share your location, every nearby Telegram user will be able to look at your profile. This may include, <strong>if explicitly specified in your privacy settings</strong>, your user handle, your first and last name, your phone number, your bio and all your profile pictures. People will see exactly how far away you are. Strangers may message and call you. It is also worth noting that “People Nearby” allows you to see public groups in your proximity. Again, any user may read all messages, view all shared media and links and see all group members without actually joining the group. Joining is only necessary for active participation.</p><p><strong>Do not make yourself publicly visible on Telegram unless you have a very, very good reason. Be aware that you’ll end up exposing a significant amount of personal data to the people around you.</strong> I assume that the majority of people who will be reading through this article are privacy-aware to some extent, and I can only call on people’s rational thinking to treat this feature with the care that it requires. Be safe out there, people!</p><h3 id="a-feature-begging-to-be-exploited">A feature begging to be exploited</h3><p>There have been many different tech outlets warning about the dangers of the “People Nearby” feature almost immediately after it was introduced. <a href="https://blog.ahmed.nyc/2021/01/if-you-use-this-feature-on-telegram.html">Ahmed’s Notes</a> was one of the first to report its implications to the public and to Telegram’s bug bounty program. Telegram later responded saying that the feature is working as intended, and that users must explicitly consent to having their location shared with others around them. So as it stands, it’s a feature that is likely to stay.</p><figure><img src="https://owlspace.xyz/images/tg-nearby/ahmed-location.png" alt="Screenshot of Ahmed's Notes on Telegram's &quot;People Nearby&quot; feature, showcasing how to determine strangers' locations"><figcaption><p>In fact, they use a similar method compared to what I’m going to present in this post, except I’ll be supercharging it</p></figcaption></figure><p>Whether you agree with how the “People Nearby” feature works is up to you. I will be sharing my personal thoughts at the end of this post. Regardless, I want to go on a quick tangent before I delve into the nerdy stuff. As mentioned at the beginning, I stumbled upon this feature randomly and found myself wanting to know how it works. I messaged my roommate about it who stayed in a different city back then. And within a few minutes, I found a new entry at the top of my list of nearby people: my roommate.</p><p>He had spoofed his GPS location on his phone to put himself six meters away from me. He then shared a screenshot of the app he used to fake his location and, indeed, he put himself right into my bedroom. This meant that not only was the distance shown for every user pretty accurate, but it also updated very frequently. I’m using the word “was” here because Telegram made the decision to not display any distances below 100 meters since then. However, we’ll soon find out that this is just a drop in the ocean, and that the accuracy we lose because of this change is easily regained.</p><h3 id="everything-at-our-feet">Everything at our feet</h3><p><a href="https://github.com/DrKLO/Telegram">Telegram’s Android messenger</a> is, like most of its core components, open source. This means that everyone can peek into the source code, copy it, edit it and create their own version of the Telegram app with whatever features they need. In Android, user interfaces and functionalities are organized into so-called activities. As such, the “People Nearby” feature finds itself in the <a href="https://github.com/DrKLO/Telegram/blob/eb2bbd32c17fa7f50009404f73b8a6a630f31bfb/TMessagesProj/src/main/java/org/telegram/ui/PeopleNearbyActivity.java">PeopleNearbyActivity</a>.</p><p>The code that requests a list of nearby users resides in the <code>sendRequest</code> function. It is called pretty much everytime the activity is navigated to and whenever the app receives a location update. The time period between location updates is ultimately decided by the operating system, but the Telegram Android app requests to receive updates as soon as possible.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="java"><span>/*
</span><span>    this code can be found in the LocationController class.
</span><span>    here, the app requests to receive location updates whenever
</span><span>    the users moves at least 1 meter, or after 0 milliseconds.
</span><span>    so basically, this is screaming "give me updates whenever you can".
</span><span>    see: https://developer.android.com/reference/android/location/LocationManager#requestLocationUpdates(java.lang.String,%20long,%20float,%20android.location.LocationListener)
</span><span>*/</span>
<span>locationManager</span><span>.</span><span>requestLocationUpdates</span><span>(</span><span>LocationManager</span><span>.</span><span>GPS_PROVIDER</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>gpsLocationListener</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div><p>When <code>sendRequest</code> is called, the app uses the last known device location and sends it off to Telegram’s servers. In return, the app receives a list of nearby entities. In addition to their unique Telegram IDs, these entities also contain their distance in meters to the submitted coordinates as well as an expiration timestamp. From what I found out, users who share their location publicly will have their expiration timestamp set to the maximum signed integer value <code>0x7fffffff</code>, meaning they technically “never” expire.</p><p>The app then iterates over all received entities and puts them into a list of either nearby users or groups. Since I’m only interested in the former, I can just add my code before or after users are added to their respective lists. Fortunately, the Telegram source code contains a class called <a href="https://github.com/DrKLO/Telegram/blob/99f5637dda59bc405734342d3e2448701d63f2d3/TMessagesProj/src/main/java/org/telegram/messenger/FileLog.java">FileLog</a> which prints debug information to the system log as well as a file log located on the device’s external storage, if present. So all I had to do was to dump the user entity information to the file log on every location update.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="java"><span>TLRPC</span><span>.</span><span>User</span> <span>user</span> <span>=</span> <span>getMessagesController</span><span>().</span><span>getUser</span><span>(</span><span>peerLocated</span><span>.</span><span>peer</span><span>.</span><span>user_id</span><span>);</span>
<span>FileLog</span><span>.</span><span>d</span><span>(</span><span>String</span><span>.</span><span>format</span><span>(</span><span>Locale</span><span>.</span><span>ENGLISH</span><span>,</span> 
    <span>"peer update [distance=%d, id=%d, displayName=\"%s\", expires=%d]"</span><span>,</span> 
    <span>peerLocated</span><span>.</span><span>distance</span><span>,</span>           <span>// distance in meters
</span><span></span>    <span>peerLocated</span><span>.</span><span>peer</span><span>.</span><span>user_id</span><span>,</span>       <span>// telegram id
</span><span></span>    <span>UserObject</span><span>.</span><span>getUserName</span><span>(</span><span>user</span><span>),</span>   <span>// displayed name
</span><span></span>    <span>peerLocated</span><span>.</span><span>expires</span><span>));</span>          <span>// expiration timestamp
</span></code></pre></div><p>Additionally, I logged the location that triggered the request for nearby users with everything the <a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/android/location/Location">Android Location API</a> offered. Then it is as easy as following the instructions in the Telegram Android app repository to install my custom Telegram version onto my Android device. I then wrote a short Python script to feed the data I accumulated into a SQLite database to run some queries on it later.</p><h3 id="excellent-math-in-an-imperfect-world">Excellent math in an imperfect world</h3><p>So now we have the ability to feed all data that “People Nearby” provides into a database. How do we find <del>hot</del> Telegram users in our area? Let’s assume that we live in a perfect world where there’s no measuring inaccuracies whatsoever. Let’s also assume that the earth is a plane (unless you’re a flat-earther, in which case you don’t need to perform any extra mental gymnastics). If we’re trying to find the coordinates of one particular user, then we need to look at how far away they are at every logged location.</p><p>The process of solving for a point’s coordinates given a set of known points with known distances to that particular point is called trilateration. At every recorded location, we can imagine a circle with the radius of the distance to the unknown point. Ideally, all circles will then intersect at exactly one point which is the one we’re looking for. However, to find a concrete solution, we need at least three points in a plane in order to solve this problem.</p><figure><img src="https://owlspace.xyz/images/tg-nearby/trilateration.png" alt="Trilateration with three known points for an unknown point in a plane, perfect intersection on the left, overlaps on the right"><figcaption><p>Trilateration in a perfect world (left) and in our world (right)</p></figcaption></figure><p>But we don’t live in a perfect world. The earth is not flat (what a shocker!) and GPS coordinates always have some sort of inaccuracy. This means that our own and other users' locations mustn’t be accurate. The circles, which are actually ellipses once mapped onto the earth’s surface, won’t intersect in one location, if at all. We’re more likely to get an area where a lot of our known ellipses overlap as opposed to a definitive point on earth’s surface. And to top it all off, we can’t be sure that Telegram is actually providing us with accurate measurements.</p><p>Luckily, all this is no big deal. Let’s think back to locations as points on a plane. If we were to make an educated guess as to where the unknown point could be, then its distance from our known points will deviate from the distances we recorded. This is an error that we can calculate and all of a sudden, the task of finding a point’s coordinates on a plane turns into an optimization problem. We’re trying to find a point such that the computed distance error is minimal.</p><figure><img src="https://owlspace.xyz/images/tg-nearby/trilateration-mse.png" alt="Trilateration but taking a guess for the unknown point, resulting in differences between measured and computed distance"><figcaption><p>Notice how the guessed point doesn’t align perfectly with the measured distances</p></figcaption></figure><p>Such an optimization method is minimizing the mean squared error. There have been countless explanations of this method in particular and I won’t be covering how or why it works. Instead, I recommend you read <a href="https://www.alanzucconi.com/2017/03/13/positioning-and-trilateration/">this article</a> by Alan Zucconi who explains the math and its implementation in Python at the example of — you guessed it — trilateration. Instead, I want to touch on one more problem I encountered before delving into the fun part of visualizing all the collected data.</p><p>I said at the beginning that Telegram won’t show distances below 100 meters. If someone is within your 100 meter radius, Telegram will simply report them being 100 meters away for you, no matter how close they are to you. This appears not only on the frontend, but also …</p></article></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://owlspace.xyz/cybersec/tg-nearby/">https://owlspace.xyz/cybersec/tg-nearby/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://owlspace.xyz/cybersec/tg-nearby/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26036613</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 14:27:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Script Lisp]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 86 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26035837">thread link</a>) | @rcarmo
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://sharpscript.net/lisp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sharpscript.net/lisp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="body">

        

        <div id="content">
            
            <p><code>#Script</code> is designed as a small, expressive and wrist-friendly dynamic scripting language that for maximum familiarity
is modelled after the world's most popular and ubiquitous scripting Language, JavaScript. Its minimal syntax was inspired 
by other small but powerful languages which heavily utilizes functions instead of adopting a larger language grammar 
defining different bespoke syntax for language constructs.</p>
<p>Small Languages like Smalltalk, despite being one of the most influential languages in history, is famous for its minimal
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smalltalk#Syntax">syntax that fits on a post card</a>. A language with arguably better power 
to size ratio is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lisp_%28programming_language%29">Lisp</a> which the inventor of
Smalltalk, Alan Kay has credited it as being
the <a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Lisp_%28programming_language%29">greatest single programming language ever designed</a>
after realizing: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>“the half page of code on the bottom of page 13… was Lisp in itself. These were 
<a href="http://www.michaelnielsen.org/ddi/lisp-as-the-maxwells-equations-of-software/">“Maxwell’s Equations of Software!”</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://languagelog.ldc.upenn.edu/myl/llog/jmc.pdf">Lisp's unprecedented elegance and simplicity</a> spawned a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Lisp-family_programming_languages">myriad of dialects</a>,
some noteworthy implementations illustrating the beauty of its small size and expressive power is <a href="http://norvig.com/lispy.html">lispy</a> by
by <a href="http://norvig.com/">Peter Norvig</a> (Director of Google Research) that implements a Lisp interpreter in just <strong>117 lines of Python 3 code</strong> (inc. a REPL).</p>
<p>Another compact dialect is <a href="https://github.com/zick/ZickStandardLisp">Zick Standard Lisp</a> which <a href="https://github.com/zick">@zick</a> 
has implemented in <strong>42 different languages</strong> including a <a href="https://github.com/zick/ZickStandardLisp/blob/master/lisp.lsp">recursive Lisp evaluator in Lisp</a>
implemented in only <strong>66 lines of code</strong>.</p>
<p>A more complete Lisp implementation in C# is the elegant <a href="https://github.com/nukata/lisp-in-cs">Nukata Lisp</a> 
by <a href="https://github.com/nukata">SUZUKI Hisao</a> which is a 
Common Lisp-like <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/q/4578574/85785">Lisp-1</a> dialect with tail call optimization and partially hygienic macros, although
has some notable limitations including a <a href="https://github.com/nukata/lisp-in-cs/blob/d4258ec4b5681b0854a0d464b708df9ae26bbe3c/lisp.cs#L1216-L1391">small standard library</a>, 
only uses the <code>double</code> numeric type and doesn't contain .NET Scripting support.</p>
<h3>Script Lisp Overview</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ServiceStack/ServiceStack/blob/master/src/ServiceStack.Common/Script/ScriptLanguage.Lisp.cs">ScriptLisp</a> is an
enhanced version of <a href="https://github.com/nukata/lisp-in-cs">Nukata Lisp</a> with a number of new features
that reuses <code>#Script</code> existing scripting capabilities to provide seamless integration with both the rest of <code>#Script</code>
(see <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/syntax#language-blocks-and-expressions">Language Blocks an Expressions</a>)
and .NET including <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/script-net">Scripting of .NET Types</a>, support for all .NET numeric types and access to its comprehensive 
library of over <strong>1000+</strong> <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/methods">Script Methods</a> - optimally designed for accessing .NET functionality from a dynamic language.</p>
<p>To improve compatibility with existing Common Lisp source code it also implements most of the <a href="http://jtra.cz/stuff/lisp/sclr/">Simplified Common Lisp Reference</a>
as well as all missing functions required to implement C# LINQ 101 Examples in Lisp:</p>

<p>To improve readability and familiarity it also adopts a number of <strong>Clojure</strong> syntax for defining a 
<a href="https://clojure.org/guides/learn/syntax#_literal_collections">data list and map</a> literals, 
<a href="https://clojure.org/guides/learn/functions#_anonymous_function_syntax">anonymous functions</a>, 
syntax in <a href="https://clojure.org/guides/learn/functions#_java_interop">Java Interop</a> for .NET Interop,
<a href="https://clojure.org/guides/learn/hashed_colls#_field_accessors">keyword syntax for indexing collections</a> and accessing index accessors
and Clojure's popular shorter aliases for <code>fn</code>, <code>def</code>, <code>defn</code> - improving source-code compatibility with Clojure.</p>
<h3>Lisp REPL</h3>
<p>In addition to being a 1st class language option in <code>#Script</code>, Lisp's dynamism and extensibility makes it particularly 
well suited for explanatory programming whose access via a REPL is now built into the latest 
<a href="https://docs.servicestack.net/dotnet-tool">x</a> and <a href="https://docs.servicestack.net/netcore-windows-desktop">app</a> dotnet tools 
which can be quickly installed in any Windows, macOS or Linux OS (with <a href="https://dotnet.microsoft.com/download/dotnet-core/3.0">.NET Core</a>) with: </p>
<pre><code>$ dotnet tool install -g x
</code></pre>

<p>Or if you have a previous version installed, update to the latest version with:</p>
<pre><code>$ dotnet tool update -g x
</code></pre>

<p>Where you'll then be able to bring up an instant Lisp REPL with:  
</p>
<pre><code>$ x lisp
</code></pre>

<p>The quick demo below shows the kind of exploratory programming available where you can query the <code>scriptMethods</code> available, 
query an objects <code>props</code>, query the Lisp interpreter's global <code>symbols</code> table containing all its global state including all 
defined lisp functions, macros and variables:</p>
<iframe width="896" height="525" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RR7yk6ReNnQ" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
<h3>Annotated REPL Walk through</h3>
<p>Here's an annotated version of the demo below which explains what each of the different expressions is doing.</p>
<p>Just like <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/sharp-scripts">Sharp Scripts</a> and <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/sharp-apps">Sharp Apps</a> the Lisp REPL runs within the 
<a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/sharp-pages">#Script Pages</a> ScriptContext <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/sandbox">sandbox</a> that when run from a Sharp App folder, 
starts a .NET Core App Server that simulates a fully configured .NET Core App. 
In this case it's running in the <a href="https://github.com/sharp-apps/redis">redis Sharp App</a> directory where it was able to access its static web assets
as well as its redis-server connection configured in its <a href="https://github.com/sharp-apps/redis/blob/master/app.settings">app.settings</a>.</p>

<div><div><pre><span><span>;</span> quick lisp test!</span>
(+ <span>1</span> <span>2</span> <span>3</span>)

<span><span>;</span> List of ScriptMethodInfo that the ScriptContext running this Lisp Interpreter has access to</span>
scriptMethods

<span><span>;</span> first script method</span>
(:<span>0</span> scriptMethods)

<span><span>;</span> show public properties of ScriptMethodInfo </span>
(props (:<span>0</span> scriptMethods))

<span><span>;</span> show 1 property per line</span>
(joinln (props (:<span>0</span> scriptMethods)))

<span><span>;</span> show both Property Type and Name</span>
(joinln (propTypes (:<span>0</span> scriptMethods)))

<span><span>;</span> view the Names of all avaialble script methods</span>
(joinln (map .Name scriptMethods))

<span><span>;</span> view all script methods starting with 'a'</span>
(globln <span><span>"</span>a*<span>"</span></span> (map .Name scriptMethods))

<span><span>;</span> view all script methods starting with 'env'</span>
(globln <span><span>"</span>env*<span>"</span></span> (map .Name scriptMethods))

<span><span>;</span> print environment info about this machine seperated by spaces</span>
(printlns envOSVersion envMachineName envFrameworkDescription envLogicalDrives)

<span><span>;</span> expand logical drives</span>
(printlns envOSVersion envMachineName envFrameworkDescription <span><span>"</span>- drives:<span>"</span></span> (join envLogicalDrives <span><span>"</span> <span>"</span></span>))

<span><span>;</span> view all current global symbols defined in this Lisp interpreter</span>
symbols

<span><span>;</span> view all symbols starting with 'c'</span>
(globln <span><span>"</span>c*<span>"</span></span> symbols)

<span><span>;</span> see how many symbols are defined in this interpreter</span>
(count symbols)

<span><span>;</span> see how many script methods there are available</span>
(count scriptMethods)

<span><span>;</span> view the method signature for all script methods starting with 'all'</span>
(globln <span><span>"</span>all*<span>"</span></span> (map .Signature scriptMethods))

<span><span>;</span> count all files accessible from the configured ScriptContext</span>
(count allFiles)

<span><span>;</span> view the public properties of the first IVirtualFile</span>
(props (:<span>0</span> allFiles))

<span><span>;</span> display the VirtualPath of all available files</span>
(joinln (map .VirtualPath allFiles))

<span><span>;</span> display the method signature for all script methods starting with 'findFiles'</span>
(globln <span><span>"</span>findFiles*<span>"</span></span> (map .Signature scriptMethods))

<span><span>;</span> see how many .html files are available to this App</span>
(count (findFiles <span><span>"</span>*.html<span>"</span></span>))

<span><span>;</span> see how many .js files are available to this App</span>
(count (findFiles <span><span>"</span>*.js<span>"</span></span>))

<span><span>;</span> show the VirtualPath of all .html files</span>
(joinln (map .VirtualPath (findFiles <span><span>"</span>*.html<span>"</span></span>)))

<span><span>;</span> view the VirtualPath's of the 1st and 2nd .html files</span>
(:<span>0</span> (map .VirtualPath (findFiles <span><span>"</span>*.html<span>"</span></span>)))
(:<span>1</span> (map .VirtualPath (findFiles <span><span>"</span>*.html<span>"</span></span>)))

<span><span>;</span> view the text file contents of the 1st and 2nd .html files</span>
(fileTextContents (:<span>0</span> (map .VirtualPath (findFiles <span><span>"</span>*.html<span>"</span></span>))))
(fileTextContents (:<span>1</span> (map .VirtualPath (findFiles <span><span>"</span>*.html<span>"</span></span>))))

<span><span>;</span> display the method signatures of all script methods starting with 'redis'</span>
(globln <span><span>"</span>redis*<span>"</span></span> (map .Signature scriptMethods))

<span><span>;</span> search for all Redis Keys starting with 'urn:' in the redis-server instances this App is configured with</span>
(redisSearchKeys <span><span>"</span>urn:*<span>"</span></span>)

<span><span>;</span> display the first redis search entry</span>
(:<span>0</span> (redisSearchKeys <span><span>"</span>urn:*<span>"</span></span>))

<span><span>;</span> display the key names of all redis keys starting with 'urn:'</span>
(joinln (map :id (redisSearchKeys <span><span>"</span>urn:*<span>"</span></span>)))

<span><span>;</span> find out the redis-server data type of the 'urn:tags' key</span>
(redisCall <span><span>"</span>TYPE urn:tags<span>"</span></span>)

<span><span>;</span> view all tags in the 'urn:tags' sorted set</span>
(redisCall <span><span>"</span>ZRANGE urn:tags 0 -1<span>"</span></span>)

<span><span>;</span> view the string contents of the 'urn:question:1' key</span>
(redisCall <span><span>"</span>GET urn:question:1<span>"</span></span>)

<span><span>;</span> parse the json contents of question 1 and display its tag names</span>
(:Tags (parseJson (redisCall <span><span>"</span>GET urn:question:1<span>"</span></span>)))

<span><span>;</span> extract the 2nd tag of question 1</span>
(:<span>1</span> (:Tags (parseJson (redisCall <span><span>"</span>GET urn:question:1<span>"</span></span>))))

<span><span>;</span> clear the Console screen</span>
clear

<span><span>;</span> exit the Lisp REPL</span>
quit</pre></div>
</div>

<h4>Enable features and access resources with app.settings</h4>
<p>You can configure the Lisp REPL with any of the resources and features that <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/sharp-apps">Sharp Apps</a> and 
<a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/gist-desktop-apps">Gist Desktop Apps</a> have access to, by creating a plain text <code>app.settings</code> file with all the 
features and resources you want the Lisp REPL to have access to, e.g. this <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/sharp-apps#pure-cloud-apps">Pure Cloud App app.settings</a>
allows the Lisp REPL to use <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/db-scripts">Database Scripts</a> against a AWS PostgreSQL RDS server and query remote 
<a href="https://docs.servicestack.net/virtual-file-system">S3 Virtual Files</a> using <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/protected-scripts#virtual-file-system-apis">Virtual File System APIs</a>:</p>
<pre><code># Note: values prefixed with '$' are resolved from Environment Variables
name AWS S3 PostgreSQL Web App
db postgres
db.connection $AWS_RDS_POSTGRES
files s3
files.config {AccessKey:$AWS_S3_ACCESS_KEY,SecretKey:$AWS_S3_SECRET_KEY,Region:us-east-1,Bucket:rockwind}
</code></pre>

<p>See the <a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/sharp-apps#registering-servicestack-plugins">plugins app.settings</a> for examples of how to load and configure 
<a href="https://docs.servicestack.net/plugins">ServiceStack Plugins</a>.</p>
<h3>Lisp REPL TCP Server</h3>
<p>In addition to launching a Lisp REPL from the Console above, you can also open a Lisp REPL into any ServiceStack App 
configured with the <code>LispReplTcpServer</code> ServiceStack plugin. This effectively opens a <strong>"programmable gateway"</strong> into any 
ServiceStack App where it's able to perform live queries, access IOC dependencies, invoke internal Server functions and query
the state of a running Server which like the <a href="https://docs.servicestack.net/debugging#debug-inspector">Debug Inspector</a> 
can provide invaluable insight when diagnosing issues on a remote server.</p>
<p>To see it in action we'll enable it one of our production Apps <a href="https://techstacks.io/">techstacks.io</a> which as it's a 
Vuetify SPA App is only configured with an empty <code>SharpPagesFeature</code> as it doesn't use any server-side scripting features.</p>
<p>We'll enable it in <code>DebugMode</code> where we can enable by setting <code>DebugMode</code> in our App's <code>appsettings.Production.json</code> 
which will launch a TCP Socket Server which by default is configured to listen to the <strong>loopback</strong> IP on port <code>5005</code>.</p>

<div><div><pre><span>if</span> (<span>Config</span>.<span>DebugMode</span>)
{
    <span>Plugins</span>.<span>Add</span>(<span>new</span> <span>LispReplTcpServer</span> {
        <span>ScriptMethods</span> <span>=</span> {
            <span>new</span> <span>DbScripts</span>()
        },
        <span>ScriptNamespaces</span> <span>=</span> {
            <span>nameof</span>(<span>TechStacks</span>),
            <span><span>$"</span>{<span>nameof</span>(<span>TechStacks</span>)}.{<span>nameof</span>(<span>ServiceInterface</span>)}<span>"</span></span>,
            <span><span>$"</span>{<span>nameof</span>(<span>TechStacks</span>)}.{<span>nameof</span>(<span>ServiceModel</span>)}<span>"</span></span>,
        },
    });
}</pre></div>
</div>

<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://sharpscript.net/docs/script-net#type-resolution">ScriptNamespaces</a> behaves like C#'s <code>using Namespace;</code> statement letting you reference Types 
by <code>Name</code> instead of its fully-qualified Namespace.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Whilst you can now connect to it with basic <code>telnet</code>, it's a much nicer experience to use it with the <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/1/rlwrap">rlwrap</a>
readline wrap utility which provides an enhanced experience with line editing, persistent history and …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://sharpscript.net/lisp/">https://sharpscript.net/lisp/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sharpscript.net/lisp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26035837</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 13:04:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[“I am dying of a broken heart” (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26034608">thread link</a>) | @johnchristopher
<br/>
February 5, 2021 | https://papyrus-stories.com/2018/10/10/i-am-dying-of-a-broken-heart/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://papyrus-stories.com/2018/10/10/i-am-dying-of-a-broken-heart/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-169">

	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		<p><span><strong>*GUEST POST by Moudhy Al-Rashid (see her bio <span><a href="https://papyrus-stories.com/guest-writers/">here</a></span>)</strong></span></p>

<p><span>The Neo-Assyrian physician Nabû-tabni-uṣurseems once upon a time for reasons we may never know to have fallen out of favour with the court. Unlike his colleagues, he no longer received compensation for his work. Payments promised by the court never materialised. Concern for his financial well-being and his position in the court snowballed into fear. Gripped by anxiety, he penned – or, rather, impressed – this letter to the king.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span>“To the king, my lord, your servant Nabû-tabni-uṣur. Good health to the king, my lord!</span></p>
<p><span>…</span></p>
<p><span>If the king, my lord, knows a fault made by me, let the king not keep my alive!</span></p>
<p><span>…</span></p>
<p><span>All my associates are happy, (and) I am dying of a broken heart. I have been treated as if I did not keep the watch of the king, my lord; my heart has become exceedingly troubled, heartbreak has seized me, I have become exceedingly afraid: may the king revive my heart before my colleagues!”&nbsp;</span><span>(ABL 525)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span>Found at Nineveh in the royal library and now housed in the British Museum (K. 590), the cuneiform tablet that carries these words provides a window onto a language for anxiety that overlaps with modern ways of framing worry, fear, and sorrow, a language that centres the heart, or Akkadian <em>libbu</em>,as an organ of thought and emotion. More specifically, a broken heart.</span></p>
<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_170" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-170"><img data-attachment-id="170" data-permalink="https://papyrus-stories.com/2018/10/10/i-am-dying-of-a-broken-heart/p334358/" data-orig-file="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg" data-orig-size="1644,3049" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="P334358" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=162" data-large-file="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=552" src="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=748" alt="P334358.jpg" srcset="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=748 748w, https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=1496 1496w, https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=81 81w, https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=162 162w, https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=768 768w, https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/p334358.jpg?w=552 552w" sizes="(max-width: 748px) 100vw, 748px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-170"><span>ABL 525: Letter from&nbsp;Nabû-tabni-uṣur © Trustees of the British Museum (<span><a href="http://www.britishmuseum.org/research/collection_online/collection_object_details.aspx?objectId=314280&amp;partId=1&amp;searchText=K.590+tablet&amp;page=1">K.590</a></span>)</span></figcaption></figure>
<p><span>Our physician’s description organises his experience of heartbreak along the same lines as those found in contemporary therapeutic medical texts, a rich corpus of texts that describe illnesses and prescribe treatments, like this one from nearby Aššur:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span>“[If] he continually has heartbreak… in his bed he is continually afraid, he suffers paralysis up his form; toward god and king, his heart is filled (with anger), his limbs are poured out repeatedly, on repeated occasions he is afraid; day and night he does not sleep, he continually sees frightening dreams, he continually suffers paralysis; he has no desire for bread or beer; he forgets the words that he speaks.”&nbsp;(BAM 234)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span>Fear, paralysis, nightmares, sleeplessness, loss of appetite, and forgetfulness are recorded as presenting with the condition labelled as heartbreak.</span></p>
<p><span>For anyone who has experienced anxiety, some of these symptoms might sound familiar. In modern biomedical models, anxiety is also described both in mental and physical terms. Adjectives that describe emotional states, like worried, afraid, and nervous, appear alongside descriptions like physical weakness, gastrointestinal problems, and a pounding heart to describe experiences associated with anxiety.</span></p>
<p><span>Symptoms of any illness are labelled according to socially available categories, and it seems that for a Neo-Assyrian physician, the vocabulary for this particular experience of mental distress has echoes in today’s world. And it seems that in the first millennium BCE, it was acceptable to admit, even to a king, that one was suffering emotional anguish.</span></p>
<p><span>Some of the earliest known expressions of mental distress come from ancient Mesopotamia, where ancient scribes impressed into clay words that capture individual, collective, and historical experiences not just of anxiety, but of a whole spectrum of mental health issues, from depressed states to disorganised thoughts.</span></p>
<p><span>So, if you ever you find yourself feeling anxious, remember Nabû-tabni-uṣur and his letter to a Neo-Assyrian king, and remember that you are not alone. These are ancient and human problems. They connect us to the past, and they connect us to each other.</span></p>
<p><strong>Technical Details: ABL 525 </strong></p>
<p><strong>Provenance</strong>: Nineveh (near modern Mosul, northern Iraq)</p>
<p><strong>Date</strong>: Neo-Assyrian (911–612 BCE)</p>
<p><strong>Language</strong>: Akkadian</p>
<p><strong>Collection</strong>: British Museum, London (<a href="http://www.britishmuseum.org/research/collection_online/collection_object_details.aspx?objectId=314280&amp;partId=1&amp;searchText=K.590+tablet&amp;page=1">K.590</a>)</p>
<p><strong>Designation</strong>: ABL 525; <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P334358">Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative P.334358</a></p>
<p><strong>Bibliography</strong>: Simo Parpola (1993)<em>Letters from Assyrian and Babylonian Scholars</em>. State Archives of Assyria 10 (Helsinki: Helsinki University Press): Text 334</p>

<p><strong>Technical Details: BAM 234</strong></p>
<p><strong>Provenance</strong>: Aššur (modern Iraq)</p>
<p><strong>Date</strong>: Middle-Assyrian (ca. 1400–1000 BCE)</p>
<p><strong>Language</strong>: Akkadian</p>
<p><strong>Collection</strong>: Vorderasiatisches Museum, Berlin</p>
<p><strong>Designation</strong>: BAM 234;&nbsp;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P285320">Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative P.285320</a></p>
<p><strong>Bibliography</strong>: Franz Köcher (1963) <em>Die babylonisch-assyrische Medizin in Texten und Untersuchungen</em>. Volume 3 (Berlin: De Gruyter): Text 234</p>
<figure data-shortcode="caption" id="attachment_171" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-171"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="171" data-permalink="https://papyrus-stories.com/2018/10/10/i-am-dying-of-a-broken-heart/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z/" data-orig-file="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z.jpg" data-orig-size="500,332" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z.jpg?w=500" src="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z.jpg?w=642&amp;h=427" alt="3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z" width="642" height="427" srcset="https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z.jpg 500w, https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z.jpg?w=150&amp;h=100 150w, https://papyrusstories.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/3412290769_7a8e901fbb_z.jpg?w=300&amp;h=199 300w" sizes="(max-width: 642px) 100vw, 642px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-171"><span>Kouyunjik Mound near the ancient city of Nineveh (<span><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/28803198@N06/3412290769">Photo by Stephen Lumsden, May 1990</a></span>)</span></figcaption></figure>
			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://papyrus-stories.com/2018/10/10/i-am-dying-of-a-broken-heart/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26034608</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 09:44:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 658 | Comments 193 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26033689">thread link</a>) | @allenleein
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Posts"><li><div data-context="conversation" data-first="true"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>Wayne Goodrich was the producer for every keynote Steve gave after his return to Apple. Before that, Wayne helped him create presentations at NeXT and Pixar. He is writing a book about what it was like on the inside.</p><p><em>This is a panel conversation, which works the same on Cake as panels do in the real world: the audience may be vast, but it’s in everyone’s interest to let the panel speak. You can add energy to Wayne’s fascinating stories in this conversation with emojis like </em><span><span>😱</span></span><em>, just like clapping and laughing does in a physical-world panel. To post comments &amp; questions check out </em><a href="https://www.cake.co/conversations/2Jf7ksx/questions-comments-about-the-wayne-goodrich-panel" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>this conversation</em></a><em>.&nbsp;</em>&nbsp;</p><p>Wayne, we knew each other at NeXT when you were working in hardware product marketing. At the time, I had the harrowing but amazing experience of <a href="https://www.cake.co/conversations/rZXhqtP/that-time-i-had-steve-jobs-keynote-at-unix-expo" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">helping Steve do his Unix Expo keynote</a>.</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/QLZzngCrcmXX_1531329024912.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>I was, but when NeXT stopped making hardware they laid me off. A week later, Steve called me and started to say “okay Wayne, we need to...” I interjected “what do you mean we need to? You laid me off.” He said “oh” and then click.&nbsp;</p><p>Eight months later I heard from my brother, who was still working customer support, “Steve wants you to call. He won’t call you but you should call him.” The result of that conversation led to working directly with Steve on all his most important presentations at Pixar and Apple for nearly the next two decades.&nbsp;</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/mg9r4Mmq9NF9_1531329508101.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>And now you’re writing a book about it!</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Yes, I’m working on it because I was a a unique Insider for 20 years and I'm disappointed at the liberties that people like Aaron Sorkin have taken. I would have gladly helped tell the story the way it really happened, or at least lent some credibility to the parts that should have been historically correct.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>I spoke to Andy Hertzfeld about that. He said Aaron explained that he was making a painting, not a photograph. It’s not supposed to be a documentary, so he felt he had creative license.</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/LJ88BGP2DN4b_1531330037651.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>I know they're making movies, but let's at least get some of the real stuff in there about who Steve was. Let's not purposely put fictitious information into the world that people are going to believe was reality. That’s just wrong in my opinion.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>I’ve heard people say that Steve’s iPhone launch was the greatest presentation in business history. It had heroes and villains, plot twists, humorous sidebars… Did the time you and Steve spend with Pixar influence his keynotes?</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/SdQxm9XxprMv_1531330726448.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>Oh, absolutely! If you look at the primitive narratives in Steve’s presentations at NeXT, you can see the influence that our experience at Pixar had on the storytelling over time that resulted in events like the iPhone launch.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>What few people realize is that, like Pixar movies, there is a color scheme throughout the 90 minutes, and an emotional ramp. And yes there are heroes and villains, action sequences, humor and plot twists. You have to be careful not to wear the audience out. You have to manage building to a climax. Steve understood this better than anyone.</p></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>How much time went into preparing the iPhone demo?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>Quite a lot! That’s the thing, no other CEO would have imagined spending the time Steve invested in his keynotes. For the most important ones, we started 3 or so months out. He would run the company until maybe 2:00 pm and then spend a few hours with me. Then he may start in again in the evening, me at my house and him at his, and we’d stay up until midnight. Sometimes we’d be at it again at 6 am.&nbsp;</p><p>I saw part of my job—and Steve never knew this—as managing his emotional ramp to the event. I’ve even described my job much like being a product manager. There were all kinds of things that could mess that up: the product timing, or the photos that were taken weren’t good enough, or he had a bad day, or we didn’t have all the assets he needed… or at times too many!&nbsp;</p><p>With movies, you never want anything to affect suspension of belief. You want your audience to stay in that magical moment and not think about how things are done.&nbsp;&nbsp;With the iPhone, we wanted to show that if you rotate your phone to landscape mode, the photo would automatically rotate too. But we were not projecting a video of the actual iPhone that Steve was holding in his hand, only the video from the iPhone. That would have made it shaky on the big screen with distracting reflections. </p><p>So we showed a graphic of an iPhone, to look like the Keynote slides, and projected Steve’s demo iPhone screen into the exact right position in the graphic.&nbsp;The trick was that when Steve rotated the iPhone to landscape mode, the right thing to do to keep customers in the moment was to rotate the iPhone graphic with its inserted video feed rotating in sync as well. But how?</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/FYLjTlvKhnRr_1531331370341.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><p>It took a month for one of the brilliant Apple engineers to work out how to do this. It looked natural to the audience and no one had to think about how it happened.&nbsp;</p><p>When Steve saw this happen he first time, he knew it’d be magic and it had to be shown live. He rotated it back and forth several times in his demo and no one ever questioned what they were seeing because it looked exactly they way it should.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>If I remember, the internal estimate of the marketing power of the iPhone demo Steve did that day was in excess of $1 billion of PR spend from demo until we shipped.</p><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/DYlF8vV1XR09_1531331556178.png" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Amazing! Did he take feedback from other people at Apple as the presentation was being constructed?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>He did. We learned from the creative process Pixar uses: iteration in front of people who can shape it by adding constructive feedback. We held high level slide and demo reviews in the town hall facility with people from each group that would be affected by the presentation. These would happen usually a week or two before the event and rehearsals onsite.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Steve was incredibly demanding when I was at NeXT and a lot of people didn’t last. How did you make it 20 years?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>I know that I quit 3 times, one kind of officially via email to HR. God only knows how many times I was actually yelled at and fired but it never went anywhere. Essentially I never really wanted to leave so I didn’t.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>That’s insane. I read an interview of Andy Cunningham who said, “I loved working for Steve Jobs even though he fired me 5 times.” What do you mean it never went anywhere?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><div><p>One afternoon he told me, “God dammit, Wayne. I want you to fucking go home right now and tell me why I shouldn’t fire you tomorrow.” So I went home that night and I probably worked on 15 or 16 versions of an email trying to explain everything. But then I just decided to say “Steve, you know how I feel, but you’re the boss. You let me know tomorrow whether I’m fired or not.” I never heard another word about it.</p><p>The mythology of him mostly comes from individuals that didn't survive around him. The people who got close knew the rules, knew how to work with him, knew his core desires and what he was trying to achieve. They never really had problems with it.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></div><div><p>Someone told me early on that if you do something great, you just have to acknowledge it yourself because you’re not going to get it from him except on a rare occasion. A lot of people who weren’t used to that would come in to present their product plan or whatever, and they would be seeking to make themselves look good and get praise from Steve. If he got a whiff of that, he would rip you down a peg.&nbsp;</p><p>He was usually right because the person usually didn’t do a great job. Those are the ones who flamed out and then had the horrible things to say because they couldn’t admit to themselves that they couldn’t cut the mustard.</p><p>He was a complex individual but he always desired the best out of everybody. He was ultimately very caring. He had his own relationship with my daughter from the age of 4 years old and let her come to rehearsals and events. He even asked her opinion a few times when the team couldn’t decide between particular graphics to use.</p></div><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/j4D3PCrR4Pyl_1531332483022.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>Give us an example of when he went off on you because he expected better.</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><div><p>When we launched the Lifesaver iMacs (the color ones), Steph Adams [Owner of Adams &amp; Asscociates—the outside production company for Apple] and I were trying to bring them out from behind the screen and raise them up out of their pedestals. A week before the event and we were still struggling to synchronize them and make the motion smooth. This was before computer-controlled movement machinery was readily available.</p><p>After mentioning this to Steve, he literally says, “I know the guys from Cirque du Soleil, why don’t you call them?” With one week left, we couldn’t do that so we stuck with our way. It was a hand-crank thing. When you looked at it close, it was really bad. But when you were in the audience, you couldn’t tell unless you knew what to look for. However, Steve was on the stage watching these things not perfectly aligned with a little bit of stuttering. He wasn’t happy and we could see it in the video feed we were watching.</p><p>The show went off, no one ever noticed or mentioned it in the press, but yet he noticed. He pulled me and Steph aside. There were people all around so he didn’t scream or yell at us. It was one of those “I’m really disappointed. At any other time I’d probably fire you.” For ten minutes he went on and on. We looked at each other and just melted into the floor.</p><p>But we came back the next show having done our research. We now had the beginnings of our computer-controlled systems. We could bring things from the back of the stage, under the stage, or out of a cabinet—and twirl them as they emerged. Cirque du Soleil couldn’t do it better than we did it.</p><p>As I look back, if we had not been berated so much, we wouldn’t have seen that these were amazing products and they could have been launched so much better.</p></div><div><div><a href="https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg" itemprop="sharedContent" itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/ImageObject"><img src="https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg?fit=max&amp;fm=pjpg&amp;h=640&amp;q=65&amp;w=680"><meta content="https://cake.imgix.net/m/wl9s4Lpk9wHX_1531333042972.jpeg" itemprop="contentUrl"></a></div></div></div></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>When I did his keynotes at NeXT, I don’t remember him ever being scripted. Did that change?</p></div></div><meta content="The man who produced Steve Jobs’ keynotes for 20 years." itemprop="headline"></article></div></li><li><div data-context="conversation"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/DiscussionForumPosting"><div><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><div><p>That’s the thing most executives don’t get. We never wrote a script. The preview monitor was just the next slide coming up. The Keynote development, the slide sequencing, the simplifying and honing were all part of his method for being as empathetic, emotive, charismatic and precise as he was on stage. It came from time spent …</p></div></div></div></div></article></div></li></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years">https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cake.co/conversations/jNZlq6j/the-man-who-produced-steve-jobs-keynotes-for-20-years</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26033689</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 06:29:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Disqus, a dark commenting system]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 512 | Comments 256 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26033052">thread link</a>) | @supz_k
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://supunkavinda.blog/disqus | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://supunkavinda.blog/disqus">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="content-real">
<p>Disqus is a free commenting system and a great example of "if you're not paying for it, you become the product". Unfortunately, in Disqus' case, your website visitors become the product too.</p><p>Today, I'm going to analyze what happens when you embed Disqus on your website.</p><p>I signed up at <a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a> and added the installation code to a <strong>blank page</strong> (So, I'm sure every HTTP request that the browser makes is from Disqus).</p><p>Disqus makes 76 HTTP requests and fetches 2MB of data! (even with 0 comments). And, it took 7 seconds to load.</p><p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/tCZxbmi.png" alt="Disqus HTTP Requests"></p><p>Disqus <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/12/05/zeta-global-acquires-commenting-service-disqus/">was acquired</a> by an advertising company called Zeta Global in 2017. Obviously, advertising companies do everything to increase their revenue (Ex: the Big G).</p><p>I analyzed the network requests log. Disqus makes HTTP requests to 11 different third-party domains through the browser. <strong>All of these websites are trackers/pixels</strong> (Even some were detected as malware by my security guard).</p><p>Here are the external domains:</p><ul><li><a href="https://viglink.com/">viglink.com</a>* - One of Disqus's major partners. Disqus use Viglink to personalize ads.</li><li><a href="http://io.narrative.io/">io.narrative.io</a> - "The data streaming platform that makes it easy to buy, sell, and win."</li><li><a href="http://live.rezync.com/">live.rezync.com</a> - a pixel website</li><li><a href="https://idsync.rlcdn.com/">idsync.rlcdn.com</a> - another pixel (website returns 404)</li><li><a href="https://netc.sfr.fr/">netc.sfr.fr</a> - another pixel (website returns 404)</li><li><a href="https://p.rfihub.com/">p.rfihub.com</a> - another pixel, malware reports on Google (website returns 404)</li><li><a href="https://pixel.tapad.com/">pixel.tapad.com</a> - pixel, main site titled "WE PROVIDE THE WORLD’S LEADING DIGITAL CROSS-DEVICE GRAPH"</li><li><a href="http://pippio.com/">pippio.com</a> - redirects to liveramp.com, titled "Build better data-driven customer experiences."</li><li><a href="https://ei.rlcdn.com/">ei.rlcdn.com</a>, <a href="https://idsync.rlcdn.com/">idsync.rlcdn.com</a> - website returns 404, GIF pixel used</li><li><a href="http://tag.clrstm.com/">tag.clrstm.com</a></li><li><a href="https://ib.adnxs.com/">ib.adnxs.com</a> - Malware site, "Adnxs appeared as the eighth-biggest name in our Tracking the Trackers data."</li></ul><p>If you are not familiar with Pixels/Trackers, take Facebook as an example. You can place a pixel on your website to share your website traffic data with Facebook. Facebook uses this data for better personalized targeting. According to GDPR, you cannot place the code without your users' consent in the EU region. But, Disqus places all of these pixels on your website (inside their iframe) without any consent.</p><p>*In 2014, Disqus inserted Viglink affiliate links to their client sites intrusively (<a href="https://poststatus.com/disqus-potentially-adding-affiliate-links-users-content-opted/">Source</a>)</p><p>When you provide a free product, money should come from somewhere. Disqus uses advertising for that. Now, I subscribed to a paid plan trial of Disqus to see if things change or not. No! Even in the paid plans, the same pixels are loaded on the client-side. Looks like there's no way to opt-out from tracking.</p><p>Even I title the article "the dark commenting system", I'm not sure if Disqus is a commenting system. Journalist Martin Gundersen once called Disqus a "data machine".</p><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Uncovering the Disqus data machine: <a href="https://twitter.com/disqus?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@disqus</a> shared the personal data of tens of millions of users without them or the websites knowing about it. thread - 1/13 <a href="https://t.co/bLW4Gl2Rhf">pic.twitter.com/bLW4Gl2Rhf</a></p>— Martin Gundersen (@martingund) <a href="https://twitter.com/martingund/status/1207327648093003777?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">December 18, 2019</a></blockquote>  <p>As I stated earlier, Disqus is owned by data/ad company ("Data-driven marketing powered by AI"). This is a large company with more than <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/marketing-software-firm-zeta-global-eyes-ipoonce-again-11583348234">$400 million in annual revenue</a>. They own the "The Web's Largest First-Party Data Set". While Disqus allows third parties like Viglink to directly access your website, they also collect information by themselves and shares them with more third-parties. Twitter has also been one of their old customers. (see <a href="https://data.disqus.com/">data.disqus.com</a>)</p><p>Actually, you give them the consent when you agree to their <a href="https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717103-disqus-privacy-policy">privacy policy</a>.</p><div><p> "Advertising is the predominant way Disqus makes money. Advertising revenue allows Disqus to support and improve the Service. Disqus uses, and also engages third party ad partners and affiliates who use cookie IDs, device IDs (including mobile), hashed email addresses, IP address, ISP and browser information, demographic or interest data, content viewed and actions taken on the Service or Partner Sites, including information about the websites you’ve viewed and advertisements you’ve interacted within order to provide you with more relevant advertising targeted to your preferences and interests derived from your interaction with the Service, Partner Sites or other third party websites." </p><p> "We partner with third parties that collect information across various channels, including offline and online, for purposes of delivering more relevant advertising to you or your business. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms, including but not limited to, computers, mobile devices, over time for advertising (including addressable TV), analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes." - Disqus Privacy Policy</p></div><h3 id="considerprivacyfirstalternatives">Consider Privacy-First Alternatives</h3><p>If you are currently using Disqus on your website and value your user's privacy, consider migrating from Disqus to a privacy-first commenting system. One such service is <a href="https://talk.hyvor.com/">Hyvor Talk</a>, which I founded as a hobby project and now has grown into a profitable SaaS business in less than one year (with 3 employees and growing). At the time of writing this article, we serve 30 million page views per month and provide our privacy-first service for 2000 customers. You can also <a href="https://talk.hyvor.com/docs/import-disqus">import your old Disqus comments</a> to Hyvor Talk.</p><blockquote><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I got so fed up with <a href="https://twitter.com/disqus?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@disqus</a>'s obnoxious ads and disregard for privacy that I finally migrated the comments of my main blog (<a href="https://t.co/2gUgV3yVEM">https://t.co/2gUgV3yVEM</a>) to <a href="https://twitter.com/HyvorTalk?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">@HyvorTalk</a>, a comment system that actual values your privacy. I highly recommend you to do the same!</p>— Bozhidar Batsov (Bug) (@bbatsov) <a href="https://twitter.com/bbatsov/status/1335891387489914880?ref_src=twsrc^tfw">December 7, 2020</a></blockquote>  <p>Feel free to leave a comment below if you have any questions.</p>  <p><strong>Tagged</strong>:
<span>Privacy</span></p></div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://supunkavinda.blog/disqus</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26033052</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 04:17:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Great SameSite Confusion]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26032896">thread link</a>) | @arkadiyt
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                <p>In this post,
I dissect a common misconception about the <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute
and I explore its potential impact on Web security.</p>
<h2 id="tldr">TL;DR <a href="#tldr">¶</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute is not well understood.</li>
<li>Conflating <em>site</em> and <em>origin</em> is a common but harmful mistake.</li>
<li>The concept of <em>site</em> is more difficult to apprehend than meets the eye.</li>
<li>Some requests are cross-origin but same-site.</li>
<li><code>SameSite</code> is only concerned with cross-site requests.</li>
<li><code>SameSite</code> paints a target on your subdomains' back.</li>
<li>Misguided practitioners may unduly eschew <code>SameSite=Strict</code>.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-advent-of-samesite">The advent of <code>SameSite</code> <a href="#the-advent-of-samesite">¶</a></h2>
<p>You have no doubt heard of the
<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-us/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Set-Cookie/SameSite" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute</a>.
It made headlines when, in February 2020,
Chrome started rolling out changes to <code>SameSite</code>’s default behaviour;
Firefox <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/08/changes-to-samesite-cookie-behavior/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">followed suit</a> a few months later.</p>
<p>Intended as a defense-in-depth mechanism against cross-site attacks,
such as <a href="https://owasp.org/www-community/attacks/csrf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cross-site request forgery (CSRF)</a>
and <a href="https://www.scip.ch/en/?labs.20160414" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cross-site script inclusion (XSSI)</a>,
<code>SameSite</code> had been lying dormant at the heart of implementing browsers
since <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-west-first-party-cookies-07" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its inception in 2016</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.chromium.org/2020/02/samesite-cookie-changes-in-february.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>SameSite</code>’s activation in early 2020</a>
required labourious adjustments
by some websites to maintain third-party access,
but was widely hailed as a welcome addition to browser defences.
Both in anticipation and in reaction to <code>SameSite</code>’s activation in browsers,
posts started
sprouting on blogs all over the Web to spread the word
about the mechanics of the “new” cookie attribute.</p>
<h2 id="playing-fast-and-loose-with-terminology">Playing fast and loose with terminology <a href="#playing-fast-and-loose-with-terminology">¶</a></h2>
<p>Some of those posts were of admirable precision,
such as <a href="https://twitter.com/rowan_m" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rowan Merewood</a>’s <a href="https://web.dev/samesite-cookies-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">web.dev piece</a>
entitled “SameSite cookies explained”.
Unfortunately, relatively few of the posts about <code>SameSite</code>
went to the effort of clarifying the concept of <em>site</em>,
from which the concepts of <em>same-site request</em> and <em>cross-site request</em>
are of course derived.</p>
<p>Moreover, many posts,
including those produced by influential members of the infosec community,
appeared to use the terms “origin” and “site” interchangeably or, at least,
somewhat loosely.</p>
<p>Back in February 2019, Kristian Bremberg <a href="https://blog.detectify.com/2019/02/05/guide-http-security-headers-for-better-web-browser-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">wrote the following</a>
on the venerable Detectify blog:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The SameSite attribute is rather new and provides excellent protection
against CSRF attacks. If a cookie uses the SameSite attribute,
the web browser will make sure that the request made with the cookie came
from the <strong>origin</strong> that sat [sic] the cookie.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(my emphasis)</p>
<p>Infosec superstar <a href="https://twitter.com/troyhunt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Troy Hunt</a> himself,
in <a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/promiscuous-cookies-and-their-impending-death-via-the-samesite-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a seminal post</a> entitled
“Promiscuous Cookies and Their Impending Death via the SameSite Policy”
and published in early January 2020, described the effects of the different
<code>SameSite</code> attribute values as follows:</p>
<blockquote>
<ol>
<li>None: what Chrome defaults to today without a SameSite value set</li>
<li>Lax: some limits on sending cookies on a <strong>cross-origin</strong> request</li>
<li>Strict: tight limits on sending cookies on a <strong>cross-origin</strong> request</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>
<p>(my emphasis)</p>
<p>And a few months later, in an otherwise fascinating <a href="https://blog.reconless.com/samesite-by-default/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">post</a>
analysing how the advent of <code>SameSite</code> was affecting a range of vulnerabilities
cherished by hackers,
the <a href="https://twitter.com/0xReconless" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reconless team</a> wrote the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After the update, all cookies without an explicit <code>SameSite</code> attribute will
be treated as having <code>SameSite=Lax</code>.
This means <strong>cross-origin</strong> requests no longer carry cookies,
except for top-level navigations.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(my emphasis)</p>
<p><em>Domain</em>, <em>host</em>, <em>origin</em>, <em>site</em>…
Using those terms loosely in informal communication is natural;
such laxity in the use of terminology can be forgiven,
and if you’ve been guilty of it yourself, you’re in good company.</p>
<h2 id="are-site-and-origin-interchangeable">Are “site” and “origin” interchangeable? <a href="#are-site-and-origin-interchangeable">¶</a></h2>
<p>However, the advent of the <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute raises some questions…</p>
<ul>
<li>Is a careful distinction between “origin” and “site” warranted, here?</li>
<li>Is it just a distinction without a difference?</li>
<li>Is a <em>cross-site</em> request no different from a <em>cross-origin</em> request?</li>
<li>Could the cookie attribute have as well been named “SameOrigin”, then?</li>
<li>Or, if there is indeed a real difference between “site” and “origin”,
does it matter to practitioners?</li>
<li>And, if the difference does matter, how so?</li>
</ul>
<p>You may have already guessed the answers from the title of this post:
“site” has a very technical meaning in the context of <code>SameSite</code>,
yet it is unduly neglected;
and the distinction between <em>site</em> and <em>origin</em> <em>does</em> matter,
yet the two concepts are frequently conflated.</p>
<p>This lapse in terminology didn’t escape everyone.
That Google’s <em>Developer Advocate of Web</em> <a href="https://twitter.com/agektmr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Eiji Kitamura</a>
felt the need to dedicate
a whole <a href="https://web.dev/same-site-same-origin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog post</a>
about the distinction between “origin” and “site”,
only a few months after Chrome activated <code>SameSite</code>, is revealing.</p>
<p>In order to understand why the distinction matters,
you first need to understand the difference between <em>origin</em> and <em>site</em>.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-we-mean-by-origin">What do we mean by “origin”? <a href="#what-do-we-mean-by-origin">¶</a></h2>
<p>If you work with Web technologies,
you have at least some familiarity with the
<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/Same-origin_policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Same-Origin Policy (SOP)</a>,
arguably one of the main pillar of Web security.
The concept of <em>origin</em> of a URI is of course central to the SOP and,
as such, it is relatively well-understood.
<a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc6454#section-3.2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Section 3.2 of RFC 6454</a> defines an <em>origin</em> as a triple:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Roughly speaking, two URIs are part of the same origin
(i.e., represent the same principal) if they have the same
scheme, host, and port.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The port is optional; if not specified, the default port associated to the scheme
is implied (e.g. 80 for <code>http</code> and 443 for <code>https</code>).
<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-us/docs/Glossary/Origin" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MDN Web Docs</a> has a series of useful examples.</p>
<h2 id="what-do-we-mean-by-site">What do we mean by “site”? <a href="#what-do-we-mean-by-site">¶</a></h2>
<p>Behind the painfully generic term that is “site”
hides a concept fundamentally more difficult to grasp
than that of <em>origin</em>.
For one thing, the term “site” was not always a technical one:
it predates the SOP and was in in common use
<a href="https://blog.jeremiahgrossman.com/2006/07/origins-of-cross-site-scripting-xss.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">when attacks like cross-site scripting came onto the scene</a>.
Furthermore, the modern concept of <em>site</em> is fraught with technical difficulties.
It is intimately linked to that of a host’s <em>registrable domain</em>,
which the <a href="https://url.spec.whatwg.org/#host-registrable-domain" target="_blank" rel="noopener">URL Living Standard</a> defines as</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[…] a domain formed by the most specific public suffix,
along with the domain label immediately preceeding it, if any.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(A host’s registrable domain is also known as its “eTLD+1”, short for
“effective top-level domain plus one”.)</p>
<p>In the simplest of cases, <strong>the site of an origin simply corresponds
to the registrable domain (if any) of the origin’s host</strong>.</p>
<p>Two examples, to fix ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li>The site of <code>https://www.example.org</code> is <code>example.org</code>,
because <code>org</code> is the host’s most specific public suffix
and, therefore, <code>example.org</code> is the host’s eTLD+1.</li>
<li>The site of <code>https://jub0bs.github.io</code> is <code>jub0bs.github.io</code>,
because <code>github.io</code> is the host’s most specific public suffix
and, therefore, <code>jub0bs.github.io</code> is the host’s eTLD+1.</li>
</ul>
<p>Yes! Perhaps surprisingly, <a href="https://publicsuffix.org/list/public_suffix_list.dat" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>github.io</code> is a public suffix</a>!</p>
<p>It’s worth noting, however, that the concept of registrable domain is a fluid one,
because it relies on the <a href="https://publicsuffix.org/list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Public-Suffix List</a>,
a list which is not set in stone but <a href="https://github.com/publicsuffix/list/blob/master/public_suffix_list.dat" target="_blank" rel="noopener">subject to change over time</a>.
Not to mention that different browsers may not necessarily stay abreast of
changes to the Public-Suffix list at the same pace.</p>
<p>The technicalities do not end there!
As <a href="https://web.dev/schemeful-samesite/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">web.dev warns us</a>,
the concept of <em>site</em> is still evolving and
will soon incorporate the scheme also.
The change currently sits behind a flag in Chrome but will soon be rolled out.
However, to sidestep this difficulty and prolong the relevance of this post,
I’ll only consider origins whose scheme is <code>https</code> in what follows.</p>
<h2 id="same-site-vs-cross-site-requests">Same-site vs. cross-site requests <a href="#same-site-vs-cross-site-requests">¶</a></h2>
<p>Now that we’ve dealt with the concept of <em>site</em>,
we can finally discuss the concepts of <em>same-site</em> and <em>cross-site</em> requests.
A given request is either <em>same-site</em> or <em>cross-site</em>.
Whether a request is same-site or cross-site depends on the comparison
between the sites of the request’s source origin and target origin:</p>
<ul>
<li>If the two sites are identical, the request is said to be <em>same-site</em>;</li>
<li>If the two sites are different, the request is said to be <em>cross-site</em>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are three examples:</p>
<ol>
<li>A request sent from <code>https://foo.example.org</code> to <code>https://bar.example.org</code>
is same-site,
because the site of both origins is <code>example.org</code>.</li>
<li>A request sent from <code>https://foo.github.io</code>
to <code>https://bar.github.io</code> is cross-site,
because the site of the first origin is <code>foo.github.io</code>,
whereas the site of the second origin is <code>bar.github.io</code>.</li>
<li>A request sent from <code>https://foo.bar.example.org</code> to <code>https://bar.example.org</code>
is same-site, because the site of both origins is <code>example.org</code>.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you’ve made it this far down the present post, I thank you for your patience.
Take heart: the payoff is near!</p>
<h2 id="cross-origin-same-site-requests">Cross-origin, same-site requests <a href="#cross-origin-same-site-requests">¶</a></h2>
<p>All cross-site requests are necessarily cross-origin; that much is clear.
However, as shown by the first and third examples above,
not all cross-origin requests are cross-site.</p>
<p><img src="https://jub0bs.com/images/cor_vs_csr.svg" alt="Venn-diagram"></p>
<p>And the <code>SameSite</code> cookie attribute is only concerned with cross-site requests;
it has no effect on cross-origin requests that happen to be same-site.
This is why the distinction between <em>origin</em> and <em>site</em> is important.</p>
<h2 id="online-demo">Online demo <a href="#online-demo">¶</a></h2>
<p>To prove my point,
I’ve drawn inspiration from <a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/promiscuous-cookies-and-their-impending-death-via-the-samesite-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Troy Hunt’s post</a> and
I’ve deployed a simple Go server to <code>samesitedemo.jub0bs.com</code> composed
of two simple endpoints.
Endpoint <code>/setcookie</code> sets a <code>SameSite=Strict</code> cookie, like so</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="http"><span>Set-Cookie: StrictCookie=foo; Path=/; Max-Age=3600; SameSite=Strict
</span></code></pre></div><p>Endpoint <code>/readcookie</code> prints the cookie (if any) attached to the request.
I’ve also set up two “attacking” pages:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled</a></li>
<li><a href="https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Both pages simply consist in a single link to
<code>https://samesitedemo.jub0bs.com/readcookie</code>.</p>
<p>To fix ideas, here’s what you can do:</p>
<ol>
<li>Navigate to
<a href="https://samesitedemo.jub0bs.com/setcookie" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://samesitedemo.jub0bs.com/setcookie</a>.
Doing so will set the <code>Strict</code> cookie in your browser.</li>
<li>Navigate to
<a href="https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://jub0bs.github.io/samesitedemo-attacker-foiled</a>
and follow the link on that page.
Because the site of the attacking URI (<code>jub0bs.github.io</code>)
is different from that of the target URI (<code>jub0bs.com</code>),
the browser does not attach the cookie to the request resulting from
following the link, and no cookie gets printed in the response.
<code>SameSite=Strict</code> works as expected, and the “attack” is foiled.</li>
<li>Now navigate to
<a href="https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://samesitedemo-attacker.jub0bs.com/</a>
and follow the link on that page.
Because the site of the …</li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/">https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jub0bs.com/posts/2021-01-29-great-samesite-confusion/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26032896</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 03:51:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Road to Utopia: A manifesto for reclaiming a humanist future (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 61 | Comments 129 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26032587">thread link</a>) | @durakot
<br/>
February 4, 2021 | https://culture.io/manifesto | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://culture.io/manifesto">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>









<div>




<article id="1892">



<section id=""><div>
<h2>☼</h2>
<p><span>A manifesto for<br>
</span></p>
<p><span><span>reclaiming a humanist future.</span></span></p>
</div>
    





















<div><figure>



<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither.png" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
    <source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-682x1024.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither.png 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
    <img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-33x50.png" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-341x512.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/hills-dither-682x1024.png 2x" alt="Image" width="1992" height="2992">
</picture>
            </figure></div>

</section>



<section id=""><div><h3><strong>Introduction</strong></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“Bathed in light, the world remains our first and last love.” —Albert Camus</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Anyone writing seriously about utopia in September of 2020 will seem—to be charitable—a little disconnected from reality.</p>
<p>The American West is burning. The Arctic is melting. Populism and authoritarianism are on the rise. Nearly a million people have died from the coronavirus. Economic inequality continues to grow, only accelerated by the pandemic.</p>
<p>If there’s anything like a road to utopia—if we can even begin to entertain such an idea—we don’t seem to be on it. The belief that society’s problems can be solved seems ridiculous when each day brings fresh horrors. Our collective failure to make so much as a dent on climate change, the cancerous spread of polarizing misinformation with its fracturing of society, and the irretrievable damage we are inflicting on the biosphere, only deepen a sense that the best we can hope for now is adaptation and survival in an environment increasingly hostile (physically, psychologically, spiritually) to the individual.</p>
<p>But hope, as “Mad” Max Rockatansky <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MaN4sboc7E8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reminds us from the other side of collapse</a>, is a mistake, and despair paralyzes. What we need are viable alternatives. Alternatives that go beyond bolt-on fixes to broken systems. Alternatives we can imagine living—and thriving—in. And most importantly, alternatives we can look for in our present and in our past, not in some idealized future.</p>
<p>Utopia is in the air again, though few dare call it by that name. Ideas that would be dismissed just a few short years ago as “utopian”—a word that has been cut down to pejorative status—are entering into the mainstream. Political programs like the Green New Deal promise solutions that could spare us from the worst effects of climate change while stimulating the economy. Universal Basic Income and its brethren suggest how we might mend broken social safety nets and ease economic inequality. But what we lack, and urgently need, is a vision of the world we want to bring into being. That’s all utopianism is: the audacity to imagine the world we want, and then living as though that world were possible.</p>
<p>Metals become malleable when subjected to heat. In higher temperatures, they melt, making it possible to cast existing forms into new shapes. Culture I/O is premised on a belief that under certain conditions, the malleability of our society increases as well. The coming decade, more than any other in recent memory, will be turbulent and heated. In the words of Arundhati Roy: <em>“We can choose to walk through it, dragging the carcasses of our prejudice and hatred, our avarice, our data banks and dead ideas, our dead rivers and smoky skies behind us. Or we can walk through lightly, with little luggage, ready to imagine another world. And ready to fight for it.”</em> </p>
<p>The Culture I/O Working Group<br>
Los Angeles &amp; Berlin, 09/2020</p>
</div>
    























</section>



<section id=""><div><blockquote>
<p><span><em>“If you wish to make an apple pie from scratch, you must first invent the universe.” —Carl Sagan</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>A guide to utopia has to start with a foundation of all the concepts feeding into it: ourselves, nature, technology, society, and the other Big Things. It’s easier to go on a journey together if we all leave from the same place.</p>
</div>
    























</section>



<section id="individuals"><div><h3><span>1. Individuals</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“I am neither a liberal nor a conservative…. My holy of holies is the human body, health, intelligence, talent, inspiration, love, and absolute freedom.” —Anton Chekhov</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>A society consists of individuals. Only individuals suffer, experience joy, love, longing, pleasure, pain, act with intent, die. They can do so collectively, but always and only as individuals. <strong>In the end, only individuals matter.</strong></li>
<li>This is an ontological position, not a value judgement. A family or society exists only insofar as its individual members exist.</li>
<li>Because of this, we should reject any ideology that stresses the primacy of a group at the expense of individuals.</li>
<li>Similarly, we should reject any ideology that places a system (such as markets) above individuals.</li>
<li>This should not be taken as an endorsement of individualism. Individuals do not exist in isolation. The point is simply that we should always treat individuals as <em>ends</em>, never as <em>means</em>.</li>
<li>Humans are complex, emotional, self-aware animals with a degree of free will—not rational agents, logic machines, or biological algorithms.</li>
<li>Humans are not the only complex, emotional, self-aware animals on this planet.</li>
<li>The quickest path to dooming any human undertaking is to assume that we can become, or even reliably pretend to be, anything other than what we are—both at our best and at our worst.</li>
</ul>
</div>
    





















<div><figure>



<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
    <source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
    <img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399-40x50.jpg" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399-412x512.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/12050980663_2aea498c77_b-e1604267228399.jpg 2x" alt="Image" width="544" height="676">
</picture>
            </figure></div>

</section>



<section id="minds"><div><h3><span>2. Minds</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“Use your head, can’t you, use your head, you’re on earth, there’s no cure for that!” —Samuel Beckett</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>The human brain is the most mysterious and versatile physical structure in the known world. We know more about how the universe came to be than how the brain works.</li>
<li>The nature of the relationship between brain, mind, and consciousness is the greatest scientific question of our time.</li>
<li>Though we are emotional creatures first and foremost, we are wired for reason. Using only his mind and some crude observations, Aristarchus of the Greek island of Samos figured out that the Earth orbits the Sun almost 2,000 years before this became accepted fact. Einstein produced four of his groundbreaking papers in one year spent hunched over a desk in a musty Bern patent office, with reason as his only instrument.</li>
<li>In spite of these impressive abilities, we are extremely susceptible to biases and fallacies in our thinking—and to those who would exploit these biases.</li>
<li>The either/or fallacy is one of the most pernicious of these errors, passed down to us by Aristotle. It suggests that everything must be either this, or that. Good or bad. Nature or nurture. Introvert or extrovert. Liberal or conservative. It is the binary logic of machines applied to an analog world full of semantic nuance, contradiction, and mystery. If we are, on a species-level, in trouble, it is in large part because of our inability to internalize the fact that multiple ideas which seem opposed to each other can simultaneously be true.</li>
<li>This does not mean that truth is relative. It isn’t. Only that out in the world, truth is more complicated than it seems. If we simplify the world in order to function in it, we do so at our peril.</li>
</ul>
</div>
    





















<div><figure>



<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321.jpg" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
    <source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-768x1024.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321.jpg 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
    <img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-38x50.jpg" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-384x512.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/CC0-img-119-e1604267877321-768x1024.jpg 2x" alt="Image" width="1920" height="2560">
</picture>
            </figure></div>

</section>



<section id="language"><div><h3><span>3. Language</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><span><em>“The map is not the territory.” —Alfred Korzybski</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Words are not reality—they represent abstractions that allow us to make sense of reality, to think and talk about it.</li>
<li>This is important because it means that words do not and cannot map perfectly to reality, and that different languages—systems of words—can reflect reality in subtly different ways.</li>
<li>Words matter. Words and mind are inextricably linked and together they create the feedback loop that makes reasoning possible.</li>
<li>The abuse of language is a form of psychological abuse. George Orwell memorably took it to task in <a href="https://www.orwellfoundation.com/the-orwell-foundation/orwell/essays-and-other-works/politics-and-the-english-language/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Politics and the English Language</em></a> three quarters of a century ago, but we’ve been at it for much, much longer. What is new is the degree to which words have saturated our lives. Social media and 24 hour news have made it impossible to escape.</li>
<li>Precision and clarity are how we push back against the abuse of language. Because we use words to think, choosing them with care leads to clearer arguments and thoughts. We should always strive to practice good linguistic hygiene, and to use language in good faith—for our own sanity, if nothing else.</li>
<li>Where pushing back is impossible, we must step away. Silence can be a virtue.</li>
<li>The only way to have a productive discussion involving abstractions (democracy, justice, utopia) is to clearly and rigorously define them first. Often we’ll find that the discussion ends up fixating on the definitions of the words themselves. This is a good thing.</li>
</ul>
</div>
    





















<div><figure>



<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-scaled.jpg" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
    <source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-1024x749.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-scaled.jpg 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
    <img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-50x37.jpg" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-512x375.jpg, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/11/2952px-Pieter_Bruegel_the_Elder_-_The_Tower_of_Babel-1024x749.jpg 2x" alt="Image" width="2560" height="1873">
</picture>
            </figure></div>

</section>



<section id="systems"><div><h3><span>4. Systems</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><em><span>“The Matrix is everywhere. It is all around us. Even now, in this very room. You can see it when you look out your window or when you turn on your television.” —Morpheus</span></em></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>We are surrounded by and enmeshed in systems.</li>
<li>Thinking in terms of systems helps us to make sense of a chaotic and unpredictable world.</li>
<li>Societies are systems. Culture is a system. Governments, markets, weather, language, and the biosphere are all examples of systems.</li>
<li>Some complex systems are too big and too complicated to think about coherently. We call these types of systems <em><strong>hyperobjects</strong></em>.</li>
<li>Complex systems can be broken down into simpler ones for the purpose of thinking about them.</li>
<li>It’s possible to understand how a system works without being able to make accurate predictions about it. But we should be wary of our tendency to believe that we understand systems which we do not.</li>
<li>It’s impossible to make accurate long-term predictions about most complex systems.</li>
<li>Some systems tend towards stability through self-regulation, while others are inherently unstable.</li>
<li>It’s not necessary to understand how a system works before acting to change it. In fact, history is the story of humans collectively changing or dismantling systems before understanding them—often with serious consequences (like climate). But a system must be understood in order to effectively change it <em>with a specific outcome in mind</em>.</li>
<li>It’s unproductive to approach systems dogmatically. No system is inherently good or bad. But we should evaluate systems, especially those created by humans, based on our convictions about what is desirable and undesirable.</li>
<li>Most complex systems are interwoven with others and cannot be fully understood in isolation.</li>
</ul>
</div>
    





















<div><figure>



<picture data-loaded="false"><source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems.png" media="(min-width: 1000px)">
    <source data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-1024x1024.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems.png 2x" media="(min-width: 400px)">
    <img src="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-50x50.png" data-srcset="https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-512x512.png, https://api.culture.io/static/2020/07/systems-1024x1024.png 2x" alt="Image" width="2440" height="2440">
</picture>
            </figure></div>

</section>



<section id="rules"><div><h3><span>5. Rules<br>
</span></h3>
<blockquote>
<p><em><span>“The creation of rules is more creative than the destruction of them. Creation demands a higher level of reasoning and …</span></em></p></blockquote></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://culture.io/manifesto">https://culture.io/manifesto</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://culture.io/manifesto</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26032587</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 03:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
