<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 12:39:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 12:39:02 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We can have democracy or we can have Facebook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 37 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25383976">thread link</a>) | @imartin2k
<br/>
December 11, 2020 | https://the.ink/p/we-can-have-democracy-or-we-can-have | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://the.ink/p/we-can-have-democracy-or-we-can-have">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ff0c86dcd-c055-427e-910c-ccc4314253f1_2094x1147.jpeg"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ff0c86dcd-c055-427e-910c-ccc4314253f1_2094x1147.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/f0c86dcd-c055-427e-910c-ccc4314253f1_2094x1147.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:798,&quot;width&quot;:1456,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:277616,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>Being on the phone with <a href="https://twitter.com/matthewstoller">Matt Stoller</a> when a giant antitrust case is announced against Facebook is like texting with the pope when the Second Coming, you know, comes.</p><p>It’s a little on the nose. A little exciting.</p><p>I’d been wanting to talk to Matt for a while, in part because the pope actually turned down my recent interview request (someone please tell him how book tours work).</p><div><figure><a target="_blank" href="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F37ce1cde-dec5-4068-8ca8-3359f838647c_1308x264.png"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F37ce1cde-dec5-4068-8ca8-3359f838647c_1308x264.png" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/37ce1cde-dec5-4068-8ca8-3359f838647c_1308x264.png&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:264,&quot;width&quot;:1308,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:51146,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/png&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null}" alt=""></a></figure></div><p>And in part because I consider him (Matt) one of the more interesting, iconoclastic, morally committed, unpredictable, critics-may-care thinkers today. In the course of a typical Twitter day, which is a week in human time, I agree with Matt, disagree with him, wish I had thought of something he said, regret something he said on his behalf, retweet something he wrote, and make a mental note to talk with him soon. So I did.</p><p>And there we were, talking about everything — his political education, why he goes back and forth between thinking of himself as a progressive and not, his highly influential recent book, “<a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/Goliath/Matt-Stoller/9781501182891">Goliath: The 100-Year War Between Monopoly Power and Democracy</a>” — when my phone began to crackle with <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/09/technology/facebook-antitrust-monopoly.html">news of an historic antitrust case against Facebook</a>.</p><p>Naturally, I began to ask Matt about it. What he said was so compelling that I’ve decided to break our interview into two issues of the newsletter. Today: Matt Stoller on Facebook, this important case, and how monopoly is mistaken as a policy issue when in fact it represents an existential question of whether we are actually a democracy.</p><p>Then, before long, <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107144/">part deux</a>, the political education of Matt Stoller — thinker, writer, civil servant, trustbuster, Twitter beefer, and, presently, aspiring political philosopher.</p><p>Without shame, I’ll add, in the spirit of Matt’s ideas, that if you want to do your part to support small, independent media, and haven’t yet, consider subscribing to The Ink.</p><h3>“The way we do business is the way we do justice”: a conversation with Matt Stoller, part one</h3><p>ANAND: Right as we're talking, I get a news alert: “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/09/technology/facebook-antitrust-monopoly.html">Facebook illegally crushed competition by buying up its rivals, according to lawsuits filed by 48 states and federal regulators</a>.” So this is the big case that we've been waiting for. Can you explain to a person who has never focused on this issue before in their life, and who just uses Facebook to try to get with their high-school ex, why is this a big deal? What does this mean?</p><p>MATT: So Facebook is a financial conglomerate. People think of Facebook as that website you use or the app that you use, but really Facebook, as a political institution, is a financial conglomerate and owns dozens of different companies, including Instagram and WhatsApp and Facebook, the social network. And it's a giant advertising company. So they have roughly three billion users. And they try to get their users to do things that their advertisers want them to do, because that's how you sell advertising.</p><p>The business model is to divert revenue that used to go to newspapers and publishers to themselves. And so by manipulating people in this specific way that they do, which is to keep them using their system and keep surveilling them so that they can target them with ads, they are, in the process, crushing newspapers and publishers, who no longer have any financing, particularly local newspapers and niche publications like Black-owned newspapers.</p><p>So increasingly those kinds of publications don't exist. You don't have reporters covering state houses and city halls and whatnot. Instead, people are now consuming things that Facebook likes them to consume because it keeps them using, and it keeps them available to sell ads to them, which are anti-social publications or posts, like anti-vax stuff or QAnon or whatever it is.</p><p>So that's the basic problem. It's a $70-, $80-, $100-billion-a-year revenue company that's destroying newspapers and publishers all over the world and getting people to pass conspiracy theories to each other so that Facebook can make money on advertising.</p><p>ANAND: You're an anti-monopoly guy. If there were three or five companies in healthy competition with each other, all doing exactly what you just described, wouldn't it still be problematic? Is the issue here that there's only one of them of that heft, or would a competitive market with five such players still be incredibly troubling?</p><p>MATT: There's a lot more that you have to do than just break them up. But the answer is, it would improve things dramatically if they were broken up, and you don't have to imagine it.</p><p>There used to be a bunch of social networks. Facebook's main competitor was Myspace, but there were a bunch of others. There was BlackPlanet; there was Friendster. And the way that Facebook actually defeated Myspace was by promising a safer, more private experience. They defeated Myspace by saying, We will treat your data carefully; in fact, when we change the terms of service, we will let our users vote on the terms of service.</p><p>This was back in 2007, 2008, 2009. And once they killed their competition, and then they bought up nascent competitors like Instagram and WhatsApp, then they didn't have to compete by offering a higher-quality service, a.k.a one that was less intrusive in terms of surveillance. They could just surveil anybody they wanted, and you didn't really have a choice.</p><p>ANAND: Where do you think this case is going?</p><p>MATT: They’re going to aim to break up the company. The House Antitrust Subcommittee did this long investigation of big tech, which includes Facebook. And one of the things they found is that Mark Zuckerberg was writing emails saying they were buying these companies to block competition. And so that's evidence that the mergers were illegal, because you're not supposed to buy companies to block competition. That's a violation of the Clayton Act. My guess is that they're going to have a pretty good complaint.&nbsp;</p><p>ANAND: Based on the history of such cases, would your assumption be that Facebook is broken up within a period of years?</p><p>MATT: Yes.</p><p>However, we haven't enforced the law for 20 years, so it’s not entirely clear. The law at this point is crazy and incoherent because we haven't done enforcement, and to the extent that we have, judges have just made wildly inconsistent rulings.</p><p>ANAND: This kind of action that's being announced today is the epitome of a systemic, public response to a problem. And when I, like you, advocate for those types of things, I often hear this response that I'm sure you do, too, which is, “OK, that's fine, but what about individual actions?” A lot of people are like, “Yes, let’s delete Facebook.” Or: “Why aren't you supporting the Facebook boycott?”, and there are different views on it.</p><p>There are some people who make the argument that those kind of small personal things are sideshows, distractions, maybe even unhelpful, because they reduce the perceived need for bigger systemic change. I fall more into that camp. There are others who say it's a gateway drug, it's a waystation, like: “Delete Facebook and then work yourself up to a political response." How do you weigh in on that?</p><p>MATT: I think it's a bad vision of politics. It's not doing politics to say, “Me, as a consumer, I can change power arrangements based on what I consume or don’t.” That's a real 1970s consumer-rights Democrat vision of the world, and that's one in which you as a citizen are irrelevant.</p><p>A boycott is only political if the goal is a policy change. If you go in and you say, "Well, I don't like Facebook, I want to change Facebook, so I'm going to delete Facebook," that's not going to do anything. If it's part of some larger political action saying, "Well, I'm going to delete Facebook, and then I'm going to push policymakers to break it up," I mean, I guess that makes sense.</p><p>But the general view of these boycotts is that just not using Facebook is the political action. But that's actually not a political action.</p><p>ANAND: An issue like monopoly is different from, say, healthcare, where you don't have to explain to most people the problem with our healthcare system. How do you think about making the issue of monopoly real to people and vivid and relevant to their lives?</p><p>MATT: I'm going to challenge the premise. I don't think monopoly is an <em>issue</em>. I think monopoly is a worldview.</p><p>My book is called “<a href="https://www.simonandschuster.com/books/Goliath/Matt-Stoller/9781501182891">Goliath: The 100-Year War Between Monopoly Power and Democracy</a>.” Anti-monopolism is a lens through which you understand power, and particularly commercial power. That’s the lens that I see the world through. And I don't just focus on Facebook or Google. I’m focused on anti-monopolism in general. How you use business institutions to coerce and bully — or liberate — other people in your society.</p><p>There's a monopolist who controls the cheerleading industry, which is very weird. I just learned there is a private-equity company that is trying to monopolize the software that churches run. There is a monopoly of Ultimate Fighting Championship-style contests. And then in healthcare there are endless numbers of monopolists. Ultimately, what a monopolist is is a person or institution that is controlling and governing a market. It's a private government versus a public government.</p><p>ANAND: You’re saying it’s incompatible with democracy.</p><p>MATT: Right. It’s a different system. When Mark Zuckerberg says he’s going to arrange electoral discourse in this particular way, or going to start a <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/meet-the-first-20-members-of-facebook-supreme-court-2020-5">Supreme Court</a>, or going to ban this or allow that, he is operating as the global privacy commissioner. <a href="https://www.vox.com/the-big-idea/2018/4/9/17214752/zuckerberg-facebook-power-regulation-data-privacy-control-political-theory-data-breach-king">He even said</a>, "In a lot of ways Facebook is more like a government than a traditional company." That's a direct quote.</p><p>As a society, the way we do business is the way we do justice.</p><p>ANAND: Understanding how these platforms work, do you think that if Mark Zuckerberg wanted to tip an election, he could? Would that even be illegal under our current system?</p><p>MATT: I don't know if it's possible, but it's certainly legal if he decided to.</p><p>I listened to this podcast with Zuckerberg where he said — this was right before he became unpopular, so he was still being relatively …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://the.ink/p/we-can-have-democracy-or-we-can-have">https://the.ink/p/we-can-have-democracy-or-we-can-have</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://the.ink/p/we-can-have-democracy-or-we-can-have</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25383976</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 09:48:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Some doctors, therapists get Health Canada permission to use magic mushrooms]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 111 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25382497">thread link</a>) | @billyharris
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/london/some-doctors-therapists-get-health-canada-permission-to-use-magic-mushrooms-1.5834485 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/london/some-doctors-therapists-get-health-canada-permission-to-use-magic-mushrooms-1.5834485">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Four months after it allowed a handful of palliative care patients to use psilocybin as a way to relieve end-of-life suffering, Health Canada has cleared the way for more than a dozen health professionals to use the psychedelic drug themselves to help develop therapies for future use.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.4039727.1492805330!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/63883228.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Psilocybin is the ingredient in magic mushrooms that causes hallucinations, but in medically supervised settings, can also potentially help people overcome depression.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Shutterstock / gsplanet)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Four months after it allowed a handful of palliative care patients to use psilocybin as a way to relieve end-of-life suffering, Health Canada has cleared the way for more than a dozen health professionals to use the psychedelic drug themselves to help develop therapies for future use.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Health Canada says it granted 16 exemptions to a selection of nurses, doctors, therapists and social workers, allowing them to possess and use&nbsp;psilocybin&nbsp;for personal training without fear of prosecution under the country's drug laws.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"This is not a small step. This is a seismic step," said Dr. Sean O'Sullivan, a Tillsonburg, Ont., doctor and medical director of TheraPsil, a non-profit group that advocates for the therapeutic use of psilocybin.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"This is permission from the Ministry of Health and the Minister of Health to allow therapists to forward their own training in psychedelic medicine."&nbsp;</p>  <p><span><span><div><div role="button" tabindex="0" title="Mushrooms: The Magic Medicine"><div><p><img src="https://thumbnails.cbc.ca/maven_legacy/thumbnails/337/291/Sickboy-640x360.jpg" alt=""></p><p><span>Sickboy</span><span>1:02:33</span><span>Mushrooms: The Magic Medicine</span></p></div></div></div><span>Thomas Hartle never used drugs before his Stage IV cancer diagnosis. That’s changed thanks to Therapsil. A couple months ago, he became the first Canadian to legally use psychedelic mushrooms to treat end of life anxiety and depression. Take a listen to his story with an open mind.<!-- --> <!-- -->1:02:33</span></span></span><span><ul><li><a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/microdosing-pschedelics-study-1.4771647" data-contentid="" flag="" text="How and why people 'microdose' tiny hits of psychedelic drugs"><span>How and why people 'microdose' tiny hits of psychedelic drugs</span></a></li></ul></span></p>  <p>The move comes after Health Canada&nbsp;gave <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/magic-mushrooms-therapy-1.5675637" target="_blank">four exemptions to palliative care patients</a> to use the drug&nbsp;for end-of-life psychotherapy in August. Since then, other exemptions have been given to patients who want to use magic mushrooms.&nbsp;</p>  <p>The exemptions for health professionals will allow those who want to treat patients with psilocybin&nbsp;to understand what it would feel like and how best to use it.&nbsp;</p>  <p>They are good for one year.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"Psychedelic substances and treatment using these substances, such as&nbsp;psilocybin, is a growing area of scientific study and research. Because&nbsp;psilocybin&nbsp;is not an authorized therapeutic substance, the availability of rigorous scientific evidence demonstrating its safety and efficacy is limited," Health Canada said in a statement to CBC News.&nbsp;</p>  <p>"The exemptions do not permit the health care professionals to prescribe or provide mushrooms containing&nbsp;psilocybin&nbsp;to another person. There are no drugs containing&nbsp;psilocybin&nbsp;that have been authorized&nbsp; by Health Canada. Health Canada's decision to grant these exemptions does not constitute an opinion or endorsement from Health Canada on&nbsp;psilocybin-assisted psychotherapy, training, or the safety, effectiveness, or quality of&nbsp;psilocybin."</p>  <h2>Psychiatrists, nurses given exemptions</h2>  <p>"This is an immense step that the minister has taken, and a very wise step, a step that is totally congruent with the science and the published literature and is a very courageous move on her part and on our government's part," O'Sullivan said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Psychedelic therapies such as psilocybin and LSD have had negative reputations, in part because of the war on drugs, O'Sullivan said.&nbsp;</p>    <p>"The war on drugs has been an unmitigated disaster worldwide. It has criminalized behaviour that does not need to be criminalized. Cannabis has been legalized, and the sky has not fallen," O'Sullivan said.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Those who have been given exemptions include psychiatrists associated with the University of Toronto, a community psychiatrist in Hamilton and his partner, as well as health professionals in Calgary and British Columbia.&nbsp;</p>  <p>O'Sullivan and his wife both got an exemption. He is a general practitioner and she is a therapist. He said it's important for doctors who could eventually prescribe psychedelics to be well versed in their effects.&nbsp;</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5834847.1607546851!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_300/dr-sean-o-sullivan.JPG 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5834847.1607546851!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_460/dr-sean-o-sullivan.JPG 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5834847.1607546851!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_620/dr-sean-o-sullivan.JPG 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5834847.1607546851!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/dr-sean-o-sullivan.JPG 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5834847.1607546851!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_1180/dr-sean-o-sullivan.JPG 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5834847.1607546851!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/dr-sean-o-sullivan.JPG"></p></div><figcaption>Dr. Sean O'Sullivan is one of 16 health professionals who has been granted an exemption from Canada's drug laws to use magic mushrooms. <!-- --> <!-- -->(Submitted by Sean O'Sullivan)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>"You would not expect a guide to take any journey over any terrain with&nbsp;which the guide was not familiar. When it comes to psychedelics, the terrain is so unusual and so outlandish that it is absolutely imperative that the therapist have familiarity with the realms of the human unconscious that are visited under psychedelics because they can help guide the patient through situations that might seem utterly bizarre, even psychotic to an untrained therapist," O'Sullivan said.</p>  <p>"Great information can be obtained if you dissect and unpack that material that comes up under these medications."</p>  <p>Psilocybin&nbsp;allows the brain to put away the "default mode network," the part of our brain that worries about taxes and dinner and the shopping list, and dive deeper.&nbsp;</p>    <p>"If you look at your <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/seeking-seat-of-consciousness-in-dark-side-of-brain-1.1415607" target="_blank">default mode network</a>, you will find that the themes that come up are the same themes that came up last year and the year before and the decade before," O'Sullivan said. "Psychedelics disassemble the default mode network and they allow a person to have new experiences in a carefully controlled clinical setting. When the default mode network is put back together, it's not put back together in the same way as it was previously."</p>  <p>That's why a single dose of a psychedelic medicine can have more effect than years of talk therapy or medication, he said.</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/london/some-doctors-therapists-get-health-canada-permission-to-use-magic-mushrooms-1.5834485</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25382497</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 05:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Google Alternatives]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 203 | Comments 170 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25380999">thread link</a>) | @yepgwer
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://justprivacy.org/google-alternatives/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://justprivacy.org/google-alternatives/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span color="000000"><p>We may earn a small commission if you choose to purchase from our links <strong>(at no extra cost to you!)</strong></p></span></p><div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="989" data-elementor-settings="[]"><div><div><section data-id="10b593b" data-element_type="section"></section><section data-id="c631736" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="72201ec" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="e877a4b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="Google Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Alternatives-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Google Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="c32dc21" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="af9583c" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="797f602" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>The purpose of this guide is to be the most in-depth list of the best alternatives to Google and its products.</p><p>Privacy and security of personal data online has become more of an issue, this means people are trying to find alternatives to Google.</p><p>The way Google makes money is by data collection and advertisements, with both affect your online privacy. The more data Google has on you the better they can find out what you’re interested in (target you) and therefore make more money off you. Did you know Google had over <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/267606/quarterly-revenue-of-google/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">$159 billion dollars in revenue</a> in 2019?</p><p>However, there is a growing amount of people who are looking for alternatives to Google.</p><p><span>Note:</span> None of these alternatives are in order, it depends on you’re specific needs.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="8997902" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="b2c7c82" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="a225dd3" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h2>Google Search Engine Alternatives</h2></p></div><div data-id="6838ece" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="519" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-1024x536.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-1024x536.jpg" alt="Google Search Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-1024x536.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-300x157.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-768x402.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives.jpg 1200w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-1024x536.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-300x157.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives-768x402.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Search-Alternatives.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Google Search Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="4d6be8b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Privacy and Google search don’t go hand in hand. When you use Google search, they will record your IP address, your search terms, and usually a unique ID.</p><p>Here are some good alternatives to Google search.</p><ol><li><a href="https://duckduckgo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DuckDuckGo</a> – An internet search engine whose goal is to protect users’ privacy and avoiding personalized search results (tracking).</li><li><a href="https://www.qwant.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Qwant</a> – Is a French search engine that doesn’t track users.</li><li><a href="https://searx.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SearX</a> – Is a free metasearch engine, intended to protect the privacy of its users.</li><li><a href="https://startpage.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Startpage</a> – a search engine extension that allows users to browse while not being tracked.</li><li><a href="https://swisscows.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SwissCows</a> – Is a Swiss search engine that was launched in 2014. They don’t keep track of the searches done on their site.</li><li><a href="https://www.mojeek.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mojeek</a> – Is a UK-based search engine, they are independent and have unbiased results which means no user tracking.</li><li><a href="https://metager.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MetaGer</a> – Is a search engine based on protecting users’ privacy, it’s also based in Germany.</li><li><a href="https://yandex.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yandex Search</a> – Is a search engine based in Russia and owned by a Russian corporation <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yandex" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Yandex</a>.</li><li><a href="https://yacy.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YaCy</a> – Is a free search engine built on principles of P2P (peer-to-peer) networks.</li></ol><p>Most of the search engines above are metasearch engines (except Mokeej and Yandex) meaning they source their search results from larger search engines like Google and Bing.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="56efb89" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="1091847" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="653fe9a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h2>Google Chrome Alternatives</h2></p></div><div data-id="0470836" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="Chrome Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Chrome-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Chrome Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="25f82ad" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Chrome is an extremely popular web browser and billions of searches are done monthly.</p><p>As you can see Google has 92.07% of the Search Engine Market Share Worldwide as of February 2020!</p></div></div></div><div data-id="e99d120" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/search-engine-market-share" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <img width="992" height="269" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-1024x278.png" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-1024x278.png" alt="Market Share Chrome" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-1024x278.png 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-300x81.png 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-768x208.png 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-1536x417.png 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome.png 1629w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-1024x278.png 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-300x81.png 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-768x208.png 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome-1536x417.png 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Market-Share-Chrome.png 1629w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Market Share Chrome Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data">		</a></p></div></div><div data-id="2d8725f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Remember that Google Chrome is not only a search engine but a super successful data collection tool! More and more people are noticing this. There are many articles saying that Google Chrome has become spyware!</p><p>If you want to read more about this you can read this forum on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BATProject/comments/c3q51d/goodbye_chrome_googles_web_browser_has_become_spy/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reddit</a> and an article on <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/06/21/google-chrome-has-become-surveillance-software-its-time-switch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Washington Post.</a></p><p>Here are some good alternatives to Chrome:</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tor Browser</a> – Is a global and decentralized computer network. This allows you to hide from tracking and surveillance.</li><li><a href="https://www.mozilla.org/fr/firefox/new/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Firefox</a> – Is a free and open-source web browser, it was developed by Mozilla Foundation and help from thousands of volunteers!</li><li><a href="https://brave.com/fr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Brave</a> – Is an open-source web browser whose goal is to protect the privacy of their users by blocking trackers or preferring pages in HTTPS.</li><li><a href="https://info.ecosia.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">ecosia</a> – Berlin-based search engine whose profits go into planting trees to fight against climate change! They are also privacy-friendly and ethical.</li><li><a href="https://iridiumbrowser.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Iridium Browser</a> – Is based on the Chromium codebase. All modifications enhance privacy for the user.</li><li><a href="https://ungoogled-software.github.io/ungoogled-chromium-binaries/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ungoogled Chromium</a> – Is an open-source version of Chromium that has been modified to enhance users’ privacy.</li><li><a href="https://www.waterfox.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Waterfox</a> – Is an open-source web browser that is based on Mozilla Firefox. Its purpose is to be speedy and ethical.</li><li><a href="https://www.epicbrowser.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Epic Browser</a> – Is a “Privacy Browser” that is a secure chromium-based web browser.</li><li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/gnuzilla/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GNUzilla</a> – Its a GNU version of the Mozilla suite. Its main advantage is that it’s ethical and entirely free!</li></ol><p>There are other alternatives to Google Chrome like Apple’s Safari and Microsoft’s Edge but many of these have serious privacy issues.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="0f232f2" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="dcd92ec" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="c5b213d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="Gmail Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Gmail Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="acb282e" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Your inbox is where the most important information is sent. You can find a lot of information on a person based on your inbox.</p><p>The unfortunate thing is that Google and its partners have access to all your information and they can <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/techs-dirty-secret-the-app-developers-sifting-through-your-gmail-1530544442" target="_blank" rel="noopener">collect data</a>, they can display ads inside your inbox, and the contents of your inbox are shared with random <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/techs-dirty-secret-the-app-developers-sifting-through-your-gmail-1530544442" target="_blank" rel="noopener">third parties</a>.</p><p>Here are some more secure Gmail alternatives:</p><ol><li><a href="https://protonmail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ProtonMail</a> – Is an encrypted email service created in 2013 by CERN and MIT scientists.</li><li><a href="https://tutanota.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tutanota</a> – Is a German-based email provider that is open-sourced with end-to-end email software. Tutanota also offers a web messaging service.</li><li><a href="https://posteo.de/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Posteo</a> – Is a German email provider whose IT foundation is based on open-source software. They also use green energy from Greenpeace Energy and is also ad-free! The service costs € 1 per month.</li><li><a href="https://runbox.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Runbox</a> – Is a company that provides email and web hosting services. It was founded in March 2011 and its headquarters are located in Oslo.</li><li><a href="https://mailbox.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mailbox.org</a> – Its an ad-free and secure email provider based in Germany, they offer a calendar, contacts lists and more.</li><li><a href="https://www.startmail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">StartMail</a> – Is created by the people who created StartPage (a secure search engine).&nbsp;</li><li><a href="https://mailfence.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mailfence</a> – Is an encrypted email service based in Belgium. It offers free accounts.</li><li><a href="https://countermail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CounterMail</a> – Is a secure email provider that is based in Sweden.&nbsp;</li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="9dd4dfa" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="5d3cd03" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="6d29af4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h2>Google Calendar Alternatives</h2></p></div><div data-id="fc23717" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-1024x576.jpg" alt="Gmail Alternatives 1" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Gmail-Alternatives-1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Gmail Alternatives 1 Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="a3398d3" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Google Calendar is amazing it helps users manage their time, set goals, and remember things.</p><p>There are many upsides to Google’s Calendar app but there are some major privacy issues and many people are looking for alternatives.</p><p>Here are multiple Google Calendar alternatives:</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.simplemobiletools.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Simple Calendar</a> – It’s an ad-free app without any unnecessary permissions.</li><li><a href="https://fruux.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fruux</a> – Offers a free account, supports many operating systems, and is open-source.</li><li><a href="https://timetreeapp.com/intl/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TimeTree</a> – It offers a free account and supports Android, iOS, and browser.</li><li><a href="https://protonmail.com/blog/protoncalendar-beta-announcement/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ProtonCalendar</a> – Created by the same people who made ProtonMail!</li><li><a href="https://github.com/Kartones/flask-calendar#introduction" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Flask-Calendar</a> – Basic, self-hosted Calendar, has a few features as well</li></ol><p>There are a few services that offer both email and calendar services in one:</p><ul><li><a href="https://tutanota.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tutanota</a></li><li><a href="https://mailbox.org/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mailbox.org</a></li><li><a href="https://posteo.de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Posteo</a></li><li><a href="https://mailfence.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mailfence</a></li><li><a href="https://outlook.live.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Outlook</a></li></ul></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="c72fb6b" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="f3c4b93" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="021a025" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h2>Google Drive Alternatives</h2></p></div><div data-id="a27452e" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="Google Drive Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Drive-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Google Drive Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="067a2fa" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Google Drive is a popular option because it’s free and extremely convenient, but Google doesn’t care about users’ privacy that much. It collects your data and uses it for their own purposes.</p><p>Here are some good Drive Alternatives:</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dropbox</a> – Is a file hosting service owned by the American company Dropbox.</li><li><a href="https://www.sync.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sync.com</a> – Is based in Canada. They offer secure and encrypted cloud storage for both businesses and individuals.</li><li><a href="https://mega.nz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mega</a> – Is a secure cloud storage service that offers free 50 GB of storage.</li><li><a href="https://nextcloud.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nextcloud</a> – This is a free and open-source file sharing platform that is based in Germany.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/syncthing/syncthing/tree/master" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Syncthing</a> – Peer-to-peer, an open-sourced cloud storage platform.</li><li><a href="https://tresorit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tresorit</a>d Hungary that is serious about en<span>&nbsp;– Is a storage service based in Switzerland enhanced</span>&nbsp;security and data encryption.&nbsp;</li><li><a href="https://owncloud.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ownCloud</a> – This is an open-source file sharing platform based in Germany.</li><li><a href="http://www.infomaniak.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Infomaniak</a> – Switzerland-based privacy-friendly service that offers drive, calendar, and more services.</li></ol><p>Some of my recommendations above (Dropbox, Mega) aren’t the best for privacy but are much more privacy-friendly than Google Drive.</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="560065d" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="473c144" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="f1693c6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="Google Docs Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Docs-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Google Docs Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="98b5c8d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Google Docs offers users to create documents easily online. But Google makes its money through data collection and Google’s bots have been caught crawling through users’ documents.</p><p>Here are some good alternatives to Google Drive:</p><ol><li><a href="https://www.zoho.com/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zoho Office</a> – This is a good Google alternative for docs since it has a good interface and works well.</li><li><a href="https://etherpad.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EtherPad</a> – Is an online free text editor that allows users to work collaboratively and in real-time.</li><li><a href="https://cryptpad.fr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CryptPad</a> – Is a great privacy-focused alternative to Google Docs.</li><li><a href="https://www.openoffice.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apache OpenOffice</a> – Is a good office suite platform that is also available <span>offline.</span></li><li><a href="https://personal.onlyoffice.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OnlyOffice</a> – Is a multifunctional online office suite.</li><li><a href="https://www.nuclino.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nuclino</a> – Is a cloud-based collaboration software that allows teams to work on projects together and share information in real-time.</li><li><a href="https://flibreoffice.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LibreOffice</a> – Is a good free and open-sourced office suite that is also available <span>offline.</span></li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="46d2732" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="c3a000e" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="2f0a056" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="YouTube Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/YouTube-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="YouTube Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="46501a2" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="ce19e75" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="8f49f0c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h2>Google Photos Alternatives</h2></p></div><div data-id="3b7c0a6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="Google Photos Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Photos-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Google Photos Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="9979111" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Google offers unlimited storage for photo’s but Google isn’t doing it to be nice. They will use your photos to scan your pictures and track things you do. I don’t think Google or any company needs to know that much about you.</p><p>Here are a few good Google Photo’s alternatives:</p><ol><li><a href="https://piwigo.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Piwigo</a> – Is an open-source photo gallery software.&nbsp;</li><li><a href="https://zyl.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zyl</a> – Is a great mobile app that cares about privacy.</li><li><a href="https://crypt.ee/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cryptee</a> –&nbsp; Is a great option if you’re serious about your privacy. They offer many services as well as not just photos.</li><li><a href="https://cluster.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cluster</a> – A free app that’s allows you to create photo albums and share them with people you choose.</li><li><a href="https://photostructure.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PhotoStructure</a> – relatively new self-hosted privacy-friendly photo manager</li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="e855368" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="205ce2f" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="2236d87" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h2>Google Analytics Alternatives</h2></p></div><div data-id="643d0e7" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-1024x576.jpg" alt="Google Analytics Alternative" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Analytics-Alternative.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Google Analytics Alternative Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="fc58c6b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>If you’re running a website there are good reasons to use alternatives to Google Analytics. One, you’re respecting your visitor’s privacy and there are more friendly alternatives.</p><p>Websites who run Google Adsense campaigns are the ones who usually use Google Analytics because it would be much more difficult to track your results without it.</p><p>Here are a few Analytics alternatives:</p><ol><li><a href="https://plausible.io/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Plausible</a> – A simple and privacy-friendly alternative to Google Analytics. It’s also lightweight, open-source, and has no cookies.</li><li><a href="https://matomo.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matomo</a> – It was formerly Piwik, and is an open-sourced platform that understands the privacy of the users. It also allows website admins to import historic Google Analytics data to Matomo.</li><li><a href="https://usefathom.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fathom Analytics</a> – Is an open-sourced website analytics platform that is efficient and fast. (<a href="https://github.com/usefathom/fathom" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a>)</li><li><a href="https://clicky.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clicky</a> – Is a good alternative to Google Analytics because it keeps the user’s privacy by making their IP anonymous. It’s also efficient and user-friendly. It is also certified by <a href="https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Privacy Shield</a>!</li><li><a href="https://www.atinternet.com/en/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AT Internet</a> – Is a French company that was created in 1996. It’s good for performance measurement or sites, and applications.</li><li><a href="https://www.foxmetrics.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FoxMetrics</a> – Is a platform that allows you to understand and analyze your customer’s actions from your desktop and mobile device.</li></ol></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section><section data-id="9f07b94" data-element_type="section"><div><div><div data-id="5b063df" data-element_type="column"><div><div><div data-id="dafc60c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default"><p><h2>Google Translate Alternatives</h2></p></div><div data-id="eb7e8e7" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default"><div><p><img width="992" height="558" src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" data-lazy-type="image" data-src="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg" alt="Google Translate Alternatives" loading="lazy" srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" data-srcset="https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-300x169.jpg 300w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-768x432.jpg 768w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://justprivacy.org/media/2020/03/Google-Translate-Alternatives.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" title="Google Translate Alternatives Google Alternatives: Protecting Your Data"></p></div></div><div data-id="bae68a8" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"><div><div><p>Google has many privacy issues and Google Translate is no exception. Google …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></section></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://justprivacy.org/google-alternatives/">https://justprivacy.org/google-alternatives/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://justprivacy.org/google-alternatives/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25380999</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:59:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Making of “The Godfather” – Sort of a home movie (1971)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25378576">thread link</a>) | @dadt
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | http://www.thestacksreader.com/the-making-of-the-godfather-sort-of-a-home-movie/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.thestacksreader.com/the-making-of-the-godfather-sort-of-a-home-movie/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
					
<p>As was his custom before the drive home from work with his son, the old man walked across the narrow, tenement‐lined street in Manhattan’s Little Italy to buy some fresh fruit. The grocer, who had known him for many years, helped the old man sort out some prize oranges and, as a gift, handed him a perfectly ripened, home‐grown fig. The old man smiled, accepted the backyard offering with a slight nod and started toward his car. It was then that he spotted two gunmen.</p>
<p>He called out to his son and began to sprint toward the safety of his car with surprising speed for a man of his age, but the gunmen were too quick. As they opened fire, the old man seemed caught in a great leap, suspended momentarily in the air, his arms thrown protectively around his head. Loud shots hammered through the street, bright oranges rolled across the gray pavement and the old man crashed onto the fender of his car and collapsed. The people of Mott Street watched in silence from tenement windows, fire escapes and rooftops as the gunmen slipped away. Then, to spontaneous applause, the grim street tableau came to life, and the old man—the godfather, <a href="http://www.thestacksreader.com/brando/">Marlon Brando</a>—lifted himself slowly from the ground, smiled at the cheering crowd and bowed.</p>
<p>At 11 o’clock on April 12, just as Brando was getting shot on Mott Street, Carlo Gambino, one of New York’s real godfathers, sat around the corner in a Grand Street cafe, sipping black coffee from a glass and holding 18th‐century Sicilian court in 20th‐century New York. He had arrived moments earlier in the company of his brother, Paul, and five bodyguards. It was his custom, as well as his duty as head of a Mafia family, to hear at regular intervals the endless woes of racketeers, dishonored fathers and deportable husbands. They were ushered before him, one at a time, from a waiting area in a restaurant across the street. He was the final judge to people still willing to accept his decisions as law.</p>
<hr>
<p>Back on Mott Street, two Mafiosi assigned to observe the movie production were unaware of his arrival. For hours, they had been watching Brando getting shot. They had had innumerable cups of coffee and had adjusted their open‐throat, hand ironed shirts so often that their collars had begun to wilt. Neither of them had been impressed when they heard Brando was to play the godfather, so they watched his performance critically. They volunteered to grips, cameramen and extras that they would have preferred Ernest Borgnine or Anthony Quinn.</p>
<p>“A man of that stature,” one of them said, pointing to Brando, “would never wear a hat like that. They never pinched them in the front like that. Italian block, that’s the way they wore them, Italian block.”</p>
<p>They did not like Brando’s wearing his belt below his trouser loops, either.</p>
<p>“He makes the old man look like an iceman. That’s not right. A man like that had style. He should have a diamond belt buckle. They all had diamond belt buckles. And a diamond ring and tie clasp. Those old bosses loved diamonds. They all wore them. Brando makes the guy look like an iceman.”</p>
<p>In truth, Brando did not look like the traditional double‐breasted, wide lapeled, blue‐serge racketeer. He had accepted the advice of an Italian American friend, rather than the Mafiosi themselves, and made himself look old and bent. He wore a sack shaped suit of an undistinguished brown stripe and an outsize over coat. He wore a cardboard‐stiff white shirt with a collar at least two sizes too large and a striped tie so indifferently knotted that its back, label and all, faced front. The makeup man, who was never very far away, had fixed Brando with an elaborate mouth plate that made his jaw heavy and extended his jowls. Brando’s complexion was sallow, his eyes were made to droop on the side and with his graying temples and mustache many people on Mott Street that day did not recognize him until the filming began.</p>
<h5>There was an aura about the production that was unmistakable, just as there is an aura of real and imagined power around the honored society itself.</h5>
<p>The two Mafiosi did approve the vintage cars and were amused by the streetlamps, pushcarts and prices, circa 1940, tacked up in store windows. But they did not like the way the godfather’s assassins fired their guns.</p>
<p>“They hold pieces like flowers,” one said.</p>
<p>Shortly before noon a third man came up behind the pair and whispered:</p>
<p>“The old man’s around the corner.” The two men were stunned. “You kidding?” one asked. “Believe me, he’s around the corner.”</p>
<p>“Kee‐rist!”</p>
<p>“Shooo!”</p>
<p>Without further hesitation—and with the same pitch of excitement most neighborhood people saved for a peek at Brando—the trio left the movie set. They walked quickly toward the intersection and stopped. One of them darted his head around the corner of the building for a quick peek and shot back to his friends: “He’s there. He’s there. I see his car. I see Paul’s guy.”</p>
<hr>
<p>Mario Puzo’s best seller may have started out to be just another multimillion‐dollar movie for Paramount, but it wasn’t long before its producers realized that to the Mafiosi themselves the making of <em>The Godfather</em> was like the filming of a home movie. Before Puzo’s book, cops‐and‐robbers novels and films about organized crime left the mobsters cold. <em>The Godfather</em> was different. When it was published in 1969 word quickly spread across the country’s most regularly tapped telephone wires about this different book on the “honored society.” It was their <em>Forsyte Saga</em>. It was filled with bits of underworld gossip and its characters could be compared to live dons, singers, movie moguls and hit men. It depicted not only their lives, but the lives of their children, wives, enemies and friends. It emphasized their peculiar code of honor rather than their seedy, greedy little maneuverings. It dealt with their strong sense of family and their passionate loyalties. It romanticized and exaggerated their political power, wealth and influence in legitimate business. But most important, it humanized rather than condemned them.</p>
<p>The godfather himself, for instance, was shot because he refused to deal in the dirty business of narcotics. Sonny Corleone, his impetuous heir, was killed in an ambush because he tried to save his pregnant sister from a brutal husband. Michael Carleone, the godfather’s college educated war‐hero son, assumed his father’s Mafia mantle not out of greed, but from a sense of responsibility to his father, who, for all his illegal activities, was a far more honorable man than all the crooked cops, venal judges, corrupt politicians and perverted businessmen who peppered the plot.</p>
<p>Though certain Italian‐American politicians and organizations condemned Puzo for defaming all Italians, the author heard no such criticism from the society about which he had written. In fact, shortly after his book’s publication, Puzo found that some Mafiosi were anxious to meet him. They wanted to compare notes with the author of <em>The Godfather.</em> They, like other fans, refused to believe that the book was all fiction. In Las Vegas he found that a gambling debt he had run up was somehow marked paid. When Puzo protested he was told, “It’s a certain party’s pleasure.” On other occasions, bottles of champagne would arrive at his table unordered. Multisyllabic names were whispered in his ear by reverential headwaiters, and men with sunglasses and diamond rings waved at him across darkened restaurants.</p>
<hr>
<p>Six weeks before the Mott Street shooting of Brando, Albert Ruddy, the film’s producer, was uncertain whether he would be able to make the movie at all. Paramount had been deluged with letters describing the project as anti‐Italian and threatening demonstrations, boycotts and wildcat strikes by everyone from maintenance men to electricians. Letters had come from Congressmen in New York, New Jersey, Connecticut, Louisiana and Pennsylvania, as well as from dozens of New York State legislators, judges, civic leaders and businessmen.</p>
<p>One of them began: “A book like <em>The Godfather</em> leaves one with the sickening feeling that a great deal of effort and labor to eliminate a false image concerning Americans of Italian descent and also an ethnic connotation to organized crime has been wasted …. There are so many careers and biographies that could be made into constructive and intellient movies, such as the life of Enrico Fermi, the great scientist; Mother Cabrini; Colonel Ceslona, a hero of the Civil War; Garibaldi, the great Italian who unified Italy; William Paca, a signer of the Declaration of Independence; Guglielmo Marconi, and many, many others.”</p>
<p>The letter was signed by “the Grand Venerable of the Grand Council of the Grand Lodge of New York State’s Sons of Italy.” It also informed Paramount that the studio could expect an economic boycott of the film, petitions of protest from all Sons of Italy lodges, regional meetings to plan protests, a complaint filed with the State Human Rights Division and demands that no governmental authorities give the production any cooperation whatever.</p>
<p>And as if this were not enough, there were rumors of union walkouts, work stoppages and boycotts. Ruddy could envision costly delays. He had already run into trouble trying to negotiate with householders in Manhasset, L.I., for a site that looked like a godfather’s compound. The entire community and its bureaucrats had ganged up to sabotage his efforts.</p>
<p>“First, they’d complain that we would bring additional cars into the area and take up parking space,” Ruddy said. “So we’d promise to bus our people to the locations. Then they’d say they didn’t want buses in the area. Some said that if we did use their homes for the mall and the wedding the newspapers couldn’t know about it. How could we guarantee that? We were ready to pay, rent, replant, repaint, replace everything in the area for them. We were ready to make all kinds of concessions, but in the end I realized that they just didn’t want us. They never flat came out and said no, but it amounted to the same thing.</p>
<p>“For …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.thestacksreader.com/the-making-of-the-godfather-sort-of-a-home-movie/">http://www.thestacksreader.com/the-making-of-the-godfather-sort-of-a-home-movie/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.thestacksreader.com/the-making-of-the-godfather-sort-of-a-home-movie/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25378576</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 20:59:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Inuttitut, a language shaped by humility, poetry, and the land]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25378558">thread link</a>) | @diaphanous
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://beside.media/new-narratives/nuna/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://beside.media/new-narratives/nuna/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <section>
                          <p>Text — Juliana Léveillé-Trudel<br>
Photos — Alexi Hobbs</p>
                                                


      

                  <div>
        <p>“She’s away on vacation for two weeks,” said Bobby, manager of the village of Quaqtaq.</p>
<p>He was talking about the head of the recreation department, who had all of the keys, most importantly the one for the Isummasarvik School’s storage room. We needed it to get the sports equipment to keep the kids occupied at day camp: balls, badminton racquets, nets, and hockey sticks.</p>
<p>I sighed inwardly. Ever since I’d been working in Nunavik, finding a key had been a recurring nightmare. I had already given up hope.</p>
<p>“Maybe you could ask the caretaker,” Bobby suggested.</p>
<p>Anne, my colleague, nodded and waved me on. We got back into the truck. On the other side of the windows, the June sun was beating down on the frozen bay that it could not crack. We stopped in front of a house near the footbridge spanning the river. The caretaker was out, but her husband exchanged a few words with Anne in Inuttitut, then disappeared and returned with the miraculous key. I pinched myself. It had taken all of five minutes.</p>
<p>That was back in 2015, my fifth summer in Nunavik. If it had happened a few years earlier, I would have probably told the story on my blog, joking about how even a simple task can be so immensely complicated in the North.</p>
<p>But as the old man held out the keys, it hit me: it was my fault that it was complicated. I had begun setting up day camps in the North in 2011. Everything that I had found difficult then was difficult because I was trying to make things work my way: planning activities and appointments in advance, holding daily meetings, requiring long-term commitment from the camp’s employees. There was another problem too: I didn’t know the people or the language well enough. I didn’t know who the caretaker was or where she lived. I wouldn’t have been able to speak with her husband, who spoke only in Inuttitut.</p>

      </div>
      

            
    
      

            
      <div>
        <figure>
          <div>
            <p><img src="https://content.beside.media/beside_/app/www/2020/10/B09_Nuna_Alexis-Hobbs-02.jpg" alt="">
                        </p>
          </div>
        </figure>
      </div>

      
    
      

                  <div>
        <p>I’d learned a few words, of course, especially words useful for working with children: <em>come here, sit down, do you understand, hurry up, are you ready, stop, wait, again, a little, a lot, yesterday, today, tomorrow, yes, no, maybe, what’s your name, and how old are you.</em> We’d played Twister once, so I also knew the names of body parts, colours, left and right. I knew the names of all the animals. It was a start, but not enough to converse with the caretaker’s husband.</p>
<p>Many of the <em>Qallunaat</em> (whites) I met among the Inuit described Inuttitut as “impossible to learn.” It did indeed seem complicated, with all those qs, ks, and js, but I loved its rough sonority. Moreover, I could never feel at ease with this linguistic one-sidedness. Some of my friends were taking online courses with Professor Marc-Antoine Mahieu at INALCO (Institut National des Langues et Civilisations Orientales), affiliated with the Sorbonne in Paris. They all spoke about the class with the same blissful smile. In 2016 I signed up too. I had just quit my job to devote myself to writing. It meant that I would no longer be travelling to Nunavik but that I had more time—and I very much wanted to learn Inuttitut and keep a foot in the North.</p>
<p>In our first class, Marc-Antoine made a point of destroying our hopes. Inuttitut is a highly unfamiliar language, not nearly as easily learned as English or Spanish. Acquiring competence would take years of study and practice, and despite all that effort, we would very likely never be able to really converse.</p>
<p>Strangely, this bleak prospect soon seemed irrelevant. Little by little, I discovered a spectacular language, immensely creative and full of humour. A language that had to invent all sorts of slightly eccentric ways of naming the elements of modern life, but that described the land and hunting techniques with staggering precision. A language that seemed made for poetry with its constructed words and love of repetition; a language that taught me so many things about people that I’d been among for years without ever really knowing.</p>

      </div>
      

            
    
      

            
        

      
    
      

                  <div>
        






<p>Don’t believe everything you’ve heard, however: there are not hundreds of words for snow.</p>

      </div>
      

            
    
      

            
      <div>
        <figure>
          <div>
            <p><img src="https://content.beside.media/beside_/app/www/2020/10/B09_Nuna_Alexis-Hobbs-06.jpg" alt="">
                        </p>
          </div>
        </figure>
      </div>

      
    
      

                  <div>
        <p>Over and over, I’d said what so many others have: that the Inuit have a very liberal concept of time. I learned that it could be as structured as my own; it was just structured around other things. For example, the months are defined by animal behaviours.</p>
<p>September, October, November: <em>amiraijaut, arnalirnguutivik, natjuijarvik.</em></p>
<p>Time when antlers lose their velvet. Time when the males compete for females. Time when caribou shed their antlers.</p>
<p>Places that I had known by their French or English names regained their original appellations: I now dared to utter the word <em>Kangiqsualujjuaq</em>; I no longer needed to say <em>George River</em>. I was unlearning my geography, just as so many Indigenous people have had to unlearn theirs. Even the idea of “the Arctic” once hadn’t existed for the Inuit. They had to invent a word for it that suited a Western geographical perspective: <em>Ukiurtatuq</em>, which translates as “repeated winter.”</p>
<p>I found that the language had a harmonious relationship with the environment—despite the occasionally ruthless climate. In the very first Inuttitut dictionary, written by Taamusi Qumaq in 1991, Nunavik is defined as “a large country occupied by animals.” I admired this humility, this awareness that a place is shared with other species, that one is living, in a way, on <em>their</em>&nbsp; land.</p>

      </div>
      

            
    
      

            
      <div>
        <figure>
                      <img src="https://content.beside.media/beside_/app/www/2020/10/AWH_2318.jpg" alt="">
                            </figure>
       </div>

              
    
      

                  <div>
        <p>It’s perhaps precisely because of this humility that one should never speak ill of <em>sila</em>, the weather. This was a blessing for a snow lover like me, tired of the eternal whinging about winter.</p>
<p>All of these words for different kinds of snow and ice, for Northern hunting and fishing techniques, show the extent to which the Inuit were at one with their land. Some people have bandied about the idea that the ancestors of the <em>Nunavimmiut</em>&nbsp; found themselves stuck in the North, blocked from going south by the Cree in the west and Innus in the east, but this is false. Research has concluded that the ancient peoples of the Arctic in fact moved even further north during a period of warming around the year 1000, because they did not know how to survive without the cold. Today, climate change has had particularly devastating consequences for the populations of Nunavik and Nunavut.</p>
<p>In the land that would become Canada, European explorers (<em>tariup akiani</em>, “from across the sea”) saw a vast reservoir of natural resources for exploitation. Our current climate crisis is the direct result of this unbridled exploitation, our stubborn insistence on doing things our way, our belief that we can draw a hermetic border between us and <em>nuna</em>, the great land, when in fact we live in each other.</p>
<p>Our language navigates modern urbanity with much more ease than Inuttitut, but it reflects a far more distant relationship with the environment, often stuck in the idea of fighting against the elements. Could the rich vocabulary of the Inuit inspire us to redefine our relationship with nature? <span>■</span></p>

      </div>
      

            
    
      

                    <div>
          <p>Born in Montréal in 1985, <strong>Juliana Léveillé-Trudel</strong> writes in various genres: fiction (<em>Nirliit</em>, La Peuplade, 2015, translated by Anita Anand, Véhicule Press, 2018), children’s literature (<em>How to Catch a Bear Who Loves to Read</em>, Chouette, 2018, coauthored with Andrew Katz), blogs, and plays. She has presented many of her theatrical and literary creations on stage. In 2018 she founded Productions de Brousse.</p>
        </div>

            
                
        </section>
      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://beside.media/new-narratives/nuna/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25378558</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 20:57:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A New Take on RSS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 129 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25376849">thread link</a>) | @jacobobryant
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://findka.com/blog/new-take-on-rss/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://findka.com/blog/new-take-on-rss/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Findka now includes an RSS aggregator.</p><p><img src="https://findka.com/img/subscriptions-example.png" alt="Example of subscribing to RSS feeds on Findka"></p><p>If you subscribe to any feeds, then 50% of the articles in your regular Findka
emails will be sampled from those feeds.
I added this because, <a href="https://findka.com/blog/2020-12-05/">as I mentioned</a>,
I'm going to start doing more manual curation to make sure that Findka has a
steady stream of new, great essays. I also think it's a valuable feature for
anyone who wants a little more control over their Findka recommendations.</p><p>How's this different from existing RSS aggregators? For one thing, since this
is built into Findka, any articles that you like will start to be recommended
to other users, too. But there's more.</p><p>Most RSS aggregators keep your feeds separate. Findka instead merges them into
a single feed using a bandit algorithm. If you've subscribed to three
feeds—A, B and C—Findka will start out picking articles from the
feeds uniformly. 1/3 of the articles will come from feed A, etc. As time goes
on, Findka will adjust the distribution based on your usage data. If you never
click on articles from feed A and you always click on articles from feed B,
then Findka will show you fewer articles from A and more articles from B.</p><p>On top of that, the number of articles in your feed is controlled by you, not
by the feeds you subscribe to.</p><p><img src="https://findka.com/img/frequency-setting.png" alt="Example of subscribing to RSS feeds on Findka"></p><p>The result is that using RSS now takes extremely little effort. You get a
single, small feed that improves itself automatically.</p><p>I'm planning to add more RSS-related features—stay tuned.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://findka.com/blog/new-take-on-rss/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25376849</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:40:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using Docker to Manage Your Test Database(s)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25376621">thread link</a>) | @craigkerstiens
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://www.tonic.ai/post/using-docker-to-manage-your-test-database | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tonic.ai/post/using-docker-to-manage-your-test-database">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure id="w-node-b46f52e7cc86-94242d82"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f0ae1534d32e5a91598eb9c/5fb81ee39c9c19251287e848_Docker%20for%20Test%20DB.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><p><em>TL;DR: Docker is a great tool for packaging and distributing test databases among your team and testing environment. We’ve created </em><a href="https://github.com/TonicAI/docker-testdb" target="_blank"><em>a starter repository</em></a><em> to show these concepts in PostgreSQL and MySQL </em><a href="https://github.com/TonicAI/docker-testdb" target="_blank"><em>on Github</em></a><em> if you’d like to dig in immediately while reviewing our process below.</em></p><p>Containers are a valuable resource for us developers. They give you the ability to package your production code, dependencies, and assets into a standardized unit. Once conveniently packaged, running your application in a variety of environments is a breeze. And yet despite containerization’s immense value, we often see teams overlook containers entirely when it comes to managing test databases. At Tonic, whether we’re helping our customers improve testing with high-quality test databases or building our own testing environments, we rely on Docker as a key part of the pipeline. Our customers are finding a lot of value in the approach, so we thought we’d share our strategy.</p><h2>The Trouble With Test Databases</h2><p>Let’s take a look at the typical growth of a test database for a team:</p><ol role="list"><li>You and your team realize that testing in production is a bad idea. You’ve heard about it or you’ve felt the pain yourself: mistakes that lead to data loss and time spent restoring from backups; poor reliability in production due to increased database load; the security team raising their eyebrows at giving too many people access to sensitive data; and the omnipresent anxiety that testing might take down production.</li><li>You decide you need data that’s similar to your production environment, so you write some scripts to generate some fake data (like<a href="https://www.tonic.ai/post/how-to-generate-simple-test-data-with-faker" target="_blank"> faker</a>), use some free or paid services to generate some random data for you (like<a href="https://www.tonic.ai/post/tonic-mockaroo" target="_blank"> Mockaroo</a>), or extract data from production and attempt to anonymize it later (dealing with the mess of maintaining referential integrity).</li><li>You shove either those scripts or data files into your code repo.</li><li>You write in a README the loader command to get it into your database of choice, and like a rite of passage, everyone on the team struggles through getting it to work during onboarding.</li></ol><p>And struggle you will! Databases are notorious for requiring large installations with a multitude of dependencies, navigating arcane configuration, and the extensive work of establishing the test dataset: creating schemas, creating tables, and finally loading your generated data.</p><p>Many teams will have a separate installation process for each operating system their developers use, each of which usually takes a good bit of trial and error after poring over database documentation. Others will set up a staging or test server for their team to use, but it risks becoming out-dated without a regular rebuild, it means a lot of coordination between team members, and there is rarely a one-size-fits-all test environment. For example, when you want to test the scale of your application, your entire team is saddled with a giant database that slows everyone down; likewise, too small of a database can limit effective testing for certain projects.</p><p>Wouldn’t it be great if there were a tool that made it easy to package a database, its dependencies, loader scripts, and its data for any operating system? That any team member could use to easily test their code against a test environment, be it on their local machine or on a quickly spun-up test server in the cloud?</p><h2>Doing Better with Docker</h2><p>Good news, everyone! There is a better way! The many benefits that Docker provides for shipping your code in production work likewise for testing. You can create a database that is easy to distribute, deploy, and reset so that individuals and teams can work effectively without stepping on each other’s toes. For larger organizations, you can even package multiple test databases that each contain different tables or amounts of data, easily available to everyone in your engineering org. Best of all, you don’t need a different local installation README for each operating system—developers can just use the OS they feel most productive in without the headaches of the past.</p><h3>The Basics</h3><p>The simplest way to get started is to use a vanilla database image for your database of choice. By using docker-compose, you can set up the configuration once, and it’s just a<tt> docker-compose up -d </tt>to start the database. Here’s a basic configuration below:</p><h5>version: '3'<br>services:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;testdb_postgres:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;image: postgres:12<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;restart: always<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ports:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;- 5432:5432<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;environment:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;POSTGRES_USER: user<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;POSTGRES_PASSWORD: password<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;POSTGRES_DB: test_data<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;container_name: testdb_postgres<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;volumes:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;- /tmp:/tmp<br></h5><p>This configuration does the following:</p><div><ul role="“list”">
<li>Creates a container named<tt> testdb_postgres </tt>that runs off of a PostgreSQL 12 image</li>
<li>Opens up Postgres’ default port of 5432 to 5432 on your host machine</li>
<li>Attaches the<tt> /tmp </tt>folder to your host machine’s<tt> /tmp </tt>folder</li>
<li>Creates a new user with credentials<tt> user/password</tt>, and a new database called<tt> testdb_postgres</tt>.</li></ul></div><p>Right off the bat, we’ve removed a lot of work from the README, and if you have data or data-generating scripts in your repo, you’ve made it much easier to get up and running quickly by simply pointing them to load into the database via the host part. Many databases have official images, including <a href="https://hub.docker.com/_/postgres/" target="_blank">Postgres</a>, <a href="https://hub.docker.com/_/mysql" target="_blank">MySQL</a>, <a href="https://hub.docker.com/_/microsoft-mssql-server" target="_blank">MS SQL Server</a>, <a href="https://hub.docker.com/_/oraclelinux" target="_blank">Oracle</a>, and <a href="https://hub.docker.com/_/mongo" target="_blank">Mongo</a>, among others.</p><h3>Even Better: Packaging Your Data &amp; Scripts with Docker</h3><p>Instead of just using the available database image and calling it a day, you can easily create a new Docker image based off of your database’s official image. Many official images have an entry point folder that allows you to run scripts upon initialization, enabling the container to be immediately useful as soon as it’s up. To do this, you’ll likely need to add a Dockerfile and a build script, and potentially any data import scripts.</p><h4>Dockerfile</h4><p>Making a basic Dockerfile is not hard at all, in fact it’s only two lines:</p><h5>FROM postgres:12<br>COPY sql/*.sql /docker-entrypoint-initdb.d/</h5><p>Here we did the following:<br></p><div><ol role="list">
<li>We started by defining a<tt> Dockerfile </tt>with a<tt> FROM </tt>declaration pointing to the base image of your database.</li>
<li>We copied over all of our data import scripts (defined in a subdirectory named sql) to the<tt> /docker-entrypoint-initdb.d/ </tt>directory. Postgres <a href="https://hub.docker.com/_/postgres/">defines this folder</a> for SQL scripts to be run during initialization.</li>
</ol></div><p>In our <a href="https://github.com/TonicAI/docker-testdb" target="_blank">code repository</a>, you’ll see we’ve commented out additional options to consider for your use case, such as:</p><ul role="list"><li>Adding any additional dependencies, like database extensions or certificates using typical package manager commands.</li><li>Adding data files to an accessible directory for use with data import scripts.</li><li>Adding custom scripts to import data outside of the container, e.g. via S3 or other data storage.</li></ul><h4>Build Script</h4><p>Here we simply create a shell script to make it easier to build the container. Our build.sh contains the following command which merely tags the new container as<tt> testdb_postgres </tt>and specifies the Dockerfile to use.</p><h5>docker build -f Dockerfile -t testdb_postgres .<br></h5><p>If you were building this in a CI environment, we’d recommend giving the tag a unique version for each build and release as a script argument, such as<tt> testdb_postgres:1.0.4</tt>.</p><h4>SQL Scripts</h4><p>Next, you’ll need to create SQL loader scripts that create your schema and load in your data. Typically the easiest way to do this is by using database dump commands with an existing test database. We recommend three scripts: the first one creates your schema without constraints, the second one loads your data, and the third one adds your constraints to all of your tables. This way, you’re able to load your data without worrying about the order in which it’s loaded (which would matter if foreign key constraints were already in place).</p><p>Some databases will turn off constraints using a data import tool until the import is complete, which means you can just keep your constraints in the schema script. For simplicity, in <a href="https://github.com/TonicAI/docker-testdb" target="_blank">our example code</a> we only use two scripts since our data script loads tables in order and doesn’t break referential integrity.</p><p>Sticking with PostgreSQL as our example, you can run the following command to get a dump of your existing schema and constraints:</p><h5>pg_dump -U user -s -f 1_schema.sql [YOUR DATABASE NAME];</h5><p>Followed by a similar command to get just the data:<br></p><h5>pg_dump -U user -a -f 2_data.sql test_data;<br></h5><p>Notably, we’ve added numbers to the beginning of each filename to ensure that the schema script is run before the data load script. (Postgres runs the scripts in this folder in alphabetical order.)</p><p>Take a look at our code to see the full output of both of these files. Feel free to modify these files as you like or write them from scratch, especially if you plan to load your data using a COPY or LOAD command.</p><h4>Modifying your docker-compose.yml</h4><p>Lastly, update the image you’re using to the name of your newly tagged one: image: testdb_postgres. If you’re versioning your container when you build it, we recommend specifying a stable release tag such as<tt> testdb_postgres:stable </tt>so that users can pull the latest update to that tag with<tt> docker-compose pull</tt>.</p><h4>Setting up CI</h4><p>Now you can check your Dockerfile, scripts, and data files into a code repo, and create a build for the Docker container in your CI service of choice using your build script. Any time the scripts or data files are changed, we recommend triggering a new release build for the container and pushing it to your container repository for use by your entire team (of course, after you’ve checked that nothing new caused the build to break 😉).</p><p>If everything is set up, it should be as simple as distributing the docker-compose.yml file to your team and running a<tt> docker-compose up</tt>.</p><h2>Next Level Test Data Management</h2><p>If you’ve followed the steps thus far, you’ll likely find that your testing setup is much more reliable and useful to your entire team, and it’s a big leap forward in efficiency.</p><p>From here, there are a lot of ways …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.tonic.ai/post/using-docker-to-manage-your-test-database">https://www.tonic.ai/post/using-docker-to-manage-your-test-database</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tonic.ai/post/using-docker-to-manage-your-test-database</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25376621</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:19:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Double fetches, scheduling algorithms, and onion rings]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25375637">thread link</a>) | @markmossberg
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://offlinemark.com/2020/11/12/double-fetches-scheduling-algorithms-onion-rings/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://offlinemark.com/2020/11/12/double-fetches-scheduling-algorithms-onion-rings/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p>Most people thought I was crazy for doing this, but I spent the last few months of my gap year working as a short order cook at a family-owned fast-food restaurant. (More on this <a href="https://offlinemark.com/2020/11/12/gap-year-restaurant/">here</a>.) I’m a programmer by trade, so I enjoyed thinking about the restaurant’s systems from a programmer’s point of view. Here’s some thoughts about two such systems.</p>



<h2>Double, triple, and even quadruple fetching</h2>



<p>Human systems, at first glance, can appear broken, but due to subtle human factors, they might actually work just fine.</p>



<p>My best example is the system for taking and fulfilling orders. We never wrote anything down, and would re-ask orders multiples times, including when ringing customers up. (In computer security, this is known as a <a href="https://ctf-wiki.github.io/ctf-wiki/pwn/linux/kernel/double-fetch/">double fetch</a>.) Not great service and can theoretically let customers lie and pay less. </p>



<p>In practice most customers didn’t mind too much, liars are rare, and we can loosely detect when something seems off with an order.</p>



<p>Writing orders down and asking strictly once seems optimal but has subtle flaws. For one thing, there’s not enough space behind the counter for everyone to walk to the written order, so it requires more internal communication. This will fail during a rush when you’re blocked on order details and coworkers are too busy for questions. <strong>Customers are always idle; coworkers aren’t</strong>.</p>



<p>It can increase confusion if order slips aren’t thrown out when orders are finished and is also logistically (and literally) messy if you have greasy gloves and want to avoid touching a pen, then food. Lastly, many of my coworkers were older and very used to the existing system. <strong>A major transition to a new system would have generated more confusion than it’s worth</strong>.</p>



<h2>Scheduling algorithms for the fry cook</h2>



<p>While I covered a range of duties including the cash register, milkshake machine, and grill, I spent the most time on the deep fryer. I’m delighted to present this overanalysis of life as a fry cook, from a programmer’s point of view.</p>



<p>This is what deep fryers look like (<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=i&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nachi.org%2Fdeep-fryer-inspection.htm&amp;psig=AOvVaw1D90dsceyn1wmU-KOGAEuy&amp;ust=1605391502547000&amp;source=images&amp;cd=vfe&amp;ved=0CAIQjRxqFwoTCNCq-sPDgO0CFQAAAAAdAAAAABAE">source</a>):</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/d12m281ylf13f0.cloudfront.net/images10-2/commercial-fryer-2.jpg?resize=360%2C352&amp;ssl=1" alt="Deep Fryer" width="360" height="352" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/d12m281ylf13f0.cloudfront.net/images10-2/commercial-fryer-2.jpg?resize=360%2C352&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure></div>



<p>This picture has 2 fryers, each with 2 baskets that can be submerged to sit in the vats of hot oil below. At work, only 1 fryer would be active on any given day which effectively allows 2 items to be fried at the same time.</p>



<p><strong>Fry cooks have a lot in common with operating systems in that they are both responsible for scheduling</strong>. Operating systems schedule threads to run on a limited number of cores; fry cooks schedule food to be fried in a limited number of fryers. Different food items have different priorities, and different lengths of time to cook.</p>



<p>French fries, curly fries, and onion rings (collectively, “fries”) are the main menu items from the deep fryer. Each fry order could be large or small (except for rings which were only large) and eat-in or to-go. The job of the fry cook is to:</p>



<ul><li>Accept fry orders from the greeter.</li><li>Allocate portions of fries from the big bags of raw fries</li><li>Cook them in the fryers</li><li>Put them into the appropriate eat-in/to-go container</li><li>Serve them onto the customer’s tray on the counter, or their to-go bag</li></ul>



<p>The goal is to do this with maximum speed and accuracy and without dropping orders. You’ll ideally minimize the number of times you ask customers and coworkers for order details. In addition, there are a few sources of complexity to handle:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Incomplete information</strong>: Depending on the greeter, they may forget to specify if it’s eat-in or to-go. You can always ask the customer, but the grill chef will likely ask the same question in a little bit. You might be able to save a customer ask if you can eavesdrop on that interaction.</li><li><strong>Timing requirements</strong>: You need to finish orders by the time the grill chef finishes the burgers/hot dogs, but you shouldn’t finish too early. If you put the fries on the counter way before the burgers are ready, they’ll get cold. This matters less for to-go orders, which you can serve into the bag immediately.</li><li><strong>Scale</strong>: During a rush, you might receive many orders per minute, while only being able to process 1-2 per minute. Once the greeter relays the order, they forget it, so it’s up to you to remember. And remember: no writing things down.</li><li><span><strong>Waste avoidance</strong>: </span>Sometimes you or another cook will make too many fries. To avoid wasting them, you can use the excess towards a future order by refreshing them with a splash later and adding them to a fresh batch.</li><li><strong>Changing orders</strong>: Customers sometimes change their order after you’ve started cooking (e.g. regular fry to curly fry). Now you have to figure out what to do with the partially cooked portion currently in the fryer.</li><li><strong><strong>Misc items</strong></strong>: In addition to fries, there other items that need to be scheduled for time in the fryer, including chicken patties, bacon, clam strips, and fish fillets. </li></ul>



<p>A few techniques to manage all this:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Batching orders together</strong>. If a large and small fry order are in the queue, you can cook them in the same basket at the same time.<ul><li>Some customers request their fries “well done”, meaning cooked extra long. This makes batching more complicated.</li></ul></li><li><strong>“Wait n Splash”</strong>: If a fry order is done cooking far before the rest of the grill items and you don’t have pressing items that need fryer time, you can raise the basket from the oil, but leave the food in it. When the grill items finish, you can quickly splash the food back in the oil to refresh it, then serve it. This will prevent it from getting cold on the counter.</li><li><strong>Inactive fryer baskets</strong>: It can be handy to have extra storage space for cooked food. If you have a “wait n splash” order waiting, but you have more orders to fry, you can use the 2 spare baskets from the inactive fryer to store the waiting order and free up the fryer slot. This is also useful when customers change their order and you need to quickly stash the half cooked portion somewhere and start the adjusted order.</li><li><strong>“The tong dip”</strong>: If both fryers are in use and the grill chef hands you bacon to be urgently cooked, you can hold the bacon in tongs and dip it into one of the submerged baskets. This lets you effectively cook more than 2 things at the same time.</li></ul>



<p>Here’s the system I ended up using. When a new order came in, I’d stop whatever I was doing and grab the appropriate container and place it in the corresponding fry bucket. This captures all 3 pieces of information about the order (fry type, size, to-go?) letting me forget it. If I strictly follow this, I can just process the containers in the buckets like a queue. However, I still need to keep a sense of order memorized because the system doesn’t capture global ordering – if I have containers in the fry, curly fry, and onion ring buckets, I can’t tell which order came in first.</p>



<p>I don’t have a solution for this. On a super busy day, this system falls apart and I drop orders. Extreme load like that has only happened a few times and in that case, I just make large batches, forget about syncing up with the grill items, and hope I don’t have too much excess at the end. Generally, the system worked nicely.</p>



<h2>Conclusion</h2>



<p>It’s fun to think about human systems, like those in a restaurant, from a programmer’s point of view. A fry cook’s job closely resembles that of an operating system scheduler, complete with optimization points and edge cases. One can try to optimize human systems as if they were computer systems, but it’s critical to understand the subtle human aspects of the system when evaluating improvements.</p>



<div><div>
<div><div>
<div><div>
<hr>



<h3>Learn something new? Let me know!</h3>



<p>Did you learn something from this post? I’d love to hear what it was — tweet me <a href="https://twitter.com/offlinemark">@offlinemark</a>! </p>



<p>I also have a mailing list if you want to know when I write new posts:</p>






<hr>
</div></div>
</div></div>
</div></div>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://offlinemark.com/2020/11/12/double-fetches-scheduling-algorithms-onion-rings/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25375637</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 16:53:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[New Relic to open-source Pixie’s eBPF observability platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 326 | Comments 61 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25375170">thread link</a>) | @htroisi
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://blog.pixielabs.ai/pixie-new-relic/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.pixielabs.ai/pixie-new-relic/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><p>We are excited to announce that we signed a <a href="http://blog.newrelic.com/product-news/pixie-developer-first-observability" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">definitive agreement</a> to join New Relic -- an outcome we certainly never predicted after only just two years.</p><p>New Relic’s focus on the developer is legendary. When New Relic's Founder/CEO, Lew Cirne, first started tinkering around with Pixie and participating in our community, we noticed an alignment in our visions for the future of observability, as well as echoes of New Relic’s developer-centric roots in Pixie. Joining New Relic will provide us with an unprecedented opportunity to reach millions of developers faster by open-sourcing a self-managed version of Pixie in the upcoming months.</p><p>When we started Pixie in 2018, Kubernetes was rapidly gaining traction. We felt that a new approach to observability was needed due to the new, fundamental challenges in observing distributed, ephemeral systems. We founded Pixie in order to provide instant, flexible observability for developers like ourselves who were building applications on Kubernetes.</p><p>However, we knew that the most developer-friendly version of Pixie must be open-source. In a forward-looking move, New Relic is giving us the opportunity to open-source Pixie and focus on providing world-class observability to all developers. The developer community is a core element of New Relic’s vision, and Pixie’s open-source offering will be a key part of that initiative and the primary area of focus for the Pixie team going forward.</p><p>We are so excited to begin working with New Relic on our shared vision for the future of observability. In the coming months, we’ll be jointly committing our roadmap in the following initiatives:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Pixie Core</strong>: An open-source and self-managed version of Pixie which we will release to the CNCF sandbox early next year. As part of the process, we look forward to speaking with you about this at Kubecon-EU on May’21. Due to Pixie’s and New Relic’s commitment to open standards, we also plan to build out integrations with OpenTelemetry, Prometheus, and Grafana.</p></li><li><p><strong>Pixie By New Relic</strong>: Our current Pixie Community offering will continue as a hosted version of Pixie Core and existing New Relic One customers will soon get instant access to Pixie data with a few clicks. Their existing experiences will be augmented with the metrics, logs, events, and application traces that Pixie automatically provides.</p></li><li><p><strong>Pixie by New Relic, Enterprise Edition</strong>: Industry-specific solutions for sectors such as Media, Telecommunications, and Government that allow enterprise customers to install Pixie entirely inside production clusters while meeting compliance, data security, support, and performance requirements.</p></li></ul><p>Finally, our journey is just beginning. We are a team of 12 people with a huge vision to reach every Kubernetes developer. As we embark on this part of our journey, we encourage anyone passionate about open source, Kubernetes, and observability to apply to join us <a href="https://pixielabs.ai/careers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p><p>You can try out Pixie <a href="https://work.withpixie.ai/auth/signup?UTM=PXNR" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>, learn more about us <a href="https://pixielabs.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a> and ping us anytime on our Pixienaut community slack.</p></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.pixielabs.ai/pixie-new-relic/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25375170</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 16:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A guide to product analytics tools for startups]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25375148">thread link</a>) | @Fission
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://satchel.com/web-analytics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://satchel.com/web-analytics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main_content"><div><div><p>Last Updated </p><!-- --><p>May 30, 2020</p></div><div><p>Reading Times:</p><p>Summary only: 1 minute</p></div></div><h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2><p>Every YC batch, Michael Seibel gives a talk about building product. He'll ask: "<a href="https://youtu.be/C27RVio2rOs?t=1677">How many of you are using Google Analytics as your primary source of metrics?</a>" But it's a trick question. When the majority of the audience eventually raises their hands, he'll fake a sigh and tell everyone that they're doing it wrong, and that they should instead by relying on an event-based analytics tool.<span></span><span>The linked video is from Startup School, but the same talk is given at YC Core as well.</span></p><p>It's a perennial favorite, but don't let the humor distract you. Michael's got a
good point. Without using an event-based analytics tool, which tracks the interactions your users have with your product, you won't know <em>how</em> your
users are using your product. This is arguably just as important as actually
building out the product. There are a lot of event-based analytics tools out
there, but we think that if you're an early-stage startup, Heap makes the best tradeoffs.</p><div><p><a target="_blank" href="https://heap.io/"><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/b6fae69c970dbd3257184ea4d909f5d858810bdc/35c24/logos/heap.svg"></a></p><div><p>Our Recommendation</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://heap.io/">Heap</a></p><p>Highest benefit-to-effort ratio</p><p>Gave us auto-tracking functionality, which we think is an exceptionally good safety net for an early-stage startup with rapidly-changing features and limited engineering resources, although it lacks some of the extensibility and more advanced analysis capabilities of its competitors. That said, we think this tradeoff best suits an early-stage startup.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://heap.io/">heap.io</a></p></div></div><summary><h2 id="summary">Summary</h2><ul><li>"Setting up event-based metrics is something that's super important very early in your company, because it's how you know whether your product is being used or not. And it's the number one source of new product ideas and inspiration." - Michael Seibel</li><li>Google Analytics by itself is insufficient to figure out how your users are using your product, although it is useful to complement an event-based analytics tool.</li><li>Event-based analytics help you figure out what actions a user took on your website.</li><li>We are primarily focused on evaluating the three main event-based analytics tools: Mixpanel, Amplitude, and Heap.</li><li>We found that event-based analytics is a category of SaaS with some of the most feature parity.</li><li>The core analytics functionality of all three tools is more or less equivalent.</li><li>The key considerations for an early-stage startup are the amount of maintenance and discipline required to maintain useful analytics, and the ability to go far without spending a lot of money.</li><li>We found that defining events in code while having auto-track as a safety net is a near-ideal setup for an early stage startup.</li><li>We recommend Heap, because it is the only major analytics tool that offers this capability. The main downside for an early-stage startup is that you can't get as far on a free plan on Heap compared to Mixpanel or Amplitude.</li><li>If pricing is the main consideration, then we recommend Amplitude. Even though its product is oriented towards later-stage companies, Amplitude has the most generous free plan of the major event-based analytics providers.</li></ul></summary><h2 id="ratings-matrix">Ratings Matrix</h2><h2 id="context">Context</h2><h3 id="what-is-event-based-analytics">What is event-based analytics?</h3><p>Pageview-based analytics tools like Google Analytics and event-based analytics tools such as Mixpanel, Amplitude, and Heap are typically grouped together under the heading of analytics tools. However, we think that lumping them all under the same heading is misleading, because they fundamentally do different things. To better understand what event-based analytics are, we need to understand what exactly Google Analytics does, figure out where its gaps are, and then use that context to motivate event-based analytics tools. </p><p>Google Analytics uses a pageview-driven paradigm, a holdover from what was important in the early 2000s. Its focus on pageviews helps answer questions such as how many users came to your website, what pages they visited, and how they found your website. Unfortunately, it isn't able to help you figure out which specific actions a user performed on any given page of your website. For example, it doesn't answer whether a user clicked on a CTA button, if they abandoned their cart, how far they got into signing up, or what part of the page they were looking at before they converted. Answering these kinds of questions can be quite informative to early-stage startups' decision-making, and can be accomplished quite easily by using an event-based analytics tool.</p><p>An event-based tool will provide two things: an interface to collect "events", and an interface to analyze those events. You can define and implement your events (commonly referred to as instrumenting) by calling the API of the event-based analytics tool you're using.</p><p>To illustrate, let's say you run an ecommerce store. You want to figure out what types of items people checkout without hesitation, and what types of items often result in abandoned carts. This isn't something that can be accomplished with pageview-based analytics tools such as Google Analytics. However, this can be performed quite easily with an event-based analytics tool. If you track two events — when someone adds something to their cart, and when someone checks out their cart — you can figure out which SKUs lead to a high checkout rate, and which SKUs lead to abandoned carts. This is implemented by calling two functions: </p><ol><li><p>a function <code>track('add-to-cart', {&lt;metadata&gt;})</code>, including metadata about the item added (e.g. SKU, name, price) in your code that executes when someone adds something to cart, and </p></li><li><p>a similar function <code>track('checkout', {&lt;metadata&gt;})</code> in your code that runs when someone checkouts. Data from these events will be sent to your analytics provider, which will provide an interface to analyze and draw conclusions from your data.</p></li></ol><p>This is a simple example, but is already quite a powerful tool to understand your users, and can be easily extended. The same power generalizes beyond an ecommerce store to any startup's web product, helping one answer essential questions such as: Is your CTA convincing? What are the characteristics of products that customers are the most hesitant about buying? What part of the signup process needs to be improved to prevent potential users from dropping off? Which portion of your product page was the most engaging and persuaded customers to take the next step?</p><h3 id="early-stage-startups-and-their-analytics-dilemma">Early-stage startups and their analytics dilemma</h3><p>If event-based analytics are so important for early-stage startups, one might rightly wonder why so many YC startups, whose founders are quite sharp in aggregate, rely primarily on Google Analytics?</p><p>It turns out that this is a rather illuminating question. The main contributor to this phenomenon is easy to understand and empathize with. Startups are busy and overworked, and analytics are often ostensibly seen as orthogonal to the priorities of understanding their users and building product<span></span><span>The <a href="https://blog.ycombinator.com/ycs-essential-startup-advice/">canonical priorities</a> for early-stage startups.</span>. Therefore, event-based analytics often fall to the wayside as they typically require engineering time and discipline to maintain. If you forget to update an event, or don't have time to implement analytics for a new feature, then you can't get any benefit out of it at all.</p><p>Yet, in reality, event-based analytics are one of the best sources of new product insights and inspiration and are a fantastic way to understand how your users are using your product. This is one of our main motivations for writing this particular guide. Early-stage startups have a unique set of challenges to face, particularly around prioritizing their time and engineering resources. That said, we think that there's an approach that can make event-based analytics require a lot less discipline, and therefore make it a lot more attainable for an early-stage startup.</p><h2 id="methodology">Methodology</h2><p>Based on a few years of first-hand experience using and testing event-based analytics tools, in addition to aggregating feedback from other founders, we have found the following factors matter most for early-stage startups choosing an analytics tool:</p><ul><li><p><strong>Core Analytics Functionality</strong> refers to the standard analytics features that are critical for an early-stage startup to understand their users. These include standard analysis tools, such as funnel analysis (i.e. figuring out when users drop out in each step of a process), retention analysis (i.e. figuring out how many users churn, and when), and cohort analysis (i.e. figuring out how different user segments interact with your product). </p></li><li><p><strong>Robustness / Ease of Maintenance:</strong> Early-stage startups need to use analytics just as much as larger companies, but also have to be a lot more resourceful and focused with their time and energy. What happens if you change a component, and don't update the tracking code? What happens if you're under time pressure from a customer and make the conscious decision to launch a complex product without tracking? While large companies have the ability to implement strict QA processes and are okay with extended deadlines, early-stage startups don't have these options. Therefore, we've kept a close eye out for how each analytics tool performs under less-than-ideal situations.</p></li><li><p><strong>Affordability:</strong> Web analytics tools are somewhat notable/notorious for giving generous free plans, attaining lock-in, and then making things more expensive once your company starts becoming successful <span></span><span>This is one of the reasons why <a href="#consider-using-segment-as-a-wrapper">we suggest using Segment</a>, since it helps you avoid vendor lock-in and gives you more negotiating power.</span>. That said, several analytics tools have generous free tiers or deals that can last you quite a long time without paying. Therefore, we've split this criterion into two subcriteria: <strong>How far you can get without paying</strong>, and <strong>Paid Plan Affordability</strong>. The latter is actually somewhat non-trivial to evaluate, because most analytics providers hide their pricing behind a Contact Us gate, even for early-stage startups. That said, we got our hands on a decent amount of data on the actual cost of each service, and we have also compiled a list of typical discounts and deals that you can reasonably expect to get from each analytics provider.</p></li><li><p><strong>Ease…</strong></p></li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://satchel.com/web-analytics/">https://satchel.com/web-analytics/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://satchel.com/web-analytics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25375148</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 16:06:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A typical day as an engineering manager]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25375100">thread link</a>) | @karlhughes
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/engineering-manager | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/engineering-manager">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
<article>
<div>
<p><img src="https://www.karllhughes.com/assets/img/engineering-manager-time.png" alt="A Day in the Life of an Engineering Manager">
</p> 

<p>
2020, Nov 01&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;—&nbsp;
7 minute read
</p>
<section id="mc_embed_signup">

</section>
<p>During the eight years I spent as an engineering manager, I regularly tracked how I spent my time. As a startup engineering manager, I was responsible for a wide range of duties, so keeping track of which areas I spent the most time on helped me plan and schedule appropriately.</p>
<p>For example, I knew that I typically spent about 1/3rd of my time helping my team solve technical problems or pairing with teammates. Knowing this, I reserved some free blocks of time for them. If my whole week were full of meetings and big-picture planning, I’d become a blocker for my team who needed my input on specific issues.</p>
<p>Since many prospective software engineering managers ask me about my job and what it entails, I decided to create this detailed look at how I spent my time. While every company and role is different, I hope this post gives you some first-hand insight into a day in the life of an engineering manager.</p>
<p><em>Note: If you’re looking for some books to help you on your journey as a software engineering manager, <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/reading-for-engineering-managers">here are some of my favorites</a>.</em></p>
<h2 id="what-does-an-engineering-manager-do">What Does an Engineering Manager Do?</h2>
<p>First, a little bit about my roles as an engineering manager: my first management role was at <a href="https://www.packback.co/">Packback</a>, a question and answer platform for college professors.</p>
<p>I joined the team when there were just four people in the company - it was essentially myself and the founders. In the intervening three years, I saw the company raise close to $5 million and grow to almost 30 people. My engineering team was pretty lean - there were five when I left in 2016 - but my role changed quite a bit over my years with the company.</p>
<p>After <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/joining-the-graide-network">I left Packback to join The Graide Network</a>, I started over as an engineering manager. Initially, my team was just a contractor and me, but over my four years at Graide, I <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/hiring-process">hired three other engineers</a> and <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/product-management-process">took on more of the product management duties</a>.</p>
<p>While my day-to-day work changed a lot over the years, <strong>as a software engineering manager, I was ultimately responsible for helping my team ship software that worked as expected on schedule and within budget.</strong></p>
<p>The tricky word there is “helping.” What does that mean exactly? Does it mean that an engineering manager writes code? Or do they just make sure everyone on their team is writing code?</p>
<p>The short answer is: it depends.</p>
<h3 id="engineering-managers-must-be-technical">Engineering Managers Must be Technical</h3>
<p>Generally, engineering managers write less code than the senior developers on their team, but <a href="https://medium.com/swlh/do-engineering-managers-need-to-write-code-d89903d68e8d">they should write some code to keep their skills sharp</a>. They also need to be good at helping their team members get “unstuck.” Sometimes this means answering technical questions, and sometimes it means solving disputes between team members.</p>
<p>They’re likely to play a role in <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/developing-talent">training new engineers</a> as well as evaluating candidates on a technical and interpersonal basis.</p>
<h3 id="engineering-managers-have-to-be-good-with-people">Engineering Managers Have to be Good with People</h3>
<p>Being “good with people” is a tough label to nail down.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/e7ML5PR.gif" alt="I have people skills! - Office Space"></p>
<p>Many people assume that you have to be an extrovert to be an effective manager, <a href="https://www.inc.com/john-brandon/are-extroverts-the-best-leaders-maybe-not.html">but that’s not necessarily true</a>. Having empathy for your team and helping them through challenges - both technical and personal - is one of an engineering manager’s primary mandates.</p>
<p>But, engineering managers have to “manage up” as well. This means they need to look out for their team’s best interests when their boss asks them for feedback, and it means they might have to let a team member go if they’re not getting the job done.</p>
<h3 id="the-hardest-part-about-engineering-management">The Hardest Part About Engineering Management</h3>
<p>As I moved into my first management role, the most challenging part was adjusting my method for self-evaluation. Nickolas Means says it well in his <a href="https://leaddev.com/self-care-burnout/learning-love-meta-productivity">fantastic piece on meta productivity for managers</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Every so often, I have a day where I look up after the last meeting has ended and feel like I’ve gotten absolutely nothing done. I’ve been busy all day long: having conversations, reading documents, and checking in with peers and team members. I’m exhausted, but I’ve accomplished nothing.” - Nickolas Means</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It was <em>relatively</em> easy for me to tell how productive I had been as a software engineer. I usually made progress on shipping a feature or opened up a pull request, but as a manager, I had a really hard time telling whether my day was productive or not.</p>
<p>That’s why I started tracking my time. While time spent on a task is not a perfect measurement of productivity, it helped me make sure I was investing enough time into each area of my job.</p>
<h2 id="how-does-an-engineering-manager-spend-their-time">How Does an Engineering Manager Spend Their Time?</h2>
<p>Engineering managers tend to have a wide range of responsibilities, and these responsibilities vary based on the employer’s size and organizational structure. To help you see how an engineering manager spends their time, I broke my time down into four categories:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Technical</strong> (35%)</li>
<li><strong>Managerial</strong> (35%)</li>
<li><strong>Recruiting</strong> (15%)</li>
<li><strong>Administrative</strong> (15%)</li>
</ul>
<p>In this section, you’ll see how I spent my time as an engineering manager. I’ll offer a little bit about the specific tasks encompassed in each area and why it was an important part of my daily work.</p>
<p>While I tracked my time pretty rigidly for periods of my 8-year management career, I decided to round each category to a nice round number for the sake of simplicity. Exact hours spent on each task aren’t the point here, but I found it helpful to know if one area spiked in one week or dropped sharply in another.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Tx9pTaz.png" alt="engineering-manager-time"></p>
<h3 id="technical">Technical</h3>
<p><em>35% of my time.</em></p>
<p>Technical work includes writing code, code reviews, hunting down bugs, pairing with teammates, and reading software updates and best practices. As my teams grew, the amount of time I devoted to writing and reviewing code dwindled, but I do think it’s important for engineering managers to spend at least <a href="http://www.drdobbs.com/architecture-and-design/engineering-managers-should-code-30-of-t/240165174">some of their time elbows deep in the code</a>.</p>
<h3 id="managerial">Managerial</h3>
<p><em>35% of my time.</em></p>
<p>This includes direct people management, creating timelines, strategic planning, and meetings with technical and non-technical team members. Making sure my team was happy, advocating for them in business meetings, and helping our product team create technical specs were all part of my engineering manager duties at Packback.</p>
<p>At The Graide Network, I took a more strategic role by consulting with the founders on software choices and jumping in on important sales calls. Interestingly, while the tasks I took on were different, the time breakdown was pretty similar.</p>
<h3 id="recruiting">Recruiting</h3>
<p><em>15% of my time.</em></p>
<p>Recruiting time included going to conferences, meetups, and coding bootcamps, writing blog posts, meeting with job candidates, and evaluating technical screenings.</p>
<p>While I spent more of my time on recruiting when I had an open engineering job, smart engineering managers are <em>always</em> hiring. The best candidates are usually the passive ones who rarely look for a job, so I spent a portion of my time getting in front of them each week.</p>
<h3 id="administrative">Administrative</h3>
<p><em>15% of my time.</em></p>
<p>Finally, I spent a few hours per week reading and writing emails, answering questions in Slack, random conversations, and “other” day-to-day things to support my team. As the manager, I tried to keep these kinds of distractions away from my engineering team, but I’d schedule time with team members when necessary.</p>
<p>If an engineering manager’s job is to make their team as productive as possible, it stands to reason that most of the administrative work will fall to them.</p>
<h2 id="what-makes-a-good-engineering-manager">What Makes a Good Engineering Manager?</h2>
<p>I don’t think I can give you <em>everything</em> you need to know about being a good engineering manager in just one blog post (<a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/reading-for-engineering-managers">here are some good books on the topic though</a>), so I’ll just pick the three things that I focus on first.</p>
<h3 id="1-empower-your-team">1. Empower Your Team</h3>
<p>Being a good manager is all about <a href="http://www.jrothman.com/articles/1999/01/successful-engineering-management-7-lessons-learned/">helping others achieve great things</a>.</p>
<p>This means that as a manager, your <a href="https://leaddev.com/self-care-burnout/learning-love-meta-productivity">impact is much less direct</a>, and therefore, you can’t spend all your time heads down in the code. It was frustrating for me to see my weekly accomplishments list shrink, but once I learned to accept that my team was getting more done without my individual contributions, I started to really enjoy the role.</p>
<h3 id="2-overcommunicate">2. Overcommunicate</h3>
<p>Whether your team is working in one room or working <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/managing-remote-engineering">remotely across the world</a>, communication is one of your most crucial roles as a manager. In marketing, there’s an idea that <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/its-nagging-repetition-effective-communication-marton-jojarth/">people must hear your message seven times before they internalize it</a>, and I think this applies to team communication as well.</p>
<p>I’m not saying you should repeat everything seven times in the same meeting, but think about reiterating significant changes in one-on-ones, group settings, via email, and in passing. Change is scary, but the more people hear about something, the less scary it tends to be.</p>
<h3 id="3-be-the-source-of-calm">3. Be the Source of Calm</h3>
<p>Finally, as the engineering manager, your role is to “<a href="https://staysaasy.com/management/2020/07/07/dont-create-chaos.html">vacuum up chaos</a>:”</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Any room that you enter should have more certainty and a firmer plan by the time that you leave it. Good leaders can walk into a situation where people have lost track of their goals and get everyone aligned on a clear path forward.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Don’t create or perpetuate drama, divide your team from the rest of the company, or pit team members against each other. Instead, be the one who absorbs uncertainty and stress so your team can get sh** done.</p>
<hr>
<p>If you’re an aspiring engineering manager or you’re just wondering what your boss does all day, I hope this helps you.</p>
<p>Interested in more great reading material? Here are some of the <a href="https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/reading-for-engineering-managers">books that helped me on my journey to become an engineering manager</a>.</p>

<section id="mc_embed_signup">

</section>
</div> 
</article> 
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.karllhughes.com/posts/engineering-manager</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25375100</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 16:01:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Problem with Corporate Innovation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25375013">thread link</a>) | @nicotesla
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://blog.codelitt.com/corporate-innovation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.codelitt.com/corporate-innovation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <article>
      

      
      <section id="Post__Main-Content">
        <div>
          <h2 id="discovering-the-problem">Discovering the Problem</h2><p>Startups are swallowing corporations' markets. This is mainly because corporations struggle with innovation, regardless of how much they use that word in press releases and PPT presentations. About 7 years ago we started <a href="http://www.codelitt.com/">Codelitt</a>, a corporate skunkworks and product incubator company. We build startups for corporations and invest 20% of our time in building products, tools, and <a href="https://github.com/codelittinc">open source projects</a> for the web. </p><p>In the beginning, we didn't set out to discover a specific problem. Put another way, we weren't being purposeful about searching for a problem to solve. This post is half about the problem with corporate innovation and half about our discovery process that led us to where we are today:</p><h2 id="eye-opening">Eye-opening</h2><p>In the beginning of my career I worked for investors in Latin America helping to build and launch startups before later moving to corporate America. Although I'm often critical of corporate culture, it was really eye opening and integral to my career. Really this is one of the best pieces of advice I can give to entrepreneurs looking for problems to solve:</p><blockquote>If you are smart and ambitious but can't find a problem to solve, go work for a large (preferably traditional) corporation. You'll find plenty there.</blockquote><p>Large enterprises succeed <em>in spite</em> of themselves. It really is a wonder that they get anything done at all. I can't speak for every single large company, but I've worked with quite a few. In one way or another they all have systemic issues. This is not to say that startups or more modern tech companies don't have their own issues. We do. But the proof is in the pudding and startups are launching products monthly that will take a huge chunk of traditional companies' markets or even render them completely irrelevant.</p><p>Some large enterprises have realized that their biggest threat isn't another corporate giant, it's some unknown kid building something. In order to compete, they have to create new value, do a little disruption of their own, and start shipping.</p><blockquote>However, traditional companies spend millions in R&amp;D and take several years to come to market.</blockquote><p>So the question is, why are they at such a disadvantage when their seemingly endless budgets should afford them a solid advantage? The answer is that the same tools, systems, and culture that they rely on to manage their large organization don't work for innovation and skunkworks teams.</p><h2 id="decisions-by-consensus">Decisions by Consensus</h2><p>Traditionally the vast majority make decisions by consensus. Note: there is a difference between collaboration and consensus. Collaboration takes different points into account but can still have one decision maker, whereas consensus decision making requires every single person to have input and be onboard. This is crippling to organizations. Teams should have a single decision maker.</p><p>Any startup who has experienced the sales cycle of a large company can attest to this first hand. While many sales people focus on identifying "the decision maker level," this person is rarely the only decision maker and they'll likely have an entire team to convince. When making a sales pitch (even for a $1,000 a month SaaS product) you'll very likely spend time in a room of 12 or so people from different areas of the company. Most of those people will likely have different needs and agendas. The same is true when it comes to developing new products, processes, or strategy. Decision making time is multiplied by an exponential factor.</p><blockquote>In the time it takes a large organization to make a decision just to move forward with something, a startup could have built, launched, and validated a new feature or model.</blockquote><h2 id="corporate-it">Corporate IT</h2><p>There are a number of reasons why normal innovation processes, product prototyping, and building new business models is so costly inside a large organization. Time is a huge factor. A close second is the cost of actual development. As with everything, I'm sure there are reasons for why things are done the way they are done. But from a product development perspective and coming from the startup world, they are nearly impossible to understand.</p><p>Corporate IT departments have a hard time looking at a product as something that develops. They see a project as having a start date, an end date, and a full set of features. There is no iterative development. They plan for every possible scenario and build to the full spec. Version releases begin with 1.0.0 launch and following releases are security patches at best.</p><p>Instead of using open source tools, large IT teams are locked in to Microsoft and Oracle products. I've never been able to understand why this is completely. It could be the fact that they spend a solid chunk of time earning Oracle or Microsoft Certifications. It could be the comfort of having support just a phone call away. Or it could even be an unwillingness to learn something new. </p><p>From a security perspective, it's like looking for a babysitter to watch your kids, asking for her recommendations, and she tells you, "Just trust me. I promise your child is secure. But just so you know, we'll be doing things my way; your house rules don't apply."</p><p>From a time perspective, there are open source technologies that allow you to whip up an MVP in much less time. Even with complaints about Rail's "magic under the hood," you can't deny that it's a powerful tool to quickly build a prototype.</p><p>From a cost perspective, licenses are expensive and they add up quickly. Millions of dollars are spent on IT licensing every year by large orgs. Imagine if that money was spent on employing core devs for the respective clients like we've seen with Red Hat, Bitpay, and Google.</p><blockquote>Developing a new product or business can often cost millions to develop with the traditional IT infrastructure and business processes. Timelines, again, are measured in years, not weeks.</blockquote><h2 id="risk-averse">Risk-averse</h2><p>The final piece to the puzzle which impedes progress and innovation is often a risk-averse nature. Being risk-averse is 'consultant speak' inside a large organization. Entire teams are dedicated to mitigating risk. I've heard a lot of different theories for why this is from insiders and outsiders over the years:</p><p><strong>Job security</strong> is one that gets floated around a lot. The 25 year Rolex, the benefits, and the cushy salary really don't require a whole lot. Don't upset the status quo, don't argue with the wrong people, play the politics, and work well with others. Do those 4 things and you have very little to worry about. Large companies rarely fire people who do those things. It's easy for anyone to become complacent when basic needs are taken care of. Unfortunately for them however, disruption requires risk. There's always the risk of being wrong. Being wrong is rarely celebrated in corporate culture and that stigma can follow someone around for the rest of their career preventing any sort of upward mobility. In our world, many of us have failed a few times, succeeded a couple, and worked for several companies. Our entire attitude towards failure and opportunity is a completely different perspective.</p><p>Another is the <strong>high visibility</strong> that corporations have in the public eye. Because of their size, most things they do are considered <a href="http://www.mediacollege.com/journalism/news/newsworthy.html">newsworthy</a> due to the impact it could have on their customers, employees, or investors. In the startup world, we have the luxury of being able to fail relatively quietly. Our customers and beta users are usually very understanding of certain degrees of failures to the point they even expect them. Remember those corporate departments dedicated to risk management? These often include legal, public relations, and marketing communications teams. They all have the responsibility to keep the public face of the company as free from blemishes as possible.</p><blockquote>Disruption requires risk. No great invention, change, or innovation ever came from doing the same thing over and over. <a href="https://blog.codelitt.com/not-innovating/">You have to be ready to break things along the way</a>.</blockquote><h2 id="their-disadvantage">Their Disadvantage</h2><p>When you begin to understand the issues that are faced by teams tasked with innovation projects, skunkworks programs, or disrupting old models you can see how simple objectives for us turn into difficult ones for them. While many of us perhaps envy their resources, they're actually at a huge disadvantage to us in every other way. They have a massive problem, one that we set out to solve:</p><blockquote>For them innovation, product development, and skunkworks is expensive, slow, regulated, ineffective, and swimming against the current.</blockquote>
        </div>
      </section>


        <div>
  <h3>Stay up to date!</h3>
  <p>
    Get all the latest &amp; greatest information delivered straight to your inbox
  </p>

  
</div>

    </article>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.codelitt.com/corporate-innovation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25375013</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 15:55:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[CentOS Stream, or Debian?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 95 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25374783">thread link</a>) | @pabs3
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://jonathancarter.org/2020/12/10/centos-stream-or-debian/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jonathancarter.org/2020/12/10/centos-stream-or-debian/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><strong>It’s the end of CentOS as we know it</strong></p><p>Earlier this week, the CentOS project announced the shift <a href="https://blog.centos.org/2020/12/future-is-centos-stream/">to CentOS stream</a>. In a nutshell, this means that they will discontinue being a close clone of RHEL along with security updates, and instead it will serve as a development branch of RHEL.</p><p>As you can probably imagine (or gleam from the comments in that post I referenced), a lot of people are unhappy about this.</p><p>One particular quote got my attention this morning while catching up on this <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/838889/">week’s edition of Linux Weekly News</a>, under the distributions quotes section:</p><blockquote><p>I have been doing this for 17 years and CentOS is basically my life’s work. This was (for me personally) a heart wrenching decision. However, i see no other decision as a possibility. If there was, it would have been made.</p><cite><a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/839521/">Johnny Hughes</a></cite></blockquote><p>I feel really sorry for this person and can empathize, I’ve been in similar situations in my life before where I’ve poured all my love and energy into something and then due to some corporate or organisational decisions (and usually poor ones), the project got discontinued and all that work that went into it vanishes into the ether. Also, 17 years is really long to be contributing to any one project so I can imagine that this must have been especially gutting.</p><p><strong>Throw me a freakin’ bone here</strong></p><p>I’m also somewhat skeptical of how successful CentOS Stream will really be in any form of a community project. It seems that Red Hat is expecting that volunteers should contribute to their product development for free, and then when these contributors actually want to use that resulting product, they’re expected to pay a corporate subscription fee to do so. This seems like a very lop-sided relationship to me, and I’m not sure it will be sustainable in the long term. In <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/centos-stream-building-innovative-future-enterprise-linux">Red Hat’s announcement of CentOS Stream</a>, they kind of throw the community a bone by saying “In the first half of 2021, we plan to introduce low- or no-cost programs for a variety of use cases”- it seems likely that this will just be for experimental purposes similar to the <a href="https://insider.windows.com/">Windows Insider program</a> and won’t be of much use for production users at all.</p><p>Red Hat does point out that their <a href="https://developers.redhat.com/products/rhel/ubi">Universal Base Image</a> (UBI) is free to use and that users could just use that on any system in a container, but this doesn’t add much comfort to the individuals and organisations who have contributed huge amounts of time and effort to CentOS over the years who rely on a stable, general-purpose Linux system that can be installed on bare metal.</p><p><strong>Way forward for CentOS users</strong></p><p>Where to from here? I suppose CentOS users could start coughing up for RHEL subscriptions. For many CentOS use cases that won’t make much sense. They could move to another distribution, or fork/restart CentOS. The latter is already happening. One of the original founders of the CentOS project, Gregory Kurtzer, is now working on <a href="https://rockylinux.org/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://rockylinux.org/">Rocky Linux</a>, which aims to be a new free system built from the RHEL sources.</p><p>Some people from Red Hat and Canonical are often a bit surprised or skeptical when I point out to them that binary licenses are also important. This whole saga is yet another data point, but it proves that yet again. If Red Hat had from the beginning released RHEL with free sources and unobfuscated patches,  then none of this would’ve been necessary in the first place. And while I wish Rocky Linux all the success it aims to achieve, I do not think that working for free on a system that ultimately supports Red Hat’s selfish eco-system is really productive or helpful.</p><p>The fact is, Debian is already a free enterprise-scale system already used by huge organisations like Google and many others, which has stable releases, LTS support and ELTS offerings from external organisations if someone really needs it. And while RHEL clones have come and gone through the years, Debian’s <a href="https://www.debian.org/social_contract">mission and contract to its users</a> is something that stays consistent and I believe Debian and its ideals will be around for as long as people need Unixy operating systems to run anywhere (i.e.  a very long time).</p><p>While we sometimes fall short of some of our technical goals in Debian, and while we don’t always agree on everything, we do tend to make great long-term progress, and usually in the right direction. We’ve proved that our method of building a system together is sustainable, that we can do so reliably and timely and that we can collectively support it. From there on it can only get even better when we join forces and work together, because when either individuals or organisations contribute to Debian, they can use the end result for both private or commercial purposes without having to pay any fee or be encumbered by legal gotchas.</p><p>Don’t get caught by greedy corporate motivations that will result in you losing years of your life’s work for absolutely no good reason. Make your time and effort count and either contribute to Debian or give your employees time to do so on company time. Many already do and reap the rewards of this, and don’t look back.</p><p>While Debian is a very container and virtualization friendly system, we’ve managed to remain a good general-purpose operating system that manages to span use cases so vast that I’d have to use a blog post longer than this one just to cover them.</p><p>And while learning a whole new set of package build chain, package manager and new organisational culture and so on can be uhm, really rocky at the start, I’d say that it’s a good investment with Debian and unlikely to be time that you’ll ever felt was wasted. As Debian project leader, I’m personally available to help answer any questions that someone might have if they are interested in coming over to Debian. Feel free to mail leader_AT_debian.org (replace _AT_ with @) or find me on the oftc IRC network with the nick <em>highvoltage</em>. I believe that together, we can make Debian the <em>de facto</em> free enterprise system, and that it would be to the benefit of all its corporate users, instead of tilting <em>all</em> the benefit to just one or two corporations who certainly don’t have your best interests in mind.</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jonathancarter.org/2020/12/10/centos-stream-or-debian/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25374783</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 15:36:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Getting our first thousand users in one day]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 150 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25374319">thread link</a>) | @frankdilo
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://francescodilorenzo.com/typefully-launch | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://francescodilorenzo.com/typefully-launch">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>Yesterday we launched <a href="https://typefully.app/">Typefully</a>, a write-only interface for Twitter, after weeks of work and refinement. I documented the whole story on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/frankdilo">@frankdilo</a>.</p>
<p>Not much deep work happened on launch day and for good reasons. It was a bigger launch than <a href="https://francescodilorenzo.com/mailbrew-launch-numbers">Mailbrew's</a>.</p>
<p>Here the numbers:</p>
<ul>
<li>16,400 Pageviews </li>
<li>1,432 Signups </li>
<li>1,843 Drafts created</li>
<li>256 Threads published</li>
<li>$155 Revenue (more on this at the end).</li>
</ul>
<p>The traffic breakdown reveals what happened:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hacker News: 6.3k</li>
<li>Twitter: 2.1k</li>
<li>ProductHunt: 1.9k</li>
</ul>
<p>Yeah, we finally managed to hit the <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25358108">Hacker News frontpage</a>. </p>
<p>The perfect formula was:</p>
<ul>
<li>interesting product</li>
<li>no-bullshit title</li>
<li>sparking a controversial discussion in the comments.</li>
</ul>
<p>When it comes to Twitter, we have been building a following there for some time, so it was a matter of publishing the <a href="https://twitter.com/frankdilo/status/1336589322670268416?s=21">right tweet</a>, at the right time, and getting the right people to retweet it.</p>
<p>For Product Hunt, we partnered with our friend <a href="https://twitter.com/chrismessina">Chris</a>. His followers got a notification when he hunted us, but we also did our part and emailed our lists.  That helped to get fast on the front page and to kickstart the discussion.</p>
<p>Once we were in front of enough people, the product did the rest.</p>
<p>Servers did hold up without a sweat. </p>
<p>It's crazy what you can do these days with a couple of well-configured dynos on Heroku and a Django app! We peaked at 8 RPS when we hit the HN frontpage.</p>
<p>Typefully was born as <a href="https://twitter.com/linuz90">Fabrizio</a>'s personal side-project. I jumped in to make the editor crazy-fast, and write the server-side code. When <a href="https://twitter.com/meseali">Ali</a> helped us refine positioning and copy, we knew we had a winner and promoted it to an official <a href="https://mailbrew.com/">Mailbrew</a> project.</p>
<p>Plans for the future? Implement all the great feature requests we got, and monetize this thing. </p>
<p>We launched with a tip-jar system where people could become <em>patrons</em> by tipping us, but with $150 earned after a crazy launch day like this, it's clear that this is not going to pay the bills. </p>
<p>We are thinking of adding some paid features. What's free is gonna stay free though, because this was first and foremost a labor of love.</p>
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://francescodilorenzo.com/typefully-launch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25374319</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 14:59:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: A DIY particle detector kit developed at CERN]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25373912">thread link</a>) | @kasbah
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://shop.kitspace.org/buy/electron-detector/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://shop.kitspace.org/buy/electron-detector/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A kit to make the electron detector variant of the DIY Particle Detector project.</p><p>This open hardware project is a mobile low-cost detector for measuring ionising radiation like electrons from beta radiation (plus some gamma photons). It's an educational tool and citizen science device made for exploring natural and synthetic sources of radioactivity such as stones, airborne radon, potassium-rich salt or food and every-day objects (Uranium glass, old Radium watches etc.).</p><p>This project is developed by Oliver Keller at CERN, see full project details <a href="https://kitspace.org/boards/github.com/ozel/diy_particle_detector/electron-detector/">here.</a></p><p>This is a kit to make your own electron detector. A required metal enclosure (see the<!-- --> <a href="https://github.com/ozel/DIY_particle_detector/wiki/Enclosures">wiki</a>) and a 9V battery are not included.</p><div><p><span>Worldwide Shipping (estimated delivery by Monday, December 21, 2020)</span></p><p><span>€15.00</span></p></div><p><b>Total: </b><b>€45.00</b></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://shop.kitspace.org/buy/electron-detector/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25373912</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 14:18:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Never work as a software engineer in a startup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25373431">thread link</a>) | @veebuv
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://www.buildingstartups.co/blog/never-work-as-a-software-engineer-in-a-startup | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.buildingstartups.co/blog/never-work-as-a-software-engineer-in-a-startup">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I'm speaking in front of 200 people tomorrow on the topic around software development for startups. There are hundreds of books written on this so I'll try to condense my learnings from most.</p><p>Even though we're a startup company at <a href="#"></a><a href="#"></a><a href="#"></a><a href="#"></a>, I stopped hiring software engineers, hell I tried to unlearn and relearn a few things in the journey as well.</p><p>Confusing I know - I still have to grapple around the entirety of it all but the honest truth is being a software engineer alone will get you easily fired or unvalued in a startup.</p><p>You need to fire yourself from that role and re-hire yourself as a product engineer. I've referenced this point multiple times in my previous articles and I really stand by this.</p><p>I don't think this necessarily applies for larger companies when they're hiring specialists and algo heavy engineers, however in a startup you need to think about the product, the marketing and most important the customer.</p><p>There is a significant disconnect in larger firms from the creator (developer) to the end user, all the way from hierarchy, to Project Managers, to Product Managers, to Marketers, to Execs etc - but in a startup, if you push code up... it's up.</p><p>So whats so special about being a product engineer that a software engineer can't do? A few things:</p><h3>1. They carry a get shit done attitude</h3><p>Sure some engineers carry that too, these statements aren't binary or exclusive but address the vast majority. When you look at github discussions or you look at conference events where people share their discoveries, it's all based around the engineer - not as much around the customer.</p><p>So yes, product engineers have a get shit done attitude, keeping in mind that they need to push good work out, but are quick on their feet to understand how much of debt some technical decisions will be vs others. This will be understood better over time, and even after a decade of programming, I can confirm that there is no right or wrong answer, its extremely situational based.</p><h3>2. Business first, software second</h3><p>You should toughen up and realise that building on the latest and greatest tech will not make you a better engineer. You almost NEVER have as much a good reputation for being the engineer for a bad startup as you may of a good startup, even though your code in the bad startup might be worthy of awards and your code in the good startup might be worthy of firing. It's inherent you see - good code isn't coincidentally in good companies, its because the companies made the smart decision of hiring mini-CTOs, people who understood that their customer mattered as much as their code.</p><p>This doesn't mean you give up all morals and build on PHP(I'M JOKING :p), but it kinda does. Not PHP but any language that is deemed unfit just because it's popular or not. You do a direct risk analysis on what will get me to my next goal ASAP. Whether that's faster iteration, more features or modularised code bases.</p><h3>3. Customer first, business second</h3><p>It should all come down to how you can make the life of the customer as easy as possible when you're solving the problem for them. Sometimes business requirements become business requirements and not customer requirements, and if you're just a software engineer by title, you will be doing what you're told to do because thats the limitation you have, at least the limitation I had a couple of years ago.</p><p>By stepping out of that box and understanding that if the business requirements step outside of the customer requirements, you get to voice your opinion and more importantly add the kicker to your "opinion" by justifying it with your technical abilities, techies are badass, we're the makers, so in the end if we have the knowledge around consumerism AS well as execution, it'll make us bulletproof.</p><p>So yes, if you're in a startup - don't work as a software engineer, work as a product engineer. Your impact will be 10X I kid you not.</p><p>People will take you ALOT more seriously, you'll climb the ranks faster, your code will matter a lot more, and the impact will be at scale. Your work matters and there should be no reason why more people shouldn't experience your genius code, the way you can make that happen is by being product focused and ensuring your customers are having the best time of their life.</p><p>As with any post, I'm always always looking to learn and become better at what I do, so I'd love to hear what you have to say, good or bad 🙌</p><p>If you liked this, definitely follow me on for the similar stuff:</p><p>twitter: twitter.com/<a href="https://dev.to/veebuv">@veebuv</a><br>linkedin: linkedin.com/in/vaibhavnamburi<br>instagram:_veebuv</p><p>‍</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.buildingstartups.co/blog/never-work-as-a-software-engineer-in-a-startup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25373431</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 13:26:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AR with SceneKit and Metal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25373105">thread link</a>) | @emllnd
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://emillindfors.com/blog/2020-12/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://emillindfors.com/blog/2020-12/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <p>Recently I found myself needing to process and visualize both point clouds and meshes in an iOS application utilizing ARKit, with the point cloud being gathered using the 2020 iPad “LiDAR” sensor. To enable maximum performance and content creation convenience I thought it would be nice to have both custom shaders and a regular, easy-to-work-with 3D hierarchy available. The best options available seemed to be Metal and SceneKit, which required some initial setup to get working together. That setup is detailed in this post.</p>
<p><em>If all this sounds unfamiliar see <a href="https://blog.halide.cam/lidar-peek-into-the-future-with-ipad-pro-11d38910e9f8">here</a>, <a href="https://developer.apple.com/metal/">here</a> and <a href="https://www.raywenderlich.com/2243-scene-kit-tutorial-getting-started">here</a> for introductions to these technologies.</em></p>












<a href="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/sceneKitAndPointCloud.webp">
    <picture>
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img-preview/blog/2020-12/sceneKitAndPointCloud.webp">
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/sceneKitAndPointCloud.webp">
        <img src="https://emillindfors.com/img-fallback/blog/2020-12/sceneKitAndPointCloud.jpg">
    </picture>
</a>

<p>To help you recreate what I did, the post is accompanied by a GitHub repository showing the specifics: <a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal">github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal</a>.</p>

<p><em>Note that the repo uses slightly confusing naming. XCode project name is “smTest” (for “SceneKit Metal test”), which leads to combinations such as smTestTest for the auto-generated unit testing project… not the best choice, but bear with me.</em></p>
<p><em>Also note that this is not really beginner level stuff, nor is having both SceneKit and Metal rendering usually required. If you just want to do some 3D+AR on iOS, good tech to start with would likely be either <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/realitykit/">RealityKit</a>+<a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/realitykit/creating_3d_content_with_reality_composer">RealityComposer</a>, the more widely applicable tool <a href="https://tutorialsforar.com/creating-an-ar-app-for-ios-using-unity-and-arkit/">Unity</a> or just plain <a href="https://blog.pusher.com/building-an-ar-app-with-arkit-and-scenekit/">SceneKit</a>.</em></p>

<p>RealityKit seems like the future, but I was interested in custom shaping of meshes at runtime with e.g. geometry shaders and there did not (yet?) seem to be hooks for integrating that kind of processing in RealityKit.</p>
<p>Turns out those hooks do exist in SceneKit, which is an older and more mature technology. They can be used to implement custom render steps either before or after regular rendering. A helpful blog post with details that aided me with the ‘<strong>renderer didRenderScene</strong>’ hook can be found here: <a href="https://rozengain.medium.com/custom-metal-drawing-in-scenekit-921728e590f1">Custom Metal Drawing in SceneKit</a>. Thanks for the writeup Mr. Ippel!</p>
<p>I chose to get started with combining ARKit, SceneKit and custom Metal rendering by mashing two of Apple’s example applications together:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Scene Depth demo app (<a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/arkit/visualizing_a_point_cloud_using_scene_depth">Visualizing a Point Cloud Using Scene Depth</a>)</li>
<li>The default SceneKit AR project created by the XCode project wizard (creation steps depicted below)</li>
</ul>












<a href="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/newSceneKitARProj.webp">
    <picture>
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img-preview/blog/2020-12/newSceneKitARProj.webp">
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/newSceneKitARProj.webp">
        <img src="https://emillindfors.com/img-fallback/blog/2020-12/newSceneKitARProj.jpg">
    </picture>
</a>


<p>The trickiest part was to get the depth blending working correctly. SceneKit and the custom Metal renderer of the Point Cloud demo use different depth buffer conventions, which caused a few moments of initial confusion before realizing I would have to adjust depth settings to make them compatible.</p>
<p>Initial depth buffer ranges <em>(from memory, might be incorrect)</em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>SceneKit:</p>
<ul>
<li>empty = zero</li>
<li>growing towards camera</li>
<li>range around 0.00-0.05</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>SceneDepthPointCloud Metal renderer</p>
<ul>
<li>empty = negative infinity(?)</li>
<li>shrinking towards camera</li>
<li>range around 1.0-9.9995</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>To make the depth blending behave nicely and consistently, it was needed to set the proper depth blending mode (<em>shown as DepthStencilState –&gt; DepthCompareFunction in the XCode Frame Debugger</em>), to find matching value ranges for both depth buffers and to keep the 3D scenes of both renderers in their respective camera frustums (having good values for znear and zfar) so that they would not get culled off by being too near or too far.</p>












<a href="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameDebug.webp">
    <picture>
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img-preview/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameDebug.webp">
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameDebug.webp">
        <img src="https://emillindfors.com/img-fallback/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameDebug.jpg">
    </picture>
</a>


<p>If you’re working in a recent Apple dev environment in a fairly empty project, there’s a good chance you can get started with GPU debugging right away. You just need to build and run your app and press the camera icon (and wait a bit):</p>












<a href="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameCaptureButton.webp">
    <picture>
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img-preview/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameCaptureButton.webp">
        <source type="image/webp" srcset="https://emillindfors.com/img/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameCaptureButton.webp">
        <img src="https://emillindfors.com/img-fallback/blog/2020-12/xcodeGPUFrameCaptureButton.jpg">
    </picture>
</a>

<p><em>(from here: <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/metal/frame_capture_debugging_tools/viewing_your_frame_graph">Viewing Your Frame Graph</a>)</em></p>
<p>If you crave more in-depth GPU debug options or have trouble getting started, more info can be found on the page about <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/metal/frame_capture_debugging_tools">Frame Capture Debugging Tools</a> as well as the guide page for <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/metal/frame_capture_debugging_tools/enabling_frame_capture">Enabling Frame Capture</a>.</p>

<p>For more specific details on how I combined the two renderers, see the changes included in the first few commits (Nov 24th &amp; 28th) on the <a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/commits/main">commits page</a> of the example repository. It shows the history of how I:</p>
<ul>
<li>started with a blank SceneKit AR project using the Project Wizard (<a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/commit/3d5358507d2824d0d57335d6988ec81d20291b9d">Initial commit</a>)</li>
<li>added custom Metal rendering as per Mr. Ippel’s <a href="https://rozengain.medium.com/custom-metal-drawing-in-scenekit-921728e590f1">post</a> (<a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/commit/75ad32f2012594ba3c09df9f351299d64f0ecb59">draws simple triangle, …</a>)</li>
<li>copied in the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/arkit/visualizing_a_point_cloud_using_scene_depth">SceneDepthPointCloud</a> demo and made sure the application still builds (<a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/commit/cbcdaf130a288a7ad68cd2a848ddd671269b93d6">builds with SceneDepthPointCloud …</a>)</li>
<li>fiddled with accumulation settings etc confusedly to get the thing closer to working (<a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/commit/39ba6d28e7f22ae202e20344c503a2136932f3ff">almost works …</a>)</li>
<li>and finally adjusted the depth blending, depth range and camera frustum settings to be able to see both scenes together (<a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/commit/4a60df6c60b380d72ec740171c3440ffa09ddc23">improved …</a>, <a href="https://github.com/emllnd/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/commit/39c9a0e7a997567ca978e1190b67cd2af9790666">draws both …</a>)</li>
</ul>

<p>The end result of all these steps can be seen in motion below. It is of course merely the starting point for a more interesting application that leverages the ease and speed of regular 3D asset workflows and selectively applies the power of customized GPU processing as needed.</p>



<p><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/485931370?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>



<p>At the time of first publication of this post (Dec 2020) I’m not sure if the depth buffer is entirely in sync between the two renderers, even though they both do render simultaneously. The point cloud looks alright behind the rocketplane(? 😄), but I’m not sure whether they behave correctly in overlap situations. However, the fix should be just a matter of adjusting camera and depth buffer parameters and possibly scene scale (<em>famous last words…</em>).</p>
<p>If and when time permits, I will update the post and the repository with improved details.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading!</p>


    	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://emillindfors.com/blog/2020-12/ar-with-scenekit-and-metal/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25373105</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 12:46:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lessons from Running a Sale That Earned 3 Month's Profit in a Week]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 180 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372636">thread link</a>) | @czue
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://www.coryzue.com/writing/black-friday/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.coryzue.com/writing/black-friday/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
                <p>A few weeks ago I was in a bad place.</p>

<p>My product Pegasus—a <a href="https://www.saaspegasus.com/">Django boilerplate for SaaS applications</a>—was 
having its worst sales slump in recent history.
Meanwhile, my other product, Place Card Me—an <a href="https://www.placecard.me/">online place card maker</a>—continued
to be hit hard by the pandemic, with sales down almost $10,000 from 2019.
It looked like I was going to fall short on my targets for the month. 
<em>Again</em>.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.coryzue.com/images/black-friday/place-card-me-2020.png" alt="Place Card Me"></p>

<p>The grey line is Place Card Me’s profits in 2019. The purple line is 2020. Thanks, Covid.</p>

<p>And then on a lark I thought, “well maybe I’ll try running a Black Friday sale.”</p>

<p><strong>And my month’s trajectory completely changed.</strong></p>

<p>A few hours of work and a week later, and I had shattered my previous earnings for any month—earning
more than 3 months’ worth of typical profit in a single week.</p>

<p>Through the process, I learned a lot about running sales—lessons I thought I should share.
Because Black Friday <em>is</em> a huge opportunity for online creators and indie hackers. 
One that—if you’re anything like me—you’re probably not taking full advantage of.</p>

<p>Here’s what I did and what I learned along the way.</p>

<h2 id="deciding-to-run-a-sale-by-overcoming-the-ickiness-factor">Deciding to run a sale by overcoming the “ickiness factor”</h2>

<p>If you’re like me, your first reaction to the idea of a Black Friday sale might be something along the lines of 
“ugh, those are so overdone and spammy”.
And it’s true, Black Friday and Cyber Monday sales have become ubiquitous online.</p>

<p><em>But Black Friday sales aren’t inherently bad.</em></p>

<p>Many consumers, including myself, happily take place in Black Friday deals.
They’re a great way to support creators and pick up products you’ve long considered buying.</p>

<p>To get over my fear of “Black Friday ickiness”, I decided to turn to other successful creators who were also running deals.
Adam Wathan and Steve Shoger of <a href="https://tailwindui.com/">Tailwind UI</a> / <a href="https://refactoringui.com/">Refactoring UI</a>;
online educator extraordinaire <a href="https://wesbos.com/">Wes Bos</a>;
fellow solopreneur <a href="https://mtlynch.io/">Mike Lynch</a> for his product <a href="https://tinypilotkvm.com/">TinyPilot</a>.
How were they doing Black Friday and what could I learn from them?</p>

<p>My favorite example came from Wes Bos, which <a href="https://marketingexamples.com/">Harry’s Marketing Examples</a>
did a great job analyzing:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.coryzue.com/images/black-friday/wes-bos-black-friday.jpeg" alt="Wes Bos Black Friday"></p>

<p>Wes Bos’s “masterful” Black Friday email. Image and analysis from <a href="https://twitter.com/GoodMarketingHQ/status/1331573176405536769">Harry’s Marketing Examples</a></p>

<p>This email and the others I looked at all shared similar qualities.
They were <em>genuine</em>, they <em>put the reader first</em>, and they <em>weren’t too pushy</em>.
It was “hey, here’s a great deal in case you’re interested, if not, sorry to bug you.”</p>

<p>Seeing that it was possible to run a deal in a classy way was enough to get me over the “ickiness” factor,
and provided a framework for crafting my own sales communications.</p>

<p><strong>Lesson: Running a sale doesn’t have to be “icky” if you do it right.</strong></p>

<h2 id="choosing-the-right-sale-structure-by-adding-value">Choosing the right sale structure by <em>adding value</em></h2>

<p>People expect Black Friday deals to offer a huge discount from normal prices—particularly 
for online products. Here’s a typical deal I received, with bundle of fonts being offered at 95% off 
the normal price:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.coryzue.com/images/black-friday/wild-ones-black-friday.png" alt="Wild Ones Font Bundle"></p>

<p>A typical Black Friday deal—offering 95%-off a bundle of commercial fonts.</p>

<p>Offering a huge discount is a great way to drive sales, but it comes with a huge cost. 
<em>Literally</em>. A big discount will substantially reduce your revenue-per-customer and 
leave money on the table.</p>

<p>And that’s not the only problem.</p>

<p>In addition to the lost revenue, <em>massive discounts devalue your product</em>.
If your customers know that you sometimes sell your product for 95% off, they’re likely 
to think it’s only worth 5% of it’s price.
<em>You’ve just turned your valuable good into a commodity.</em></p>

<p>So how do you run a sale without reducing your prices? <strong><em>You add value.</em></strong></p>

<p>Take Adam Wathan and Steve Shoger’s deal.
They took their two products, <a href="https://tailwindui.com/">Tailwind UI</a> (normally $249) and 
<a href="https://refactoringui.com/">Refactoring UI</a> (normally $149), and bundled them together for $279.
Their customers are simultaneously <em>saving $120</em> while <em>paying more than the price of either individual product.</em>
This is adding value at its finest.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.coryzue.com/images/black-friday/refactoring-ui.jpg" alt="Refactoring UI Black Friday"></p>

<p>The Tailwind UI / Refactoring UI deal—which used bundling to offer 30% off while simultaneously increasing prices.</p>

<p><em>Bundling</em>—what Adam and Steve did by offering two products together at a discount—is a great way to 
add value while not lowering prices.
A similar approach is to <em>offer increased benefits on a lower pricing tier</em>. 
This is the approach I took with my own product.</p>

<p>My product, <a href="https://www.saaspegasus.com/">SaaS Pegasus</a>, is designed to help people launch new web applications quickly.
Pegasus has two pricing tiers, a <em>single-site</em> version for $295, and an <em>unlimited</em> version for $750.
The product is the same, but the single-site version is only able to be used on—well—a single site,
while the unlimited version can be used on—you guessed it—unlimited sites.
The unlimited version also comes with lifetime updates to Pegasus itself, instead of just a year.</p>

<p>Anyway, the details aren’t important, but what <em>is</em> important is that more than 90% of my customers 
opt—at least initially—for single-site. 
So for my Black Friday deal I decided to offer the unlimited version at price of single-site. 
This allowed me to offer a 60% discount without significantly reducing my revenue per customer
or devaluing my product.</p>

<p>Whether you use bundling, the “increased benefits on a lower tier” approach, or something else, 
adding value is a great way to create a “Black Friday deal” feeling while not incurring 
some of the financial and psychological costs associated with heavy discounting.</p>

<p><strong>Lesson: Don’t lower prices, add value.</strong></p>



<p>Ok, you’ve gotten over the ickiness factor and you’ve chosen a sale structure that adds value.
Now’s the most important part: <em>spreading the word</em>.</p>

<p>When considering how best to get the word out, think of the following breakdown.
Everyone is either <em>interested</em> or <em>not interested</em> in your sale.
Likewise everyone will either <em>find out</em> or <em>not find out</em> about it.
This creates four buckets that any person might fall into:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.coryzue.com/images/black-friday/sale-matrix.png" alt="Sale Categorization Breakdown"></p>

<p>Breakdown of the possible ways people can experience your sale.</p>

<p>The two green boxes are what you’re aiming for. 
Of course, you want everyone who might be interested in the sale to find out about it—these are your potential customers!
Also, you want everyone who <em>isn’t</em> interested in the sale to not get spammed by it—the blissfully unaware.</p>

<p>The tradeoffs and mistakes happen in the red boxes.
What you really want to prevent is <em>lost customers</em>—people who would have been interested in the deal
but never knew it was happening.
You also want to annoy as few people as possible, but <em>it’s generally better to promote the deal to someone who wasn’t interested
than to have someone who was interested miss it</em>. 
The upside of a potential sale clearly outweighs the downside of mildly annoying someone.</p>

<p><strong>Lesson: Default to promoting everywhere that the signal-to-noise ratio isn’t terrible.</strong></p>

<h3 id="where-to-promote-your-sale">Where to promote your sale</h3>

<p>The key avenues for promotion—in order of importance—are your <em>website</em>, your <em>email list</em>, and <em>other online marketing channels</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Your website is your best source of potential customers.</strong></p>

<p>No one is more likely to be interested in your deal than someone who is already browsing your product website,
so you should do everything you can to ensure all website visitors see your deal.</p>

<p>I used the common technique of splashing a big-ass colorful banner on every page of the site.
Here’s what it looked like.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.coryzue.com/images/black-friday/pegasus-sale.png" alt="Pegasus Sale"></p>

<p>Don’t be shy promoting your sale on your website. These are the people most likely to benefit from it.</p>

<p>Your goal is to make it impossible for someone visiting your website to not hear of the sale,
so err on the side of flashy, even if it seems a bit much.</p>

<p><strong>Your email list is your next best source of potential customers.</strong></p>

<p>People on your email list were interested in your product at one point, and so are more likely
than almost anyone else to still be interested, so make sure to let them know!</p>

<p>My email sequence consisted of two mails:</p>

<ol>
  <li>An email at the start of the sale telling people about it.</li>
  <li>An email with 24 hours left in the sale telling people it was about to end.</li>
</ol>

<p>Some people add a third email in the middle—often with 48 hours to go. 
I don’t recommend more than 3 emails as you seriously risk pushing people 
further into the “annoyed” category.</p>

<p>In terms of email copy—you can’t do better than the Wes Bos example above.
But for the sake of transparency, here’s the mail I used:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.coryzue.com/images/black-friday/pegasus-email.png" alt="Pegasus Email"></p>

<p>The first email in my sequence announcing the Pegasus Black Friday deal.</p>

<p>One difference between Wes and I is that my email list is <em>cold</em>—I almost never use it.
So I added a reminder for people who might be wondering what Pegasus even was.
I also included details on some new features to show that I’m still improving the product.</p>

<p><strong>All other channels besides your website and email list are a distant third in terms of usefulness.</strong></p>

<p>For this reason, I severely limited promotion in other places unless they were 
specifically aggregating Black Friday deals—and therefore unlikely to annoy anyone.</p>

<p>Depending on your product and audience, social media can be a good channel, though it’s not for Pegasus
so I didn’t bother promoting there.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">1</a></sup></p>



<p>It’s important to realize that unless you did something very wrong, 
<strong><em>people will be more likely to purchase your product during a sale than at any other time.</em></strong></p>

<p>Now, if you’ve taken the advice above and are still getting good revenue-per-customer during
the sale, there is an interesting side-effect:
<strong>website traffic <em>during a sale</em> is more valuable than at any other time</strong>.</p>

<p>I’ll show you just how much more valuable it was for me in the next section <em>(preview: it was way more than I expected)</em>.</p>

<p>In practice, this means that any additional effort you can expend to get people to your website—for any reason—will 
have a higher payoff during a sale.</p>

<p>How you leverage this information depends on your marketing strategy.
If you’re running ads, consider increasing your budget while the sale is running;
if you do content marketing, consider publishing your next big article during the sale, etc.
These efforts—while not necessarily directly related to the sale—will have the side-effect of getting
more eyes on your site at the exact moment your …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.coryzue.com/writing/black-friday/">https://www.coryzue.com/writing/black-friday/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.coryzue.com/writing/black-friday/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25372636</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 11:47:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Burnt $72k testing Firebase and Cloud Run and almost went bankrupt]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 249 | Comments 347 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25372336">thread link</a>) | @bharatsb
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>                
			<blockquote>
  <p>This is the story of how close we came to shutting down before even launching our first product, how we survived, and the lessons we learnt.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In March, 2020, when COVID hit the world, our startup Milkie Way too was hit with a big blow and almost shut down. <strong>We burnt $72,000 while exploring and internally testing Cloud Run with Firebase within a few hours.</strong></p>

<p>In November 2019, after having the idea, I started developing <strong>Announce <a href="https://annc.in/">https://announce.today</a></strong>. The goal was to create an “MVP”, a functional V1 of the  product, and for this reason our code was based on a simple stack. We used JS, Python and deployed our product on Google App engine.</p>

<center>
<em>Announce on Desktop</em>
<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/post_images/anc-first-look.png" width="100%"><br>
</center>

<p>Having a very small team, our focus was on writing code, designing the UI and getting product ready. I spent minimal time in Cloud management, just enough to make us go live, and have basic development flow (cicd) going.</p>

<p>In the V1 web application, user experience was not the smoothest, but we just wanted to make a product that some of our users could experiment with, while we built a better version of Announce. With Covid hitting the world, we thought it was the best time to make a difference as Announce could be used by the governments to make announcements world wide.</p>

<p>Wouldn’t it be cool to have some rich data on the platform even if users don’t create content to begin with? This thought that led to another project, called <strong>Announce-AI</strong>. It’s purpose was to create rich content for Announce automatically. Rich data == events, safety warnings like earthquakes, and possibly local relevant news.</p>

<h3 id="some-technical-details">Some Technical Details</h3>
<p>To begin developing Announce-AI, we used Cloud Functions. As our bot scraping the web was fairly young, we believed light weight Cloud functions were the way to go. However, as we decided to scale, we ran into troubles because Cloud Functions have a timeout of ~9 minutes.</p>

<p>At this time we learn about Cloud Run, which then had a big free usage tier! Without understanding it completely, I asked my team to deploy a “test” Announce AI function on Cloud Run, and see it’s performance. The goal was to play around with Cloud Run, so we can learn and explore it really fast.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/cloud-run.jpg" width="80%"><br>
<em>Google Cloud Run</em></center>

<p>To keep it simple, as our experiment was for a very small site, we used Firebase for database, as Cloud Run doesn’t have any storage, and deploying on SQL server, or any other DB for a test run would have been an over kill.</p>

<p>I created a new GCP project ANC-AI Dev, set up $7 Cloud Billing budget, kept Firebase Project on the Free (Spark) plan. The worst case we imagined was exceeding the daily free Firestore limits if we faltered.</p>

<p>After some code modifications, we deployed the code, ran it by making few requests in middle of the day manually and then left it.</p>

<h3 id="nightmare-begins">Nightmare Begins</h3>
<p>Everything went fine on the day of test, and we got back to developing Announce. Next day after working, I went for a quick nap in late afternoon. On waking up I read few emails from Google Cloud, all sent within few minutes of each other.</p>

<center>
<em>First Email: Auto upgrade of our Firebase Project</em>
<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/auto-upgrade.jpg" width="80%"><br>
</center>

<center>
<em>Second Email: Budget Exceeded</em>

<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/budget.jpg" width="80%"><br>
</center>

<p>Luckily my card had a spending limit of $100 preset. This led to declining the charges, and Google suspending all our accounts with it.</p>

<center>
<em>Third email: Card was declined</em>

<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/card-declined.jpg" width="80%"><br>
</center>

<p>I jumped out of the bed, logged into Google Cloud Billing, and saw a bill for ~$5,000. Super stressed, and not sure what happened, I clicked around, trying to figure out what was happening. I also started thinking of what may have happened, and how we could “possibly” pay the $5K bill.</p>

<p>The problem was, every minute the bill kept going up.</p>

<p>After 5 minutes, the bill read $15,000, in 20 mins, it said $25,000. I wasn’t sure where it would stop. Perhaps it won’t stop?</p>

<p>After two hours, it settled at a little short of $72,000.</p>

<p>By this time, my team and I were on a call, I was in a state of complete shock and had absolutely no clue about what we would do next. We disabled billing, closed all services.</p>

<p>Because we used same company card across all our GCP Projects, all our accounts and projects were suspended by Google.</p>

<h3 id="nightmare-continues">Nightmare Continues</h3>
<p>This happened on Friday evening, March 27th, 3 days before we had planned V1 of Announce to go live. Our product development was dead as Google suspended all our projects as they were tied to same credit card. My morale was as low as it could be, and the future of our company was unsure.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/suspended.jpg" width="80%"><br>
<em>All our Cloud Projects were suspended; development stopped</em></center>

<p>Once my mind made peace with this new reality, at midnight I sat down to actually investigate what happened. I started writing a document detailing all the investigations… I called this document: “Chapter 11”.</p>

<p>Two of my team members who were in this experiment also stayed up all night investigating and trying to make sense of what had happened.</p>

<p>The next morning on Saturday, March 28th, I called and emailed over a dozen law firms to book an appointment / have a chat with some attorney. All of them were away, but I was able to get response from one of them over email. Because the details of the incident are so complicated even for engineers, explaining this to an attorney in plain english was a challenge of its own.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>As a bootstrapped company, there was no way for us to come up with $72K.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>By this time, I was well versed with Chapter 7 and Chapter 11 of Bankruptcy and mentally prepared of what could come next.</p>

<h3 id="some-breather--gcp-loopholes">Some Breather : GCP Loopholes</h3>

<p>On the Saturday after sending emails to lawyers, I started reading more and going through every single page in GCP Documentation. We did make mistakes, but it didn’t make sense that Google let us spend $72K without even making a payment on the project before!</p>

<center>
<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/firebasegcp.jpg" width="80%"><br>
<em>GCP and Firebase</em></center>

<h4 id="1-automatic-upgrade-of-firebase-account-to-paid-account">1. Automatic Upgrade of Firebase Account to Paid Account</h4>
<p>We never anticipated this, nor was this ever displayed while signing up for Firebase. Our GCP project had billing connected to have Cloud Run execute, but Firebase was under Free plan (Spark). GCP just out of the blue upgraded it, and charged us for the amount it needed to.</p>

<p>It turns out this is their process as “Firebase and GCP are deeply integrated”.</p>

<h4 id="2-billing-limits-dont-exist-budgets-are-at-least-a-day-late">2. Billing “Limits” don’t exist. Budgets are at least a day late.</h4>
<p>GCP Billing is actually delayed by at least a day. In most of their documentation Google suggests using Budgets and auto shut-off cloud function. Well guess what, by the time the cut off function would trigger, or the Cloud Users be notified, the damage would’ve probably been done.</p>

<p>Billing takes about a day to be synced, and that’s why we noticed the charges the next day.</p>

<h4 id="3-google-was-supposed-to-charge-us-100-not-72k">3. Google was supposed to charge us $100, not $72K!</h4>
<p>As our account had not made any payment thus far, GCP should’ve first made charge for $100 as <a href="https://cloud.google.com/billing/docs/how-to/billing-cycle#find-threshold-amount">per billing info</a>, and on non-payment, stopped the services. But it didn’t. I understood the reason later, but it’s still not the user’s fault!</p>

<p>The first billing charge made to our account was of ~ $5,000. The next one for $72,000.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/automatic-payments.jpg" width="100%">
<em>Billing threshold for our account was $100</em>

</center>

<h4 id="4-dont-rely-on-firebase-dashboard">4. Don’t rely on Firebase Dashboard!</h4>
<p>Not just Billing, but even Firebase Dashboard took more than 24 hours to update.</p>

<p>As per Firebase Console documentation, the Firebase console dashboard numbers may differ ‘slightly’ from Billing reports.</p>

<p>In our case, it differed by <strong>86,585,365.85 %</strong>, or 86 million percentage points. Even when the bill was notified to us, Firebase Console dashboard still said 42,000 read+writes for the month (below the daily limit).</p>

<h3 id="new-day-new-challenge">New Day, New Challenge</h3>
<p>Having been a Googler for ~6.5 years and written dozens of project documents, postmortem reports, and what not, I started a document to share with Google outlining the incident, and adding the loopholes from Google’s side in a postmortem. Google team would come back to work in 2 days.</p>

<p>EDIT: Some readers suggested that I used my internal contacts at Google. The truth is that I haven’t been in touch with anyone, and I used the path that any normal developer / company would take. Like any other small developer, I spent countless hours on chat, in consults, lengthy emails, and bugs. In one of my next posts on how to look at incidents, I’d like to share the doc/postmortem I sent to Google during this incident.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/assets/images/72K/googleplex.jpg" width="40%"><br>
<em>Last day at Google</em></center>

<p>Another task was to understand our mistake, and devise our product development strategy. Not everyone on the team knew what was going on, but it was quite clear that we were in some big trouble.</p>

<p>As a Googler I had experienced teams making mistakes costing Google millions of dollars, but the Google culture saves the employees (except engineers have to write a long incident report). This time, there was no Google. Our own limited capital and our hard work, was at complete stake.</p>

<hr>

<p>This post is already getting long, so I’ll continue the details of how we managed to make this blunder, how we survived, and what did we learn.</p>

<p>See you in <strong><a href="https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-2/">Part 2: https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-2</a></strong>.</p>
                
			</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.tomilkieway.com/72k-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25372336</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 10:56:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[This Week in Rust 368]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25371862">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
December 10, 2020 | https://this-week-in-rust.org/blog/2020/12/09/this-week-in-rust-368/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://this-week-in-rust.org/blog/2020/12/09/this-week-in-rust-368/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <p>Hello and welcome to another issue of <em>This Week in Rust</em>!
<a href="http://rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> is a systems language pursuing the trifecta: safety, concurrency, and speed.
This is a weekly summary of its progress and community.
Want something mentioned? Tweet us at <a href="https://twitter.com/ThisWeekInRust">@ThisWeekInRust</a> or <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/this-week-in-rust">send us a pull request</a>.
Want to get involved? <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md">We love contributions</a>.</p>
<p><em>This Week in Rust</em> is openly developed <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/this-week-in-rust">on GitHub</a>.
If you find any errors in this week's issue, <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/this-week-in-rust/pulls">please submit a PR</a>.</p>

<h3 id="official">Official</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blog.rust-lang.org/2020/12/07/the-foundation-conversation.html">The Foundation Conversation</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="newsletters">Newsletters</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://rust-gamedev.github.io/posts/newsletter-016/">This Month in Rust GameDev #16 - November 2020</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/k6cka7/rib_newsletter_18_on_to_the_ribbles/">RiB Newsletter #18 - On to the Ribbles</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="tooling">Tooling</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://rust-analyzer.github.io/thisweek/2020/12/07/changelog-54.html">Rust Analyzer Changelog #54</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/knurling-changelog-9/">Knurling-rs Changelog #9</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.jetbrains.com/clion/2020/12/intellij-rust-updates-for-2020-3/">IntelliJ Rust: Updates for 2020.3</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="observationsthoughts">Observations/Thoughts</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.fpcomplete.com/blog/monads-gats-nightly-rust/">Monads and GATs in Nightly Rust</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fanf.dreamwidth.org/134024.html">Vanishing zeroes for geometric algebra in Rust</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.thomasheartman.com/posts/on-generics-and-associated-types">On Generics and Associated Types</a></li>
<li><a href="https://vector.dev/blog/adaptive-request-concurrency/">Adaptive Request Concurrency. Resilient observability at scale.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.logrocket.com/rust-compression-libraries/">Rust compression libraries</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.marcoieni.com/2020/12/rust-makes-cross-compilation-childs-play/">Rust makes cross compilation child's play</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jmmv.dev/2020/12/builder-pattern-for-tests.html">Using the builder pattern to define test scenarios</a></li>
<li><a href="https://rust-analyzer.github.io/blog/2020/12/04/measuring-memory-usage-in-rust.html">Measuring Memory Usage in Rust</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.tag1consulting.com/blog/saving-time-switching-users-async-support-goose">Saving time by switching users: Async support in Goose</a></li>
<li><a href="https://evrone.com/rust-vs-c">Why Rust is meant to replace C</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="rust-walkthroughs">Rust Walkthroughs</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://subvisual.com/blog/posts/real-time-video-processing-with-rust-ffmpeg-opencv/">Real-time video processing with Rust, FFmpeg and OpenCV</a></li>
<li><a href="https://dev.to/creativcoder/merge-k-sorted-arrays-in-rust-1b2f">Merge k sorted arrays in Rust</a></li>
<li><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/13/">Make A Language - Part Thirteen: Whitespace &amp; Events</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jmmv.dev/2020/12/unit-testing-a-console-app.html">Unit-testing a console app (a text editor)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.drogue.io/rust-and-async/">Rust and Async (on embedded devices)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.fpcomplete.com/blog/avoiding-duplicating-strings-rust/">Avoiding Duplicating Strings in Rust</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.knoldus.com/os-in-rust-custom-target-to-build-kernel-for-a-bare-metal-part-3/">OS in Rust: Custom target to build kernel for bare metal: Part-3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://blog.knoldus.com/os-in-rust-building-kernel-for-custom-target-part-4/">OS in Rust: Building kernel for custom target: Part-4</a></li>
<li>[video] <a href="https://youtu.be/lLWchWTUFOQ">Introduction to Rust Part 2</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="project-updates">Project Updates</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/EmbarkStudios/rust-gpu/releases/tag/v0.2">rust-gpu v0.2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ibraheem.ca/posts/rust-interior-mutability-understanding-cell">Interior Mutability in Rust: Understanding The Cell Type</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="miscellaneous">Miscellaneous</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2020/12/cpp-rust-interop-cxx/">Safe Interoperability between Rust and C++ with CXX</a></li>
<li><a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2020/12/expanding-fuchsias-open-source-model.html">Expanding Fuchsia's open source model</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/k75tez/miri_can_now_detect_data_races/">Miri can now detect data races</a></li>
</ul>

<p>This week's crate is <a href="https://github.com/not-a-seagull/breadx">breadx</a>, a X-windows protocol implementation in 100% safe and mutex-free Rust.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/crate-of-the-week/2704/851">Willi Kappler</a> for the suggestion!</p>
<p><a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/crate-of-the-week/2704">Submit your suggestions and votes for next week</a>!</p>

<p>Always wanted to contribute to open-source projects but didn't know where to start?
Every week we highlight some tasks from the Rust community for you to pick and get started!</p>
<p>Some of these tasks may also have mentors available, visit the task page for more information.</p>
<p>If you are a Rust project owner and are looking for contributors, please submit tasks <a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/twir-call-for-participation/4821">here</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/AaronErhardt/Triox/labels/good%20first%20issue">Triox - Good First Issues</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/libssh2/libssh2/pull/517">libssh2 - Pull Request Needs Windows Reviewer</a></li>
</ul>

<p>279 pull requests were <a href="https://github.com/search?q=is%3Apr+org%3Arust-lang+is%3Amerged+merged%3A2020-11-30..2020-12-07">merged in the last week</a></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/78684">add wasm32 support to inline asm</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79509">improve attribute message error spans</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/chalk/pull/659">chalk: always relate with Invariant to non-General inference vars</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79680">fix perf regression caused by match exhaustiveness split</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79623">pass around Symbols instead of Idents in doctree</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79620">tweak diagnostics on shadowing lifetimes/labels</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/78122">avoid panic_bounds_check in <code>fmt::write</code></a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79650">fix incorrect <code>io::Take</code>'s limit resulting from <code>io::copy</code> specialization</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79600"><code>std::io</code>: use sendfile for UnixStream</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/pull/8937">cargo: slightly optimize `cargo vendor</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/cargo/pull/8725">cargo: add "--workspace" to update command</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79539">rustdoc: JSON backend experimental impl</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="rust-compiler-performance-triage">Rust Compiler Performance Triage</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rustc-perf/blob/master/triage/2020-12-08.md">2020-12-08</a>:
0 Regressions, 2 Improvements, 1 Mixed</li>
</ul>
<p>Triage done by @simulacrum.</p>
<p>See the <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rustc-perf/blob/master/triage/2020-12-08.md">full report</a> for more.</p>
<h2 id="approved-rfcs">Approved RFCs</h2>
<p>Changes to Rust follow the Rust <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs#rust-rfcs">RFC (request for comments) process</a>. These
are the RFCs that were approved for implementation this week:</p>
<p><em>No RFCs were approved this week.</em></p>

<p>Every week <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/team.html">the team</a> announces the
'final comment period' for RFCs and key PRs which are reaching a
decision. Express your opinions now.</p>
<h3 id="rfcs"><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/labels/final-comment-period">RFCs</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/3007">RFC: Plan to make core and std's panic identical</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2992">RFC: Add <code>target_abi</code> configuration</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rfcs/pull/2859">added secret types rfc</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="tracking-issues-prs"><a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/labels/final-comment-period">Tracking Issues &amp; PRs</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79642">rustdoc: stabilise --default-theme command line option</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79502">Implement <code>From&lt;char&gt;</code> for u64 and u128.</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79485">Stabilize <code>unsafe_cell_get_mut</code></a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79473">Move <code>{f32,f64}::clamp</code> to core</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79342">Stabilize all stable methods of <code>Ipv4Addr</code>, <code>Ipv6Addr</code> and <code>IpAddr</code> as const</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79270">Acknowledge that <code>[CONST; N]</code> is stable</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79261">Deprecate atomic compare_and_swap method</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79213">Stabilize <code>core::slice::fill</code></a></li>
<li>[disposition: close] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79188">Made matches! more useful by adding mapping support</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79073">passes: prohibit invalid attrs on generic params</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/79022">stabilize deque_range</a></li>
<li>[disposition: close] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/78367">Apply <code>unused_doc_comments</code> lint to inner items</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/78242">Rename <code>overlapping_patterns</code> lint</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/78083">Stabilize or_insert_with_key</a></li>
<li>[disposition: close] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/77688">Add built-in implementations of <code>Default</code> for function definition and… </a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/74699">Mark <code>-1</code> as an available niche for file descriptors</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/pull/74304">Stabilize the Wake trait</a></li>
<li>[disposition: merge] <a href="https://github.com/rust-lang/rust/issues/63514">Tracking issue for map_ok and map_err method for <code>Poll&lt;Option&lt;Result&lt;T, E&gt;&gt;&gt;</code></a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="new-rfcs">New RFCs</h2>
<p><em>No new RFCs were proposed this week.</em></p>

<h3 id="online">Online</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Rust-Community-Stuttgart/events/274892215/">December 10, Stuttgart, DE - Hack &amp; Learn - Directions for 2021 - Rust Community Stuttgart</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.meetup.com/San-Diego-Rust/events/274757235/">December 10, San Diego, CA, US - San Diego Rust December 2020 Tele-Meetup - San Diego Rust</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.meetup.com/RustDC/events/274460587">December 10, Washington, DC, US - How oso built a runtime reflection system for Rust—Rust DC</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.meetup.com/Rust-%D0%B2-%D0%9C%D0%BE%D1%81%D0%BA%D0%B2%D0%B5/events/274924961/">December 15, Russia - Russian Rust Online Meetup</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.meetup.com/Vancouver-Rust/events/npqfbsybcqbvb/">December 16, Vancouver, BC, US - Are Results just Checked Exceptions? - Vancouver Rust</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="north-america">North America</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.meetup.com/utah-rust/events/273530244/">December 10, Provo, UT, US - Mob Programming: Add <code>--tree -d</code> to <code>lsd</code></a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you are running a Rust event please add it to the <a href="https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?src=apd9vmbc22egenmtu5l6c5jbfc%40group.calendar.google.com">calendar</a> to get
it mentioned here. Please remember to add a link to the event too.
Email the <a href="mailto:community-team@rust-lang.org">Rust Community Team</a> for access.</p>

<p><em>Tweet us at <a href="https://twitter.com/ThisWeekInRust">@ThisWeekInRust</a> to get your job offers listed here!</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.pathai.com/careers/?gh_jid=4983568002">Software Engineer, Systems at PathAI (Boston, MA, US)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.welcometothejungle.com/fr/companies/meilisearch/jobs/software-developer-rust_paris">Software Developer (Rust) at MeiliSearch (Remote)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jobs.lever.co/kraken/4019a818-4a7b-46ef-9225-c53c7a7f238c">Backend Engineer - Rust at Kraken (Remote NA, SA, EMEA)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jobs.lever.co/kraken/fe1e07f4-6d7c-4f65-9a8f-27cf3b3fd2b1">Backend Engineer, Kraken Futures - Rust at Kraken (Remote)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jobs.lever.co/kraken/2442ee5c-56b6-4a73-a477-8cdda2b218d5">Rust Engineer, Desktop GUI - Cryptowatch at Kraken (Remote)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jobs.lever.co/kraken/4c864c8f-bde6-443d-b521-dd90df0e9105">Senior Backend Engineer - Rust at Kraken (Remote NA, SA, EMEA)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jobs.lever.co/kraken/2863623f-13c9-4f50-992d-7c25736a60f9">Senior Banking Engineer - Rust at Kraken (Remote)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://jobs.lever.co/kraken/4485f672-dc5f-4e49-a10b-2b0399e28a8d">Software Engineer - Trading Technology (Rust) at Kraken (Remote NA, SA, EMEA)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/jobs/294502/rust-for-embedded-environments-ockam">Rust for Embedded Environments at Ockam (Remote)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/jobs/400828/messaging-protocol-architect-in-elixir-and-rust-ockam">Messaging protocol architect in Elixir (and Rust) at Ockam (Remote)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://nzxt.bamboohr.com/jobs/view.php?id=259">Senior Software Engineer (Rust &amp; C++) at NZXT (Remote)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.notion.so/Embedded-Firmware-Engineer-in-C-Rust-a9c741c539454ee7b8bbb969d8e90da2">Embedded Firmware Engineer in C &amp; Rust at Astropad (Remote, US)</a></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
<p>Writing rust for me is a gradual process of the compiler patiently guiding me towards the program I should have written in the first place, and at the end I take all the credit.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>– <a href="https://discord.com/channels/442252698964721669/448238009733742612/783395725991084074">@felixwatts on Discord</a></p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/twir-quote-of-the-week/328/972">Joshua Nelson</a> for the suggestion.</p>
<p><a href="https://users.rust-lang.org/t/twir-quote-of-the-week/328">Please submit quotes and vote for next week!</a></p>
<p><em>This Week in Rust is edited by: <a href="https://github.com/nellshamrell">nellshamrell</a>, <a href="https://github.com/llogiq">llogiq</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/cdmistman">cdmistman</a>.</em></p>
<p><small><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/ka8fvg/this_week_in_rust_368/">Discuss on r/rust</a></small></p>
  </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://this-week-in-rust.org/blog/2020/12/09/this-week-in-rust-368/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25371862</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 09:54:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Crossminds.ai – A knowledge graph indexed AI research video library]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25369075">thread link</a>) | @tecresearch
<br/>
December 9, 2020 | https://crossminds.ai/explore/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://crossminds.ai/explore/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://crossminds.ai/explore/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25369075</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 02:54:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
