<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 04:31:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 04:31:23 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[And this world’s a fickle measure]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25250968">thread link</a>) | @jseliger
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-12060">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>They told me, “You have to watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rhThso-PE_o">this interview where Mike Tyson talks about medieval history</a>,” and so I did, and there he was at the New York Public Library in 2013 being interviewed by curator Paul Holdengräber, whose German accent strikes the American ear as both effortlessly intellectual and lightly amusing, and who would seem to have nothing in common with the face-tattooed boxer.</p>



<p><img data-attachment-id="12067" data-permalink="https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11-57-11-pm-copy/" data-orig-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" data-orig-size="1816,934" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2020-11-28 at 11.57.11 PM copy" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=863" src="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" alt=""></p>



<p>The two men do, in fact, find much to talk about. Their discussion is mesmerizing, because to most of us Mike Tyson is nothing but a face and fists, not a man who reflects aloud and at length about his inner life. Holdengräber prompts a reticent Tyson to narrate clips of his greatest moments in the ring, and newcomers to boxing will easily see why Tyson was such a sensation, but Iron Mike grows more animated when other matters arise.</p>



<p>Half an hour into the interview, Holdengräber says that their mutual friend, eccentric German filmmaker Werner Herzog, urged him to ask Tyson why he’s so fascinated by Clovis, the founder of the Merovingian Frankish dynasty, and Pepin the Short, the first Carolingian king of the Franks. Tyson’s answer, however halting, makes him come alive: </p>



<blockquote><p>I don’t know—it all comes from my insecurity from being poor, and not having enough—to be insecure, and being—yeah, that’s what it is: obscure. I never wanted to be obscure. I was born in obscurity and I never wanted to deal with that again, never wanted to be that. And they came from obscurity.</p></blockquote>



<p>Tyson then narrates a capsule history of the Frankish kings. He rambles, he doesn’t get all the details right, and his mispronunciation of names marks him as an autodidact, but it’s a shame to hear the audience laugh when Holdengräber asks, “Mike, how do you know all this shit?” Whether Tyson is mapping his own experiences onto medieval history or hearing echoes of the Franks in his troubled life, the credentialed, status-conscious audience is uncomfortable with his sincere interest in a past they find trivial.</p>



<p>Yet Tyson is the real deal, a book lover not because his peer group yaks about whichever author the <em>New York Times</em> has dubbed fame’s latest love child, but because he’s hungry for ideas, for meaning, for connections across time. He speaks with undisguised emotion about Cus D’Amato, the trainer and manager who turned him into a lethal boxer. Obsessed with Nietzsche and Clausewitz, D’Amato taught Tyson to see boxing as war and war as the key to decoding the world. “That is just what I do,” Tyson explains, an attentive pupil and dutiful son. “I love war. I love the act of war. I love the players in war, the philosophy of war.”</p>



<p>Tyson is searching for more than war on the pages of the past. Having grown up amid crime and chaos and founded his life on violence, he now relies on books to make moral and ethical sense of the world:</p>



<blockquote><p>Yeah—they’re our most priceless possessions, because if you think about it, you know, a room without a book is like a body without a soul. It’s the only way that we can connect the future with the past. Without that, there’s no way that we can know about the future, and know about particularly the past, or the present, you know, that when you think about history, the value of history is not necessarily scientific but moral. By liberating our minds and deepening our sympathies and fortifying our will, we can control—pretty much history allows us to control not society but ourselves, which is a much more important thing to do, you know what I mean? And it would allow us to pretty much meet the future more so than foretell it, and for that reason alone, in order to predict the future we always have to look through the past, because very rarely does time not repeat itself, and it always will repeat itself. </p><p>I’ve heard a quote before in a book that we would be fools to think historically that the past is us in funny clothes, but the past <em><span>is</span></em> us in funny clothes, and that’s truly what it is. That’s from somebody who really said a really profound statement but he misquoted what he was saying, he must have been saying it backwards, because that’s really what the past was, it’s just us in funny clothes, in different times, that’s really what it is.</p></blockquote>



<p>Of course, to hear Tyson cite <a href="http://thecampvs.com/2011/08/03/cicero-on-books-and-the-soul/">a quip inaccurately attributed to Cicero</a>, “a room without books is like a body without a soul,” is to wonder if he’s putting us on. Late in the interview, he jokes that if you quote books, you fool people into thinking you’re smart—but Tyson, for all his malapropisms and mispronunciations and odd mannerisms, <em>is</em> intelligent. He’s going round after round with big questions that  many of the ostensibly educated attendees at his book-talk don’t bother to ask.</p>



<p>When Holdengräber suggests that Tyson’s knowledge of history didn’t improve his behavior, Tyson calmly disagrees. He compares himself to the fictional Ben-Hur, a fellow athlete and celebrity who achieved glory but was doomed to be unfree until he set his priorities in order: “He may not have been famous again,” Tyson points out, “but he got his family, and that was his success.” </p>



<p>After listening to Mike Tyson—childhood criminal, devastating fighter, struggling alcoholic and recovering drug addict, convicted rapist, pop-culture eidolon—speak for an hour and a half, I still don’t quite know who he is. He may be the closest thing 21st-century America has to <a href="https://quidplura.com/2011/11/03/but-the-answers-you-seek-will-never-be-found-at-home/">a Robert E. Howard character</a>, a born barbarian who’s ignorant of social niceties but possesses earned wisdom that the civilization around him disdains. I don’t know whether he’s all in on his bookish pursuits or one slight away from again gnawing off someone’s ear. Whether he’s a good man or a bad man feels foolish to ask about a professional punch-thrower who reads Nietzsche, but Tyson looks like a <em>better</em> man, one who has perhaps searched harder for his humanity than the onlookers snickering from the safety of their library seats. What has their pride gained them? Tyson’s, by contrast, has brought him perspective, and with it the humility to admit that his story is still being written—and has been before.</p>




			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25250968</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Making Playstation 1 Modchips (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248660">thread link</a>) | @cwaffles
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
    <article>

        

        <section>
            <p>When I was young I owned a PlayStation 1 (PS1). It was one of the first, if not the first, game consoles I owned and it had a profound effect on my future. </p>

<p>I can trace the history of how I got involved in computers back to playing and modding video games. While I wasn't smart enough to mod game consoles when I was young, my dad wasn't bad at it. He modded my PS1 to have a little switch in the back that would allow it to play burnt games. They say the apple doesn't fall far from the tree. </p>

<p>Fast-forward to today and I no longer have my original PS1. I remember some games wouldn't load anymore and I had gotten a PS2. So why keep an old console? Turns out the answer is nostalgia and memories. You miss what you don't have anymore.</p>

<p>Recently a friend gifted me a PS1. And so then the journey begins, how do I mod this thing? </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you are looking for them I am selling <a href="http://rover.ebay.com/rover/1/711-53200-19255-0/1?icep_ff3=2&amp;pub=5575378759&amp;campid=5338273189&amp;customid=&amp;icep_item=223024408143&amp;ipn=psmain&amp;icep_vectorid=229466&amp;kwid=902099&amp;mtid=824&amp;kw=lg&amp;toolid=11111">flashed, prewired modchips</a>. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Very simply, the principles behind PS1 DRM work as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Sony baked (not the technical term) strings (i.e. <code>SCEA</code>, <code>SCEI</code>, <code>SCEE</code>, or in rare cases <code>SCEW</code>) into official PS1 games in locations which cannot be replicated by a regular reader. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XUwSOfQ1D3c">This video</a> and <a href="http://www.psxdev.net/forum/viewtopic.php?t=128">this post</a> discuss it reasonably well.  </li>
<li>The CD drive controller looks for those strings to identify a disc as official. Once the controller decides that the disc is/isn't official, the main CPU reads this decision and acts accordingly.  </li>
<li>If the string can't be found or is garbled, the PS1 knows the disc isn't an <strong>authentic</strong> PS1 game. However, because the PS1 needs to account for disc read errors, there's a good amount of leeway in what passes the authenticity check.  </li>
<li>Because region <small>(<strong>A</strong> for America, <strong>I</strong> for Japan, <strong>E</strong> for Europe, and <strong>W</strong> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_Yaroze">Net Yaroze</a>)</small> as well as authenticity are rolled into one string, Sony kills two birds with one stone here and achieves region locking as well as copy protection. </li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you want a real in-depth discussion you can read <a href="http://www.oldcrows.net/mcc2.html">the original posts by The Old Crow</a> or the <a href="https://problemkaputt.de/psx-spx.htm#cdromprotectionmodchips">No$PSX documentation page</a> or this <a href="http://psx-scene.com/forums/f10/psx-modchip-faq-64110/">Modchip FAQ</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>PSX modchips work by electrically stifling the output originally generated by whatever CD is inside the drive and then injecting a new, faked signal into the CD microcontroller. This causes the PS1 to believe that whatever disc is inside is legitimate and proceed to boot up. </p>

<p>Later on Sony added more complicated checks like:</p>

<ul>
<li>Checking for the magic strings during the game instead of at boot </li>
<li>Changing the overall process to make it more difficult to bypass by simply emitting the correct strings.</li>
</ul>

<p>However, modern modchips already deal with this. Modchips that work under these updated circumstances are known as "stealth modchips" because the console shouldn't be able to detect them at all. </p>



<p>The first "open source" modchip was reverse engineered by a guy named "The Old Crow". Surprisingly, The Old Crow specializes in electronic music synthesizers, not hacking video game consoles. It's from his modchip that most other modchips are derived from in some sense. He originally reverse engineered a commercial PS1 modchip that was designed by a western engineer working for a Chinese company. </p>

<p>Today, there are three main modchips which are still used by the community today.</p>

<p>The modchips include:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide/mm3/">Multimode 3 (MM3)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide/mayumi-v4/">Mayumi v4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee">PSNee</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The three have their pros and cons but generally they can be summarized as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>MM3 is the most common PS1 modchip seen/used today. Its only real downside is that it uses an internal oscillator which can become out of sync with the oscillator used by the CD drive. If this happens you simply need to reboot your console to try reading again.  </p></li>
<li><p>Mayumi v4 attempts to use the oscillator used by the CD drive. This reduces the chance of the oscillator sync issue from happening; however, Mayumi v4 is considered a bit difficult to install. </p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee">PSNee</a> is an open source modchip originally written by <a href="https://assemblergames.com/threads/psnee-a-stealth-modchip-for-all-ps1-models.57907/">TheFrietMan</a>. Development on it was <a href="http://www.psxdev.net/forum/viewtopic.php?t=1262">later continued by others</a> and it appears to work rather well on all Playstation 1/PSOne models. Based on the code I believe it attempts to infer where the PS1 is in the boot process to begin injecting fake <code>SCEX</code> strings. Unfortunately PSNee is complicated to install. The provided diagrams are atrocious and nowhere near as simple as the available diagrams for MM3 and Mayumi. I worked out <a href="https://gist.github.com/ColdHeat/be633b7eb6e25758ec80ae0115c1887a">the pinout for the Attiny45</a> but I ended up going with MM3 and Mayumi because it's easier. </p></li>
</ul>



<blockquote>
  <p>If you want them I am selling <a href="http://rover.ebay.com/rover/1/711-53200-19255-0/1?icep_ff3=2&amp;pub=5575378759&amp;campid=5338273189&amp;customid=&amp;icep_item=223024408143&amp;ipn=psmain&amp;icep_vectorid=229466&amp;kwid=902099&amp;mtid=824&amp;kw=lg&amp;toolid=11111">flashed, prewired modchips</a>. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>It's generally pretty easy to make a PS1 modchip provided you have the right tools. In this tutorial we will focus on making MM3 or Mayumi v4 modchips.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>While I do have an Arduino, I prefer to use the MM3 and Mayumi chips over PSNee. If you want to make a PSNee modchip, you can follow the <a href="http://www.instructables.com/id/Program-an-ATtiny-with-Arduino/">instructions here</a> to flash the <a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee/blob/master/PsNee.ino">.ino file</a> to your Attiny. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>You will need:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=PIC12F508+DIP">Microchip PIC12F508</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2tfdeP0">PICkit 3</a>
<ul><li>Also download and install <a href="http://www.microchip.com/mplab/mplab-x-ide">MPLAB IPE</a> from the MPLAB X IDE package. </li></ul></li>
<li>Some kind of <a href="https://amzn.to/2llKUG7">wiring &amp; breadboard</a> to connect the PIC to to the PICkit.</li>
<li>HEX codes for the modchip of your choice (provided below).</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Many tutorials call for the PIC12C508. This is an old model and continuing to use them is unnecessary unless you have them stockpiled. HEX codes that work for the 12C will work for the 12F. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>To begin you should first look your IC and determine which leg is which. The leg nearest the imprinted circle is Pin 1. The leg opposite it is Pin 8. </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/pic12f508-2.JPG" alt="This is a DIP chip. I accidentally got SOIC-8 (i.e. surface mount) and had to solder my chip to a breadboard but generally you can avoid that"></p>

<p>You can plug this into a bread board and then wire it into the Pickit according to the following diagrams. You want to match the following (the rest are unused for now):</p>

<ul>
<li>PICKit 1 ⟷ IC 4 (V<sub>PP</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 2 ⟷ IC 1 (V<sub>DD</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 3 ⟷ IC 8 (V<sub>SS</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 4 ⟷ IC 7 (ICSPDAT)</li>
<li>PICKit 5 ⟷ IC 6 (ICSPCLK)</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/pickit-12f508-1.jpg" alt="PICKit 3 on the left, PIC12F508 on the right"></p>

<p>Once you've properly wired up the chip, connect the PICKit to your computer and start MPLAB IPE. Under <code>Device</code> select <code>PIC12F508</code>. </p>

<p>Go into <code>Settings &gt; Advanced Mode</code>. The default password for <code>Advanced Mode</code> is <code>microchip</code>. I don't recommend changing it, not sure why the option is even available. </p>

<p>Go into the <code>Power</code> tab on the left and enable <code>Power Target Circuit from Tool</code>.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-8.39.15-PM.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Go back to the <code>Operate</code> tab and hit <code>Connect</code>.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-8.40.54-PM.png" alt=""></p>

<p>From here download the appropriate HEX code for your chip and console. They are different per console region. </p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3USA.HEX">MM3 for American Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3EUR.HEX">MM3 for European Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3JAP.HEX">MM3 for Japanese Consoles</a></li>
</ul>

<p>You can also use Mayumi v4 on the PIC12F508 if you choose.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-usa4.hex">MayumiV4 for American Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-eu4.hex">MayumiV4 for European Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-jap4.hex">MayumiV4 for Japanese Consoles</a></li>
</ul>

<p>In the <code>Source</code> file, select your hex code. </p>

<p>Hit the big <code>Program</code> button. </p>

<p>You should see something similar to the following text:</p>

<pre><code>2018-06-20 20:48:02 -0400 - Loading hex file. Please wait...  
Loading code from /Users/kchung/Repositories/PsNeePy.wiki/hexcodes/mm3/MM3USA.HEX...  
2018-06-20 20:48:03 -0400 - Hex file loaded successfully.

2018-06-20 20:48:20 -0400 - Programming...

Device Erased...

Programming...

The following memory area(s) will be programmed:  
program memory: start address = 0x0, end address = 0x1e7  
configuration memory  
Programming/Verify complete  
2018-06-20 20:48:25 -0400 - Programming complete  
</code></pre>

<p>If you'd like, you can hit the <code>Verify</code> button to make sure that your flash was correct. Your output should look something like the following:</p>

<pre><code>2018-06-20 20:50:10 -0400 - Verifying...

Verifying...

The following memory areas(s) will be verified:  
program memory: start address = 0x0, end address = 0x1ff  
configuration memory  
User Id Memory

Verification successful.  
2018-06-20 20:50:13 -0400 - Verify complete  
</code></pre>

<p>From here you can follow online diagrams for soldering your chip to the PSX that you own. I personally used <a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide">William Quade's excellent diagrams</a> and think you should as well.   </p>



<p>While looking at all these modchips, I figured it would be nice to read and write Python code instead of Assembly and C code so I started working on porting PSNee to Python. </p>

<p>By using <a href="https://micropython.org/">MicroPython</a> and an <a href="https://amzn.to/2K4HdTq">ESP8266</a> we can actually create a modchip that we can remotely update and modify through the <a href="https://amzn.to/2K4HdTq">ESP8266</a>'s WiFi.  </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/IMG_1084.jpg" alt="Effectively the very first WiFi enabled PS1!"></p>

<p>In the above photo (SCPH-7501), the ESP8266 is on the top left with the headers face up. The wires connect to the headers and route under the CD drive to a breadboard on the bottom right. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The breadboard has wires that are soldered to the correct MM3 points and then labeled with the corresponding pin number. By using this breadboard I can test modchips that I make much faster than soldering to the board over and over again. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>My modchip (named PsNeePy) is available on Github: <br>
<a href="https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy">https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy</a></p>

<p>While my test console is quite bad at reading discs and the console rarely boots into games, the modchip does work. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For the most part (ignoring stealth functionality), modchips are known to be working once you reach the black Playstation logo screen as this indicates that the CPU considers the game authentic. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>However, because the code is based off an older version of PSNee, stealth functionality does not seem to work on some newer PS1 revisions.</p>

<p>I mostly created this as a proof of concept and I'm unlikely to maintain it very much. While I don't recommend using my modchip, I hope that the community adopts it and helps improve it. Despite being a dead console, the PSX community is fairly active. </p>

<p>With <a href="https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy">PsNeePy</a>, you can remotely update the ESP8266 over WiFi, debug remotely, and also reset the chip easily. Having spent many hours working on the PS1 at this point, a more modern experience is quite refreshing. </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-21-at-2.47.33-AM.png" alt="Remotely controlling the modchip"></p>

<p>Thanks to an anonymous friend for my PS1, Sharan for fixing my PS1, <a href="https://quade.co/">William Quade</a> for the excellent diagrams, AssemblerGames for having good information despite not accepting me into the forum, and PSXDEV for answering some of my questions.</p>
        </section>

        

    </article>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248660</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 22:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Run a Ponzi Scheme for Tech People]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 382 | Comments 187 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248563">thread link</a>) | @nish1500
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article role="article" itemscope="" itemprop="blogPost" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">
<center>
<header>


</header>
</center>
<p>More people are online than ever before. More people are desperate than ever before. Learn how to use that 👇</p>
<h2>Is this the right course for me?</h2>
<p>Good question. My courses are NOT for everyone. You need to be a good fit. This is the prefect course for you if you check any of the following boxes:</p>
<ol><li>You like having a business card that says <strong>I’m CEO bitch</strong></li><li>You dream of petting elephants in a Southeast asian monarchy with a questionable human rights record</li><li>doTerra didn’t work out</li><li>You have $100 to spare</li></ol>
<h2>Basics first. What is a Ponzi scheme?</h2>
<p>Say I managed to save $500 from my day job. I find 5 people who begrudgingly agree to give me $100 because I told them I can turn it into $200 in a month. I give them $200 each at the end of the month.</p>
<p>Now, I am <strong>out of savings</strong> but I have 5 people who doubled their money in a month with no hard work at all.</p>
<p>I use their story as an example to show people that my idea works. Now it’s easier to find people who pay me. I take $100 from 10 more people, wait for a month, and use the proceeds ($1,000) to give $200 each to 5 of those people.</p>
<p>Now I have a <strong>proven business model</strong>, and a good number of people who will vouch for my method. I use the proceeds from each successive group to pay the previous cohort of people.</p>
<h2>But this is a tech community. Not Wall Street.</h2>
<p>A Ponzi scheme can be used in any part of your life. Let’s see how we can use this around us today:</p>
<h3>Example 1: Sell a Course</h3>
<p>Create a twitter account and manage to get 100 followers through a combination of spamming famous people, dad jokes, and paid followers. Write this blog post and share it:</p>
<blockquote><p>How I got 100 followers in my first week with no hard work at all.</p></blockquote>
<p>Over the next week 50 people will read your tweet / post and start following you. These people are curious, and it costs them nothing to follow you. 50 followers isn’t much but you get to write another exciting post:</p>
<blockquote><p>How I increased my twitter following by 50% in less than 3 days.</p></blockquote>
<p>Now people are intrigued, and you have 500 more followers. Write another post.</p>
<blockquote><p>How I got 500 followers overnight</p></blockquote>
<p>Does it remind you of something – like a <strong>for</strong> loop? When iteration = 5, <strong>sell a course</strong> on Gumroad.</p>
<h3>Example 2: Become a Digital Nomad</h3>
<p>Quit your job in Colorado and move to Thailand because a long-haired guy and his hot girlfriend shared a beach selfie telling you how they are living the digital nomad life, and how you can do it too. Best $100 you ever spent.</p>
<p>Except, it didn’t work out (teaching English in Thailand only pays so much), and now you’re stuck in Koh Samui running out of money and ideas. Go to the nearest beach, take a picture of your laptop with sunset in the background and write this blog post:</p>
<blockquote><p>How quitting my 9-5 job and moving to Thailand was the best thing I ever did.</p></blockquote>
<p>Congrats, now people are listening. Create a course, somehow manage to make $1,000. Now use that $1,000 to buy some food, rent a moped, and share more selfies about your perfect life. It’s a massive market – these regular folks working boring jobs in rich white countries who believe in the good intentions of strangers on the internet. Exploit them.</p>
<h3>Example 3: No Code, Only Money</h3>
<p>Aren’t you sick of all these I’m-so-smart programmers with their statically-typed-languages-are-fast on HackerNews? When you came across this priceless <strong>No Code</strong> directory of tools you realized it was the next big thing. You spend $100 on the site, and use the knowledge to create a form (using a form builder) and a Zapier hook that emails people on new responses. Genius idea. You try to sell it for $500. No buyers. It’s all your fault.</p>
<p>Time to pivot. You create a <strong>No Code</strong> website to teach people how to make money using No Code tools (like you did, haha) such as <strong>Airtable</strong> and <strong>Zapier</strong>.</p>
<p><em>Note: the lesson here is NOT that you can make money by creating a valuable tool like Airtable using code. No.</em></p>
<p>Between your <strong>No Code website</strong> and <strong>No Code podcast</strong> you manage to make $500. You take a screenshot of your Stripe dashboard and share it with the world. Now you are hot shit. Going from 0 to $500 was the hard bit; going from $500 to $5,000 is easier.</p>
<h2>FAQ</h2>
<h4>Are places like Indiehacker and Gumroad and just enablers of Ponzi schemes?</h4>
<p>Of course not. There are some amazing people there working on cool new ideas. They write comments here and there, and make a post once in a while, but mostly it’s busy work building something. Most such communities are started by a group of well-intentioned people, who slowly become the minority.</p>
<p>Not all courses are scams. I bought one on Gumroad yesterday. Except it wasn’t teaching me how to grow my twitter following; it was teaching me a cool programming language that I’ve been meaning to learn for a while.</p>
<h4>Will I be sharing fake milestones and fake Stripe dashboards?</h4>
<p>You didn’t read anything, did you? No, you will actually get 500 new followers, and actually make $5,000. The ones who won’t are the suckers who buy your course.</p>
<h4>Won’t people call me out when they buy my course and fail to become rich?</h4>
<p>That is the best part – they will blame <strong>themselves</strong>. You made money. The people who gave you Twitter testimonials apparently made money. If people fail they will think it’s them. In fact, sell them your <strong>Advanced Course</strong>.</p>
<h4>How do I convince people I am legit?</h4>
<p>Tell people you are open to <strong>speaking engagements</strong>. Talk about the number of <strong>trees you planted</strong> this month. Tell them someone else forced you to post on IH or HN because of how great your content is. Talk about <strong>failure</strong> so you seem relatable. Act <strong>quirky</strong> on Twitter.</p>
<h4>Wait, are you writing this just to make me a part of your Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<p>Do you really think I am going to spend half a Sunday writing and formatting this long-ass post (instead of using my magic formula to make money for myself) for any reason other than the goodness of my heart?</p>
<p>Of course not. I swear. I just want to share my success with the world, help the little guy, Build in Public™, like every other ‘How I Made $5,000’ post. Pinky promise.</p>
<h4>I am sold. So, how DO I run a Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<p>You see, my goal in sharing my success here is to see <strong>YOU grow</strong>. Just like the guy who sold me into his Ponzi scheme – I am only paying it forward 🙏🏼.</p>
<p>I do like to charge <strong>$100</strong> JUST to ensure that only serious people become a part of my Ponzi-family. We call it an investment.</p>
<p>Enough talk. Signup here:</p>
<p><a href="https://nish.formcrafts.com/ponzi-scheme" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://nish.formcrafts.com/ponzi-scheme</a></p>
<h4>How do I NOT run a Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<ol><li>Look around you for problems people would pay to resolve.</li><li>Create something of value.</li><li>Have fun while you do it.</li></ol>
<p>Discuss on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248563" target="_blank">HN</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nish_crafts" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">@nish_crafts</a></p>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248563</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 22:10:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Vancouver's empty home tax is increasing to 3% next year]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247904">thread link</a>) | @synack
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>VANCOUVER -- 
	The empty homes tax in Vancouver will more than double next year, the city announced Wednesday.</p>
<p>
	Council voted in favour of increasing the tax from 1.25 per cent to three per cent for 2021. The current rate still applies for 2020 declarations, which are due by Feb. 2.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	"I'm so glad that council backed my plan to stand up for renters and raise the empty homes tax to three per cent," said Mayor Kennedy Stewart in a news release.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	"This groundbreaking tool has helped move thousands of homes back onto the rental market to help house our neighbours, but there are still too many homes that remain empty."</p>
<p>
	When the tax was first introduced in 2017, it started at one per cent. Then council voted to increase it for the first time in 2019, to 1.25 per cent.</p>
<p>
	"By tripling the tax from one to three per cent since the tax launched, we're sending an even stronger message that homes are for people, not speculation," Stewart said.</p>
<p>
	According to the city, $61.3 million in net revenues from the tax has been used to support affordable housing initiatives. Vacant property has decreased by 25 per cent since the tax was introduced in 2017, the city says.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
                                              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247904</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 20:43:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Simple Password Management with GPG]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247211">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <!--**This is a post about a password management system where you GPG encrypt markdown files on Linux and Syncthing them to Android.**-->

<!--Want to use GPG encrypted files to manage your passwords?-->

<!-- use the word `markdown files` instead of `plain-text files` is because people who care enough to read on are tech savvy people that knows markdown anyway, but then 会make it too 复杂吗, 再看吧, 感觉 say plain-text might 也比较好的 -->

<!--I'm not too fond of using password management tools like `Dashlane` or `1Password`, I've never really tried them, because there's no guarantee that they will live forever, nor that their security perfect.-->

<!--Even though some of them are open-source, they are still at the mercy of their developers unless I'm willing to modify it myself,-->
<!--so it is harder to modify it to fit my needs better.-->

<!--I just want a password management system that is simple, extensible and will live forever, this is my setup:-->
<p>If you want a password management system that is plain-text based, let me introduce to you my setup which utilizes GPG encrypted files to do that.</p>

<p>It uses GPG to encrypt markdown files containing my login credentials, and Syncthing to synchronize them to my Android phone to realize cross-device availability.</p>


<!--To be more exact, I create markdown files and store my login credentials plain-text, then-->

<ul>
  <li>On my computer, I use
    <ul>
      <li><code>gpg</code> to encrypt the markdown files</li>
      <li><a href="https://vimawesome.com/plugin/gnupg-vim">jamessan/vim-gnupg</a> Vim plugin to easily decrypt and edit the files</li>
      <li><code>Git</code> to version control the folder so I have full history of my login credentials</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>To access them from my phone, I use
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://syncthing.net/">Syncthing</a> to synchronize the folder to my phone</li>
      <li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.sufficientlysecure.keychain&amp;hl=en">OpenKeychain</a> app to decrypt and read the encrypted files</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I could just Syncthing the markdown files <em>without encryption</em> to my phone, but on the off chance that my phone is stolen / lost / hacked, I don’t want my passwords to go down with it, so it is safer to have it gpg encrypted.</p>

<p><del>I’m aware of <a href="https://www.passwordstore.org/">pass</a> and tried it before I came to this setup, but I want to put more info than just a password string in my files, so that’s why <code>pass</code> doesn’t fit my need.</del>
As many have pointed out in this <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247211">HackerNews thread</a>, pass allows multi-line edit, so this paragraph is incorrect.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-replicate-this-setup">How to replicate this setup</h3>

<p><strong>1. Generate a PGP keypair with GPG</strong></p>

<p>you can skip this if you already have a keypair.</p>

<p>$ <code>gpg --full-gen-key</code></p>

<p><strong>2. Install the Vim plugin and put in corresponding config</strong></p>

<p>Assuming you’re using VimPlug ( a vim plugin manager ),
put this into your ~/.vimrc and run <code>:PlugInstall</code> in Vim.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Plug 'jamessan/vim-gnupg'
" Armor files
let g:GPGPreferArmor=1
" Set the default option
let g:GPGDefaultRecipients=["youremail@provider.com"]"
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>NOTE: remember to modify the <code>youremail@provider.com</code> to the email associated with your PGP key</p>

<!--This plugin will auto decrypt encrypted files when you open them with Vim, making the only difference with opening a normal unencrypted file a slight delay of opening the file due to the decryption process.-->
<!--有点啰嗦 this ^ line, comment it out first-->

<p><strong>3. Create a markdown file</strong></p>

<p>$ <code>touch mygmail.md</code></p>

<p><strong>4. Encrypt the markdown file</strong></p>

<!--$ `gpg --recipient youremail@provider.com --armor --output %f.asc --encrypt %f`-->
<p>$ <code>gpg -e -r youremail@provider.com path/to/file</code></p>

<p>if you use <a href="https://github.com/ranger/ranger">Ranger</a>, you can put this mapping into your rc.conf to encrypt it easily by pressing <code>te</code> when the selection is hovering on the file:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>map te shell gpg --recipient youremail@provider.com --armor --output %f.asc --encrypt %f &amp;&amp; rm %f
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Open the file with Vim to make sure it can auto decrypt and open up the file.</p>


<p><strong>5. Setup Syncthing</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://syncthing.net/downloads/">Install Syncthing</a> on Linux and Android, then set it up to sync your password folder to your phone.</p>

<p><strong>6. Setup OpenKeychain</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Install <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.sufficientlysecure.keychain&amp;hl=en">OpenKeychain</a> Android app on your phone</p>
  </li>
  <li>export your PGP private key from Linux
    <div><div><pre><code>  $ gpg --export-secret-keys --armor youremail@provider.com &gt; privkey.asc
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>Transfer the file to your Android phone (for example through wire)</li>
  <li>Import the key file into <code>OpenKeychain</code> app</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>7. Try decrypting your files on Android</strong></p>

<p>To decrypt and view your password file:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Open the <code>OpenKeychain</code> app</li>
  <li>
    <p>Press the hamburger menu icon on the top left</p>
  </li>
  <li>Press <code>Encrypt/Decrypt</code></li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://tylerlmz1.github.io/assets/decrypt.png" width="200px"></p>

<ol>
  <li>Press <code>Select input file</code> and browse to the encrypted password file</li>
  <li>Enter your PGP key passphrase</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>8. Done</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://tylerlmz1.github.io/assets/view_decrypted_pw_file.png" width="200px"></p>

  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247211</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:13:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Only distributed fact-checking can keep up with democratized distribution]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 164 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25246733">thread link</a>) | @awinter-py
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><img src="https://abe-winter.github.io/assets/swift-ftl.png" alt="tweet: the problem with being faster than light is that you always live in darkness"></p>

<p>Has social media democratized reporting as promised?
We’ve democratized <em>writing and publishing</em> but this year has made the point that there’s more to journalism than hitting send.
The rest of the stuff that happens in the newsroom has stayed in the newsroom:
cultivating sources, editing for quality, and most importantly, fact-checking.</p>

<p>Lacking checks, social media is amplifying or at least fertilizing false beliefs,
and then people cross state lines to shoot up pizza joints.
If the newsroom’s adversarial functions can’t make the jump to social media,
life will continue to be this weird.</p>

<p>We’re starting to address fact-checking, and will do more.
<a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/why-cant-internet-companies-stop-awful-content/">Failing to curb antisocial behavior kills companies</a>, as well as communities.</p>

<p>Facebook has the technology to filter out the worst-quality content that their users think is ‘P(bad for the world)’ – <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinroose/status/1331257332538359810">but only at the cost of lower engagement</a>.
Given these incentives, nobody benefits if we leave this to platforms to solve.
Users should bring their own moderation to the web.</p>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles" id="markdown-toc-private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles">Private groups will decamp if they don’t like the fact bubbles</a></li>
  <li><a href="#conspiracies-are-topics-too" id="markdown-toc-conspiracies-are-topics-too">Conspiracies are topics too</a></li>
  <li><a href="#cranky-boomers-r-us" id="markdown-toc-cranky-boomers-r-us">Cranky boomers R us</a></li>
  <li><a href="#byo-vs-centralized-moderation" id="markdown-toc-byo-vs-centralized-moderation">BYO vs centralized moderation</a></li>
  <li><a href="#information-also-has-professional-customers" id="markdown-toc-information-also-has-professional-customers">Information also has professional customers</a></li>
  <li><a href="#conclusions" id="markdown-toc-conclusions">Conclusions</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles">Private groups will decamp if they don’t like the fact bubbles</h2>

<p>Filter bubbles don’t have to put up with fact bubbles.
By filter bubbles, I mean clique groups that see mostly content that supports their priors.
By fact bubbles, I mean those blue exclamation marks that say ‘official sources have called the election differently’.</p>

<p>Private groups have the power to resist centralized moderation if they don’t like it.
Private groups are sticky which is why facebook <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/30/18524188/facebook-f8-keynote-mark-zuckerberg-privacy-future-2019">bet their future on them</a>,
but this stickiness makes them hard to control.
Yes, their internal cohesion leads to engagement on FB, but it also allows them to move off the platform if they’re unhappy.
They own their slice of the network; their moat has a drawbridge.</p>

<p>A heavy hand will drive private groups to dark corners of the web –
not <em>un</em>-moderated exactly, because trust me, nobody wants that.
But ‘differently moderated’.
Reality is a participation sport and groups which don’t want to participate, won’t.</p>

<p>That said, deplatforming isn’t zero-cost for groups:
they recruit in public spaces, and are helped by ‘suggested groups’ features (which FB <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/facebook-suspended-group-recommendations-election">partially disabled</a> for the election).
Standalone forums can’t grow like that.
The fickle graces of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/5/20754943/8chan-epik-offline-voxility-service-cutoff-hate-speech-ban">hosts</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/4/20754310/cloudflare-8chan-fredrick-brennan-ddos-attack">DDOS-protection companies</a> also make it hard to go solo.</p>

<p>But it’s not like IRL networks will stop feeding online groups.
The counterargument to ‘social media gives bad politicians a voice’ is that once someone has been elected, they’ll probably <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f7131IkiSCg">have a voice anyway</a>.
FB’s design gives eyeballs to demagogues but <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triumph_des_Willens">so did Leni Riefenstahl</a>.</p>

<p>As I drafted this in early november, twitter was fact-bubbling multiple tweets in a row from the president,
the ‘uncensored’ social media app parler <a href="https://twitter.com/yashar/status/1325229370126991363">trended to #1</a> in apple’s store,
and local hero <a href="https://twitter.com/WilliamShatner/status/1326223481646665728">Bill Shatner took up the cause of moderation</a> to oppose them.
The ‘moderation drives exodus’ hypothesis is plausible.</p>

<p>But parler can’t really want to be unmoderated.
Their debut came with a quick correction that despite the sales pitch, <a href="https://twitter.com/viaCristiano/status/1277941967402553345">your username can’t be cumdumpster</a>.
(<a href="https://twitter.com/cumdumpster">Twitter has allowed this</a> since at least 2013).</p>

<p>My point: nobody wants to live in a trash can.
Every community has some kind of semi-official management.
I think even 8kun revoked someone’s access to the Q account after they had a falling out (admittedly, not over content I think, and also I don’t really understand this world).
But the <em>forms</em> of moderation we invent have to be trusted or at least tolerated, or people will ditch.</p>

<p>Fact-checking, if it’s trustworthy and useful, will be embraced IMO. But it can’t be imposed.</p>

<h2 id="conspiracies-are-topics-too">Conspiracies are topics too</h2>

<p>A swedish friend, trying to explain why their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweden_Democrats">far-right party</a> gained power in the Riksdag,
said something like ‘It’s not that we’re all nazis, but nobody else would even talk about immigration, and it’s a real problem’.</p>

<p>I like the ‘marketplace of ideas’ as a concept.<sup id="fnref:marketplace" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:marketplace">1</a></sup>
Markets are an interesting model for public discourse.
Like goods on markets, there are a limited number of explanations or ideologies available (assuming most people can’t coin our own – for various reasons, I believe we can’t).
Also, like a real market, it’s two-sided, in that in addition to the ideas on offer, there are buyers:
people looking for an action, belief, or political party that suits them.</p>

<p>The marketplace model explains why political parties get to lie out loud, be revealed for hypocrisy, and admit their strategy is disingenuous.
They’re <em>still</em> the only rallying point for ‘critical idea X’ that their buyers need.
It may not matter to the fighting faithful if the center is hollow.
They’re willing to ignore the cognitive dissonance.</p>

<p>I wonder if there’s a similar effect in the antivax movement –
autism seems to really be on the rise (0.7 to 1.5% in this century),
and if your family is affected by this, and there’s no other explanation, you ‘buy’ the idea that comes with a clear cause and a solution.</p>

<h2 id="cranky-boomers-r-us">Cranky boomers R us</h2>

<p>People are seeking answers that are plausible to them,
but may not be able or willing to dig deeply, and may not be ready to hear the truth if it means abandoning their hope, identity, or <a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-11-beliefs-world-filter.html">existing opinions</a>.
I suspect if someone is at the bottom of a rabbit hole and sees a fact bubble saying ‘this is stupid’, that’s the same as saying ‘you’re stupid’, and they won’t listen.
The challenge here is matching them with a well-meaning authority whom they’ll trust and find useful.</p>

<p>There was a measles outbreak in Minnesota enabled by high vaccine refusal rate in a single immigrant community.
Parents noticed a lot of their kids in special autism education<sup id="fnref:stat-antivax" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:stat-antivax">2</a></sup>, then fell prey to antivax lecturers or something.
But the parents had access to doctors.
And presumably they had access to other experts at the autism schools.
They ignored the fact bubble.
They chose who to trust.</p>

<p>On the flip side, community-owned moderation sometimes works rather well.
I’m thinking about subreddits, who tend to have very specific rules about what to post, and their users accept that these communities are actively moderated for the benefit of the community.
(Given that the community is a result of moderation, this is a little circular and feedback loop-y, but that may not be a bad thing).</p>

<p>I asked a friend who mods a small subbredit what it’s like:
“In six years, no one has ever said anything mean on my subreddit. I’ve never had to ban anyone and submitters and subscribers are respectful.”</p>

<p>Cranky boomers got us into this mess by believing everything they read on facebook.
Maybe Cranky-Boomers-R-Us™️ is the right branding for a community fact check to filter out some fast-spreading egregious claims.</p>

<p>We train people to consider the source, but mainstream mastheads like NYT feel ideologically hostile to readers who aren’t centrists over 55.
Their news coverage can be accurate without being neutral – factual claims in articles are fact-checked, but that’s mixed with interpretive conclusions.
The op-eds are <a href="https://www.cjr.org/the_media_today/james_bennet_tom_cotton_objectivity.php">far stranger</a>.</p>

<p>I don’t blame people for switching to ideologically comfortable news.
I just wish they had a fact-check that was ideologically comfortable, but also competent and reputation-bound, to go along with it.</p>

<p>Repentant neocon Francis Fukuyama writes about social trust now and is <a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-emergence-of-a-post-fact-world-by-francis-fukuyama-2017-01">worried about post-fact world</a> where
“all authoritative information sources are challenged by contrary facts of dubious quality and provenance”.
Readers have reasons for straying from reality.
Let’s give people an ideologically comfortable way to come back.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harm_reduction">Gentler public health messaging</a> that accepts people’s lifestyles can have higher efficacy;
I suspect the same is true of fact-checks.
Our goal isn’t to change minds; it’s to improve outcomes.</p>

<h2 id="byo-vs-centralized-moderation">BYO vs centralized moderation</h2>

<p>We need a market ecosystem of moderation vendors who provide different kinds of value to different kinds of users.
A moderation marketplace is good for platforms because they don’t want to be the arbiter of truth, they just want users to have a good experience.
(Platforms will still have some policing to do on their own).</p>

<p>It’s good for users because they’re not forced into anything; they can pick which web they want to dwell on.
This may sound like a filter bubble, where ‘everyone has their own truth’,
but moderation vendors will still need to maintain their reputation for being right –
whatever their ideological alignment.
Moderation vendors, unlike cable news channels, don’t produce content;
they just react to it and grade it.
BYO moderation isn’t BYO newspaper, it’s BYO snopes / politifact.</p>

<p>Centralized moderation has problems:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The costs are asymmetric, meaning it’s too expensive to do widely, well, and fast (see lego point below). Jimmy Wales of wikipedia describes the economics here leading to a <a href="https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/jimmy-wales-tyler-cowen-wikipedia-610b6e931d20">sweatshop model</a>.</li>
  <li>It’s susceptible to abuse by platforms and institutions and therefore will be less trusted by users, especially the more conspiracy-minded ones whom we want to deradicalize. Note I’m not saying ‘prone to abuse’ or ‘untrustworthy’. Just less trust-<em>ed</em>, and less able to balance minority viewpoints in a way that feels authentic to minorities.</li>
  <li>Private groups will turn off mod systems if not effective / ergonomic / trustable, or else deplatform.</li>
  <li>For messy issues, cookie-cutter moderation can <a href="https://www.eff.org/wp/caught-net-impact-extremist-speech-regulations-human-rights-content">support violence by hiding its proof</a>. Or like <a href="https://twitter.com/KatMurti/status/1276183164109697028">where’s the parler for breastfeeding</a>?</li>
</ul>

<p>Every community needs moderation.
Some get away without it because they moderate membership rather than content –
small workplaces, for example, have relatively informal content moderation processes, but can fire you.</p>

<p>This isn’t just a facebook / twitter issue anymore – it’s a problem for anyone with a supply of eyeballs and UGC or DM features, like <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/11/07/pinterest-linkedin-election-disinfo/">pinterest and linkedin</a>.
The older and funnier version of this is the <a href="https://www.managingcommunities.com/2015/06/04/lego-universes-penis-problem-and-why-moderation-efforts-arent-hopeless/">lego MMO’s penis problem</a> –
they …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html">https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25246733</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:01:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Study links mindfulness and meditation to narcissism and “spiritual superiority”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245512">thread link</a>) | @Bologo
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-5234" role="main"><div><div><div><p><strong>A <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ejsp.2721" target="_blank">new study</a> has found that some popular forms of spiritual training — such as energy healing, aura reading, and, to a lesser degree, mindfulness and meditation — correlate with both narcissism and “spiritual superiority.”</strong></p><p>An implicit feature of spiritual training is that it allows its adherents to distance themselves from their egos, and thereby from things such as the need for social approval or success. By encouraging self-compassion and non-judgmental self-acceptance, spiritual training should presumably make people less concerned with such things.</p><p>But as a new paper explains, spiritual training may have the opposite effect. Namely, spiritual training might in fact enhance people’s need to feel “more successful, more respected or more loved,” as the authors Roos Vonk and Anouk Visser write.</p><h2>The first study to measure spiritual superiority</h2><p>No previous studies had specifically examined topic, which prompted Roos Vonk and Anouk Visser to investigate. Their <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ejsp.2721" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">new paper</a>, “An Exploration of Spiritual Superiority: The Paradox of Self‐Enhancement,” appears in the <em><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10990992" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">European Journal of Social Psychology</a></em>.</p><p>The authors developed a new measure they call “spiritual superiority.” It measures whether people feel superior to those “who lack the spiritual wisdom they ascribe to themselves.”<span data-ez-name="psychnewsdaily_com-medrectangle-4"></span></p><p>The measure’s questionnaires ask people to respond on a scale of 1 to 7 to a series of statements. Example statements include “I am more in touch with my senses than most others,” “I am more aware of what is between heaven and earth than most people,” and “The world would be a better place if others too had the insights that I have now.”</p><h2>Spiritual guidance, supernatural overconfidence, and self-worth</h2><p>The authors also created three scales that they hypothesized would correlate with spiritual superiority.</p><p>The first scale, “spiritual guidance,” relates to how much people try to help others acquire the same wisdom they have acquired. It includes statements such as “I help others whenever possible on their path to greater wisdom and insight,” “I gladly help others to acquire my insights too,” and “I am patient with others, because I understand it takes time to gain the insights that I gained in my life and my education.”</p><p>The second scale is “supernatural overconfidence,” and it encompasses self-ascribed abilities in the paranormal domain. Example statements include “I can send positive energy to others from a distance,” “I can get in touch with people who are deceased,” and “I can influence the world around me with my thoughts.”</p><p>The third scale, “spiritual contingency of self-worth,” measures how much a person’s self-esteem is derived from their spirituality. Sample statements include “My faith in myself increases when I acquire more spiritual wisdom” and “When I gain new spiritual insights, this increases my self-worth.”</p><p>In the three studies described below, the researchers found that their scale of spiritual superiority is a valid instrument. Moreover, it correlates significantly with the other three scales. It also correlates significantly with narcissism, self‐esteem, and other psychological variables. Finally, it also correlates, to varying degrees, with diverse forms of spiritual training.</p><h2><strong>Assessing spiritual superiority</strong></h2><p>For the first of the three studies included in the current paper, Vonk and Visser recruited 533 participants. They found them by contacting schools and spiritual centers that offer courses in subjects such as mindfulness and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Energy_medicine" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">energetic training</a>.</p><p>The participants in this first study were about 75% female, with an average age of 51. They indicated that they were currently following some form of spiritual training. The types mentioned included <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/category/mental-health/mindfulness/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mindfulness</a>, meditation, energetic therapy, reading/healing aura, haptotherapy, reiki, and others.</p><p>The respondents filled in the questionnaires described above, and also answered questions about their age, sex, education, religion, and spiritual training.</p><p>The researchers found that “spiritual superiority” correlated significantly with self-esteem, mindfulness, supernatural overconfidence, and spiritual guidance.</p><p>As the authors predicted, these correlations were strongest for participants following forms of “energetic” training. These participants rated higher than the <a href="https://amzn.to/36jmlSH" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored nofollow">mindfulness/meditation</a> students on all of the superiority-related scales, especially on the scale of supernatural overconfidence.</p><p>This makes sense, the authors write, as energetic training is meant to develop supernatural skills. This likely attracts students who already believe they have talents in this area.</p><p>Likewise, the training itself might further enhance their confidence. This is because no objective performance standards can conclusively demonstrate they are not in fact paranormally gifted.</p><h2><strong>What about people who don’t follow spiritual training</strong>?</h2><p>The second study broadened the pool of respondents to include people who are not currently undergoing spiritual training. The goal was to compare their results on the spiritual superiority scale to those of the spiritual training students.</p><p>For this study, the researchers recruited 2,223 participants via a Dutch popular psychology magazine. Of these, 1960 were women. Their ages ranged from 15 to 82, with an average age of 41.</p><p>About a third had never followed any spiritual training; another third had followed mindfulness or meditation training. About 10% had followed some form of energetic training (including aura healing/reading). Another 10% had followed other kinds of spiritual training.</p><p>The result of this second study also showed that “spiritual superiority” significantly correlates with all the other measures. Furthermore, it also found the same pattern in Study 1. Namely there was a gradual increase in spiritual superiority as one moved from the “no spiritual training” group to the “mindfulness training” group to the “energetic training” group. And again, the results for the “energetic” group were much higher than for both the “mindfulness” and the “no-training” groups.</p><h2>Correlations with <strong>narcissism</strong></h2><p>Study 3 tested the hypothesis that spiritual superiority is related to narcissism. As the researchers explain, past research has used the term “spiritual narcissism,” but none those studies empirically measured it.</p><p>For this study, the authors did not measure “agentic narcissism” (for example, “I am more special than others and deserve special privileges”), but rather “<a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/tech-support/201605/the-communal-narcissist-another-wolf-wearing-sheep-outfit">communal narcissism</a>,” which describes people who think of themselves as more nurturing and empathic than others. Example statements that characterize this trait include “I have a very positive influence on others” and “I am generally the most understanding person.”</p><p>This study recruited 965 participants via various channels. These included a Facebook page about psychology, spiritual schools, and participants who were not able to participate in the previous two studies due to a lack of space. The final sample included about 88% women, aged 19-79, with an average age of 46.</p><p>The participants answered the questionnaires for spiritual superiority and spiritual guidance, as well as several existing scales related to humility and overconfidence, a short 7-item version of the <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22889074/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Communal Narcissism scale</a>, and a three-item self-esteem scale.</p><p>The researchers found that the correlation between spiritual superiority and narcissism was 0.47. This is significantly stronger than the correlation with self-esteem. And once again, the same pattern emerged in terms of the type of spiritual training that the participants followed. The weakest correlations were among subjects with no spiritual training, and the highest for those who practiced energetic training. The mindfulness/meditation group was in between, though it was considerably closer to the “no-training” group than to the “energetic” group.</p><h2><strong>Why t</strong>he link between <strong>spiritual superiority and narcissism</strong>?</h2><p>The authors argue that the lack of objectivity in the spiritual domain plays a role here. “Like religiosity, spirituality is a domain that seems like a safe and secure investment for self-worth,” they write. “One’s spiritual attainments allow lots of room for wishful thinking, thus easily lending themselves to the grip of the self-enhancement motive.”</p><p>And because spiritual matters are generally “elusive to external objective standards,” that makes them a “suitable domain for illusory beliefs about one’s superiority.”</p><p>The results of these three studies do not imply any casual direction; the authors suggest the causal arrow may work in both directions. On one hand, people may use spirituality as a self-esteem booster: it allows them to see themselves as special, and they can achieve progress in the spiritual domain relatively easily, as there are no objectively measurable outcomes (in contrast to, for example, sports, academic success, or wealth accumulation).</p><p>On the other hand, spiritual training may attract people who already feel superior. And the “extensive exploration of one’s personal thoughts and feelings” that spiritual training encourages “may be particularly appealing” to <a href="https://amzn.to/3lhtAhZ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener sponsored nofollow">narcissists</a>, the authors write.</p><h2>Towards genuine spiritual growth</h2><p>The people who agreed to take part in this research might not represent spirituality students in general. “The question is whether a truly enlightened person would even participate in our studies,” the authors write. “Would such a person be interested in or even capable of answering all these ‘me’ questions?”</p><p>GIn any case, the researchers hope that future research can “reveal more insights into the effects of spiritual training, and possibly the conditions and personality characteristics that facilitate genuine spiritual growth.”</p><hr><p><strong>Study:</strong> “<a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/ejsp.2721">An Exploration of Spiritual Superiority: The Paradox of Self‐Enhancement</a>“<br><strong>Authors: </strong>Roos Vonk and Anouk Visser<br><strong>Published in:</strong> <em><a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10990992" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">European Journal of Social Psychology</a></em><br><strong>Publication date:</strong> October 1, 2020<br><strong>DOI:</strong> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsp.2721">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejsp.2721</a><br><strong>Photo: </strong>by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/kalyanayahaluwo-1767926/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5353620">Bhikku Amitha</a>&nbsp;via&nbsp;<a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5353620">Pixabay</a>&nbsp;</p><p>For a weekly summary of the latest psychology news, subscribe to our <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/the-psych-news-weekly-newsletter/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Psych News Weekly …</a></p></div></div></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/">https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245512</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 15:09:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Little Things That Made Amiga Great]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 213 | Comments 172 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245206">thread link</a>) | @eitland
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>



<p><b>A deep dive into a selection of ingenious AmigaOS features.</b></p>

<p><i>Autumn 2020</i></p>

<h2 id="toc">Table of Contents</h2>

<ul>
  <li><a href="#intro">Introduction</a></li>
  <li><a href="#jargon">Jargon buster</a></li>
  <li>
    <a href="#littlethings">The Little Things</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="#ramdisk">The RAM Disk</a></li>
      <li><a href="#raddisk">The RAD Disk</a></li>
      <li><a href="#propscroll">Proportional scroll bars</a></li>
      <li><a href="#editors">The Text Editors</a></li>
      <li><a href="#arexx">ARexx</a></li>
      <li><a href="#nocd">No CD</a></li>
      <li><a href="#filesys">File Systems</a></li>
      <li><a href="#assigns">Assigns</a></li>
      <li><a href="#libs">Libraries</a></li>
      <li><a href="#asl">ASL</a></li>
      <li><a href="#datatypes">Datatypes</a></li>
      <li><a href="#readargs">ReadArgs</a></li>
      <li><a href="#guide">AmigaGuide</a></li>
      <li><a href="#installer">Installer</a></li>
      <li><a href="#filestruct">Standardized File Structure</a></li>
      <li><a href="#resident">Resident Programs</a></li>
      <li><a href="#reqchoice">RequestChoice</a></li>
      <li><a href="#infofiles">.info Files</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#closing">Closing words</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="intro">Introduction</h3>

<p>
To most people, the Amiga is probably synonymous with the Amiga 500 and that 
machine was, above all, a video game: something into which you plonked 
3.5" floppy disks that transported you to strange, wonderful worlds and 
hours of fun. To this group, the gamers, the operating system wasn't 
important. They probably booted Workbench 1.3 
only once, took a good look at the garish blue and orange interface,
and decided that enough was enough, before going back to blasting enemies 
in Silkworm.
</p>

<p>
And why not? The machine was great for games. There are tons of great 
texts about the groundbreaking audio and video capabilities of the 
Amiga.
</p>

<p>
This text is not one of those.
</p>

<p>
This text is about the later versions of AmigaOS produced by Commodore, 
from 2.0 to 3.1. While these newer versions (with majors released in 1990 
and 1992, respectively) certainly carried the Amiga heritage with pride 
and were - mostly - backwards compatible, the advent of AmigaOS 2.0 
marked a paradigm shift. The shift is best symbolized by the fact that 
AmigaBASIC - the ubiquitous and mandatory language of any 
self-respecting eighties home computer - was ditched and replaced by 
ARexx, a professional scripting language without any kind of graphics or 
sound features whatsoever.
</p>

<p>
This paradigm shift is also why so many of us who had the good fortune 
to come across those versions clung to the Amiga so desperately. A lot
of us stuck with it
well into the late nineties, years after Commodore's demise. And we were
fierce: if 
you think Apple fanboys are annoying today, be very happy you didn't meet an 
Amiga zealot in 1995. Things got personal quickly. It was downright ugly.
</p>

<p>
I still think there were some grounds for our fanaticism, though.
</p>

<p>
In a time when home PC:s were single tasking DOS boxes with 8 character 
file names and Ataris and Macs were single tasking GUI boxes, hampering
any hacker  with their glaring lack of a CLI, the Amiga was a champion of both 
worlds: It combined the CLI and GUI, leveraging both their strengths.
But there was more to it than that, something that's hard to convey
in so many words.
</p>

<p>
Many a time have I come across exasperated Amiga users who, on some 
online forum, tries to explain the greatness of the Amiga's operating 
system in a few short sentences. It often, quite understandably, boils 
down to something akin to "It's like UNIX", which I always think is 
unfair to both of the systems.
</p>

<p>
Sure, it was an early multitasking system with a capable command line. 
At the same time, it was also a mature and coherent desktop environment 
with levels of user friendliness much more like today's MacOS X than any 
traditional UNIX. But, contrary to today's MacOS, it never mollycoddled the
end user. It opened the machine up, rather than closing certain parts off.
</p>

<p>
Unlike UNIX, AmigaOS is a system designed for home computer use, lacking a 
lot of what makes UNIX so popular: memory protection, multi user 
support, source code portability and built in networking support.
</p>

<p>
They're very much alike in one aspect, though. Like UNIX, the Amiga's 
operating system is a collection of a lot of little strokes of genius 
that come together to make it bigger than the sum of its parts.
</p>

<p>
I invite you to explore this ingenuity with me. But first, let's get the 
terminology sorted.
</p>

<h3 id="jargon">Jargon buster</h3>

<p>
The Amiga's operating system has been called a lot of things by a lot of 
people, because it consists of many components that different types of 
users interacted more or less with. Let me try to clear things up a bit:
</p>


<dl>
<dt>AmigaOS</dt>

<dd>
This was never an official name during the Commodore days, but it's a 
handy way of describing all of the components below as a whole.
</dd>

<dt>Kickstart</dt>

<dd>
This is basically the firmware of the Amiga, residing in the ROM chip. 
On version 2.0 and up, the ROM chip was 512 kB large and contained not 
only code for self tests and bootstrapping but also quite sizable 
portions of the other parts of AmigaOS.
</dd>

<dt>AmigaDOS</dt>

<dd>
This is, roughly speaking, the command line interface, device drivers, 
file system management and so on. It was originally based on TRIPOS, a 
heritage that still shows to this day. (There are newer versions of AmigaOS
than 3.1, but this text will only cover the ones released by Commodore.)
</dd>

<dt>Intuition</dt>

<dd>
Best likened to a modern desktop compositor, Intuition handles screen 
updates and manages windows. The custom sound and video chips in the 
Amiga had mostly female names (Paula, Denise and later Alice), so I 
suppose Intuition is a fitting name for an abstraction layer that lets 
the OS interface with them.
</dd>

<dt>Workbench</dt>

<dd>
This is often used interchangeably with "AmigaOS" but it's really the 
name of just the desktop environment - which is a workbench, not a 
desktop: Programs are called tools, folders a called drawers and data 
files are called projects.
</dd>

</dl>

<h4>Other terminology</h4>

<dl>

<dt>Requesters</dt>

<dd>
Not really a major part of the OS per se, a requester is the Amiga's 
name for a dialog box. A "file requester" is a file selection dialog, 
for example. I still often use this term to describe any dialog on any 
platform, much to the confusion of friends and colleagues. Old habits 
die hard.
</dd>

<dt>Devices</dt>

<dd>
Devices, much like in UNIX, usually represent peripherals attached to the 
computer, such as storage media, printers, etc. The Amiga has a number 
of built-in devices that are automatically mounted,
for example the internal floppy drive, <code>DF0:</code>
and  the serial and parallel ports, <code>SER:</code> and <code>PAR:</code>
respectively. Other 
common devices are <code>DF1:</code>, the first external floppy drive,
<code>DH0:</code>, the 
common device name given to the bootable hard drive partition, and 
<code>CON:</code>, the text console.
There are also devices that can't
be mounted but only
be accessed using programming languages, such as <code>timer.device</code>
which is used to interface with hardware clocks.
</dd>

<dt>Volumes</dt>

<dd>
Mounted devices (such as <code>DF0</code>, <code>DF1</code>, <code>DH0</code>)
can contain a volume. In the 
case of <code>DH0:</code>, a bootable hard drive partition,
the volume is fixed and 
is represented by the name of the partition, such as <code>System:</code> or 
<code>Boot:</code>.
If you insert the Deluxe Paint program disk into the internal 
floppy drive, the current volume in device <code>DF0:</code>
will be <code>DPaint:</code>.
</dd>

</dl>


<h2 id="littlethings">The Little Things</h2>

<p>
<a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/cleanboot.png">
<img src="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/cleanboot.png" alt="The Amiga Workbench after a clean boot.">
</a>
</p>
<p>
<i>The Amiga Workbench after a clean boot. To the left are device icons,
for the RAM disk and hard drive partitions. The other icons represent various
applications, placed on the desktop for easy access.
Click the image for full resolution.</i>
</p>

<h3 id="ramdisk">The RAM Disk</h3>

<p>
The Amiga always has a RAM disk ready for use and the device name is 
always <code>RAM:</code>. No mounting, no third party software - it just sits 
there, waiting. That's clever in its own right, but the really ingenious 
part about it is that it's dynamically allocated. That means the size of the 
RAM disk corresponds to the amount of free memory currently available on 
the system, and that it never takes up more memory than is needed to
accommodate the files currently stored on it.
</p>

<p>
A RAM disk might sound esoteric today, but in the days of slow 
mechanical hard drives and floppy disks, it was a godsend for unpacking 
archives, running test compiles and storing temporary working documents.
</p>

<p>
The downside is that every time you reboot your computer, all the 
contents of the RAM disk are lost. Which brings us to...
</p>

<h3 id="raddisk">The RAD Disk</h3>

<p>
RAD, which (somehow) stands for Recoverable Ram Disk, is another 
testament to the flexibility and ingenuity of AmigaOS. The RAD disk is a 
fixed size RAM disk that can not only survive reboots but also itself
be booted from. It can be used as a small but extremely fast mini hard
drive, or  for extracting disk images to, for checking out their contents.
</p>

<h3 id="propscroll">Proportional scroll bars</h3>

<p>
A proportional scroll bar is a scroll bar that grows and shrinks to 
reflect the size of the scrollable content it represents:
</p>

<p>
<a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/propscroll.png">
<img src="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/propscroll.png" alt="Screenshot of proportional scroll bars">
</a>
</p>
<p>
<i>Click the image for full resolution.</i>
</p>

<p>
Highlighting a feature like this might 
seem like a silly point to make, because today all scroll bars are 
proportional. Not so in the bad old days: Microsoft 
didn't implement them until Windows 95 and Apple, as far as I know,
didn't make the move until MacOS 9 in 1999. In a time when computer mice 
had no scroll wheels, this was a nifty feature indeed.
</p>

<h3 id="editors">The Text Editors</h3>

<p>
<a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/ed.png">
<img src="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/gfxs/ed.png" alt="Screenshot of Ed in full screen mode.">
</a>
</p>
<p>
<i>
Above, Ed is used to edit S:Shell-Startup, the equivalent of .bashrc for
AmigaShell. The editor is currently in command mode, getting ready to delete
a line of text.
Click the image for full resolution.</i>
</p>

<p>
AmigaOS shipped with three different text editors: Ed, Edit and MEmacs. 
The latter is a port of, you guessed it, Micro Emacs, and will of course 
appeal to Emacs fans. The other two are sort of curiously named: Edit is 
a line editor mostly resembling ed on UNIX. The Amiga's Ed, on the other 
hand, is a full screen editor with both mouse support and an 
extensive command language. Amiga Ed is probably best likened with vi.
</p>

<p>
All three of them are capable and powerful editors. Both MEmacs and Ed 
make use of the Amiga's drop down GUI menus and feature support for 
macros and extensive configuration.
</p>

<p>
Ed's command mode is, as mentioned earlier, somewhat reminiscent of vi. 
Consider the following examples:
</p>

<p>
Change the next three occurrences of "data" to "gubbe":<br>
<code>3 E/data/gubbe/</code>
</p>

<p>
Move to top of file, repeat (RP) replace of "data" with "gubbe" until 
end of file:<br>
<code>T; RP E/data/gubbe/</code>
</p>

<p>
Move to top of file, find all occurrences of "gubbe" and insert three 
blank lines after every occurrence, repeat until end of file:<br>
<code>T; RP (F /gubbe/; 3A//)</code>
</p>

<p>
Ed also has something called an ARexx port, which completely </p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/">https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245206</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:14:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pijul – The Mathematically Sound Version Control System Written in Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245129">thread link</a>) | @initialcommit
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
			                <div>
			                    <p><img src="https://initialcommit.com/img/initialcommit/pijul-version-control-system.png" title="Pijul - The Mathematically Sound Version Control System Written in Rust" alt="Image of Pijul - The Mathematically Sound Version Control System Written in Rust">
			                    </p>
			                    
			                    
			                    	
			                    
			                    
			                    
			                    <h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>In our <a href="https://initialcommit.com/blog/Technical-Guide-VCS-Internals">Evolution of Version Control System Internals</a> post, we covered the inner workings of many version control systems, both historical and current. However, we haven't really covered <em>the possible future</em> of version control.  How will this field evolve going forward?</p>
<p>Although Git is dominant now and will certainly remain a strong player for years to come, will better tools be created? Pijul could be a strong contender.</p>
<p>In this article, we'll discuss Pijul - an alpha stage version control system that is gaining attention in the community.</p>
<h2>Background</h2>
<p><a href="https://pijul.org/">Pijul</a> is a VCS written by Pierre-Ã‰tienne Meunier and Florent Becker. After releasing a number of experimental prototypes between 2015 and 2020, the first alpha version was released in November 2020. By operating on diffs <em>and</em> on versions at the same time, Pijul combines aspects of third-generation VCS such as <a href="https://initialcommit.com/blog/Technical-Guide-VCS-Internals#git">Git</a> and <a href="https://initialcommit.com/blog/Evolution-of-VCS-Internals-2/#darcs">Darcs</a>.</p>
<p>Pijul is written in <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> and is currently in alpha stage development. The algorithms and formats underlying Pijul's design were recently overhauled for performance and robustness of the system, and the team is working on making it as stable as possible after these updates.</p>
<p>Pijul's architecture and design methodology was influenced by the <a href="http://darcs.net/">Darcs</a> project, which we <a href="https://initialcommit.com/blog/Evolution-of-VCS-Internals-2/#darcs">covered in detail here</a>.</p>
<p>One distinctive feature of Pijul (shared with Darcs) is <strong>change commutation</strong>, whereby changes that could be recorded independently can be applied in any order, without affecting the result.</p>
<p>However, unlike Darcs, which operates on changes only, Pijul applies changes to an abstract data structure representing generalized files, allowing it to maintain a notion of version as well as a notion of change between versions. This has a number of advantages, in particular in terms of performance and in terms of mathematical soundness.</p>
<p>The source code for Pijul can be found at <a href="https://nest.pijul.com/pijul/pijul">https://nest.pijul.com/pijul/pijul</a>. The <a href="https://nest.pijul.com/">Pijul Nest</a> is a remote hosting platform for Pijul repositories. Think of it as Pijul's version of GitHub or BitBucket.</p>
<h2>Purpose</h2>
<p>We already have <a href="https://git-scm.com/">Git</a>, the most popular and functional VCS on Earth. Git handles all of the features we could expect from a solid VCS (in fact it sets the benchmark for these features), including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Intuitive method and interface for version tracking</li>
<li>Easily sharing work and collaborating remotely</li>
<li>Lightweight branching and merging</li>
<li>Fast performance and security features</li>
<li>A long list of tools for conveniently managing repositories depending on desired workflow and personal style</li>
</ul>
<p>We also have Darcs, a patch-centric perspective on version control with the following advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>In Darcs, a repository can be better thought of as a "set of patches" - applied as needed - as opposed to a linear history of dependent changesets.</li>
<li>The Darcs model preserves the <strong>identity</strong> of patches during operations like rebasing and cherry-picking, whereas Git sometimes needs to rewrite history due to chained identifiers that depend on the order of application. Preserving a change's ID can be considered a more natural approach.</li>
<li>Darcs has a very well designed interface and command set that provides verbose output to help speed up the learning curve for users and clarify what actions the users are taking.</li>
<li>Patch bundles can be easily transmitted via email to be applied by the remote repository owner.</li>
</ul>
<p>So since we have Git and Darcs, why do we need Pijul? Pijul was created to solve unrelated problems that exist in Git and Darcs.</p>
<p>Pijul uses a patch-centric model similar to Darcs, which doesn't require history to be re-written when reordering, cherry-picking, or otherwise reorganizing patches. All patches retain their identities permanently regardless of their context, order, operations performed, or team workflow. This is a very elegant solution and arguably a more natural way to create such a system. This is in contrast to Git in which certain operations such as rebases and cherry-picks can change commit ID's (and other identifiers), even if the content itself doesn't change.</p>
<p>Furthermore, subsequent cherry-picks from a remote branch in Git can lead to unnatural conflicts due to the rewriting of the initial cherry-picked commit's ID. Pijul avoids this problem completely as patches always retain their identity, regardless of their location in a branch.</p>
<p>So what about Darcs? In certain scenarios, Darcs runs into performance issues such as the <a href="http://darcs.net/FAQ/Performance#is-the-exponential-merge-problem-fixed-yet">exponential merge problem</a>. This issue causes certain merges to increase exponentially in difficulty, effectively preventing these merges from being performed. Pijul has solved this problem.</p>
<p>As is summed up nicely in <a href="https://pijul.org/posts/2020-11-07-towards-1.0#are-edge-labels-minimal">Pierre Meunier's recent post <strong>Toward's 1.0</strong></a>: "Our goals are to find the smallest possible system, both for reasons of mathematical aesthetics (why store useless stuff?) and the other one for performance."</p>
<p>Pijul's main purpose is to be an efficient VCS based on a sound mathematical theory, guaranteeing that basic properties of changes are always maintained. This consistency bolsters peace of mind in the software development process. With Pijul, developers can be 100% confident that the code they reviewed is the code that gets merged, which is not necessarily the case in Git and Mercurial. Even though file reshuffles do not seem to happen very often in these existing VCS, (and some of them are caught by tests), there are a few statistical studies highlighting their occurrence, and the security implications are huge.</p>
<p>One particular goal of Pijul is to model conflicts as normal states of collaboration, so that conflicts are resolved by normal changes, valid even for the same conflicts in any other context.</p>
<h2>Architecture</h2>
<p>A Pijul repository has a <code>pristine</code> directory, containing a number of <strong>channels</strong>. At any given time, a channel contains a set of unordered <strong>changes</strong>, which can also be seen as a version, since the order of independent changes does not matter in Pijul.</p>
<p>The "working copy" is simply the set of files directly editable by the user, and the correspondence between the working copy and the pristine is done by a <strong>file tracking tree</strong>, which is just a mapping between working copy files and files as stored in the pristine.</p>
<p>Moreover, changes <strong>can</strong> (but don't need to) depend on each other, and do so explicitly (see the section about the "sample change" below), in the sense that each change is uniquely identified by its cryptographic hash, and dependencies are explicit hashes of other changes. The <strong>minimal dependencies</strong> are enforced by Pijul to make sure that text edits make sense. For example, a change editing a file or a paragraph depends on the change that introduced that file or paragraph. This is because it doesn't make sense to change a piece of content that was never added in the first place, so the patch that added the content must be present for the patch that changed it to have meaning. Additionally, the user may specify extra, language-specific dependencies to model the edits more accurately, for example the dependency between introducing a function and using it in another file or another part of the same file. This is an extremely powerful feature.</p>
<p>If desired, this scheme of dependencies between changes allows Pijul to mimic the strict sequential ordering of commits used by Git and Mercurial, turning Pijul into a sort of "Git, but with mathematically sound merges". The downside of using Pijul like this is that changes relative to independent features of the project might need to be more carefully split between different channels, like Git branches. The "plain", or "standard" Pijul way is to try and record changes that are as independent as possible, and keep them on the same channel, since independent changes can always be split later on without changing their identity (i.e. their hash). Channels are useful for different "flavors" of the project, and one can push the same changes to multiple channels without modifying these changes.</p>
<h2>Q&amp;A with the Creator</h2>
<p>We wanted to get inside the head of Pierre-Ã‰tienne Meunier, the creator and lead developer of Pijul, so we <a href="https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-creator">asked him a series of questions related to his background and the creation of Pijul, and the direction of the version control field</a>. His answers were <strong>extremely</strong> interesting and worth a read (we split them into a separate post since they were fairly lengthy).</p>
<h2>Basic Commands</h2>
<p>One of Pijul's goals is to minimize the number of commands, so as to allow users to get a full understanding of the system as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>The commands are:</p>
<p><code>pijul init</code>: Creates a directory named <code>.pijul</code>, containing the following structure:</p>
<div>
    <pre><code>.pijul/
    changes
    config
    pristine
        db0
        db.lock</code></pre>
</div>
<p>Here, the meaningful things that get created are <code>db0</code>, which contains the pristine, in binary format, and a sample <code>config</code> file, editable in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TOML">TOML format</a>.</p>
<p><code>pijul add &lt;filename.ext&gt;</code>: Adds a file to the repository's tracking list.<br>
<code>pijul remove &lt;filename.ext&gt;</code>:  Remove a file from the tracking list.<br>
<code>pijul mv &lt;filename1.ext&gt; &lt;filename2.ext&gt;</code>: Move and/or rename a file in the tracking list.<br>
<code>pijul ls</code>: Displays a list of currently tracked files.<br>
<code>pijul record</code> (or <code>pijul rec</code>): Creates a change and applies it to the pristine. Once we do that, the <code>.pijul/changes</code> gets populated with one change:</p>
<div>
    <pre><code>./
    file
    .pijul/
        changes
            ZN
                PGE4DJNVY4JAQABNSQYVF5LBFWNO6FRJI3LXX7E7EB4Y3NGGGQC.change
        config
        pristine
            db0
            db.lock</code></pre>
</div>
<p><code>pijul unrecord &lt;hash&gt;</code>: If no change depends on a change <code>hash</code>, we can also "undo" or "unapply" it using the <code>unrecord</code> command. For example, here our change's hash is <code>ZNPGE4DJNVY4JAQABNSQ...</code>, and we can use any unambiguous prefix of that hash, for example <code>pijul unrecord ZNPG</code>, or even <code>pijul unrecord Z</code> to undo it.<br>
<code>pijul reset</code>: Resets the repository to the state of a channel. Without any …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system">https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245129</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:01:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A better Kubernetes from the ground up]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 249 | Comments 147 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25243159">thread link</a>) | @mr-karan
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<div>
		<p><span>Written by</span>
        David Anderson
        <br>
        <span>on&nbsp;</span><time datetime="2020-11-28 00:00:00 +0000 UTC">November 28, 2020</time>
</p>
		


		

		<p>Recently I had a chat with the excellent <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery Lancey</a>, about Kubernetes. Specifically, what we would do differently if we built something new, from the ground up, with no regard for compatibility with Kubernetes. I found that conversation so stimulating that I feel the need to write things down, so here we are.</p>

<p>Before we get started, I want to stress a few things.</p>

<ul>
<li>This is not a fully formed design. Some of these things may not work at all, or require significant redesign. Each section is one random piece of the entire puzzle.</li>
<li>These are not solely my ideas. Some I <em>think</em> are original, but like many things in the Kubernetes community it’s the product of collective thinking. I know at least <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/maisem_ali">Maisem Ali</a> have influenced my thinking at one time or another, and I’m forgetting many more. If you like an idea, it was a group effort. If you hate it, it’s entirely mine.</li>
<li>Some of these things are polarizing. I’m designing something that makes <em>me</em> happy.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="guiding-principles">Guiding principles</h2>

<p>My experience of Kubernetes comes from two very different places: authoring <a href="https://www.metallb.org/">MetalLB</a> for bare metal clusters, and operating a large fleet of clusters-as-a-service in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine">GKE SRE</a>. Both of these taught me that Kubernetes is extremely complex, and that most people who are trying to use it are not prepared for the sheer amount of work that lies between the marketing brochure and the system those brochures promise.</p>

<p>MetalLB taught me that it’s not possible to build robust software that integrates with Kubernetes. I think MetalLB makes a damn good go of it, but Kubernetes still makes it far too easy to construct broken configurations, and far too hard to debug them. GKE SRE taught me that even the foremost Kubernetes experts cannot safely operate Kubernetes at scale. (Although GKE SRE does a spectacular job with the tools they’re given.)</p>

<p>Kubernetes is the C++ of orchestration software. Immensely powerful, includes all the features, looks deceptively simple, and <em>will</em> hurt you repeatedly until you join its priesthood and devote your life to its mysteries. And even then, the matrix of possible ways to configure and deploy it is so large that you’re never on firm footing.</p>

<p>Continuing that analogy, my guide star is Go. If Kubernetes is C++, what would the Go of orchestration systems look like? Aggressively simple, opinionated, grown slowly and warily, and you can learn it in under a week and get on with what you were actually trying to accomplish.</p>

<p>With that, let’s get going. Starting with Kubernetes, and with a license to completely and utterly break compatibility, what would I do?</p>

<h2 id="mutable-pods">Mutable pods</h2>

<p>In Kubernetes, pods are mostly (but not entirely) immutable after creation. If you want to change a pod, you don’t. Make a new one and delete the old one. This is unlike most other things in Kubernetes, which are mostly mutable and gracefully reconcile towards the new spec.</p>

<p>So, I’m going to make pods be not special. Make them entirely read-write, and reconcile them like you would any other object.</p>

<p>The immediately useful thing I get from that is in-place restarts. If scheduling constraints and resource allocations haven’t changed, guess what? SIGTERM runc, restart runc with different parameters, and you’re done. Now pods look like regular old systemd services, that can move between machines <em>if necessary</em>.</p>

<p>Note that this doesn’t require doing mutability at the runtime layer. If you change a pod definition, it’s still mostly fine to terminate the container and restart it with a new configuration. The pod is still holding onto the resource reservation that got it scheduled onto this machine, so conceptually it’s equivalent to <code>systemctl restart blah.service</code>. You could try to be fancy and make some operations actually update in place at the runtime level as well, but don’t have to. The main benefit is decoupling scheduling, pod lifetime, and lifetime at the runtime layer.</p>

<h2 id="version-control-all-the-things">Version control all the things</h2>

<p>Sticking at the pod layer for a bit longer: now that they’re mutable, the next obvious thing I want is rollbacks. For that, let’s keep old versions of pod definitions around, and make it trivial to “go back to version N”.</p>

<p>Now, a pod update looks like: write an updated definition of the pod, and it updates to match. Update broken? Write back version N-1, and you’re done.</p>

<p>Bonus things you get from this: a diffable history of what happened to your cluster, without needing GitOps nonsense. By all means keep the GitOps nonsense if you want, it has benefits, but you can answer a basic “what changed?” question using only data in the cluster.</p>

<p>This needs a bit more design. In particular, I want to separate out external changes (human submits a new pod) from mechanical changes (some internals of k8s alter a pod definition). I haven’t thought through how to encode both those histories and make both accessible to operators and automation. Maybe it could also be completely generic, wherein a “changer” identifies itself when submitting a new version, and you can then query for changes by or excluding particular changers (think similar to how label queries work at the minute). Again, more design needed there, I just know that I want versioned objects with an accessible history.</p>

<p>We’ll need garbage collection eventually. That said, changes to single pods should delta-compress really well, so my default would be to just keep everything until it becomes a truly dumb amount of data, and figure something out at that point. Keeping everything also acts as a useful mild pressure to avoid “death by a thousand changes” in the rest of the system. Prefer to have fewer, more meaningful changes over a flurry of control loops each changing one field in pursuit of convergence.</p>

<p>Once we have this history, we can do some neat minor things too. For example, the node software could keep container images for the last N versions pinned to the machine, so that rollbacks are as fast as they can possibly be. With an accessible history, you can do this more precisely than “GC older than 30 days and hope”. Generalizing, all the orchestration software can use older versions as GC roots for various resources, to make rollbacks faster. Rollbacks being the primary way of ending outages, this is a very valuable thing to have.</p>

<h2 id="replace-deployment-with-pinneddeployment">Replace Deployment with PinnedDeployment</h2>

<p>This is a short section to basically say that <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery</a> knocked it out of the park with her <a href="https://timewitch.net/post/2019-12-30-pinneddeployments/">PinnedDeployment</a> resource, which lets operators explicitly control a rollout by tracking 2 versions of the deployment state. It’s a deployment object designed by an SRE, with a crisp understanding of what SREs want in a deployment. I love it.</p>

<p>This combines super well with the versioned, in-place pod updates above, and I really don’t have anything to add. It’s clearly how multi-pod things should work. There’s probably some tweaking required to adapt from the Kubernetes-constrained world to this new wonderful unconstrained universe, but the general design is perfect.</p>

<h2 id="explicit-orchestration-workflows">Explicit orchestration workflows</h2>

<p>The biggest issue I have with the “API machinery” bits of Kubernetes is the idea of orchestration as a loose choreography of independent control loops. On the surface, this seems like a nice idea: you have dozens of little control loops, each focused on doing one small thing. When combined in a cluster, they indirectly cooperate with each other to push the state forward and converge on the desired end state. So, what’s the problem?</p>

<p>The problem is that it’s entirely impossible to debug when it goes wrong. A typical failure mode in Kubernetes is that you submit a change to the cluster, then repeatedly refresh waiting for stuff to converge. When it doesn’t… Well, you’re screwed. Kubernetes doesn’t know the difference between “the system has converged successfully” and “a control loop is wedged and is blocking everything else.” You can hope that the offending control loop posted some events to the object to help you, but by and large they don’t.</p>

<p>At which point your only option is to cat the logs of every control loop that might be involved, looking for the one that was wedged. You can make this a bit faster if you have intimate knowledge of all the control loops and what each one does, because that lets you infer from the object’s current state which loop might be trying to run right now.</p>

<p>The key thing to notice here is that the complexity has been shifted from the designer of the control loop to the cluster operator. It’s easy (though not trivial) to make a control loop that does a dinky little thing in isolation. But to operate a cluster with dozens of these control loops requires the operator to assimilate the behavior of all of them, their interactions with each other, and try to reason about an extremely loosely coupled system. This is a problem because you have to write and test the control loop once, but work with it and its bugs many more times. And yet, the bias is to simplify the thing you only do once.</p>

<p>To fix this, I would look to systemd. It solves for a similar lifecycle problem: given a current state and a target, how do you get from A to B? The difference is that in systemd, the steps and their dependencies are made explicit. You <em>tell</em> systemd that your unit is a required part of <code>multi-user.target</code> (aka “normally-booted happy system”), that it must run after filesystems have been mounted, but before networking it brought up, and so forth. You can also depend on other concrete parts of the system, for example to say that your thing needs to run whenever sshd is running (sounds like a sidecar, right?).</p>

<p>The net result of this is that systemd can tell you precisely what piece of the system malfunctioned, or is still working on its thing, or failed a precondition. It can also print you a graph of the system’s boot process, and analyze it for things like “what’s the long pole of bootup?”</p>

<p>I want to steal all this wholesale, and plop it into my cluster orchestration …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/">https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25243159</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 05:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Undeleting a file overwritten with mv]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 262 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25242444">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">

    <article>

        

<!--         <header class="post-header">
            <a id="blog-logo" href="https://behind.pretix.eu">
                
                    <span class="blog-title">pretix – behind the scenes</span>
                
            </a>
        </header> -->

        <!-- <span class="post-meta">
            <time datetime="2020-11-28">28 Nov 2020</time>
            
                on Technology, Forensics, and Linux
            
        </span> -->

        <!-- <h1 class="post-title">Undeleting a file overwritten with mv</h1> -->

        <section>
            <p>It’s been a while since we shared the story of an incident with you, and that’s probably a good thing –
most operational incidents we had in the past year were “boring” enough in nature to fix them easily.
This time, we’ve got a story of a data loss, caused by pure and simple human error – and the story of
how we recovered the data.</p>

<p>Even though it is quite embarrassing how the data loss happened, we think it’s worth sharing the story
of its recovery, as it might allow you to learn a few useful things in case you ever end up in a
similar situation.</p>

<p>As you might have seen, over the last 7 months we’ve extended our offerings beyond ticketing to allow
our customers to transform their events into the digital space as long as the global pandemic makes
traditional event formats impossible. The result of our effort is a joint venture called 
<a href="https://venueless.org/">Venueless</a> that you should absolutely check out if you haven’t yet.</p>

<p>One component of the virtual events we run on venueless is <strong>live video streaming</strong>. In this process,
our customers use a tool like <a href="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a> or <a href="https://streamyard.com/">StreamYard</a>
to create a live video stream. The stream is then sent to an <strong>encoding server</strong> of ours via RTMP.
On the encoding server, we re-encode the stream into different quality levels and then distribute
it to our very own tiny streaming CDN.</p>

<p>Venueless currently does <strong>not yet</strong> include a video-on-demand component and usually, our customers record
their content at the source, e.g. with OBS or StreamYard, and process or publish them on their own.
However, just to be safe, we keep a recording of the incoming stream as well. This isn’t currently
part of our promoted service offering, we rather see it as a free backup service to our clients in case they
lose their recording. Given that we already consider it to just be a backup, we currently don’t make any
further backups of this data.</p>

<h4 id="data-loss">Data loss</h4>

<p>Usually, we delete these recordings after a while, but in some cases, our customers ask us to get them, e.g.
because their own recording failed, or because StreamYard only records the first 8 hours of every
stream. Since this doesn’t happen a lot, it’s not yet an automated process in our system. Whenever a customer
requests a recording we SSH into the respective encoding server and move the recording file to a
directory that’s accessible through HTTP, like this:</p>

<pre><code>/var/recordings $ mv recording-12345.flv public/
</code></pre>

<p>That’s it, we share the link with the customer, and the process is done. One of the simplest steps possible
in all this. Yesterday, a customer asked us for the recordings of the two last streams of their event. Just
before finishing up for the week, I wanted to supply them with the required file, SSH’d into the server,
looked for the correct files and typed…</p>

<pre><code>/var/recordings $ mv recording-16678.flv recording-16679.flv
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Oops.</strong> I hit return before typing out <code>public/</code>, and therefore replaced the last stream with the
second-last, losing one of the videos.</p>

<h4 id="damage-control">Damage control</h4>

<p>Having a very naive understanding of how file systems work, I knew that the <code>mv</code> command has only
changed the directory listing of the file system, but hasn’t actually wiped the file from the disk,
so I knew there is likely still a chance to recover the file, if it’s not overwritten by something
else in the meantime.</p>

<p>Since I didn’t manage to re-mount the root partition as read-only to avoid further damage softly,
I used the <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/sysrq.html">big hammer</a> to remount
everything read-only immediately:</p>

<pre><code># echo u &gt; /proc/sysrq-trigger
</code></pre>

<p>Uhm, okay, this worked, but how do I install any data recovery tools now? After some experiments,
I decided it would be easiest to reboot into the recovery system provided by our server provider
<a href="https://www.hetzner.com/">Hetzner</a>. So I configured the boot loader to boot their recovery system
from the network and forcefully rebooted the server.</p>

<p>To be able to perform disk dumps and have some operational flexibility without downloading a 2 TB
disk image to my local machine (which would take rougly a week), I also quickly purchased
a <a href="https://www.hetzner.com/storage/storage-box">Hetzner Storage Box</a> with 5 TB space.</p>

<h4 id="failed-attempts">Failed attempts</h4>

<p>Just before I executed my fatal <code>mv</code> command, I executed <code>ls -lisah</code> to get a directory listing
of the files:</p>

<pre><code>3146449 1.1G -rw-r--r-- 1 www-data www-data 1.1G Nov XX XX:XX recording-16678.flv
3146113 1.6G -rw-r--r-- 1 www-data www-data 1.6G Nov XX XX:XX recording-16679.flv
</code></pre>

<p>This meant I <strong>knew</strong> the inode number of the deleted file! As I mentioned before, my understanding
of file systems was (and is) rather naive, and I was pretty optimistic to be able to recover the
file using that information. Isn’t that sort of what a journaling file system is for?</p>

<p>Recovering the file this way hover appeared to be impossible. <a href="http://ext4magic.sourceforge.net/howto_en.html">ext4magic</a>
and <a href="http://extundelete.sourceforge.net/">extundelete</a> are powerful tools that did find some 
deleted files on my disk – but not the one I was looking for, even after trying different options
for over two hours.</p>

<p>I did not spend the time to really understand how ext4 works, but from what I gathered from various
blogs, I was pretty much out of luck since the inode did no longer contain the relevant information
and ext4magic also wasn’t able to <a href="http://ext4magic.sourceforge.net/howto_en.html#Recovery_process_5">recover the neccessary information from the journal</a>
either.</p>

<pre><code>debugfs:  inode_dump &lt;3146113&gt;
0000  a081 0000 8503 0000 e83a c15f e83a c15f  .........:._.:._
0020  e83a c15f 0000 0000 7200 0100 0800 0000  .:._....r.......
0040  0000 0800 0100 0000 0af3 0100 0400 0000  ................
0060  0000 0000 0000 0000 0100 0000 e6eb c000  ................
0100  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000  ................
*
0140  0000 0000 92d0 2cf5 0000 0000 0000 0000  ......,.........
0160  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 6fb2 0000  ............o...
0200  2000 e3fb 208a 515b 7c65 5d5a 7c65 5d5a   ... .Q[|e]Z|e]Z
0220  e83a c15f 7c65 5d5a 0000 0000 0000 0000  .:._|e]Z........
0240  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000  ................
*
</code></pre>

<p>However, if you’re in a similar situation – the ext4magic how-tos are really helpful and worth a try.</p>

<h4 id="successful-recovery">Successful recovery</h4>

<p>There is this one other approach to file recovery that is often recommended on the internet, usually
for “small text files”: Just <code>grep</code> your whole disk for known parts of its contents! So why wouldn’t
this work on larger non-text files as well?</p>

<p>The first problem is obviously what to grep for. The only thing I know about the missing file, apart
from its rough size, is that it’s a FLV video file. Luckily, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_Video#Flash_Video_Structure">all FLV files</a>
that contain video start with the byte sequence <code>FLV\x01\x05</code>. So let’s search our 2 TB disk for
that byte sequence and print out the byte offset of all occurences!</p>

<pre><code>cat /dev/md2 \
	| pv -s 1888127576000 \
	| grep -P --byte-offset --text 'FLV\x01\x05' \
	| tee -a /mnt/storagebox/grep-log.txt
</code></pre>

<p>This took roughly 7 hours. The <code>pv</code> command with the (rough) total size of the disk is optional, but gives you
a nice progress bar. Overall, this took a little over 6 hours on our server.</p>

<p><code>grep</code> works line-based, which in a binary file menas “any byte sequence between two ASCII line breaks”. The
log file therefore contained lots of lines like this:</p>

<pre><code>184473878409:&lt;some binary data&gt;FLV&lt;some binary data&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>In total, the search found 126 FLV file headers on our disk. This was pretty reassuring, since we had 122 FLV files
still known to the file system – so there are at least four FLV byte sequences without a filename!</p>

<pre><code># find /mnt/disk/var/recordings/ -name '*.flv' -not -empty -ls | wc -l
122
</code></pre>

<p>Now, I needed to find out which of the 126 byte sequences did not have a filename. Since I really didn’t want
to spend all weekend with a deep-dive into the ext4 disk layout, I went for an easier solution: For every file
still known in the file system, I computed a hash of the first 500 kilobytes of the file:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>#!/usr/bin/python3
</span><span>import</span> <span>glob</span>
<span>import</span> <span>hashlib</span>
<span>import</span> <span>os</span>

<span>hashsize</span> <span>=</span> <span>500</span> <span>*</span> <span>1024</span>
<span>known_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>not_deleted_files</span> <span>=</span> <span>sorted</span><span>(</span>
    <span>glob</span><span>.</span><span>glob</span><span>(</span><span>'/mnt/disk/var/recordings/*.flv'</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> 
    <span>glob</span><span>.</span><span>glob</span><span>(</span><span>'/mnt/disk/var/recordings/public/*.flv'</span><span>)</span>
<span>)</span>
<span># Ignore files shorter than our hash size
</span><span>not_deleted_files</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>f</span> <span>for</span> <span>f</span> <span>in</span> <span>not_deleted_files</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>os</span><span>.</span><span>stat</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>).</span><span>st_size</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>hashsize</span>
<span>]</span>

<span>for</span> <span>fname</span> <span>in</span> <span>not_deleted_files</span><span>:</span>
    <span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
        <span>h</span> <span>=</span> <span>hashlib</span><span>.</span><span>md5</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>hashsize</span><span>)).</span><span>hexdigest</span><span>()</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"duplicate hash found:"</span><span>)</span>
        <span>known_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>fname</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>fname</span><span>)</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span>
    <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>not_deleted_files</span><span>),</span> <span>"files with"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>known_hashes</span><span>),</span> <span>"hashes"</span>
<span>)</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Interestingly, two files from the completely different customers shared the same hash of the first 500 kilobytes.
I haven’t tested it yet, but my theory is that those were streams that just did not contain any audio or video
in their first minutes, but only empty frames. However, since I knew this isn’t the case for my missing file,
I felt confident in proceeding with this approach.</p>

<p>Next, I computed the same hash for every byte offest found by grep and compared it to the hashes found in the
previous step:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>grep_log</span> <span>=</span> <span>'/mnt/storagebox/grep-log.txt'</span>
<span>disk</span> <span>=</span> <span>'/dev/md2'</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Parsing grep log…"</span><span>)</span>
<span>positions</span> <span>=</span> <span>[]</span>
<span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>grep_log</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>line</span> <span>in</span> <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>().</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>b'</span><span>\n</span><span>'</span><span>):</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>line</span><span>:</span>  <span># ignore empty line e.g. at end of file
</span>            <span>continue</span>
        <span>pos</span><span>,</span> <span>data</span> <span>=</span> <span>line</span><span>.</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>b':'</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span>
        <span>pos</span> <span>=</span> <span>int</span><span>(</span><span>pos</span><span>.</span><span>decode</span><span>())</span>
        <span># add offset of FLV within line
</span>        <span>binoffset</span> <span>=</span> <span>data</span><span>.</span><span>index</span><span>(</span><span>b"FLV</span><span>\x01</span><span>"</span><span>)</span>
        <span>pos</span> <span>+=</span> <span>binoffset</span> 
        <span>positions</span><span>.</span><span>append</span><span>(</span><span>pos</span><span>)</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Computing hashes of files on disk…"</span><span>)</span>
<span>found_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>disk</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>p</span> <span>in</span> <span>positions</span><span>:</span>
        <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>seek</span><span>(</span><span>p</span><span>)</span>
        <span>d</span> <span>=</span> <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>hashsize</span><span>)</span>
        <span>h</span> <span>=</span> <span>hashlib</span><span>.</span><span>md5</span><span>(</span><span>d</span><span>).</span><span>hexdigest</span><span>()</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"At offset"</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span><span>,</span> <span>"found known hash"</span><span>,</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span>
                  <span>"corresponding to"</span><span>,</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>])</span>
        <span>else</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"At offset"</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span><span>,</span> <span>"found unknown hash"</span><span>,</span> <span>h</span><span>)</span>
        <span>found_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>p</span>

<span>unknown_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>h</span><span>:</span> <span>p</span> <span>for</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span> <span>in</span> <span>found_hashes</span><span>.</span><span>items</span><span>()</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>not</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>files_not_found</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>fname</span> <span>for</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>fname</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>.</span><span>items</span><span>()</span>
   …</code></pre></figure></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/">https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25242444</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 02:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Isetta: Writing a Game Engine from Scratch]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25241361">thread link</a>) | @da_big_ghey
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div data-md-component="container">
          
            
              
            
            
              
            
          
          <div>
            <article>
              
                
                
                
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction<a href="#introduction" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h2>
<p>The Isetta Engine is a student-driven project about demystifying game engine development and providing a roadmap and relevant knowledge for novice developers. To do so, <a href="https://isetta.io/team/">our team</a> will make a game engine by ourselves starting from a collection of base frameworks, and document the process, pitfalls, and advice for our audience with periodic blogs. Besides that, we will conduct interviews with experienced professionals to augment our novice perspective. We believe the novice perspective from our blogs and expert perspective from the interviews will nicely come together and form a complete document to help people get started. </p>
<p>The reason we think more work needs to be done in this field is that too many game engine developers wait until the completion of the engine, typically years, to talk about their development. For studios, this is because they consider the final product to be the game, not the engine. For others, it may be because the engine is what they see as valuable, not the writing. As a result, these talks typically lose the minutiae of the actual daily struggles that took place in the development process. There are others who document their development which has been going on for years, which makes it a daunting task for newcomers to start following along. </p>
<p>Although the project is aimed at helping novice developers, this is not to be used as a sole source of learning engine development. Being new engine developers ourselves, we can't guarantee the way we develop the engine will be correct, which is why interviews will help the project remain grounded. This means others who are learning can use what we've done as a guide and not necessarily the ground truth. The blogs won't be a walkthrough/tutorial/step-by-step instructions on how to develop an engine. We are learning as we go and think our journey is what can be valuable to you. </p>
<h3 id="about-the-project">About the Project<a href="#about-the-project" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>This project is being done as a student-pitched project at the <a href="https://www.etc.cmu.edu/">Entertainment Technology Center</a> (ETC). The ETC is an interdisciplinary Master's degree program at Carnegie Mellon University where students' main focus is working on small teams on a project each semester during a 3-month time period. Throughout the semester, a team's work will be presented to faculty and peers with feedback and critique being presented to help aid in the project development. Our particular project idea has gone through multiple iterations to do the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>Simplify the engine to be feasible within 3 months and</li>
<li>Deliver content that would be useful, and hopefully enjoyable, to consume.</li>
</ol>
<p>As of writing this, we've learned that creating content that will satisfy both is difficult and time-consuming, so we will be focusing on writing these milestone-type blogs as well as posting various types of content to test which is the best form of presenting our work. The short project duration also forces us to think clearly about our scope and be lean on the features we include before starting. </p>
<h3 id="schedule">Schedule<a href="#schedule" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>During the course of this project <strong>(08/26 - 12/16, 2018</strong>), a blog post will be published every week to share our thoughts and process, and an interview will be published every 1-2 weeks. The interview schedule depends on our progress on the engine itself, as each interview's topic will be themed around our current work.</p>
<p>For latest schedule, see our <a href="https://isetta.io/schedule/">schedule</a> page.</p>
<h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites<a href="#prerequisites" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>Although we will cover some basic features of engine development, it will profoundly help if you have experience in C++ programming and developing software, especially games, as our project won't provide step-by-step instructions on how to do everything. For a list of resources on how to gain related knowledge, please go to the <a href="#Readings">Readings</a> section. Additional resources will be posted on our <a href="https://isetta.io/resources/">resource page</a>.</p>
<p>Another prerequisite is passion for learning game engine development. As you are still reading this, we assume you are as excited about this as we are. This will be a bumpy ride, but you will have us on your side.</p>
<h2 id="research">Research<a href="#research" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h2>
<p>Being a student-pitched ETC project means that the project needed to pass through a pitch process of consulting and convincing faculty in the program. This allowed us to receive feedback about what could be considered a reasonable/manageable scope and where we might hit challenges for a general project. For this project to be a valid ETC project as well as accomplish our mission statement, there needs to be a fine balance between documentation and development. </p>
<p>Before confronting the big monster of engine development and documentation, we thought it would be a good idea to gear up by getting input from people who have actually done this. During our pitch process, we reached out and got the chance to talk to numerous industry professionals and got extremely helpful advice from them. All of these suggestions helped us shape our project into what it is now and provided invaluable knowledge on how to start a game engine. Thus we encourage you, too, to approach professionals and get advice if possible. We've compiled our notes from our conversations with them into a write-up, which will be published soon.</p>
<h3 id="why-another-engine">Why another engine?<a href="#why-another-engine" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>Using an existing game engine like <a href="https://unity3d.com/">Unity</a>, <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/what-is-unreal-engine-4">Unreal</a> or <a href="https://www.panda3d.org/">Panda3D</a> is always a handy option to make a game. These well-established engines have a strong collection of tools and APIs so that developers can focus on making the game, not the wheels. However, there is the limitation of not having full control over all systems in the engine as well as not knowing how the engine is processing the game logic and assets. These can obstruct the complex systems of an engine, so although you may have an understanding of how a physics or graphics engine works, each engine operates differently and optimizes for different constraints. </p>
<p>In terms of learning about game engines and how to develop one, these established engines aren't a good source. Panda3D, originally developed by Disney and expanded by past ETC projects, has an older codebase in 2018 with limited community involvement. It is also not using the current industry standard language (C++). Unity and Unreal are both too massive and too cutting-edge to be suitable engine learning material for novices. In addition, Unity's source code isn't publicly available so you technically can't learn from it. The huge codebase sets a high threshold for any beginner to get started.</p>
<h2 id="roadmap">Roadmap<a href="#roadmap" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h2>
<p>The Isetta Engine will support the most primitive form of networked multiplayer twin-stick shooter game. Networked multiplayer was selected to be a part of the engine because it offers significant design and development challenge on every level of the project, and will help differentiate this engine from others being developed. We decided to create the engine in 3D for two reasons: Most AAA engines are 3D, and 3D requires more math and problem solving for us as developers to learn and grow from.</p>
<p>While planning, and before we knew too much about game engines, we had a basic idea of what a game engine would consist of. The image below displays the second/third iteration of what the Isetta engine would look like. We were initially naive thinking we may be able to do both networking as well as physics, however quickly came to grips that would balloon the scope too much. The audio and graphics were and are still planned to be imported from external libraries, and more of the discussion of what is imported and why will be included in a future blog. This diagram of the engine will soon be replaced with more in-depth explanations.</p>
<p><img alt="alt_text" src="https://isetta.io/images/blogs/week-0/pitch_architecture.png" title="Engine Architecture During Pitch"></p>
<h3 id="genre">Genre<a href="#genre" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>As for our choice of the twin-stick shooter genre, we came to the decision after lengthy consideration of the components required to build other game types as well as how that genre would utilize multiplayer. Twin-stick shooters can effectively have little to no physics, which is different from collisions (this will be explained in <a href="https://isetta.io/blogs/week-1/">week 1 blog</a>). Likewise, the information passed between networked sessions is relatively minimal and not too strict on latency. What's more, a twin-stick shooter specializes in simplistic gameplay that doesn't need a world editor or too much design. </p>
<p>In a Skype meeting, <a href="https://waltdestler.com/">Walt Destler</a> explained to us that each game -and more particularly, each genre- requires vastly different netcode solutions. This is also one of the reasons why we prefer netcode over physics, as it can greatly narrow down the genre options. For example, multiplayer shooters, specifically PvP shooters, require small amounts of information to be passed (i.e. bullet and player locations) from server to client with relatively low latency. PvP shooters can also feature client-side prediction <sup id="fnref:0"><a href="#fn:0" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> as well as the additional requirement of lobby/matchmaking with usually more than 2 players. On the other hand, genres like turn-based strategy require large amounts of information to be passed (all units, decisions, resources, etc.) to all users without too much concern for latency or prediction.</p>
<h3 id="building-with-an-example-game">Building with an Example Game<a href="#building-with-an-example-game" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>The other piece of advice we frequently heard from professionals and our faculty alike was the benefit of developing a game in conjunction with the engine. Doing so, they explained, allows you to prove and demonstrate your engine works as expected. The game can also test features to show immediate edge cases of the engine. </p>
<p>Another nicety of developing an engine is that feature creep can be prevented when you keep expanding certain features that won't be utilized in the final product. What the game built from this engine <em>won't</em> be is something original or necessarily fun. However, that's not to say a fun, original game couldn't be created from this engine. The idea of our sample game is to intentionally be derivative so features of a basic twin-stick shooter will be already included in the engine, rather than only specific …</p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/">https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25241361</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 23:09:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Growl in Retirement]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 440 | Comments 228 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25241030">thread link</a>) | @flyingyeti
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | http://336699.org/GrowlRetirement | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://336699.org/GrowlRetirement">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="container">
  <article id="8GugXoUrk4po3a8J7EZnDS">
	<time datetime="2020-11-28">November 28, 2020</time>
  
	<p>Growl is being retired after surviving for 17 years. With the announcement of Apple’s new hardware platform, a general shift of developers to Apple’s notification system, and a lack of obvious ways to improve Growl beyond what it is and has been, we’re announcing the retirement of Growl as of today.</p>

<p>It’s been a long time coming. Growl is the project I worked on for the longest period of my open source career. However at WWDC in 2012 everyone on the team saw the writing on the wall. This was my only WWDC. This is the WWDC where Notification Center was announced. Ironically Growl was called Global Notifications Center, before I renamed it to Growl because I thought the name was too geeky. There’s even a sourceforge project for Global Notifications Center still out there if you want to go find it.</p>

<p>We’ve had a lot of support over the years; from our hosting providers at <a href="http://www.networkredux.com/">Network Redux</a>, <a href="http://www.cachefly.com/">CacheFly</a> and others, to all of the apps using our framework, bindings, or any other integration. Special thanks go to <a href="https://adium.im/">Adium</a> and <a href="https://colloquy.app/">Colloquy</a>. Without these two projects having developers who wanted different types notifications, Growl wouldn’t have existed. Without Growl I do not know that we would have any sort of decent notification system in OS X, iOS, Android or who knows what else. </p>

<p>Special thanks goes to <a href="https://www.transifex.com/">Transifex</a> who made localizing into 24 languages a lot easier than anything else we tried. It’s a fantastic product, if you make software please try it. Our localizers were fantastic people and should all be commended for their work. </p>

<p>For developers we recommend transitioning away from Growl at this point. The apps themselves are gone from the app store, however the code itself still lives. Everything from our rake build system to our code is available for use on our <a href="https://github.com/growl/growl/">GitHub page</a></p>

  <figure id="kudo_8GugXoUrk4po3a8J7EZnDS">
    <a href="#kudo">
      
    </a>
    <p>1,807</p>
    <p>Kudos</p>
  </figure>
  <figure id="kudo_side_8GugXoUrk4po3a8J7EZnDS">
    <a href="#kudo">
      
    </a>
    <p>1,807</p>
    <p>Kudos</p>
  </figure>
</article>

</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://336699.org/GrowlRetirement</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25241030</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 22:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Blogging vs. Blog Setups]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 258 | Comments 105 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25240939">thread link</a>) | @Kye
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hi, I'm Rakhim. I teach, program, make podcasts, comics and videos on computer science at <a href="https://codexpanse.com/">Codexpanse.com</a>. You can learn more about <a href="https://rakhim.org/about">my work</a> and even <a href="https://www.patreon.com/rakhim">support me</a> via Patreon.</p><p><form action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/rakhim" method="post" target="popupwindow" onsubmit="window.open('https://buttondown.email/rakhim','popupwindow')"><label for="bd-email">Oh, and I have a monthly non-spammy personal newsletter:</label><br>

</form></p><nav><p><a href="https://rakhim.org/">Home</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://blog.rakhim.org/">Blog</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/about">About</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://codexpanse.com/">Courses</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/talks">Talks</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined">Comics</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/bookshelf">Bookshelf</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/codexpanse">YT</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://twitter.com/freetonik">TW</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/index.xml">RSS</a></p></nav><p>© Rakhim Davletkaliyev, 2020<br>Powered by <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a>, <a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify and the Everett interpretation of QM.</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25240939</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 22:03:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Second Swiss firm allegedly sold encrypted spying devices]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 247 | Comments 171 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25240179">thread link</a>) | @secfirstmd
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/second-swiss-firm-allegedly-sold-encrypted-spying-devices/46186432 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/second-swiss-firm-allegedly-sold-encrypted-spying-devices/46186432">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<section>
<div>
<div>
<figure>
<picture>
<source srcset="https://www.swissinfo.ch/resource/image/46186430/landscape_ratio3x2/880/587/a683e845a8c9bdb270a5b635dfc947ed/gO/omnisec.jpg" media="(min-width: 900px)">
<source srcset="https://www.swissinfo.ch/resource/image/46186430/landscape_ratio3x2/580/387/a683e845a8c9bdb270a5b635dfc947ed/Gx/omnisec.jpg" media="(min-width: 321px)">

</picture>
<figcaption>
Omnisec is the second Swiss company that allegedly sold manipulated encryption devices to US intelligence services. <span>Keystone / Walter Bieri</span>
</figcaption> </figure>
</div>
</div><p>Swiss public television, SRF, has found a second company besides Crypto AG&nbsp;was involved in manufacturing manipulated devices allegedly used for spying by foreign intelligence.</p>
<span>This content was published on November 26, 2020 - 11:34</span>
<time datetime="2020-11-26T11:34:28+01:00">

</time><p>According to <a rel="noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.srf.ch/news/schweiz/verschluesselungsgeraete-geheimdienstaffaere-weitere-schweizer-firma-rueckt-in-den-fokus">SRF sources</a>, the Swiss company Omnisec AG had ties to US intelligence services. This follows revelations in February by SRF, German television ZDF and <em>The Washington Post</em> that Zug-based firm Crypto AG was at the heart of a huge international spying operation led by the CIA, and to a lesser extent by the German BND spy agency.&nbsp;Omnisec was one of the largest competitors of Crypto AG.</p><p>Swiss cryptologist and professor Ueli Maurer was a consultant for Omnisec for years and told SRF that in 1989 US intelligence services (National Security Agency) contacted Omnisec through him.</p><p>Of concern are the OC-500 series devices. Devices were sold to several Swiss federal agencies. However, Swiss&nbsp;authorities only noticed the devices weren't secure&nbsp;in the mid-2000s.</p><p>Several Swiss companies also received manipulated devices from Omnisec, including Switzerland’s largest bank, UBS. It is unclear whether the authorities informed UBS about the weak devices in the mid-2000s. UBS told SRF that it does not comment on security matters but that it had no indications that sensitive data were exposed at the time.</p>
<p>Omnisec, founded in 1987, manufactured voice, fax and data encryption equipment. It was dissolved a few years ago. The most recent head of the company, Clemens Kammer, told SRF that Omnisec customers “have and will continue to place great value on security, confidentiality, discretion and reliability in business relationships”.</p><p>Some politicians have called for further investigations into these latest allegations that may reveal who, if anyone, in the federal government knew of Omnisec’s business affairs with foreign intelligence.</p><h2>Crypto affair</h2><p>Earlier this month, a nine-month&nbsp;<a rel="noopener" target="_blank" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20201110183555/https:/www.parlament.ch/press-releases/Pages/mm-gpdel-2020-11-10.aspx">investigation</a>&nbsp;by the Swiss parliamentary audit committee (GPDel), found that the Swiss intelligence service knew that the US Central Intelligence Agency was behind the Swiss-based Crypto AG as far back as 1993. The report says that Swiss intelligence later collaborated with them to gather information from foreign sources.&nbsp;</p><p>More than 100 countries bought encryption devices from the Zug-based company, which did business under the guise of Swiss neutrality. In reality, the firm belonged to the CIA and Germany intelligence service, which could freely read what it encrypted. Information intercepted with the help of Crypto’s devices changed the course of events, including the Iran hostage crisis of 1979.</p> </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/second-swiss-firm-allegedly-sold-encrypted-spying-devices/46186432</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25240179</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 20:18:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[30 years later, QBasic is still the best]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 312 | Comments 131 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25239424">thread link</a>) | @ohjeez
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | http://www.nicolasbize.com/blog/30-years-later-qbasic-is-still-the-best/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.nicolasbize.com/blog/30-years-later-qbasic-is-still-the-best/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p><span><em>(5 minutes read)</em></span></p>
<p><span>My oldest son Noah turned 7 three months ago. If he could trade his family for a 2 hour session of playing minecraft, he would do it in a heartbeat. The other love of his life is Super Mario Maker, and&nbsp;it’s been a thrill to see him play the same game and levels that I played when I was his age. About 5 months ago, I left my family for my yearly pilgrimage of <a href="http://ludumdare.com/compo/">ludum dare</a>: a game dev competition during which I lock myself away with friends, return to a&nbsp;state of primitive caveman, not sleep for 48h, and create&nbsp;a full game from scratch (play it at the end of this post!) As I proudly showed my revolutionary AAA title to my wife, Noah was naturally intrigued and I introduced him to the world of code, showing him how simple&nbsp;words&nbsp;(he had just learned how to read) produced an actual game. Since&nbsp;that very day, Noah&nbsp;has been asking me repeatedly to teach him how to make&nbsp;his own video games. And for the past 5 months, I have been looking for the holy grail of language/IDE for kids in the hope of turning that spark of interest into a memorable experience…</span></p>
<p><span>My quest has led me to&nbsp;endless forums, through which I have tried countless suggestions: SmallBasic, Pico-8, Smalltalk, Scratch, etc. I have even inquired of the Great&nbsp;Oracles of StackOverflow,&nbsp;to&nbsp;no avail. After 5 months,&nbsp;I&nbsp;ended up with a disappointing conclusion: nothing is even close to what I had back in another era. 30 years later, QBasic is still the best when it comes to&nbsp;discovering programming.&nbsp;</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span>“OMG please don’t teach him GOTOs!!”</span></p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>10 PRINT “OH NO, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!!!”
20 GOTO 10</code></pre>
<p><span>Yes, QBasic is a terrible procedural language. It introduces one to concepts widely considered harmful, uses awkward syntax for implicit declarations, is not case sensitive, is non-zero-based, etc. the list goes on… When developing a skill, it is much better to acquire the right reflexes from the start rather than have to correct years of bad practice. Following this advice, I should have probably started off with&nbsp;the basics of the ruby language which I love. Yet, while most of those QBasic concepts are today generally considered&nbsp;as red flags by our peers, they each served a very specific&nbsp;purpose at the time: to keep the language simple and accessible, a notion that every other language has left behind in favor of flexibility, complexity and logic.</span></p>
<p><span>I installed QBasic on my son’s 11” HP Stream today, having to hack a DOSBox manual installation. He double clicked the icon on his desktop and in a split second, we were in the IDE, greeted with the introduction screen which brought back so many memories to my mind:</span></p>
<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/01/QBasic_Opening_Screen.png" alt="" width="640" height="400"></p>
<p><span>I then told Noah that there was a very sacred ritual, mandatory&nbsp;for anyone who enters the secret&nbsp;inner&nbsp;circle of programmers, to start off with a program that greets every other programmer out there. As I dictated the formula, he slowly&nbsp;searched for each&nbsp;key, carefully&nbsp;typing with his right finger&nbsp;the magic words: <code>PRINT “hello world”</code></span></p>
<p><span>He pressed F5 and looked amazed as he saw his code being compiled into text rendered on his black screen. He smiled, gave me a high-five, and then scribbled down the code in his little notebook so that he could remember later.</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_1.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p>We went on to a couple more commands: CLS, COLOR, PLAY, INPUT, and IF. There was nothing to explain: no complexity, no awkward operator, no abstract concepts, no documentation that needed to be read, no notion of objects/class/methods, no framework to install, no overwhelming menu/buttons in the IDE, no special keyword or parenthesis. It was code in its purest simplicity and form.</p>
<p><span>After less than an hour, he wrote his first program on his own – an interactive and incredibly subtle application which lets you know the computer’s feelings towards&nbsp;you as an individual and sensible human being:</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_3.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p><span>…which he ran with utmost pride for his cousin and best friend Christian:</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_4.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p><span>…after which he proceeded to easily explain him&nbsp;</span><span><b>how</b></span><span>&nbsp;it worked and what the code was doing!</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_5.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p><span>And so it was that in a single hour, my 7 year old was able to not only write his first text game, but also to experience the fun and thrill that comes from creating, compiling and executing his own little program. Bonus points, it all fit on a single notebook page:</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_2.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800"></p>
<p><span>I was so glad that he was able to understand why I keep saying that I have the best job in the world.&nbsp;</span><span>My only regret today was to realize that in more than 30 years, we have not been able to come up with something&nbsp;better for our kids: Qbasic has a limited set of simple keywords (the entire help fits on a single F1 screen and is packed with simple examples!), does not distract the coder with any visual artifacts, has a very confined and cosy dev environment, shows errors as early as possible, compiles and executes the code in a heartbeat with a single key, and is extremely straightforward. &nbsp;We have built more robust and more complex languages/frameworks/IDEs (which are of course necessary for any real-life application), but we have never really made a simpler or more direct access to the thrill of programming than QBasic. Even running QBasic today has become dreadful&nbsp;to the novice that uses&nbsp;a modern Mac/PC/Linux machine, whereas it used to simply require inserting a 3,5” floppy in the A:\ disk drive…</span></p>
<p><span>Enough rant, today is all about the celebration of yet another person who discovered the excitement and beauty of programming!</span></p>
<p><span>Cheers!</span></p>
<p><span>(as promised, <a href="http://nicolasbize.com/ld34/">my AAA title</a> for which I await&nbsp;EA’s call to purchase copyrights)</span></p>
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.nicolasbize.com/blog/30-years-later-qbasic-is-still-the-best/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25239424</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 18:32:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple Silicon M1: A Developer's Perspective]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 393 | Comments 485 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25238608">thread link</a>) | @steipete
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://steipete.com/posts/apple-silicon-m1-a-developer-perspective/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://steipete.com/posts/apple-silicon-m1-a-developer-perspective/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> <p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7dbf04694dfeeec9985b2ebb27cc1faff153111b/75e93/assets/img/2020/m1/m1.jpg"></p><p>The excitement around Apple’s new M1 chip is <a href="https://www.singhkays.com/blog/apple-silicon-m1-black-magic/">everywhere</a>. I bought a MacBook Air 16GB M1 to see how viable it is as main development machine - here’s an early report after a week of testing.</p><h2 id="xcode">Xcode</h2><p>Xcode runs FAST on the M1. Compiling the <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/">PSPDFKit PDF SDK</a> (debug, arm64) can almost compete with the fastest Intel-based MacBook Pro Apple offers to date, with <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332052251712614405?s=21">8:49 min vs 7:31 min</a>. For comparison, my Hackintosh builds the same in less than 5 minutes.</p><p>One can’t overstate how impressive this is for a fan-less machine. Apple’s last experiment with fan-less MacBooks was the 12-inch version from 2017, which builds the same project in 41 minutes.</p><p>Our tests mostly ran just fine, although I found <a href="https://github.com/Aloshi/dukglue/pull/27">a bug specific to arm64</a> that we missed before, as we don’t run our tests on actual hardware on CI. Moving the Simulator to the same architecture as shipping devices will be beneficial and will help find more bugs.</p><p>Testing iOS below 14 is problematic. It seems <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332654247809257473?s=21">WebKit is crashing in a memory allocator</a>, throwing EXC_BAD_INSTRUCTION (code=EXC_I386_INVOP, subcode=0x0) (Apple folks: FB8920323). Performance also seems really bad, with Xcode periodically <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332348616145563653?s=21">freezing</a> and the whole system becoming so <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332648748158246922?s=21">slow</a> that the mouse cursor gets choppy. Some Simulators even make problems on iOS 14, <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1331628274783543297?s=21">such as the iPad Air (4th gen) which still emulates Intel</a>, so try to avoid that one.</p><p>We were extremely excited to be moving our CI to Mac Mini’s with M1 chip and are <a href="https://www.macstadium.com/m1-mini">waiting on MacStadium to release devices</a>, however it seems we will have to restrict tests to iOS 14 for that to work. With our current schedule, we plan to drop iOS 12 in Q3 2021 and iOS 13 in Q3 2022, so it will be a while until we can fully move to Apple Silicon.</p><p>There is a chance that Apple fixes these issues, however it’s not something to count on - given that this only affects older versions of iOS, the problem will at some point just “go away”.</p><p><strong>Update:</strong> We’re working around the WebKit crashes for now via detecting Rosetta2 translation at runtime and simply skipping the tests where WebKit is used. This isn’t great, but luckily we’re not using WebKit a lot in our current project. <a href="https://gist.github.com/steipete/e15b1fabffc7da7d49c92e3fbd06971a">See my Gist for details</a>. Performance seems acceptable if you restrict parallel testing to at most two instances - else the system simply runs out of RAM and swapping is just really slow.</p><h2 id="docker">Docker</h2><p>We use Docker to automate our Website and load environments for our <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/pdf-sdk/web/">Web and Server PDF SDKs</a>. Docker posted a <a href="https://www.docker.com/blog/apple-silicon-m1-chips-and-docker/">status update blog post</a> about the current state of things, admitting that it currently won’t work but that they’re <a href="https://github.com/docker/roadmap/issues/142">working on it</a>. There are more <a href="https://finestructure.co/blog/2020/11/27/running-docker-on-apple-silicon-m1-follow-up">hacky ways to use Apple’s Hypervisor to run Docker container manually</a>, however this needs arm-based containers.</p><p>I expect a solution in Q1 2021 that runs arm-based containers. We’ll have to do some work to add arm-support (something already on the roadmap) so this is only a transitional issue.</p><h2 id="virtualization-and-windows">Virtualization and Windows</h2><p>To test our <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/pdf-sdk/windows/">Windows PDF SDK</a>, most folks are using a VMware virtual machine with Windows 10 and Visual Studio. Currently none of the Mac virtualisation solutions support Apple Silicon, however both <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/20/11/11/parallels-confirms-apple-m1-support-amid-silence-from-other-virtualization-companies">VMware and Parallels</a> are working on it. I do not expect Virtualbox to be updated <a href="https://forums.virtualbox.org/viewtopic.php?f=8&amp;t=98742">anytime soon</a>.</p><p>I expect that eventually we’ll be able to run ARM-based Windows with commercial tooling. Various <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/11/27/arm-windows-virtualization-m1-mac/">proof-of-concepts</a> already exist, and performance seems <a href="https://twitter.com/imbushuo/status/1332772957609922561?s=21">extremely promising</a>. Microsoft currently doesn’t sell ARM-based Windows, so getting a license will be interesting.</p><p>ARM-Windows can emulate x86 applications, and Microsoft is working on <a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/it039s-official-x64-emulation-is-coming-to-windows-on-arm">x64 emulation</a>, which is already rolling out in Insider builds. In a few months, it should be possible to develop and test our Windows SDK with Visual Studio on M1 in reasonable performance.</p><p>Running older versions of macOS might be more problematic. We currently support macOS 10.14 with our <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/blog/2017/pspdfkit-for-macos/">AppKit PDF SDK</a> and macOS 10.15 with the <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/blog/2019/pspdfkit-for-mac-catalyst/">Catalyst PDF SDK</a>, both OS releases that require testing. It remains to be seen if VMWare or Parallels include a complete x64 emulation layer. This would likely be really slow, so I wouldn’t count on it.</p><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/bbf100981357e4bc26c49722d31253daf76d293d/5b456/assets/img/2020/m1/memory.png" alt=""></p><p>Lastly, 16 GB RAM just isn’t a lot. When running parallel tests, the machine starts to heavily swap and performance really goes down the drain. This will be even more problematic with virtual machines running. Future machines will offer 32 GB options to alleviate this issue.</p><p><strong>Update:</strong> <a href="https://gist.github.com/niw/e4313b9c14e968764a52375da41b4278#file-readme-md">How to run Windows 10 on ARM in Qemu with Hypervisor.framework patches on Apple Silicon Mac</a></p><h2 id="android-studio">Android Studio</h2><p>IntelliJ is working on porting the <a href="https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/JBR-2526">JetBrains Runtime</a> to Apple Silicon. The apps currently work through Rosetta 2, however building via Gradle is <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/androiddev/comments/jx4ntt/apple_macbook_air_m1_is_very_slow_in_gradle_builds/">extremely slow</a>. Gradle creates code at runtime, which seems a particular bad combination with the Rosetta 2 ahead-of-time translation logic.</p><p>I expect that most issues will be solved by Q1 2021, however it will likely be some more time until all Java versions run great on ARM. A lot of effort has been put into <a href="https://bell-sw.com/java/arm/performance/2019/01/15/the-status-of-java-on-arm/">loop unrolling and vectorisation</a>, not everything there is available on ARM just yet.</p><p><strong>Update:</strong> <a href="https://www.azul.com/press_release/azul-announces-support-of-java-builds-of-openjdk-for-apple-silicon/">Azul offers macOS JDKs for arm64</a>, including for <a href="https://www.azul.com/downloads/zulu-community/?os=macos&amp;architecture=arm-64-bit&amp;package=jdk">Java 8</a>.</p><h2 id="homebrew">Homebrew</h2><p><a href="https://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a> currently works via Rosetta 2. Just prefix everything with <code>arch -x86_64</code> and it’ll just work. It is possible to install an additional (arm-based) version of Homebrew <a href="https://soffes.blog/homebrew-on-apple-silicon">under <code>/opt/homebrew</code></a> and mix setup, as <a href="https://github.com/Homebrew/brew/issues/7857">more and more software</a> is adding support for arm.</p><p>This is not a problem currently (performance is good) and will eventually just work natively.</p><h2 id="applications">Applications</h2><p>Most applications just work, Rosetta is barely noticeable. Larger apps to take a longer initial performance hit (e.g. Microsoft Word takes <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/microsoft-office-will-be-about-20-second-slower-initially-on-apple-silicon-rosetta-2/">around 20 seconds</a> until everything is translated), but then these binaries are cached and subsequent runs are fast.</p><p>There’s the occasional app that can’t be translated and fails on startup (e.g. <a href="https://beamer-app.com/download">Beamer</a> or the <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en_gh/drive/download/">Google Drive “Backup and Sync” client</a>), but this is rare. Some apps are confused about their place on disk and ask to be moved to the Applications directory, when really it’s just the translated binary that runs somewhere else. Most of these dialogs can be ignored. Some apps (e.g. Visual Studio Code) <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1331884524934995968?s=21">block auto-updating</a> as the translated app location is readonly. However, in case of VS Code, the Insider build is already updated to ARM and just works.</p><p>Electron-based apps are slow if they run on Rosetta. It seems the highly optimized V8 JavaScript compiler blocks ahead-of-time translation. The latest stable version of Electron (Version 11) already <a href="https://www.electronjs.org/blog/apple-silicon">fully supports Apple Silicon</a>, and companies like Slack already updated their beta version to run natively.</p><p>Google just shipped <a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/3597749/google-releases-chrome-87-with-support-for-apple-silicon-macs.html">Chrome that runs on ARM</a>, however there’s still quite a performance gap between it and Apple Safari, which just <em>flies</em> on Apple Silicon.</p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>The new M1 MacBooks are fast, beautiful and silent and the hype is absolutely justified. There’s still a lot to do on the software-front to catch up, and the bugs around older iOS Simulators are especially problematic.</p><p>All of that can be fixed in software and the whole industry is currently working on making the experience better, so by next year, when Apple updates the 16-inch MacBook Pro and releases the next generation of their M chip line, it should be absolutely possible to use a M1 Mac as main dev machine.</p><p>For the time being, the M1 will be my <del>travel</del> secondary laptop, and I’ll keep working on the 2,4 GHz 16-inch MacBook Pro with 32 GB RAM, which just is the faster machine. I’ll be much harder to accept the loud, always-on fans though, now that I know what soon will be possible.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://steipete.com/posts/apple-silicon-m1-a-developer-perspective/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25238608</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 16:47:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No Config for Old Men]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 358 | Comments 285 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25238523">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://datagubbe.se/noconf/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://datagubbe.se/noconf/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p><b>...or anyone else, for that matter.</b></p>

<p><i>Autumn 2020</i></p>

<p>Ask anyone who's really into cooking and they'll tell you how important it is to have a kitchen that's arranged just right. To someone who rarely cooks, a kitchen is probably just a place to store a few pots and a toaster, and the placement of such stuff doesn't matter much: canned soup and microwave dinners are designed for ease of preparation.</p>


<p>For the enthusiastic home cook, however, a lot of things can go wrong. Often there's only a second's notice to fix something that might ruin a perfect meal or set you back hours of hard toil. Hollandaise starting to split? Better bring out that ice cold water post haste! Garlic burning? Better chop some more right this instant, or the pasta will be overcooked and there goes the Aglio e Oglio.</p>


<p>To achieve speed, you have to know where your knives, pots, pans, spoons, whisks and other utensils are and you want to be able to arrange them so that they're easy to reach. Seasonings, spices, herbs and condiments should be within reach from the stove. Then there's the mise en place before the actual cooking begins: chopping all the vegetables, cubing the meat, slicing the bacon and so on.</p>


<p>All of this is, thankfully, easy to achieve. Even the most cramped kitchen will, after having been battle tested through a few meals, be as optimal as possible according to the cook's personal preference. The same goes for painters, carpenters, car mechanics and even office dwellers. Hammer missing from the hammer hook? For shame! Stapler not to the immediate right of the stack of post-its? Well it should be!</p>


<h3>The regulated kitchen</h3>


<p>Now imagine if you couldn't organize your kitchen to your heart's content. Not because you're lacking the funds or skills, but because some federally appointed clerk is constantly coming to inspect it.</p>


<p>"Nah," he says, adjusting his clip-on tie, "you can't put your spices there. Against regulations. All spices must be kept more than two yards from the stove at all times." He then goes on to explain that you'll have to call him every time you want to use the stove, just to make sure the pots you're using are compliance tested. Plus, they have to be stored in the government approved pot storage cabinet below the sink, otherwise they're not fit for kitchen use.</p>


<p>Want to change the color of the counter top? Sorry, no can do. Want to switch from glass bowls to stainless? Alas, you used to be able a few years ago, but nobody wants stainless anymore anyway, right? The salt <i>can</i> be put next to the stove, but it's not recommended and might change in the near future. Knives are now to be honed every Tuesday afternoon by a designated craftsman. Sure, you can postpone a few times, but eventually, you just have to live with that. Plus, there's going to be some dudes coming to inventory your pantry on a regular basis, most likely when you're in the middle of cooking something really complicated. There's no use in protesting - this is all for your own good.</p>

<p>And yes.


</p><p>Of course this is a metaphor for computers.</p>


<h3>The curious disappearance of configuration</h3>


<p>For the casual user, some of this can <i>maybe</i> be convenient - or at least not annoying. If someone who rarely uses the kitchen has decided to whip up a home cooked feast, it doesn't matter that the spices are kept strangely far from the stove: they're just happy they found them. And <i>maybe</i> there is, for the casual user, some "security" in lock-in efforts such as MacOS calling home<sup><a href="#footnote1">[1]</a></sup> to check if a program is allowed to run and that web browsers automatically block certain URLs.</p>


<p>Likewise, maybe a handful of confused beginners are helped by the fact that certain system settings are extremely hard to find, or that you're supposed to put all your photos in a specific directory, or that you can't decide what partition you want to install a program on, or that some indexing service starts running when you least expect it, or that not a single application gives a crap about the few color settings you're allowed to make.</p>


<p>For the power user, such things range from nuisances to something that seriously hampers productivity and creativity.</p>


<p>It used to be that whenever I got a new computer, I spent a day or two setting it up. I selected the fonts I wanted to use, I picked the colors I liked for window decorations and GUI elements, I installed my preferred tools and utilities and I organized the desktop icons and program launchers to my liking. It took a bit of time, but it was a labor of love. In times of trouble I was, if nothing else, at least the boss of my own desktop environment.</p>


<p>I don't know of any proprietary OS where I can do that anymore. Linux is, considering what's going on with the major distributions, desktop environments and UI toolkits, seemingly heading the same way. Sure, pick your own window manager, see if we care - we've got client side decorations! Want to theme your GUI? Yeah, but not in our Snap packages you won't! Want to turn off cursor blinking? Mmmmyyeeaahhh, not too sure about that. Oh, you started a GUI file manager? Hey, enjoy the ten new folders we've littered your home directory with! They all start with capital letters: designed for typing convenience in a case sensitive file system.</p>


<p>Of course I still spend a fair amount of time setting up a Windows machine, but these days it's not the joyful experience of configuring the best fonts and nicest colors and arranging the icons on the start menu in the correct order for my muscle memory. Instead it's usually a week of swearing over removed settings and working hard to find the ones that actually remain, or trying various registry hacks to circumvent seemingly unchangeable defaults. I'm working against the system instead of with it, and someone else is trying to boss me around.</p>


<h3>A better example</h3>


<p>All of this could be different. It used to be. On my <a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/">Amiga</a>, I could configure <i>everything</i>. Apart from things like fonts and colors I could draw my own mouse pointer, tiling desktop backgrounds and icons. (Yes, the system really shipped with separate little paint programs just for pointers, desktop tiles and icons.) I could customize double click speed and key repeat rates on millisecond levels. I could even control the exact position of individual icons and the size and position of every individual directory window opened.</p>


<p>Most casual users didn't care about all that, but they didn't have to. The system came with a reasonable set of defaults and when or if they grew more proficient and wanted to change something about their daily working environment, they had the option to do so.</p>


<p>This was a great approach to users. Instead of being treated like an incompetent moron and placed in a walled garden, you were entrusted and empowered. Something as simple as drawing my own mouse pointer on the Amiga was a profound and formative experience for me. As corny as it sounds, it was as if the guys who built this amazing machine put it in my hands and said, "Hey kid, you're in charge. This computer is yours. Learn how to use it and you can make it do anything." It was a call for exploration and creativity.</p>


<p>Today, I can't even change the system font in Windows. I can select an "accent color", but most applications completely ignore it. Every program defaults to downloading into a Downloads folder and I've lost count of how many times I've changed its folder view from grouped to not grouped, only to discover it's been magically changed back the next time I browse it. Lots of settings have been removed completely while others are buried deep in strange places where a user clearly isn't really supposed to venture.</p>


<p>The problem is that there's no toggle for enabling "advanced mode". I'm just supposed to accept that I can no longer change simple things I've been able to configure for the past thirty years. Someone, somewhere just decided that all users have the same basic skill level and that the defaults are always acceptable.</p>


<h3>General purpose Instagram cameras</h3>


<p>I suppose the lack of configurability is a metaphor for personal computing in general: we're not buying our machines, we're renting them by way of bizarrely complex EULA:s for everything from the firmware to the OS and we're not supposed to be curious or creative, we're supposed to sit back and passively consume advertisements. The base level of creative computer use is no longer exploring programming or graphics or music, but photographing a meal someone else has prepared and then applying a predefined sepia filter to said photo. The base level of configuring a system is no longer picking some personal favorites among fonts and colors, but - maybe - selecting between dark and light mode.</p>


<p>
On the flip side, more and more people also need to use computers 
for actually producing stuff - not least programming all those ad 
delivery platforms and the curiously unconfigurable operating systems 
they run on. But there are also armies of innocents; office workers,
administrators, hotel clerks, librarians, teachers - those people now often 
have no choice but to strain their eyes staring at black text on bright 
white backgrounds, unable to select a font they find easier to read.
</p>

<p>Too bad they can no longer store their spices close to the stove, but hey, who cares? Let them take one for the team. We're all swimming in ad revenue and if people learn to configure things, maybe they'll suddenly realize that the presence of those ads should be configurable as well.</p>

<br>

<hr>



<p id="footnote1">
<sup>1</sup> In case my sarcasm isn't coming through here: No, it's not secure. The privacy and security problems this entails are huge.
</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://datagubbe.se/noconf/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25238523</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 16:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Is Probability Real?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 215 | Comments 191 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25237356">thread link</a>) | @EbTech
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Today, I want to address an issue with statements involving chance. To demonstrate, let’s first consider a statement that doesn’t involve chance:</p>

<p>“<em>A cubic die tossed onto a flat surface will come to rest on one of its six sides.</em>”</p>

<p>This claim can be empirically tested, with various dice and surfaces. If any one of our experiments results in the die spinning endlessly on a corner, we will have disproven the claim. We may have to refine the claim’s conditions; for instance, by requiring the presence of gravity. Nonetheless, it’s fairly clear what it means for the statement to be true or false. Now let’s try to make a claim involving probability:</p>

<p>“<em>If a pair of standard dice are thrown, the probability of their face-up sides summing to nine will be one in nine (about 0.11 or 11%).</em>”</p>

<p>What does it mean for this statement to be true? Unlike the first statement, this one doesn’t specify which result we’ll actually see. How can we possibly hope to test it, or to make use of its information?</p>



<p>Within the realm of abstract mathematics, we’re free to model probability in a way that fits our intuitions. Imagine a multiverse containing an infinity of possible worlds, whose total <em>measure</em> is 100%. Define the probability of an <em>event</em>, such as that of rolling a nine, to be the measure assigned to the subset of worlds in which the event actually occurs.</p>

<p>In the abstract formalism, we’re allowed to assign the measure however we like, subject to Kolmogorov’s axioms: the measure must be non-negative, countably additive, and total to 100%. By respecting the symmetry of an idealized die,<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup> we might argue that only one such assignment makes sense; from it, we can calculate the probability of any event involving dice rolls.</p>

<p>There are two shortcomings to this approach. Firstly, we won’t always deal with nicely symmetrical objects for which direct a priori arguments are possible. Thus, we still need a means of testing probabilistic claims using real-life observations. Secondly, such arguments can never be airtight: after all, how can we hope to infer the measure on a hypothetical multiverse, when we only ever experience <em>one</em> world? Indeed, a realist might question if it makes any sense to discuss the chances of an event happening: either it happens or it doesn’t!</p>



<p>You might be more trusting of someone who puts their money where their mouth is. To back up a definite claim, not involving chance, I can simply agree to pay a penalty if it turns out I’m wrong.</p>

<p>This idea can be extended to probabilistic claims in the following manner: consider a lottery that pays a $90 jackpot if the next roll of a pair of dice yields a nine. If the maximum that I’m willing to pay to play is $10, this indicates that I believe a not-nine roll is eight times more likely than a nine roll. This approach is appealing because, after all, the <em>raison d’être</em> of probability theory is to explain the decision-making of individuals facing uncertainty.</p>

<p>If another gambler’s view conflicts with mine, you may aggregate our beliefs by creating a market on which we buy and sell predictions. Consider a contract that pays $100 (plus interest) when a specified event occurs. Its price on the market can be interpreted as the percentage probability of that event. Thus, to say an event is twice as “likely” as another, simply means its market price is double.</p>

<p>Unlike your typical gambler, a frictionless market offers transparent near-identical buy and sell prices. As a result, any violations of Kolmogorov’s axioms become money-making arbitrage opportunities. Arbitrage activity acts as an enforcer of the axioms, creating what economists call the <em>risk-neutral probability measure</em>.</p>

<p>In real markets, however, this probability measure exhibits several inconsistenties. Firstly, it depends on which currency is used: as an extreme example, we wouldn’t buy a dollar-denominated wager that only pays out if the dollar collapses, no matter how likely we imagine the collapse to be. Secondly, this measure is sensitive to (non-diversifiable) risk: if a widely-believed prophecy held that rolling a nine would induce a catastrophic famine, the market would value this outcome a lot more, because everyone wants to buy insurance against such a catastrophe. Thirdly, markets can be misinformed: indeed, one motivation for participating in a market is to try to beat it! And finally, liquid markets are hard to set up.</p>

<p>For these reasons, we abandon this approach. We’ll seek to define probability in terms of actual outcomes instead of human bets. Nonetheless, human bets are what inspired the creation of probability theory: it’s hard to think of any other practical application! Therefore, we should remember to revisit the matter once we’ve found an appealing probability concept. Ultimately, we must be able to explain <em>how</em> individuals and markets behave with respect to our concept, and answer <em>why</em> they should care about it at all.</p>

<p>These questions are incredibly subtle: the theory of evolution by natural selection tells us that individuals are wired to use strategies that enabled their ancestors’ survival; however, the nature of probabilistic beliefs is that a wide range of outcomes are plausible. Indeed, while a coin will always land heads or tails, it’s considered unwise to bet your life savings on either heads or tails. Intuitively speaking, the rationale is that you’re almost certain to lose <em>eventually</em>, if you keep playing this way. This idea of repeated trials inspires our next interpretation, which happens to be the most popular among scientists.</p>



<p>According to the frequentist school of thought, a probabilistic statement is not to be taken literally. Although it refers to a single event, the statement should be taken as shorthand for a claim involving a very large collection of similar events. Imagine rolling the dice over and over. The probabilistic claim that we started with is converted into the following:</p>

<p>“<em>If a pair of standard dice are thrown repeatedly, then in the limit as the number of throws goes to infinity, the proportion of nines converges to one in nine (about 0.11 or 11%).</em>”</p>

<p>The short-run probability is replaced by a long-run proportion. Given an infinite sequence of rolls, this statement unambiguously reveals itself to be true or false. In light of the frequentist interpretation, we can even make more sense of our earlier interpretations. While we only experience one world, repeating an experiment under similar conditions is like observing the experiment in a parallel universe: whether we count trials or worlds, the math is virtually identical. In the limit of infinitely many bets, we can make some unambiguous conclusions about the quality of a gambler’s strategy, too: this is how casinos ensure that the house always wins!</p>

<p>Testing our claim is a simple matter: we roll the dice, over and over, and over and over… infinity times. Oops. Of course, there is no such thing as an experiment with infinity trials. Our arms will get tired, the dice will wear out, the Sun will explode, and all the free energy in the universe will be consumed. At best, we can do a very large number of trials. Let’s say we roll dice 9,000 times; one in nine of these would be 1,000. Perhaps we won’t roll exactly 1,000 nines, so let’s interpret our claim with a suitable margin of error, called a <em>confidence interval</em>:</p>

<p>“<em>If a pair of standard dice are thrown 9,000 times, then the face-up sides will sum to nine for between 920 and 1,080 of the throws.</em>”</p>

<p>The probability of obtaining between 920 and 1,080 nines can be calculated to be 99.3%.<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup> Thus, we’ve turned a probabilitic statement into a much more certain but still probabilistic statement. If we observe 1,100 nines, we should be able to dismiss the probabilistic claim as false. And yet, if every household on Earth were to independently perform this 9,000-throw experiment, we should expect that a great many of their results would fall outside the confidence interval. They would disagree on the truth of our statement!</p>

<p>There’s no getting around it: despite its intuitive appeal, the frequentist definition of probability is circular, reducing probability claims to probability claims.<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup> To end the cycle, the frequentist chooses a threshold (say, 99%) beyond which to treat events as objective truths. This grants the claim an empirically observable meaning. And yet, the frequentist must take care not to consider too many such events, for otherwise the probability of <em>at least one</em> of the events failing may ALSO exceed the threshold of certainty: a logical contradiction.</p>

<p>Things only work out nicely in the limit of infinite sample size. Statisticians mainly deal with experiments which can be repeated so many times that, for most practical purposes, their conclusions can be treated as definite. Non-philosophers are usually happy to ignore a sub-1% chance of error; and if that’s not good enough, make it 0.0001%! Confidence can be increased by gathering more data, i.e., increasing the sample size.</p>

<p>This approach turns out to be very powerful. By designing more complex hypotheses in which probabilities vary as a function of context variables, even some phenomena that aren’t easily repeatable can be statistically analyzed. For example, weather forecasts are based on well-tested models that use measurements of variables such as temperature, pressure, humidity, and wind.</p>

<p>On the other hand, statistical models of sports games, democratic elections, or company stocks tend to be less testable: the interactions are very complex and there are too few outcomes from which to extrapolate. Similarly, when you try to predict which colleges will admit you or which of your friends will start a business, you don’t make your case using repeatable tests. Clearly, the frequentist interpretation cannot apply. One may argue that no conclusions in these cases would hold up to a scientific standard; nonetheless, if we seek a theory of decision-making under uncertainty, there’s no …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability">https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25237356</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 13:23:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What were these Roman objects used for?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25237271">thread link</a>) | @jd115
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
<p><strong>DECODING THE DRUIDIC DODECAHEDRON </strong></p>

<p><img src="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/OrgImages/Dodecahedron/Dodecahedron%20Types.jpg" width="900" height="438"></p>
<p><strong>These bronze artefacts are so-called <em>Roman</em> dodecahedra (plural of dodecahedron)  of which about 120 have been found in the Celtic countries of Europe. Strangely, none of these have been found in Italy, home turf of the Romans.</strong> <strong>To the left is seen a dodecahedron from the Römermuseum Schwarzenacker, Homburg, Germany collection. To the right is seen another pristine example from the Hunt Museum in Limerick Ireland </strong></p>

<p><img src="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/OrgImages/Dodecahedron/Dodecahedron%20Types3.jpg" width="935" height="438"></p>
<p><strong>To the left is a dodecahedron from Archaeological  Service Canton Aargau, Brugg, Switzerland (Vindonissa Museum). To the right is a dodecahedron from the Gallo-Roman Museum, Tongeren, Belgium. </strong></p>
<p>The basic design of these artefacts remains relatively constant (12 pentagonal faces with knop-shaped legs), however, there can be a range of different  incised designs in the layout of the faces<strong>. </strong></p>
<p>The actual function of these artefacts cannot be explained by our historians or archaeologists, although many theories abound,  none of which seem particularly convincing. Also, there is no  mention of these items in old historical records of the Romans or those of anyone else for that matter. They are such an enigma that academics have pretty-much come to the defeatist conclusion that <em><strong>"we will never know what these dodecahedrons were used for". </strong></em></p>
<p>In reviewing the academic literature, one begins to see why the mystery will probably never be solved within that community. Here are some of the impediments and pitfalls our experts create for themselves:</p>
<p>All archaeological measurements are given in metric increments (centimetres or millimetres), which is a modern system that was created as much as 2000-years after some of these dodecahedra were cast in bronze. Earlier exemplars in stone or wood could predate the latter, more refined ones, by yet another thousand years or more. This  metric measurement preoccupation renders the  encoded numbers invisible or unrecognisable. Our academics know a large swathe of the ancient measurements that were in use two thousand years ago or before, so why not apply them to this study? </p>
<p>Most assuredly, the various sized holes in the 12-faces, the concentric circles that circumnavigate them, as well as the additional incised lines or dotted circles, etc, infer that there is something vividly measurable going on and it's evident that each hole or ring  has been very purposely fabricated to represent a known, precise and sought-after measurement.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/OrgImages/Dodecahedron/Calibrated.jpg" width="900" height="476"> </p>
<p><strong>A number of dodecahedra have calibration marks along their edges or around the holes in their faces. To the left is seen a calibrated dodecahedron from Hereford Museum, Kenchester and to the right is seen another from Goodrich Castle. Yet another one found in Wales shows etched calibration marks. </strong></p>
<p>In their reports,  archaeologists will often round out measurements of the holes in the dodecahedron faces to the nearest millimetre only, which is grossly insufficient. It's much appreciated by researchers when measurements can be supplied to 1/10th  of a millimetre, but  it is nigh on impossible  to acquire more refined measurements undertaken with electronic vernier callipers. Precise measurements and scaling must precede any serious analysis of these artefacts, but our experts don't seem to think there would be anything significant to find anyway, so don't subject the dodecahedra to rigorous measurement analysis.</p>
<p>Despite the fact that 25.4 millimetres (1 British Standard Inch) or fraction expressions of the same will recur repeatedly in the faces of dodecahedra, no-one seems to have arrived at the conclusion that the enigmatic<em><strong> "inch"</strong></em> recurrence is worthy of serious investigation. </p>
<p>Almost anything considered high-art, technically advanced or an engineering feat within ancient European civilisations seems to be automatically attributed to the Romans, which is certainly the case for these dodecahedra artefacts. This  is a hangover of biased, classicist-isolationist historical  interpretations of  European history where, first came the  Roman conquerors, who finally retreated after centuries of domination, only to be replaced by Rome's State church. With the pedigree of the church being Greco-Roman it was in their interests to push the concept that the Roman armies had found everything in the regions they invaded to be backwards, rudimentary or crude until Rome delivered the great-unwashed masses out of their depravity and into  enlightenment and high-civilisation. </p>
<p>This general process of misattribution further hobbles or seriously limits proper investigation into the purpose and function of dodecahedra artefacts, inasmuch as focus is  directed, almost exclusively, to what Roman armies might have used them for as range-finders or other battle related paraphernalia, including club-heads. The druids or others don't get  any serious consideration, despite the fact that they are historically recorded as having been  advanced mathematicians and astronomers.</p>
<p>Within controlled academia the ability to do open-ended, ground-breaking research can be severely curtailed by the requirements of <em><strong>"peer review"</strong></em> by colleagues.  This is largely a racket that ensures one doesn't move too far from the protected consensus opinion upon which academic reputations are built and anyone venturing too far out into left field is considered a maverick who threatens the insulated central body.</p>
<p>By the same token academia, these days, is lumbered with deep-set social responsibilities and crippling political agendas. When it comes to European history, especially, the requirement is to be self-effacing, while lauding and applauding the (often meager) accomplishments of other ethnicities. Under  guises of political correctness and racial sensitivity, the door is opened for antagonistic non-European, prejudiced individuals, to write and interpret  our history for us, while pushing their own  cultural-Marxist or similar wheel-barrows.  All one has to do is sit through lectures in our western universities to see just how far out of kilter the abysmal problem of  European history-misrepresentation has become.</p>
<p>But, with regards to the dodecahedra artefacts,what one person can build, another can generally duplicate or back-engineer, sufficient to make sense of what's going on. </p>
<p>So, let's cut to the chase, bypass all the  confusion of modern-day naysayers and source testimony directly from an observer who lived contemporary to the druids, before they fell under Roman domination </p>
<p>Julius Caesar, who was a very thorough historian, writes the       following regarding the late era druids of his time (circa 55 BC) and        practices within their many universities in Britain, where students from Gaul       and elsewhere, including Rome, went for training:</p>
<p><strong>'They hold aloof from war and do not pay war taxes; they       are excused from military service and exempt from all liabilities. Tempted       by these great advantages, many young men assemble of their own motion to       receive their training, many are sent by parents and relatives. Report says       that in the schools of the Druids they learn by heart a great number of verses,       and therefore some persons remain twenty years under training'. </strong></p>
<p><strong>'They do not think it proper to commit these utterances to       writing, although in all other matters and in their public and private accounts       they make use of Greek characters. I believe that they have adopted the practice       for two reasons- that they do not wish the rule to become common property,       nor those who learn the rule to rely on writing and so neglect the cultivation       of memory; and, in fact, it does usually happen that the assistance of writing       tends to relax the diligence of the student and the action of memory...They       also lecture on the stars in their motion, the magnitude       of the Earth and its divisions, on natural history, on the power and       government of God; and instruct the youth in these subjects' <em>(see De Ballo       Gallico, VII, 15, 16.).</em></strong></p>
<p>Historian, Isabel Hill Elder  writes, <strong>'The students at these       colleges numbered at times sixty thousand of the youth and young nobility       of Britain and Gaul. Caesar comments on the fact that the Gauls sent their       youth to Britain to be educated...It required twenty years to master the complete       circle of Druidic knowledge. Natural philosophy, astronomy,       mathematics, geometry, medicine, jurisprudence, poetry and oratory       were all proposed and taught-natural philosophy and       astronomy with severe exactitude' (Elder refers to <em>Strabo I IV,       page 197. Caesars Comm. Lib V. Sueotonius, V Calegula. E. Campion, Accounts       of Ireland, pg. 18.).</em></strong></p>
<p>Isabel Hill Elder further writes,<strong> 'The education system       adopted by the Druids is traced to about 1800 BC when Hu Gardarn Hysicion       (Isaacson), or Hu the Mighty, led the first colony of Cymri into Britain from       Defrobane, where Constantinople now stands'.</strong> </p>
<p>Further commenting on Hu       Gardarn Hysicion, Isabel Hill Elder writes that he, <strong>'is commemorated in       Welsh archaeology as having made poetry the vehicle of memory'.</strong> Elsewhere       she writes, he <strong>'is said to have mnemonically systematized the wisdom of       the ancients...'.</strong> She goes on to say,<strong> 'The published compositions of       the Druids and Bards form but a very small portion of the extant remains of       their works. The Myvyrian MSS. alone, now in the British Museum, amount to       47 volumes of poetry, in 1600 pages, besides about 2000 epigrammatic stanzas.       Also in the same collection are 53 volumes of prose, in about 15,300 pages,       containing many curious documents on various subjects...' <em>(see Celt, Druid       and Culdee, pages 54 &amp; 55).</em></strong></p>
<p>With the testimony of Julius Caesar ringing in our ears, lets see how the druids would have used the dodecahedron artefacts as <em><strong>"memory"</strong></em>devices for mathematically encoding astronomical cycles,<em><strong> ("the stars in their motion")</strong></em>, navigation systems <em><strong>("the …</strong></em></p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html">http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25237271</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 13:03:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Generalized f-Mean]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25236328">thread link</a>) | @goldenkey
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://churchofthought.org/blog/2017/03/26/the-generalized-mean-an-algorithmic-approach/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://churchofthought.org/blog/2017/03/26/the-generalized-mean-an-algorithmic-approach/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			<p>In school, we are first taught the arithmetic mean, then later the geometric mean, and maybe one or two others like the harmonic/contraharmonic mean.</p>
<p>But most teachers do not teach the logic or derivation behind these means. They merely provide the formulas and perhaps provide some scenarios where each mean would be more useful than the others.</p>
<p>I’d like to illustrate the definition of a mean, in the most abstract sense, from a programmer’s perspective, an algorithmic point of view.</p>
<h2>A Balancing Act</h2>
<hr>
<p>Suppose we have a list of N numbers, and a binary operation $f(a,b)$</p>
<p>If we apply that binary operation to one number from the list, we must&nbsp;apply its inverse operation to another number from the list.</p>
<p>We can continue applying $f$ to one element then $f^{-1}$ to another element as many times as we need to, until every number in the list is equal. That number that all elements are equal to…is the mean!</p>
<p>Means are just balancing acts!</p>
<p>** I am aware we haven’t specified the most&nbsp;optimized way to perform this algorithm to ensure it halts.</p>

<h2>Example</h2>
<hr>
<p>let our list be $(2,4,6)$ and our $f(a,b)=a+b$</p>
<p>then we apply the operation and its inverse to two elements respectively:</p>
<p>$(f(2,2), 4 ,f^{-1}(6,2)) = (2+2, 4 ,6-2) =&nbsp;(4,4,4)$</p>
<p>So our mean is 4.&nbsp;We just performed the&nbsp;<em>arithmetic mean</em>!</p>

<h2>What is it good for?</h2>
<hr>
<p>Well, given ANY invertible&nbsp;symmetric binary function, we can define a mean and derive its “shortcut” formula!</p>
<p>Here are the functions that define the means we usually come across:</p>
<p>arithmetic mean: $f(a,b) = a+b$<br>
geometric mean: $f(a,b) = ab$<br>
geometric mean (alternative definition): $f(a,b) = ln(a) + ln(b)$<br>
harmonic mean: $f(a,b) = 1/(1/a + 1/b)$</p>

<h2>Favoring Large or Small Numbers</h2>
<hr>
<p>Now, most of us learn that geometric mean tends to favor smaller&nbsp;numbers.</p>
<p>For example, the arithmetic mean of 1&nbsp;and 100 is $50\frac{1}{2}$. But the geometric mean of 1 and 100 is 10.</p>
<p>Knowing what we do now, can we create a mean that favors smaller numbers&nbsp;even more?</p>
<p>I don’t know if these already exist in the formal mathematics universe, ie. books or published papers. So let me know if you find a previous name for them!</p>
<p>Franken-mean: $f(a,b) = a^b b^a$</p>
<p>Franken-mean v2: $f(a,b) = a^b + b^a$</p>
<p>You might ask if we can skew our mean toward smaller numbers&nbsp;even more than our above exponential mean. We sure can. Using something called Tetration, simply put – it is iterated exponentiation. There are even operations that encompass iterated tetration and so on…these kind of operations are called&nbsp;hyperoperations. So we can make a mean skewed toward lows or highs as much as we want, and it’s beautiful isn’t it? Before different means are taught, the theory of what defines a mean should really be taught.</p>
<p>But before I forget,&nbsp;you must be saying: “Where’s my shortcut formulas?!!”</p>
<p>Okay okay.</p>

<h2>Deriving the Closed Formulas</h2>
<hr>
<p>Let’s derive the arithmetic mean first. Assume we have a list of 4 elements, ${x,y,z,t}$</p>
<p>Given the binary symmetric&nbsp;function that defines the arithmetic mean $f(a,b)=a+b$,</p>
<p>we let $g(a) = f(a,f(a,f(a,a))) = a + a + a + a = 4a$</p>
<p>Our formula for the mean of the 4 numbers in our list will be:</p>
<p>$g^{-1}(f(x,f(y,f(z,t))))$</p>
<p>We know $g(a) = 4a$, so $g^{-1}(a) = a/4$</p>
<p>That means our mean is $(x+y+z+t)/4$, which is what we expected from the arithmetic mean</p>
<p>Above was just a demonstration for a fixed size list of 4 elements. The concept is the same for any sized list. We can use induction to extrapolate what the formula will be for a list of n&nbsp;elements, $(x+y+z+t…….+w)/n$</p>

<h2>Mathematica code for the generalized mean</h2>
<hr>
<pre id=""><code>GeneralizedMean[l_List, f_Function] := (
InverseFunction[
(Fold[f, ConstantArray[#, Length[l]]]) &amp;
] [Fold[f, l]]
);
</code></pre>
<ul>
<li>Arithmetic Mean
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x,y,z,t},(#+#2)&amp;]
Out= 1/4 (t+x+y+z)</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Geometric Mean
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x, y, z, t}, (#*#2) &amp;]
Out= (t x y z)^(1/4)
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Harmonic Mean
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x, y, z, t}, (1/(1/# + 1/#2)) &amp;]
Out= 4/(1/t + 1/x + 1/y + 1/z)
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Franken Mean v1
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x, y}, (#^#2 * #2^#) &amp;]
Out= Log[x^y y^x]/(2 ProductLog[1/2 Log[x^y y^x]])
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I had to use 2 variables for the above, because Mathematica’s symbolic inverses aren’t strong enough.<br>
Franken Mean v2 does not even compute with symbolics or even numbers.<br>
I will eventually work on this to hopefully get at least numerics to work nomatter what.</p>
<h2>Alternative Implementation</h2>
<hr>
<p>This is an alternative implementation which seems to yield better results in some cases:</p>
<pre id=""><code>GeneralizedMean[l_List, f_Function] := (
Module[{x},
Solve[Fold[f, l] == Fold[f, ConstantArray[x, Length[l]]], x][[-1,
1, 2]]
]);
</code></pre>

<h2>Create your own means!</h2>
<hr>
<p>Enjoy creating your own means! Number theoretic means on lists of primes and that sort of stuff should be very interesting to explore, cheers!</p>
<h3><strong>Continued in:</strong></h3>

<h3><a href="https://churchofthought.org/means-of-infinite-sets-and-more/"><strong>Part Two: Means of Infinite Sets</strong></a></h3>
<p><em>P.S.</em></p>
<p>Kolmogorov actually did something similar and came up with what’s called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quasi-arithmetic_mean">Generalized f-mean</a></p>
<p>But he restricted his construct to only functions of the form $f(a,b) = g(a) + g(b)$, where g is the function that determines the mean and is to be specified.</p>


		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://churchofthought.org/blog/2017/03/26/the-generalized-mean-an-algorithmic-approach/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25236328</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 08:51:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
