<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 08:27:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 08:27:23 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Guide to OOMKill Alerting in Kubernetes Clusters]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25192733">thread link</a>) | @draganm
<br/>
November 23, 2020 | https://www.netice9.com/blog/guide-to-oomkill-alerting-in-kubernetes-clusters | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.netice9.com/blog/guide-to-oomkill-alerting-in-kubernetes-clusters">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>   <span>Monday 23 Nov 2020, 18:30</span> <h2>Intro</h2> <p>RAM is most likely the scarcest resource that is first exhausted on your servers. If you’re serious about running software under Linux/Unix, you’re certainly aware of what an OOMKill is.</p> <p>Short refresher: when a program requests a new memory page from the kernel two things can happen.</p> <ul><li>There is a free memory page: The kernel page assigns the page to the process and everything is great.</li> <li>The system is Out Of Memory (OOM): The kernel chooses a process based on its ‘badness’ (mainly by how much ram it uses). It sends a SIGKILL to the process. This forces the receiving process to exit with exit code <code>137</code>. All the memory pages belonging to that process are free and now the kernel can fulfill the memory request.</li></ul> <p>Lately, I had a task to add alerting to a sizeable Kubernetes cluster. The cluster has ~100 active Deployments with autoscaling of nodes up to ~50 nodes at peak times. The cluster is well maintained and has a robust autoscaling strategy. All deployments have resource limits defined. Sometimes, some of the deployed pods would breach the memory limits. In those cases, it would be nice to find out when that happens and investigate the cause of it.</p> <p>Prometheus and Alertmanager were already deployed. So I’ve thought that alerting on OOMKills will be as easy. I just had to find the right metric(s) indicating that OOMKill has happened and write an alerting rule for it. Given the length of this post, you could imagine how wrong I was!</p> <h2>First Attempt</h2> <p>A brief Google search has led me to the <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kube-state-metrics/blob/master/docs/pod-metrics.md" rel="nofollow">kube pod state metric</a>. It turns out it has a metric called <code>kube_pod_container_status_last_terminated_reason</code>. The value of the metric is <code>1</code> when a container in a pod has terminated with an error. Based on the exit code, the <code>reason</code> label will be set to <code>OOMKilled</code> if the exit code was <code>137</code>. That sounded promising! So I’ve created an alert for that.</p> <p>As usual, things are rarely straightforward. As soon as the container restarts, the value of this metric will be <code>1</code>. For alerting purposes, one has to combine it with another metric that will change when a pod restarts. <code>kube_pod_container_status_restarts_total</code> does that. Combine the two - and Bingo! It Worked!</p> <h2>“Invisible” OOMKills</h2> <p>For a brief moment, I’ve thought that I was done. I was about to declare victory over OOMKills in production! But then a puzzle came my way: One of our software developers has come forward. He claimed that one of his pods was running out of memory and he couldn’t see any alerts for it.</p> <p>At first, I wasn’t inclined to believe that his diagnosis of running out of memory was correct. Mainly because his Pod didn’t even restart! But then I looked at the graph of the memory use of the Pod. It did show the usual pattern: Memory usage would grow, reach its peak at the memory limit, and then suddenly drop.</p> <p>I’ve asked the developer for the gory details of the implementation. It turned out that the init process in the container would start a child process and wait for the result of it. If the child process would exit with an error, it would return an error to the requester and not terminate (because - why should it?).</p> <p>That is when it dawned to me - my alerting is effective only if container exits. This is usually the case when the init process of the container is OOMKilled. But there is no guarantee this will happen if a child of the init is OOMKilled. In the case where the container’s init tries to handle OOMKill by itself, my alerting is not triggering!</p> <h2>Trying the Existing Solutions</h2> <p>Given that OOMKills are as old as Unix, I thought: surely someone will have a solution for this already.</p> <p>I’ve ensued onto a frantic search for some kind of metric exporter for this. I just needed the number of OOMKill events in a pod, or at least in a Docker container. Here is what I’ve found:</p> <h3>cAdvisor</h3> <p>My first stop was cAdvisor itself. It turns out that cAdvisor is <a href="https://github.com/google/cadvisor/issues/1837" rel="nofollow">getting the OOMKill events, but not exporting them as a Prometheus metric and no one really seems to care.</a> So that was a dead-end.</p> <h3>kubernetes-oomkill-exporter</h3> <p>My second stop was <a href="https://github.com/sapcc/kubernetes-oomkill-exporter" rel="nofollow">kubernetes-oomkill-exporter</a>. A very promising-sounding project with two huge disadvantages:</p> <ul><li>There is really no documentation for it, literally anywhere.</li> <li>It does not work.</li></ul> <p>I’ve tried the latest version of <a href="https://hub.docker.com/layers/sapcc/kubernetes-oomkill-exporter/0.3.0/images/sha256-b80875b903635f0336ea0b122b332e086da51ec5cd797de5d682dd14c3910b9f?context=explore" rel="nofollow">the Docker image</a>, but once started it crashes and burns with:</p> <pre><code>standard_init_linux.go:211: exec user process caused "no such file or directory"</code></pre> <p>Going <a href="https://hub.docker.com/layers/sapcc/kubernetes-oomkill-exporter/0.2.0/images/sha256-5e1b57f4ac0b57406ef067da3e83f743d70ff89aa1db717d41af2c699dc12f3a?context=explore" rel="nofollow">back one minor version</a> one gets the following output:</p> <pre><code>F1120 22:04:21.571246       1 main.go:73] Could not create log watcher
I1120 22:04:21.572066       1 main.go:64] Starting prometheus metrics</code></pre> <p>As it seems no one has committed any code to in over a year. It has a low number of stars (14). All that meant that I was back to square one.</p> <h2>Rolling my Own: <code>missing-container-metrics</code></h2> <p>Having a hard time finding an existing solution meant only one thing: I will have to write my own.</p> <p>A cursory look at <a href="https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/events/" rel="nofollow">Docker’s events</a> delivered everything I needed. There is an event called <code>oom</code>. Docker emits this event every time the OOMKiller process gets active in the container. Now I was only missing a piece of code that will listen to those events and export them as Prometheus metrics.</p> <p>This is how <a href="https://github.com/draganm/missing-container-metrics" rel="nofollow">missing-container-metrics</a> was born. What it does is to connect to a local Docker instance (via <code>/var/run/docker.sock</code>). It lists all existing containers as a starting point. And then it listens to Docker events. Using those events, it keeps track of the currently running containers. It also gathers the basic stats of each container it knows about:</p> <ul><li>Number of restarts</li> <li>Last exit code</li> <li>Number of OOMKills</li></ul> <p>By design, it is not Kubernetes specific. This means it can be used with a plain Docker. But it also has a couple of very convenient Kubernetes specific features.</p> <p>Whenever it finds a container label for the pod name or namespace, it adds them as a label to the exported metrics. Also, label naming is compatible with <code>kube-state-metrics</code>.</p> <p>This keeps things simple for metric joins in PromQL.</p> <h2>Running it in the Cluster</h2> <p>In a Kubernetes cluster, <code>missing-container-metrics</code> needs to run on every node. The simplest way to achieve this is to use a daemon-set. The source code comes with an example <a href="https://github.com/draganm/missing-container-metrics#kubernetes" rel="nofollow">daemon set</a> deployment.</p> <h2>An Interesting Find Using <code>missing-container-metrics</code></h2> <p>The most interesting issue I’ve found was where I’ve least expected it: Fluentd!</p> <p>Fluentd log forwarder for node/pod/kubelet logs to the log aggregator. When the volume of logs was very high, Fluentd is OOMKilled.</p> <p>Looking at the details of how Fluentd works, it becomes clear what is going on.</p> <p>Fluentd has one main process (that ends up being init process in the container). This main process forks a worker process that forwards the logs. When the worker process dies for some reason (for example OOMKill), the main process starts a new one. This leads to an endless loop of spawn/OOMKill.</p> <p>The fact that Fluentd is the log forwarder is very unfortunate. OOMKill loop would stop the log forwarding, so you could not ‘see’ what is going on by inspecting the logs.</p> <h2>Epilogue</h2> <p>If you want to make sure that your Kubernetes cluster is healthy, it is essential to alert on OOMKills. This enables you to know when processes hit their memory limits. Be it because of memory leaks or wrongly configured memory limits.</p> <p>It turns out that monitoring for OOMKills in Kubernetes is not as an easy task as one might think. Using <a href="https://github.com/draganm/missing-container-metrics" rel="nofollow">missing-container-metrics</a> makes it much easier though.</p> <p>So go ahead, deploy <a href="https://github.com/draganm/missing-container-metrics" rel="nofollow">missing-container-metrics</a> to your cluster. You might be surprised how many of OOMKills you have not been noticing.</p> <p>I hope that it will be useful to you, and will save you the time that I’ve spent searching for the solution.</p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.netice9.com/blog/guide-to-oomkill-alerting-in-kubernetes-clusters</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25192733</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 22:31:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Walmart Exclusive Wi-Fi Router Contains Backdoor to Control Devices]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 281 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25189673">thread link</a>) | @wikus
<br/>
November 23, 2020 | https://hfet.org/walmart-exclusive-wi-fi-router-contains-backdoor-to-control-devices/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://hfet.org/walmart-exclusive-wi-fi-router-contains-backdoor-to-control-devices/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

			
	<main id="main" role="main">

		
<article id="post-1238">

	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
		<figure>
			<img width="1080" height="540" src="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/wallmart_router_backdoor_humans_for_ethical_technology_hfet-1080x540.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/wallmart_router_backdoor_humans_for_ethical_technology_hfet-1080x540.jpg 1080w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/wallmart_router_backdoor_humans_for_ethical_technology_hfet-20x11.jpg 20w" sizes="(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px">		</figure>

		
	
<div>

	<h4>A Walmart-exclusive Wi-Fi router, and others sold on Amazon &amp; eBay contain hidden backdoors to control devices <a href="https://cybernews.com/security/walmart-exclusive-routers-others-made-in-china-contain-backdoors-to-control-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reports CyberNews</a>.</h4>
<ul>
<li>Researchers discovered that many low cost, Chinese-made Wi-Fi routers contain a hidden backdoor which is being actively exploited to create botnet attacks.</li>
</ul>
<p>CyberNews researchers discovered suspicious backdoors in a Chinese made router sold under the name ‘Jetstream’. This router is part of Walmart’s new line of affordable Wi-Fi routers.</p>
<blockquote><p>This backdoor would allow an attacker the ability to remotely control not only the routers, but also any devices connected to that network.</p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-1024x681.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="532" srcset="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-300x199.jpg 300w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-768x511.jpg 768w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-20x13.jpg 20w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-36x24.jpg 36w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-48x32.jpg 48w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232-272x182.jpg 272w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pexels-brett-sayles-2881232.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></p>
<p>The researchers contacted Walmart to get a statement, and a Walmart spokesperson had this to say:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Thank you for bringing this to our attention. We are looking into the issue to learn more. The item in question is currently out of stock and we do not have plans to replenish it.”</p></blockquote>
<p>CyberNews researchers also discovered that ‘Wavlink’ branded routers, often sold on Amazon or eBay, <a href="https://cybernews.com/security/walmart-exclusive-routers-others-made-in-china-contain-backdoors-to-control-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">contain similar backdoors</a>.</p>
<p>Worryingly, they also discovered that these <strong>backdoors are being actively exploited</strong>, and there have been attempts to add the routers to a botnet with malware that allows them to be used in large scale DDoS attacks, which have <a href="https://cybernews.com/security/walmart-exclusive-routers-others-made-in-china-contain-backdoors-to-control-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in the past taken down major websites</a> such as Reddit, Netflix, CNN, GitHub, Twitter, AirBnb and more.</p>
<h4><strong>Read more of the <a href="https://cybernews.com/security/walmart-exclusive-routers-others-made-in-china-contain-backdoors-to-control-devices/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">full report on CyberNews</a>.</strong></h4>
<p><strong><a href="https://james-clee.com/2020/04/18/multiple-wavlink-vulnerabilities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">James Clee’s Report</a> on ‘Wavlink’ routers’ backdoors.<br>
</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://hfet.org/feed/"><img src="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/rss_button_hfet-1.png" alt="" width="219" height="30"></a><a href="https://hfet.org/support/"><img src="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/support_button_hfet.png" alt="" width="165" height="30"></a></p>
    <div itemtype="http://schema.org/Person" itemscope="" itemprop="author"><p><img width="100" height="100" src="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-150x150.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-150x150.jpg 150w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-300x300.jpg 300w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-20x20.jpg 20w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-36x36.jpg 36w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-48x48.jpg 48w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-24x24.jpg 24w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel-96x96.jpg 96w, https://hfet.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/karl-swanepoel.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 100px) 100vw, 100px"></p><div><p>I’m an AI &amp; Robotics Student interested in FOSS, Tech Sustainability and Data Rights. I’m also the founder of Humans For Ethical Technology.</p></div></div>	
</div><!-- .entry-content -->


</article>

	</main><!-- #main -->

	


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://hfet.org/walmart-exclusive-wi-fi-router-contains-backdoor-to-control-devices/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25189673</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 18:10:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On Small Games]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 72 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25188542">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
November 23, 2020 | https://lorenzo.itch.io/on-small-games | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lorenzo.itch.io/on-small-games">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><em>I wanted to write a Small Games Manifesto for the Manifesto Jam, but I&nbsp;was too tired, so I collected&nbsp;other people's thoughts about small games instead.</em></p>

<p><em>See also: <a href="http://ebeth.itch.io/small-games-manifesto" target="_blank">Small Games Manifesto</a> by Ebeth.</em><br></p>

<p><em>Looking for some small games to play? Check out my <a href="https://itch.io/c/6160/small-is-beautiful" target="_blank">Small is Beautiful</a> and&nbsp;<a href="https://itch.io/c/232207/bitsy-faves-pt2-20192020" target="_blank">Bitsy Faves</a>&nbsp;collections.</em></p>

<p><em>Follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/LorenzoPilia" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">@LorenzoPilia</a></em></p>

<p>• • • • •</p>

<p>Make short and intense games:<br>think haiku, not epic.<br>Think poetry, not prose.<br><strong>— Auriea Harvey &amp; Michaël Samyn: Realtime Art Manifesto</strong><br><a href="http://tale-of-tales.com/tales/RAM.html" rel="nofollow noopener">http://tale-of-tales.com/tales/RAM.html</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>things i will never do in this lifetime:&nbsp;<br>play a game for a few straight hours<br>play a game with more than a few hours worth of content<br><strong>— @moshboy</strong><br><a href="https://twitter.com/moshboy/status/607408540496465922" rel="nofollow noopener">https://twitter.com/moshboy/status/607408540496465922</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>Hell, you'd be surprised at how many people buy games with a moderate length and never finish them. On PC over 50 percent of the people who bought the latest Wolfenstein, a game you can beat in under 15 hours, never earned the achievement for finishing the story. Only 31 percent of Dishonored players on the PC beat the game. People think game length is mandatory, but even shorter games aren't finished by the majority of players.
<br><strong>— Ben Kuchera: To hell with longer games, tell me how SHORT your game is</strong><br><a href="https://www.polygon.com/2014/10/14/6974791/short-games-review" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.polygon.com/2014/10/14/6974791/short-games-review</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>Especially if you're starting out, try to do small projects and don't worry too much about polishing them, don't worry about shipping the perfect game, embrace the messiness of getting into games for the first time, embrace not knowing what you're doing exactly yet. (...) If you just put your heart into it in that way, and embrace the messiness of small games, people will really connect with that.<br><strong>— Nina Freeman: Keynote at A MAZE. / Johannesburg 2017<br></strong><a href="https://twitter.com/AMazeFest/status/908032352953217038" rel="nofollow noopener">https://twitter.com/AMazeFest/status/908032352953217038</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>Duration doesn't need to be a burden. It can be a tool to wield.<br><strong>— Thomas McMullan: Inside and the rise of short games</strong><br><a href="http://www.alphr.com/games/1003958/inside-and-the-rise-of-short-games" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.alphr.com/games/1003958/inside-and-the-rise-of-short-games</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>Small-scale works are often derided for feeling embryonic or unfinished, throwaway motifs or fledgling ideas that the artist failed to integrate into a sufficiently ambitious whole. Game designer Jake Elliott, who drew the title of his Ruins from Schumann’s appraisal of Chopin’s preludes, defended their proportion in an interview: “Maybe [Chopin] felt like they were complete objects, but there wasn’t a vocabulary for talking about pieces of music that were short at the time. Their length is what drew me … there is a lot that’s unspoken.” Having conventionally privileged length, magnitude, and formal unity, games too have left critics bereft of a clear rubric for evaluating intentionally abbreviated, serialized, even disorderly exercises in interactive design.<br><strong>— Peter Lido: Undertale, one year later</strong><br><a href="https://killscreen.com/articles/undertale-one-year-later/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://killscreen.com/articles/undertale-one-year-later/</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>The final idea that we brought over as gamers, the final idea that we had to let go of, was that a longer game makes a better game. We felt that the sense of completion and catharsis that you get when you watch our ending was so critical to the experience, that we decided that we had to help as many people as possible to complete Monument Valley. And that was more important than making the game longer or more difficult.<br><strong>— Ken Wong: Games Without Gamers (#DICE2014 Europe)</strong><br><a href="http://youtu.be/YdSClYHDow0?t=13m37s" rel="nofollow noopener">https://youtu.be/YdSClYHDow0?t=13m37s</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>I value games being short, it makes them easier to fit into life, they get to the point sooner, it's possible to play them more times, trying out different possibilities, there's a clearer connection between decisions and outcome.<br><strong>— Michael Brough: imbroglio notes 6 - meditation</strong><br><a href="http://mightyvision.blogspot.de/2016/08/imbroglio-notes-6-meditation.html?m=1" rel="nofollow noopener">http://mightyvision.blogspot.de/2016/08/imbroglio-notes-6-meditation.html?m=1</a></p>

<p>• • • • •<br></p>

<p>Small games must be protected from their own defenders!! They must be defended against a rhetoric of convenience, as if fitting helpfully into the meagre free time allotted us by rentiers was something to be proud of rather than something to grind against - they must be defended against the meagre virtues of "minimalism", parsimony, elegance, the values of those with enough cultural cachet that they can afford to speak softly, and which hold the same relation to an actual human economy of wants and needs as does a millionaire who doesn't tip.<br><strong>— thecathamites: Small Game Manifesto (part of&nbsp;Buttertown, 10 manifestos for groups of no people)</strong><br><a href="https://thecatamites.itch.io/buttertown">https://thecatamites.itch.io/buttertown</a></p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lorenzo.itch.io/on-small-games</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25188542</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 16:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Getting Started with Firecracker on Raspberry Pi]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 82 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25187965">thread link</a>) | @sairamkunala
<br/>
November 23, 2020 | https://dev.l1x.be/posts/2020/11/22/getting-started-with-firecracker-on-raspberry-pi/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dev.l1x.be/posts/2020/11/22/getting-started-with-firecracker-on-raspberry-pi/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 id="abstract">Abstract</h2><p>Traditionally services were deployed on bare metal and in the last decades we have seen the rise of virtualisation (running additional operating systems in a operating system process) and lately containerisation (running an operating system process in a separate security context from the rest of processes on the same host). Virtualisation and containerisation offers different levels of isolation by moving some operating system functionality to the guest systems.</p><p>The following chart illustrates that pretty well:</p><p><img src="https://dev.l1x.be/img/isolation.png" alt="OS functionality location"></p><p>Source: <a href="https://research.cs.wisc.edu/multifacet/papers/vee20_blending.pdf">https://research.cs.wisc.edu/multifacet/papers/vee20_blending.pdf</a></p><p>In this article, I perform a deep dive into Firecracker and how it can be used for deploying services on Raspberry Pi (4B).</p><h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2><p>There are few paths to take here. First I am going to try the easy one, using Ubuntu. Later on we can investigate the use of Alpine Linux which is much more lightweight than Ubuntu, ideal for devices like RPI.</p><h3 id="installing-the-image-on-a-microsd-card">Installing the image on a microSD card</h3><p>We need a 64 bit Ubuntu image and a microsd card. For the imaging I use <a href="https://www.balena.io/etcher/">Balena Etcher</a> that makes the imaging process super easy.</p><p>Getting the pre-installed image:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">wget https://cdimage.ubuntu.com/releases/20.04/release/<span>\
</span><span></span>ubuntu-20.04.1-preinstalled-server-arm64+raspi.img.xz
</code></pre></div><p>Preinstalled means that we get a fully working operating system and there is no need for additional installation steps after booting up. With Balena Etcher it is super easy to write the compressed image file to the sd card and boot the system up once ready. SSHD starts up after the installation and we can log in via ssh if we know the IP address that the DHCP server issues to our device (assuming DHCP server is present in our LAN).</p><p>There are few mildly annoying things with Ubuntu (snaps, unattended-upgrades) that I usually remove. I also prefer to use Chrony over the systemd equivalent. Ansible repo for these is available here: <a href="https://github.com/l1x/rpi/blob/main/ubuntu.20/ansible/roles/os/tasks/main.yml">https://github.com/l1x/rpi/blob/main/ubuntu.20/ansible/roles/os/tasks/main.yml</a></p><h3 id="installing-firecracker-jailer-and-firectl">Installing Firecracker, Jailer and Firectl</h3><ul><li>Firecracker: The main component, it is a virtual machine monitor (VMM) that uses the Linux Kernel Virtual Machine (KVM) to create and run microVMs.</li><li>Jailer: For starting Firecracker in production mode, applies a cgroup/namespace isolation barrier and then drops privileges. There</li><li>Firectl: A command line utility for convenience</li></ul><h4 id="getting-firecracker-and-jailer">Getting Firecracker and Jailer</h4><p>For the first two it is possible to download the release binaries from Github.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>version</span><span>=</span><span>'v0.23.0'</span>

wget https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker/<span>\
</span><span></span>releases/download/<span>${</span><span>version</span><span>}</span>/firecracker-<span>${</span><span>version</span><span>}</span>-aarch64
wget https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firecracker/<span>\
</span><span></span>releases/download/<span>${</span><span>version</span><span>}</span>/jailer-<span>${</span><span>version</span><span>}</span>-aarch64

mv firecracker-<span>${</span><span>version</span><span>}</span>-aarch64 firecracker
mv jailer-<span>${</span><span>version</span><span>}</span>-aarch64 jailer

chmod +x firecracker jailer

./firecracker --help
./jailer --help
</code></pre></div><h4 id="firectl">Firectl</h4><p>Firectl is a bit trickier to install because there is no release binary and it requires Golang 1.14 to compile. We can do these in two steps.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">wget https://golang.org/dl/go1.14.12.linux-arm64.tar.gz
tar xzvf go1.14.12.linux-arm64.tar.gz
</code></pre></div><p>After getting go we can get the source of firectl and compile it:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">git clone https://github.com/firecracker-microvm/firectl.git
<span>cd</span> firectl/
 ~/go/bin/go build -x
</code></pre></div><p>Testing Firectl:</p><p>We have all the tools we need for running our first microVM the only thing is missing: something to run.</p><h3 id="downloading-our-first-image">Downloading our first image</h3><p>For a microVM there are two things necessary to have:</p><ul><li>an uncompressed linux kernel (vmlinux)</li><li>a filesystem</li></ul><p>Later on we are going to investigate how we could create our own version of these, but for now we are going to use images from</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">wget https://s3.amazonaws.com/spec.ccfc.min/<span>\
</span><span></span>img/aarch64/ubuntu_with_ssh/kernel/vmlinux.bin
wget https://s3.amazonaws.com/spec.ccfc.min/<span>\
</span><span></span>img/aarch64/ubuntu_with_ssh/fsfiles/xenial.rootfs.ext4
</code></pre></div><h3 id="configuring-network">Configuring network</h3><p>For the microVM to function properly we need a networking device. For this scenario we are going to use tap and create a device:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">sudo ip tuntap add dev tap0 mode tap
sudo ip addr add 172.16.0.1/24 dev tap0
sudo ip link <span>set</span> tap0 up
ip addr show dev tap0
</code></pre></div><p>If we want to give access to our VM we have to enable IP forwarding:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>DEVICE_NAME</span><span>=</span>eth0
sudo sh -c <span>"echo 1 &gt; /proc/sys/net/ipv4/ip_forward"</span>
sudo iptables -t nat -A POSTROUTING -o <span>$DEVICE_NAME</span> -j MASQUERADE
sudo iptables -A FORWARD -m conntrack --ctstate RELATED,ESTABLISHED -j ACCEPT
sudo iptables -A FORWARD -i tap0 -o <span>$DEVICE_NAME</span> -j ACCEPT
</code></pre></div><h3 id="running-our-first-microvm">Running our first microVM</h3><p>This is how we can start up our first microVM. I usually start it in screen so I can open a new session easily because it will use the standard input and output for the newly started of console (unless you redirect it).</p><p>This is for debug mode, starting with sudo:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">sudo ./firectl/firectl <span>\
</span><span></span>--firecracker-binary<span>=</span>./firecracker <span>\
</span><span></span>--kernel<span>=</span>vmlinux.bin <span>\
</span><span></span>--tap-device<span>=</span>tap0/aa:fc:00:00:00:01 <span>\
</span><span></span>--kernel-opts<span>=</span><span>\
</span><span></span><span>"console=ttyS0 reboot=k panic=1 pci=off \
</span><span>ip=172.16.0.42::172.16.0.1:255.255.255.0::eth0:off"</span> <span>\
</span><span></span>--root-drive<span>=</span>./xenial.rootfs.ext4
</code></pre></div><p>If everything went well you can see something like this:</p><pre><code>Ubuntu 18.04.2 LTS fadfdd4af58a ttyS0

fadfdd4af58a login:
</code></pre><p>User and password is root:root.</p><h3 id="testing-networking">Testing networking</h3><p>For this we need to have a bit bigger image.</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">dd <span>if</span><span>=</span>/dev/zero <span>bs</span><span>=</span>1M <span>count</span><span>=</span><span>800</span> &gt;&gt; xenial.rootfs.ext4
resize2fs -f xenial.rootfs.ext4
</code></pre></div><p>After starting up the usual way and logging in we need to fix few things:</p><p>Adding some working nameserver:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>echo</span> <span>'nameserver 1.1.1.1'</span> &gt;  /etc/resolv.conf
</code></pre></div><p>Now trying to update:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">root@fadfdd4af58a:~# apt update
Get:1 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic InRelease <span>[</span><span>242</span> kB<span>]</span>
Get:2 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic-updates InRelease <span>[</span>88.7 kB<span>]</span>
Hit:3 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic-backports InRelease
Hit:4 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic-security InRelease
Get:5 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic/universe arm64 Packages <span>[</span>11.0 MB<span>]</span>
Get:6 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic/multiverse arm64 Packages <span>[</span><span>153</span> kB<span>]</span>
Get:7 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic/main arm64 Packages <span>[</span><span>1285</span> kB<span>]</span>
Get:8 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic/restricted arm64 Packages <span>[</span><span>572</span> B<span>]</span>
Get:9 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic-updates/universe arm64 Packages <span>[</span><span>1865</span> kB<span>]</span>
Get:10 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic-updates/restricted arm64 Packages <span>[</span><span>2262</span> B<span>]</span>
Get:11 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic-updates/main arm64 Packages <span>[</span><span>1431</span> kB<span>]</span>
Get:12 http://ports.ubuntu.com/ubuntu-ports bionic-updates/multiverse arm64 Packages <span>[</span><span>5758</span> B<span>]</span>
Fetched 16.1 MB in 6s <span>(</span><span>2543</span> kB/s<span>)</span>
Reading package lists... Error!
E: flAbsPath on /var/lib/dpkg/status failed - realpath <span>(</span>2: No such file or directory<span>)</span>
E: Could not open file  - open <span>(</span>2: No such file or directory<span>)</span>
E: Problem opening
E: The package lists or status file could not be parsed or opened.
</code></pre></div><p>Fixing the apt issues:</p><div><pre><code data-lang="bash">mkdir -p /var/lib/dpkg/<span>{</span>info,alternatives<span>}</span>
touch /var/lib/dpkg/status
apt install apt-utils -y
</code></pre></div><p>Enjoy!</p><p>Next time we can go through how to compile a new kernel and have a different rootfs (potentially using Alpine).</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dev.l1x.be/posts/2020/11/22/getting-started-with-firecracker-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25187965</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:48:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Django refactoring game – can you fix all the Models anti-patterns?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25187507">thread link</a>) | @rikatee
<br/>
November 23, 2020 | https://django.doctor/challenge | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://django.doctor/challenge">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://django.doctor/challenge</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25187507</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:11:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Tech Stack of a One-Man SaaS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 432 | Comments 235 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25186342">thread link</a>) | @amzans
<br/>
November 23, 2020 | https://panelbear.com/blog/tech-stack/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://panelbear.com/blog/tech-stack/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>Being an engineer at heart, each time I see a company write about their tech stack, I brew a fresh cup of coffee, sit back and enjoy reading the newfound little treat.</p><p>There’s just something fascinating about getting to know what’s under the hood of other people’s businesses. It’s like gossip, but about software.</p><p>A couple of months ago I started working on <a href="https://panelbear.com/blog/why-panelbear/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">yet another private analytics service</a>, a project which has gone through numerous iterations, and I feel lucky that 400+ websites have already integrated with it, even though it's still in the early stages.</p><p>That’s why, in the same spirit as Jake Lazaroff’s <a href="https://jake.nyc/words/tools-and-services-i-use-to-run-my-saas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tools and Services I Use to Run My SaaS</a>, I thought it’s now my turn to do a short write up of the technologies I’m using to run this new service.</p><h2>Languages</h2><p>Over the years I have added many programming languages to my toolbelt, but for solo projects I have converged to two in particular that strike a good balance of productivity and reliability.</p><ul><li><p><a href="https://python.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Python</a>: Most of the backend code is in Python. Which has enabled me to ship features incredibly fast. Additionally, I use <a href="http://mypy-lang.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mypy</a> for optional type hints, which helps keep the codebase manageable.</p></li><li><p><a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Typescript</a>: I used to avoid working on the frontend as much as I could. That is until I discovered Typescript about 4 years ago. It just makes the whole experience a lot better, and I now use it for all my projects together with React.</p></li></ul><h2>Frameworks and libraries</h2><p>This list could have been huge, as I stand on the shoulders of giants who have published the vast amount of open-source code which I rely on. But I'd like to highlight only a handful due to their major role in the stack:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Django</a>: It's like a superpower for solo developers. The longer you work in this industry, the more you appreciate not having to reinvent the wheel for the 100th time. A monolithic framework can get you <a href="https://instagram-engineering.com/web-service-efficiency-at-instagram-with-python-4976d078e366" target="_blank" rel="noopener">really</a>, <a href="https://github.com/getsentry/sentry" target="_blank" rel="noopener">really</a> <a href="https://djangostars.com/blog/10-popular-sites-made-on-django/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">far</a>. To me, it's about predictable software that's fast in every way that matters. In case you're interested, I talk more about this topic on <a href="https://panelbear.com/blog/boring-tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Choose Boring Technology</a>.</li><li><a href="https://reactjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">React</a>: The web app for the dashboards is built using React + Webpack. After using Angular for a long time, I switched to React because it's just a pluggable view layer that doesn't get in the way. I use the fantastic <a href="https://github.com/Frojd/django-react-templatetags" target="_blank" rel="noopener">django-react-templatetags</a> to embed the React components in my Django templates.</li><li><a href="https://nextjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">NextJS</a>: I use it for the landing pages, documentation and the blog which you are currently reading. It enables me to re-use various React components, and still reap the performance and SEO benefits of a statically generated site.</li><li><a href="https://docs.celeryproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Celery</a>: I use it for any kind of background/scheduled tasks. It does have a learning curve for more advanced use-cases, but it's quite reliable once you understand how it works, and more importantly when it fails.</li><li><a href="https://getbootstrap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Bootstrap 4</a>: I built a custom theme on top of Bootstrap. It has saved me a lot of time, and there's lots of documentation around it. That's why I picked it.</li></ul><h2>Databases</h2><p>I originally stored all data in a single SQLite database, doing backups meant making a copy of this file to an object storage like S3. At the time, it was more than enough for the small sites I tested Panelbear with. But as I added more features and websites, I needed more specialized software to support those features:</p><ul><li><a href="https://clickhouse.tech/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Clickhouse</a>: I believe this is one of those technologies that over time will become ubiquitous. It's honestly a fantastic piece of software that enabled me to build features that initially seemed impossible on low-cost hardware. I do intend to write a future blog post on some lessons learned from running Clickhouse on Kubernetes. So stay tuned!</li><li><a href="https://www.postgresql.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PostgreSQL</a>: My go-to relational database. Sane defaults, battle-tested, and deeply integrated with Django. For Panelbear, I use it for all application data that is not analytics related. For the analytics data, I instead wrote a simple interface for querying Clickhouse within Django.</li><li><a href="https://redis.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Redis</a>: I use it for many things: caching, rate-limiting, as a task queue, and as a key/value store with TTL for various features. Rock-solid, and great documentation.</li></ul><h2>Deployment</h2><p>I treat my infrastructure as <a href="https://joachim8675309.medium.com/devops-concepts-pets-vs-cattle-2380b5aab313" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cattle instead of pets</a>, things like servers and clusters are meant to come and go. So if one server gets "sick", I just replace it with another one. That means everything is described as code in a git repo, and I do not change things by SSH'ing into the servers. You can think of it like a template to clone my entire infrastructure with one command into any AWS region/environment.</p><p>This also helps me in case of disaster recovery. I just run a few commands, and some minutes later my stack has been re-created. This was particularly useful when I moved from DigitalOcean, to Linode, and recently to AWS. Everything is described in code, so it's easy to keep track of what components I own, even years later (all companies have some AWS IAM policy or VPC subnet lurking around which was created via clicky-clicky on the UI, and now everyone depends on it).</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.terraform.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Terraform</a>: I manage most of my cloud infrastructure with Terraform. Things like EKS clusters, S3 buckets, roles, and RDS instances are declared in my Terraform manifests. The state is synced to an encrypted S3 bucket to avoid getting in trouble in case something happens to my development laptop.</li><li><a href="https://www.docker.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Docker</a>: I build everything as Docker images. Even stateful components like Clickhouse or Redis are packaged and shipped as Docker containers to my cluster. It also makes my stack very portable, as I can run it anywhere I can run Docker.</li><li><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kubernetes</a>: Allowed me to simplify the operational aspects tremendously. However, I wouldn’t bindly recommend it to everyone, as I already felt comfortable working with it after having the pleasure of putting down multiple production fires for my employer over the years. I also rely on managed offerings, which helps reduce the burden too.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/features/actions" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub Actions</a>: Normally I’d use <a href="https://circleci.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CircleCI</a> in the past (which is also great), but for this project I prefer to use GitHub Actions as it removes yet another service which needs to have access to my repositories, and deployment secrets. However, CircleCI has plenty of good features, and I still recommend it.</li></ul><h2>Infrastructure</h2><p>I started in a single $5/mo instance in DigitalOcean, then moved to the managed Kubernetes offering as I was reinventing the wheel for a lot of things Kubernetes already gives me out of the box (service discovery, TLS certs, load balancing, log rotation, rollout, scaling, fault-tolerance, among others).</p><p>Unfortunately, I had <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/questions/kubernetes-unable-to-connect-to-the-server" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reliability issues</a> with DigitalOcean's Kubernetes offering, even on larger instances. The cluster API would often go down randomly and no longer recover, this disrupted a lot of cluster services including the load balancer, which translated into downtime for me. I had to create a new cluster each time this happened, and while Terraform made it trivial, this was not something that inspired a lot of confidence about their managed service. I suspect their control plane was underprovisioned, which would be kind of understandable given the price tag.</p><p>Unfortunately I was not able to resolve the issue after several weeks. That's why I decided to move to <a href="https://www.linode.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Linode</a>, and had exactly 0 problems during the 1.5 month-long honeymoon that followed.</p><p>However, I recently moved once again, this time to AWS due to a pretty good deal I received. It also enabled me to use managed services like RDS to offload managing PostgreSQL, which is a big plus. What made all these migrations relatively easy, was that all my infrastructure was described via Terraform and Kubernetes manifests. The migrations essentially consisted of an evening, some tea, and patience. But that's for another post.</p><ul><li><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AWS</a>: Predictable, and lots of managed services. However, I use it at my full-time job, so I didn't have to spend too much time figuring things out. The main services I use are EKS, ELB, S3, RDS, IAM and private VPCs. I might also add Cloudfront and Kinesis in the future.</li><li><a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cloudflare</a>: I mainly use it for DDoS protection, serving DNS, and offloading edge caching of various static assets (currently shaves off 80% of the egress charges from AWS - their bandwidth pricing is insane!).</li><li><a href="https://letsencrypt.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Let’s Encrypt</a>: Free SSL certificate authority. I use cert-manager in my Kubernetes cluster to automatically issue and renew certificates based on my ingress rules.</li><li><a href="https://www.namecheap.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Namecheap</a>: My domain name registrar of choice. Allows MFA for login which is an important security feature. Unlike other registrars, they haven't surprised me with an expensive renewal every few years. I like them.</li></ul><h2>Kubernetes components</h2><p>The following components automate most of the devops work for me. I use several others too, but some of the main ones I use are:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/ingress-nginx/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ingress-nginx</a>: Rock-solid ingress controller for Kubernetes using NGINX as a reverse proxy, and load balancer. Sits behind the NLB which controls ingress to the cluster nodes.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/jetstack/cert-manager" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cert-manager</a>: Automatically issue/renew TLS certs as defined in my ingress rules.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/external-dns" target="_blank" rel="noopener">external-dns</a>: Synchronizes exposed Kubernetes Services and Ingresses with DNS providers (such as Cloudflare).</li><li><a href="https://github.com/prometheus-operator/prometheus-operator" target="_blank" rel="noopener">prometheus-operator</a>: Automatically monitors most of my services, and exposes dashboards via Grafana.</li><li><a href="https://fluxcd.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">flux</a>: GitOps way to do continuous delivery in Kubernetes. Basically pulls and deploys new Docker images when I release them.</li></ul><h2>CLI tools</h2><p>There’s plenty here, but frequently used include:</p><ul><li><a href="https://kubernetes.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">kubectl</a>: To interact with the Kubernetes cluster to watch logs, pods and services, SSH into a running container, and so on.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/wercker/stern" target="_blank" rel="noopener">stern</a>: Multi pod log tailing for Kubernetes. Really handy.</li><li><a href="https://htop.dev/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">htop</a>: Interactive system process viewer. Better than “top” if you ask me.</li><li><a href="https://curl.se/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cURL</a>: Issue HTTP requests locally, inspect headers.</li><li><a href="https://httpie.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HTTPie</a>: Like cURL, but simpler for JSON APIs.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/rakyll/hey" target="_blank" rel="noopener">hey</a>: Load testing HTTP endpoints. Gives a nice latency distribution summary.</li></ul><h2>Monitoring</h2><ul><li><a href="https://prometheus.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prometheus</a>: Efficient storage of time series data for monitoring. Tracks all the cluster and app metrics. It was a lot cheaper than using Cloudwatch for app metrics.</li><li><a href="https://grafana.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Grafana</a>: Nice dashboards for the Prometheus monitoring data. All dashboards are described in JSON files and versioned in the …</li></ul></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://panelbear.com/blog/tech-stack/">https://panelbear.com/blog/tech-stack/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://panelbear.com/blog/tech-stack/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25186342</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 13:06:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Use Netlify Functions and the Twitter API v2 as a CMS for Your Gatsby Blog]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25186006">thread link</a>) | @pauliescanlon
<br/>
November 23, 2020 | https://paulie.dev/posts/2020/11/gatsby-netlify-twitter/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paulie.dev/posts/2020/11/gatsby-netlify-twitter/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/www-paulie-dev/image/upload/v1605613346/paulie.dev/2020/11/gatsby-netlify-twitterjpg_ok1k0q.jpg"></p><div><div><div><p>Date published: </p><!-- --><p>17-Nov-2020</p></div></div></div><hr><p>JavaScript</p><p>React</p><p>Gatsby</p><p>Netlify Functions</p><p>Twitter API v2</p><hr><p>Apologies in advance for the rather long-winded blog title but as it suggests in this post i'm going to explain how you can use <a href="https://www.netlify.com/products/functions/">Netlify Functions</a> to access your Twitter profile data using the <a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-api/early-access">Twitter v2 API</a> and display it on your Gatsby blog.</p><h2>A rather unique requirement</h2><p>This might be a specific to me but I wanted to solve a little problem I was having with my "digital footprint". As you can see I have this blog: <a href="https://paulie.dev/">https://paulie.dev</a> and a commercial portfolio: <a href="https://www.pauliescanlon.io/">https://www.pauliescanlon.io</a></p><p>Both sites are built on top of my Gatsby theme: <a href="https://gatsby-theme-terminal.netlify.app/">gatsby-theme-terminal</a> which is Open source and can be found on my <a href="https://github.com/PaulieScanlon/gatsby-theme-terminal">GitHub</a></p><p>Using a Gatsby Theme solves one of my issues as I'm able to have two sites that look and work pretty much the same way and any changes I make to the theme are inherited by both my sites. It's kind of like managing your own multi brand design system, but just for yourself.</p><p>There was one other problem though. 🤔</p><p>I wanted both sites to have the same "intro" section, but every time I made a change to one I had to make the same change to the other site to ensure they were both displaying the same intro text.</p><p>This might be fine if I weren't a developer but doing something twice is one time too many IMO.</p><p>It was also a little frustrating because I also wanted my Twitter profile description to be in sync with both the sites so, again another place to remember to update my personal blurb.</p><p>One option I considered would have been to hook up a Content Management System, and this would have been fine and it would have kept both my sites in sync but it wouldn't have been able to update my Twitter profile blurb...</p><p>So, I've decided to reverse engineer the Twitter API and use that as a CMS to populate both my sites. The idea is quite simple. I'll use the Twitter profile description as though it were a field from a CMS. Naturally any changes I make to this will appear on my Twitter profile and below is how I pull that same info into both of my sites.</p><h2>Demo</h2><p>Here's what I'll be showing you how to build:</p><ul><li>App / API <a href="https://gatsby-netlify-twitter.netlify.app/">https://gatsby-netlify-twitter.netlify.app</a></li><li>GitHub repo <a href="https://github.com/PaulieScanlon/gatsby-netlify-twitter">https://github.com/PaulieScanlon/gatsby-netlify-twitter</a></li></ul><p>... but the actual API I use for my blog and site is here: <a href="https://paulie-api.netlify.app/">https://paulie-api.netlify.app</a></p><h2>Tech</h2><h3>Netlify Functions</h3><p>"Power your site without managing servers" is how Netlify describe Functions and for all intents and purposes thats exactly what they are. Similar to how you might create an <a href="https://expressjs.com/">Express</a> app and deploy it somewhere but without the hassle of having to setup server side environments and more crucially any really dweeby server uptime monitoring.</p><h3>Twitter API v2</h3><p>A set of endpoints that can be used to get data from Twitter. Any Twitter requests must be done server side and use a set of keys and tokens. You can't unfortunately hit the Twitter API from the browser so we need a "server" or as mentioned above, a Netlify Function</p><p>Using both of the above i've made my own API endpoint which goes off and hits the Twitter API and returns my Profile information which I can then display in the intro section of my blog and site. I've deployed this API to Netlify and it's completely de-coupled from either of my sites but will return data which can be fetched from client side "fetch" request from within my site and blog. That url again is here: <a href="https://paulie-api.netlify.app/">https://paulie-api.netlify.app</a></p><h2>Before we start</h2><p>Before we get started there's a couple of things you'll need to have in place.</p><h3>Twitter API v2</h3><p>Apply for access to the <a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/products/twitter-api">Twitter API</a>. This is quite a lengthy process so strap in and also bookmark this post as it might take a few days for Twitter to accept your application.</p><p>Once you have access you can head over to the <a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/portal/dashboard">Developer Portal</a> and create a new project, and within the project you can create an "app", I called mine "paulie-api".</p><p>In here you'll find all the API keys and tokens required to access the Twitter API. Make a note of them somewhere as we'll be using them later.</p><h3>Netlify CLI</h3><p>To run Netlify Functions we'll be using <code>netlify dev</code> rather than <code>gatsby develop</code> or <code>yarn develop</code> so you'll need to install the <a href="https://docs.netlify.com/cli/get-started/">Netlify CLI</a></p><h2>The Build</h2><p>In order to develop you own API I found it easiest to have some kind of "site" running at the same time which will access the API endpoint and render the response on the page. In the demo repo you'll see i've set up a really simple Gatsby Site with one page that uses "fetch" to, er fetch and then render the data.</p><p>I've used <a href="https://theme-ui.com/home">Theme UI</a> for the style but naturally you can choose whatever you like to do this.</p><p>Whether you're starting from scratch or adding Netlify Functions to an existing project you'll need to start by adding a <code>functions</code> dir to the root of your project.</p><hr><pre><p><span>|</span><span>-- functions</span></p><p><span>  </span><span>|</span><span>-- package.json</span></p><p><span></span><span>|</span><span>-- src</span></p><p><span>package.json</span></p></pre><hr><p><code>functions</code> is kind of it's own application so it'll need it's own <code>package.json</code> and will have one dependency on <a href="https://github.com/HunterLarco/twitter-v2">twitter-v2</a></p><hr><pre><p><span></span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"name"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"gatsby-netlify-twitter-api"</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"version"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"1.0.0"</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"description"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"An api for the Twitter v2 api"</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"main"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"index.js"</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"scripts"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>"test"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"echo \"Error: no test specified\" &amp;&amp; exit 1"</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>}</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"keywords"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>]</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"author"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>""</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"license"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"ISC"</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>"dependencies"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>"twitter-v2"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"^0.1.2"</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>}</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>}</span></p></pre><hr><p>Next have a look at <a href="https://github.com/PaulieScanlon/gatsby-netlify-twitter/blob/main/.env.example">.env.example</a>. You'll need to create your own <code>.env</code> file and add the environment variables as seen in the <code>.env.example</code>. Naturally you'll want to change the <code>GATSBY_TWITTER_USERNAME</code> to your own Twitter username and the Twitter keys and tokens will be what I referenced earlier which are provided by the Twitter Developer Portal</p><hr><pre><p><span></span><span>GATSBY_API_URL</span><span>=</span><span>.</span><span>/</span><span>.</span><span>netlify</span><span>/</span><span>functions</span></p><p><span></span><span>GATSBY_TWITTER_USERNAME</span><span>=</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>TWITTER_API_KEY</span><span>=</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>TWITTER_API_KEY_SECRET</span><span>=</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN</span><span>=</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN_SECRET</span><span>=</span></p></pre><hr><p>Next create a Twitter client, this is what we'll use to pass the keys and tokens onto the Twitter API when we make a request</p><hr><pre><p><span></span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>Twitter</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>require</span><span>(</span><span>"twitter-v2"</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>module</span><span>.</span><span>exports</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>  client</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>new</span><span> </span><span>Twitter</span><span>(</span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>    consumer_key</span><span>:</span><span> process</span><span>.</span><span>env</span><span>.</span><span>TWITTER_CONSUMER_KEY</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    consumer_secret</span><span>:</span><span> process</span><span>.</span><span>env</span><span>.</span><span>TWITTER_CONSUMER_KEY_SECRET</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    access_token</span><span>:</span><span> process</span><span>.</span><span>env</span><span>.</span><span>TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    access_token_secret</span><span>:</span><span> process</span><span>.</span><span>env</span><span>.</span><span>TWITTER_ACCESS_TOKEN_SECRET</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>}</span></p></pre><hr><p>You should now be looking at something similar to the below</p><hr><pre><p><span>..</span><span>.</span></p><p><span></span><span>|</span><span>-- functions</span></p><p><span>  </span><span>|</span><span>-- client.js</span></p><p><span>  </span><span>|</span><span>-- package.json</span></p><p><span></span><span>|</span><span>-- src</span></p><p><span>package.json</span></p><p><span>.env</span></p><p><span></span><span>..</span><span>.</span></p></pre><hr><p>Now we need to create the "endpoint" that our frontend will hit, which in turn goes off and grabs the data from the Twitter API.</p><p>I created a dir called <code>twitter-user</code> and inside I create a new file and called it <code>twitter-user.js</code></p><hr><pre><p><span>..</span><span>.</span></p><p><span></span><span>|</span><span>-- functions</span></p><p><span>  </span><span>|</span><span>-- client.js</span></p><p><span>  </span><span>|</span><span>-- twitter-user</span></p><p><span>    </span><span>|</span><span>-- twitter-user.js</span></p><p><span>  </span><span>|</span><span>-- package.json</span></p><p><span></span><span>|</span><span>-- src</span></p><p><span>package.json</span></p><p><span>.env</span></p><p><span></span><span>..</span><span>.</span></p></pre><hr><p>It's in here where we can use the <code>client.js</code> to hit a Twitter API endpoint and pass with it the required keys and tokens from the <code>client</code></p><hr><pre><p><span></span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> client </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>require</span><span>(</span><span>"../client"</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>exports</span><span>.</span><span>handler</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>async</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>event</span><span>,</span><span> context</span><span>,</span><span> callback</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> data </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>await</span><span> client</span><span>.</span><span>get</span><span>(</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>`</span><span>users/by/username/</span><span>${</span><span>process</span><span>.</span><span>env</span><span>.</span><span>GATSBY_TWITTER_USERNAME</span><span>}</span><span>`</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>      user</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>        fields</span><span>:</span><span></span></p><p><span>          </span><span>"created_at,description,entities,id,location,name,pinned_tweet_id,profile_image_url,protected,public_metrics,url,username,verified,withheld"</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>}</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>}</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>callback</span><span>(</span><span>null</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>    headers</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>"Access-Control-Allow-Origin"</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>"*"</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>}</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    statusCode</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>200</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>    body</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>JSON</span><span>.</span><span>stringify</span><span>(</span><span>{</span><span> user</span><span>:</span><span> data </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span>,</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>}</span></p></pre><hr><p>In the above you can see we use our <code>client</code> to hit the <code>users/by/username</code> Twitter API endpoint which you can read more about <a href="https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/twitter-api/users/lookup/introduction">here</a>, which returns a <code>data</code> object which I pass on to the callback body as <code>{ user: data }</code></p><p>This is the object that'll we receive in our frontend</p><p>The next bit will greatly depend on how you've set up your frontend but in the <a href="https://github.com/PaulieScanlon/gatsby-netlify-twitter/blob/main/src/pages/index.js">Demo</a> I have one <code>page</code> called <code>index.js</code> which uses a <code>useEffect</code> to "fetch" the data from the Netlify Function.</p><p>The example file contains a few extra bits for <code>isLoading</code> and <code>hasError</code> but the below should be enough to allow you hit to the Netlify Function which in turn hits the Twitter API and returns your profile information data.</p><hr><pre><p><span></span><span>import</span><span> </span><span>React</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> useState </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>from</span><span> </span><span>"react"</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>IndexPage</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>response</span><span>,</span><span> setResponse</span><span>]</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> </span><span>useState</span><span>(</span><span>{</span><span> user</span><span>:</span><span> </span><span>null</span><span> </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>useEffect</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>fetch</span><span>(</span><span>`</span><span>${</span><span>process</span><span>.</span><span>env</span><span>.</span><span>GATSBY_API_URL</span><span>}</span><span>/twitter-user</span><span>`</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>.</span><span>then</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>response</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> response</span><span>.</span><span>text</span><span>(</span><span>)</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>.</span><span>then</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>response</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>        </span><span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>JSON</span><span>.</span><span>parse</span><span>(</span><span>response</span><span>)</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>        </span><span>setResponse</span><span>(</span><span>JSON</span><span>.</span><span>parse</span><span>(</span><span>response</span><span>)</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>.</span><span>catch</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>error</span><span>)</span><span> </span><span>=&gt;</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span></span></p><p><span>        </span><span>console</span><span>.</span><span>error</span><span>(</span><span>{</span><span> error </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>}</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>}</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>[</span><span>]</span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>const</span><span> </span><span>{</span><span> user </span><span>}</span><span> </span><span>=</span><span> response</span></p><p><span>  </span><span>return</span><span> </span><span>(</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>&lt;</span><span>pre</span><span>&gt;</span><span></span></p><p><span>      </span><span>&lt;</span><span>code</span><span>&gt;</span><span>{</span><span>JSON</span><span>.</span><span>stringify</span><span>(</span><span>user</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>null</span><span>,</span><span> </span><span>2</span><span>)</span><span>}</span><span>&lt;</span><span>/</span><span>code</span><span>&gt;</span><span></span></p><p><span>    </span><span>&lt;</span><span>/</span><span>pre</span><span>&gt;</span><span></span></p><p><span>  </span><span>)</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>}</span><span></span></p><p><span></span><span>export</span><span> </span><span>default</span><span> </span><span>IndexPage</span></p></pre><hr><p><code>process.env.GATSBY_API_URL</code> is the path to the Netlify Function we added earlier to <code>.env</code> and i've hard-coded <code>/twitter-user</code> in the component / page as you might want to create different endpoints that return different data on different pages.</p><p>You might be wondering why this environment variable is prefixed with <code>GATSBY_</code>. This is so Gatsby can access it from the frontend. You can read more about Gatsby environment variables <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/environment-variables/#client-side-javascript">here</a></p><h3>IMPORTANT</h3><p>In order for Netlify Functions to work both locally and when deployed we need to ensure we've got <code>netlify-lambda</code> installed and have added both a <code>"start"</code> and <code>"postinstall"</code> script to the root <code>package.json</code> (not the <code>package.json</code> in <code>./functions</code>)</p><hr><pre><p><span>npm</span><span> </span><span>install</span><span> netlify-lambda --save -dev</span></p></pre><hr><pre><p><span>// ./package.json</span></p><p><span>...</span></p><p><span></span><span>  "scripts": {</span></p><p><span>    "develop": "gatsby develop",</span></p><p><span>    "build": "gatsby build",</span></p><p><span>    "clean": "gatsby clean",</span></p><p><span>    "serve": "gatsby serve",</span></p><p><span></span><span>+    "start": "npm run develop",</span></p><p><span>+    "postinstall": "netlify-lambda install"</span></p><p><span></span><span>  },</span></p><p><span>   "devDependencies": {</span></p><p><span></span><span>+   "netlify-lambda": "^1.6.3",</span></p><p><span></span><span>  }</span></p><p><span></span><span>...</span></p></pre><hr><p>Before we get too carried away, it's important to note that we'll no longer be using <code>gatsby develop</code> or <code>yarn develop</code> to start the Gatsby app, if you do that our Netlify Function won't be running and you'll get an error.</p><p>Instead, run <code>netlify dev</code> this is so both the Gatsby site and the Netlify Function are run at the same time.</p><p>Instead of visiting the usual <code>http://localhost:8000/</code> we'll now be visiting <code>http://localhost:8888/</code></p><p>And to ensure when we deploy everything works as it should you'll need to modify your <a href="https://github.com/PaulieScanlon/gatsby-netlify-twitter/blob/main/netlify.toml"><code>netlify.toml</code></a></p><p>For …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://paulie.dev/posts/2020/11/gatsby-netlify-twitter/">https://paulie.dev/posts/2020/11/gatsby-netlify-twitter/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paulie.dev/posts/2020/11/gatsby-netlify-twitter/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25186006</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:27:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
