<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 08:27:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 08:27:05 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Birth of Unix with Brian Kernighan – CoRecursive Podcast]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 16 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25176318">thread link</a>) | @rodrigo975
<br/>
November 22, 2020 | https://corecursive.com/brian-kernighan-unix-bell-labs1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://corecursive.com/brian-kernighan-unix-bell-labs1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><span>When you work on your computer, there are so many things you take for granted: operating systems, programming languages, they all have to come from somewhere. </span></p><p><span>In the late 1960s and 1970s, that somewhere was Bell Labs, and the operating system they were building was UNIX. </span></p><p><span>They were building more than just an operating system though. They were building a way to work with computers that had never existed before.&nbsp; </span></p><p><span>In today’s episode I talk to Brian Kernighan about the history of Unix.</span></p><p><span>“If you wanted, you could go sit in your office and think deep thoughts or program, or write on your own blackboard or whatever, but then come back to the common space when you wanted to.“ – Brian Kernighan </span></p><p><span>“I found it easier to program when I was trying to figure out the logic for myself rather than trying to figure out where in the infinite stack of documentation was the function I needed. So for me, programming is more like creating something rather than looking it up, and too much of today’s programming is more like looking it up.” – Brian Kernighan </span></p><p><span>“If what I find challenging or hard or whatever is also something that other people find hard or challenging or whatever, then if I do something that will improve my lot, I’m perhaps improving their lot at the same time.” – Brian Kernighan</span></p><p><span><strong>Links:</strong></span></p><p><a href="https://www.cs.princeton.edu/people/profile/bwk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brian’s Homepage</a></p><p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1695978552" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Book: Unix: A History and a Memoir</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://corecursive.com/brian-kernighan-unix-bell-labs1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25176318</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 10:14:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build a Minimum Loveable Product]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25175220">thread link</a>) | @grwthckrmstr
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>You've validated your micro-SaaS idea and are ready to start building the product.</p><p>The obvious next questions are</p><ol start="" role="list"><li>Which features should the product include in its first version?</li><li>How long should you take to build it?</li></ol><p>Through this post, I provide you with a framework to identify your initial product features, how to decide what to include or exclude from the first versions, and continue building upon it.</p><p>Before jumping into MLP, let's first understand what MVP&nbsp;is and why it's not enough in today's times.</p><h2>What is a Minimum Viable Product (MVP)?</h2><p><a href="https://twitter.com/ericries" target="_blank">Eric Ries</a> popularized the term <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product" target="_blank">minimum viable product</a> in his book <a href="http://theleanstartup.com/" target="_blank">The Lean Startup</a> as that version of a new product that is just usable enough by early customers who can then provide feedback to the team. This feedback should help the team generate validated learnings and guide them on future product development and features.</p><h4>When MVP still works</h4><p>MVP is not dead though. It still works, given the right kind of problem statements.</p><p>Suppose you're building something that simply doesn't exist in the world, and it's something that people really want and have no alternative to getting it except from you.</p><p>At this time, people will accept a textbook MVP, simply because they have no frame of reference to compare it with. Or better yet, because they have no alternative to replace your MVP with.</p><h4>Why MVP&nbsp;is not enough in 2021</h4><p>Over the past few years as smartphone penetration boomed, products matured, product design and user experience matured, people's expectations have increased.</p><p>No longer does a quickly thrown together prototype cut it. People expect a minimum level of good UX and ease-of-use, else they'll leave your app before even giving it a proper try.</p><p>In fact, in 2021 great UX might be one strong reason people pick your product over incumbents. That's what happened with <a href="https://transistor.fm/" target="_blank">Transistor.fm</a>, who made podcast hosting simple and easy.</p><p>People expect good aesthetics that make a first impression, simply because that's what they have become used to from the plethora of beautiful and well-designed apps out there in the world.</p><p>People expect products to be fully functional as advertised. Buggy products are not acceptable, and in fact people might quickly take to Twitter or social media to let others know that a product is unreliable.</p><p>The MVP mindset intensely focuses on building the bare minimum, and that often leaves users frustrated and drives them to seek alternative solutions. Stiffer competition means that people WILL compare your product to alternatives in the market, it's inevitable. And unless you provide something unique and valuable that nobody else does, people are likely to leave.</p><p>All these reasons and more make MVP&nbsp;a dated concept, especially in the context of SaaS products. But above all, I think the MVP mindset makes product builders think too heavily about the "minimum" and often so at the cost of "viable".</p><p>That's a common pitfall and to avoid that, I propose the MLP framework.</p><h2>What is a Minimum Loveable Product (MLP)?</h2><p>A great new concept that I've fallen in love with and personally follow in every product I build is MLP, or Minimum Loveable Product.</p><p>The term MLP was first coined by Brian de Haaff, the co-founder of Aha!, in his book <a href="https://www.aha.io/lovability" target="_blank">Lovability</a>.</p><p>Its definition is an extension of what Eric Ries already introduced to the world with MVP. With MLP though, you are trying to build the minimum "loveable" product, with a focus on no matter how small or feature-stripped the first version of your product is, it is sufficient to deliver a delightful experience to your user.</p><h4>Minimum Viable Product and the burnt pizza analogy</h4><p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jiaona/" target="_blank">Jiaona Zhang</a>, who is currently VP&nbsp;of Product at Webflow (this blog is built using Webflow) introduced the <a href="https://firstround.com/review/dont-serve-burnt-pizza-and-other-lessons-in-building-minimum-lovable-products/" target="_blank">burnt pizza analogy</a> to her students at Stanford.</p><p>“<em>Say you’re trying to test whether people like pizza. If you serve them burnt pizza, you’re not getting feedback on whether they like pizza. You only know that they don’t like burnt pizza. Similarly, when you’re only relying on the MVP, the fastest and cheapest functional prototype, you risk not actually testing your product, but rather a poor or flawed version of it.</em>"</p><p>A great practical example of Minimum Loveable Product is the Apple iPad. All the tablets that came before Apple's tablet were MVPs.</p><h2>MLP vs MVP</h2><p>If you're new to all these terminologies, I understand that it can be confusing. Bear with me, you'll wrap your head around it soon enough.</p><p>Build an MLP when you are solving a problem that's already understood by people, and an MVP when people don't easily understand a problem.</p><p>Build an MLP when you can clearly define and understand a market and you are trying to stand out from the existing tools. Build an MVP when you're trying to gauge if there even exists a market to serve.</p><p>An&nbsp;MLP can be built when you know exactly what customers want. An MVP is when you don't know what customers want, and therefore you want to throw things at the wall as quickly as possible and see what sticks.</p><p>An MLP is necessary if you are building in a market where several large and well-known alternatives already exist. An MVP is the right approach for a new market with barely any alternatives, or those solutions are not yet known by the masses.</p><p>While building an MLP, you make a dedicated effort to succeed with that idea. With MVP, you are trying to determine quickly whether the idea can succeed or whether it will fail.</p><p>Building an&nbsp;MVP means you're ready for failure and also ready to pivot quickly as you learn more about the market. Which means you should make tech and architecture decisions that help you move fast above anything else. Scalability or good architecture design is a concern to pay attention to while building an MLP.</p><p>Finally, the end goal of an MLP is that the customers who use it find it sufficient in functionality and experience to be able to "love" it. With an MLP, you're building just enough that a customer with (hopefully) a real pain point would "tolerate" and continue using your product while you validate your assumptions.</p><h2>Minimum Marketable Product, Minimum Remarkable Product, Minimum Launchable Product</h2><p>The what?</p><p>I know, I know. I came across these terms for the first time today while researching to write this post. And I went through the literature so that I can tell you to safely ignore it.</p><p>If you understand and embody the concept of MLP, you don't need to think about any other frameworks or terminologies that you may discover while researching on Google.</p><h2>How to build an MLP for your Micro SaaS idea</h2><p>Alright, let's put aside theory and dive right in.</p><p>Here are the steps you should loosely follow to building an MLP.</p><h4>1. Understand the #1 problem you're trying to solve</h4><p>What's the #1 reason someone would want to use your Micro SaaS product over existing alternatives?</p><p>Is it that existing options have poor UX?&nbsp;Great, create a well designed and easy-to-use product. You'd be surprised to know how often people switch to an easier to use tool, simply because they are fed up of the poor UX that they encounter repeatedly.</p><p>Is it that existing alternatives are very expensive?&nbsp;Carve out a minimum set of features that people are paying a lot of money for and charge 1/10th for your v1 product. This might not work for very large customers, but vast majority of customers who are small or mid-sized are always looking for affordable alternatives.</p><p>It might not just be raw quantum of pricing, but certain companies targeting Enterprise customers have very complicated pricing slabs and tiers that are designed to give their sales person more room. In such a case, coming out with a competitor product which has a simple, easy-to-understand pricing is how you attract customers.</p><p>Are existing alternatives lacking certain features that leaves a subset of users very dissatisfied?&nbsp;Great, your MLP should specifically address that problem by building functionality that attracts these dissatisfied users. Side note - This is perhaps one of the best ways to go about building a new product.</p><p>In all cases, it involves understanding the problem you are solving and the exact reason why someone would use your product.</p><h4>2. Design a simple product that solves the top customer needs satisfactorily</h4><p>Once you have identified the #1 reason, it's time to decide on a feature set for your product that solves your customer's top pain points satisfactorily.</p><p><strong>Let's take an example</strong> - People want to add a feedback tracking tool inside their product, so that they can collect user feedback automatically. However, the existing solutions don't allow them to embed the feedback tracker within their tool.</p><p>That's your entry point into providing value that customers seek, but are not getting as of today.</p><p>Having understood the #1 problem, you also have to understand other requirements that fall under the "minimum" set of things you need to do to build a "loveable" product.</p><p>These could be:</p><ul role="list"><li>existing solutions are all well designed and aesthetically pleasing =&gt;&nbsp;your minimum loveable product needs to be well designed too</li><li>existing solutions are affordably priced with a easy to understand pricing structure =&gt; your MLP also needs a simple pricing structure that's affordable</li></ul><p>In general, you want to analyze your competitors and understand </p><ol start="" role="list"><li>What they are doing well</li><li>What users value from among those things</li></ol><p>In your MLP, you need to cover the intersection of (what they are doing well) x (what users value from among those).</p><h4>3. Set a short timeline for building your MLP</h4><p>No matter what you build, building in isolation for too long is dangerous. The main reason for that is - you get to know too late whether your assumptions about what the user really values are on point or off course.</p><p><strong>"But Preetam, you just told me to build a Minimum Loveable Product. And now you're saying I got to build it quickly?"</strong></p><p>Yes, that's exactly what I'm saying.</p><p>Short timeframe depends on what you are building, and the size of your team.</p><p>For example - with SuperLemon (WhatsApp plugin for Shopify), Sankalp and I built a MLP in 2 weeks time.</p><p>How?</p><p>We identified precisely the way we could do better - …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas">https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.preetamnath.com/micro-saas/minimum-loveable-product-micro-saas</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25175220</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 05:40:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Abandoned Mansion in NYC Raises Questions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 13 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25174361">thread link</a>) | @new_guy
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.hooch.net/an-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hooch.net/an-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><img src="https://b.scorecardresearch.com/p?c1=2&amp;c2=22453632&amp;cv=2.0&amp;cj=1">

<!-- End comScore Tag -->
	

	
    			<header role="banner">
                

                <div id="inner-header">
                                        <p><a href="https://www.hooch.net/">
                        <img src="https://www.hooch.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/06/hooch-header-logo-30832.png" rel="Home" id="logo">
        </a>
    </p><!-- .site-branding -->
                    <nav id="main-nav" role="navigation">
                                    <ul>
                            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/celebrity/">Celebrity</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/entertainment/">Entertainment</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/sports/">Sports</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/trending/">Trending</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/television/">Television</a>
                
            </li>
                            <li id="menu-search">
                <label for="menu-search-toggle" id="menu-search-label"><i></i></label>
                <form role="search" name="search" method="get" id="searchform" action="https://www.hooch.net/">
    <p><label for="s">Search for:</label>
        

        
    </p>
</form>
            </li>
            </ul>          
                    </nav>
                    
                                <ul>
                            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hooch.net%2Fan-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions%2F%3Futm_source%3Dshare-facebook%26utm_content%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dmainnav%26utm_campaign%3Dshare-mainnav" target="_blank"><i></i></a>
                
            </li>	
	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/create/button/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hooch.net%2Fan-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions%2F%3Futm_source%3Dshare-pinterest%26utm_content%3Dpinterest%26utm_medium%3Dmainnav%26utm_campaign%3Dshare-mainnav&amp;media=https://www.hooch.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/snow-abandoned-mansion-12796-30176.jpg&amp;description=An+Abandoned+Mansion+In+NYC+Raises+Questions" target="_blank"><i></i></a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hooch.net%2Fan-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions%2F%3Futm_source%3Dshare-twitter%26utm_content%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dmainnav%26utm_campaign%3Dshare-mainnav" target="_blank"><i></i></a>
                
            </li>
                
            </ul>                </div>
                                                <div id="offscreen">

                                        
                    <p><a href="https://www.hooch.net/">
                                                                <img src="https://www.hooch.net/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/06/hooch-header-logo-30832.png" rel="Home" id="logo">
                            </a>
                                            </p><!-- .site-branding -->
                                <ul id="side-nav">
                            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/celebrity/">Celebrity</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/entertainment/">Entertainment</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/sports/">Sports</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/trending/">Trending</a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/television/">Television</a>
                
            </li>
                
            </ul>
                    

                    <div id="nav-footer">

                                    <ul>
                            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hooch.net%2Fan-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions%2F%3Futm_source%3Dshare-facebook%26utm_content%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dsidenav%26utm_campaign%3Dshare-sidenav" target="_blank"><i></i></a>
                
            </li>	
	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/create/button/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hooch.net%2Fan-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions%2F%3Futm_source%3Dshare-pinterest%26utm_content%3Dpinterest%26utm_medium%3Dsidenav%26utm_campaign%3Dshare-sidenav&amp;media=https://www.hooch.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/snow-abandoned-mansion-12796-30176.jpg&amp;description=An+Abandoned+Mansion+In+NYC+Raises+Questions" target="_blank"><i></i></a>
                
            </li>	
            <li>
                            <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.hooch.net%2Fan-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions%2F%3Futm_source%3Dshare-twitter%26utm_content%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dsidenav%26utm_campaign%3Dshare-sidenav" target="_blank"><i></i></a>
                
            </li>
                
            </ul>                        <ul id="menu-footer">
    <li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hooch.net/about-us/">About</a></li>
    <li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hooch.net/contact-us/">Contact</a></li>
    <li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hooch.net/dmca/">Copyright</a></li>
    <li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hooch.net/privacy/">Privacy</a></li>
    <li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.hooch.net/terms/">Terms</a></li>
</ul>                    </div>

                </div><!-- #offscreen -->                			</header>
            	<div id="content">

        <div id="lefternary">
            
            
            
            
            
        </div>

		<div id="quaternary">
            
            
            
            
            
        </div>

		<div id="inner-content">
				
			

			
			<main id="main" role="main">
	
				<div id="primary">
	<article id="post-50815">
		
					<div id="primary-over-title-wrapper">
				
			</div>

			<header>

				

				<div>
            <p><a href="https://www.hooch.net/category/weird" target="_blank">weird</a> 
        <span>8/2/17</span>
    
    
</p></div>
			</header><!-- .entry-header -->

			<div id="primary-under-title-wrapper">
				
			</div>
		
		<section>

						
			

			<div id="primary-over-next-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			<div id="primary-over-next-container">
				<div id="primary-over-next-P2-wrapper">
					
				</div>
				<div id="primary-over-next-P3-wrapper">
					
				</div>
			</div>

			        
				<div id="primary-over-header-1-wrapper">
					
				</div>
				<div id="primary-over-header-2-wrapper">
					
				</div>
				<div id="primary-over-header-3-wrapper">
					
				</div>
				<div id="primary-over-header-4-wrapper">
					
				</div>
				
			
			<div id="primary-under-image-P1-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			<div id="primary-under-image-P2-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			<div id="primary-under-image-P3-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			<div id="primary-under-image-P4-wrapper">
				
			</div>

			<div id="primary-over-paragraph-1-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			<div id="primary-over-paragraph-2-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			<div id="primary-over-paragraph-3-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			<div id="primary-over-paragraph-4-wrapper">
				
			</div>

			<div id="next-button"><p><a href="https://www.hooch.net/an-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions/2/">Next</a></p></div>

			<div id="primary-under-next-wrapper">
				
			</div>
			
		</section><!-- .entry-content -->
		
	</article><!-- #post-## -->
</div>


                            <div id="sidebar">

                                
                
            </div>
                <div>
                    <div id="tertiary">
                        
                        
                        
                        
                                   
                    </div>
                </div>

                
	
			</main>

		</div>
    </div>
		

		<!-- Quantcast Tag -->



<!-- End Quantcast tag -->




	
</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hooch.net/an-abandoned-mansion-in-nyc-raises-questions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25174361</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 02:23:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using Python's Bisect Module]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25174048">thread link</a>) | @kaunta
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://johnlekberg.com/blog/2020-11-21-stdlib-bisect.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://johnlekberg.com/blog/2020-11-21-stdlib-bisect.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://johnlekberg.com/blog.html">Return to Blog
</a></p><p>By John Lekberg on November 21, 2020.
</p><hr>
<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25174048">Hacker News discussion.</a></p>
<hr>
<p>This week's post is about Python's <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html">bisect</a> module. You will learn:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_binning">Statistical data binning</a> with <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.bisect">bisect.bisect</a>.</li>
<li>Adding new data to a sorted list with <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.insort">bisect.insort</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>The goal of the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html">bisect</a> module is to allow you to efficiently search and
update sorted lists. To this end, it provides:</p>
<ul>
<li>A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_search_algorithm">binary search</a> implementation, <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.bisect">bisect.bisect</a>.</li>
<li>An "insert" -- as in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insertion_sort">insertion sort</a> -- implementation, <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.insort">bisect.insort</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_binning">statistical data binning</a>, you have data that you want to group into "bins". E.g.</p>
<ul>
<li>You have data on different fruits and want to group "lemon" and "orange" into
"citrus".</li>
<li>You have data on students' grades and want to group scores between 80 and 90
into "B", scores between 90 and 100 into "A", etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>To me, a straightforward approach is to write a function that computes the bin.
E.g., binning fruits:</p>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>def bin_fruit(fruit):
    if fruit in ["lemon", "orange"]:
        return "citrus"
    elif fruit in ["apple", "pear"]:
        return "malinae"


import random

data = random.choices(
    ["lemon", "orange", "apple", "pear"], k=10
)
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>['lemon',
 'lemon',
 'apple',
 'apple',
 'apple',
 'lemon',
 'apple',
 'apple',
 'lemon',
 'pear']
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>[bin_fruit(x) for x in data]
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>['citrus',
 'citrus',
 'malinae',
 'malinae',
 'malinae',
 'citrus',
 'malinae',
 'malinae',
 'citrus',
 'malinae']
</code></pre>
<p>E.g., turning test scores into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academic_grading_in_the_United_States">letter grades</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>def bin_score(score):
    if 90 &lt;= score &lt;= 100:
        return "A"
    elif 80 &lt;= score &lt; 90:
        return "B"
    elif 70 &lt;= score &lt; 80:
        return "C"
    elif 60 &lt;= score &lt; 70:
        return "D"
    elif score &lt; 60:
        return "F"


import random

data = [random.randint(50, 100) for _ in range(10)]
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>[78, 87, 93, 78, 53, 92, 64, 70, 75, 60]
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>[bin_score(x) for x in data]
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>['C', 'B', 'A', 'C', 'F', 'A', 'D', 'C', 'C', 'D']
</code></pre>
<p>For a dataset of <var>n</var> records and <var>m</var> bins, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">time
complexity</a> of this approach tends to be</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_O_notation">O</a>(<var>m</var><var>n</var>)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Because binning one record takes O(<var>m</var>) time -- O(<var>m</var>)
if-statements are checked -- and <var>n</var> records need to be binned.</p>
<p>If the number of bins <var>m</var> is constant, then the overall time
complexity is simply O(<var>n</var>).</p>
<p>But what if the number of bins <var>m</var> is large enough that the
straightforward approach is too slow?</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>For <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_or_discrete_variable">discrete data</a>, you can use <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/stdtypes.html#mapping-types-dict">dictionaries</a>. E.g., binning
fruits:</p>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>bins = {
    "lemon": "citrus",
    "orange": "citrus",
    "apple": "malinae",
    "pear": "malinae",
}

def bin_fruit(fruit):
    return bins[fruit]


import random

data = random.choices(
    ["lemon", "orange", "apple", "pear"], k=10
)
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>['lemon',
 'pear',
 'lemon',
 'lemon',
 'apple',
 'orange',
 'apple',
 'orange',
 'pear',
 'apple']
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>[bin_fruit(x) for x in data]
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>['citrus',
 'malinae',
 'citrus',
 'citrus',
 'malinae',
 'citrus',
 'malinae',
 'citrus',
 'malinae',
 'malinae']
</code></pre>
<p>Binning one record this way takes O(1) time -- regardless of the number of
bins <var>m</var> -- because <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/stdtypes.html#mapping-types-dict">dictionaries</a> are implemented using
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table">hash tables</a>. And creating the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/stdtypes.html#mapping-types-dict">dictionary</a> take O(<var>m</var>) time --
one entry for each bin. Thus, the overall time complexity, for <var>n</var>
records and <var>m</var> bins, is</p>
<blockquote>
<p>O(<var>m</var> + <var>n</var>).</p>
</blockquote>
</li>
<li>
<p>And, for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_or_discrete_variable">continuous data</a>, you can use <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.bisect">bisect.bisect</a>. E.g., turning
test scores into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Academic_grading_in_the_United_States">letter grades</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>score_bins = [60, 70, 80, 90]
score_letters = ["F", "D", "C", "B", "A"]

import bisect


def bin_score(score):
    i = bisect.bisect(score_bins, score)
    return score_letters[i]


import random

data = [random.randint(50, 100) for _ in range(10)]
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>[60, 100, 88, 98, 55, 52, 52, 94, 71, 85]
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>[bin_score(x) for x in data]
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>['D', 'A', 'B', 'A', 'F', 'F', 'F', 'A', 'C', 'B']
</code></pre>
<p>Binning one record this way takes O(logÂ&nbsp;<var>m</var>) time, because
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.bisect">bisect.bisect</a> uses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_search_algorithm">binary search</a> to navigate <code>score_bins</code>. And
creating <code>score_bins</code> takes O(<var>m</var>) time. Thus, the overall time
complexity, for <var>n</var> records and <var>m</var> bins, is</p>
<blockquote>
<p>O(<var>m</var> + <var>n</var> log <var>m</var>)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>NOTE: If you are able to use 3rd-party libraries, such as <a href="https://numpy.org/">NumPy</a> or
<a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/">Pandas</a>, then look at these functions: <a href="https://numpy.org/doc/stable/reference/generated/numpy.digitize.html">numpy.digitize</a>,
<a href="https://numpy.org/doc/stable/reference/generated/numpy.searchsorted.html#numpy.searchsorted">numpy.searchsorted</a>, <a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/reference/api/pandas.Series.searchsorted.html">pandas.Series.searchsorted</a>, <a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/reference/api/pandas.qcut.html#pandas.qcut">pandas.qcut</a>,
<a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/stable/reference/api/pandas.cut.html">pandas.cut</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>

<p>In this scenario, you have a sorted list of data and you want to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Compute <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Order_statistic">order statistics</a> (e.g. compute the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Median">median</a>).</li>
<li>Add new data.</li>
</ul>
<p>For example, you can imagine having a temperature sensor that regularly reports
the temperature. You want to regularly report the median temperature, as well
as be able to incorporate new temperature data as it arrives.</p>
<p>To me, a straightforward approach is to use <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/stdtypes.html#mutable-sequence-types">list.append</a> and
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/statistics.html#statistics.median">statistics.median</a>. E.g., monitoring temperatures:</p>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>def add_new_measurement(data, temperature):
    data.append(temperature)


def median(data):
    return statistics.median(data)


import random
import statistics

data = [random.randint(93, 100) for _ in range(10)]
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>[98, 94, 97, 94, 94, 98, 98, 94, 94, 95]
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>median(data)
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>94.5
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>add_new_measurement(data, 97)
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>[98, 94, 97, 94, 94, 98, 98, 94, 94, 95, 97]
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>median(data)
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>95
</code></pre>
<p>For a dataset of <var>n</var> records, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">time complexity</a> of this approach
tends to be</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Computing median:</strong> O(<var>n</var>) or O(<var>n</var> log <var>n</var>) --
depending on how the median is computed.</li>
<li><strong>Adding new data:</strong> O(1).</li>
</ul>
<p>So if the workload requires frequently adding new data and infrequently
computing the median, this approach works well.</p>
<p>But what if the workload is inverted? For example, if temperature measurements
are received every couple of minutes, but the median must be computed every
couple of seconds.</p>
<p>In that scenario, I think we would be better suited by speeding up computing
the median, even at the expense of slowing down adding new data.</p>
<p>Computing order statistics can be done in O(1) time if the data is already
sorted. So a straightforward way to handle this workload would be to sort the
data after appending and use the fact that the data is sorted to efficiently
compute the median:</p>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>def add_new_measurement(data, temperature):
    data.append(temperature)
    data.sort()


def median(data):
    n = len(data)
    if n % 2 == 0:
        return (data[(n // 2) - 1] + data[n // 2]) / 2
    else:
        return data[n // 2]


import random

data = sorted(random.randint(93, 100) for _ in range(10))
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>[93, 94, 94, 96, 96, 97, 98, 99, 100, 100]
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>median(data)
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>96.5
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>add_new_measurement(data, 97)
data
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>[93, 94, 94, 96, 96, 97, 97, 98, 99, 100, 100]
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<pre><code>median(data)
</code></pre>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>97
</code></pre>
<p>For a dataset of <var>n</var> records, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">time complexity</a> of this approach
tends to be</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Computing median:</strong> O(1).</li>
<li><strong>Adding new data:</strong> O(<var>n</var> log <var>n</var>).</li>
</ul>
<p>But I think that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">time complexity</a> for adding new data can further be
improved by using <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.insort">bisect.insort</a>, which runs in</p>
<blockquote>
<p>O(<var>n</var>)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Here's Python code that does that:</p>
<pre><code>import bisect


def add_new_measurement(data, temperature):
    bisect.insort(data, temperature)
</code></pre>
<p>Doing this changes the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">time complexity</a> of adding new data from</p>
<blockquote>
<p>O(<var>n</var> log <var>n</var>)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>to</p>
<blockquote>
<p>O(<var>n</var>)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In this week's post you learned how to use the <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html">bisect</a> module for
statistical data binning and adding new data to sorted lists.</p>
<p>For further reading:</p>
<ul>
<li>Algorithms that process input piece-by-piece -- like the temperature sensor
scenario -- are called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_algorithm">online algorithms</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.insort">bisect.insort</a> can be used to implement an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insertion_sort">Insertion sort</a>. Insertion
sort is an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_algorithm">online algorithm</a> and -- along with Python's built-in
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timsort">timsort</a> -- is an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adaptive_sort">adaptive sorting algorithm</a> because it takes
advantage of data that is partially sorted.</li>
</ul>
<p>My challenge to you:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html">bisect</a> module provides "left"- and "right"-variants of
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.insort">bisect.insort</a> and <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.bisect">bisect.bisect</a>: <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.insort_left">bisect.insort_left</a>,
<a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.insort_right">bisect.insort_right</a>, <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.bisect_left">bisect.bisect_left</a>, <a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/bisect.html#bisect.bisect_right">bisect.bisect_right</a>.</p>
<p>Read the documentation and figure out what the difference between the "left"-
and "right"-variants is.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you enjoyed this week's post, share it with your friends and stay tuned for
next week's post. See you then!</p>

<hr>
<p>(If you spot any errors or typos on this post, contact me via my
<a href="https://johnlekberg.com/contact.html">contact page</a>.)
</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://johnlekberg.com/blog/2020-11-21-stdlib-bisect.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25174048</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 01:20:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 133 | Comments 153 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25173522">thread link</a>) | @spekcular
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | http://paskpiano.org/about/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://paskpiano.org/about/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="30" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div>
							<div>
							<section data-id="6b7c51e" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="0db4fdb" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="89500ce" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<section data-id="02b9628" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="c6a8384" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="39c182b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>PASK – Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards – is an international movement committed to achieving change in relation to piano keyboard size.</p><p>Specifically, PASK aims to convince piano manufacturers to begin producing piano keyboards in three standard sizes. Purchasers of new pianos will then have a choice of keyboard size. In addition to the current ‘large’ size, we need two additional sizes with <u>narrower keys</u>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>The current piano keyboard has prevailed since the 1880’s and was not designed for the physical capabilities of the population at large. It has been assumed that the current size is suitable for all, whereas in fact it is isn’t. The keys are too wide for the majority of pianists, considering men, women and children of all nationalities and across all age groups.</p><p>The current keyboard size and key width suits people with large hands, generally adult males with average to above average spans. However, for those with smaller hands, today’s piano increases technical difficulties and learning time. It limits musical expression and prevents access to a large amount of the piano repertoire. Worst of all, it can cause debilitating pain and injury.</p><p>A simple analogy illustrates the point. Does it make sense that all men in an athletics race should have to wear the same size shoes? And that female athletes have to run in the same size shoes as the men? And that children have to run in the same size shoes as adults?</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div data-id="86f8594" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="93ab53a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="290" height="300" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-290x300.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-290x300.jpg 290w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-768x796.jpg 768w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2-989x1024.jpg 989w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Square-logo-2.jpg 1145w" sizes="(max-width: 290px) 100vw, 290px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="be5765d" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="6591610" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<section data-id="721b21b" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="77af1a3" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="b67b3fe" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="763" height="1024" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-763x1024.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-763x1024.jpg 763w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-224x300.jpg 224w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014-768x1031.jpg 768w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Kristen1-Nov-2014.jpg 1216w" sizes="(max-width: 763px) 100vw, 763px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div data-id="bdfaffa" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="984bedd" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div>
					<p><img width="720" height="960" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists.jpg 720w, http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Students-at-SMU-Institute-for-Young-Pianists-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px">											</p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="d469830" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="6326091" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="cb76b18" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="25d103d" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>The<strong> long term goal of PASK </strong>is for acoustic and digital piano manufacturers to offer a choice of three standard keyboard sizes in accordance with the DS standards. These are: DS5.5® (7/8) and the DS6.0® (15/16) as well as the current ‘large’ DS6.5<em>&nbsp;</em>keyboard. They need to be&nbsp;mass-produced and marketed worldwide in such a way that the new alternative sizes are readily available and naturally accepted options for all pianists and teachers.&nbsp;</p><p>For this to happen, we need to focus on both building the demand from the piano world as well as encouraging supply from manufacturers. Clearly, these are interdependent.&nbsp;</p><p>Pianists with smaller hands must create a united voice and demand access to keyboards with narrower keys. Piano teachers, universities and conservatoriums need to recognise their benefits. Competitions and concert venues should provide a choice of keyboard for performers.</p><p>Alternatively sized keyboards are currently only available from a limited number of sources, are expensive and often involve long wait times for customers. The major piano manufacturers need to take up this challenge.&nbsp;A key factor in creating change will be public support from prominent pianists, academics and teachers around the world.</p><p>There are three main strategies required to achieve this goal:</p><p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Raising awareness of the benefits of reduced size keyboards for those with smaller hands.</p><p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Creating opportunities for pianists to experience the difference in playing on narrower keys.</p><p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Breaking down barriers and resistance to change.</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="8b8c474" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="0033df0" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="dea7d2a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="heading.default">
				<p>
			<h2>PASK structure and founders</h2>		</p>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="c7ddbd5" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="3edd0c6" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="925cf88" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<p>PASK is not a formally constituted organisation, but a network of people working towards a common goal.

There are three founders of PASK:

Ms Erica Booker from Sydney, Australia – Graduate of the New South Wales Conservatorium of Music, pianist and piano teacher. Erica is also a Suzuki teacher trainer and leading advocate for alternatively sized piano keyboards:<a href="https://ericabookerpiano.com/%E2%80%8B" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&nbsp;</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://ericabookerpiano.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://ericabookerpiano.com</a>

Dr Carol Leone from Dallas, Texas – Chair of Keyboard Studies at SMU Meadows School of the Arts in Dallas, internationally recognized performing artist, teacher, lecturer, and author. Carol is one of the world’s leading researchers and proponents of ergonomic piano keyboards to promote a pianist’s wellness:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.carolleone.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.carolleone.com</a>

Ms Rhonda Boyle from Melbourne, Australia – Former government policy analyst/strategic planner with qualifications in physics, environmental science and urban planning. Rhonda is a pianist, independent researcher and author of peer-reviewed articles relating to hand size and piano playing:
<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/rhonda-boyle/30/931/352" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.linkedin.com/pub/rhonda-boyle/30/931/352</a>

<span>These three founders have no financial connections with any piano or keyboard manufacturers.</span>

The PASK network is gradually growing and now includes many others around the world who support the PASK goals and who are actively engaged in encouraging change.

If you would like to be an active member of PASK or be kept up to date on developments, please be in touch: <a href="mailto:info@paskpiano.org">info@paskpiano.org</a></p>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="d757218" data-element_type="section">
						
		</section>
				<section data-id="c8bb5bb" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="e92354b" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="759652a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div>
					<div><p>The term ESPK (ergonomically scaled piano keyboard) is now mostly used in the academic community when referring to keyboards smaller than the current ‘standard’ size i.e., with 6.5 inch octave. The term ‘reduced-size keyboard’ has also been used in some literature. &nbsp;Also note that the DS5.5®<em>&nbsp;</em>is often referred to as the ‘7/8 keyboard’ as the key widths are close to (but not exactly) 7/8 of the ‘standard’ keyboard. Likewise, the DS6.0®<em>&nbsp;</em>is often referred to as the 15/16 keyboard. ESPK is a generic term that also includes keyboards of other sizes, i.e. that do not conform to the DS standards.&nbsp;</p><p>The ‘DS’ abbreviation stands for Donison-Steinbuhler. (Chris Donison and David Steinbuhler pioneered the introduction of piano keyboards with narrower keys for acoustic pianos, mainly in North America.) &nbsp;The PASK movement (Pianists for Alternatively Sized Keyboards) generally uses the term ‘alternative sizes’ to avoid confusion as ‘reduced size’ could imply fewer than 88 keys.</p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section data-id="41a669e" data-element_type="section">
						<div>
							<div>
					<div data-id="2e65a40" data-element_type="column">
			<div>
							<div>
						<div data-id="3ee7b0a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="wp-widget-sfsi-widget.default">
				<div>
					<div data-position="widget">
			
			<div><div><p><a data-effect="" target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdiQ0iwCWFsGjZ1QI41KSBg/playlists" id="sfsiid_youtube"><img data-pin-nopin="true" alt="YouTube" title="YouTube" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/plugins/ultimate-social-media-icons/images/icons_theme/default/default_youtube.png" width="40" height="40" data-effect=""></a></p></div><div><p><a data-effect="" target="_blank" href="http://instagram.com/paskpianos" id="sfsiid_instagram"><img data-pin-nopin="true" alt="Instagram" title="Instagram" src="http://paskpiano.org/wp-content/plugins/ultimate-social-media-icons/images/icons_theme/default/default_instagram.png" width="40" height="40" data-effect=""></a></p></div></div>			
		</div>
			</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://paskpiano.org/about/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25173522</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 23:28:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Covid Vaccine Delays – Why?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25172930">thread link</a>) | @ishmandoo
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | http://blog.benwiener.com/economics/2020/11/19/vaccine-delays.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://blog.benwiener.com/economics/2020/11/19/vaccine-delays.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>I keep hearing about small delays in the vaccine development process that I don’t understand given how urgent the need is. I read a perfect example today. <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/18/health/pfizer-covid-vaccine.html">A New York Times article</a> sharing good news about the effectiveness of the Pfizer vaccine mentioned that the company would be applying for emergency use authorization “within days”. <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/11/16/health/Covid-moderna-vaccine.html%22">A similar article</a> cited a period of weeks for the Moderna vaccine. This progress is great news. It made me wonder, though, why not today? What prevented these companies from being ready to file with the FDA right away?</p>

<p>By all accounts, the rapid progress of COVID-19 vaccine candidates has been miraculous. Still, I’m confused by the apparent lack of urgency in certain parts of the process. Most of the vaccine development work is probably difficult to speed up. For example, it isn’t possible to speed up the rate at which trial participants get exposed to the virus so that effectiveness can be proven<sup id="fnref:hcc" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:hcc">1</a></sup>. But what prevents Pfizer and Moderna from pre-writing their application to the FDA while the trial is running and netting a few days or weeks? Even just a few days has serious value. Of course, the data is still coming in so there would be some uncertainty about what should be written in the application. But they must have a pretty good sense of how the trial is going. They could even pre-write two or three versions to cover the most likely scenarios. And of all possible trial outcomes, why would these companies both be unprepared for best-case scenarios where their vaccines are proving to be highly effective?</p>

<p>Getting a bit more speculative, why aren’t scientists at Pfizer and Moderna already in conversation with decision makers at the FDA so that the evaluation process can be started based on preliminary data? Then they could be possibly be ready to issue emergency use authorization immediately once the trial concludes. If there is an unexpected change in the latest data regulators should of course be prepared to reassess. To be clear, I am not suggesting that the approval process be less rigorous. I just want it happening in parallel with the trial as much as it can. Given how ridiculously destructive this pandemic is, I sure hope COVID vaccines are the FDA’s top priority.</p>

<p>This possibility reminds me of the mechanics of my thesis defense. My adviser, the main decision maker, was already very familiar with my work. Little information was actually transmitted to him that day. He already knew what he needed to know to make his decision. In fact, we wouldn’t have even gone forward with the defense if he wasn’t ready to pass me. He didn’t take a month after the defense to closely read my thesis, consider all the arguments, check the math, and then deliberate. That process occurred while the data was coming in. Maybe some parallelization of the approval process like this is happening for the COVID vaccines, but I’ve never read anything that gives the sense that it is.</p>

<h3 id="possible-answers-to-my-own-questions">Possible answers to my own questions:</h3>
<h4 id="why-werent-the-eua-applications-ready">Why weren’t the EUA applications ready?</h4>

<p>Maybe a document like this is <em>way</em> more complicated than I’m imagining and the drug companies are writing them as fast as possible. This sort of suggests that writing the application is a similar challenge to developing the vaccine. I hope that’s not right.</p>

<p>Maybe the drug companies <em>are</em> already working with the FDA, and the timing of the application isn’t important. As I mentioned above, I’ve never seen anything that suggests this.</p>

<p>Maybe these companies aren’t incentivized to actually get the vaccine to market as fast as they can. Off the bat this didn’t seem right to me, but could the advance purchase agreements that Moderna and Pfizer signed with governments eliminate their urgency?</p>

<h4 id="why-arent-the-drug-companies-working-with-the-fda">Why aren’t the drug companies working with the FDA?</h4>

<p>Maybe this just isn’t the way the FDA usually works and they weren’t able to adapt to this extraordinary situation.</p>

<p>Obviously scientific integrity is important here. Maybe the scientists are intentionally kept separate from other parts of Pfizer and from the FDA to prevent some kind of academic dishonesty. I wonder about the relative dangers involved, but I could imagine an explanation like this.</p>

<h3 id="answers-that-other-people-have-suggested">Answers that other people have suggested:</h3>

<p>Commenters on Hacker News and Reddit have suggested that the things I want to happen are already happening. I’ve looked into this a little bit, and I’m unsure. Both Moderna and Pfizer have been granted the FDA’s <a href="https://www.fda.gov/patients/fast-track-breakthrough-therapy-accelerated-approval-priority-review/fast-track">Fast Track status</a>. This sounds great. It apparently means these companies have the opportunity for closer collaboration with the FDA, at least on clinical trial design. Some have suggested that the companies would also already be sharing advance results from their studies, but I haven’t found any reference saying that.</p>

<p>Fast Track also gives them the opportunity to participate in Rolling Review, which allows them to submit sections of their applications as they become ready. The references I’ve found discussing this are mostly <a href="https://www.pfizer.com/news/press-release/press-release-detail/pfizer-and-biontech-submit-emergency-use-authorization">press releases by the companies</a> or closely based on them. They discuss participation in Rolling Review in Europe and elsewhere, but I haven’t seen that they are doing this in the US.</p>



  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://blog.benwiener.com/economics/2020/11/19/vaccine-delays.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25172930</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 21:37:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Best of NeXT Collection]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25172693">thread link</a>) | @mpweiher
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="container">
    <!-- Start container -->

    <!-- End sidebar wrapper -->

    <div id="contentContainer">
      <!-- Start main content wrapper -->

      <div id="content">
        <!-- Start content -->

        <p><img alt="KeyFobHeader6" src="http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/files/page0_1.jpg" width="604" height="197">
        <br></p>

        <p><span>After Steve Jobs was forced out of Apple
        in 1985, everyone wanted to know what Steve would do
        next.... so NeXT was what he did.
        <p>
        
        In 1988 his NeXT team launched a new kind of computer for
        it's time, built on standards with a Unix core but with a
        user experience "my grandma could understand". It was well
        ahead of it's time, so naturally, it was not embraced by
        main stream consumers... a classic "Crossing the Chasm"
        issue. But many saw it for what it was, a breakthrough
        product as innovative as today's iTunes, iPod and iPhone.
        </p><p>
        
        Building upon NeXT's hardware and more importantly, their
        software development environment, many third party NeXT
        developers added their own magic dust to create
        revolutionary products, like the world's first web browser,
        or a new form of spread sheet, Lotus Improv or WebObjects,
        the foundation upon which the iTune store is built, to name
        only a few. Some of these ground breaking products may
        never be repeated. Most contained innovations embraced by
        future applications, with a clear lineage back to NeXTSTEP.
        </p><p>
        
        During the relatively short time of NeXT ascendency
        (1985-1996), Apple was bleeding red ink from repeated
        financial losses and two hugely expensive attempts to
        create a follow on Operating System. Apple's third
        president since Steve's departure, Gil Amelio saw the
        merits of Steve, his team and their technology. In December
        1996 Apple bought Next. Then the Next team took over Apple.
        The result is their hugely successful Mac OS X, built on
        the foundations of the NeXTSTEP OS.
        </p><p>
        
        While NeXT is no more, as a product or a stand alone
        company, it's impact on the industry will be felt for years
        to come. We should remember it, perhaps even study it. In
        decades to come, it will be understood as a watershed of
        innovation. Current Mac and iPhone users will be astonished
        to see how many of their beloved Mac OS X innovations had
        their roots in NeXTSTEP. There are many lessons about
        product innovation, market acceptance, and the creative
        people involved, that have yet to be uncovered.
        </p><p>
        
        This web site details part of our unique collection of NeXT
        related products and assorted items which grew up around
        NeXT Computer ecosystem, including of course NeXT hardware
        but also those rare items such as dealer sales kits, logo'd
        clothing, NeXT jewelry, banners, training tapes for
        servicing NeXT computers and printers, developer guides,
        plus third party software and hardware products.
        </p><p>
        
        While the site describes only part of the actual
        collection, the site does cover over 800 NeXT and third
        party products, many with multipage brochures and white
        papers. If you were to print all the html and PDF documents
        it would be over 3,000 pages.
        </p><p>
        
        This site describes what may well be the most extensive
        NeXT related collection available today.
        </p><p>
        
        It's history worth preserving.
        </p></span></p>

        
      </div><!-- End content -->

      <!-- End Footer -->
    </div><!-- End main content wrapper -->
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.kevra.org/TheBestOfNext/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25172693</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 20:55:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[FTC commissioner met with Apple regarding Facebook’s iOS 14 complaints]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 92 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25171707">thread link</a>) | @aeromusek
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a href="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings.jpg" data-caption=""><img width="696" height="416" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-696x416.jpg" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-696x416.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-300x179.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-768x459.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings-702x420.jpg 702w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings.jpg 926w" sizes="(max-width: 696px) 100vw, 696px" alt="FTC-Apple-Facebook-iOS14" title="FTC_Apple_Facebook_Meetings"></a></p><p>In a<span>&nbsp;</span>letter sent to the Ranking Digital Rights organization, Apple’s Jane Horvath, senior director of global privacy, reiterated that the company believes that<strong> “privacy is a fundamental human right.”</strong></p><p>Horvath explains that Apple <span>delayed the App Tracking Transparency (ATT) feature</span> to give developers more time to prepare for the changes.</p><h2><strong>Facebook’s complaints about Apple’s App Tracking Transparency (ATT)</strong></h2><p>Facebook has criticized the App Tracking Transparency feature and said it <span>could cause ad revenue to&nbsp;drop as much as 40%</span>.</p><p>Facebook has reportedly met with advertising partners to discuss the impact the change has on advertising when users have the ability to easily opt-out of cross-platform tracking.</p><p>The company also announced the following <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/preparing-our-partners-for-ios-14-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">in a press release</a> on Sept 10th.</p><blockquote><p>“We, along with the rest of the business community, continue to await final policy details from Apple.”</p><p>Given Apple’s delayed implementation of the user permission requirement, we will continue collecting IDFA on iOS 14 in an attempt to reduce unnecessary disruption to our customers’ businesses.”</p></blockquote><p>We checked in with FTC to see if they were looking into some of the claims made by FaceBook against Apple’s iOS 14.</p><figure id="attachment_1004628" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1004628"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple.jpg" alt="FTC looking into Facebook's complaints against Apple" width="977" height="511" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple.jpg 977w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-300x157.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-768x402.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-696x364.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-investigating-Facebooks-claim-against-Apple-803x420.jpg 803w" sizes="(max-width: 977px) 100vw, 977px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1004628">Email send by FTC commissioner on Aug 28th (Source: myHealthyApple.com)</figcaption></figure><p>It appears, based on the reports under our FOIA filing, that Noah Philips, FTC commissioner reached out to Kate Adams from <strong>Apple on 28th August</strong> to understand some of the details around Facebook’s complaints.</p><p>A meeting was subsequently scheduled between Apple’s team and FTC attorneys around the first week of September.</p><figure id="attachment_1004629" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1004629"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14.jpg" alt="FTC Meeting with Apple on iOS 14" width="967" height="650" srcset="https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14.jpg 967w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-300x202.jpg 300w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-768x516.jpg 768w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-696x468.jpg 696w, https://www.myhealthyapple.com/wp-content/uploads/FTC-meeting-with-Apple-about-IOS-14-625x420.jpg 625w" sizes="(max-width: 967px) 100vw, 967px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1004629">Source: MyHealthyApple.com</figcaption></figure><p>Given the timing of Apple’s announcement today, it is clear that the company has good cause to take this position following meetings with FTC.</p><p>According to the letter today, Apple continues to emphasize that advertising that protects user privacy is possible.</p><p>You can read today’s complete Apple’s letter posted by Chance Miller at <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/11/19/apple-privacy-letter-ios-14-facebook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">9to5Mac</a>.</p><p><em>As an Amazon Associate MyHealthyApple may earn commissions from qualifying purchases using our links</em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.myhealthyapple.com/etc-apple-facebook-ios14/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25171707</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 18:41:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: WireGuard vs. OpenVPN, a 2.5x Difference]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170710">thread link</a>) | @vpnintel
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://vpnintel.com/insights/one-month-of-speedtest-data-shows-wireguard-is-2.5x-faster-than-openvpn | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vpnintel.com/insights/one-month-of-speedtest-data-shows-wireguard-is-2.5x-faster-than-openvpn">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div>
      

      <p>
        WireGuard has gained traction over the past few years due, in part, to its high performance. We wondered how fast it really is, and realized that since we're already tracking VPN performance metrics for our <a href="https://vpnintel.com/unit-prices">VPN unit price index</a>, we could use the same data to answer the question, <strong>"how much faster is WireGuard than OpenVPN?"</strong>
      </p>

      <p>
        We focused on Windscribe, Mullvad, and NordVPN, three providers that support both WireGuard and OpenVPN, and built a <a href="https://vpnintel.com/wireguard-vs-openvpn">dashboard</a> to visualize their comparative download speeds. We've embedded the charts for the week ending November 20, 2020 below along with some commentary.
      </p>

      <p>
        Note that all data on this page represent speedtests between U.S.-based speedtest servers and VPNs. Our methodology section below has more on this.
      </p>
    </div>

    <p>
      <h2>Windscribe</h2>
    </p>
    <p>
      For the week ending November 20, 2020, Windscribe's average download speed over OpenVPN was <span>134 Mbps</span> and its average download speed over WireGuard was <span>363 Mbps</span>. This means that by simply toggling the WireGuard option, Windscribe users can get a free 2.7x speed boost!
    </p>
    <p><img src="https://vpnintel.com/assets/news-dfd25285653d0eb57e648315d449e97092408746e1412f7bc9b4ed13395df2ab.svg">
       As of November 24, 2020, our 7-day Windscribe averages are 339 Mbps for WireGuard and 144 Mbps for OpenVPN.
    </p>

    
    <p>
        Windscribe's Wireguard speeds are almost always in the 300-400 Mbps ranges. Dig deeper into performance and pricing info on our dedicated pages for <a href="https://vpnintel.com/windscribe-wireguard">Windscribe WireGuard</a> and <a href="https://vpnintel.com/windscribe">Windscribe OpenVPN</a>.
      </p>

    <p>
      <h2>Mullvad</h2>
    </p>
    <p>
      Mullvad was one of WireGuard's earliest commercial supporters. For the week ending November 20, 2020, Mullvad's average download speed over OpenVPN was <span>258 Mbps</span> and its average download speed over WireGuard was <span>672 Mbps</span> – a free 2.6x performance boost for Mullvad's WireGuard users!
    </p>
    <p><img src="https://vpnintel.com/assets/news-dfd25285653d0eb57e648315d449e97092408746e1412f7bc9b4ed13395df2ab.svg">
       As of November 24, 2020, our 7-day Mullvad averages are 676 Mbps for WireGuard and 273 Mbps for OpenVPN.
    </p>

    
    <p>
        Mullvad's WireGuard speeds consistently land in the 600-700 Mbps range. Take a closer look at the pricing and performance data on our dedicated pages for <a href="https://vpnintel.com/mullvad">Mullvad WireGuard</a> and <a href="https://vpnintel.com/mullvad-openvpn">Mullvad OpenVPN</a>.
      </p>

    <p>
      <h2>NordVPN</h2>
    </p>
    <p>
        NordVPN launched support for WireGuard via its NordLynx product in Spring 2020. For the week ending November 20, 2020, Mullvad's average download speed over OpenVPN was <span>395 Mbps</span>. If the only number you remember from this page is NordVPN's average WireGuard download speed, you'll have the idea: a ridiculously fast <span>777 Mbps</span>, a 1.9x boost over its OpenVPN service.
      </p>
    <p><img src="https://vpnintel.com/assets/news-dfd25285653d0eb57e648315d449e97092408746e1412f7bc9b4ed13395df2ab.svg">
       As of November 24, 2020, our 7-day NordVPN averages are 780 Mbps for WireGuard and 416 Mbps for OpenVPN.
    </p>

    
    <p>
        You can see that NordVPN actually exceeds gigabit speeds on occasion. Its WireGuard speeds have a bit more variance than the other providers, but is uniformly well above 500 Mbps. For a deeper dive into NordLynx pricing and performance, check out our dedicated pages for <a href="https://vpnintel.com/nordvpn-wireguard">NordVPN WireGuard/NordLynx</a> and <a href="https://vpnintel.com/nordvpn">NordVPN OpenVPN</a>.
      </p>

    <p>
      <h2>Conclusions</h2>
    </p>
    <div>
      <p>
        For the week ending November 20, 2020, our global average download speed over OpenVPN was <span>251 Mbps</span> and <span>583 Mbps</span> over WireGuard – WireGuard outperformed OpenVPN by an incredible 230%!
      </p>
      <p>
        All the more incredible is that customers of these services get this speed boost for free simply by selecting the WireGuard option.
      </p>
      <p>
        NordVPN's 1.9x ratio is a little lower than the other providers', but it still has a massive raw speed advantage. If NordVPN can get its WireGuard speeds up to the 2.5x+ ratios held by Windscribe and Mullvad, then it will be consistently serving gigabit speeds.
      </p>
      <p>
        That's it for now! We think this stuff is interesting, so we'll probably make this a monthly or quarterly report. If you'd like to know when we launch new tools and publish reports like this, please join our newsletter:
      </p>

      <div><p>
        Be the first to hear about new tools and reports
        </p><!-- Begin Mailchimp Signup Form -->
        
        <!--End mc_embed_signup-->
      </div>
    </div>
    <p><img src="https://vpnintel.com/assets/news-dfd25285653d0eb57e648315d449e97092408746e1412f7bc9b4ed13395df2ab.svg">
       As of November 24, 2020, WireGuard clocks in at 598 Mbps to OpenVPN's 287 Mbps, a 2.1x speed boost.
    </p>

    <div>
      <h2>Methodology</h2>
      <p>
        Our system is fully automated which lets us take thousands of readings a day. The data on this page represents speedtests conducted between servers based in the U.S. and VPN servers also based in the U.S. – the speeds shown here are likely to be faster than what you would experience at home.
      </p>

      <p>
        All speedtests are done over UDP with the native OpenVPN and WireGuard Linux clients except for NordVPN's NordLynx/WireGuard service which uses the NordVPN Linux client since NordVPN does not provide WireGuard configuration files.
      </p>

      <p>
        At least as of November 20, 2020, you'll see some lumps shared across the three charts which may reflect resource usage patterns for our own hosting provider. We will report back on this.
      </p>
    </div>

    
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vpnintel.com/insights/one-month-of-speedtest-data-shows-wireguard-is-2.5x-faster-than-openvpn</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170710</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 16:44:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Production-Oriented Development]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 169 | Comments 123 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170547">thread link</a>) | @kiyanwang
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
          <p><span></span> read
          </p>
          <a name="topofpage"></a>
          <p>Throughout my career, I’ve developed some <em>opinions</em>. Some have worn particularly deep ruts,
reinforced by years of experience. I tried to figure out what these
had in common, and it’s
the idea that <strong>code in production is the only code that matters</strong>. Staging doesn’t
matter, code on your laptop doesn’t matter, QA doesn’t matter,
only production matters. Everything else is debt.</p>

<p>This perspective probably comes from years sitting in between
operations and product development. I strongly
believe that teams should optimize for getting code to production as quickly as
possible as well as responding to incidents in production.</p>

<p>This idea, and a lot of the practices it implies, can be
counter-intuitive or controversial, so I want to dive into them a little
further. What follows is a set of practices and principles I believe are true,
considering my underlying belief that code working in production is the only
code that matters.</p>

<h2 id="engineers-should-operate-their-code">1. Engineers should operate their code.</h2>

<p><strong>Engineers are the subject matter experts for the code they write and should be
responsible for operating it in production</strong>. In this context, “operating” means
deploying, instrumenting, and monitoring code as well as helping to resolve
incidents related to or impacting that code. The responsibility of operating
code aligns incentives - it encourages engineers to write code that is
observable and easy to debug, and connects them to what customers really care
about. It encourages them to be curious about how their code is performing in
production. Importantly, engineers should be on-call for their code - being
on-call creates a positive feedback loop and makes it easier to know if their
efforts in writing production-ready code are paying off. I’ve heard people
complain about the prospect of being on-call, so I’ll just ask this: if you’re
not on-call for your code, who is?</p>

<p>If you’re not currently on-call for your code but want to be, and can help
influence this decision, there are some things you can do. Set up PagerDuty (or
similar) schedules for each group of engineers responsible for specific
services or parts of your code. A good schedule has 6–8 engineers. There are
plenty of variations, but a typical template is to have one-week rotations,
where you’ll be on-call for secondary for a week and then primary for a week.
Configuring alerts is a separate topic, which probably deserves it’s own blog
post entirely, but focus on things that impact your customers (see:
Symptom-based alerting) and remember that you’re ultimately responsible for how
you respond to alerts, which means you can change them.</p>

<p>There are two talks I’d recommend watching that touch on the topic of
configuring alerts: Liz Fong-Jones talks about SLOs in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MT4jbUzEVL0">Cultivating Production Excellence</a> and Aditya Mukerjee does a great job talking about techniques for
managing alerts in <a href="https://vimeo.com/274820572">Warning: This Talk Contains Content Known to the State of California to Reduce Alert Fatigue</a>.</p>

<h2 id="buy-almost-always-beatsbuild">2. Buy Almost Always Beats&nbsp;Build</h2>

<p><strong>If you can avoid building something, you should.</strong> Code is the most expensive
way to solve a problem that isn’t addressing a core area of your business. For
most small to mid-sized companies, there are open source or better yet, hosted
solutions that solve a wide range of common problems. I mean things like git
repository hosting (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, etc), observability tooling
(Honeycomb, Lightstep, etc), managed databases (Amazon RDS, Confluent Kafka,
etc), alerting (PagerDuty, OpsGenie, etc) and a whole host of other commodity
technologies. This even applies to your infrastructure - if you can help
it, don’t roll your own Kubernetes clusters (side note: do you even need to use
Kubernetes?), don’t roll your own load balancers if you can use Amazon ELB or
ALBs.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Not_invented_here">NIH</a> syndrome is very real and some companies get burned badly by
this. I’ve seen teams light time and money on fire reinventing components when
better, more battle-tested alternatives exist in the market. Those same teams
almost always end up spending years contending with the resulting technical
debt. If you’re on such a team and have the will and ability to impact change,
start rolling back these decisions one by one. Migrate your databases to a
managed provider, migrate your feature flagging system to a SaaS tool (i.e.
LaunchDarkly). Keep going until the only software you maintain yourselves is
the software that delivers value to your customers. You’ll be much, much better
off for it.</p>

<h2 id="make-deployseasy">3. Make Deploys&nbsp;Easy</h2>

<p>Deploying should be a frequent and unexciting activity. <strong>Engineers should be
able to deploy with minimal manual steps and it should be easy to see if the
deploy is successful</strong> (this requires instrumenting your code for observability,
which - tada - is covered above), and it should be easy to roll back a deploy
if something doesn’t go well. Deploying frequently implies that
deploys are smaller, and smaller deploys are generally easier, faster and
safer.</p>

<p>Many teams implement periods where deploys are forbidden - these can be
referred to as code freezes, or deploy policies like “Don’t deploy on Fridays”.
Having such blackout periods can lead to a pile-up of changes, which increases
the overall risk of something going very wrong.</p>

<p>If you’re on a team that fears deploys, dedicate a percentage of your
engineering time to improvements in your deployment pipeline until the fear is
gone. On a recent team I worked with, we were able to improve deploy times from
3 hours to 30 minutes, which drastically improved the teams’ confidence in the
deploy process. A natural side effect of this was that engineers started
deploying much more frequently instead of waiting for changes to pile up enough
to warrant a “release” (which was synonymous with a deploy).</p>

<p>The book
<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Accelerate-Software-Performing-Technology-Organizations/dp/1942788339">Accelerate</a>
has been getting a lot of attention. If you haven’t read it, I’d recommend it.
The team behind it also publishes the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/devops/">State of DevOps</a>
reports, which are full of well-researched information about what various
companies in the industry are doing. It’s not a coincidence that two of the
four key metrics that the book focuses on are directly related to this (Deploy
Frequency, Change Lead Time). Shipping is <a href="https://www.heavybit.com/library/podcasts/o11ycast/ep-12-speed-of-deployment-with-rich-archbold-of-intercom/">your company’s heartbeat</a>.</p>

<h2 id="trust-the-people-closest-to-theknives">4. Trust the People Closest to the&nbsp;Knives</h2>

<p><strong>The people who work with a system are the ones who understand it best.</strong> This
applies to any part of the socio-technical systems within which we all work. In
the case of software systems, the engineers who deploy every day and are
on-call for critical services understand the level of risk they operate in. A
sad trend is that managers tend to overestimate their teams’ progress on
certain transitions - i.e. cloud-native, DevOps, etc. The higher up the
management chain, the larger this overestimation tends to be. Engineers who
deploy and get paged when things break know where the bodies are buried and
they know what needs the most work. They should, therefore, be the primary
stakeholders responsible for prioritizing technical work.</p>

<p>Another manifestation of this principle applies to platform or services teams.
If you’re responsible for building some shared component that’s used within
your organization (i.e. a messaging system, ci/cd infrastructure, shared
libraries or services) there’s an uncomfortable truth lurking for you: the
people who use your work know more about it than you do in many cases. They
understand implicitly how it serves customers and they know what contortions or
hoops they have to jump through to get it to work. Listen to them for
clues on how to improve the UX of your services and tools.</p>

<h2 id="qa-gates-make-qualityworse">5. QA Gates Make Quality&nbsp;Worse</h2>

<p>Many teams have a manual QA step that gets performed before deploys. The idea,
I guess, is to have someone run automated or manual tests to verify that a set
of changes are ready to be released. This sounds like a comforting
idea - having a human being (or team of human beings) “verify” a release before
it goes out - <strong>but it falls victim to several false assumptions and creates
some misalignments that do more harm than good.</strong></p>

<p>First of all, if there’s manual work that needs to be done before a deploy can
go out, that creates a bottleneck - if you’re making deploys easy, and
deploying small changes frequently, no QA team is going to be able to keep up
testing every deploy, and will inevitably block teams from deploying. That’s no
good. If you have manual tests, automate them and build them into your CI
pipeline (if they do deliver value).</p>

<p>Secondly, the teams doing QA often lack context and are under time pressure.
They may end up testing “effects” instead of “intents”. For example, I’ve seen
QA teams burn time testing that when something happens in a UI, something
related happens in a database. What happens when an engineer refactors that UI
component and changes the underlying data model? The functionality works, but
the test breaks. Because two teams are involved, this takes coordination and
time to fix. Similarly, I’ve seen QA teams block deploys because of failing
tests when caching was introduced at the CDN layer - a TTL of 5 seconds on an
activity feed may not ever be noticed by a user but it might break QA tests
causing unnecessary conflicts between product and QA engineers.</p>

<p>Luckily, solving this one is easy. Instead of having a dedicated QA team work
on creating manual and automated test cases that run in a fictitious QA
environment, reassign that team to work on continuous testing in production.
Instead of being a gate for deploys, a QA team could continuously verify that
production is working as expected. QA teams are also well situated to lead
Chaos Engineering initiatives, where faults are intentionally injected in
production. QA engineers could also work on making the CI/CD pipeline more
reliable, so that deploys are no longer a nightmare.</p>

<h2 id="boring-technology-isgreat">6. Boring Technology is&nbsp;Great.</h2>

<p>With thanks to <a href="https://mcfunley.com/choose-boring-technology">Dan McKinley</a>,
always <strong>strive for boring tech when possible</strong>. Systems are inherently
unpredictable, and you want a wide …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html">https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paulosman.me/2019/12/30/production-oriented-development.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170547</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 16:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Winding down my Debian involvement (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 175 | Comments 186 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170312">thread link</a>) | @ecliptik
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
  
  <details>
    <summary>Table of contents</summary>
    <nav>
<ul>
<li>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-does-this-mean">What does this mean?</a></li>
<li><a href="#why">Why?</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#change-process-in-debian">Change process in Debian</a></li>
<li><a href="#fragmented-workflow-and-infrastructure">Fragmented workflow and infrastructure</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-package-uploads">Old infrastructure: package uploads</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-bug-tracker">Old infrastructure: bug tracker</a></li>
<li><a href="#old-infrastructure-mailing-list-archives">Old infrastructure: mailing list archives</a></li>
<li><a href="#debian-is-hard-to-machine-read">Debian is hard to machine-read</a></li>
<li><a href="#complicated-build-stack">Complicated build stack</a></li>
<li><a href="#developer-experience-pretty-painful">Developer experience pretty painful</a></li>
<li><a href="#i-have-more-ideas">I have more ideas</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
</nav>
  </details>
  

<p>This post is hard to write, both in the emotional sense but also in the “I would
have written a shorter letter, but I didn’t have the time” sense. Hence, please
assume the best of intentions when reading it—it is not my intention to make
anyone feel bad about their contributions, but rather to provide some insight
into why my frustration level ultimately exceeded the threshold.</p>

<p>Debian has been in my life for well over 10 years at this point.</p>

<p>A few weeks ago, I have visited some old friends at the Zürich Debian meetup
after a multi-year period of absence. On my bike ride home, it occurred to me
that the topics of our discussions had remarkable overlap with my last visit. We
had a discussion about the merits of systemd, which took a detour to respect in
open source communities, returned to processes in Debian and eventually
culminated in democracies and their theoretical/practical failings. Admittedly,
that last one might be a Swiss thing.</p>

<p>I say this not to knock on the Debian meetup, but because it prompted me to
reflect on what feelings Debian is invoking lately and whether it’s still a good
fit for me.</p>

<p>So I’m finally making a decision that I should have made a long time ago: I am
winding down my involvement in Debian to a minimum.</p>

<h2 id="what-does-this-mean">What does this mean?</h2>

<p>Over the coming weeks, I will:</p>

<ul>
<li>transition packages to be team-maintained where it makes sense</li>
<li>remove myself from the <code>Uploaders</code> field on packages with other maintainers</li>
<li>orphan packages where I am the sole maintainer</li>
</ul>

<p>I will try to keep up best-effort maintenance of the
<a href="https://manpages.debian.org/">manpages.debian.org</a> service and the
<a href="https://codesearch.debian.net/">codesearch.debian.net</a> service, but any help
would be much appreciated.</p>

<p>For all intents and purposes, please treat me as permanently on vacation. I will
try to be around for administrative issues (e.g. permission transfers) and
questions addressed directly to me, permitted they are easy enough to answer.</p>

<h2 id="why">Why?</h2>

<p>When I joined Debian, I was still studying, i.e. I had luxurious amounts of
spare time. Now, over 5 years of full time work later, my day job taught me a
lot, both about what works in large software engineering projects and how I
personally like my computer systems. I am very conscious of how I spend the
little spare time that I have these days.</p>

<p>The following sections each deal with what I consider a major pain point, in no
particular order. Some of them influence each other—for example, if changes
worked better, we could have a chance at transitioning packages to be more
easily machine readable.</p>

<h3 id="change-process-in-debian">Change process in Debian</h3>

<p>The last few years, my current team at work conducted various smaller and larger
refactorings across the entire code base (touching thousands of projects), so we
have learnt a lot of valuable lessons about how to effectively do these
changes. It irks me that Debian works almost the opposite way in every regard. I
appreciate that every organization is different, but I think a lot of my points
do actually apply to Debian.</p>

<p>In Debian, packages are nudged in the right direction by a document called the
<a href="https://www.debian.org/doc/debian-policy/">Debian Policy</a>, or its programmatic
embodiment, lintian.</p>

<p>While it is great to have a lint tool (for quick, local/offline feedback), it is
even better to not require a lint tool at all. The team conducting the change
(e.g. the C++ team introduces a new hardening flag for all packages) should be
able to do their work transparent to me.</p>

<p>Instead, currently, all packages become lint-unclean, all maintainers need to
read up on what the new thing is, how it might break, whether/how it affects
them, manually run some tests, and finally decide to opt in. This causes a lot
of overhead and manually executed mechanical changes across packages.</p>

<p>Notably, the <strong>cost of each change</strong> is distributed onto the package maintainers in
the Debian model. At work, we have found that the opposite works better: if the
team behind the change is put in power to do the change for as many users as
possible, they can be significantly more efficient at it, which reduces the
total cost and time a lot. Of course, exceptions (e.g. a large project abusing a
language feature) should still be taken care of by the respective owners, but
the important bit is that the default should be the other way around.</p>

<p>Debian is <strong>lacking tooling for large changes</strong>: it is hard to programmatically
deal with packages and repositories (see the section below). The closest to
“sending out a change for review” is to open a bug report with an attached
patch. I thought the workflow for accepting a change from a bug report was too
complicated and started <a href="https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2016-07-17-mergebot/">mergebot</a>, but only Guido
ever signaled interest in the project.</p>

<p>Culturally, reviews and reactions are slow. There are no deadlines. I literally
sometimes get emails notifying me that a patch I sent out a few years ago (!!)
is now merged. This turns projects from a small number of weeks into many years,
which is a huge demotivator for me.</p>

<p>Interestingly enough, you can see artifacts of the slow online activity manifest
itself in the offline culture as well: I don’t want to be discussing systemd’s
merits 10 years after I first heard about it.</p>

<p>Lastly, changes can easily be slowed down significantly by holdouts who refuse
to collaborate. My canonical example for this is rsync, whose maintainer refused
my patches to make the package use debhelper purely out of personal preference.</p>

<p>Granting so much personal freedom to individual maintainers prevents us as a
project from raising the abstraction level for building Debian packages, which
in turn makes tooling harder.</p>

<p>How would things look like in a better world?</p>

<ol>
<li>As a project, we should strive towards more unification. Uniformity still
does not rule out experimentation, it just changes the trade-off from easier
experimentation and harder automation to harder experimentation and easier
automation.</li>
<li>Our culture needs to shift from “this package is my domain, how dare you
touch it” to a shared sense of ownership, where anyone in the project can
easily contribute (reviewed) changes without necessarily even involving
individual maintainers.</li>
</ol>

<p>To learn more about how successful large changes can look like, I recommend <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TrC6ROeV4GI">my
colleague Hyrum Wright’s talk “Large-Scale Changes at Google: Lessons Learned
From 5 Yrs of Mass Migrations”</a>.</p>

<h3 id="fragmented-workflow-and-infrastructure">Fragmented workflow and infrastructure</h3>

<p>Debian generally seems to prefer decentralized approaches over centralized
ones. For example, individual packages are maintained in separate repositories
(as opposed to in one repository), each repository can use any SCM (git and svn
are common ones) or no SCM at all, and each repository can be hosted on a
different site. Of course, what you do in such a repository also varies subtly
from team to team, and even within teams.</p>

<p>In practice, non-standard hosting options are used rarely enough to not justify
their cost, but frequently enough to be a huge pain when trying to automate
changes to packages. Instead of using GitLab’s API to create a merge request,
you have to design an entirely different, more complex system, which deals with
intermittently (or permanently!) unreachable repositories and abstracts away
differences in patch delivery (bug reports, merge requests, pull requests,
email, …).</p>

<p>Wildly diverging workflows is not just a temporary problem either. I
participated in long discussions about different git workflows during DebConf
13, and gather that there were similar discussions in the meantime.</p>

<p>Personally, I cannot keep enough details of the different workflows in my
head. Every time I touch a package that works differently than mine, it
frustrates me immensely to re-learn aspects of my day-to-day.</p>

<p>After noticing workflow fragmentation in the Go packaging team (which I
started), I tried fixing this with the <a href="https://go-team.pages.debian.net/workflow-changes.html">workflow changes
proposal</a>, but did not
succeed in implementing it. The lack of effective automation and slow pace of
changes in the surrounding tooling despite my willingness to contribute time and
energy killed any motivation I had.</p>

<h3 id="old-infrastructure-package-uploads">Old infrastructure: package uploads</h3>

<p>When you want to make a package available in Debian, you upload GPG-signed files
via anonymous FTP. There are several batch jobs (the queue daemon, <code>unchecked</code>,
<code>dinstall</code>, possibly others) which run on fixed schedules (e.g. <code>dinstall</code> runs
at 01:52 UTC, 07:52 UTC, 13:52 UTC and 19:52 UTC).</p>

<p>Depending on timing, I estimated that you might wait for over 7 hours (!!)
before your package is actually installable.</p>

<p>What’s worse for me is that feedback to your upload is asynchronous. I like to
do one thing, be done with it, move to the next thing. The current setup
requires a many-minute wait and costly task switch for no good technical
reason. You might think a few minutes aren’t a big deal, but when all the time I
can spend on Debian per day is measured in minutes, this makes a huge difference
in perceived productivity and fun.</p>

<p>The last communication I can find about speeding up this process is <a href="https://lists.debian.org/debian-project/2008/12/msg00014.html">ganneff’s
post</a> from 2008.</p>

<p>How would things look like in a better world?</p>

<ol>
<li>Anonymous FTP would be replaced by a web service which ingests my package and
returns an authoritative accept or reject decision in its response.</li>
<li>For accepted packages, there would be a status page displaying the build
status and when the package will be available via the mirror network.</li>
<li>Packages should be available within a few minutes after the build completed.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="old-infrastructure-bug-tracker">Old infrastructure: bug tracker</h3>

<p>I dread interacting with the Debian bug
tracker. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debbugs">debbugs</a> is a piece of software
(from 1994) which is only used by Debian and the GNU project these days.</p>

<p>Debbugs processes emails, which is to say it is asynchronous and cumbersome to
deal with. Despite running on the fastest machines we …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/">https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://michael.stapelberg.ch/posts/2019-03-10-debian-winding-down/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170312</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 15:53:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I got rich on the other hand (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 87 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25170030">thread link</a>) | @damir
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://sive.rs/richand | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sive.rs/richand">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

<article>
<header>


<small>2019-10-30</small>
<audio src="https://m.sive.rs/sive.rs.richand.mp3" preload="none" controls="controls"></audio></header>

<p>
I don’t usually talk about money, but a friend asked me what it was like to get rich, and he wanted to know specifics, so I told him my story.
</p><p>
I had <a href="https://sive.rs/xn">a day job</a> in midtown Manhattan paying $20K per year — about minimum wage.
On weekends I would earn $150 per day performing circus shows for kids, though I’d spend about $50 in bus fare to get to the gigs.
I was sharing a three-bedroom apartment with two other roommates in Queens, so our rent was $333 per month each.
I made peanut butter sandwiches for three meals a day, and at night maybe some eggs.
I never ate out, and never took a taxi.
<strong>
My cost of living was about $1000/month, and I was earning $1800/month.
I did this for two years, and saved up $12,000.
</strong>
I was 22 years old.
</p><p>
Once I had $12,000 I could quit my job and become a full-time musician.
I knew I could get a few gigs per month to pay my cost of living.
So I was free.
<a href="https://sive.rs/nq">I quit my job</a> a month later, and never had a job again.
</p><p>
When I finished telling my friend this story, he asked for more.
I said no, that was it.
He said, “No, what about when you sold your company?”
</p><p>
I said no, that didn’t make a big difference in my life.
That was just more money in the bank.
The difference happened when I was 22.
</p><p>
It’s not how much you have.
<strong>
It’s the difference between what you have and what you spend.
</strong>
If you have more than you spend, you’re rich.
If you spend more than you have, you’re not.
If you live cheaply, it’s easy to be free.
</p><p>
Magicians wave one hand around to get your attention, while the other hand does the trick.
To be smart, watch the other hand.
</p>
<img src="https://sive.rs/images/magichands.jpg">


</article>



</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sive.rs/richand</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25170030</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 14:54:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interpretation of confidence intervals and Bayesian credible intervals]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25169595">thread link</a>) | @jwb133
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text">
			
<p>This post was prompted by a tweet by Frank Harrell yesterday asking:</p>



<figure></figure>



<p>In this post I'll say a little bit about trying to answer Frank's question, and then a little bit about an alternative question which I posed in response, namely, how does the interpretation change if the interval is a Bayesian credible interval, rather than a frequentist confidence interval.</p>



<h2>Frequentist confidence intervals</h2>



<p>A frequentist 95% confidence interval is constructed such that if the model assumptions are correct, if you were to (hypothetically) repeat the experiment or sampling many many times, 95% of the intervals constructed would contain the true value of the parameter. I made a short video last year which performs a simulation in R to demonstrate this definition/idea:</p>



<figure><p><span><iframe width="1125" height="633" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IGXg6L98lJM?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span>
</p></figure>



<p>Frank asked how one interprets a particular realised confidence interval (0.72,0.91). The difficulty (as he is well aware!) is that all a frequentist can say is that this particular realised interval either does or does not contain the true parameter value, and they cannot tell you if it does or doesn't. All they can say is that if modelling assumptions are correct, in hypothetical repetitions 95% of the intervals constructed using this procedure contain the true value.</p>



<h2>Bayesian credible intervals</h2>



<p>Let’s now suppose that we’ve done a Bayesian analysis. We’ve specified a prior distribution for the parameter, based on prior evidence, our subjective beliefs about the value of the parameter, or perhaps we used a default ‘non-informative’ prior built into our software package. We use the same model as before, and Bayes theorem gives us the posterior distribution. A Bayesian posterior credible interval is constructed, and suppose it gives us some values. For the sake of simplicity, I’ll assume the interval is again 0.72 to 0.91, but this is not done to suggest a Bayesian analysis credible interval will generally be identical to the frequentist's confidence interval.</p>



<p>How should we interpret this credible interval? A Bayesian would I think say say something like it is an interval for which there is a 95% chance or probability the true parameter lies. At this point we must ask, what do they mean by 95% probability?</p>



<p>We could interpret it as a classical long run frequentist probability, but this means interpreting it like a confidence interval. In fact Bayesian procedures often have good frequentist properties. For example see <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://cdn1.sph.harvard.edu/wp-content/uploads/sites/343/2013/03/large-sample.pdf" target="_blank">Wang and Robins 1998</a> for an analysis of the frequentist properties of multiple imputation for missing data, or <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://doi.org/10.1177%2F0962280216667764" target="_blank">Bartlett and Keogh 2018</a> for a simulation investigation of the frequentist properties of Bayesian approaches for handling covariate measurement error. In fact, under certain conditions, Bayesian procedures achieve the same frequentist properties of maximum likelihood methods when the sample size gets large - see Chapter 4 of Gelman <em>et al</em>'s excellent<a href="http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Bayesian Data Analysis book</a>.</p>



<p>But conceptually we do not choose to do a Bayesian analysis simply as a means to performing frequentist inference. We choose it because it (hopefully) answers more directly what we are interested in (see Frank Harrell's '<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.fharrell.com/post/journey/" target="_blank">My Journey From Frequentist to Bayesian Statistics</a>' post). Namely, it enables us to make probability statements about the unknown parameter given our model, the prior, and the data we have observed. So what is the interpretation of the 95% chance or probability for a credible interval? </p>



<p>I don't know the no doubt large literature on this topic well at all, but the Bayesian's interpretation or definition of probability isn't that clear to me. The Wikipedia entry on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayesian_probability" target="_blank">Bayesian probability</a> says:</p>



<blockquote><p>Broadly speaking, there are two interpretations of Bayesian probability. For objectivists, who interpret probability as an extension of logic, probability quantifies the reasonable expectation that everyone (even a "robot") who shares the same knowledge should share in accordance with the rules of Bayesian statistics, which can be justified by Cox's theorem.[2][8] For subjectivists, probability corresponds to a personal belief.[3] Rationality and coherence allow for substantial variation within the constraints they pose; the constraints are justified by the Dutch book argument or by decision theory and de Finetti's theorem.[3] The objective and subjective variants of Bayesian probability differ mainly in their interpretation and construction of the prior probability.</p><cite>Wikipedia entry on Bayesian probability</cite></blockquote>



<p>Section 1.5 'Probability as a measure of uncertainty' of <a href="http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bayesian Data Analysis</a> talks about the way Bayesian analysis uses probability as a measure of uncertainty, but to my mind it doesn't really define the concept. This is not a criticism. As Gelman et al say earlier in their book:</p>



<blockquote><p>Rather than argue the foundations of statistics—see the bibliographic note at the end of this chapter for references to foundational debates—we prefer to concentrate on the pragmatic advantages of the Bayesian framework, whose flexibility and generality allow it to cope with complex problems.</p></blockquote>



<p>If part of the appeal of Bayesian inference is that it answers the question we really want (i.e. conditional on what we've seen, what do we know / believe about the parameter(s)), it seems to me that the interpretation or definition of prior/posterior probabilities should be relatively straightforward and clear to us. But for me at least, it isn't. I am quite confident (whatever I mean by that!) that this reflects my ignorance on the topic. Part of my motivation for writing this post is the hope that people will help me understand better how to unambiguously define what is meant by a Bayesian prior/posterior probability. Please write a comment if you can help in this regard.</p>



<p>The above does not mean I don't like Bayesian methods. Indeed much of the last 10 years I have been working with and using methods like multiple imputation for missing data whose development take place in the Bayesian paradigm. For me this is fine because I know that methods like multiple imputation have good frequentist properties, and while there are definitely interpretational issues with things confidence intervals, I at least think I understand what they claim to do/be.</p>



<h2>22nd November 2022 postscript</h2>



<p>This evening there was further discussion of this topic on Twitter. As part of this Frank Harrell offered an interpretation for the Bayesian credible interval as follows:</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Under data model F and prior P, [0.72, 0.91] is the shortest interval such that the probability the unknown OR generating our data is in that interval is 0.95 (highest posterior density interval).</p>— Frank Harrell (@f2harrell) <a href="https://twitter.com/f2harrell/status/1330633833713111040?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 22, 2020</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>I followed up with him as to the nature of the probability being referred to here, since it is clear that the probability notion being invoked is broader or distinct than the relative frequency notion of probability. Frank helpfully pointed me in the direction of the entry for 'probability' in his course glossary of terms, which can be <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf" target="_blank">accessed here</a>. Part of this entry says:</p>



<blockquote><p>The&nbsp;meaning&nbsp;attached to the metric known as a probability is up to the user; it can represent long-run relative frequency of repeatable observations, a degree of belief, or a measure of veracity or plausibility.</p><cite>https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf</cite></blockquote>



<p>and</p>



<blockquote><p>There are other schools of probability that do not require the notion of replication at all. For example, the school of&nbsp;subjective&nbsp;probability (associated with the&nbsp;Bayesian&nbsp;school) “considers probability as a measure of the degree of belief of a given subject in the occurrence of an event or, more generally, in the veracity of a given assertion” (see P. 55 of5). de Finetti defined subjective probability in terms of wagers and odds in betting. A risk-neutral individual would be willing to wager $P&nbsp;that an event will occur when the payoff is $1 and her subjective probability is&nbsp;P&nbsp;for the event.</p><cite>https://hbiostat.org/doc/glossary.pdf</cite></blockquote>



<p>As I wrote in the original post, I do not know the extensive literature on this topic well at all. But what Frank has summarised here is really useful in aiding my understanding of what the interpretation should be of the 95% probability statement attached to a 95% credible interval. It seems to me the notion of probability being invoked when interpreting a 95% credible interval has to be the subjective probability / degree of belief one described in the previous quote. Whether this definition/interpretation meets the criterion of being 'exact', as required by Frank in his tweet at the top of this post when asking for the exact interpretation of a particular realised frequentist confidence interval, I leave readers to decide.</p>
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thestatsgeek.com/2020/11/21/interpretation-of-frequentist-confidence-intervals-and-bayesian-credible-intervals/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25169595</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 13:21:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mastering TorchScript: Tracing vs. Scripting, Device Pinning, Graph Modification]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25169493">thread link</a>) | @briggers
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://paulbridger.com/posts/mastering-torchscript | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paulbridger.com/posts/mastering-torchscript">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  
  
  <h5>October 29, 2020</h5>



  
  
  

  


  <h2 id="intro">
  Intro
  <a href="#intro">#</a>
</h2>
<p>TorchScript is one of the most important parts of the Pytorch ecosystem, allowing portable, efficient and nearly seamless deployment. With just a few lines of <code>torch.jit</code> code and some simple model changes you can export an asset that runs anywhere <code>libtorch</code> does. It’s an important toolset to master if you want to run your models outside the lab at high efficiency.</p>
<p>Good <a href="https://pytorch.org/tutorials/beginner/Intro_to_TorchScript_tutorial.html">introductory material</a> is already available for starting to work with <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/jit.html">TorchScript</a> including <a href="https://pytorch.org/tutorials/advanced/cpp_export.html">execution in the C++ <code>libtorch</code> runtime</a>, and <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/jit_language_reference.html">reference material</a> is also provided. This article is a collection of topics going beyond the basics of your first export.</p>
<h2 id="tracing-vs-scripting">
  Tracing vs Scripting
  <a href="#tracing-vs-scripting">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Pytorch provides two methods for generating TorchScript from your model code — tracing and scripting — but which should you use? Let’s recap how they work:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/generated/torch.jit.trace.html"><strong>Tracing.</strong></a> When using <code>torch.jit.trace</code> you’ll provide your model and sample input as arguments. The input will be fed through the model as in regular inference and the executed operations will be traced and recorded into TorchScript. Logical structure will be frozen into the path taken during this sample execution.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/generated/torch.jit.script.html"><strong>Scripting.</strong></a> When using <code>torch.jit.script</code> you’ll simply provide your model as an argument. TorchScript will be generated from the static inspection of the <code>nn.Module</code> contents (recursively).</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s not obvious from the tutorial documentation, but choosing which method to use is a fairly simple and fluid choice:</p>
<h3 id="use-scripting-by-default">
  Use Scripting by Default
  <a href="#use-scripting-by-default">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Because <code>torch.jit.script</code> captures both the operations and full conditional logic of your model, it’s a great place to start. If your model doesn’t need any <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/jit_unsupported.html">unsupported Pytorch functionality</a> and has logic restricted to the <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/jit_builtin_functions.html#python-built-in-functions">supported subset of Python functions</a> and <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/jit_python_reference.html">syntax</a>, then <code>torch.jit.script</code> should be all you need.</p>
<p>One major advantage of scripting over tracing is that an export is likely to either fail for a well-defined reason — implying a clear code modification — or succeed without warnings.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Unlike Python, TorchScript is Statically Typed</strong></p>
<p>You will need to be consistent about container element datatypes, and be wary of implicit function signatures. A useful practice is to use type hints in method signatures.</p>

</blockquote>

<p>Despite TorchScript’s ability to capture conditional logic it does not allow you to run arbitrary Python within <code>libtorch</code> — a popular misconception.</p>
<h3 id="use-tracing-if-you-must">
  Use Tracing if You Must
  <a href="#use-tracing-if-you-must">#</a>
</h3>
<p>There are a few special cases in which <code>torch.jit.trace</code> may be useful:</p>
<ul>
<li>If you are unable to modify the model code — because you do not have access or ownership — you may find scripting the model simply will not work because it uses unsupported Pytorch/Python functionality.</li>
<li>In pursuit of performance or to bake in architectural decisions the logic freezing behavior of tracing might be preferable — similar to inlining C/C++ code.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Pay Close Attention to Tracer Warnings</strong></p>
<p>Due to how tracing can simplify model behavior, each warning should be fully understood and only then ignored (or fixed). Also, be sure to trace in eval mode if you are exporting a model for production inference!</p>

</blockquote>

<h3 id="use-both-together">
  Use Both Together
  <a href="#use-both-together">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Scripted and traced code can be freely mixed, and this is often a great choice. See the existing <a href="https://pytorch.org/">pytorch.org</a> documentation for <a href="https://pytorch.org/docs/stable/jit.html#mixing-tracing-and-scripting">details</a> and <a href="https://pytorch.org/tutorials/beginner/Intro_to_TorchScript_tutorial.html#mixing-scripting-and-tracing">examples</a>.</p>
<h2 id="device-pinning">
  Device Pinning
  <a href="#device-pinning">#</a>
</h2>
<p>If you find yourself using <code>torch.jit.trace</code> on some code, you’ll have to actively deal with some of the gotchas or face performance and portability consequences. Besides addressing any warnings Pytorch emits, you’ll also need to keep an eye out for device pinning. Just like <code>torch.jit.trace</code> records and freezes conditional logic, it will also trace and make constant the values resulting from this logic — this can include device constants.</p>
<p>Using this sample code:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>):</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>arange</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>.</span><span>size</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>))</span></code></pre></div>
<p>If we trace while executing on CPU or GPU we get this TorchScript (scroll to the right on mobile):</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>:</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>:</span>
  <span>_0</span> <span>=</span> <span>ops</span><span>.</span><span>prim</span><span>.</span><span>NumToTensor</span><span>(</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>size</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>))</span>
  <span>_1</span> <span>=</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>arange</span><span>(</span><span>annotate</span><span>(</span><span>number</span><span>,</span> <span>_0</span><span>),</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>layout</span><span>=</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>device</span><span>=</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>device</span><span>(</span><span>"cpu"</span><span>),</span> <span>pin_memory</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>)</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>_1</span></code></pre></div>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>You can see that <code>torch.device("cpu")</code> has been inserted as a constant into the generated TorchScript. If we try to get clever with this code:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>):</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>arange</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>.</span><span>size</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>),</span> <span>device</span><span>=</span><span>X</span><span>.</span><span>device</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Tracing will now result in TorchScript that is pinned to the tracing device. When traced on GPU, we see this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>,</span>
    <span>X</span><span>:</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>:</span>
  <span>_0</span> <span>=</span> <span>ops</span><span>.</span><span>prim</span><span>.</span><span>NumToTensor</span><span>(</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>size</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>,</span> <span>0</span><span>))</span>
  <span>_1</span> <span>=</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>arange</span><span>(</span><span>annotate</span><span>(</span><span>number</span><span>,</span> <span>_0</span><span>),</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>,</span> <span>layout</span><span>=</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>device</span><span>=</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>device</span><span>(</span><span>"cuda:0"</span><span>),</span> <span>pin_memory</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>)</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>_1</span></code></pre></div>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Tensors Created During Tracing Will Have Their Device Pinned</strong></p>
<p>This can be a significant performance and portability problem.</p>

</blockquote>

<h3 id="performance-and-portability">
  Performance and Portability
  <a href="#performance-and-portability">#</a>
</h3>
<p>If we later deserialize and run this TorchScript in <code>libtorch</code> the <code>arange</code> tensor will always be created on the device that is pinned — <code>torch.device("cpu")</code> or <code>torch.device("cuda:0")</code> in the examples above. If the rest of the model is running on a different device this can result in costly memory transfers and synchronization.</p>
<p>This device pinning issue extends to multi-GPU scenarios as well. If you have traced and exported a model on <code>cuda:0</code> and then run it on <code>cuda:1</code> you’ll see transfers and synchronization between the devices. Not good. Perhaps even worse, if such a model is run in an environment without any CUDA-capable device it will fail since <code>cuda:0</code> doesn’t exist.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Replace Tensors Created During Execution With Parameters</strong></p>
<p>Tensors created in the execution path while tracing will have their device pinned. Depending on model logic, these can often be turned into Parameters created during construction.</p>

</blockquote>

<p>An example of the problem looks like this in Nsight Systems:</p>








<a href="https://paulbridger.com/posts/mastering-torchscript/images/pinned_devices.png">
    <figure>
        <img src="https://paulbridger.com/posts/mastering-torchscript/images/pinned_devices_hub20c76c57b334a1bd11edec46dac0166_414004_896x580_fill_box_top_2.png" width="896" height="580">
        <figcaption><small></small></figcaption>
    </figure>
</a>

<h3 id="tensor-subscript-mask-and-indexing-will-pin-devices">
  Tensor Subscript Mask and Indexing Will Pin Devices
  <a href="#tensor-subscript-mask-and-indexing-will-pin-devices">#</a>
</h3>
<p>Unlike their more explicit counterparts (<code>masked_select</code> and <code>index_select</code>), using tensor subscripting will pin the mask or indexes to the tracing device:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>):</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>X</span><span>[</span><span>X</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>1</span><span>]</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Generates this TorchScript:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>:</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>:</span>
  <span>_0</span> <span>=</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>to</span><span>(</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>gt</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>),</span> <span>dtype</span><span>=</span><span>11</span><span>,</span> <span>layout</span><span>=</span><span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>device</span><span>=</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>device</span><span>(</span><span>"cpu"</span><span>),</span> <span>pin_memory</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>non_blocking</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>copy</span><span>=</span><span>False</span><span>,</span> <span>memory_format</span><span>=</span><span>None</span><span>)</span>
  <span>_1</span> <span>=</span> <span>annotate</span><span>(</span><span>List</span><span>[</span><span>Optional</span><span>[</span><span>Tensor</span><span>]],</span> <span>[</span><span>_0</span><span>])</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>index</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>,</span> <span>_1</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>Whereas:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>):</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>X</span><span>.</span><span>masked_select</span><span>(</span><span>X</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Generates this TorchScript:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>:</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Tensor</span><span>:</span>
  <span>_0</span> <span>=</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>masked_select</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>,</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>gt</span><span>(</span><span>X</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>_0</span></code></pre></div>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>The same pattern holds for <code>tensor[indexes]</code> and <code>tensor.index_select(0, indexes)</code>. This device pinning carries the same performance and portability risks as noted above.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Replace Tensor Subscripting With <code>masked_select</code> and <code>indexed_select</code></strong></p>
<p>Subscript-based masking and indexing will always pin the tracing device into generated TorchScript. :(</p>

</blockquote>

<h2 id="direct-graph-modification">
  Direct Graph Modification
  <a href="#direct-graph-modification">#</a>
</h2>
<p>Once we’ve used <code>torch.jit.script</code> or <code>torch.jit.trace</code> to generate a ScriptModule or ScriptFunction we can use <code>.graph</code>, <code>.inlined_graph</code> or <code>.code</code> to understand exactly what TorchScript has been generated. Though it has an entirely undocumented interface it is possible (and fun) to access and modify the generated TorchScript AST directly via the <code>.graph</code> method.</p>
<p>The most useful parts of the API are defined in <a href="https://github.com/pytorch/pytorch/blob/master/torch/csrc/jit/python/python_ir.cpp">torch/csrc/jit/python/python_ir.cpp</a>. As you can see, all the basic functionality is present for finding and changing the graph nodes you want. If you change nodes or arguments and then persist the module your subsequent TorchScript load and inference will reflect your changes, though modules cannot be changed recursively in this way (<code>torch.jit.freeze</code> can be useful here).</p>
<p>An example of the kind of graph modification that is possible:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>def</span> <span>undevice</span><span>(</span><span>tsc</span><span>):</span>
    <span># use ::to variant which does not hardcode device</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>to_node</span> <span>in</span> <span>tsc</span><span>.</span><span>graph</span><span>.</span><span>findAllNodes</span><span>(</span><span>'aten::to'</span><span>):</span>
        <span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>,</span> <span>layout</span><span>,</span> <span>device</span><span>,</span> <span>pin_mem</span><span>,</span> <span>non_blocking</span><span>,</span> <span>copy</span><span>,</span> <span>mem_format</span> <span>=</span> <span>list</span><span>(</span><span>to_node</span><span>.</span><span>inputs</span><span>())</span>
        <span>to_node</span><span>.</span><span>removeAllInputs</span><span>()</span>
        <span>for</span> <span>a</span> <span>in</span> <span>[</span><span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>dtype</span><span>,</span> <span>non_blocking</span><span>,</span> <span>copy</span><span>,</span> <span>mem_format</span><span>]:</span>
            <span>to_node</span><span>.</span><span>addInput</span><span>(</span><span>a</span><span>)</span>

    <span>for</span> <span>constant</span> <span>in</span> <span>tsc</span><span>.</span><span>graph</span><span>.</span><span>findAllNodes</span><span>(</span><span>'prim::Constant'</span><span>):</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>constant</span><span>.</span><span>hasUses</span><span>():</span>
            <span>constant</span><span>.</span><span>destroy</span><span>()</span></code></pre></div>
<p>The above code will modify a traced graph, changing <code>aten::to</code> to use an overload which doesn’t change memory location.</p>
<p>But what is this really useful for? As an undocumented API you’d be unwise to use this capability in a production pipeline unless you like maintenance coding. I would only recommend it for research, as in the above example which I used to understand and profile the transfer/synchronization behavior of tensor subscripting.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Don’t Bother With Direct Graph Modification</strong></p>
<p>For legitimate production use-cases you can almost always find a way to modify your model code to generate the TorchScript you want.</p>

</blockquote>

<h2 id="rewrite-for-onnxtensorrt-export">
  Rewrite for ONNX/TensorRT Export
  <a href="#rewrite-for-onnxtensorrt-export">#</a>
</h2>
<p>You can get some <a href="https://paulbridger.com/posts/video-analytics-deepstream-pipeline/#stage-3-hacked-deepstream-mdash-80-tensorrt-20-torchscript">awesome results with TensorRT</a> but exporting a model from Pytorch to TensorRT is far from a sure thing. The export path to ONNX and then to TensorRT can fail due to missing or incompatible operations at either step and this can be frustrating.</p>
<p>After the obligatory Google search, I’ve found a reasonable hail-mary approach is to rewrite your tensor processing code to avoid unsupported operators. I can’t give general advice for this but let me show you an example of how this can be possible: <code>repeat_interleave</code>.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>class</span> <span>RI</span><span>(</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>nn</span><span>.</span><span>Module</span><span>):</span>
    <span>def</span> <span>forward</span><span>(</span><span>self</span><span>,</span> <span>X</span><span>,</span> <span>repeat</span><span>):</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>X</span><span>.</span><span>repeat_interleave</span><span>(</span><span>repeat</span><span>,</span> <span>dim</span><span>=</span><span>0</span><span>)</span>

<span>inputs</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>arange</span><span>(</span><span>5</span><span>),</span> <span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>tensor</span><span>(</span><span>3</span><span>))</span>
<span>torch</span><span>.</span><span>onnx</span><span>.</span><span>export</span><span>(</span><span>RI</span><span>(),</span> <span>inputs</span><span>,</span> <span>'please_work.onnx'</span><span>,</span> <span>opset_version</span><span>=</span><span>11</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Doesn’t work:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">RuntimeError: Exporting the operator repeat_interleave to ONNX opset version <span>11</span> is not supported. Please open a bug to request ONNX <span>export</span> support <span>for</span> the missing operator.</code></pre></div>
<p>However, the behavior of <code>repeat_interleave</code> with a fixed <code>dim</code> argument can be replicated in a form that will export to ONNX …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://paulbridger.com/posts/mastering-torchscript">https://paulbridger.com/posts/mastering-torchscript</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paulbridger.com/posts/mastering-torchscript</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25169493</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 13:05:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Miss Working from the Office]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 553 | Comments 456 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25168589">thread link</a>) | @sysoleg
<br/>
November 21, 2020 | https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
    <section id="main-content" role="main">
	<article>
		


		<div><p>I went into my office yesterday for the first time in a few months to pick some stuff up. We got notified
a couple of days ago to get any personal property out of the office before Thanksgiving or else it'd be
thrown out, so I guess we're moving out of the office<sup id="fnref:moving-out"><a href="#fn:moving-out">1</a></sup>. It was a pretty eerie place to be; even now, 8
months later, most people haven't been back and it kind of looks like the entire office was abducted by aliens in
early March.</p>

<p>Despite how weird it is, I still miss working out of the office.</p>
<!-- more -->

<p>I miss having a clean delineation between "work" and "home".</p>
<p>I miss having copious desk space and a big monitor<sup id="fnref:house"><a href="#fn:house">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>I miss the 48" TVs on the wall showing Grafana dashboards with key metrics so there was always ambient knowledge of
what was going on with the product.</p>
<p>I miss having meetings in conference rooms where you can see other people and have a giant whiteboard to sketch on.</p>
<p>I miss casual collaboration. Video chat is a poor substitute and Slack is a deeply irritating tool that combines the
worst aspects of synchronous and asynchronous communication.</p>
<p>I miss productivity! Our engineering productivity has fallen through the floor since COVID despite everyone
working longer and harder; I fundamentally do not think remote teams can <em>ever</em> be as productive as in-person teams.</p>
<p>I miss having my employer pay for electricity and heat and fast symmetric multi-gigabit Internet access instead of
shifting those costs to me.</p>
<p>I miss having a plethora of convenient and delicious options for take-out lunch! I miss the gyros and french fries
at <a href="https://www.ayolagreek.com/">Ayola</a>. I miss the chicken pesto sandwich at <a href="https://working-girls-cafe.square.site/">Working Girls'
Cafe</a>. I miss the chow mein and pork buns from <a href="https://yanksing.com/">Yank Sing</a>. I
miss the katsu curry from <a href="http://www.muraccis.com/">Muracci's</a>. I miss the curry burritos from <a href="https://www.curryupnow.com/">Curry Up
Now</a>. I miss the croque monsieur from <a href="https://cafemadeleinesf.com/">Cafe Madeline</a>. I
miss the $5 lunch specials from <a href="http://www.mehfilindian.com/">Mehfil</a>.</p>
<p>I miss the succession of friendly baristas at our <a href="https://www.yelp.com/biz/hermanos-coffee-juice-san-francisco">favorite coffee shop</a> who always knew our orders and put up with our banter.</p>
<p>I miss occasional after-work drinks at the <a href="https://sf.eater.com/2019/4/25/18516128/skydeck-spirits-in-the-sky-rooftop-bar-san-francisco">sky bar</a> with the $18 well drinks that we always convinced management to pay for.</p>
<p>Hell, I miss <a href="https://www.bart.gov/">BART</a> in all its loud and smelly glory.</p>
<p>Look, I know, it's not all bad. It's a lot easier taking care of a baby while working from home than it would be if
I were commuting 45 minutes each way every day. I'm spending a lot less money on food and coffee and BART. And I'm
not arguing that we should be in the office now; not a single one of those things I listed above is worth the health
risk of jamming 150 people<sup id="fnref:deniers"><a href="#fn:deniers">3</a></sup> into an open-plan office with a quasi-functional ventilation
system<sup id="fnref:ventilation"><a href="#fn:ventilation">4</a></sup>. But I
really hope that office-work isn't a permanent victim of this pandemic, that all the companies pushing for
permanent WFH to save a few bucks on rent reconsider their stances, and that there comes a time when I can go back to
work again.</p>
</div>
<hr>
<h2>Comments</h2>


	</article>
    </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.roguelazer.com/2020/11/i-miss-working-from-the-office/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25168589</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 08:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mvp.css – build your landing page with only semantic HTML]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 301 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25167928">thread link</a>) | @rahimnathwani
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <hr>
        <section>
            <header>
                <h2>Simple, reusable components</h2>
                <p>For a clean looking design that doesn't get in the way</p>
            </header>
            
            
            
        </section>
        <hr>
        <section id="testimonials">
            <blockquote>
                <img alt="Quote" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/icon-quote.svg" height="80"><br>
                "By far the easiest stylesheet I've ever used. It integrates easily into <s>one</s> all of my
                startup&nbsp;projects."
                
            </blockquote>
        </section>
        <hr>
        <section id="features">
            <header>
                <h2>Flexibility without complexity</h2>
                <p>A few, clean styling options without all the bells and whistles</p>
            </header>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <th></th>
                        <th>MVP.css</th>
                        <th>No CSS</th>
                        <th>Custom CSS</th>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody><tr>
                    <td>Mobile friendly</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Works out of the box</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Easy to customize</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Only semantic HTML</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>No class names</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>✓</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>Perfect for an MVP</td>
                    <td><b>✓</b></td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                    <td>∅</td>
                </tr>
            </tbody></table>
        </section>
        <hr>
        <div id="figure">
            <header>
                <h2>A decent MVP in no time</h2>
                <p>More building and less designing with "set and forget" styling.</p>
            </header>
            <figure>
                <img alt="Stock photo" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/stock.jpg">
                <figcaption><i>"Uber for X" brainstorming session</i></figcaption>
            </figure>
        </div>
        <hr>
        <article id="docs">
            <h2>Docs</h2>
            <h3 id="html">HTML Reference</h3>
            
            <p>MVP.css works with the following HTML elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><code>&lt;a&gt;</code> <small>— text links</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;b&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;</code> <small>— solid
                                link buttons</small>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;em&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;a&gt;&lt;i&gt;</code> <small>— outlined
                                link buttons</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;article&gt;</code> <small>— content area with normal styling</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;article&gt;&lt;aside&gt;</code> <small>— text callout</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;blockquote&gt;</code> <small>— quote callout</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;footer&gt;</code> <small>— quote attribution</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;body&gt;</code> <small>— default parent element</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;button&gt;</code> <small>— form buttons</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;code&gt;</code> <small>— inline code highlighting</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;details&gt;</code> <small>— default expandable content section</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;</code> <small>— expandable heading</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;div&gt;</code> <small>— unstyled element</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;figure&gt;</code> <small>— image callouts</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;</code> <small>— image callout captions</small>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;footer&gt;</code> <small>— footer area</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;form&gt;</code> <small>— small form area</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;input&gt;</code> <small>— short input field</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;label&gt;</code> <small>— form field labels</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;select&gt;</code> <small>— dropdown options container</small>
                            <ul>
                                <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;select&gt;&lt;option&gt;</code> <small>— dropdown option
                                        items</small></li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;form&gt;&lt;textarea&gt;</code> <small>— large input field</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;header&gt;</code> <small>— content area with centered styling</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;h1&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h2&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h3&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h4&gt;</code>,
                    <code>&lt;h5&gt;</code>, <code>&lt;h6&gt;</code> <small>— headings</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;hr&gt;</code> <small>— horizontal rule (divider)</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;main&gt;</code> <small>— main content area</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;mark&gt;</code> <small>— text highlighting</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;</code> <small>— top navigation</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— nav links container</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— nav link items</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— nav dropdown
                                container</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;nav&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— nav dropdown
                                link items</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;ol&gt;</code> <small>— numbered list container</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— numbered list items</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;p&gt;</code> <small>— paragraph tag</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;</code> <small>— preformatted text</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</code> <small>— code block</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;samp&gt;</code> <small>— computer output block</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;samp&gt;</code> <small>— inline computer output</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;section&gt;</code> <small>— content area for centered / special content</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;section&gt;&lt;aside&gt;</code> <small>— content card</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;small&gt;</code> <small>— smaller text</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;sup&gt;</code> <small>— raised text (notification bubbles)</small></li>
                <li><code>&lt;table&gt;</code> <small>— data table</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;td&gt;</code> <small>— data table cell</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;th&gt;</code> <small>— data table header cell</small></li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;</code> <small>— data table header section</small>
                        </li>
                        <li><code>&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;</code> <small>— data table row</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li><code>&lt;ul&gt;</code> <small>— unordered list container</small>
                    <ul>
                        <li><code>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;</code> <small>— unordered list item</small></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <br>
            <h3 id="variables">Modifying the CSS variables</h3>
            <p>MVP.css includes a list of CSS variables. Editing these variables will change the styles globally.</p>
            <pre>                <code>
:root {
    --border-radius: 5px;
    --box-shadow: 2px 2px 10px;
    --color: #118bee;
    --color-accent: #118bee0b;
    --color-bg: #fff;
    --color-bg-secondary: #e9e9e9;
    --color-secondary: #920de9;
    --color-secondary-accent: #920de90b;
    --color-shadow: #f4f4f4;
    --color-text: #000;
    --color-text-secondary: #999;
    --font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, "Segoe UI", Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, "Helvetica Neue", sans-serif;
    --hover-brightness: 1.2;
    --justify-important: center;
    --justify-normal: left;
    --line-height: 150%;
    --width-card: 285px;
    --width-card-medium: 460px;
    --width-card-wide: 800px;
    --width-content: 1080px;
}
                </code>
            </pre>

            <p>Custom styles can be added below the <code>/* Custom styles */</code> comment at the end of the file.</p>
        </article>
        <hr>
        <article id="faq">
            <h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2>
            <details>
                <summary>Why would I use this?</summary>
                <p>If you just want to launch already.</p>
                <p><sup>PRO TIP</sup> An MVP is a temporary site, it doesn't have to be <i>and shouldn't be</i> perfect.
                </p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What skills will I need?</summary>
                <p>Mostly HTML, maybe a hint of CSS if you want to get fancy.</p>
                <p><i>CSS</i>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="5">5</progress></p>
                <p><i>Design</i>&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="0">0</progress></p>
                <p><i>HTML</i>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <progress max="100" value="100">100</progress></p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>Is there a minified version?</summary>
                <p>No, you don't need one for an MVP.</p>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>How can I improve my design?</summary>
                <p>Here are some helpful resources:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Emojis - <a href="https://www.emojicopy.com/" target="_blank">Emojicopy
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Icons - <a href="https://www.toptal.com/designers/htmlarrows/" target="_blank">HTML Entities
                            List by TopTal
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Icons - <a href="https://thenounproject.com/" target="_blank">TheNounProject
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Illustrations - <a href="https://gallery.manypixels.co/" target="_blank">Manypixels
                            ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Illustrations - <a href="https://undraw.co/illustrations" target="_blank">Undraw ↗</a>
                    </li>
                    <li>Logo - <a href="https://www.namecheap.com/logo-maker/app/" target="_blank">Namecheap Logo
                            Maker ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Product Shots - <a href="https://www.screely.com/" target="_blank">Screely ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Stock Photos - <a href="https://www.pexels.com/" target="_blank">Pexels ↗</a></li>
                    <li>Stock Photos - <a href="https://unsplash.com/" target="_blank">Unsplash ↗</a></li>
                </ul>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What if I don't like the default styles?</summary>
                <p>Most styles are editable through <em>CSS variables</em>. You can also add your own styles
                    inline, at the end of MVP.css or in a new stylesheet.</p>
                <p><sup>PRO TIP</sup> If there are two conflicting CSS styles, the last one will take precedence.</p>
                <pre>                    <code>
:root {
    --color: #118bee;
}

/* Lower in the CSS, or in a 2nd stylesheet */

:root {
    --color: green; /* This will take precedence */
}
                    </code>
                </pre>
            </details>
            <details>
                <summary>What if I still don't like it?</summary>
                <p>That's OK, you probably shouldn't love your MVP. The goal of MVP.css is to help you
                    feel <i>slightly</i> less embarrased about it.</p>
                <p><span>👉</span> If you
                    want a CSS framework with more features check out <a href="https://bulma.io/" target="_blank">Bulma
                        ↗</a> or <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/" target="_blank">Tailwind ↗</a>.</p>
            </details>
        </article>
        <hr>
        <section id="ideas">
            <header>
                <img alt="Idea" src="https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/img/idea.svg" height="200">
                <h2>What can you build with MVP.css?</h2>
                <p>Free ideas below ↓</p>
            </header>
            
        </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://andybrewer.github.io/mvp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25167928</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 04:49:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Jupystar – Run any Jupyter notebook in the browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25167906">thread link</a>) | @protoduction
<br/>
November 20, 2020 | https://starboard.gg/jupystar | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://starboard.gg/jupystar">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://starboard.gg/jupystar</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25167906</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 04:40:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
