<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 04:41:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 04:41:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The road to electric is filled with tiny cars]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 102 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232760">thread link</a>) | @jimmy2020
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

			<!-- Article Start -->
			
<p><span>I</span>n Beijing’s southwestern outskirts, past a four-lane overpass with sidewalks as wide as the streets themselves, is Zhengyang Road. It has the usual banks, small convenience stores, and noodle houses of many areas in the capital, but it is set apart by a row of about a dozen shops all selling the same thing — tiny electric cars. The cars look, variously, like small Range Rovers, golf carts, trolley cars, or rickshaws with sheet-iron sides, and they are slow. Their fundamental attraction is their price — between $600 and $2,500 — and that drivers can charge them the same way they would a cell phone. They also come with the perks of being loosely regulated. These low-speed electric cars, nicknamed “elderly transport vehicles,” have an enormous market, made up mostly of people who earn very little. And in China, there are a lot of them — <a href="http://english.www.gov.cn/premier/news/202005/29/content_WS5ed058d2c6d0b3f0e9498f21.html">more than 40%</a> of the population, or some 600 million people, make around $150 per month.</p>



<p>On a Sunday afternoon in October, Zhengyang Road is filled with potential customers chatting with store owners.<strong> </strong>Outside a shop with a worn sign, a young couple with a child are in the midst of a heated conversation.<strong> </strong>They came on an electric scooter and are debating whether to leave with a tiny car.</p>



<p>“Don’t we need one for school pickups?” the woman argues. “The children won’t have to put up with the cold in winter.” Her scooter offers no protection from the weather other than oven-mitt-like gloves secured to its handlebars. Her husband counters, “The 1,000 renminbi [$150] quote was for normal batteries, but lithium ones can be five times that. Can’t you just add a windshield to your scooter instead?” The shop owner shows them a cheaper model — which is cheaper because it has no roof. He suggests putting a plastic covering on top.</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_25-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 600px(max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="A woman exits a tiny car near a subway station in Beijing.">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<p>Having decided that the future of mobility is electric,<strong> </strong>the Chinese government has subsidized sales of regular electric cars since 2010. With <a href="https://insideevs.com/news/394229/plugin-electric-car-sales-china-2019/">close to 1.18 million sold</a> in 2019, China accounts for just over half of electric-vehicle sales globally. Bill Russo, founder and CEO of advisory firm Automobility Limited, sees a “steady and solid rise” in China’s electric-vehicle sales generally. The country has set a top-down target for electric vehicles to <a href="http://energy.mit.edu/news/chinas-transition-to-electric-vehicles/">make up 40%</a> of car sales by 2030, and Russo thinks they’ll have no problem hitting this goal. Tiny cars,<strong> </strong>which first began appearing in the early 2010s,<strong> </strong>have more than double the sales of regular electric cars but have<strong> </strong>never benefited from subsidies. Nor do advertisements for them air on television — instead, they appear on Kuaishou, a short-video platform popular with people living outside China’s big cities. Alongside streamers selling plums by the thousands, and others telling viewers what long-haul trucker life is like, drivers show off their tiny cars. Su Hua, Kuaishou’s founder, has long maintained that his app’s users are not “cool,” unlike those on Douyin, the TikTok predecessor popular with China’s urban elite. Rather, they are ordinary — the kind of people who might be in the market for miniature cars.</p>



<p>As they don’t technically require licenses, tiny cars tend to be popular with migrant workers, who struggle to pay for driving lessons and other car-related costs. The elderly, too, find tiny cars attractive since, up until October of last year, people over 70 could not apply for a driving license in China. They’re also convenient for anybody who wants a car to pick up groceries or their kids from school: No tiny car is longer than 1.5 meters, and their speed tops out at between 40 and 56 kilometers an hour. They’re for the short trips of daily life, not for traveling from one side of the city to another.</p>



<p>Some cities have banned sales of tiny cars — Beijing did so in 2018. Their production isn’t regulated by the government, and since they can’t be insured in many parts of China, it can be difficult for other drivers to get a payout if a tiny car is involved in an accident. Because tiny-car drivers don’t need to take a driving test, other drivers complain, they often go the wrong way and weave in and out of traffic. But since enforcement is lax, sales have quietly resumed in Beijing over the past two years. These little electric cars now exist in a kind of regulatory gray zone.</p>


    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_34-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_44-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_32-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_41-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      
    </figure>

    <figure>
      <div>
				<ul>
					<li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_43-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_38-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_31-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li><li>		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-768x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-400x267.jpg 400w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-600x400.jpg 600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-1000x667.jpg 1000w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-1600x1067.jpg 1600w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/EVBeijing_47-2800x1868.jpg 2800w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) calc(100vw + 40px), 50vw" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				
			</figcaption>
		</figure></li>
				</ul>
			</div>
      <figcaption>Tiny cars come in a variety of styles and cost between $600 and $2,500.</figcaption>
    </figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>One of the</strong> smaller shops on Zhengyang Road is officially known as Xinlei Scooters, its name emblazoned in white characters on a large red sign above its doors. But inside, past rows of electric scooters, is a smaller, flimsier plaque above the counter announcing its other name: Shitou Cars. This subterfuge is necessary because the police could shut down the operation and confiscate its vehicles if the owners were caught selling tiny cars. Yet because enforcement hasn’t been strict of late, attempts at being covert go only so far: There are several tiny cars parked outside, an open-air showroom.</p>



<p>Xinlei/Shitou’s owner is a middle-aged man with pronounced cheekbones wearing a black tracksuit. He is more attentive to the phone calls he’s constantly receiving than the customers in the shop. It is his wife, with dyed-dark-brown hair and a pink coat, who maintains the sales patter: “I taught an auntie who had never driven a car before. She got the hang of it in three days.” She shows the cars outside to potential customers, opening their doors, instructing people to sit inside, and rolling down the windows. When two old men come in for repair services, her husband finally gets off the phone to deal with them. Meanwhile, two government functionaries in black uniforms pace down the street. They tell one owner to make his storefront tidier, but otherwise overlook the illicit operation.</p>



<p>Part of the reason why tiny cars are so popular is because there has not been an official decision on whether they need license plates. For regular cars, unfettered access to Beijing’s inner city — anywhere within the fifth ring road — is restricted to cars with Beijing plates. Licenses for gas cars are distributed through a special system so competitive that it has generated its own black market. License-plate holders can collect up to $2,700 a year by renting them to those who want to drive in the city. In addition to government subsidies, getting around some of the more onerous aspects of the licensing system is one of the main selling points for regular electric cars.</p>



<p>With Beijing temperatures reaching lows of 4 degrees Celsius in wintertime, Xinlei/Shitou has been selling,<strong> </strong>on average, two of its four-wheeled fully enclosed models every day, a saleswoman boasts. Younger couples prefer four wheels, she adds, while older people usually want three. When asked about the possibility of a tiny car being confiscated, she draws in a breath. “Don’t go on the main roads. Don’t make a business out of it,” she advises.</p>



<p>At least one of Zhengyang Road’s customers isn’t listening: Guo Caiying, who works primarily in the construction-supply industry,<strong> </strong>chauffeurs Fengtai residents around her district. She has a sticker on her tiny car’s back window with the phone number of her car dealer. Guo’s car looks like a golf cart, with cushioned brown seats enclosed by windows. A red <em>fudai</em>, a lucky charm, swings from the ceiling, its characters spelling out “peace.” There is enough space for two people to comfortably sit upright but not enough to extend your legs without hitting the plexiglass divider between driver and passenger. The car tops out at 40 kilometers an hour, and<strong> </strong>as a result, Guo never ventures beyond Fengtai — a borderland where urban and rural meet.</p>



<p>Guo wears the uniform of the countryside: a padded jacket. She is from Henan, a province 800 kilometers southwest of Beijing, and speaks its dialect. Guo starts taking calls from her regulars around 7 a.m., arriving at their door whenever they want to be picked up. She stops driving at 9 a.m., when the traffic police begin work. She characterizes her customers as “people with money who sit in offices.” Once, while in the middle of a trip, Guo saw a cop stop a car like hers. She kept driving, but dropped her passenger off before their destination. Now, if a customer calls her after 9:00, she sends her husband to pick them up with his electric scooter. He charges 75 cents (5RMB), which is half her price. Guo’s flat rate was fixed by the tiny-cab drivers who preceded her.</p>



<p>The economy of tiny cars depends on such informal practices.<strong> </strong>When asked whether she would consider undercutting other drivers, Guo is adamant. “No one can break the rules,” she says. There are local WeChat groups for tiny-car drivers that new owners are inducted into upon purchasing one. Within these groups, members swap information on the whereabouts of local cops and whether anyone has been fined or had their car taken away.</p>



<p>Despite the risks, Guo still thinks it’s worth being a tiny-car driver to make a little pocket money.<strong> </strong>Tiny cars are part of a last-mile economy that flourishes at the beginning and end of the workday. Many Fengtai residents are employed at the local high-tech park, which is host to thousands of businesses. It takes 20 minutes to walk from one end of the park to the other, a trip many would rather make by tiny car. The cars’ main competitors are share bikes, which are cheaper but lack space for luggage and can’t be split with a friend. Tiny cars are also more social — a feature Guo tries to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/">https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2021/tesla-vs-tiny-cars/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232760</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 01:12:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Nintendo DS-TV-Out Restoration Project]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 176 | Comments 30 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232600">thread link</a>) | @max-m
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <section id="main_content">
        

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>During late 2020, we discovered that the Nintendo DS Lite had a leftover feature in its SoC allowing it to easily have cheap hardware video output. With a little circuitry and some software hacks, we were able to restore it and make it usable for anyone. No FPGA’s, no bulky or cumbersome hardware. This mod is specially useful to revive consoles with only the lower screen, being able to watch the upper screen on your TV. Or to create a GBA Macro with additional TV Output.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/DSTVOUT.jpg" width="250" height="250"><br></center>
<center>
  <b>First iteration of the TV-OUT board in action</b>
  </center>

<h2 id="installation">Installation</h2>

<p>If you are just interested in installation, this is the current method <strong>while we work on simpler methods</strong> and more features you have requested:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Install the <a href="https://ezflash.sosuke.com/wiki/index.php/Flashme">flashME CFW</a> (Custom FirmWare) on your DS Lite</li>
  <li>Connect the Nintendo DS Lite’s upper screen flex to the PCB board.</li>
  <li>Donwload the “NDS TV OUT ENABLE.nds” homebrew from the <a href="https://github.com/LostNintendoHistory/Lost-NDS-TV">NDS TV OUT repo</a></li>
  <li>Download <a href="https://github.com/DS-Homebrew/TWiLightMenu/releases">Twilight Menu</a></li>
  <li>Copy both the NDS TV OUT ENABLE and Twilight Menu .nds files to a flashcart.</li>
  <li>Use flashme to autoboot into the flashcart. You can do this by pressing A + B + Start + Select while booting. Run Twilight menu, and from there, run the enabler homebrew.</li>
  <li>The console will return to Twilight Menu. Now you can use the buttons on the board to swap between the different screen modes (Upper Screen to TV, Bottom Screen to TV, etc) and launch your games.</li>
</ol>

<hr>

<h2 id="software">Software</h2>

<p>The retail firmware of the Nintendo DS Lite disables this specific feature early in the boot process. To reenable it, we use a custom firmware like flashme, which is very easy to install and is required only once, plus a homebrew. Despite that, we are working on an even simpler solution to make it available to as many people as possible, our own custom firmware which integrates patches to enable this feature directly on boot. Additionally, we are currently working with homebrew developers to integrate control of this new feature into existing software for the DS Lite.</p>

<h2 id="hardware">Hardware</h2>

<p>This feature is only found on the Nintendo DS Lite. Nintendo DS Phat does not contain this feature nor does the Nintendo DSi. It is important to remark that <strong>this is not the same hardware</strong> found on Devkits or other special units. This hardware feature is present in virtually <strong>every single Nintendo DS Lite</strong> out there. The reason why it was left there is unknown, but as said before, it is not related to development units, those use a different video capture hardware. Perhaps Nintendo imagined the Nintendo Switch as early as 2006?</p>

<center><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/PCB_Rev_11.png" width="350" height="400"></center>

<p>We only need a few extra hardware components to make this video signal usable. You will be able to download the schematics and gerber files for our open hardware circuit board <a href="https://github.com/LostNintendoHistory/Lost-NDS-TV">from the repository</a>. The latest version is revision 1.2 which fixes some minor issues with a component in the board.</p>

<center>
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LostNintendoHistory/lostnintendohistory.github.io/main/img/NDSTVOUT/Prototype.jpg" width="350" height="350"><br>
</center>
<center>
  <b>First prototype and tests before designing a proper board</b></center>


<p>The final, production-ready board contains a DAC (Digital to Analogue Converter) which turns the 10 bits digital signal at 16.7 MHz provided by the DS Lite into a proper analogue signal. This signal then goes through an operational amplifier and it’s ready to be delivered to your nearest TV trough composite video.</p>

<p>We are currently considering creating an additional PCB revision which would allow to install the mod on consoles without lossing a working upper screen.</p>


      </section>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lostnintendohistory.github.io/DS-TV-OUT</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232600</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:48:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Bombard Story]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26232597">thread link</a>) | @jbergstroem
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">
				<div id="content">
			
	<div id="primary">
		<main id="main">
			
<article id="post-618" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="">
	<div>
					
			
		<div itemprop="text">
			<p><strong>The Bombard Story</strong> is the account of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alain_Bombard">Alain Bombard’s</a> amazing journey in 1952 across the <a href="http://greatestadventurers.com/the-north-west-passage-by-roal-amundsen/">Atlantic</a> on a small 14-foot inflatable boat. Alain Bombard left without food or fresh water and sailed 4.400 kilometers. He lost 25 kg. but proved his point: Man can actually survive on ocean water for an extended period of time!</p>
<figure id="attachment_619" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-619"><img loading="lazy" src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/TheBombardStory1953.jpg" alt="The Bombard Story" width="300" height="203" data-src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/TheBombardStory1953.jpg" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="><figcaption id="caption-attachment-619">In this small vessel Bombard sailed across the Atlantic – without freshwater</figcaption></figure>
<p>As a doctor, Bombard was concerned about the hundreds of deaths at sea every year related to sailors drinking ocean water. He developed the theory that humans can not just survive but live for years on seawater. This sounds very strange, but his big idea was to begin drinking seawater, while you are still hydrated – and in small quantities. It turns out that saltwater is only dangerous if you are dehydrated and suddenly drink large amounts of it. – The way shipwrecked sailors typically would do when they run out of fresh water. From the book:</p>
<blockquote><p>For some time I had made a study of the resistance of the human organism to privations and had convinced myself that it was possible for an individual to survive beyond the limits normally assigned by physiological science. I had paid particular attention to the case histories of political deportees, prisoners, and undernourished populations. But, with my background as a doctor, for whom the teachings of science remain a dead letter unless they can find practical application, my theoretical studies only seemed to lead to the question: ‘What use can made of this knowledge?’</p></blockquote>
<p>Bombard ate spoonfuls of plankton that he collected in a fine net and he also drank juice made from pressed fish he caught along the way. Sound disgusting, but the man survived and he might have discovered an important piece of knowledge for survival on the ocean.</p>
<p>Download the free PDF e-book here (223 pages/38MB):</p>
<h3><img loading="lazy" src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/PDF-download-e1597850191432.png" alt="" width="35" height="35" data-src="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/PDF-download-e1597850191432.png" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">&nbsp;<a href="http://greatestadventurers.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/The-Bombard-Story-1953.pdf">The Bombard Story 1953</a></h3>

		</div>

				
			</div>
</article>

			

					</main>
	</div>

	

	</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://greatestadventurers.com/the-bombard-story/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26232597</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:48:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Living Like It's 99: No Social Media, No Smartphone]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 143 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26226864">thread link</a>) | @betaman0
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://www.alvarez.io/posts/living-like-it-s-99/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.alvarez.io/posts/living-like-it-s-99/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				<p><img src="https://www.alvarez.io/img/color/l99.jpg" alt="Robot"></p>
<p>At the time of writing this article, I’ve been living without social media for 3 years and without a smartphone for 2 years. Everything started as an experiment motivated by my privacy concerns. I ended up living like that for an entire different reason: peace of mind. You can find a lot of people on internet that have tried this experiment, from a couple of days to an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B0RVWU_nROk">entire month</a>. However I discovered that the brain dependencies created by social media and smartphones take a lot longer to go away (30 days for me). You can’t really see the effects it has on your life unless you try this kind of experiment for a long time, because you will be stuck in the withdrawal phase that makes you crave dopamine.</p>
<p>Contrary to popular belief, I do not live in a cave where I spend my time coding without any social life, sorry guys ;) I did this experiment while having a busy professional and personal life: I traveled around the world, moved to a new city without knowing anyone, ran <a href="https://www.duple.io/">my own software startup</a>, met new people and made new friends, etc… So it is possible to live your life the same way, or even better, without a smartphone or social media.</p>
<p>I will share with you my experience leaving social media and my smartphone, the tools I replaced them with, some tips and tricks, people’s reactions to my experiment, as well as some funny anecdotes.</p>
<h2 id="lets-start-with-why">Let’s Start With Why</h2>
<h3 id="privacy">Privacy</h3>
<p>The original motivation behind this experiment was privacy. I’m a professional hacker, the things I can do are scary and I’m far from being the only one with these skills. <strong>Smartphones are a dream come true for people like me, little spy devices that are 24/7 on you, remotely accessible from anywhere around the world</strong>. Throw social media into the equation, and you can get inside the head of anybody, and make them do whatever you want. Yes, you should be scared. And that’s even without mentioning all the other <a href="https://lithub.com/what-does-privacy-really-mean-under-surveillance-capitalism/">privacy</a> and <a href="https://the.ink/p/we-can-have-democracy-or-we-can-have">freedom</a> issues that come with <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/04/facebook-phone-numbers-exposed/">social media</a> and <a href="https://nrkbeta.no/2020/12/03/my-phone-was-spying-on-me-so-i-tracked-down-the-surveillants/">smartphones</a>.</p>
<h3 id="curiosity">Curiosity</h3>
<p>Another reason, which is less dark, was curiosity. I like to experiment and try new things in my life. I was curious about the idea of living without a smartphone and social media especially in a world more connected than ever. And if I didn’t like the experiment, I could always go back to <a href="https://www.meta-nomad.net/avoiding-the-global-lobotomy/">zombieland</a>.</p>
<h3 id="planned-obsolescence">Planned Obsolescence</h3>
<p>The cherry on top was to stop paying each year for a new smartphone, that does nothing more than the previous one, just because the providers decided to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planned_obsolescence">sabotage old models</a> so they <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Batterygate">stop working</a>.</p>
<h3 id="peace-of-mind">Peace of mind</h3>
<p>This is for me the most important reason (even though I discovered it afterwards). The positive effects on your mind, being free from social media and smartphones, are incredible. More on it later.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“Technology has solved old economics problems by giving us new psychological problems.”<br>
Mark Manson, The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In 2018 I deleted my accounts from Twitter, Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp. No coming back, no temptation to reactivate them later on. I kept LinkedIn on standby for professional use although it came close to being deleted as well. WhatsApp got replaced by <a href="https://signal.org/">Signal</a> because Facebook bought them, plus <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/parmyolson/2018/09/26/exclusive-whatsapp-cofounder-brian-acton-gives-the-inside-story-on-deletefacebook-and-why-he-left-850-million-behind/">they’re not really big fan s of privacy</a>.</p>
<p>During that year I kept my smartphone, as I wanted to do the experiment gradually. This decision allowed me to discover something quite counter intuitive about social media and smartphones (more on it later).</p>
<p>From that point on I was reachable by SMS, call, email and Signal. I wasn’t ready for what happened next. Fasten your seatbelts.</p>
<h3 id="people-thought-i-was-dead">People Thought I Was Dead</h3>
<p>The first reaction people had was to think something bad had happened to me, some of them even thought I was dead. Then something socially curious happened: everybody started speaking to each other on Facebook and WhatsApp to try to figure out what was wrong. Some of them even contacted my family multiple times. They all had my phone number, email address and other ways of contacting me. <strong>However, none of them did</strong>. It was like I had exited the matrix, and was living in another reality.</p>
<h3 id="trustworthiness">Trustworthiness</h3>
<p>I was told that I couldn’t be trusted since people can’t check online what I’m doing when I’m not around.</p>
<p>Yeah, you read that right.</p>
<p><strong>Society has been brainwashed to believe that privacy is something criminal. Sorry to disappoint, but privacy is a basic fundament of freedom and democracy. That’s why the voting system is anonymous</strong> [1]. When people tell you “<a href="https://write.privacytools.io/freddy/why-privacy-matters-even-if-you-have-nothing-to-hide">If you have nothing to hide, you have nothing to fear</a>”, what they really mean is “democracy is overrated, get over it”.</p>
<p><em>[1] Privacy: you know who I am but not what I do. Anonymity: You know what I do but not who I am. The voting system uses both, privacy when you go vote, anonymity when they count the results.</em></p>
<h3 id="whatsapp">WhatsApp</h3>
<p>This was for me the biggest problem. <a href="https://seirdy.one/2021/01/27/whatsapp-and-the-domestication-of-users.html">Getting people out of WhatsApp</a> if they wanted to talk to me created a lot of friction. Some of them even stopped texting me because they had to open another app on their phone in order to write to me.</p>
<p>Yeah, you also read that right.</p>
<p>I don’t miss WhatsApp, nor do I miss its endless group talks without anything useful. If you leave one of these groups people look at you as if you did something wrong. In the end I still had access to all the event’s information I needed despite them being organized on WhatsApp. In regards to this, not having the app didn’t change my life much.</p>
<p>A trick I’ve developed, when giving my contact info to new people, is to enter my phone number on their smartphone myself, and install Signal for them. This removed a lot of friction. I would then explain my experiment to them and tell them I can only be contacted via this app. I’ve always had a positive reaction. Everybody’s been curious and asking a lot of questions.</p>
<h3 id="and-then-nothing-happened">And Then Nothing Happened</h3>
<p>During the first weeks without social media, I felt off. As if I was missing out on something big that was happening. Like everybody was having fun except me. Once the <a href="https://joshcsimmons.com/quit-social-media/">withdrawal phase</a> went away, I realized that my life hadn’t changed that much. I was still doing the same things, talking to the same people, going to the same parties, etc… It was just more quiet and peaceful.</p>
<p><strong>I was no longer bombarded with pictures of everybody trying to fake a life they’re not living for the sole purpose of impressing someone else: <a href="https://hbr.org/2017/04/a-new-more-rigorous-study-confirms-the-more-you-use-facebook-the-worse-you-feel">my life had just upgraded</a>.</strong></p>
<p>In the end, after everybody got over their initial shock and calmed down, it became normal for them to contact me using Signal, and life went on as usual.</p>
<h2 id="round-2-goodbye-smartphone">Round 2: Goodbye Smartphone</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.alvarez.io/img/color/l99-2.jpg" alt="Phone"></p>
<p>Unlike social media, smartphones are a lot harder to get rid off. They handle many more things than just simply communicating with people.  I work all day long with a computer, most of what the smartphone was doing could be handled by my laptop. For the rest, I narrowed down my bare essential to Music, Pictures, GPS navigation and of course GSM calls.</p>
<h3 id="the-hardware">The Hardware</h3>
<p>You could solve these problems quite easily using multiple devices, however I wanted to be smart about it and not walk around with a luggage just to carry around all this stuff. After doing some research I figured out the perfect combination and I was even able to reduce the amount of things I had in my pockets.</p>

			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.alvarez.io/posts/living-like-it-s-99/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26226864</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 17:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Abundant Capital]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 348 | Comments 183 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26226723">thread link</a>) | @tomhoward
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://blog.aaronkharris.com/abundant-capital | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.aaronkharris.com/abundant-capital">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
      <div><p>The venture capital industry was built on the premise that both capital and high quality companies are scarce. For most of the history of the industry, this has been true. I remember sitting at demo day in 2011 and marveling at the fact that the combined capital of all the VCs in the room was less than that controlled by the hedge fund at which I had worked. But the model is wrong. Venture capital is abundant, and that fact should fundamentally change how founders fundraise.<br></p><p>This scarcity model has shaped the structure of startups and VCs - most of what an early stage startup does is designed to convince a VC to invest. Companies treat VCs as a limited resource that is both hard to access and hard to convince. Investors do their best to perpetuate this idea because it allows them to retain control of the pitch and fund dynamic.[1]</p><p>Something interesting happens, though, whenever a company has a signifier of quality - a YC demo day slot, a high quality angel, pedigreed founders, or, even better, strong growth. In these cases, there are investor feeding frenzies, leading to oversubscribed rounds, ever climbing prices, and investors willing to accept ownership targets they - until recently - would have termed unacceptable.</p><p>To be sure, there have always been bidding wars in private equity (of which venture is a subset), but these bidding wars are so frequent now as to be approaching the norm. If capital was actually scarce, this wouldn’t happen, there wouldn’t be enough money to create so many bidding wars.[2]</p><p>Bidding wars aren’t the only evidence of capital abundance. The VCs are changing their businesses because of this abundance, whether or not they admit the reason. The evidence is in the new funds that seem to launch on a daily basis, the multi-billion dollar growth funds that have become increasingly common, and the ownership targets at various rounds that continue to drop.</p><p>At the same time that capital has become more abundant, founders have become smarter about fundraising. There are now a huge number of blogs, classes, essays, guides, and advisers ready to help founders navigate the previously opaque world of fundraising. As a result, founders can approach each funding event with a clear plan of how to run a process. Running an orderly process further increases the chances that a company will see competitive bids.</p><p>As a thought experiment, assume that the abundance model is here to stay. It is also safe to assume that founders will not suddenly forget their newfound knowledge about process. I think this should encourage founders to think about changing fundraising in a few major ways:</p><ol>
<li><p>Founders should approach every fundraising as an auction. This is what each process already is, but the auction is inefficient. There’s lots of language and pseudo-moral arguments about why this is bad, but most of those fall apart if capital is abundant.</p></li>
<li><p>Founders should expand their funnels beyond the traditional VCs. These VCs hold a marketing and branding advantage, much of which is built around the signal to later rounds. If, however, each round is an auction, this benefit evaporates. YC’s demo day proved this funnel expansion works at seed, and there’s no logical reason it should fail at later rounds.</p></li>
<li><p>Once a founder has the information produced by this process, she can decide whether to minimize dilution, maximize price, or optimize around the partner. The answer will change based on the situation, but having access to the choice is important.</p></li>
</ol><p>Founders are hesitant to run this model because they fear that running an auction will create a negative quality signal. Investors encourage this belief because it allows them to keep deal flow proprietary. This is flawed logic. The quality of a company can’t be determined by the investors to whom that company talks when raising money. The quality of a company is determined by whether or not the company is good, and good companies should take advantage of abundant capital markets.[3]</p><p><i>Thanks to Adora Cheung, Janelle Tam, Ilya Sukhar, and Nabeel Hyatt for helping me think this through, even though our conclusions might differ.<br></i></p><p>__</p><p>[1] Perhaps more importantly to the investors’ business model is that this dynamic creates a reason for the existence of VCs. If founders and LPs both internalized how non-scarce capital actually is, they could find one another directly, bypassing VCs.</p><p>[2] It’s important to remember that, even though capital is abundant, it remains unevenly distributed. There are companies that struggle to raise money - some of these may be bad investments, but many are good. This is a problem of access rather than capacity, which is a whole different issue.</p><p>[3] When a company IPOs, it opens ownership up to anyone who can afford a share. Imagine, for a second, an investor arguing that this is a sign of low quality.</p></div>
    
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.aaronkharris.com/abundant-capital</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26226723</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:54:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Practical Color Theory for People Who Code (2016)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26225339">thread link</a>) | @martinlaz
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><header>
	
	<h3>Natalya Shelburne
		<br>
		<a href="https://twitter.com/natalyathree">@natalyathree</a>
	</h3>
</header>
	
		<div>
			<div>
				<div>
					

					<div><p>
						Hi! I'm Natalya! <img src="http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/images/tally-pic.jpg" title="natalya-profile" description="vector art self portrait">I'm a classically trained fine artist who spent 6 years teaching people how to paint, draw, and grow their creativity. I am now a front end developer, and I love writing code as much as I love painting. </p><p>I have a degree in Studio Art, a bachelor's in Developmental Psychology, and a master's degree in Creativity and Talent Development. But, most importantly, I have mixed gallons and gallons of paint. </p><p>I abstracted my domain knowledge as a fine artist into variables and functions in order to reveal color selection as being logical, predictable, and driven by principles anyone can learn. Sass color functions give you the same creative power as owning a set of paints, brushes, and canvas. </p><p>This is a demo of my functions for a complementary color scheme - pick any color on the color wheel and the functions will make sure that the scheme will still work! 🎨</p></div>
					</div>
					<div>
						
					
					<h4>Completely new to this? Check out these resources first:</h4>
					
				</div>
			</div>
		</div>
		<a href="#" name="start"></a>
<section>
	<h2>Let's build a Complementary Color Scheme!</h2>
	<img src="http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/images/color-circle.png" alt="color-wheel" title="color wheel" description="the color wheel with corresponding hsl degrees">
	<p>This is the color wheel, consider this the documentation for using color. <br> Notice that the degrees on the color wheel correspond to colors.</p>
	
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Pick a color <span> hsl($hue, $saturation, $lightness)</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		<p>Pick any color by selecting its hue (0-360) on the color wheel at full saturation (100%) and at half lightness (50%) - this way you start with the 'most colorful color' you can get.</p>
		<p>This is what your website will look like if you set every element to this one color. Notice how you can't tell one item from another. Color is information.</p>
	</div>
	<div>

		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>


	</div>
	<div>
		
		<div>
			<p>Why pick a fully saturated color, but only half lightness?</p>
			<p>Ever mix up a bunch of colors only to end up with a gray blob? In the real world, you can't mix a color to be more saturated - you only "lose" color information as you mix. So, the practice is to start with the most saturated colors at their most chromatic so you can still have a full range of mixing opportunities.</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>
</section>


<section>
	<h2>Generate Complementary Color<span>complement( );</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		<p>Generate your second color without having to guess what will work. Thanks to science and wavelengths, we know that this works. The opposition of these two colors stimulate your photoreceptor cells in a good way!</p>
		<p>Finally! A different color - now hue separates elements from each other and a layout can be seen.</p>
	</div>
	<div>
		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

	</div>
	<div>
		
		<p>The complement to any color is always 180 degrees across on the other side of the color wheel. If you've ever wondered why it's the color wheel instead of a color line, this is part of that answer. Remember that the color wheel is our visual documentation for color relationships. <br> Fun fact, if you mix complementary colors, they'll cancel each other out and you'll end up with a neutral gray.</p>
		
	</div>
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Color Relationship Established by Mixing<span>harmonious-mix( );</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		
		<p>Establish a color relationship by mixing them together. This makes the colors look like they're under similar lighting conditions.</p>
		<p>Here, you see less saturated hues, with a clear relationship between each other.</p>
		</div>
		<div>
			<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

		</div>
		<div>
			
			<div>
				<p>Our eyes may be legacy systems, but they are really good at spotting patterns, especially things that look like they don't belong in a set.</p>
				<p>This mixing method is another way we can simulate lighting and color found in nature. It's a bit more complicated, but my favorite way of explaining it is this: Everything outside has some "yellow" mixed in from the sunshine during the day. Same thing happens when everyone and everything looks bad in photos taken under the glow of green flourescent lights - there is green added to all of the colors you're looking at, including adding a green glow to your skin if you're standing under the flourescent light yourself. Whether it looks good or bad, this color (light) mixing creates a visual harmony. We don't really notice it when it's there, but we really notice its absence.</p>
				<p>When you're painting, you want to simulate similar lighting conditions for a scene, and that effect is accomplished mixing a bit of one color into the other. Mixing different ratios of the same colors will usually generate a matching color palette.</p>
				<p>How do I decide what to do? Thanks to art school and science, I know that cool colors have lower luminosity than warm colors, and will dominate in mixes, with yellow being the lightest color. For example, a touch of blue will really affect yellow, whereas you can add a lot of yellow to blue before it is affected. So, here is this decision making in function form - I am weighing different colors differently when mixing.</p>
	</div>
		
		
		
</div>
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Create Neutrals<span>mix-neutral( ); lighten( ); darken( );</span></h2>
	<div>
		
		
		
		<p>Let your chosen color pop (in other words, don't exhaust your eyes by making them process non-stop intense chromatic colors!) by surrounding it with neutrals. Desaturate the painter way: by mixing complementary colors! Then, vary that neutral's lightness to create a highlight and a shadow.</p>
		<p>Making the complementary color neutrals will help the 'call to action' color you selected stand out - notice how much the button in the top right "pops" all of a sudden. Make things "pop" by making other things around them not pop.</p>
	</div>
	<div>
		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

	</div>
	<div>
		
		
		
		<p>We can do the same for our primary color too. More neutrals to work with.</p>
		<p>Doesn't it seem like we went too far with this whole making things neutral? Now, nothing "pops"! But, on the plus side, none of this seems to be irritating any eyeballs, either. Remember that our eyes don't like to handle seeing everything our computers are capable of rendering.</p>
	</div>
	<div>
		<div>

	
	
	<div>
		<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tin rem ipsum ?</p>
	<p> tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tiny lorem ipsum tinyny lorem ipsum </p>
	<p>cta
	</p></div>
	
</div>

	</div>
	<div>
		
		<div>
			<p>The colors are way too intense at their full saturation for our eyes to handle. If all the colors are bright, none of the colors are bright.</p>
			<p>I picked my starting color for a reason -  I want that to be the heart of my design! That means the complementary color should support the chosen color, and we do that by mixing neutrals. Our eyes don't really handle saturated colors very well next to other saturated colors. Our eyes get confused at the edges - is it this color or the other one? Ahh both! We end up seeing optical illusions. Just give your eyes a break between super strong saturated colors with neutrals so they don't stress out about that much visual information. At the very minimum a rule of thumb is that your viewport should have 33% neutral space (white, desaturated, or black colors) so your poor eyes can have a break and process the information right. Otherwise you get eye strain!</p>
		</div>
		
	</div>
</section>

<section>
	<h2>Why not just desaturate?<span>mix-neutral( ); lighten( ); darken( );</span></h2>
		<p>You totally can! Desaturate does a great job. But, I think not only is it important to understand what "desaturate" means. How would you desaturate a real color in the real world? Remember, you want "ugly" colors for your neutrals! You want to create bland and forgettable colors that recede into the background. These ugly duckling colors are how you get those other call to actions and buttons "pop"!</p>

		<h3>Primary and complementary Colors</h3>
			
			
		<h3>Mixed neutrals</h3>
			
			


		<h3>Desaturated neutrals</h3>
			
			

		<div>
			
			<p>Even though these may look "ugly", neutral colors are the heart of any painting, and that is the case on the web, too. Notice that the same decisions are …</p></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/">http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://tallys.github.io/color-theory/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26225339</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 15:07:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Do We Talk About When We Talk About Dashboards? (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 64 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26224846">thread link</a>) | @sebg
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://alper.datav.is/publications/dashboards/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alper.datav.is/publications/dashboards/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
      <p>Dashboards have long been the much maligned visualization vehicle of choice for decision-making in commercial and governmental situations.  While the visualization research community has concentrated much of its effort on visual analytics, the commercial success and widespread use of dashboards begs more attention.  Critically, dashboards are becoming many peoples’ direct connection to “big data” sources, enabling data democratization and wider access to data.</p>

<p>In this paper, we explore the genre of dashboards through a two-prong approach.  We survey the existing literature in business, marketing, and related fields to capture the relevant factors to consider when designing appropriate dashboards and their tools for consumption by different parties, all of which have differing levels of visualization literacy, data literacy, and decision agency.  We also collect examples of dashboard designs based on the dimensions derived from our literature search, and identify different clusters of dashboard designs with similar analysis goals, audiences, and decision support.</p>

<p>We call ourselves the “dashboard conspiracy:” a truly diverse collection of authors across Tableau Research, Microsoft Research, and Simon Fraiser University.</p>

<p><em>This work was presented at <a href="http://ieeevis.org/year/2018/welcome">IEEE VIS 2018</a> in Berlin, Germany.</em></p>

<p><em>This work was discussed in an half-hour datastori.es podcast, <a href="https://datastori.es/135-the-dashboard-conspiracy-with-lyn-bartram-and-alper-sarikaya/">give it a listen</a>!</em></p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alper.datav.is/publications/dashboards/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26224846</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 14:22:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[JSON with Commas and Comments]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 155 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26224255">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<p><em>Summary: JWCC is a minimal extension to the widely used JSON file format with
(1) optional commas after the final element of arrays and objects and (2) C/C++
style comments. These two features make it more suitable for human-editable
configuration files, without adding so many features that it’s incompatible
with numerous other (deliberate and accidental) existing JSON extensions.</em></p>

<h2 id="extensibility">Extensibility</h2>

<p>The Peter Principle is the half-joking, half-serious observation that people
get promoted to their level of incompetence, because being competent at level
<code>N</code> leads to being promoted to level <code>N+1</code>.</p>

<p>My colleague Simon Morris made a similar observation about software complexity:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Software has a Peter Principle. If a piece of code is comprehensible, someone
will extend it, so they can apply it to their own problem. If it’s
incomprehensible, they’ll write their own code instead. Code tends to be
extended to its level of incomprehensibility.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="the-many-json-extensions">The Many JSON Extensions</h3>

<p>There’s a similar story with file formats. If they’re comprehensible, they’ll
get extended. JSON (JavaScript Object Notation) is this article’s example. The
<a href="https://json.org/">original specification</a> fits on a single page, either as
text or diagrams. The file format is simple and ubiquitous. Therefore, there
are many extensions - supersets of JSON. Here’s just a few (including two
slightly different extensions both called “JSONC”):</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://json5.org/">JSON5</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://komkom.github.io/">JSONC</a> #1</li>
  <li><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/languages/json#_json-with-comments">JSONC</a> #2</li>
  <li><a href="https://hjson.github.io/">HJSON</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/lightbend/config/blob/master/HOCON.md">HOCON</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Suprisingly, <a href="https://yaml.org/">YAML</a> is also a superset of JSON. Not just
conceptually, but also in the sense that valid JSON files are also valid YAML
files (although there’s some divergence about whether duplicate keys are
legitimate). As a bonus, if you use YAML, then to paraphrase <a href="http://regex.info/blog/2006-09-15/247">Jamie
Zawinski</a>: now you have <a href="https://noyaml.com/">NO
problems</a>.</p>

<h3 id="wandering-off-the-specification">Wandering Off the Specification</h3>

<p>There are also informal supersets-of-JSON in widespread use, sometimes more by
accident than by design. The Chromium web browser’s <a href="https://source.chromium.org/chromium/chromium/src/+/master:base/json/json_reader.h;l=27;drc=d0919138b7951c1a154cf802a68aad7904b6f4c9">JSON parser goes
off-spec</a>
in a number of ways. The timeline could have been:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Some developer long ago (perhaps in a yak-shaving hurry) wrote or
copy/pasted some parsing code that was accidentally too lenient, allowing a
superset-of-JSON. Perhaps they re-used existing code that handled C-style
string escapes, like the <code>"\n"</code> in <code>"line\nbreak"</code>, without realizing that
it also unescaped <code>"\v"</code>, valid in a C string but not a JSON string.</li>
  <li>People use the software. They write first-party and third-party JSON for it.
Some of it is actually malformed (e.g. they have <code>"\v"</code> inside strings) but
tests (manual and automatic) usually check that new features work, not that
all the slightly-incorrect things are rejected. Nobody notices at the time.</li>
  <li>Years pass. <a href="https://www.hyrumslaw.com/">Hyrum’s Law</a> slowly kicks in. We
can no longer tighten this custom JSON parser implementation to follow the
spec more strictly because too many things (in unknown places) will break.</li>
</ol>

<p>This also affects our ability to replace one JSON library with another. For
example, we might want to switch from a C++-based JSON parser to a Rust-based
one, because of its security benefits. If the upstream Rust library chooses to
follow the spec diligently (which is a perfectly reasonable position) then it
would ‘break’ our apps that have inadvertently relied on the previous
looser-than-the-spec implementation.</p>

<p>We could carry local patches, but that isn’t free. Upstream fuzz-testing
infrastructure only exercises the unmodified library, not our patched flavor.
Future upstream changes may also invalidate the downstream patch, possibly in
subtle ways. An upstream “this new unsafe block is OK because it’s a private
implementation detail and nothing in this crate does X” comment might not be
aware that our out-of-tree patch does X to its internals.</p>

<h3 id="quirks">Quirks</h3>

<p>The Wuffs library approach is to expose
<a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/blob/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/doc/note/quirks.md">quirks</a>: runtime
configuration options to go off-spec in various ways so that Wuffs’
implementation can be a drop-in replacement for other implementations, without
the need for downstream patches.</p>

<p>Wuffs has <a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/blob/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/std/json/decode_quirks.wuffs">20 JSON
quirks</a>
so far. As always, there are trade-offs. They’re not free (in terms of
maintenance cost) and have super-linear complexity: that file’s comments also
has 12 call-outs to the subtleties of combining two particular quirks.</p>

<p>Here’s an example of the emergent complexity when combining two simple-sounding
JSON extensions. The first one adds C++-style <code>/* slash-star block comments */</code>
and <code>// double-slash line comments</code>. The second one packs multiple top-level
values in a single stream, separated by line breaks.</p>

<p>That second extension - by itself and when holding minified, whitespace-free
‘vanilla’ (non-extended) JSON - plays well with Unix’s traditional
line-oriented tools. It is sometimes known as Line-Delimited JSON
(<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON_streaming#Line-delimited_JSON">LDJSON</a>),
Newline-Delimited JSON (<a href="http://ndjson.org/">NDJSON</a>) and JSON Lines
(<a href="http://jsonlines.org/">JSONL</a>). But “one value per line” tools’ assumptions
can break if slash-star comments can also contain blank lines.</p>

<p>Here’s another question (let’s call it the ‘end of comment’ question). Is the
<code>'\n'</code> at the end of of a <code>// double-slash line comment</code> actually part of the
comment? At first, this sounds merely philosophical. Comments are ignored and,
in ‘vanilla’ JSON, all whitespace is ignored, so why the distinction?</p>

<p>The ‘right’ answer to that ‘end of comment’ question isn’t obvious, but it can
affect whether a line comment at the end of a multi-value stream should end in
1 or 2 <code>'\n'</code> bytes. Ideally the answer should be self-consistent with whether
a line comment at the end of file must end with the <code>'\n'</code> or whether the
implicit EOF (end-of-file) alone suffices. See also the <a href="http://seriot.ch/parsing_json.php">“Parsing JSON is a
Minefield”</a> and <a href="https://nullprogram.com/blog/2019/12/28/">“Unintuitive JSON
Parsing”</a> articles for how subtle a
‘simple’ format like JSON can be.</p>

<p>Wuffs makes one particular choice for that ‘end of comment’ question. Its
particular choice probably isn’t that important, more that it made a concious
and documented choice.</p>

<h3 id="clarity-not-terseness">Clarity, not Terseness</h3>

<p>Some general advice, when designing a new file format or extending an existing
one, is keep some room for future extensions. For example, allowing unquoted
strings (writing <code>foo</code> instead of <code>"foo"</code>), is certainly convenient, but
re-defining <code>undefined</code> or <code>datetime</code> without quotes, from invalid JSON syntax
to valid some-extension-of-JSON strings, rules out a future extension adding
new ‘keywords’.</p>

<p><a href="https://cbor.io/">CBOR</a> is binary at the wire format level (unlike textual
JSON) but naturally extends JSON at the object model level. It also has an
<code>undefined</code> concept separate from <code>null</code>, and <code>undefined</code> can be a map key. We
couldn’t do the ‘obvious’ CBOR-to-some-extended-JSON conversion if <code>undefined</code>,
without quotes, was already repurposed to mean a string.</p>

<p>I find it suprising that, <a href="https://github.com/lightbend/config/blob/master/HOCON.md#unquoted-strings">in
HOCON</a>,
“<code>truefoo</code> parses as the boolean token <code>true</code> followed by the unquoted string
<code>foo</code>. However, <code>footrue</code> parses as the unquoted string <code>footrue</code>”.</p>

<p>It can also be helpful for a <a href="https://github.com/search?q=return.flase+extension%3Apy">typo like
<code>flase</code></a> to be picked
up early as a syntax error (without needing schemas or type checking) instead
of silently accepted (as a string, not a bool). This can otherwise be
especially dangerous if further processed in a weakly-typed programming
language where any non-empty string is ‘truthy’.</p>

<p><code>[a b c]</code> is invalid ‘vanilla’ JSON syntax, but in the various extended-JSON
variants, is it a list with three 1-byte strings or one 5-byte string? Or is it
one 3-byte string because three 1-byte strings are implicitly
whitespace-delimited and also then implicitly concatenated? Any particular
answer can be consistent in its own world, but different JSON extensions make
different choices. This can be confusing when software grows large enough (or
gains enough transitive dependencies) to have to speak multiple JSON
extensions.</p>

<p>These days, when I’m programming in C/C++ or Go, I often add unnecessary
parentheses in expressions like <code>(a * b) + c</code>. Even though they’re redundant
because of well-defined operator precedence rules, different programming
languages have different precedence rules and getting the precedence wrong can
lead to <a href="https://github.com/jbangert/nail/issues/7">hard-to-spot bugs</a>. The
Wuffs language actually <a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/blob/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/doc/wuffs-the-language.md#operators">rejects a bare <code>a * b +
c</code></a>
and you have to parenthesize the multiplication or the addition.</p>

<p>Similarly, for JSON-like documents, I prefer the clarity of either <code>["a", "b",
"c"]</code> or <code>["a b c"]</code>, even if it means a little extra typing. Reading is more
important than writing for code and configuration, especially when multiple
people or long periods of time are involved.</p>

<h2 id="introducing-jwcc">Introducing JWCC</h2>

<p>Having said all of that, here is yet another superset-of-JSON, called JWCC
(JSON With Commas and Comments). It is a minimal extension. As its name
suggests, there are only two new features:</p>

<ul>
  <li>“Commas” lets you optionally have a comma after the final element of an array
or an object: <code>[1,2,3,]</code>. When you format one element per line, it’s easier
to insert and remove elements (and eyeball the diffs) when you don’t have to
fiddle with any commas (or lack of commas) on adjacent but otherwise
unrelated lines.</li>
  <li>“Comments” lets you have C++-style <code>/* slash-star block comments */</code> and <code>//
double-slash line comments</code>, anywhere where ‘vanilla’ JSON allows whitespace.
Line comments must end with a <code>'\n'</code> byte, even at the end of the file.</li>
</ul>

<p>To be clear, while every JSON file is valid JWCC, this is a new file format. It
just happens to be very familiar if you (or your software) already speak JSON.
Yes, Doug Crockford <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20150105080225if_/https://plus.google.com/+DouglasCrockfordEsq/posts/RK8qyGVaGSr">deliberately removed comments from
JSON</a>
but people keep putting them back in. If we’re going to have comment-enriched
JSON (e.g. for human-editable configuration files), we might as well have a
standard one. Cue <a href="https://xkcd.com/927/">XKCD #927 “Standards”</a>.</p>

<h3 id="cc-implementation">C/C++ Implementation</h3>

<p><a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs">Wuffs</a>’ JSON library (availble as a C or C++
API) can decode either ‘vanilla’ JSON or JWCC, using its quirks mechanism.
<a href="https://github.com/google/wuffs/tree/3d6c609dc12de3c81e1b8079ceecf96370b086a2/example/jsonptr"><code>jsonptr</code></a>
is a command line tool (a JSON formatter) that uses this library. By default,
it speaks spec-compliant ‘vanilla’ JSON:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ echo '[1,2,/*hello*/3,]' | jsonptr
[
    1,
    2
json: bad input
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It has a JWCC mode:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>$ echo '[1,2,/*hello*/3,]' | jsonptr -jwcc
[
    1,
    2,
    /*hello*/
    3,
]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It can also convert from JWCC syntax to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html">https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nigeltao.github.io/blog/2021/json-with-commas-comments.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26224255</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 13:30:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Virtual passport app presents real data risk, experts warn]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26223347">thread link</a>) | @pseudolus
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/passport-application-online-program-1.5920625 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/passport-application-online-program-1.5920625">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Canadian privacy experts are concerned the federal government's plan to develop an online passport application process could put&nbsp;personal information at risk and open a new angle of attack for fraudsters.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.4612031.1536417303!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/passport.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>IBM Canada's digital passport application platform is expected to begin testing in three months, and could be ready for use as early as 2022.<!-- --> <!-- -->(John Badcock/CBC)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>Canadian privacy experts are concerned the federal government's plan to develop an online passport application process could put&nbsp;personal information at risk and open a new angle of attack for fraudsters.</p>  <p>IBM Canada has been awarded the&nbsp;$1.5-million contract to create software that would allow Canadians to apply for a passport using their&nbsp;smartphones, tablets or&nbsp;computers.</p>  <p>The new platform would also allow applicants to&nbsp;pay fees and upload their passport photos securely, according to a statement from Immigration, Refugees and Citizenship Canada (IRCC).</p>    <blockquote><span><span><svg version="1.1" focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="30px" height="25px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g display="none"><g display="inline"> <path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg>They will attempt to&nbsp;exploit the program very quickly, very intensely to obtain the most fraudulent passports they can in the least amount of time.<svg focusable="false" x="0px" y="0px" width="23px" height="22px" viewBox="0 0 52.157 39.117" enable-background="new 0 0 52.157 39.117" space="preserve"><g display="none"><g display="inline"><path fill="000000" d="M22.692,10.113c-5.199,1.4-8.398,4.4-8.398,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.6,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.4,3.4,3.4,6.602   c0,3.799-3.4,6.799-7.4,6.799c-4.6,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z M45.692,10.113   c-5.199,1.4-8.399,4.4-8.399,8.801c0,2.4,2,3,3.601,4.199c2.2,1.602,3.399,3.4,3.399,6.602c0,3.799-3.399,6.799-7.399,6.799   c-4.601,0-8.8-3.199-8.8-10.6c0-13.6,7-20,17.599-21.799V10.113z"></path></g></g><g><g><path fill="000000" d="M6.648,29.759c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.399-3.4-3.399-6.6   c0-3.801,3.399-6.801,7.399-6.801c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z M29.648,29.759   c5.199-1.4,8.398-4.4,8.398-8.801c0-2.398-2-3-3.599-4.199c-2.2-1.6-3.401-3.4-3.401-6.6c0-3.801,3.401-6.801,7.401-6.801   c4.599,0,8.8,3.201,8.8,10.6c0,13.6-7,20-17.6,21.801V29.759z"></path></g></g></svg></span><cite>- Benoît&nbsp;Dupont, l'Université de Montréal</cite></span></blockquote>    <p>But privacy and data protection experts worry that personal information may be stored on foreign servers, providing an appealing target to criminals.</p>  <p>Sébastien Gambs, a professor in the information technology department of l'Université de Québec à Montréal&nbsp;and Canada Research Chair on privacy and data protection, said there are real&nbsp;concerns about&nbsp;where the data will be stored, a detail neither the government nor IBM Canada has divulged, though the tender identifies Amazon Web Services (AWS), the cloud computing branch of the American online retail giant.</p>  <p>"Even when we do business with an American company that agrees to store data within Canada, under the [U.S.] CLOUD Act, data could eventually be transferred out of the country," Gambs said in French.</p>  <p>In a statement, AWS said its clients retain full ownership and control of their data, including who may access that information.</p>  <p>In a separate statement, IRCC said "the privacy of Canadians and the safety of their personal information will be an absolute priority."</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_300/tech-cloud.JPG 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_460/tech-cloud.JPG 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_620/tech-cloud.JPG 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/tech-cloud.JPG 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_1180/tech-cloud.JPG 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5555269.1588631660!/fileImage/httpImage/image.JPG_gen/derivatives/original_780/tech-cloud.JPG"></p></div><figcaption>Amazon Web Services (AWS) says its clients retain full control over the data it stores.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Ivan Alvarado/Reuters)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <h2>Canadian passports highly valued</h2>  <p>Benoît Dupont, a criminology professor at l'Université de Montréal and Canada Research Chair in cybersecurity, said the passport app will likely be a major target for fraudsters&nbsp;eager to get their hands on&nbsp;Canadian passports and the mobility that comes with them.</p>  <p>"That's very attractive for organized crime groups who specialize in human trafficking," Dupont said in French. "They will attempt to&nbsp;exploit the program very quickly, very intensely to obtain the most fraudulent passports they can in the least amount of time."</p>  <p>But&nbsp;Gambs said any virtual application will likely have extra&nbsp;steps built in to protect against hackers.</p>  <p>"As soon as we're doing things remotely, verifying somebody's identity becomes much more difficult," he said. "The government will definitely need to collect more personal information in order to verify an applicant's identity."</p>  <h2>'Vicious cycle': PIPSC</h2>  <p>The Professional Institute of the Public Services (PIPSC) said this tender should never have gone out to the private sector when it could have been developed in-house by public servants, as was done with the online tax portal.</p>  <p>"It's a vicious cycle. Instead of developing resources internally, we go externally," said&nbsp;Stéphane Aubry, vice-president of PIPSC. "Then we don't have the needed expertise internally,&nbsp;which&nbsp;unfortunately, over the years, fades and makes it so we need to contract out."</p>  <p>PIPSC said the project raises <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/phoenix-pay-system-cost-report-1.5138036">the spectre of the Phoenix pay system fiasco</a>, which also involved IBM.&nbsp;IBM Canada will be required to train and support IRCC employees in running the new passport system, according to the tender documents.</p>  <p>In 2020, the government issued just 897,401 passports, compared to 2.6 million the year before. For the first four months of the pandemic, Service Canada was only providing critical passport services for urgent travel.&nbsp;</p>  <p>Nevertheless, the Canadian Anti-Fraud Centre received 1,806 reports of passport-related fraud last year.</p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/ottawa/passport-application-online-program-1.5920625</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26223347</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 11:36:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ethereum Isn't Fun Anymore]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 285 | Comments 592 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26222709">thread link</a>) | @timdaub
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://timdaub.github.io/2021/02/22/ethereum-isnt-fun-anymore/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://timdaub.github.io/2021/02/22/ethereum-isnt-fun-anymore/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><strong>Ethereum isn't fun anymore. There I said it.</strong> And although, the last time I developed an app using it has been more than a year ago, I stand by my word. <strong>Developing dapps on Ethereum has become annoying</strong>. Here's why:</p>
<p><img src="https://timdaub.github.io/assets/images/pedro.gif"></p>
<h2 id="i-used-ethereum-before-it-was-cool.">I used Ethereum before it was cool.</h2>
<p>I know; it's such a hipster statement. But it's true. Ethereum has stopped being edgy. It has transitioned out of its niche to build a world computer. Its community has become huge, and I stopped knowing most faces. Where there was a feeling of revolution and new beginnings, now there are people in suits talking corporate. Within just a few years, it went from <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/DaddyDeFi/DaiDaddy">DAI daddys</a> and only <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.molochdao.com/">half-ironic satanist cults</a> to lending, insurance, and trade protocols.</p>
<p>"What's Ethereum's killer app?" we asked ourselves not long ago. Now we know. It's the world's best publicly-accessible settlement platform for financial transactions. In a way, that's exciting. The markets think so too. But for anyone else that worked with Ethereum but outside of financial applications, it's somewhat of a letdown.</p>
<p><img src="https://timdaub.github.io/assets/images/homer.gif"></p>
<h2 id="how-do-you-do-fellow-ethereans">How do you do, fellow Ethereans?</h2>
<p>I think it must have been around the time of the last big crypto bubble when Monero enthusiasts called for "Making Monero cheap again."</p>
<p>Monero, being the anonymous digital currency that had indeed just legit use cases apart from the occasional rumors that entangled it in drug trafficking, had suddenly become too expensive for everyday use. Realizing the glaring threat of becoming too valuable, its core developers went on to fix the problem by campaigning at CoinDesk's yearly industry gathering Consensus.</p>
<p>They announced the "Monero Enterprise Alliance." An inside joke, supposed to piss off other projects that had started to take themselves too seriously. Being slightly confused that day myself, I now can't recall if the effort had ever been successful. But in any case, I can't recommend buying Monero. It's useless.</p>
<h2 id="gas-prices-are-too-damn-high">Gas prices are too damn high!</h2>
<p><img src="https://timdaub.github.io/assets/images/deepfried_high_rents.jpg"></p>
<p>There was a phase in my short career as an Ethereum developer where I looked at Etherscan's "<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://etherscan.io/contractsVerified">Verified Contracts</a>" page all day long to find vulnerabilities in newly uploaded contracts. "My name's Tim and I'm an etherholic!"</p>
<p>It was addictive. I ended up calling a few of those contracts, failing to cause any havoc, sadly. But it was so much fun! Back when transaction fees were still affordable on Ethereum, building projects was great. We started up Ganache and our favorite text editor (vim). The only choice we had was Solidity. And off we went.</p>
<p>Now, building Ethereum applications has become painful. <a href="https://timdaub.github.io/2020/09/08/web3/">web3 is a stupid idea</a>. Layer 2 isn't ready. Neither is Eth 2.0. And there are still <a href="https://timdaub.github.io/2019/02/28/poa/">many reasons to NOT ship to a Proof of Authority network</a>. Finally, gas prices are too damn high!</p>
<p>How do we move on from here?</p>
<h2 id="i-need-a-hero.">I need a hero.</h2>
<p><strong>I need a hero, and by that, I mean that I need a usable methodology for building scaleable decentralized apps.</strong> Yes, you've heard that right. We don't need more "Ethereum killers" that can do 10x more tx/s than Ethereum. Those are useless.</p>
<p>Instead, we need an approach for the average Joe developer to create their idea within the Ethereum ecosystem without the need for hardcore unproven technologies. I know, you Vitalik will say: "Oh, it's not a problem, we can has '<a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://vitalik.ca/general/2020/03/21/garbled.html">Garbled Circuits</a>' and zkrollups." But I'm telling you that no sane Joe will touch that shit without a serious cryptographic specialist by their side.</p>
<p>We want what we stayed for initially: Good ol smart contracts. But right now, they're too damn expensive to innovate.</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://timdaub.github.io/2021/02/22/ethereum-isnt-fun-anymore/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26222709</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 10:05:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Start with a Niche]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26222313">thread link</a>) | @tablet
<br/>
February 22, 2021 | https://fibery.io/blog/start-with-a-niche/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://fibery.io/blog/start-with-a-niche/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>The most popular products don’t become mass popular overnight. It’s a process. Usually, their popularity is uneven, they are unknown in some niches, but very popular in other niches.</p><p>When you start a product, sometimes you know the niche already and can easily define target customers. However, in many cases, you just don’t and try to find the niche and this miraculous niche-market-fit. </p><p>One of the most common mistakes is to ignore niches and just try to attract all kinds of customers. It’s essential to find 1-2 ponds to start from and then expand to the other, larger, and more promising lakes and oceans 🚰 → 🛁 → 🌊.</p><p>Here are a couple, maybe surprising examples, that demonstrate how popular products took off. </p><h4>Electrical telegraph (1837)</h4><p>Its adoption was not easy, since it was not clear what are the benefits for commercial institutions. Stockbrokers and reporters got the benefits first. They understood that fast information transition increases efficiency and helps to get an edge. In a short term, all major news agencies and major stock markets were connected to the telegraph. </p><h4>Telephone (1876)</h4><p>Telephones were adopted by police departments and fire stations. Fast reaction to crime reports and fires was great, but the telegraph was not enough. You have to have two-ways communication to get some details that the sender maybe is not expecting to report initially. </p><h4>Phonograph (1877)</h4><p>Try to guess the first niche market for the phonograph. Rich music lovers? Nope. First phonographs were coin-machines in bars. Throw a nickel and enjoy Stephen Foster ballads.</p><h4>Car (1886)</h4><p>Cars are almost among the lucky exception to the niche rule. However, there was still one group of people in the USA that moved from horses to cars enormously fast — farmers. Cars just expanded the borders of farmers’ social life and business activities. Suddenly you can buy goods, not from a local dealer, but a dealer in a remote town (much cheaper). Suddenly you can visit a town and watch a movie. These benefits were not important for the urban population, for they were life-changers for the rural population. Nevertheless, cars were adopted in cities quite fast as well.</p><blockquote><p>In addition, the car delivered you to the door and was faster than a horse-and-buggy, thus allowing longer trips in shorter time. Farmers had traditionally felt guilty about taking such trips, even when the time was available. </p></blockquote><h4>Radio (1895)</h4><p>Radio was immediately adopted by the British Royal Navy, they thought that radio can speed up communication between ships and were right. Fun fact: in 1912 Titanic sent CQD (distress signal), however, <a href="https://www.nationalgeographic.com/history/article/why-titanic-first-call-help-not-sos-signal">radio receiver was turned off on the closest ship</a>:</p><blockquote><p>Meanwhile, the closest ship, Californian, didn’t receive Titanic’s distress calls at all. Its wireless operator had switched off his receiver and gone to bed after Phillips told him to shut up.</p></blockquote><h4>VisiCalc (Excel predecessor, 1979)</h4><p>First, it was adopted by accountants. Businessmen and analysts joined the party much later. Accountants just saw the value right away (and quite many people pirchased Apple II just to get <a href="https://thenewstack.io/how-visicalcs-spreadsheets-changed-the-world/">VisiCalc</a>):</p><blockquote><p>Like an accountant, I remember showing it to one around here and he started shaking and said, “That’s what I do all week. I could do it in an hour.” … I meet these people now, they come up to me and say, “I gotta tell you, you changed my life. You made accounting fun.”</p></blockquote><h4>Facebook (2004)</h4><p>Everybody knows that Facebook got its popularity in universities first. Everybody knows the rest of the story.</p><blockquote><p>Within 24 hours, 1,200 Harvard students had signed up, and after one month, over half of the undergraduate population had a profile. The network was promptly extended to other Boston universities, the Ivy League and eventually all US universities</p></blockquote><hr><p>Can you start without any niche in mind? Yes, you can, but this is just hard. The most problematic part is marketing. Who are your ideal customers? How to reach them? How to target your message? <strong>Product is the message</strong>, so without proper marketing startup success chances are low. </p><h4>My experience</h4><p>In Fibery we did our first release in April 2020 as a general work management tool. We were not sure in what types of companies it will work better and what use cases will be more valuable. In just a month it became clear that we had all kinds of leads from all kinds of companies. Leads demanded all kinds of improvements that just didn’t form a sane strategy. </p><p>We quickly <a href="https://fibery.io/blog/chronicles-21/">decided to select a single niche and focus on it</a>. The niche we choose was product companies from 20 to 200 people. And it made everything much simpler. Finally, we can quite accurately say what features are important and what features are not so important, what is our value proposition, who is our ideal lead (Product Ops or CPO). It took us 9 months to prepare the <a href="https://fibery.io/product-management">second release</a>, but in this niche Fibery can fly much better, I believe. </p><p>OK, niche strategy looks convincing, but how to find the niche? We used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conway%27s_law">Conway’s law</a>, and it’s just partially a joke. We’ve reviewed a couple of alternatives and selected one we knew best and were confident that our product will provide a significant value boost. There were other alternatives, like education space or digital agencies space, but our knowledge here was not deep enough. It means we should rely on some domain experts, etc. It’s not a huge problem, but we also did not feel that these niches are better.</p><p>A startup should be an experimentation facility that hypothesizes, executes, and measures the results. The faster you can do it, the faster you find your niche. Why it took us 9 months to make this niche release? In fact we spend time to create a niche-probing framework. Now we can asseble solutions for various niches in 1-2 weeks and check initial response in 1-2 months. If the first niche will not be successful, we at least have a decent experimentation framework 🧬.</p></section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://fibery.io/blog/start-with-a-niche/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26222313</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 09:05:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Indian Government Breached, Massive Amount of Critical Vulnerabilities]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 293 | Comments 65 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26221607">thread link</a>) | @astroanax
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>A writeup detailing the vulnerability reporting process that took place after Sakura Samurai had breached the Indian Government</p><p>Reading time: 6 minutes.</p><div>
      

<p>Sakura Samurai knew that the Indian Government operated an RVDP (Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure Program). <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> put a list together of initial assets in scope for Sakura Samurai to legally test. <a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a> reported that he had found sensitive data and was able to breach police assets. <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> was working in the enumeration processes with his friend, <a href="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001" title="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001">Zultan Holder</a> [not an active Sakura Samurai member] and identified a slew of various attack vectors, immediately resulting in the exposure of many pairs of credentials for databases and other pertinent applications.</p>
<p>The team was informed of the initial enumeration results as they continued to work on the list of assets within scope, while also further jumping into the research and began performing analysis on the sensitive data, identifying additional vectors of attack, exposed PII, and even more credentials.</p>
<p>Sakura Samurai team members included <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner">Aubrey Cottle</a>, and<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking"> John Jackson</a></p>
<p>In total, the following vulnerabilities were identified, in no specific order:</p>
<ul>
<li>35 Separate Instances of Exposed Credential Pairs (Servers, Important Applications, etc)</li>
<li>3 Instances of Sensitive File Disclosure</li>
<li>5 Exposed private-key pairs for servers</li>
<li>13K+ PII Records [and those are only the records that we were inadvertently exposed to]</li>
<li>Dozens of Exposed Sensitive Police Reports</li>
<li>Session Hijacking Chained via Multiple Vulnerabilities, resulting in the compromise of extremely sensitive government systems</li>
<li>Remote Code Execution on a sensitive financial server; a server that contained large backups of Financial Records</li>
</ul>

<p>First and foremost, it is important to note that so many Critical findings had been identified during our testing that we cannot possibly include all of the vulnerabilities without making this writeup unnecessarily heavy. Therefore, we have opted to include small snippets of repetitive findings in this section. Many variations of application and server credentials also were obtained but the point has already been made.</p>
<p><strong>Exposed Database Credentials</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/db-creds.png" alt=""><br>
<strong>Private SSH Keys</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/priv-ssh.png" alt=""></p>
<p><strong>Sensitive File Exposure</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/sens-file-exp.png" alt=""><br>
<strong>Exposed PHP Mailer Credentials</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/mailer.png" alt=""></p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">Robert Willis</a> identified an application that resulted in a vulnerability that allowed him to access Sensitive Police Records, containing PII of individuals listed on the report. In addition, sample forensic reports and forensic tooling that is used by the police department was identified by Willis. The exposure of citizen’s sensitive information, some being victims, is a sensitive subject within itself and highly alarming.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/police.png" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/police2.png" alt=""><br>
Shortly after, <a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">Jackson Henry</a> found a vulnerability that resulted in the exposure of 14,000+ user records. The records included a wide range of sensitive information, including full name, contact info, employee’s department, date of birth, etc. These exposed records along with other various SQL server dumps and Rob’s Police Record Exposure is enough to constitute a data breach without even logging into any of the servers.</p>
<p>Henry identified many credential pairs which could have resulted in even more exploitation of many other people. The PII identified is a small sample of a much larger issue.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/14k-records.png" alt=""><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">John Jackson</a> was able to identify a relevant Remote Code Execution Vulnerability, affecting an out-of-date application residing on one of the government servers. The remote code execution vulnerability allowed for complete access to sensitive files on the server, including the ability to exfiltrate complete backups of financial records [although data exfiltration wasn’t performed to avoid unnecessary action]</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/rce1.png" alt=""><br>
<img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/rce2.png" alt=""><br>
Finally, <a href="https://www.twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://www.twitter.com/Kirtaner">Aubrey Cottle</a> identified the presence of what appeared to be an extremely important application being hosted by the same server that John had achieved successful Remote Code Execution on. Cottle then chained together multiple vulnerabilities in conjunction with the Remote Code Execution vulnerability, resulting in the ability to hijack any user’s session on the web application. The application contained troves of sensitive government data and could have given a threat actor the ability to perform highly-critical, admin-based government actions.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/session-chained.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Even though the Indian Government has a RVDP in place, we didn’t feel comfortable disclosing the vulnerabilities right away. The hacking process was far from the standard situation of business-as-usual security research. In total, our report compounded to a massive 34 page report worth of vulnerabilities. We knew that our intent was good, but we wanted to ensure that the US Government had eyes on the situation. Sakura Samurai coordinated with the <a href="https://twitter.com/DC3VDP" title="https://twitter.com/DC3VDP">U.S. DoD Vulnerability Disclosure Program (VDP)</a> to assist in facilitating initial conversations of disclosure. <a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">John Jackson</a> spoke with DC3’s Program Manager via email and coordinated on a plan of action.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-1.png" alt=""><br>
Roughly 4 days later, after further communication with the DC3, we felt safe to begin our initial reveal of research on the NCIIPC’s RVDP program.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-2.png" alt=""></p>
<p>In addition, the DC3 also commended the hacking that we did in support of making the cyberspace a better place for everyone.</p>
<p><img src="https://johnjhacking.com/uploads/dc3-3.png" alt=""></p>
<p>Unfortunately, what seemed like a done deal turned out to be quite the unprofessional ride. Any organization knows that fixing breach-worthy vulnerabilities is extremely time sensitive. Once threat actors catch wind of major vulnerabilities against an organization they begin poking on their own, looking for more vectors of attack. Immediately upon revealing that Sakura Samurai was the group responsible for hacking the Indian Government, we followed up with them via Email.</p>
<p><strong>Timeline</strong></p>
<p><strong>2021/02/04</strong> - DC3 begins initial contact with the Indian Government.<br>
<strong>2021/02/08</strong> - Sakura Samurai informs the public that they breached the Government.<br>
<strong>2021/02/08</strong> - Sakura Samurai makes contact with the NCIIPC, noting that the report that they received was a result of their research.<br>
<strong>2021/02/09</strong> - The NCIIPC responds, with a basic acknowledgement and thank you for the research.<br>
<strong>2021/02/09</strong> - Sakura Samurai asks for clarification on patching and the responsibility of breach disclosure to the public.<br>
<strong>2021/02/10</strong> - Sakura Samurai, having received no response, asks for an update on the involved remediation and breach notification processes.<br>
<strong>2021/02/16</strong> - Sakura Samurai once again asks for NCIIPC’s plans for remediation and disclosure.<br>
<strong>2021/02/17</strong> - The NCIIPC makes contact, 7-days later, stating that they will follow up in a short time. Again, we ask about plans of anticipated patching and breach notification to the affected citizens.<br>
<strong>2021/02/19</strong> - In the morning, we ask again about patching and disclosure, 8-hours later and still no response on the matter.<br>
<strong>2021/02/19</strong> - Sakura Samurai reviews the submitted vulnerability report and notes that only about an eighth or less of the submitted Critical Vulnerabilities have been resolved within a two-week period. No notification of breach has occurred even though Government Employees and Indian Citizens are at risk of exploitation from threat actors.</p>

<p>Governments have an obligation to protect the private data of its employees and citizens. In addition, the exposure of proprietary government data can be used for great means of manipulation and for other destructive purposes. While the NCIIPC operates a Responsible Vulnerability Disclosure Program, the recklessness and avoidance of communication represents the complete opposite of a responsible program. A failure to release notification of breach to affected citizens and to patch highly-critical vulnerabilities in a timely manner reflects poorly on the state of their Information Security posture. The clock to patch vulnerabilities began immediately when the DC3 contacted the NCIIPC via Twitter, as it is a highly visible space - one which threat actors avidly monitor.</p>
<p>Sakura Samurai urge the NCIIPC to patch the remainder of the vulnerabilities. The criticality of some of the issues cannot wait weeks or months for adequate resolution.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Check out our website</strong><br>
<a href="https://sakurasamurai.org/" title="https://sakurasamurai.org">https://sakurasamurai.org</a></p>
<p><strong><em>Twitter Links:</em></strong><br>
Main Page<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii" title="https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii">https://twitter.com/SakuraSamuraii</a><br>
Founders<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking" title="https://twitter.com/johnjhacking">https://twitter.com/johnjhacking</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/nicksahler" title="https://twitter.com/nicksahler">https://twitter.com/nicksahler</a><br>
Members<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax" title="https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax">https://twitter.com/JacksonHHax</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner" title="https://twitter.com/Kirtaner">https://twitter.com/Kirtaner</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/rej_ex" title="https://twitter.com/rej_ex">https://twitter.com/rej_ex</a><br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/endingwithali" title="https://twitter.com/endingwithali">https://twitter.com/endingwithali</a><br>
Collaborator<br>
<a href="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001" title="https://twitter.com/orpheus9001">https://twitter.com/orpheus9001</a></p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://johnjhacking.com/blog/indian-government-breached-massive-amount-of-critical-vulnerabilities/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26221607</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 06:57:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Frustrated with Parler deplatforming, I am building a service no one can silence]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 110 | Comments 190 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218900">thread link</a>) | @anon20190221
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      
      

      

<p>This is the first post in this blog, it was published on February 19, 2021.</p>

<h2 id="motivation">Motivation</h2>

<h3 id="censorship">Censorship</h3>

<p>The year of 2020 will be remembered for the pandemic, the BLM movement, and the U.S. elections among other billion of things around the globe. It is funny I even mention the third one considering how little I give a damn about U.S. politics, yet this whole story begins with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parler">Parler</a> deplatforming that happened about a month ago. Let me remind you: Apple, Google, Amazon, and a few other companies terminated their service to the free speech social network for insufficient moderation effectively destroying the platform in a matter of just a couple of days. What the fuck?</p>

<p>OK, let me be clear with my position: I believe every private company has a right to refuse service to anyone, whether an individual or a business, but I also have my own right to despise them for exercising that. What they did was probably legal, but screw them anyway, they failed us. Regardless what these psychopathic corporations like to tell the public, they are only concerned with maximizing shareholder value, and if there is anything  even remotely resembling an image liability (through pressure by political radicals, cancel culture SJWs, you name it), they will not think twice. What disgusts me the most here is neither greed nor hypocrisy but their unwillingness to grow a pair of balls and stand up for freedom of speech.</p>

<p>You see, freedom of speech and expression must be absolute. You cannot have censorship-resistance with exceptions; otherwise, these exceptions could be used to remove or block anything unwanted, not only offensive. This way, the Chinese cannot access Wikipedia because of what originally started as a counter-terrorism measure, and the Russians cannot access LinkedIn because of what originally started as a children protection measure. We cannot deprive humanity of their freedom just because some small fraction of users might, unfortunately, use that freedom to spread offensive content. In the same way, you do not ban electricity because people get electrocuted.</p>

<p>Let us now switch from corporates to governments. Ooh, wee! Do not even get me started on that. And I am not even talking about cases like Google happily not letting people disable <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SafeSearch">SafeSearch</a> in Indonesia because its government knows best, that is just the tip of the iceberg. I am talking about political censorship which includes silencing people with torture, gulags, and bullets. Here is the world map of the freedom of the press status:</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/press-freedom.png" alt="2020 Press Freedom Index"></p>

<p>Just look at this mess. Blue tones mean OK-ish, others not so much. This map is <a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/User:NordNordWest">NordNordWest</a>’s work based on the <a href="https://rsf.org/en/ranking">2020 Press Freedom Index</a> and is distributed under <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/de/legalcode">CC BY-SA 3.0 de</a>. Keep in mind population densities, e.g. there are about 90 times more people per unit area living in Vietnam than Australia. I am actually surprised the U.S. did so well in 2020 considering how badly they wanted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julian_Assange">Mr. Assange</a> to be extradited and executed.</p>

<p>What would you answer your children if they asked you how in the world North Korea still exists in its current form with 25 million Koreans suffering for over 70 years and no one is doing anything about that? Or how about 28 million people in Venezuela? Or 82 million people in Iran? Giving voice to all whistleblowers and activists, especially the ones risking their lives and freedom in hostile environments is the fundamental goal of Pepe.</p>

<h3 id="darknets">Darknets</h3>

<p>There is already <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tor_(anonymity_network)">Tor</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I2P">I2P</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freenet">Freenet</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GNUnet">GNUnet</a> etc. We can run emails, message boards, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BitTorrent">BitTorrent</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kad_network">Kad</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System">IPFS</a> on top of them, maybe even use <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethereum">Ethereum</a> smart contracts for decentralized computing. All the technology is there, why bother with something new? Well, first of all, these are all amazing projects, there is nothing wrong with them. The peculiar thing, however, is none of them except BitTorrent (and perhaps Tor) gained much popularity, neither do we see any readily available censorship-resistant communication platforms. Why is that?</p>

<p>I claim there are 2 main reasons for that:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>They are hard to use. The “Unix is user-friendly, it is just picky about who its friends are.” aphorism still lives in most them: you may need to install a bunch of additional software (such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_virtual_machine">JVM</a> or shared libraries) potentially dealing with a dependency hell on some platforms; read through sparse documentation and dead forums on optimal network, security, and sharing settings; carefully configure your router, computer, and client; install, study, and configure applications running on top of the darknet, i.e. repeat the steps. The reason why Tor became popular outside of research was not because it was first, but because of the hacky all-in-one Tor Browser Bundle with sane defaults.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>They prefer purity to practicality. Instead of concentrating manpower on few specific use cases, most existing tools try to conquer the world: a new internet, interplanetary, infrastructure, an application framework, APIs, a Turing-complete language on the blockchain etc. This is great and all, it is general, conceptual, modular, extensible, and stackable—everything we like—but sometimes overengineering is just overengineering given the goal. And our goal here is not to make a technical revolution, but to help as many people as we can communicate without fear of retribution.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>BitTorrent evolved into something that is used by 150 million people worldwide, it seamlessly adopted <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_hash_table">DHT</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer_exchange">PEX</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Micro_Transport_Protocol">µTP</a>, trackerless <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnet_URI_scheme">magnet links</a>, and people do not even know what the hell it all means. Even though proprietary, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skype">Skype</a> thrived very similarly (at least before it was crippled by Microsoft), millions of its users did not even know what peer-to-peer meant, not to mention how it worked under the hood, it just did. These two systems succeeded not because of luck but rather as a result of some excellent product decisions. We need to learn from that and reiterate.</p>

<h2 id="pepe-overview">Pepe overview</h2>

<h3 id="user-level">User level</h3>

<p>For the messaging platform, I chose to use an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Imageboard">imageboard</a> similar to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4chan">4chan</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futaba_Channel">Futaba Channel</a>. While not the most popular type of forum, imageboards are extremely flexible and free of junk like authentication or karma, they promote anonymity in a very practical way, and over 30 million people are already familiar with them. Perhaps, I am not a big fan of their crowded old-school design, but the initial user traction is more important than my sense of beauty, we will refine the looks through time.</p>

<p>That is, the Pepe imageboard is going to be the only application running on top the Pepe darknet, they are in fact inseparable. This way, we can design the network specifically for this one use case. This brings both security and performance benefits. Joining the darknet can be as simple as double clicking the application, and users do not need to install or configure any third-party browsers or proxy servers, they can just go to <a href="http://localhost:8666/">localhost:8666</a> using Chrome, Safari, or whatever they like, and it is going to be safe without any third-party extensions.</p>

<p>Once online, users may browse existing or create new message boards about various topics in any language such as <code>/en/food/</code> or <code>/ja/math/</code>. A board is a collection of threads about something more specific, would it be an idea or a question. A thread has a collection of posts that people send replying to each other. Each post may have one or multiple attachments such as photos, videos, you name it. So that you have an idea of what it looks like, here is a screenshot of a random thread on the 4chan DIY board:</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/4chan-thread.png" alt="4chan thread"></p>

<p>What is fundamentally different with Pepe is moderation. Instead of relying on a centralized entity with a banhammer, each board and thread owner may anonymously moderate their spaces on their own. However, nothing can actually be deleted, it can only be shadowed, and each user decides whether they want to see the light or the full version of the page at any moment in time. People can still reply to shadowed posts inside their own shadowed posts, so no one cannot silence anyone, only maintain order on the light side.</p>

<p>If people are no longer interested in particular threads, they will eventually become forgotten by the network and naturally disappear from their board. But if there is at least one person who is subscribed to or has archived some thread, no one in the world (even Pepe creators) can censor or somehow shut it down without hurting most of the network Pepe is running on top of.</p>

<h3 id="network-level">Network level</h3>

<p>The three biggest problems with 4chan and similar communication platforms are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>They use closed source software so no one can tell how secure everything is and what is really going on there.</li>
  <li>They are centralized, i.e. some individual or business owns the servers and fully controls the whole infrastructure.</li>
  <li>They collect lots of metadata including but not limited to “someone with this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address">IP address</a> posted this at this moment in time”.</li>
</ul>

<p>Mitigating the first problem is the easiest: just use open-source software whenever possible. Regarding the centralization issue, we could switch to a decentralized solution like BitTorrent (imagine each torrent containing a thread with its posts and attachments), but that itself does not help with privacy, people can still see what others are doing. Similarly, we could tackle the privacy issue with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network">VPN</a> or a darknet like Tor or I2P, but that, contrary to popular belief, does not solve the centralization issue in any way. Clearly, we need the best of the two worlds. Let us fuse them together!</p>

<p><img src="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/pepe-routing.png" alt="Pepe routing"></p>

<p>Here is an very simplified walk through how the network works. Imagine Bob is an undercover journalist who wants to anonymously share his report and Alice is a political activist who is interested in the investigation Bob had been doing. It all starts with Bob announcing he has the report:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Bob joins the network and gathers information about random peers on it through the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_hash_table">DHT</a>. This way, Bob discovers hundreds of participants including X and Y. Similarly, Bob registers himself on the network through the DHT so that others …</p></li></ol></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/">https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://1b677b8f8bb20100.github.io/introduction/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218900</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:28:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[TransferWise changes name to Wise]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 237 | Comments 225 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218693">thread link</a>) | @watbe
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>
<div>
<p>Today, we’re changing our name from TransferWise to Wise.</p>
<p>Our customers now need us for more than money transfers. Sending, spending, and receiving money internationally is too expensive, slow, and inconvenient. We’re fixing that for people and businesses.</p>
<p>You can <a href="https://transferwise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise#transferwise-is-now-wise">skip ahead to see what changes for you</a> (spoiler: not much, right away), but first, let’s go back a bit.</p>
<h2><a href="#a-decade-into-our-mission" id="a-decade-into-our-mission"></a>A decade into our mission</h2>
<p>Ten years ago, Taavet and I set out to fix international money transfers for all of us who’d been overcharged and underserved by banks. We named our idea ‘TransferWise’ — because our early customers were ‘wise’ to know their banks were charging hidden fees in exchange rate markups.</p>
<p>We set ourselves a mission to make money work without borders — to make money move instantly, transparently, conveniently, and — eventually — for free.</p>
<p>Now, we’re a community of 10 million like-minded people and businesses managing money all over the world, saving billions and fighting as hard as ever against hidden fees.</p>
<p>Our multi-currency account and the clever debit card is replacing international banking for many of you. By building this infrastructure for you, we’ve created a platform that more than a dozen banks use today.</p>
<p>You’ve told us for years the problem is bigger than money transfers. Any time money moves into another currency, it’s still a maze of hidden exchange rate markups, high fees, delays, and small print.</p>
<h2><a href="#well-fix-international-banking-together" id="well-fix-international-banking-together"></a>We’ll fix international banking together</h2>
<p>Sending, spending, receiving, and holding money internationally doesn’t work like it should, because the international banking system was built for the past.</p>
<p>For generations, banks have been defined by borders. Traditional bank accounts trap our money in one country, making international lives more difficult and expensive than they need to be. We shouldn’t have to accept this status quo.</p>
<p>Today, we don’t. We’ll fix it with Wise — the world’s most international account. It makes your money borderless — with instant, super-cheap money transfers, a debit card to spend in any currency, account details to get paid in 30+ countries, balances to hold your money safely in 50+ different currencies, multi-currency direct debits, and other revolutionary features.</p>
<h2><a href="#transferwise-is-now-wise" id="transferwise-is-now-wise"></a>TransferWise is now Wise</h2>
<p>Today our name catches up with who we’re already building for — a community of people and businesses with multi-currency lives. Wise is for all of us who live, work, travel, or support family around the world. It’s for those of us who want to cut out the middlemen that hold us back from being truly borderless.</p>
<p>For customers, not too much will change right away. We become “Wise” or “Wise Business” — depending how you use us. You can access your exact same account via <a href="http://wise.com/">wise.com</a>, using your current email and password. You won't need a new account. In a few weeks we will start to redirect transferwise.com to wise.com.</p>
<p>Our logo has changed, and our apps will be renamed. But our icon — the fast flag — remains as a symbol for money without borders. Beyond that, you’ll notice some new colours, words, and designs.</p>
<p>The core experience of using Wise will remain faster, cheaper, and more convenient than anything else. Our mission remains the same. We’re still making — and always will be making — money work without borders.</p>
<p>We’re humbled that 10 million of you already rely on us to help you lead your international lives. We can’t wait to bring the next 100 million of you with us as we continue to build a new, fair, and transparent world of money.</p>
<p>Onwards.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wise.com/gb/blog/world-meet-wise</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218693</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:02:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tap your phone at Gold Coast bus stops to access my website]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 73 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26218432">thread link</a>) | @joshuawithers
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://joshwithers.blog/2021/02/22/tap-your-phone.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://joshwithers.blog/2021/02/22/tap-your-phone.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
      <p>My February 2021 Apple Fitness challenge is to walk 227km in the month. So I was out late last night closing in on the target when I stopped and looked at the bus timetable sign at a local bus stop.</p>

<p><img src="https://joshwithers.blog/uploads/2021/7f4522c3f4.jpg"></p>

<p>That NFC tag piqued my curiosity. I wondered if it worked on iPhone?</p>

<p>So I tapped my iPhone 12 Pro up against the NFC logo and a website hyperlink notification popped up like when you scan a QR code.</p>

<p><img src="https://joshwithers.blog/uploads/2021/0c4028d20c.jpg"></p>

<p>And TransLink, the local public transport provider, had neglected to renew the domain name used in the NFC tag.</p>

<p>I now own the <a href="http://transl.in/">transl.in</a> domain name and the people of the Gold Coast now have easy access to my website. 🤷‍♂️</p>

<p>As an example, a local bus stop links to <a href="http://transl.in/k_300428">http://transl.in/k_300428</a></p>

  </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://joshwithers.blog/2021/02/22/tap-your-phone.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26218432</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 23:29:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Data Pipeline Is a Materialized View]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 138 | Comments 47 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26217911">thread link</a>) | @nchammas
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Say you run an online book store and want to build a data pipeline that figures out who the top-selling authors are. Logically, the input to the pipeline is a log of every individual book purchase on the store for all time, along with details about each book like who authored it. And the output is a list of the top-selling authors per month.</p>

<!-- [image: book purchases + authorship info -> top-selling authors of the month] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/top-selling-authors.png" width="1000">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>The output of this data pipeline is a function of the input. In other words, the output is derived from the input by running the input through the pipeline.</p>

<!-- [image: f(input) -> output] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/f-input-output.png" width="400">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>This is an important characteristic of the output. As long as the input data and pipeline transformations (i.e. the pipeline code) are preserved, the output can always be recreated. The input data is <em>primary</em>; if lost, it cannot be replaced. The output data, along with any intermediate stages in the pipeline, are <em>derivative</em>; they can always be recreated from the primary data using the pipeline.</p>

<h2 id="the-logical-view">The Logical View</h2>

<p>Let’s represent our hypothetical “Top-Selling Authors” pipeline as a directed graph, where the nodes represent datasets and the edges represent transformations of those datasets. Furthermore, let’s color each dataset in the graph based on whether it’s primary or derivative.</p>

<!-- [image: colored graph of transformations] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/pipeline-graph.png" width="500">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>Most data pipelines, if you zoom out far enough, look something like this. You have some source data; it gets sliced, diced, and combined in various ways to produce some outputs. If someone were to wipe out all the derived data in this pipeline, you’d be able to regenerate it without any data loss. The pipeline could include any number of arbitrary steps, like copying files from an FTP share, or scraping data from a web page. It doesn’t matter as long as the pipeline produces the same output when given the same input.</p>

<p>Any time someone queries the output of the pipeline, it’s logically equivalent to them running the entire pipeline on the source data to get the output they’re looking for. In this way, a pipeline is a <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/relational-databases/views/views?view=sql-server-ver15">view</a> into the source data.</p>

<h2 id="materializing-the-view">Materializing the View</h2>

<p>Of course, data pipelines don’t work this way in practice. It would be a waste of resources and a long wait for users if every query triggered a series of computations stretching all the way back to the primary data. When you ask for this month’s top-selling authors, you expect a quick response.</p>

<p>Hence, the typical real-world pipeline <em>materializes</em> its output, and often also several of the intermediate datasets required to produce that final output. Materializing a dataset simply means saving it to persistent storage, as opposed to repeatedly computing it on the fly. So when you ask for that list of authors, whatever system answering your query can start from the closest materialized dataset, as opposed to starting at the source or primary data.</p>

<!-- [image: cached nodes in graph colored; key explaining colors; caption] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/pipeline-with-cached-nodes.png" width="500">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    A query against dataset B only needs to recompute the pipeline starting from A, since A is materialized.
    All derivative datasets, whether materialized or not, can be thrown away and recreated from the primary data.
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>So we’ve turned our view into a <em>materialized view</em>. “View” represents the logical transformations expressed in the pipeline. “Materialized” represents the fact that we cache the output of the pipeline, and perhaps also some of the intermediate steps. A complex set of interdependent data pipelines can be conceptualized in this way, as a graph of materialized views.</p>

<p>Note that this concept can be applied very broadly, and not just to what we think of as “normal” data pipelines:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A traditional web cache alleviates read traffic from the primary database, which is the source of truth. The cache is derivative and can be regenerated from the database at any time. The data in the cache is materialized so that incoming queries do not need to go all the way back to the database to get an answer.</li>
  <li>A build system compiles or assembles source code into artifacts like executables or test reports. The artifacts are derivative, whereas the source code is primary. When you run a program over and over, you reuse the artifacts output by your build system, as opposed to recompiling them from source every time.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="updating-a-materialized-view">Updating a Materialized View</h2>

<p>Materializing the output, though a practical necessity for most pipelines, adds an administrative cost. When the source data changes, the materialized views need to be updated. Otherwise, the data you get from the view will be <em>stale</em>.</p>

<!-- [image: highlighted new source row; out-of-date output aggregation] -->

<div>
<figure>
    <span>
        <img src="https://nchammas.com/assets/images/data-pipeline-materialized-view/update-materialized-view.png" width="600">
    </span>
    <figcaption>
    The sales total of 101 for Eric Carle is stale. The correct value is now 103.
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>

<p>To update a materialized view, there are two high-level properties you typically care about: the update <em>trigger</em>, and the update <em>granularity</em>. The former affects the freshness of your output, which impacts end-users of the data, and the latter affects the performance of your update process, which impacts the engineers or operators responsible for that process.</p>

<h3 id="update-trigger">Update Trigger</h3>

<p>The update trigger is the event that prompts a refresh of the materialized view—e.g. by running your pipeline against the latest source data.</p>

<p>That event may be a file landing in a shared drive, or some data arriving on an event stream, or another pipeline completing. For some pipelines, the update trigger may just be a certain time of day, in which case it might be more useful to talk about the update <em>frequency</em> rather than trigger.</p>

<p>A typical batch pipeline, for example, might run on a daily or hourly cadence, whereas a streaming pipeline may run every few seconds or minutes, or whenever a new event is delivered via some sort of event stream. Whenever the pipeline runs, it updates its output, and the whole process can be viewed as a <em>refresh</em> of the materialized view.</p>

<h3 id="update-granularity">Update Granularity</h3>

<p>The update granularity refers to how much of the materialized view needs to be modified to account for the latest changes to the source data.</p>

<p>A common update granularity is the full refresh. No matter how small or large the change to the source data, when the pipeline runs it throws away the entire output table and rebuilds it from scratch.</p>

<p>A more sophisticated pipeline might rebuild only a subset of the table, like a date partition. And an extremely precise pipeline may know how to update exactly the output rows that are impacted by the latest changes to the source data.</p>

<p>The update trigger and granularity are independent. You can have a pipeline that runs every second and does a full refresh of its output, and you can have a pipeline that runs once a day but carefully updates only the rows that it needs to.</p>

<h3 id="typical-examples">Typical Examples</h3>

<p>Let’s explore these two properties a bit using our example pipeline that computes the top-selling authors of the month.</p>

<h4 id="the-daily-batch-update">The Daily Batch Update</h4>

<p>Every night at 1 a.m., an automated process looks for a dump of the latest purchases from the previous day. The dump is a compressed CSV file.</p>

<p>The update process uses this dump to recompute the month’s sales numbers for all authors. It replaces the entire output table with all-new calculations for all authors. Many of the authors’ numbers may not have changed since the last update (because they had no new sales in that time period), but they all get recomputed nonetheless.</p>

<p>This is a very typical example of a batch pipeline. It has a scheduled update trigger at 1 a.m. every night, and an update granularity of the entire output.</p>

<h4 id="the-live-updating-table">The Live-Updating Table</h4>

<p>In this version of our top-selling authors pipeline, individual purchases are streamed in as they happen, via a stream processor like Apache Kafka. Every purchase on this stream triggers an update to the calculation of top-selling authors.</p>

<p>The update process uses each individual purchase to incrementally recompute the sales total for the relevant author. If an author has no new sales over a given span of updates, their sales total is not recomputed (though their rank in the top-selling authors may need to be updated).</p>

<p>This is an example of a precise streaming pipeline. The update trigger is the purchase event that is streamed in, and the update granularity is the sales total for a single author.</p>

<h2 id="the-declarative-data-lake">The Declarative Data Lake</h2>

<p>We previously discussed the idea of conceptualizing your <a href="https://nchammas.com/writing/modern-data-lake-database">data lake as a database</a>. And here we’ve shown how you can conceptualize your data pipelines as materialized views.</p>

<p>But what if we could take this idea further than just as a conceptual tool? What if you could actually implement your data pipelines as a graph of materialized views?</p>

<p>Taken far enough, the promise of such an idea would be to build a <em>declarative data lake</em>, where the code that manages the lake focuses more on defining <em>what</em> the datasets are and less on <em>how</em> to mechanically build or update them.</p>

<p>Two relatively new projects express aspects of this vision in clear but different ways, and they merit some discussion here: <a href="https://www.getdbt.com/">dbt</a> and <a href="https://materialize.com/">Materialize</a>.</p>

<h3 id="dbt-pipelines-as-batch-updated-sql-queries">dbt: Pipelines as Batch-Updated SQL Queries</h3>

<p>The core of <a href="https://www.getdbt.com/">dbt</a> is an engine for building <a href="https://docs.getdbt.com/docs/introduction#what-makes-dbt-so-powerful">a graph of SQL queries</a>. Parts of any given query can be generated dynamically using a templating language (<a href="https://docs.getdbt.com/tutorial/using-jinja/">Jinja</a>), and queries can reference other queries.</p>

<p>Every query has a configured materialization strategy, which defines whether the results of the query are generated ahead of time, and if so, how they are stored and updated.</p>

<p>If the results are materialized, they can be updated with a full refresh or <a href="https://docs.getdbt.com/docs/building-a-dbt-project/building-models/configuring-incremental-models/#understanding-incremental-models">incrementally</a>, though there are some restrictions on what kinds of updates can be done incrementally. Updates are typically triggered on a schedule.</p>

<h3 id="materialize-pipelines-as-live-updated-materialized-views">Materialize: Pipelines as Live-Updated Materialized Views</h3>

<p><a href="https://materialize.com/">Materialize</a> is an engine for building live, incrementally updated materialized views from streaming sources like Apache Kafka. A view can reference other live-updated views, as well as fixed tables.</p>

<p>The primary interface for creating these views is plain and elegant: A <a href="https://materialize.com/docs/sql/create-materialized-view/"><code>CREATE MATERIALIZED VIEW</code></a> SQL statement.</p>

<p>Conceptually, this is roughly the same statement that is available in 
<a href="https://docs.oracle.com/en/database/oracle/oracle-database/21/sqlrf/CREATE-MATERIALIZED-VIEW.html">tradition…</a></p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view">https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://nchammas.com/writing/data-pipeline-materialized-view</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26217911</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 22:26:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[An Introduction to Crystal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 68 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26217013">thread link</a>) | @thejokersthief
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://blog.oisinaylward.me/blog/crystal/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.oisinaylward.me/blog/crystal/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>February 21, 2021</p><p><span>
      <a href="https://blog.oisinaylward.me/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/3684f/crystal.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Crystal logo" title="Crystal logo" src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/8a901d72da53e5eb6edcf11dce08acb6818f1731/a9b08/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/3684f/crystal.png" srcset="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/9076bceecd20a42a2fcc6f79b977cd7842af0266/e2060/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/12f09/crystal.png 148w,https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/8a901d72da53e5eb6edcf11dce08acb6818f1731/a9b08/static/4b7744fa7f6437cd019695014a425c0f/3684f/crystal.png 225w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p><p>One of my favourite programming languages in the last few years has been <a href="https://crystal-lang.org/">Crystal</a>. While the language has not yet reached its 1.0 version, it has been widely used in production and has a growing ecosystem. Crystal provides an easy setup and allows you to jump straight into developing your own Crystal programs. I’m going to walk you through getting it setup and how you can get started!</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">puts "Hello World"</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>Crystal is a general purpose, Ruby-inspired compiled programming language, making it extremely fast and easy to program with. The syntax is strongly inspired by Ruby, but also provides static typechecking. Crystal sits somewhere in the top 100 programming languages according to <a href="https://www.tiobe.com/tiobe-index/">TIOBE</a>, not widely used but don’t let that put you off!</p><p>I was originally interested in Crystal due to its expressive syntax and the claims on its speed. I am likely in the minority in that I came into Crystal with no prior Ruby experience. Crystal soon became my go-to language for personal programming projects. My project <a href="https://github.com/azula-lang/azula">Azula</a> (WIP programming language) was built entirely in Crystal - a choice a made due to Crystal’s nice macro system and built-in LLVM bindings. Crystal was an excellent choice, allowing rapid development and producing a small binary (1.9mb in Crystal vs 3mb in Go).</p><h3>Shards</h3><p>The Crystal ecosystem is powered by its Shard system. Shards is Crystal’s dependency manager that is usually installed along with Crystal. It aims to allow reproducible installs across platforms by declaring dependencies and their versions. You can read more about Shards <a href="https://crystal-lang.org/reference/the_shards_command/index.html">here</a>.</p><h2>Installing Crystal</h2><p>On Ubuntu, installing Crystal is as easy as running:</p><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ curl -fsSL https://crystal-lang.org/install.sh | sudo bash</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>For other platforms, have a look at the <a href="https://crystal-lang.org/install/">Crystal install guide</a>!</p><h2>First Crystal Program</h2><p>Crystal provides a nice scaffolding tool to setup a new project, including a README template, license and gitignore.</p><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ crystal init app myproject</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>If we open up <code>myproject/src/myproject.cr</code>, we can start writing our Crystal program!</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">def say(message : String)
    puts message
end

say "Hello!"</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>In this example, we create a function called <code>say</code> that accepts a string and passes it to <code>puts</code>. As you can see, almost identical to Ruby except for the typing of the parameter in the function.</p><h2>Project Structure</h2><h3>src</h3><p>Inside the <code>src/</code> directory is where all the Crystal files will go. It can contain subdirectories, allowing you to divide up your code. You can include separate files by using the <code>require</code> keyword.</p><h3>spec</h3><p>The <code>spec/</code> directory is the home for your tests. Using the <code>crystal spec</code> subcommand, we can run all our tests.</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">it "works" do
    i = 5 + 10
    i.should eq 15
end</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><h3>shard.yml</h3><p><code>shard.yml</code> is used to define our project. In here, we define the name, version, authors, Crystal version, licence &amp; dependencies.</p><deckgo-highlight-code yaml="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">name: myproject
version: 0.1.0

authors:
  - OisinA

targets:
  myproject:
    main: src/myproject.cr

crystal: 0.36.1

license: MIT</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><h2>Building &amp; Running</h2><h3>Running</h3><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ crystal run src/myproject.cr
Hello!</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>Running your Crystal project is as simple as running <code>crystal run [file]</code>.</p><h3>Building</h3><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ crystal build src/myproject.cr
$ ./myproject
Hello!</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>To build your project, you use <code>crystal build [file]</code> producing an executable. You can optionally use the <code>--release</code> optimising the executable. This flag will significantly increase the build time but the produced binary should be smaller and faster.</p><p>Crystal’s build times are reasonable. Compiling my project <a href="https://github.com/azula-lang/azula">Azula</a> takes ~16s with the release flag. Compiling our barebones project above takes ~8s.</p><h2>Example</h2><h3>Simple Web Server</h3><p>In this example, I am using <a href="https://github.com/kemalcr/kemal">Kemal</a>, a HTTP framework for Crystal, to set up a really simple web server to return some JSON on a request. Kemal makes it really easy to quickly write a web application and has built-in JSON support, static file serving and templating. Kemal is installed using Crystal Shards, adding it to the <code>shards.yml</code>.</p><deckgo-highlight-code crystal="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">require "kemal"
require "json"

get "/" do |env|
    env.response.content_type = "application/json"
    {name: "Oisin", time: Time.local}.to_json
end

Kemal.run</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>Running this will start up a HTTP server on port 3000, returning JSON containing name and the current time.</p><deckgo-highlight-code bash="" terminal="carbon" highlight-lines="">
          <code slot="code">$ curl http://localhost:3000
{"name":"Oisin","time":"2021-02-21T18:07:46+00:00"}</code>
        </deckgo-highlight-code><p>It’s as simple as that!</p><h2>The Future of Crystal</h2><p>With Crystal being in a nice place at the moment - what are the next steps? The next step for Crystal is to reach a 1.0 release. This version of Crystal will be completely stable and fully ready for production. The Crystal team are currently working towards this goal currently. While there is no timeline in place, its an exciting prospect! I am excited for the future of Crystal and hope to see it more widely used.</p><h2>Resources</h2><p>If you’ve enjoyed this blog post, you might be interested in reading more about Crystal and its ecosystem. I’ll list some links here and feel free to reach out to me on <a href="https://twitter.com/oisinaylward">Twitter</a> if you have any questions!</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/veelenga/awesome-crystal">Awesome Crystal List</a> A big list of Crystal code and resources</li><li><a href="https://crystal-lang.org/reference/index.html">Crystal Reference</a> The Crystal Team’s own language reference</li><li><a href="https://crystal-lang.org/api/">Crystal API Docs</a> Crystal’s API docs for working with the standard library</li></ul><h3>Footnotes:</h3><ul><li><a href="https://twitter.com/osslate">@osslate</a>
For proof-reading and giving nice criticism &lt;3</li><li><a href="https://crystal-lang.org/2020/03/03/towards-crystal-1.0.html">Towards 1.0</a>
Information about Crystal’s upcoming 1.0 release</li></ul><hr><ul><li></li><li></li></ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.oisinaylward.me/blog/crystal/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26217013</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 20:47:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to design a motherboard for your electronics project]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26215270">thread link</a>) | @frenchie4111
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content_area">
    <div>
        
            
        

        
             <h2>-1. Overview</h2>
<p> After the prototyping phase of any electronics project, I like to make a "Motherboard" PCB. For this phase I will continue to use breakout boards for all of the individual components, but link them together using a PCB. This allows the PCB design to stay simple and flexible, and makes them easy to hand manufacture them in my workshop. This is a great setup if you want to do a small (10ish) beta run of your project before designing a full product. I have shipped many hardware products using this stage, it's a great way to validate your MVP before putting money into tooling and CM bring up. </p> <p> This tutorial will walk through the process that I follow to create a motherboard. The intended audience is someone who has already wired up a prototype on a breadboard, and wants to get started bundling them together into a motherboard. This will be the guide I wish existed when I got started doing this. </p>
 <p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/4018eef6e0333515d064a35fe2336c2858a216c3/83757/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/thermostat-motherboard.jpeg"></p><p>Here is an example of the motherboard I designed for my <a href="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/caffstat_beta">Thermostat</a> project </p>
<p> This is just the process I figured out for myself, it's by no means perfect. If you have any feedback or questions about any of this stuff, want a PCB design for your project, or just want to chat, feel free to reach out to me: mdl0394@gmail.com </p>
<p> This is Part 1 of the guide. In this guide we will go through initial setup, component model sourcing and schematic design. In Part 2 we will go through board layout and ordering PCBs. If you want to be notified when Part 2 comes out, sign up for email notifications, or subscribe to the RSS feed. </p> 
            <div>
    <p>

    Thanks for reading! If you want to stay updated feel free to follow the <a href="https://staycaffeinated.com/feed.xml">RSS feed</a>, if you have any suggestions feel free to email me at <a href="mailto:mdl0394@gmail.com">mdl0394@gmail.com</a></p><p>
    

    You could also submit your email here, and I will personally email you whenever I post new things:

    </p>
</div>

        

        <h2>Table of Contents</h2>
        <ul><li><a href="#0-before-you-build-a-pcb">0. Before you build a PCB</a><ul><li><a href="#01-installing-eagle">0.1 Installing Eagle</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#1-anatomy-of-a-pcb-design">1. Anatomy of a PCB Design</a></li><li><a href="#2-finding-or-creating-component-models">2. Finding or Creating Component Models</a><ul><li><a href="#21-octopart">2.1. Octopart</a></li><li><a href="#22-desparate-googling">2.2. Desparate Googling</a></li><li><a href="#23-installing-a-library">2.3. Installing a library</a></li><li><a href="#24-creating-your-own-library">2.4. Creating your own Library</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#3-creating-your-schematic">3. Creating your Schematic</a><ul><li><a href="#31-basic-project-setup">3.1. Basic Project Setup</a></li><li><a href="#32-place-your-components">3.2. Place your components</a></li><li><a href="#33-placing-the-ground-label">3.3. Placing the Ground Label</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#34-wiring-using-labels">3.4. Wiring using Labels</a><ul><li><a href="#35-reviewing-your-schematic">3.5. Reviewing your Schematic</a></li></ul></li><li><a href="#40-part-2-board-layout---coming-soon">4.0 Part 2 (Board Layout) - Coming Soon</a></li></ul>


        <h2 id="0-before-you-build-a-pcb">0. Before you build a PCB</h2>

<p>Before you build a PCB you should already have all of the breakout boards &amp; devkits you want to use for the project. When designing the motherboard you should already have a good understanding of how the electronics components are wired together, if you donâ€™t itâ€™s easy to make costly mistakes.</p>

<p>For this project I will be using my Caffstat (Hackable Smart Home Thermostat) project. If you are interested in a smart home thermostat feel free to check out that <a href="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/caffstat_beta">project here</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7eacc185287abd48aa4bca8d5f02bff250b987d9/def8e/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/untitled.png" alt="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7eacc185287abd48aa4bca8d5f02bff250b987d9/def8e/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/untitled.png">
<img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%201.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%201.png">
<img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%202.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%202.png"></p>

<p>These 3 images represent the stages of any electronics project: Breadboard -&gt; Project Board -&gt; PCB</p>

<p>This project contains 3 different breakout boards and a few through hole components. The brains of the operation are an ESP32 Devkit, there are breakouts for the Thermostat and Screen, and through hold components for the buttons, resistors, and relays.</p>

<h3 id="01-installing-eagle">0.1 Installing Eagle</h3>

<p>For this tutorial I will we be using Eagle. Itâ€™s got a free tier tool that, and it integrates well into the Autodesk suite. Eagle is free for up to two layer boards, which should be all you need for most electronics projects. The information here will be pretty generally applicable to any tool, although the screenshots will be of eagle specifically.</p>

<p>You can download eagle for free <a href="https://www.autodesk.com/products/eagle/overview">here</a></p>

<h2 id="1-anatomy-of-a-pcb-design">1. Anatomy of a PCB Design</h2>

<p>A PCB Design contains two main parts, the schematic and the layout. The schematic is an abstract diagram of the connections between components in your project, and the layout is the actual physical layout of those components, and the electrical traces that connect them. The great thing about PCB design software, is that the schematic will be enforced when you are creating the layout, this makes it very straight forward to create the layout after youâ€™ve created the schematic.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%203.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%203.png"></p>

<p>This is the completed schematic for the caffstat project. You can see all of the breakout boards as individual components (red). The connections between them are mostly being managed by net labels to simplify the schematic (more on this later).</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%204.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%204.png"></p>

<p>Here is an image of the completed layout. Every component has found a space on the board, and all of the electrical traces have been drawn. Donâ€™t worry if it looks complicated/messy now, when we go step by step it will be very easy to create.</p>

<h2 id="2-finding-or-creating-component-models">2. Finding or Creating Component Models</h2>

<p>Before you can begin drawing a schematic and layout, you need to find or create models for each and every one of your components. A device model contains both a <strong>symbol</strong> for part (goes in the schematic) and a <strong>footprint</strong> of the part (for the layout). I will list out some great resources for finding or creating these here. I can create a full tutorial for creating your own component models if you are interested, let me know at mdl0394@gmail.com</p>

<p>One thing to note is that Eagle comes pre-packaged with a bunch of common components. These are mostly things like standard resistors/capacitors. Itâ€™s worth checking the pre-installed library before spending too much time scouring the internet. The easiest way to check the library is to use the â€œAdd Partâ€� button discussed in section 3.2 of this tutorial.</p>

<h3 id="21-octopart">2.1. Octopart</h3>

<p>The best tool I have found for looking up components and downloading models is <a href="https://octopart.com/">Octopart</a>. Their mission is to provide the best search engine for electronics components. Almost every part can be found in the search engine, I always check here first.</p>

<p>If octopart has the CAD Model for your part, it will appear like this, you want to download the Eagle format, this will download the library that you can install later.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%205.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%205.png"></p>

<h3 id="22-desparate-googling">2.2. Desparate Googling</h3>

<p>I have also found quite a few schematics by just googling the part. It can often be helpful to try different variations on the name, and include the term â€œEagleâ€� or â€œ.lbrâ€� (Eagle library file extension) in your query. If you do find a schematic, make sure you do some measurements (you can do this on the layout of your design) to ensure it matches well with your part (sometimes people upload bad designs, or are modeling something slightly different than yours, you donâ€™t want to order a PCB with bad footprints)</p>

<h3 id="23-installing-a-library">2.3. Installing a library</h3>

<p>Once you have a library itâ€™s easy to install, drag the Library (.lbr) file into the <code>libraries</code> section of the Eagle Control Panel. <strong>Important:</strong> after dragging the lbr file, make sure you right click and hit â€œUseâ€� otherwise you wonâ€™t actually be able to add it to your project. Libraries in use will have a green dot next to them</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%206.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%206.png"></p>

<h3 id="24-creating-your-own-library">2.4. Creating your own Library</h3>

<p>If you fail to find any schematics online (often the case with cheap breakout boards, or with chinese knockoffs) you might have to make your own. Itâ€™s not too hard to make your own models, mostly just a little bit tedious. Creating your own models &amp; libraries is a full tutorial in itself, if I get interest I can put that together, for now I will refer you to the resources I used to learn the process.</p>

<p>A good tutorial on how to make custom eagle components can be found here: <a href="https://www.build-electronic-circuits.com/eagle-components/">https://www.build-electronic-circuits.com/eagle-components/</a></p>

<h2 id="3-creating-your-schematic">3. Creating your Schematic</h2>

<p>Once you have your components, you can start creating your schematic.</p>

<h3 id="31-basic-project-setup">3.1. Basic Project Setup</h3>

<p>First thing is to make a new Project and new Schematic in eagle. Go into the projects section, right click and hit â€œNew Projectâ€�. Then right click and hit â€œNew Schematicâ€�. Once the schematic opens, you also want to create a layout (Weâ€™ll use this in Step 4). Do this by hitting the â€œGenerate/Switch to Boardâ€� button on the top bar.</p>

<p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/6647e677a7889893fc65d08499400076efd2adee/d3801/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/screen_shot_2021-01-18_at_9.26.13_am.png" alt="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/6647e677a7889893fc65d08499400076efd2adee/d3801/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/screen_shot_2021-01-18_at_9.26.13_am.png"></p>

<h3 id="32-place-your-components">3.2. Place your components</h3>

<p>Once you have a schematic you need to put all of your part symbols on. The add part button is on the left bar, clicking this will bring up a dialogue that lets you choose a component. If you donâ€™t see a component you installed here, go back to the control panel and make sure you selected â€œUseâ€� on the right click menu.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%207.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%207.png"></p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%208.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%208.png"></p>

<p>Add all of your components to your schematic. Make sure you give yourself a bunch of room around components to create connections. You should also try to sort the parts in logical groupings, the simpler your schematic, the less likely-hood of bugs.</p>

<p>While placing components there are a few useful tools at your disposal. The Move, Rotate and Copy tools at the top of the left panel are all useful for organizing your schematic. When you want to select an object, the easiest thing to do is to click the + symbol (probably either at the center, or the origin of the part).</p>

<p>Here is what my schematic looks like after I have placed all of my parts.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%209.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%209.png"></p>

<h3 id="33-placing-the-ground-label">3.3. Placing the Ground Label</h3>

<p>The standard for schematics is to use a specialty component to label the shared ground. You can find this by searching â€œgndâ€� in the Add Part menu.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2010.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2010.png"></p>

<p>I will usually place one of these per component, just off the bottom of the component, and wire them to the ground pin.</p>

<h2 id="34-wiring-using-labels">3.4. Wiring using Labels</h2>

<p>You can directly connect parts together using the â€œNetâ€� tool (Green line) however with more than a few parts, this will very quickly become unmanageable. Instead of doing that, I will show you how to use labels to cleanly connect parts together. Note that for some components I will not use labels for connections, this makes sense for analog circuits, or things like pull down resistors because they can be logically grouped together.</p>

<p>For every node that I want to connect, I will first draw a one or two unit Net. Like so:</p>

<p><img src="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2011.png" alt="/images/how-to-pcb-part-1/Untitled%2011.png"></p>

<p>Then using the â€œNameâ€� tool I will name all of the new nets something that makes them easier to keep track of. To name a net, select the tool, then select the green line for the net, a text dialogue should …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1">https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.staycaffeinated.com/2021/02/21/how-to-design-a-motherboard-for-your-project-part-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26215270</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 17:23:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Please do not put IP addresses into DNS MX records]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 221 | Comments 174 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26215112">thread link</a>) | @hannob
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://blog.hboeck.de/archives/904-Please-do-not-put-IP-addresses-into-DNS-MX-records.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.hboeck.de/archives/904-Please-do-not-put-IP-addresses-into-DNS-MX-records.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            
            <div>
                <!-- s9ymdb:498 --><p><img width="225" height="300" src="https://blog.hboeck.de/uploads/postbox.jpg" alt="Postbox">I want to highlight a common misconfiguration in the DNS records for e-mail servers.<img src="https://ssl-vg03.met.vgwort.de/na/a108fe84457f4d03abf3877bee3dad9f" width="1" height="1" alt=""></p><p>

When a domain is configured to receive mails usually a DNS record of the type MX is configured pointing to the host name of the mail server.</p><p>

Notably, according to the respective <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1035">RFC 1035</a> the MX record must contain a domain name and may not directly point to an IP address. However some mail servers do configure an IP address. Many mail servers are lenient when it comes to this misconfiguration and will deliver mails nevertheless, so this may stay undetected.</p><p>

I happen to use a mail server that is less forgiving (Courier), and every now and then I cannot send a mail due to this. It’s rare, but it does happen. If your mail server has such a configuration you may not receive some legitimate e-mails.</p><p>

So I’m hoping to raise some awareness and get some of those servers fixed.</p><ul><li>Obviously if you run a mail and DNS server please don’t do this and correctly set your MX records.</li><li>If you do any kind of IT service or consulting that is related to mail and DNS servers this is a good thing to add to your list of things to check regularly (here's a <a href="https://github.com/hannob/ipmx">very simple python script you can use</a>).</li><li>If you run any form of service or tool that checks DNS and mail servers for misconfigurations, please add a check for IP addresses in MX records and warn your users. Unfortunately only few services do this currently (thanks to <a href="https://www.hardenize.com/">Hardenize</a> and <a href="https://intodns.com/">IntoDNS</a> who will warn users about this), and some popular services don’t.</li></ul><p>

I did a quick scan of the Alexa Top 1 Million list. Currently <a href="https://github.com/hannob/ipmx/blob/main/scans/ipmx-2021-02-20.txt">around 0,06 % are affected</a> (if you happen to know someone responsible for a host on this list please consider pointing them to this blogpost). I hope by writing this I can reduce that number, I may later try to contact them via their postmaster alias.</p><p>

(<a href="https://nohat.cc/f/post-box-mailbox-letterbox-mail-box-postage/4671034800209920-201811091927.html">Image source: nohat.cc / CC0</a>)
            </p></div>

            
            
            
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.hboeck.de/archives/904-Please-do-not-put-IP-addresses-into-DNS-MX-records.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26215112</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 17:07:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Alice 4 FPGA Rasterizer (Open Hardware Video Card Related)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26214600">thread link</a>) | @peter_d_sherman
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            

            <h2>Overview</h2>

            <p>The Alice 4 rasterizer is broken into two main parts:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>A <a href="https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/libgl.html">software library</a> linked with the C application program. The library
                    implements the IrisGL API. It performs transformations, lighting, clipping,
                    and retained mode (display lists). Its output is a list of commands
                    (clear screen, draw triangle, swap buffers, etc.) that it writes to
                    memory outside Linux's range.</li>
                <li>An FPGA configuration that reads these commands from SDRAM and
                    executes them. For triangles it interpolates color (RGB) and depth
                    (Z). The FPGA also scans out the image buffer to the
                    LCD and performs other minor tasks.</li>
            </ul>

            <h2>Buffers</h2>

            <p>There are three image buffers in shared memory:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>A front color buffer, which is displayed to the user via the LCD.
                The scanning is continuous because the LCD has no memory of its own.
                The timing and wire format is similar to VGA.</li>
                <li>A back color buffer, which is being rasterized into.</li>
                <li>A depth buffer, used along with the back buffer during rasterization.</li>
            </ul>

            <p>The first two buffers are only virtually “front” and “back”. Those two
            labels switch every frame as the back buffer becomes the new front
            buffer and is shown to the user.</p>

            <h2>Modules</h2>

            <p>The Verilog code is broken into about a dozen modules:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>Main: Integrates all the other modules.
                    <ul>
                        <li>soc_instance: Module generated by Qsys to interface with
                            SDRAM and I<sup>2</sup>C.</li>
                        <li>LCD_control: Generates LCD control signals (H-Sync, V-Sync,
                            pixel enable, next frame signal, X coordinate, Y coordinate).
                            This runs at 25&nbsp;MHz (about 50&nbsp;FPS). It could run faster (up to 40&nbsp;MHz)
                            but the board clock is 50&nbsp;MHz, so it was convenient to
                            divide that by two and avoid having asynchronous clocks.</li>
                        <li>LCD_text: Given screen pixel X and Y, returns character X and Y
                            (text column and row) and sub-character X and Y.</li>
                        <li>LCD_debug: Given character X and Y and three 32-bit debug values,
                            returns which character to draw.
                            <ul>
                                <li>Binary_to_hex: Converts a nybble to a hex
                                    ASCII value. Used for each nybble of the
                                    debug values to generate hex output.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>Frame_buffer: Sends the front frame buffer to the LCD.</li>
                        <li>LCD_font: Given ASCII character and sub-character X and Y,
                            returns whether the pixel is on or off.
                            <ul>
                                <li>Font_ROM: The font pixels.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>Command_reader: Pre-fetches drawing commands from
                            SDRAM into a FIFO.</li>
                        <li>Rasterizer: Reads drawing commands and executes them.
                            <ul>
                                <li>Read_FIFO: Queues rasterized pixels,
                                    waiting for Z read to complete.</li>
                                <li>Write_FIFO: Queues rasterized and Z-compared
                                    pixels, waiting for pixel writes to complete.
                                    See the “Write FIFO” section below for more details.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>Prescaler: Generates a tick every N clocks.</li>
                        <li>PWM: Generates a PWM signal for LCD backlight brightness.</li>
                        <li>Debouncer: Debounces the Home button.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <h2>Memory controller</h2>

            <p>The Altera Cyclone V SoC has a wonderful memory controller for accessing
            the synchronous dynamic RAM (SDRAM). It has a port for the ARM and six ports
            for the FPGA. Each FPGA port can be configured for input or output, and their
            relative priorities (including the ARM port) can be set. The priorities were
            critical for making sure the front-buffer scan-out was never starved of
            pixels. The SDRAM itself ran so fast (400&nbsp;MHz DDR) that all the ports could
            be active and not stall too often. The ports were set up as follows:</p>

            <ul>
                <li>Reading the front-buffer for LCD scan-out. This was configured
                to be the highest priority.</li>
                <li>Reading the graphics command buffer.</li>
                <li>Reading the depth buffer for the pixel being rasterized.</li>
                <li>Writing the color of the pixel just rasterized.</li>
                <li>Writing the depth of the pixel just rasterized.</li>
            </ul>

            <p>All five ports were hooked up to FIFOs to minimize the effects of
            memory latency.</p>

            <h2>Rasterization</h2>

            <p>Rasterization uses the edge-equation technique. The idea is to test every
            pixel to see whether it's inside the triangle. “Inside” is defined as “on the
            same side of every edge”. Only pixels in the bounding box of the triangle are
            tested. This technique wastes at least 50% of its time on pixels outside the
            triangle, but it's simpler to implement than edge-walkers.</p>

            <p>The state machine in <tt>Rasterizer.v</tt> reads commands from SDRAM
            (indirectly through the FIFO) and executes them. Because the SDRAM interface
            is (logically) 64 bits wide, and each pixel takes 32 bits (8 bits each of
            red, green, and blue, with 8 bits wasted), we always rasterize two pixels
            at a time. At 50&nbsp;MHz, that's 100 million pixels per second, but with (at least)
            half of them wasted, that's at most 50 million drawn pixels per second.</p>

            <p>To minimize SDRAM latency stalls, we use three FIFOs in the rasterization
            process:</p>
            
            <ul>
                <li>The Command FIFO queues the drawing commands so that the
                    state machine need not block too long.</li>
                <li>The Read FIFO queues drawn pixels while we wait for the
                    depth read to return. After determining that a pixel is
                    inside the triangle, we initiate a read of its
                    corresponding depth value (if depth-comparison is enabled
                    for this triangle). This can take some time (tens of clocks) and we don't
                    want to block the rasterizer. Instead, we queue up all the
                    information we have about this pixel (depth memory address,
                    depth value, color memory address, and color) and move on to the
                    next pixel.
                    Another module (<tt>Read_FIFO.v</tt>) waits for the SDRAM read
                    to return. Since SDRAM reads return in the order they were
                    made, the module then gets the next item in our FIFO,
                    compares the depth values, and if the new pixel is closer to
                    the camera than the existing pixel, enqueues the same pixel
                    information into the Write FIFO. (All of this is done two
                    pixels at a time.)</li>
                <li>The Write FIFO queues pixels that must be written back to SDRAM.
                    The pixel's color must be written, and optionally the depth value
                    must be written (if enabled for this triangle). This is a complicated
                    module because we must take into account whether there are pixels
                    in the FIFO to write, whether the depth memory controller is ready
                    to accept another write, and whether the color memory controller is
                    ready to accept another write. See the section “Write FIFO” below
                    for details.</li>
            </ul>

            <p>There's very little stalling in this pipeline, so we end up with a
            rasterization rate of about 50 million Gouraud (color-interpolated)
            Z-buffered pixels per second. The triangle overhead lets us do
            almost 2 million (empty) triangles per second. It's hard to compare
            these numbers to
            <a href="http://www.sgidepot.co.uk/gfxtables.html">real SGI machines</a>, 
            but we seem to be matching the performance of machines built in the
            early 1990s.</p>

            <h2>Reciprocal</h2>

            <p>For each triangle, the rasterizer computes its on-screen area, then takes
            the reciprocal of the area. This is necessary for the normalization of
            the barycentric coordinates used to interpolate color and depth.
            <a href="https://www.scratchapixel.com/lessons/3d-basic-rendering/rasterization-practical-implementation/rasterization-stage">Scratchapixel</a> has a great explanation
            of how this works; scroll down to the “Barycentric Coordinates” section.</p>

            <p>To compute the reciprocal we use the built-in
            <a href="https://www.altera.com/en_US/pdfs/literature/ug/ug_lpm_alt_mfug.pdf"><tt>lpm_divide</tt></a> module:</p>

            <pre>lpm_divide
    #(.LPM_WIDTHN(32),
      .LPM_WIDTHD(32),
      .LPM_NREPRESENTATION("UNSIGNED"),
      .LPM_DREPRESENTATION("SIGNED"),
      .LPM_PIPELINE(6)) area_divider(
        .clock(clock),
        .clken(area_reciprocal_enabled),
        .numer(32'h7FFF_FFFF),
        .denom(tri_area),
        .quotient(tri_area_recip_result)
    );
            </pre>

            <p>The module is configured to have six pipeline stages, which means that
            the result will come out six clocks after the denominator was put in.
            We don't pipeline (overlap) our reciprocals (we only need one per triangle), but our
            state machine must wait six clocks for this result. We found the
            number 6 by trying various values until the compiler stopped complaining
            about timing violations.</p>

            <h2>Write FIFO</h2>

            <p>The Write FIFO, which writes pixel data to the back color buffer and
            to the depth buffer, was one of the most difficult modules to write in
            this project. Conceptually the state machine should perform these
            steps in a loop:</p>

            <ol>
                <li>Wait for a new pixel to be available in the Write FIFO.</li>
                <li>Write it to the back color buffer and to the depth buffer.</li>
                <li>Wait for both SDRAM controller ports to acknowledge that they had
                    accepted the writes.</li>
            </ol>

            <p>Remember that wherever we talk about “a pixel” here, we mean two
  …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html">https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://lkesteloot.github.io/alice/alice4/fpga-rasterizer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26214600</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 16:19:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Efficient blockchain architecture based on FIDO keys]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26214175">thread link</a>) | @dandanua
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://dandanua.github.io/posts/super-efficient-blockchain-architecture-based-on-fido-keys/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dandanua.github.io/posts/super-efficient-blockchain-architecture-based-on-fido-keys/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction</h2><p>Reaching decentralized consensus is hard. Really, there must be a reason why Bitcoin network is such an energy-inefficient monster with its Proof-of-Work algorithm. Of course, many other consensus algorithms exist that are not that power-hungry, for example, Proof-of-Stake variations. But they require some sort of centralization, usually hidden under details and complexity. And they still have limits, a boundary on the total number of transactions per second that a network can process.</p><p>I don’t believe it’s possible to find an efficient consensus algorithm, which would be truly decentralized. But why restrict ourselves to just software solutions? Here I want to explain that a super-efficient hardware solution exists. And it’s already within the reach of our current technologies.</p><h2 id="2-the-main-problem">2. The Main Problem</h2><p>What is the root cause of why it’s so hard to achieve a decentralized consensus?</p><p>Well, in the case of cryptocurrencies it’s called <em>double spending</em>. If Clara has 100 coins at some point in time then she can’t spend 200 coins – the network will just ignore such transaction as incorrect. But transferring 100 coins to Alice or 100 coins to Bob are both correct transactions. Yet they are conflicting. If Clara simultaneously commits both these transactions then the network has to decide what to choose as the right one and what to discard.</p><p>Making a decision based on time is not a deterministic way, because some participants can receive one of the conflicting transactions earlier in time, while the others will see a different order.</p><p>Somehow the whole network, i.e. every participant of it, has to decide what to pick as the correct transaction in a way, that will be in agreement with the decisions of every other participant.</p><p>This decision can’t be based on some mathematical function of a transaction (if Clara has enough freedom of composing it). For example, we can’t have a rule where we pick the transaction of 100 coins to Alice as correct because <em>A &lt; B</em>. Because if Clara commits another conflicting transaction of 100 coins to Aaron later in time, then the whole network would have to change its decisions.</p><p>Note that the same problem exists in a broader context, not related to currencies. For example, you can have a blockchain network where users can play chess games. At any moment in time a player has a set of allowable moves. But a player is allowed to choose only one move. If he commits two moves simultaneously, then, again, the network has to decide what to pick as the right one.</p><p>There are many consensus algorithms invented, but they are just ways to centralize a network, where these conflict resolution decisions are made by some selected (or elected) set of participants. In fact, Bitcoin PoW consensus algorithm is a form of election of a participant (miner), whose decision will be set as correct for the whole network.</p><hr><p>So, how can we use hardware to solve this problem?</p><p>Imagine hypothetical hardware that additionally signs Clara’s transactions (via some cryptographic microchips). Moreover, this hardware keeps a counter of Clara’s transactions and <em>attaches</em> this number to a signed transaction. So, the network will see a transaction with its number that has two signatures – the one by Clara’s private key and another one by hardware private key.</p><p>Conflict resolution is trivial in this case. The network will accept a transaction that has a lower counter (it has to be +1 of the previous transaction number).</p><p>The main assumption that we need for network security is that Clara can’t tamper hardware or simulate it in some way. Of course, making tamper-proof hardware is also a hard task, but the technology is almost there. There are a lot of tamper-resistant USB keys that are already on the market.</p><p>Actually, FIDO keys are already satisfying our blockchain needs!</p><h2 id="3-fido-keys">3. FIDO keys</h2><p>FIDO (Fast IDentity Online) is an alliance of the world’s major IT companies. They developed U2F (Universal 2nd Factor) – an open standard of two-factor authentification that uses USB or NFC keys. Luckily, this standard is indeed universal. Even though it was developed as an addition to password authentification in centralized services, we can use it in a blockchain network instead!</p><p>A nice overview of U2F protocol you can see <a href="https://developers.yubico.com/U2F/Protocol_details/Overview.html">here</a>.</p><p>In particular, look at this diagram</p><p><img src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://developers.yubico.com/U2F/Protocol_details/auth_flow4.svg" alt="Mobile View"><em>https://developers.yubico.com/U2F/Protocol_details/Overview.html</em></p><p>It is supposed that a Relying Party (server) starts second-factor authentification by sending a <em>challenge</em> to a client. But blockchain network has no servers. Instead of a challenge, Clara uses the hash of her transaction, where <em>app_id</em> is just a name of the blockchain network and <em>handle</em> is Clara’s personal public key. Then the U2F device will update the counter and return the signed transaction with the attached counter. This is exactly what we need! Clara then sends this information along with the actual transaction and her own signature to the network.</p><p>To ensure that Clara can’t simulate the device, U2F protocol additionally includes the attestation certificate of the device manufacturer, as explained <a href="https://fidoalliance.org/fido-technotes-the-truth-about-attestation/">here</a>.</p><h2 id="4-typical-usage-scenario">4. Typical usage scenario</h2><p>First of all, a user has to register in the network. To do this, he needs to have FIDO hardware key and to generate his personal private/public keys. The registration is essentially linking personal keys with device keys. For this, an empty challenge can be used in the device signing flow.</p><p>Making transactions was described in the previous section.</p><p>If the device is lost/broken/stolen then the user can register another device with its personal key. Though, in this case, the network should wait for some time, for example, 24 hours, to be sure that the previous device (in a couple with the personal key) is not used anymore.</p><h2 id="5-threats">5. Threats</h2><p>Since every transaction must have two signatures – by device and user, the device alone can’t be used to harm its user.</p><p>But an incorrect or tampered device can be used to submit conflicting transactions to the network (for example, with the same counter). This will split the network if no other consensus algorithm is involved.</p><p>But we can assume that manufacturer has no incentives to make incorrect devices to harm the network.</p><p>So, the only threat is device tampering. Even though modern FIDO keys are tamper-resistant, their security is probably not enough to be used in blockchain networks, because there were no reasons to make them fully tamper-proof in usage with centralized servers. But nearly tamper-proof technology is certainly possible.</p><h2 id="6-super-efficiency">6. (Super) Efficiency</h2><p>As for this blockchain efficiency, it’s certainly unreachable for ordinary blockchains. Because in this architecture, no additional communication to resolve possible conflicts is needed <strong><em>AT ALL</em></strong>. Every possible conflict is resolved immediately in an independent and coherent fashion.</p><h2 id="7-final-words">7. Final Words</h2><p>This is, of course, only a high-level overview of blockchain architecture. A lot of details are skipped. But I hope it can be seen that this architecture is a real solution to a lot of blockchain problems.</p><hr><p><em><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26214175">Discussion</a> on HackerNews.</em></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dandanua.github.io/posts/super-efficient-blockchain-architecture-based-on-fido-keys/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26214175</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 15:36:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Build an SMS Forwarder with Raspberry Pi Zero W and Waveshare SIM7000E Hat]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 118 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26213956">thread link</a>) | @mtrcn
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://mete.dev/2021/02/21/build-an-sms-forwarder-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w-and-waveshare-sim7000e-hat/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mete.dev/2021/02/21/build-an-sms-forwarder-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w-and-waveshare-sim7000e-hat/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
						
<p>In this guide, I will explain how to receive SMS messages and forward them to your Telegram account using Raspberry PI Zero W and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.waveshare.com/SIM7000E-NB-IoT-HAT.htm" target="_blank">Wireshare GSM hat</a>. </p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard.png" alt="" width="473" height="380" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard.png 945w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard-300x241.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/2021-02-21-14_09_49-Clipboard-768x618.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 473px) 100vw, 473px"></figure></div>



<p>Python will be used to read SMS messages and forward them to <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://core.telegram.org/bots/api" target="_blank">Telegram Bot API</a>. Messages will be listened to by <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://wammu.eu/smsd/" target="_blank">Gammu</a> SMS service and it will trigger the Python script when an SMS message received.  </p>



<h2>Setup</h2>



<p>First of all, we have to enable communication between GSM hat and Raspberry PI Zero, run Raspberry Pi Software Configuration Tool (raspi-config);</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo raspi-config</code></pre>



<p>Then, follow following actions;</p>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png" alt="" width="743" height="458" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1.png 990w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1-300x185.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-1-768x474.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 743px) 100vw, 743px"><figcaption>Go to Interface Options</figcaption></figure></div>



<figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2.png" alt="" width="745" height="457" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2.png 993w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2-300x184.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-2-768x471.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 745px) 100vw, 745px"><figcaption>Select and enter P6 Serial Port</figcaption></figure>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3.png" alt="" width="740" height="458" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3.png 987w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3-300x185.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-3-768x475.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"><figcaption>Select No at this screen.</figcaption></figure></div>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4.png" alt="" width="740" height="459" srcset="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4.png 986w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4-300x186.png 300w, https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image-4-768x477.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"><figcaption>Lastly, select Yes at this screen.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Exit configuration tool. Now we need to enable UART on raspberry pi. Shutdown and eject SD card to open in another computer. Open /boot/config.txt file, find the below statement and uncomment it to enable the UART. You can directly append it at the end of the file as well.</p>



<pre><code>enable_uart=1</code></pre>



<p>Now, reboot raspberry pi device and open the console to install Gammu SMS Deamon and Python PiP package installer. </p>



<pre><code>$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install python-pip gammu-smsd</code></pre>



<p>Install Telegram Bot API python library.</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo pip install python-telegram-bot==12.3.0</code></pre>



<p><em>Note: Version 12.3.0 is the latest version that is compatible with Python 2.7, if you want to use it with Python 3+ version, you can install the latest available version.</em></p>



<p>Now you need to create a bot in Telegram and obtain a token. Afterwards, start a chat with that bot in your Telegram account and send a test message to your bot. This will help us to identify your chat ID. </p>



<p>Open following URL with you Telegram Bot token and copy the chat ID in the response; </p>



<pre><code>https://api.telegram.org/bot[YOUR-BOT-TOKEN]/getUpdates</code></pre>



<div><figure><img loading="lazy" width="269" height="29" src="https://mete.dev/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/image.png" alt=""><figcaption>This is your chat ID.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Save following script in /home/pi/forward-telegram.py;</p>



<pre><code>#!/usr/bin/env python
from __future__ import print_function
import os
import sys
import telegram

numparts = int(os.environ['DECODED_PARTS'])

text = ''
# Are there any decoded parts?
if numparts == 0:
    text = os.environ['SMS_1_TEXT']
# Get all text parts
else:
    for i in range(1, numparts + 1):
        varname = 'DECODED_%d_TEXT' % i
        if varname in os.environ:
            text = text + os.environ[varname]

# Log
print('Number %s have sent text: %s' % (os.environ['SMS_1_NUMBER'], text))

#Send by Telegram
bot = telegram.Bot(token='[YOUR-BOT-TOKEN]')
bot.send_message(chat_id=[YOUR CHAT ID], text=os.environ['SMS_1_NUMBER'].strip() + " | "+ text)
</code></pre>



<p>Make python file executable</p>



<pre><code>$ chmod +x /home/pi/forward-telegram.py</code></pre>



<p>Update Gammu SMS Deamon’s configuration to use GSM hat. Waveshare uses /dev/ttyS0 for communication. </p>



<pre><code>$ sudo nano /etc/gammu-smsdrc</code></pre>



<p>Find following lines in the configuration file and update with correct values, for me these values are following;</p>



<pre><code>port = /dev/ttyS0
connection = at115200</code></pre>



<p>Also, we need to specify the script path to be ran by Gammu so add following line below [smsd] section;</p>



<pre><code>RunOnReceive = /home/pi/forward-telegram.py</code></pre>



<p>You can find my complete configuration file <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://gist.github.com/mtrcn/045d7eeef1e38c092939d5ee87f96fb0" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>



<p>Restart Gammu SMS service.</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo systemctl restart gammu-smsd.service</code></pre>



<p>That’s all! You should now able to get your SMS messages to your Telegram account. </p>



<p>You can monitor Gammu SMS service for any problem with the following command;</p>



<pre><code>$ sudo systemctl status gammu-smsd.service</code></pre>




						
											</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mete.dev/2021/02/21/build-an-sms-forwarder-with-raspberry-pi-zero-w-and-waveshare-sim7000e-hat/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26213956</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 15:07:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When Bitcoin miners take over a town (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 469 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26213693">thread link</a>) | @edward
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
									<p><span>EAST WENATCHEE,&nbsp;Washington — Hands on the&nbsp;</span>wheel, eyes squinting against the winter sun, Lauren Miehe eases his Land Rover down the main drag and tells me how he used to spot promising sites to build a bitcoin mine, back in 2013, when he was a freshly arrived techie from Seattle and had just discovered this sleepy rural community.</p>
<p>The attraction then, as now, was the Columbia River, which we can glimpse a few blocks to our left. Bitcoin mining — the complex process in which computers solve a complicated math puzzle to win a stack of virtual currency — uses an inordinate amount of electricity, and thanks to five hydroelectric dams that straddle this stretch of the river, about three hours east of Seattle, miners could buy that power more cheaply here than anywhere else in the nation. Long before locals had even heard the words “cryptocurrency” or “blockchain,” Miehe and his peers realized that this semi-arid agricultural region known as the Mid-Columbia Basin was the best place to mine bitcoin in America — and maybe the world.</p>
<p>The trick, though, was finding a location where you could put all that cheap power to work. You needed an existing building, because in those days, when bitcoin was trading for just a few dollars, no one could afford to build something new. You needed space for a few hundred high-speed computer servers, and also for the heavy-duty cooling system to keep them from melting down as they churned out the trillions of calculations necessary to mine bitcoin. Above all, you needed a location that could handle a lot of electricity — a quarter of a megawatt, maybe, or even a half a megawatt, enough to light up a couple hundred homes.</p>
<p>The best mining sites were the old fruit warehouses — the basin is as famous for its apples as for its megawatts — but those got snapped up early. So Miehe, a tall, gregarious 38-year-old who would go on to set up a string of mines here, learned to look for less obvious solutions. He would roam the side streets and back roads, scanning for defunct businesses that might have once used a lot of power. An old machine shop, say. A closed-down convenience store. Or this: Miehe slows the Land Rover and points to a shuttered carwash sitting forlornly next to a Taco Bell. It has the space, he says. And with the water pumps and heaters, “there’s probably a ton of power distributed not very far from here,” Miehe tells me. “That could be a bitcoin mine.”</p>
<blockquote><p>Over the past two years, the region has taken on the vibe of a boomtown.</p></blockquote>
<p>These days, Miehe says, a serious miner wouldn’t even look at a site like that. As bitcoin’s soaring price has drawn in <a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2018/03/09/how-bitcoin-works-illustration-infographic-217333" target="_blank">thousands of new players worldwide</a>, the strange math at the heart of this cryptocurrency has grown steadily more complicated. Generating a single bitcoin takes a lot more servers than it used to — and a lot more power. Today, a half-megawatt mine, Miehe says, “is nothing.” The commercial miners now pouring into the valley are building sites with tens of thousands of servers and electrical loads of as much as 30 megawatts, or enough to power a neighborhood of 13,000 homes. And in the arms race that cryptocurrency mining has become, even these operations will soon be considered small-scale. Miehe knows of substantially larger mining projects in the basin backed by out-of-state investors from Wall Street, Europe and Asia whose prospecting strategy, as he puts it, amounts to “running around with a checkbook just trying to get in there and establish scale.”</p>
<p>For years, few residents really grasped how appealing their region was to miners, who mainly did their esoteric calculations quietly tucked away in warehouses and basements. But those days are gone. Over the past two years, and especially during 2017, when the price of a single bitcoin&nbsp;<a href="https://99bitcoins.com/price-chart-history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jumped</a>&nbsp;from $1,000 to more than $19,000, the region has taken on the vibe of a boomtown. Across the three rural counties of the Mid-Columbia Basin — Chelan, Douglas and Grant — orchards and farm fields now share the rolling landscape with mines of every size, from industrial-scale facilities to repurposed warehouses to cargo containers and even backyard sheds. Outsiders are so eager to turn the basin’s power into cryptocurrency that this winter, several would-be miners from Asia flew their private jet into the local airport, took a rental car to one of the local dams, and, according to a utility official, politely informed staff at the dam visitors center, “We want to see the dam master because we want to buy some electricity.”</p>
<p>The Mid-Columbia Basin isn’t the only location where the virtual realm of cryptocurrency is colliding with the real world of megawatts and real estate. In places like China, Venezuela and Iceland, cheap land and even cheaper electricity have resulted in bustling mining hubs. But the basin, by dint of its early start, has emerged as one of the biggest boomtowns. By the end of 2018, according to some estimates, miners here could account for anywhere from 15 to 30 percent of all bitcoin mining in the world, and impressive shares of other cryptocurrencies, such as Ethereum and Ripple. And as with any boomtown, that success has created tensions. There have been disputes between miners and locals, bankruptcies and bribery attempts, lawsuits, even a kind of intensifying guerrilla warfare between local utility crews and a shadowy army of bootleg miners who set up their servers in basements and garages and max out the local electrical grids.</p>
<div id="attachment_846110"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-846110" loading="lazy" src="https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-714x476.jpg" alt="" width="714" height="476" srcset="https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-714x476.jpg 714w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-1160x773.jpg 1160w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-380x253.jpg 380w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-171x114.jpg 171w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-90x60.jpg 90w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-104x69.jpg 104w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-200x133.jpg 200w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-390x260.jpg 390w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-54x36.jpg 54w, https://www.politico.eu/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/h_54129347-1080x720.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px"></p><p id="caption-attachment-846110">The Datacenter Mjoelnir in Iceland, a cryptocurrency mine run by Genesis-Mining | Hanna Andresdottir/EPA</p></div>
<p>More broadly, the region is watching uneasily as one of its biggest natural resources — a gigantic surplus of hydroelectric power — is inhaled by a sector that barely existed five years ago and which is routinely derided as the next dot-com bust, or this century’s version of the Dutch tulip craze, or, as&nbsp;New York Times&nbsp;columnist Paul Krugman&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/paulkrugman/status/955107120671797248?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener">put it in January</a>, a Ponzi scheme. Indeed, even as Miehe was demonstrating his prospecting chops, bitcoin’s price was already in a swoon that would touch $5,900 and rekindle widespread doubts about the future of virtual currencies.</p>
<p>For local cryptocurrency enthusiasts, these slings and arrows are all very much worth enduring. They believe not only that cryptocurrency will make them personally very wealthy, but also that this formerly out-of-the-way region has a real shot at becoming a center — and maybe&nbsp;<i>the&nbsp;</i>center — of a coming technology revolution, with the well-paid jobs and tech-fueled prosperity that usually flow only to gilded “knowledge” hubs like Seattle and San Francisco. Malachi Salcido, a Wenatchee building contractor who jumped into bitcoin in 2014 and is now one of the basin’s biggest players, puts it in sweeping terms. The basin, he tells me, is “building a platform that the entire world is going to use.”</p>
<p>And squarely between these two competing narratives are the communities of the Mid-Columbia Basin, which find themselves anxiously trying to answer a question that for most of the rest of us is merely an amusing abstraction: Is bitcoin for real?</p>
<p>***</p>
<p><b>A few miles from the shuttered carwash</b>, David Carlson stands at the edge of a sprawling construction site and watches workers set the roof on a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CfrjhflKGzQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Giga Pod</a>, a self-contained crypto mine that Carlson designed to be assembled in a matter of weeks. When finished, the prefabricated wood-frame structure, roughly 12 by 48 feet, will be equipped with hundreds of high-speed servers that collectively draw a little over a megawatt of power and, in theory, will be capable of producing around 80 bitcoins a month. Carlson himself won’t be the miner; his company, Giga-Watt, will run the pod as a hosting site for other miners. By summer, Giga-Watt expects to have 24 pods here churning out bitcoins and other cryptocurrencies, most of which use the same computing-intensive, cryptographically secured protocol called the blockchain. “We’re right where the rubber hits the road with blockchain,” Carlson shouts as we step inside the project’s first completed pod and stand between the tall rack of toaster-size servers and a bank of roaring cooling fans. The main use of blockchain technology now is to keep a growing electronic ledger of every single bitcoin transaction ever made. But many miners see it as the record-keeping mechanism of the future. “We’re where the blockchain goes from that virtual concept to something that’s real in the world,” says Carlson, “something that somebody had to build and is actually running.”</p>
<p>Granted, all that real-worlding and road-hitting is a little hard to visualize just now. The winter storms that have turned the Cascade Mountains a dazzling white have also turned the construction site into a reddish quagmire that drags at workers and equipment. There have also been permitting snafus, delayed utility hookups, and a lawsuit, recently settled, by impatient investors. But Carlson seems unperturbed. “They are actually making it work,” he told me earlier, referring to the mud-caked workers. “In a normal project, they might just say, ‘Let’s just wait till spring,’” Carlson adds. “But in bitcoin and blockchain, there is no stopping.” Indeed, demand for hosting services in the basin is so high that a desperate miner offered Carlson a Lamborghini if Carlson would bump him to the head of the pod waiting list. “I didn’t take the offer,” Carlson assures me. “And I like Lamborghinis!”</p>
<blockquote><p>Across the expanding bitcoin universe, lots of miners are turning their basements and spare bedrooms into jury-rigged data centers.</p></blockquote>
<p>Carlson has become the face of the Mid-Columbia Basin crypto boom. Articulate, infectiously optimistic, with graying hair and a trim beard, the Microsoft software developer-turned-serial entrepreneur has built a series of mines, made (and lost) several bitcoin fortunes and endured countless setbacks to become one of the region’s largest players. Other local miners credit Carlson for launching the basin’s boom, back in 2012, when he showed …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/">https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/this-is-what-happens-when-bitcoin-miners-take-over-your-town/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26213693</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 14:35:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Viking Invasion of Leicestershire (2012)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 70 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26212092">thread link</a>) | @zeristor
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-8898898974994971235" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p><span>We know exactly when the Viking Age
began in England – it was more than 1,200 years ago – on June 8, 793. That was
the day when invading Norsemen destroyed the Abbey church on the island of
Lindisfarne, off the north-east coast of England. Lindisfarne was a centre of
learning famous across the continent – but that meant nothing to these fierce
invaders.</span></p>
<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-n4m_7H0fvSE/UKSycIixbvI/AAAAAAAAAfo/DAUUpjbSAwM/s1600/Viking+Leicester.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="212" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-n4m_7H0fvSE/UKSycIixbvI/AAAAAAAAAfo/DAUUpjbSAwM/s320/Viking+Leicester.jpg" width="320"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>The Vikings arrived in England in 793 AD</td></tr>
</tbody></table>
<p><span>Monks were either killed in the abbey,
thrown into the sea to drown or carried away as slaves – along with the church’s
treasures. The devastation of Northumbria’s Holy Island shocked Europe. “Never
before has such an atrocity been seen”, declared the Northumbrian scholar,
Alcuin of York. The Vikings had announced themselves in a devastating way. This
was just a warning of what was to come.</span></p>

<p><span>Over the next 300 years, more and more
invaders would flood into England, and Leicestershire would be full of Vikings.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Divided country</span></b></p>
<p><span>At the
time, England was not one united country – it was divided up into Anglo-Saxon
kingdoms.</span><b> </b><span>Leicester was
included within Mercia, and was known as Legreceastre. It was the principal
city in that kingdom. Even a thousand years ago and more, Legreceastre was a
bit of a melting pot.</span><b> </b><span>It
was a meeting point of several different cultures – the Angles from the Wash
and the Humber, Saxons from Warwickshire, Mercians from the Trent, and Celts
from the hills of Charnwood. In Leicester, they met, traded and eventually
settled.</span><b> </b><span>What increasingly
united these peoples was Christianity.</span><b>
</b><span>Mercia was Christian – the “new” religion reached Leicester in the
year 658. A church was said to have stood from the 7th century on the current
St Margaret’s site.</span><b> </b><span>Leicestershire,
as we know it, was in the heart of the Mercian kingdom and is thought to have
been the capital for political and ecclesiastical affairs. It was far enough
away from the frontiers to avoid changing hands as the unstable boundaries of
the mini-kingdom advanced and receded.</span><b>
</b><span>But what the Anglo-Saxons had worked so hard to build in
Leicestershire, was about to come to an end. The Scandinavian enemy was at the
gates and Mercia would never be the same again.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Ruthlessly pillaged</span></b></p>
<p><span>In 10 short years, between 865 and 874,
the whole structure of life in Mercia collapsed. A huge Scandinavian army
marched and pillaged up and down England. The Anglo-Saxon Chronicle has
preserved a glimpse of these years of chaos in its records of “a great heathen
army” that pillaged East Anglia in the year 865. Between 865 and 868 the
Northmen widened their field for plunder and tribute to East Mercia. Leicester
was attacked in 868, partly destroying the ancient Roman city walls.</span></p>

<p><span>Thousands of Danes swarmed down the
River Soar in their small, easily-managed boats, penetrating the very heart of
the country, carrying fire and sword among the simple and terrified population,
whom they ruthlessly pillaged and massacred. In the winter of 874 to 5, after
defeating Burhed, King of Mercia in battle, the raiders established their
quarters at Repton on the River Trent. Monasteries, the repositories of rich
and beautiful objects in gold, silver and jewellery, formed particular targets
for the pagan invaders. The monastery that had been founded at Breedon in
Leicestershire was reputedly sacked. But these Danes didn’t just hit and run,
like the early invaders on Lindisfarne.</span></p>

<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-RAtAWAWsTdU/UKSybtWvK9I/AAAAAAAAAfc/l0Lz_w86CgM/s1600/Viking+Boat.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="243" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-RAtAWAWsTdU/UKSybtWvK9I/AAAAAAAAAfc/l0Lz_w86CgM/s320/Viking+Boat.jpg" width="320"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>The Vikings swarmed down the River Soar</td></tr>
</tbody></table>
<p><span>In its records of the year 877, the
Anglo-Saxon Chronicle suggests a permanent settlement of the land. The Danish
army it says “went into the land of the Mercians, and shared out some of it,
and gave some to Ceolwulf”. Ceolwulf was the puppet king whom the Danes placed
on the Mercian throne. It seems Mercia was now divided in half.</span></p>

<p><span>Large parts of its eastern territories
had passed into the hands of the Scandinavian invaders and were open to
settlement. Within the next decade, in 886, the losses of Anglo-Saxon territory
in Mercia were clearly defined by a treaty that King Alfred the Great concluded
with Guthrum, the leader of the Danes, after his Wessex Saxons had recaptured
London.</span></p>

<p><span>A permanent “country of Danes” was now
established within England, known as the Danelaw. This Danish part of England
comprised the greater part of eastern England from East Anglia to North
Yorkshire, incorporating most of Leicestershire. You could say that Leicester
was part of Denmark.</span></p>

<p><span>Leicestershire was close to the Danelaw
boundary though, and it is believed that some of the wealthier inhabitants
migrated with as many possessions as they could carry. As the churches were
destroyed and Christian rites trampled, the Bishop of Leicester retired to
safety at Dorchester-on-Thames. It would be more than a thousand years before
there would again be a Diocese of Leicester. Leicester, with Derby, Nottingham,
Lincoln and Stamford, became one of the “Five Boroughs” of the Danelaw. Leicester,
as a former Anglo-Saxon royal city, continued its importance under Danish rule.
Danish forms of taxation and local government took root in Leicester.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Danish Leicester</span></b></p>
<p><span>Although the Danelaw’s existence was
relatively short-lived, it left an everlasting mark on the history of
Leicestershire. The Scandinavians left an indelible impression on the language
of the East Midlands. </span><span>&nbsp;</span><span>Vocabulary,
grammatical structures and the very tones of local dialect were deeply affected
by the contact with Scandinavia. Despite this, there aren’t many archeological
finds to be seen; visible remains of the Norsemen are hard to come by. Leicestershire’s
archaeological record lacks burials, pottery and everyday implements.</span></p>

<p><span>Finds that we do have are generally
personal ornaments such as brooches, horse accessories, coinage and weaponry. There
are also some distinctly Irish objects found in Leicestershire that were
probably plundered by Vikings during raids, and transported back to the Danelaw
lands. Such finds include a “shrine mount” from Breedon and belt buckles from
Melton.</span></p>

<p><span>Our understanding of Danish settlement
and the geography of the Danelaw depends largely on the evidence of
Scandinavian place-names. The place-name ending of by, which means a farm or
more usually a settlement, is seen throughout Denmark. That same ending is
common in England too. In Leicestershire alone, 56 villages end in by (such as Oadby)
and of these, half the number contain a Danish personal name as their other
element. But towards Leicester, on the broad gravel spreads where the River
Wreake empties into the Soar, the character of place-names changes. The sounds
of the Scandinavian invaders gives way to names of an older Mercian origin with
names ending in -ton. Thrussington, Syston and Cossington all speak of an
earlier period in Leicestershire’s settlement history. Even though the ton
element suggests the presence of a settlement that survived the impact of the
Danish army, the first element in these names is frequently a Scandinavian
personal name. Many Leicestershire villages were named after powerful Danes.
Ingarsby is named after the Danish Prince Ingar and it is now believed that
Humberstone may be named after Ingar’s brother, Hubba. </span><span>&nbsp;</span><span>Both Princes entered Leicester during the
Danish invasion and could have settled in the villages named after themselves.</span></p>

<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ij1MO4XWLvQ/UKS0APCvwSI/AAAAAAAAAgE/HVsFvpOADvw/s1600/Viking+Princes.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="320" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ij1MO4XWLvQ/UKS0APCvwSI/AAAAAAAAAgE/HVsFvpOADvw/s320/Viking+Princes.jpg" width="295"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Some think the Viking princes are on the tower of Humberstone church</td></tr>
</tbody></table>
<p><span>But as well as being named after actual
people, many villages were named after the gods. Thurmaston, Thurcaston,
Thurlaston and Thurnby all owe their name to one of the principal pagan gods of
the Scandinavian culture – Thor, who together with Odin, were the most commonly
worshipped gods. An archaeological find from Leicestershire of a miniature
“Thor’s Hammer”, the god’s famous magical weapon, is on display in the Jewry
Wall Museum.</span></p>

<table><tbody>
<tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1ehV6iV7B9k/UKSyduMs2kI/AAAAAAAAAfs/-kxLGS5K0VU/s1600/thor+hammer.jpg" imageanchor="1"><img height="210" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1ehV6iV7B9k/UKSyduMs2kI/AAAAAAAAAfs/-kxLGS5K0VU/s320/thor+hammer.jpg" width="320"></a></td></tr>
<tr><td>Miniature Thor's Hammer&nbsp; found in Leicestershire</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<p><b><span>Names are clues</span></b></p>
<p><span>With invading forces, you may assume
that they would settle on the broad and fertile river terraces of the Soar. But
settlements already existed here and new areas of land were needed to house the
large band of men who came to dwell in Leicestershire. By the study of
place-names, it appears that they turned towards the emptier and perhaps less
rewarding river terraces that flank the narrow valley of the Wreake. Along that
river we find Frisby, Hoby, Rotherby, Brooksby and Rearsby. The word “Wreake”
is also derived from Scandinavia, being the Old Norse word for “twisted”. So,
Wreake is both a description and the new name for the river once known as the
River Eye. Historian Sir Frank Stenton said the Wreake settlement was occupied
by a large body of the Danish army who took permanent occupation of the land
some time around 877.</span></p>

<p><span>The army would have been stationed here
so it could spring to the defence of Leicester if the town was ever threatened
by invaders from the west. Another Danish encampment is thought to have stood
on the area of Leicester known as Dane Hills. The creation of the Danelaw made
as great an impression on Leicester as in the surrounding countryside. The
colonising Danes, soldiers and farmers, turned the Mercian cathedral city into
a garrison town. The term “gate,” descended from the Old Norse, “gata,” meaning
a street, occurs in a handful of streets in the heart of Leicester. All in the
same part of town we find Gallowtree Gate, Humberstone Gate, Church Gate,
Belgrave Gate and Sanvey Gate. They lie outside the line of the former Roman
and medieval wall, beyond the bounds of the Anglo-Saxon town. As we all know,
the first four streets converge at the Clock Tower where High Street passed
through the former East Gate out of the walled enclosure of the medieval town. Thus,
the presence of the “gata” element in modern street names of Leicester suggests
that the Danes, when they made Leicester one of their strongholds, established
a new town outside the wall of the Mercian city. By the early years of the 10th
century, Leicester may have been like a town of two halves, sharply divided
into Anglo-Saxon and Danish quarters.</span></p>

<p><b><span>Fresh …</span></b></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html">http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.thiswasleicestershire.co.uk/2012/11/the-viking-invasion-of-leicestershire.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26212092</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 09:25:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How my school gamed the stats]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 142 | Comments 157 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26211921">thread link</a>) | @optimalsolver
<br/>
February 21, 2021 | https://www.greaterwrong.com/posts/Yv9aj9bWD5H7aaDdy/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.greaterwrong.com/posts/Yv9aj9bWD5H7aaDdy/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>I was reading the Slate Star Codex <a href="https://astralcodexten.substack.com/p/book-review-the-cult-of-smart">review</a> of The Cult of Smart. Part of it discusses charter vs state schools and the allegations of fraud of various kinds undermining charter schools record of better achievement. Reading it, I realized that I took for granted that public schools engage in systematic fraud in a variety of ways. I donâ€™t think this is something everyone understands, hence this post.</p>
<p>I went to a state school in the UK. State schools are rated on a 1 âˆ’ 4 scale from unsatisfactory to outstanding. My school was rated good, meaning a 3. A few memories which stand out. During my first week I saw one of the boys in my class who was 11 at the time held up against the wall in a corridor while a 16 year old put a shiv to his throat and robbed him. He handed over his wallet and keys. A year or two later and I remember seeing a small boy who struggled with depression held up by the throat against a locker and slapped in the face by a troublemaker from the same class in front of everyone just before we went in to the classroom. I remember classes which were filled start to finish with people shouting and talking. Neither of the first two events were common but they also werenâ€™t uncommon. No one was surprised to witness them. Itâ€™s worth emphasizing again that my school was above average, in fact quite far above average, and in a middle class area. Itâ€™s also worth noting that I was mostly in top ability streamed classes, meaning my classroom experience was likely far better than average.</p>
<p>There were many ways in which the school and teachers gamed the system to boost their measured performance. One way was to do exams for students. I was on a bottom set language class for French. After two years I literally couldnâ€™t speak a single sentence in french and maybe knew 20 words in total. I still passed my exams. How? We did the tests in class. Often the teacher would go through them with us. Literally giving us the test and then going through each question on the whiteboard and telling us what to write. A different year and a different teacher, this time the teacher would sit next to us and write the answers down. Why sit next to us? It was the bottom set so people often wouldnâ€™t even bother to write down the answer if they were told it. This kind of thing was normal, so much so that I, and I think most people there, didnâ€™t realize anything unusual was happening.</p>
<p>Another way schools game metrics is to cheat inspections. A major component of how schools are judged in the UK is through independent inspections carried out by an independent quasi-governmental organization called Ofsted. Now, you may imagine that these inspections would be unannounced, so as to best get a real image of how a school works. Not the case. Theyâ€™re scheduled well in advance. Before every inspection, a few things would happen in my school:</p>
<ul><li><p>The worst troublemaker kids would be taken aside and put in a special room where inspectors wouldnâ€™t see them. Either that or they would just be told not to come into school at all on that day.</p></li><li><p>All of us were told in assembly that an inspection was coming and to be on our best behavior on that day. Often teachers would have conversations with less serious troublemakers and impress on them that they would behave on that day or face consequences afterwards.</p></li><li><p>Teachers would put a great deal more effort into their lesson plans than was normal. Classroom behavior management would also be far stricter.
Because of these and other measures my school during an inspection was utterly different than my school on a normal day. On some level this isnâ€™t surprising. If teachersâ€™ promotions and managementâ€™s jobs depend on good inspection results and inspections are easy to game, people will game them. Incentives drive behavior. But itâ€™s still sad.</p></li></ul>
<p>Another way the stats were gamed was by not recording bad behavior. When a school gives a detention or suspends/â€‹expels a student, thereâ€™s a record of it. This is especially true of suspensions, students being sent home or expulsions. The more of these you have, the worse you look as a school. The solution then is obvious, donâ€™t punish people or punish them in non-recorded ways. Again, in my school it was completely normal for students in lower sets to swear at the teacher, talk over them or disrupt the class for everyone else. It was normal for someone to be aggressive and abusive towards others and to face at most a 40 minute detention, but even getting a detention would be unusual.</p>
<p>I realize that one data point is not enough to draw solid general conclusions. My own perception is that this kind of fraud wasnâ€™t specific to my school. My cousin went to a state school fairly nearby. Heâ€™s 4 years younger than me. During one of my winters back from undergrad we discussed his school and his experiences mirrored mine. His exact words regarding inspections were â€œI learned 4 times more that day than any other day that year. It was amazingâ€�. I talked to a few British students at university, although specifically the not middle/â€‹upper class ones who would have gone to public schools. They had gone to schools similar to mine in different parts of the country and their stories were similar and often worse. Two particularly funny examples from my friendsâ€™ experiences stand out. A teacher in year 9 walked up to a student who was talking, picked them up and threw them out of an (open) first floor window. My friend sitting in class noticed two boys making fun of him and then proceeded to get up in the middle of class while the teacher was talking, walk to their table, flip the table upwards to hit them in the face before going to sit down again when the teacher told him to. (Remember, my friend was a studious, sporty Asian kid and not a troublemaker. This kind of thing is normal in that environment). Comedic stories aside, my experiences in school, while not universal, seem fairly common in the UK and from what Iâ€™ve read of the statistics, bad US schools are far, far worse.</p>
<p>Iâ€™m unsure what my point here is. I think I have two:</p>
<ul><li><p>Charters may cook their books in various ways. In the UK, State schools do too. I would be surprised if it wasnâ€™t also the case in the US.</p></li><li><p>I think that I feel like a lot of commentators on places like SSC have fairly middle class experiences of fairly good schools and that bleeds into how their comparison between state vs charter schools. Itâ€™s just good to remember that itâ€™s not those nice middle class schools that charters typically replace.</p></li></ul>
<p>Crossposted to my blog at <a href="https://dissent.blog/2021/02/20/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats/">https://â€‹â€‹dissent.blog/â€‹â€‹2021/â€‹â€‹02/â€‹â€‹20/â€‹â€‹how-my-school-gamed-the-stats/â€‹â€‹</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.greaterwrong.com/posts/Yv9aj9bWD5H7aaDdy/how-my-school-gamed-the-stats</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26211921</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 08:44:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Modern software controls dependencies because it helps software authors]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 111 | Comments 107 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26210576">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 20, 2021 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/BundlingHelpsSoftwareAuthors | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/BundlingHelpsSoftwareAuthors">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Modern software controls dependencies because it helps software authors</h2>

	<p><small>February 20, 2021</small></p>
</div><div><p>Over on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/thatcks/status/1363196953065099265">I had a hot take</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Hot take: Every distribution packager who's saying "you shouldn't
bundle dependencies" is implicitly telling software authors "you
should do more work for us and limit the features (and reliability) of
your software".</p>
</blockquote>

<p>(This was sparked by reading <a href="https://blogs.gentoo.org/mgorny/2021/02/19/the-modern-packagers-security-nightmare/">The modern packagerâ€™s security
nightmare</a>,
<a href="https://lobste.rs/s/zb1c4k/modern_packager_s_security_nightmare">via</a>.
I'm not exactly on one side or the other, but <a href="https://twitter.com/thatcks/status/1363263921960980485">I do think distributions
should be honest about what they're asking for</a> and I
don't think they're going to get it.)</p>

<p>This hot take is a bit too narrow. What really matters is software
authors and modern software systems restricting the versions of
dependencies (for both maximum and minimum versions). Explicit or
implicit bundling on top of that just makes the problem slightly worse
for distributions.</p>

<p>For software authors, restricting the versions of dependencies that
they work with reduces the amount of work that they have to do,
both to test against a range of versions and to either forever chase
after whatever changes those dependencies like to make or to forever
limit what features of dependencies they use to ones available in
old versions (and sometimes both at once). In theory, both testing
and chasing after changes would be dealt with by <a href="http://semver.org/">Semantic Versioning</a> (if everyone followed it), at least for a
single program. In practice, not only are people fallible but also
<a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/SemverHasLimits">people have a different understanding of what semantic versioning
means</a> because semantic versioning is ultimately
a social thing, not a technical one. Our field's history has shown
(sometimes vividly) that if software authors allow versions of
dependencies to move on them, soon or later things break and the
software author has to fix it.</p>

<p>(There's also the practical issue that not all dependencies even
claim or agree to follow semantic versioning in the first place.)</p>

<p>For distributors, once software authors start restricting versions
the distributor has both an upgrade problem and a distribution
problem. On the upgrade side, dealing with an issue in a program may now
require persuading it to accept a new version of a dependency. On the
distribution side, it's now likely that you'll have multiple programs
that have different version requirements for the same dependency. At the
very least this multiplies the packages involved.</p>

<p>(Many distributions also have package system design problems that
restricts the range of versions of things that they can have installed
at the same time. Even under <a href="http://semver.org/">Semantic Versioning</a>, this is a
problem for the distribution the moment that you have two programs
with conflicting version requirements that can't both be packaged and
installed at the same time.)</p>

<p>However, there's no free lunch here. What distributors want when
they ask for unbundled dependencies without version restrictions is
for software authors to do the work to accept any version of their
dependencies, or at least any version that falls within <a href="http://semver.org/">Semantic
Versioning</a>, and for dependencies to faithfully follow semver and
also make it possible to package and install different major versions
(at least) at the same time. <strong>Accepting a broad version range of your
dependencies is actual work</strong>, even apart from the limitations it may
impose on what your code and your software can do. Software authors and
the creators of software package ecosystems (like Go and Rust) are not
refusing to do this because they don't like distributions; they are
refusing to do this because they have found, over and over again, that
this doesn't really work and does cause problems for software authors
(and often users of programs) in the long run.</p>

<p>(The software community that's gone through this experience the
most visibly is Go, which started out with intrinsically unversioned
dependencies that were used universally across all your programs
by default and wound up switching to strongly versioned dependencies
after many people had many problems with that initial state. Go
experienced so many problems that <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/programming/FallibleSemverAndMVS">they adopted an unusually strict
and software author friendly versioning scheme</a>.)</p>

<p>It's popular for people to argue that software authors should be doing
this work anyway even if the distributions weren't asking for it,
so them actually doing it is no big deal. This is quite convenient
for the people making the argument, but it doesn't make the argument
valid. Software authors don't owe anyone any work what so ever; they
do whatever work serves their needs and is interesting to them. With
limited time and interest, it's both rational and proper for software
authors to optimize for their own development.</p>

<p>PS: Generally distributions also want some combination of all software
to update to the latest version of their dependencies and for
dependencies to explicitly support older versions. This is also extra
work for software authors, especially when the distribution also wants
it to happen for older versions of programs.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/BundlingHelpsSoftwareAuthors</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26210576</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 03:36:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Boeing 747 loses parts after take-off from Maastricht – 2 injuries]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26209611">thread link</a>) | @UncleOxidant
<br/>
February 20, 2021 | https://www.aviation24.be/airlines/longtail-aviation/boeing-747-loses-parts-after-take-off-from-maastricht-diverts-to-liege-two-people-injured/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.aviation24.be/airlines/longtail-aviation/boeing-747-loses-parts-after-take-off-from-maastricht-diverts-to-liege-two-people-injured/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" srcset="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident.jpg 1920w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-300x169.jpg 300w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-768x432.jpg 768w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-696x392.jpg 696w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-1068x601.jpg 1068w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-747x420.jpg 747w, https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Longtail_accident-600x338.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px">A Boeing 747-400BCF freighter registered VQ-BWT (MSN 24975) flying for Bermuda-based Longtail Aviation took off from runway 21 at Maastricht Aachen Airport this Saturday afternoon at 16:11 (UTC+1). The aeroplane operating flight LGT5504 to New York JFK experienced heavy damage on an engine shortly after take-off. Engine parts (turbine blades) fell in the nearby village of Meerssen resulting in 2 people slightly injured and damage to cars.</strong></p>
<p>According to a spokesman for the South Limburg Safety Region, an explosion has probably occurred in engine number one of the aircraft. Metal parts such as turbine blades have come down around the Limburg town of Meerssen.</p>
<p>Debris hit an elderly woman, who was slightly injured as a result. A child also burned his fingers on a piece of metal.</p>
<p>In Meerssen several houses and cars got damaged by falling debris.</p>
<p>The thirty-year-old plane immediately diverted on three engines to Liège airport, where it landed safely after making a number of laps over the Ardennes to burn fuel and lose weight.</p>
<p><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1.jpg" alt="blank" width="1001" height="610" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1.jpg 1001w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-300x183.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-768x468.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-696x424.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-689x420.jpg 689w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Capture-1-600x366.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 1001px) 100vw, 1001px"></p>
<p>According to aviation expert Joris Melkert, it is a special incident: “<em>I cannot remember a recent case in the Netherlands where parts of an engine fell down.</em>”</p>
<p>The cause of the incident is unknown. The engine may have sucked up something causing the turbine blades to break. This is what the debris looks like, says the airport spokesman.</p>
<p>The police are calling on people to leave the debris behind, in connection with recording the damage.</p>
<p>The Onderzoeksraad voor Veiligheid (Dutch Safety Board) has started an exploratory investigation.</p>
<p>Spotter Aubrey Verbaere was present at Liège Airport when the Longtail Boeing 747 landed and provided <em>Aviation24.be</em> with the following pictures:</p>
<figure id="attachment_107911" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107911"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-scaled.jpg" alt="blank" width="2048" height="1365" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-scaled.jpg 2048w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-300x200.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1024x683.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-768x512.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-696x464.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1068x712.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-1920x1280.jpg 1920w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-630x420.jpg 630w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862657303-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107911">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107912" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107912"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643.jpg" alt="blank" width="1280" height="1280" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643.jpg 1280w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-300x300.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-150x150.jpg 150w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-768x768.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-696x696.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-1068x1068.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-420x420.jpg 420w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-600x600.jpg 600w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725643-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107912">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107914" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107914"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364.jpg" alt="blank" width="1280" height="1280" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364.jpg 1280w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-300x300.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-150x150.jpg 150w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-768x768.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-696x696.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-1068x1068.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-420x420.jpg 420w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-600x600.jpg 600w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856725364-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107914">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107906" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107906"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231.jpg" alt="blank" width="1280" height="1280" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231.jpg 1280w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-300x300.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-150x150.jpg 150w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-768x768.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-696x696.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-1068x1068.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-420x420.jpg 420w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-600x600.jpg 600w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613856726231-100x100.jpg 100w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107906">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_107909" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-107909"><img onload="Wpfcll.r(this,true);" src="https://wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/plugins/wp-fastest-cache-premium/pro/images/blank.gif" loading="lazy" data-wpfc-original-src="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-scaled.jpg" alt="blank" width="2048" height="1365" data-wpfc-original-srcset="//wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-scaled.jpg 2048w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-300x200.jpg 300w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1024x683.jpg 1024w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-768x512.jpg 768w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-696x464.jpg 696w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1068x712.jpg 1068w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-1920x1280.jpg 1920w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-630x420.jpg 630w, //wwwaviation24be-q41r3jh.stackpathdns.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Photo_1613862659838-600x400.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-107909">© Aubrey Verbaere</figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Longtail Aviation</b> is a charter airline based in St. George’s, Bermuda and was formed in August 1999.</p>
<blockquote data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Longtail Aviation cargo 747 loses engine parts over Meerssen after failure on departure from Maastricht Airport in The Netherlands. Aircraft landed safely in Liege. <a href="https://t.co/b22hB9QgKF">https://t.co/b22hB9QgKF</a> <a href="https://t.co/NYps5GoBzT">pic.twitter.com/NYps5GoBzT</a></p>
<p>— Breaking Aviation News &amp; Videos (@breakingavnews) <a href="https://twitter.com/breakingavnews/status/1363175798438510603?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 20, 2021</a></p></blockquote>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.aviation24.be/airlines/longtail-aviation/boeing-747-loses-parts-after-take-off-from-maastricht-diverts-to-liege-two-people-injured/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26209611</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:35:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
