<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:51:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:51:25 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Visualization of 40M Cell Towers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 431 | Comments 118 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26169747">thread link</a>) | @alprc
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<!-- <hr> -->

<p>
	
	<a href="https://www.opencellid.org/">OpenCelliD</a> is the world's largest 
	open database of cell towers with a license
	<a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">CC BY-SA 4.0</a>
</p>

<p>
	Data has full world coverage and freely available for
	<a href="https://www.opencellid.org/">download.</a>
</p>

<p>
	This tabular data[1] has ~40 million rows and 6 columns in it but only 3
	columns (latitude, longitude, and type) are used in this visualization.
</p>

<p><a href="https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/csv.png" target="_blank">
	<img src="https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/csv.png" alt="">
</a>

<em>[1] Structure of input data.</em></p><p>
	Above table data is read line by line and grouped by their location info.
	Grouping is done as if they were <a href="https://developers.planet.com/planetschool/xyz-tiles-and-slippy-maps/">XYZ Tiles.</a></p>


<p>
	First, empty 2d integer arrays for each tile are created and its elements are 
	initialized with value = 0. 
	Those values hold a counter that shows the number of rows that 
	geographically contained in that pixel.
	Every row increases the relevant counter by one[2]. 
	After iterating all rows with this method, we end up with a bunch of
	integer values (in different 2d arrays) that represent row counts per region.
</p>

<p><a href="https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/step2.png" target="_blank">
	<img src="https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/step2.png" alt="">
</a>
<em>[2] Each row increases relevant counter.</em></p><p>
	In order to achieve city-level resolution for visualization, tiles up to
	zoom level 9 should be generated. 
	<a href="https://www.maptiler.com/google-maps-coordinates-tile-bounds-projection/">
	For XYZ tiles, the number of tiles per zoom level is 4^zoom.</a>
	Therefore, for zoom levels between 0 to 9, the number of tiles that should be generated 
	becomes 4^0 + 4^1 + 4^2 + .. + 4^9 which equals to 349525.
	Every tile has 256x256 integer values.
	Even with using 32 bit-sized integer values, 
	one tile occupies 256 * 256 * 32 bit = 256 kilobytes of storage,
	and <b>349525 tiles</b> occupies <b>87 gigabytes of storage</b> which is 
	definitely not acceptable.
</p>

<p>
	To solve this size problem every tile blob is compressed independently
	with a modern compression algorithm 
	<a href="https://github.com/google/brotli">brotli</a>.
	Despite being slow to encode, brotli has a fast decoding speed and high compression ratio
	compared to older compression methods like gzip. Additionally, 
	brotli-compressed-data is <a href="https://caniuse.com/#search=brotli">
	natively decodable with all modern browsers</a>.
	Since there are no cell towers in oceans or uninhabitable areas, tiles for those regions 
	are full of zero values or very sparse. Due to this high redundancy,
	compression performed extremely well for those regions (256kb compressed to 20~100bytes).
</p>

<p>
    In order to simplify the algorithm, it is described as if there was only one 
    counter value in each pixel, but there are 4 counter values per pixel each
    holding number of row counts for different cell tower types[3]
</p>


<p><a href="https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/step3.png" target="_blank">
	<img src="https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/step3.png" alt="">
</a>
<em>[3] Every pixel stores more than one channels (counter)</em></p><p>
    Even though these tiles are stored like XYZ tiles, they are not 
    valid XYZ tiles.Since these blobs are just brotli-compressed-integer-arrays.
    Visualization requires a blob to image conversion. This conversion is
    done by client side javascript and HTML5 Canvas API.
</p>

<p>
    Underlying map displaying library in this visualization is
    <a href="https://leafletjs.com/" target="_blank">leaflet</a>.
    Kudos to leaflet author(s) for writing such a well documented and extendable
    map library, I was able to write a custom tile layer for leaflet that 
    intercepts the image tile requests made by leaflet and redirects those
    image tile requests to an image generating (client-side) web worker that 
    works like a tile server. Web worker follows a simple algorithm for image generation.

    It reads the row count values pixel by pixel and generates a color for that
    pixel (higher the row count lighter and more opaque the pixel color).
</p>
<p>
    To summarize, this was a fun project for me to work on and I learned a lot 
    about data compression and multi-threading while working on this. 
    By off-loading compute-intensive tasks to web-workers, very impressive visualizations
    can be made even without sacrificing a single FPS drop on UI thread. 
</p>


</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alpercinar.com/open-cell-id/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26169747</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 18:29:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Passwordless Logins with Yubikey]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 87 | Comments 60 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26169369">thread link</a>) | @adl1995
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://adl1995.github.io/passwordless-logins-with-yubikey.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://adl1995.github.io/passwordless-logins-with-yubikey.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Yubikey is currently the de facto device for <span>U2F</span> authentication. It enables adding an extra layer of security on top of <span>SSH</span>, system login, signing <span>GPG</span> keys, and so on. It is also compatible with several other authentication methods, such as WebAuthn and <span>PAM</span>.</p>
<p>This post will show how to leverage your Yubikey for unlocking the system lock-screen, both with and without using a password. It will then delve into how to automatically lock the screen when the Yubikey is&nbsp;unplugged.</p>
<p>To achieve logins with Yubikeys we require a <span>PAM</span> configuration. <span>PAM</span> or Pluggable Authentication Modules define the authentication flow for common Linux utilities, such as <code>sudo</code>, <code>su</code>, and <code>passwd</code>. We will override the default authentication flow for the <a href="https://linux.die.net/man/1/xlock">xlock</a> lock manager to allow logins with&nbsp;Yubikey.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: The above process should be similar across most lock managers, such as <code>i3lock</code> or <code>xscreensaver</code>.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Creating a <span>PAM</span>&nbsp;configuration</h2>
<p>We shall first replicate the default authentication provided with xlock using <span>PAM</span>. With this configuration the user should only be able to log in with their&nbsp;password.</p>
<p>All <span>PAM</span> configuration files lie under the <code>/etc/pam.d/</code> directory. We create a file named <code>xlock</code> which replicates the default&nbsp;authentication:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ cat /etc/pam.d/xlock
<span>#%PAM-1.0</span>
auth            include         system-auth
</code></pre></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: For the above configuration file to take effect the tool (<code>xlock</code>) must be <span>PAM</span> compatible. We can confirm that <code>xlock</code> is <span>PAM</span> compatible by inspecting the output of <code>ldd /usr/bin/xlock | grep libpam.so</code>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The first comment line indicates the <span>PAM</span> version. The lines that follow define the authentication&nbsp;flow:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>auth</code> is the module interface responsible for verifying the user’s&nbsp;password.</li>
<li><code>include</code> is the <span>PAM</span> control flag which <em>includes</em> the <code>system-auth</code> configuration file (this file defines the default authentication flow). This flag can also be used to load modules, as we shall see&nbsp;later.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: There is an excellent <a href="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-us/red_hat_enterprise_linux/6/html/managing_smart_cards/pam_configuration_files">documentation</a> provided by RedHat on <span>PAM</span> configuration&nbsp;files.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Supporting Yubikey&nbsp;logins</h3>
<p>We shall now add Yubikey login functionality to our <span>PAM</span> configuration, but we first need to install the Yubico module for <span>PAM</span> and set it&nbsp;up.</p>
<p>Yubico, the company behind Yubikeys, exposes the <a href="https://developers.yubico.com/yubico-pam/">pam_yubico.so</a> module which can be used for Yubikey&nbsp;authentication.</p>
<p>It provides two authentication mechanisms, the <code>client</code> mode and the <code>challenge-response</code> mode. The <code>client</code> mode sends a request to the Yubico server for verifying the user’s <span>OTP</span>, and requires an active Internet connection for the user to login. As this is inconvenient we shall only explore the <code>challenge-response</code> mode in this&nbsp;post.</p>
<p>Before proceeding with the configuration the <code>pam_yubico</code> package must be installed manually. This package is easily available across most Linux distributions. On Arch Linux it can be installed&nbsp;with:</p>

<p>We next add Yubikey mappings before setting the challenge-response&nbsp;credential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Warning: It is recommended that you use a secondary account to perform the next steps as there is a risk of permanently locking your account (in case of <span>PAM</span>&nbsp;misconfiguration).</p>
</blockquote>
<h4>Adding&nbsp;mappings</h4>
<p>Each Yubikey must be paired with a unique public <span>ID</span> which the <code>pam_yubico</code> module uses to uniquely identify the user. The public <span>ID</span> consists of the first 12 characters extracted from the <span>OTP</span>&nbsp;token.</p>
<p>To obtain your Yubikey’s public <span>ID</span> open up your shell and press the Yubikey button. You will see a similar output as&nbsp;below:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code><span>vvctffbvkhdnliklfhbbfiecudthfvrvuhnhtirehidr</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>Now copy take the first 12 characters (<code>vvctffbvkhdn</code>) and add them to a file named <code>yubikey_mappings</code> in the <code>/etc/</code> directory, along with your username. In our case this will&nbsp;be:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ cat /etc/yubikey_mappings
adeel:vvctffbvkhdn
</code></pre></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: This file also allows specifying multiple Yubikey mappings, each separated by a new&nbsp;line.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4>Setting the challenge response&nbsp;credential</h4>
<p>Yubikey needs to somehow verify the generated <span>OTP</span> (One Time Password) when it tries to authenticate the user. It does so by using the <code>challenge-response</code> mode.</p>
<p>To set up the <code>challenge-response</code> mode, we first need to install the Yubikey manager tool called <code>ykman</code>. On Arch Linux it can be installed&nbsp;with:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ pacman -S yubikey-manger
</code></pre></div>
<p>The <code>ykman</code> tool will generate a secret credential and store it in a local file. Whenever the user tries to login with <code>xlock</code>, the <code>pam_yubico</code> module will verify the generated <span>OTP</span> against the stored&nbsp;credential.</p>
<p>The challenge response credential can be set on slot 2 of the Yubikey&nbsp;with:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ ykman otp chalresp --generate <span>2</span>
Using a randomly generated key: 29eb38b6f50b246c46f954af9710a77c78792114
Program a challenge-response credential in slot <span>2</span>? <span>[</span>y/N<span>]</span>: y
</code></pre></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Warning: Ensure that the slot you’re writing the data to doesn’t already contain any credential, as it might not be&nbsp;recoverable!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>After the <code>challenge-response</code> credential is set it needs to be written to a local file which will be later read by <code>pam_yubico</code>.</p>
<p>Yubico provides another tool called <code>ykpamcfg</code> (which should be bundled with the <code>yubikey-manger</code> package) to write this file to disk. It takes the Yubikey slot number as its parameter and writes the secret to a&nbsp;file:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ ykpamcfg -2
Stored initial challenge and expected response in <span>'/home/adeel/.yubico/challenge-&lt;Serial ID&gt;'</span>.
</code></pre></div>
<h3>Updating the Linux <span>PAM</span>&nbsp;configuration</h3>
<p>We shall now update the <code>/etc/pam.d/xlock</code> file and add the Yubico <span>PAM</span> at the very&nbsp;beginning.</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ cat /etc/pam.d/xlock
<span>#%PAM-1.0</span>

auth  sufficient  pam_yubico.so debug <span>mode</span><span>=</span>challenge-response <span>authfile</span><span>=</span>/etc/yubikey_mappings
auth  include     system-auth
</code></pre></div>
<p>We pass three parameters to the <code>pam_yubico.so</code> module:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>debug</code> prints all the authentication steps to the console when the ‘Enter’ key is&nbsp;pressed.</li>
<li><code>mode</code> specifies which mode the module will use for authentication (<code>challenge-response</code> or <code>client</code>).</li>
<li><code>authfile</code> points to the credential file written by the <code>ykpamcfg</code> tool. </li>
</ul>
<p>Setting the module type to <code>sufficient</code> means that if Yubikey authentication succeeds, no further steps will be processed and the user will get logged in. This is the key point which enables passwordless logins. However, in the event of authentication failure, remaining authentication steps will still be applied, i.e. the user can still log in with their password if the Yubikey is not plugged&nbsp;in.</p>
<p>If the module type is set to <code>required</code> instead of <code>sufficient</code> it will enable Two-Factor Authentication (<span>2FA</span>) which will require the user to plug in their Yubikey <em>and</em> enter their password to&nbsp;login.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: For passwordless logins the user will need to press the <code>Enter</code> with their Yubikey plugged in to unlock their&nbsp;screen.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>At this stage you should be able unlock your screen with they&nbsp;Yubikey.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: You may need to replug your Yubikey for the changes to take&nbsp;effect.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Automatically locking the screen when Yubikey is&nbsp;unplugged</h2>
<p>Up till locking the screen still requires manually invoking the <code>xlock</code> command. It would be nice if we can somehow automatically lock the screen whenever our Yubikey is unplugged. We can achieve this with&nbsp;Udev.</p>
<p>Udev is the device manager used in Linux which can be used for a myriad of tasks. It tracks the state changes for all external devices, for example, it can be used to identify when a <span>USB</span> device is plugged or unplugged. Each device outputs a series of attributes which can be used to uniquely identify&nbsp;it.</p>
<p>We shall use these attributes to create a Udev rule which triggers an <code>xlock.service</code> Systemd service when the Yubikey is&nbsp;unplugged.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: We can also achieve this with a Shell script instead of Systemd, but Udev discourages executing long-running programs using scripts as it terminates them after a certain time&nbsp;period.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Creating the Systemd&nbsp;service</h3>
<p>Systemd is the Linux service manager which can be used to launch user processes. We create a file named <code>xlock.service</code> in the <code>/etc/systemd/system/</code> directory:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ cat /etc/systemd/system/xlock.service
<span>[</span>Unit<span>]</span>
<span>Description</span><span>=</span>xlock

<span>[</span>Service<span>]</span>
<span>User</span><span>=</span>adeel
<span>Type</span><span>=</span>simple
<span>Environment</span><span>=</span><span>DISPLAY</span><span>=</span>:0
<span>ExecStart</span><span>=</span>/usr/bin/xlock 

<span>[</span>Install<span>]</span>
<span>WantedBy</span><span>=</span>multi-user.target
</code></pre></div>
<ul>
<li>The <code>Type=simple</code> implies that this service does not exit after&nbsp;execution.</li>
<li>The <code>Environment</code> tag specifies which display should be locked (<code>0</code> is the default&nbsp;display).</li>
<li>The <code>ExecStart</code> tag takes a path of the binary or script it will&nbsp;execute.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Note: Consult the <a href="https://www.freedesktop.org/software/systemd/man/systemd.service.html">official docs</a> to explore Systemd in&nbsp;detail.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3>Creating the Udev&nbsp;rule</h3>
<p>We first need to identify a set of unique attributes for our device (Yubikey). The <code>udevadm</code> tool allows monitoring Udev output whenever a device state changes. We shall invoke the following command and then remove our&nbsp;Yubikey:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ udevadm monitor --environment --udev 
monitor will print the received events <span>for</span>:
UDEV - the event which udev sends out after rule processing

UDEV  <span>[</span><span>461872</span>.738673<span>]</span> remove   /devices/pci0000:00/0000:00:14.0/usb1/1-2/1-2.1/1-2.1:1.0/0003:1050:0407.0157/input/input294/event18 <span>(</span>input<span>)</span>
<span>ACTION</span><span>=</span>remove
<span>ID_VENDOR</span><span>=</span>Yubico
<span>SUBSYSTEM</span><span>=</span>input
<span>DEVNAME</span><span>=</span>/dev/input/event18
<span>ID_INPUT_KEY</span><span>=</span><span>1</span>
...
</code></pre></div>
<p>We only show a truncated output above, but once you have identified the attributes you would like to use, create a file named <code>yubikey-actions.rules</code> in the <code>/etc/udev/rules.d/</code> directory:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ cat /etc/udev/rules.d/yubikey-actions.rules 
<span>ACTION</span><span>==</span><span>"remove"</span>, ENV<span>{</span>ID_MODEL_ID<span>}==</span><span>"0407"</span>, ENV<span>{</span>ID_VENDOR_ID<span>}==</span><span>"1050"</span>, <span>RUN</span><span>+=</span><span>"/usr/bin/systemctl start xlock.service"</span>
</code></pre></div>
<p>It might be worthwhile to reload the configuration for both Systemd and&nbsp;Udev:</p>
<div><pre><span></span><code>$ systemctl daemon-reload
$ udevadm control --reload
</code></pre></div>
<p>If everything worked out fine your screen should now get locked whenever you remove your&nbsp;Yubikey.</p>
<h2>References:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Using_Yubikeys_with_Fedora#Using_a_Yubikey_to_authenticate_to_a_machine_running_Fedora">Using a Yubikey to authenticate to a machine running&nbsp;Fedora</a></li>
<li><a href="https://ocramius.github.io/blog/yubikey-for-ssh-gpg-git-and-local-login/">YubiKey for <span>SSH</span>, Login, <span>2FA</span>, <span>GPG</span> and Git&nbsp;Signing</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.fraggod.net/2015/01/12/starting-systemd-service-instance-for-device-from-udev.html">Starting systemd service instance for device from&nbsp;udev</a></li>
</ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://adl1995.github.io/passwordless-logins-with-yubikey.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26169369</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 17:59:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[RetroForth 2021.1]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 45 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26168640">thread link</a>) | @mindcrime
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | http://forthworks.com/retro | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://forthworks.com/retro">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>[DIR] <a href="http://forthworks.com/">Forthworks</a>
______________________________________________________________________

RETRO is a clean, elegant, and pragmatic dialect of Forth. It provides
a simple alternative for those willing to make a break from legacy
systems.

The language draws influences from many sources including traditional 
Forth systems, cmForth, colorForth, Factor, and Parable. It was
designed to be easy to grasp and adapt to specific uses.

The basic language is very portable. It runs on a tiny virtual
machine (Nga), which is written in C. There are multiple interface
options, the main one (rre) is buildable with just the standard C
compiler and libraries on most systems.
______________________________________________________________________

Source Code

These include source code, documentation, and examples.

 BIN  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/r/latest.tar.gz">Nightly Snapshot (.tar.gz)</a>

 BIN  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/r/RETRO12-2021.2.tar.gz">Latest Release (2021.2, .tar.gz)</a>
 TXT  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/r/RETRO12-2021.2.tar.gz.sig">Signature for Latest Release</a>
 TXT  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/r/RETRO12-2021.2.tar.gz.pub">Public Key for Latest Release</a>

[DIR] <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/r">Prior Versions</a>
______________________________________________________________________

Documentation

 TXT  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/r/RETRO12-2021.2.epub">RETRO Handbook (epub)</a>

You can view the glossary via Gopher or HTTP. This is served off the
latest documentation in the repository by a server written in RETRO.

[DIR] <a href="http://forthworks.com/">Glossary Browser (gopher)</a>
 HTM  <a href="http://forthworks.com:9999/">Glossary Browser (http)</a>
 TXT  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/s/doc/Glossary.txt">Glossary (text)</a>
______________________________________________________________________

Repository

Development is tracked using a Fossil repository.

Clone the repo:

  fossil clone http://forthworks.com:8000 retro.fossil

And open it:

  mkdir retro
  cd retro
  fossil open /path/to/retro.fossil

Mirrors of the repo are available via git.

 HTM  <a href="https://git.sr.ht/~crc_/retroforth">https://git.sr.ht/~crc_/retroforth</a>
 HTM  <a href="https://github.com/crcx/retroforth">https://github.com/crcx/retroforth</a>

I generate nightly snapshots of the development version.

 BIN  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/r/latest.tar.gz">Nightly Snapshot</a>
 TXT  <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/changes.txt">Latest Changes (updates hourly)</a>
______________________________________________________________________

Packages &amp; Ports

NetBSD pkgsrc: lang/forth-retro
LiteBSD: lang/retro12
FreeBSD: lang/retro12
Milis Linux: "mps kur retro12" (or build-install "mps derle retro12")
______________________________________________________________________

Commercial Versions

I develop and maintain versions for iOS and macOS. These run the same
image and virtual machine as all of the other systems, but add a
custom editor-centric interface and some additional words to make
them more useful on their respective platforms.

 HTM  <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/retro-forth/id1317494014?ls=1&amp;mt=12">RETRO for macOS</a>
 HTM  <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/retro-forth-12/id1170943580?ls=1&amp;mt=8">RETRO for iOS</a>
______________________________________________________________________

Patreon

I have a Patreon at https://www.patreon.com/_crc for those that want
to financially support development. All funds raised are put into
development related expenses (server expenses, app store fees,
hardware, etc).

Thanks go out to my current and past patrons:

- Kiyoshi YONEDA
- Krinkleneck
- Rick Carlino
- Scott McCallum
______________________________________________________________________

Discussion

I can be reached:

- @crcx on Twitter
- @crc@mastodon.social on Mastodon
- /r/forth on reddit (/u/_crc)
- /u/crc_ on lobste.rs
- #retro on irc.freenode.net (look for crc)

The IRC channel is logged at http://tunes.org/~nef/logs/retro and a
mirror is provided via gopher:

[DIR] <a href="http://forthworks.com/retro/irc-logs">IRC Channel Logs</a>
</p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://forthworks.com/retro</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26168640</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 17:06:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Coronavirus human challenge study gets green light in UK]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 111 | Comments 175 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26166556">thread link</a>) | @timthorn
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://www.politico.eu/article/worlds-first-coronavirus-human-challenge-study-gets-green-light-in-uk/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.politico.eu/article/worlds-first-coronavirus-human-challenge-study-gets-green-light-in-uk/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
									<p>The U.K. is set to begin the world’s first trial of healthy volunteers being intentionally infected with coronavirus, after the study received ethics approval.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The so-called human challenge study will begin within a month, said the U.K. Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy in a statement Wednesday, with up to 90 people being exposed to a very small amount of coronavirus in a safe and controlled environment. These kinds of trials are controversial as they expose healthy volunteers to diseases that may be deadly.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The next stage of the study, which has not yet been approved, will involve giving a coronavirus vaccine to different volunteers and then exposing them to coronavirus. Only vaccines that “have proven to be safe in clinical trials” will be used. However, researchers are still a “long way” from this stage of the study, according to Terence Stephenson, chair of the Health Research Authority, which gave ethics approval.</p>

<p>Proponents say these studies provide the fastest way to evaluate new vaccines, especially when the world emerges from an active pandemic, said Robert Read, head of clinical and experimental sciences within medicine at the University of Southampton, who belongs to this camp and is part of the team involved in the study.</p>
<p>This initial part of the study will help doctors understand how the immune system reacts to the virus and identify what affects transmission. The drug&nbsp;Remdesivir will be used as soon as volunteers start developing symptoms. </p>
<p>The volunteers, who are being encouraged to come forward for the study, will be between 18 and 30 and will be exposed to the variant circulating in the U.K. since March 2020. </p>
<p><em>This article is part of </em><span>POLITICO</span><em>’s premium policy service: Pro Health Care. From drug pricing, EMA, vaccines, pharma and more, our specialized journalists keep you on top of the topics driving the health care policy agenda. Email <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/worlds-first-coronavirus-human-challenge-study-gets-green-light-in-uk/%E2%80%9Cmailto:pro@politico.eu%E2%80%9D" target="_blank"><span data-cfemail="82f2f0edc2f2edeeebf6ebe1edace7f7">[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a> for a complimentary trial.</em></p>
								</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/worlds-first-coronavirus-human-challenge-study-gets-green-light-in-uk/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26166556</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 14:24:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Declassified spacecrafts and orbital weapons of the USSR (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 295 | Comments 94 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26166204">thread link</a>) | @eternalban
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://www.xissufotoday.space/2018/04/declassified-spacecrafts-and-orbital.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.xissufotoday.space/2018/04/declassified-spacecrafts-and-orbital.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-8701437466444498891" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hR9EPgdNTO0/V6igmMBuAsI/AAAAAAAABPs/RyK0eKmYbkor6nNer0HytjJN5OsSST14QCLcB/s1600/skif-20.jpg"><img alt="" height="296" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hR9EPgdNTO0/V6igmMBuAsI/AAAAAAAABPs/RyK0eKmYbkor6nNer0HytjJN5OsSST14QCLcB/s640/skif-20.jpg" width="640"></a></p><br>

<p>Fighting orbital laser station “Polyus” / “Skif”</p>
<p>(THE USSR)</p>
<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vRb_iAi4sj8/V6igjYWZOKI/AAAAAAAABPo/6LaxidVk0dI_X7swTaVcqIBXuXhq_xqAACLcB/s1600/pole%2B16.gif"><img alt="Space program of Star Wars, and the technology that you have not seen before." src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vRb_iAi4sj8/V6igjYWZOKI/AAAAAAAABPo/6LaxidVk0dI_X7swTaVcqIBXuXhq_xqAACLcB/s1600/pole%2B16.gif" title="Space program of Star Wars"></a></p>
<p>Specifications</p>
<p>Length: 37.00 m (121.39 ft)</p>
<p>Maximum Diameter: 4.10 m (13.5 ft)</p>
<p>Mass: 80,000 kg (180,000 lb)</p>
<p>Associated Launch Vehicle: Energia.</p>
<p>Intended orbit: altitude 280 km (170 mi), inclination 64°</p>
<p>Targeting system: optical, radar, with low-yield laser for final targeting</p>
<p>Armament: 1-megawatt carbon-dioxide laser</p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ITAhROrlH5w/V6igsIb3bjI/AAAAAAAABPw/EEm94HDTt7sCoOJYU8ClpAGYHgefGZqsQCLcB/s1600/skif-11.jpg"><img alt="" height="296" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ITAhROrlH5w/V6igsIb3bjI/AAAAAAAABPw/EEm94HDTt7sCoOJYU8ClpAGYHgefGZqsQCLcB/s640/skif-11.jpg" title="Armament: 1-megawatt carbon-dioxide laser" width="640"></a></p><br>

<p>The&nbsp;Polyus&nbsp;spacecraft (<a title="Russian language" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russian_language">Russian</a>:&nbsp;<span lang="ru" xml:lang="ru">Полюс</span>,&nbsp;<a title="Geographical pole" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geographical_pole">pole</a>), also known as&nbsp;Polus,&nbsp;Skif-DM,&nbsp;<a title="GRAU" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GRAU">GRAU</a>&nbsp;index&nbsp;17F19DM, was a prototype<a title="Space weapon" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Space_weapon">orbital weapons platform</a>&nbsp;designed to destroy&nbsp;<a title="Strategic Defense Initiative" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategic_Defense_Initiative">SDI satellites</a>&nbsp;with a megawatt&nbsp;<a title="Carbon dioxide laser" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carbon_dioxide_laser">carbon-dioxide laser</a>.<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyus_(spacecraft)#cite_note-starwars-1">[1]</a>&nbsp;It had a Functional Cargo Block derived from a&nbsp;<a title="TKS spacecraft" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TKS_spacecraft">TKS spacecraft</a>&nbsp;to control its orbit and it could fire test targets to demonstrate the fire control system.</p>
<p>The Polyus spacecraft was launched 15 May 1987 from&nbsp;<a title="Baikonur Cosmodrome" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baikonur_Cosmodrome">Baikonur Cosmodrome</a>&nbsp;<a title="Baikonur Cosmodrome Site 250" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baikonur_Cosmodrome_Site_250">Site 250</a>&nbsp;as part of the first flight of the&nbsp;<a title="Energia" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Energia">Energia</a>system,<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyus_(spacecraft)#cite_note-2">[2]</a>&nbsp;but failed to reach orbit.</p>
<p>According to&nbsp;<a title="Yuri Kornilov (page does not exist)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Yuri_Kornilov&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1">Yuri Kornilov</a>, Chief Designer of the Salyut Design Bureau, shortly before Polyus’ launch,&nbsp;<a title="Mikhail Gorbachev" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mikhail_Gorbachev">Mikhail Gorbachev</a>&nbsp;visited the Baikonur Cosmodrome and expressly forbade the in-orbit testing of its capabilities. Kornilov claims that Gorbachev was worried that it would be possible for Western governments to view this activity as an attempt to create a weapon in space and that such an attempt would contradict the country’s previous statements on the USSR’s peaceful intent.<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyus_(spacecraft)#cite_note-kornilov-3">[3]</a></p>
<p>For technical reasons, the payload was launched upside down. It was designed to separate from the Energia, rotate 180 degrees in yaw, then 90 degrees in roll and then fire its engine to complete its boost to orbit. The Energia functioned perfectly. However, after disconnecting from Energia, the Polyus spun a full 360 degrees instead of the planned 180 degrees. When the rocket fired, it slowed and burned up in the atmosphere over the south Pacific ocean. This failure was attributed to a faulty<a title="Inertial guidance system" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inertial_guidance_system">inertial guidance system</a>&nbsp;that had not been rigorously tested due to the rushed production schedule.<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polyus_(spacecraft)#cite_note-grondine-4">[4]</a></p><br>
<br>
<br>

<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-teiFsqZWb7A/V6ihr9TtXaI/AAAAAAAABP8/HzSWNCrGZZQnx6BbBREK4OTHhQYh6skAACLcB/s1600/pole12.jpg"><img alt="Space program of Star Wars, and the technology that you have not seen before." height="348" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-teiFsqZWb7A/V6ihr9TtXaI/AAAAAAAABP8/HzSWNCrGZZQnx6BbBREK4OTHhQYh6skAACLcB/s640/pole12.jpg" title="Space program of Star Wars, and the technology that you have not seen before." width="640"></a></p>
<p>NPO&nbsp;Energia&nbsp;received orders from the&nbsp;<a title="Government of the Soviet Union" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Government_of_the_Soviet_Union">Soviet government</a>&nbsp;to begin research on space-based strike weapons in the mid-70s. Even before, the USSR had been developing maneuverable satellites for the purpose of satellite interception. By the beginning of the 1980s,&nbsp;Energia&nbsp;had proposed two programs: laser-equipped&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;and guided missiles platform&nbsp;Kaskad&nbsp;(where&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;would cover the low-orbit targets,&nbsp;Kaskad&nbsp;engaged targets in high and geosynchronous orbits). Together with NPO&nbsp;Astrofizika&nbsp;and KBSalyut, they began developing their orbital weapons platform based on the&nbsp;<a title="Salyut program" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salyut_program">Salyut</a>&nbsp;DOS-17K frame.</p>
<p>Later, when the objective of ICBM interception proved too difficult, the aims of the project were shifted towards anti-satellite weapons. The 1983 announcement by the US of their SDI program prompted further political and financial support for the satellite interceptor program. In the nuclear exchange scenario, the interceptors would destroy the SDI satellites, followed by a so-called “pre-emptive retaliation” large-scale Soviet ICBM launch.</p>
<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Hi0M3Kqk2yU/V6ih91L_cxI/AAAAAAAABQA/hQqNjrWW5-syquXFC5bw8VN7v7Wz33VVgCLcB/s1600/pole13.jpg"><img alt="Skif spacecraft was the 1-megawatt carbon-dioxide laser, developed for the Beriev A-60 aircraft (an Il-76 flying laboratory with a combat laser)" height="332" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Hi0M3Kqk2yU/V6ih91L_cxI/AAAAAAAABQA/hQqNjrWW5-syquXFC5bw8VN7v7Wz33VVgCLcB/s640/pole13.jpg" title="Skif a combat laser)" width="640"></a></p><br>

<p>The laser chosen for the&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;spacecraft was the 1-megawatt carbon-dioxide laser, developed for the&nbsp;<a title="Beriev A-60" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beriev_A-60">Beriev A-60</a>&nbsp;aircraft (an Il-76 flying laboratory with a combat laser). The introduction of the&nbsp;Energia, capable of launching about 95 tonnes into orbit, finally allowed the spacecraft to accommodate the massive laser. The massive exhaust of the carbon-dioxide laser precipitated the objective of making the laser “recoil-less”. The&nbsp;zero-torque exhaust system&nbsp;(SBM) was developed to that end. Its testing in orbit meant the release of a large cloud of carbon dioxide, which would hint at the satellite’s purpose. Instead, the xenon-krypton mix would be used to simultaneously test the SBM and perform an innocent experiment on Earth’s&nbsp;<a title="Ionosphere" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ionosphere">ionosphere</a>.</p>
<p>In 1985, the decision was made to test-launch the new&nbsp;Energia&nbsp;launch vehicle, which was still in the&nbsp;<a title="Testbed" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Testbed">testbed</a>&nbsp;phase. A 100-ton dummy payload was initially considered for the launch, but in a series of last-minute changes, it was decided that the almost-completed&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;spacecraft would be launched instead for a 30-day mission.</p>
<p>The launch May 15, 1987, shot by 24 cameras from different angles.</p>
<p>Prelaunch installation&nbsp;04.02.1987</p>
<p>The development of the real&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;was completed in just one year, from September 1985 to September 1986. Testing and tweaking the&nbsp;Energia&nbsp;launch vehicle, the launch pad and the&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;itself moved the launch to February, and later to May 1987. According to Boris Gubanov, the head designer of the&nbsp;Energia&nbsp;launch vehicle, the work schedule of the preceding years was exhausting, and at the point of Mikhail Gorbachev’s visit on 11 May, he asked the Soviet premier to clear the launch now, because “there will be heart attacks”.</p>
<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CwxOEC0MP1o/V6ij0CpjnyI/AAAAAAAABQQ/EkKtncbH2OM8cwUp419gnVtycH86sGcZACLcB/s1600/gud_anim.gif"><img alt="Prelaunch installation 04.02.1987" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CwxOEC0MP1o/V6ij0CpjnyI/AAAAAAAABQQ/EkKtncbH2OM8cwUp419gnVtycH86sGcZACLcB/s1600/gud_anim.gif" title="Prelaunch installation 04.02.1987"></a></p>
<p>The catastrophic malfunction that led to&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;entering the atmosphere in the same area as&nbsp;Energia’s&nbsp;second stage was successfully investigated. It was found that 568 seconds after launch, the timing control device gave the logical block a command to discard the side modules’ covers and laser exhaust covers. Unknowingly, the same command was earlier used to open the solar panels and disengage the maneuvering thrusters. This wasn’t discovered because of the logistics of the testing process and overall haste. Main thrusters engaged while the&nbsp;Skif&nbsp;kept turning, overshooting the intended 180-degree turn. The spacecraft lost speed and reverted to the&nbsp;<a title="Ballistic trajectory" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ballistic_trajectory">ballistic trajectory</a>.</p><br>

<p>Air-orbital plane “Spiral”</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-STY5S6KFa5A/V6imrd6R8MI/AAAAAAAABQc/0vSgs5_ceE03HJFT6TPu2zTt2tC1GwG_ACLcB/s1600/spiral7.gif"><img alt="Air-orbital plane &quot;Spiral&quot;" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-STY5S6KFa5A/V6imrd6R8MI/AAAAAAAABQc/0vSgs5_ceE03HJFT6TPu2zTt2tC1GwG_ACLcB/s1600/spiral7.gif" title="Air-orbital plane &quot;Spiral&quot;"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-awSlGVXU2MM/V6inOZK9REI/AAAAAAAABQk/4CO-uHtBTngwWFReSMGI1ihvVKlMaSK0ACLcB/s1600/bor4_13.gif"><img alt="Air-orbital plane &quot;Spiral&quot;" height="400" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-awSlGVXU2MM/V6inOZK9REI/AAAAAAAABQk/4CO-uHtBTngwWFReSMGI1ihvVKlMaSK0ACLcB/s640/bor4_13.gif" title="Air-orbital plane &quot;Spiral&quot;" width="640"></a></p><br>
<br>
<div>
<p>Aerospace System “Spiral” – space application system consisting of the orbital plane, which is the start of the air technology was displayed in hypersonic space plane, overclockers, and then stage rocket into orbit.</p>
<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Sdl49qj8rKg/V6inZw8e77I/AAAAAAAABQo/WSA3ZjZaT1w9wuc6Zq-uBKZAXLDqErORwCLcB/s1600/MiG-105-11a.jpg"><img alt="Aerospace System &quot;Spiral&quot; - space application system consisting of the orbital plane" height="426" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Sdl49qj8rKg/V6inZw8e77I/AAAAAAAABQo/WSA3ZjZaT1w9wuc6Zq-uBKZAXLDqErORwCLcB/s640/MiG-105-11a.jpg" title="Aerospace System &quot;Spiral&quot; - space application system consisting of the orbital plane" width="640"></a></p>
<p>Source of image WIKIPEDIA</p>
<p>The “Spiral”, launched in 1960, was a response to the creation of the US space program interceptor reconnaissance-bomber, the X-20, “the Dyna Soar”</p><br>
<br>
<div>
<p>Plane-overclockers</p>
<p>Powerful airship overclockers (weight 52 tons, length 38 meters, wingspan of 16.5 m) was dispersed to six times the speed of sound (6M), then with his “back” at an altitude of 28-30 km was supposed to start a 10-ton manned orbital plane 8 m long and 7.4 m span.</p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oSes4d9bcsg/V6inJIfNtfI/AAAAAAAABQg/lqy4GYfzDyk1Pp_vJyG_SIqnIVVrvhkzgCLcB/s1600/spiral1.gif"><img alt="Plane-overclockers" height="262" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oSes4d9bcsg/V6inJIfNtfI/AAAAAAAABQg/lqy4GYfzDyk1Pp_vJyG_SIqnIVVrvhkzgCLcB/s640/spiral1.gif" title="Plane-overclockers" width="640"></a></p><br>

<p>“The plane-overclockers to 6 Mach suggests the possibility of use as a passenger plane, airliner, which, of course, was rational: its high speed characteristics would allow to raise the rate of civil aviation.”</p>
<p>Plane-overclockers was the first technologically revolutionary detailed design of hypersonic aircraft with jet engines. At the 40th Congress of the International Aeronautical Federation (the FAI), which took place in 1989 in Malaga (Spain), representatives of the US National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA’s) gave the plane-overclockers high praise, noting that he “was designed in accordance with the modern requirements. “</p><br>

<p>In view of the requirements of a lot of money for brand new motor, aerodynamic and material science technologies for the creation of such a hypersonic-overclockers aircraft in the latest versions of the project was considered less costly and more quickly achievable possibility of creating not a hypersonic and supersonic overclockers, as is considered modified shock-reconnaissance aircraft T-4 ( “100”), however it was not realized.</p><br>
</div>
<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-f56Ka-Kmgx4/V6ing6SrPHI/AAAAAAAABQw/wSvcahmzZrUuhoyTc6KunO_st0HMdJsRwCLcB/s1600/spiral%2B1.gif"><img alt="hypersonic-overclockers aircraft" height="168" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-f56Ka-Kmgx4/V6ing6SrPHI/AAAAAAAABQw/wSvcahmzZrUuhoyTc6KunO_st0HMdJsRwCLcB/s640/spiral%2B1.gif" title="hypersonic-overclockers aircraft" width="640"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ntrWcYZ1jMY/V6ing_kTtCI/AAAAAAAABQs/vzqLBGTn4AEoWQ_7w-FnT3bYQFDpNslWACLcB/s1600/spiral%2B2%2B%25281%2529.gif"><img alt="hypersonic-overclockers aircraft" height="458" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ntrWcYZ1jMY/V6ing_kTtCI/AAAAAAAABQs/vzqLBGTn4AEoWQ_7w-FnT3bYQFDpNslWACLcB/s640/spiral%2B2%2B%25281%2529.gif" title="hypersonic-overclockers aircraft" width="640"></a></p><br>
<br>

<p>BOR&nbsp;space drone</p>
<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vYoT5DevGH4/V6ipam0sBYI/AAAAAAAABRo/V6aXqq5FKt8-46cakc0zzbqGkH3Hr-yiwCLcB/s1600/i1053rp.jpg"><img height="194" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vYoT5DevGH4/V6ipam0sBYI/AAAAAAAABRo/V6aXqq5FKt8-46cakc0zzbqGkH3Hr-yiwCLcB/s640/i1053rp.jpg" width="640"></a></p><br>

<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-wLcFH5YIyno/V6ipKJ5PMVI/AAAAAAAABRM/Lut7B63tcT08_Kqvl82jsFVW-H4-p1x8ACLcB/s1600/bor4-15.gif"><img alt="Unpiloted Orbital Rocketplane 4" height="412" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-wLcFH5YIyno/V6ipKJ5PMVI/AAAAAAAABRM/Lut7B63tcT08_Kqvl82jsFVW-H4-p1x8ACLcB/s640/bor4-15.gif" title="Unpiloted Orbital Rocketplane 4" width="640"></a></p><br>
<br>
<div>
<p>The&nbsp;BOR-4&nbsp;(<span lang="ru" xml:lang="ru">Bespilotnyi Orbital’nyi Raketoplan 4</span>, “Unpiloted Orbital Rocketplane 4”) flight vehicle is a scaled (1:2) prototype of the Soviet&nbsp;<a title="Spiral spaceplane" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spiral_spaceplane">Spiral</a>&nbsp;<a title="VTHL" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VTHL">VTHL</a>&nbsp;(vertical takeoff, horizontal landing)<a title="Spaceplane" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaceplane">spaceplane</a>. An unmanned, subscale&nbsp;<a title="Spacecraft" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacecraft">spacecraft</a>, its purpose was to test the heatshield tiles and reinforced carbon-carbon for the&nbsp;<a title="Buran (spacecraft)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buran_(spacecraft)">Buran space shuttle</a>, then under development.<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BOR-4#cite_note-1">[1]</a></p>
<p>Several of them were built and flown between 1982 and 1984 from the&nbsp;<a title="Kapustin Yar" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kapustin_Yar">Kapustin Yar</a>&nbsp;launch site at speeds of up to Mach 25. After reentry, they were designed to parachute to an ocean splashdown for recovery by the&nbsp;<a title="Soviet Navy" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soviet_Navy">Soviet Navy</a>. The testing was nearly identical to that carried out by the&nbsp;<a title="US Air Force" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/US_Air_Force">US Air Force</a>&nbsp;<a title="ASSET (spaceplane)" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASSET_(spaceplane)">ASSET program</a>&nbsp;in the 1960s, which tested the heatshield design for the&nbsp;<a title="X-20 Dyna-Soar" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X-20_Dyna-Soar">X-20 Dyna-Soar</a>. On June 3, 1982 a&nbsp;<a title="Royal Australian Air Force" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Royal_Australian_Air_Force">Royal Australian Air Force</a>&nbsp;<a title="P-3 Orion" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/P-3_Orion">P-3 Orion</a>&nbsp;reconnaissance aircraft captured the first Western images of the craft as it was recovered by a Soviet ship near the&nbsp;<a title="Cocos Islands" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cocos_Islands">Cocos Islands</a>.<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BOR-4#cite_note-2">[2]</a></p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HAbZbRnqeZ4/V6ipQtSw7HI/AAAAAAAABRQ/ZzElR0QP8iQPgvjpcaG761a29F3tTdFVQCLcB/s1600/bor4-7.gif"><img height="640" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HAbZbRnqeZ4/V6ipQtSw7HI/AAAAAAAABRQ/ZzElR0QP8iQPgvjpcaG761a29F3tTdFVQCLcB/s640/bor4-7.gif" width="96"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EfUE1OWo-q8/V6ipQ5Jsr9I/AAAAAAAABRY/lf6Bx_Idsg8PG1gu2i0r46PFAZ-imiQ0QCLcB/s1600/bor4-81.gif"><img src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EfUE1OWo-q8/V6ipQ5Jsr9I/AAAAAAAABRY/lf6Bx_Idsg8PG1gu2i0r46PFAZ-imiQ0QCLcB/s1600/bor4-81.gif"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-pQX430XulG0/V6ipQitpQII/AAAAAAAABRU/SEG93Sg14nwtZBsQci-UTdqaWowXrCDHACLcB/s1600/i0865rp.jpg"><img height="304" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-pQX430XulG0/V6ipQitpQII/AAAAAAAABRU/SEG93Sg14nwtZBsQci-UTdqaWowXrCDHACLcB/s640/i0865rp.jpg" width="640"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vCQ4NhAyzF4/V6ipQ9YS97I/AAAAAAAABRc/VucBuBk__mgOtRDAI3ayI70kg1vaQ-aAwCLcB/s1600/i0937rp.jpg"><img height="300" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vCQ4NhAyzF4/V6ipQ9YS97I/AAAAAAAABRc/VucBuBk__mgOtRDAI3ayI70kg1vaQ-aAwCLcB/s400/i0937rp.jpg" width="400"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4ecLgpjXV38/V6ipRJYXmZI/AAAAAAAABRg/08wrJ-l3LY0f6aG_xaaSOv3vrUwTeGw8ACLcB/s1600/i1040rp.jpg"><img height="640" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4ecLgpjXV38/V6ipRJYXmZI/AAAAAAAABRg/08wrJ-l3LY0f6aG_xaaSOv3vrUwTeGw8ACLcB/s640/i1040rp.jpg" width="478"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z39-2F9dR44/V6ipRQ0HF0I/AAAAAAAABRk/1J2wISGkfnIwKtECHQX7SODuAfjmsMO-gCLcB/s1600/i1043rp.jpg"><img height="640" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-z39-2F9dR44/V6ipRQ0HF0I/AAAAAAAABRk/1J2wISGkfnIwKtECHQX7SODuAfjmsMO-gCLcB/s640/i1043rp.jpg" width="478"></a></p><br>
<br>
<br>
<br>

<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-329Ztj6nwh0/V6io8aeDcfI/AAAAAAAABRE/RAwaJyioMJ8V0dxgtXEHAZVAc0YhZDpBACLcB/s1600/bor13_11.gif"><img height="300" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-329Ztj6nwh0/V6io8aeDcfI/AAAAAAAABRE/RAwaJyioMJ8V0dxgtXEHAZVAc0YhZDpBACLcB/s400/bor13_11.gif" width="400"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eS6bZ2WgV4E/V6io8grD54I/AAAAAAAABRI/4vMejPNeBKQODrUBQ7B15-7uR3t1nlJbQCLcB/s1600/bor13_10.gif"><img height="300" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eS6bZ2WgV4E/V6io8grD54I/AAAAAAAABRI/4vMejPNeBKQODrUBQ7B15-7uR3t1nlJbQCLcB/s400/bor13_10.gif" width="400"></a></p><br>

<p>Russian Aerospace Plane</p><br>
</div>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-qBYyz-vcWwc/V6irQnxpysI/AAAAAAAABR0/Y9E9GfdOROAy0Pz-s4v6yvZCV2iJnPVbACLcB/s1600/6803551.jpg"><img alt="Russian Aerospace Plane" height="427" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-qBYyz-vcWwc/V6irQnxpysI/AAAAAAAABR0/Y9E9GfdOROAy0Pz-s4v6yvZCV2iJnPVbACLcB/s640/6803551.jpg" title="Russian Aerospace Plane RAKS" width="640"></a></p><br>
<br>
<div>
<p>Possible Features</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;Length 7900 mm</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;Wingspan mm 3600</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;Starting weight, kg 2200</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;The stock of liquid oxygen, 18 kg</p>
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;Speed range, Max 6 … 14</p><br>
</div>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Id1G8Ai3FHk/V6irWH6acmI/AAAAAAAABSA/7Tq_By2nMfQp4R_0el1V0uAB6SkEsJjpgCLcB/s1600/3587219.jpg"><img alt="Russian Aerospace Plane (RAKS) is created as part of the research work &quot;Eagle&quot; by order of the Russian Aerospace Agency in 1993." height="318" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Id1G8Ai3FHk/V6irWH6acmI/AAAAAAAABSA/7Tq_By2nMfQp4R_0el1V0uAB6SkEsJjpgCLcB/s640/3587219.jpg" title="Russian Aerospace Plane" width="640"></a></p>
<p>Russian Aerospace Plane (RAKS) is created as part of the research work “Eagle” by order of the Russian Aerospace Agency in 1993.</p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ls7d5uPaNL8/V6irV7m1QEI/AAAAAAAABR8/eeGSYmibxNAM7JsA05O0p5SwrodovDUrwCLcB/s1600/8450700.jpg"><img height="244" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ls7d5uPaNL8/V6irV7m1QEI/AAAAAAAABR8/eeGSYmibxNAM7JsA05O0p5SwrodovDUrwCLcB/s640/8450700.jpg" width="640"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DXSuq544CWo/V6irWQKDKiI/AAAAAAAABSE/hVzjAmz0vLoXJyiHuddT5r3rSp2BiwEJgCLcB/s1600/vks-4.jpg"><img height="305" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-DXSuq544CWo/V6irWQKDKiI/AAAAAAAABSE/hVzjAmz0vLoXJyiHuddT5r3rSp2BiwEJgCLcB/s400/vks-4.jpg" width="400"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Wx9dP_DpcJk/V6irWTOUtYI/AAAAAAAABSI/Tm0kUSc5vFgPXRYnwiN3TLgxtOqMOqI9ACLcB/s1600/vks-7.jpg"><img height="320" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Wx9dP_DpcJk/V6irWTOUtYI/AAAAAAAABSI/Tm0kUSc5vFgPXRYnwiN3TLgxtOqMOqI9ACLcB/s320/vks-7.jpg" width="316"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/--w6856Ho57Y/V6irWvdAPII/AAAAAAAABSM/1gAUY-GV0voWH-WJ5jf4BNGfJ2Eo_7fzgCLcB/s1600/vks-8.jpg"><img height="176" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/--w6856Ho57Y/V6irWvdAPII/AAAAAAAABSM/1gAUY-GV0voWH-WJ5jf4BNGfJ2Eo_7fzgCLcB/s400/vks-8.jpg" width="400"></a></p><br>
<div>
<p>Main targets:</p>
<p>– The integration of scramjet and airframe;</p>
<p>– Study questions work ramjet engine in real hypersonic flight at cruising speed up to M = 14;</p>
<p>– The study of the thermal problems associated with operating ramjet engine and aerodynamic heating of the airframe;</p>
<p>– Dynamic throttling in a hypersonic scramjet flight;</p>
<p>– Check ground flight test experiments</p><br>
</div><br>
<br>

<p>Kliper</p>
<p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nM6wVrsBtIw/V6itl14uJtI/AAAAAAAABSc/M5lmXznMma4YD02HQ6vUv2moH-Xw_wO-ACLcB/s1600/%25D0%259A%25D0%25BB%25D0%25B8%25D0%25BF%25D0%25B5%25D1%2580_Infografia.jpg"><img alt="Kliper (Клипер, English: Clipper) was a proposed partly reusable manned spacecraft by RSC Energia. Due to lack of funding from the ESA and RSA, the project has been indefinitely postponed as of 2006." height="398" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nM6wVrsBtIw/V6itl14uJtI/AAAAAAAABSc/M5lmXznMma4YD02HQ6vUv2moH-Xw_wO-ACLcB/s640/%25D0%259A%25D0%25BB%25D0%25B8%25D0%25BF%25D0%25B5%25D1%2580_Infografia.jpg" title="spacecraft by RSC Energia." width="640"></a></p><br>
<br>
<div>
<p>Kliper&nbsp;was a proposed partly&nbsp;<a title="Reusable launch system" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reusable_launch_system">reusable</a>&nbsp;manned&nbsp;<a title="Spacecraft" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacecraft">spacecraft</a>&nbsp;by&nbsp;<a title="S.P. Korolev Rocket and Space Corporation Energia" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S.P._Korolev_Rocket_and_Space_Corporation_Energia">RSC Energia</a>. Due to lack of funding from the ESA and RSA, the project has been indefinitely postponed as of 2006. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kliper" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Source</a></p>
<p>Designed primarily to replace the&nbsp;<a title="Soyuz spacecraft" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soyuz_spacecraft">Soyuz spacecraft</a>, Kliper was proposed in two versions: as a pure&nbsp;<a title="Lifting body" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lifting_body">lifting body</a>&nbsp;design and as<a title="Spaceplane" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaceplane">spaceplane</a>&nbsp;with small&nbsp;<a title="Wing" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wing">wings</a>. In either case, the craft would have been able to glide into the atmosphere at an angle that produces much less stress on the human occupants than the current Soyuz. Kliper was intended to be designed to be able to carry up to six people and to perform ferry services between Earth and the&nbsp;<a title="International Space Station" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Space_Station">International Space Station</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YBFudwoXK3Q/V6iuRRYYdOI/AAAAAAAABS0/C6Me6merYrY-ciSKCcGxOkMx-CabSkeQQCLcB/s1600/cliperan2.gif"><img alt="Kliper (Клипер, English: Clipper) was a proposed partly reusable manned spacecraft by RSC Energia." height="173" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YBFudwoXK3Q/V6iuRRYYdOI/AAAAAAAABS0/C6Me6merYrY-ciSKCcGxOkMx-CabSkeQQCLcB/s400/cliperan2.gif" title="Kliper (Клипер, English: Clipper) was a proposed partly reusable manned spacecraft by RSC Energia." width="400"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aalzuaqor_8/V6iuIEwP4xI/AAAAAAAABSg/7J4fzKwYq-8xHUTn7PBkoZmN3oygLP8LgCLcB/s1600/cliper05.gif"><img height="227" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aalzuaqor_8/V6iuIEwP4xI/AAAAAAAABSg/7J4fzKwYq-8xHUTn7PBkoZmN3oygLP8LgCLcB/s400/cliper05.gif" width="400"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2fm-a4DRCOg/V6iuIOu-FgI/AAAAAAAABSk/iBERytjejZAx0SR_pVzGyPovDNhCquSuACLcB/s1600/cliper07.gif"><img height="162" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2fm-a4DRCOg/V6iuIOu-FgI/AAAAAAAABSk/iBERytjejZAx0SR_pVzGyPovDNhCquSuACLcB/s640/cliper07.gif" width="640"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-71vQS8q3AtQ/V6iuKHoZdoI/AAAAAAAABSo/8ssaVZSXKwAQimgqlWlfVn3nVePBVrxGwCLcB/s1600/cliper09.gif"><img alt="Kliper (Клипер, English: Clipper) was a proposed partly reusable manned spacecraft by RSC Energia." height="417" src="https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-71vQS8q3AtQ/V6iuKHoZdoI/AAAAAAAABSo/8ssaVZSXKwAQimgqlWlfVn3nVePBVrxGwCLcB/s640/cliper09.gif" title="Kliper RSC Energia." width="640"></a></p>
<p><a href="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4RaU28U7s8Y/V6iuOuvWlHI/AAAAAAAABSs/SepEgtWvjVEdsvrOGsAalTmO6W3R3MHVQCLcB/s1600/clipeani.gif"><img height="180" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4RaU28U7s8Y/V6iuOuvWlHI/AAAAAAAABSs/SepEgtWvjVEdsvrOGsAalTmO6W3R3MHVQCLcB/s400/clipeani.gif" width="400"></a></p><br>
<br>
</div><br>
</div><br>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.xissufotoday.space/2018/04/declassified-spacecrafts-and-orbital.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26166204</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 13:48:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why did I leave Google or, why did I stay so long?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 740 | Comments 777 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26165809">thread link</a>) | @mrowland
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://paygo.media/p/25171 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paygo.media/p/25171">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paygo.media/p/25171</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26165809</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 12:59:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Dear Email Industry, We've Got a GDPR Problem]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 84 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26164553">thread link</a>) | @iamacyborg
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://www.jacquescorbytuech.com/writing/gdpr-email-tracking | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jacquescorbytuech.com/writing/gdpr-email-tracking">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="content">
<article>
<header>

</header>
<p><small><time datetime="2019-06-10T13:37:00+01:00">
      Mon 10 June 2019
    </time></small>
</p>
<div>
<p><strong>The email industry's got a GDPR problem.</strong></p>
<p>Some of you reading this might have seen me talk about this problem in the very excellent <a href="https://email.geeks.chat/">Email Geeks Community</a>, but if you're new, let me break it down for you.</p>
<p>Last year, the GDPR came into effect, which put in place some rigorous laws around data processing and how personally identifiable information (PII) has to be handled. This stressed out a lot of email marketers, who quite rightly realised that the new regulations would have a significant effect on their ability to acquire and market to customers via their email address (which counts as PII). </p>
<p>Now if you're reading this, you're probably familiar with how that's gone, so I won't bore you with the details.</p>

<h2>So What's the Problem?</h2>
<p>The overwhelming majority of commercial email sent today contains tracking pixels and tracking links, these are used to uniquely identify individuals so that opens and clicks can be correctly attributed to them. This isn't strictly a problem, the GDPR does not ban processing of personal data for tracking purposes, however email tracking frequently fails to meet a number of criteria necessary to be legal under the GDPR.</p>
<p><strong>We're not collection consent to track user behaviour</strong> - That means we're probably relying on good old Legitimate Interest and that's frought with a number of risks.</p>
<p>Firstly, most brands aren't disclosing in their privacy policies or at moment of signup that they're tracking user behaviour in marketing emails. That's a problem. <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-5-gdpr/">Article 5</a> clearly states that to be legally compliant, personal data should be processed in the following manner:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner in relation to the data subject (‘lawfulness, fairness and transparency’);</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is further expanded upon in <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/recitals/no-39/">Recital 39</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It should be transparent to natural persons that personal data concerning them are collected, used, consulted or otherwise processed and to what extent the personal data are or will be processed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Failure to adequately disclose email tracking within your brand's privacy policy is a clear breach of the regulation.</p>
<p>Secondly, when Legitimate Interest is used as the legal basis for processing of personal data, the data subject has the <a href="https://gdpr-info.eu/art-21-gdpr/">Right to Object</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The data subject shall have the right to object, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning him or her which is based on point (e) or (f) of Article 6(1), including profiling based on those provisions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This means that when processing data under a Legitimate Interest basis, the data subject has the right to object to your tracking, this brings us round to our second problem.</p>

<h2>Email Marketing Platforms Are Not GDPR Compliant†</h2>
<p>Take a look at your ESP, does it allow you to, on a per individual basis, opt-out of email tracking?</p>
<p>If the answer to that is no, and in most cases the answer will be no, you're in breach of the GDPR as soon as a customer objects to your data processing. That is assuming you disclose the tracking in your privacy policy, if you don't you're already in breach.</p>
<p>This becomes even more of a legal quagmire as soon as we start looking at tracking in emails sent on a legal basis other than Consent or Legitimate Interest.</p>
<p>So what can you do about it?</p>
<p><strong>Complain to your ESP!</strong> Complain frequently and loudly. Make them do something about it. Ultimately the GDPR is here to stay, and ESP's must put in the work to allow marketers to comply with the law.</p>

<h2>Where Does That Leave Email Marketing?</h2>
<p>Email marketing isn't going anywhere, email remains one of the most valuable channels for reaching your customers and losing the ability to track behavioural data isn't going to change that fundamental fact. What is going to change is our ability to act upon vast swathes of personal data.</p>
<p>You know what?</p>
<p>That's not a problem, personal data is not a crucial part of gauging the success of a campaign and anonymised data is more than good enough for us to achieve our objectives.</p>
<p>I'll leave you with a parting note; as marketers, we've become entirely too comfortable handling vast swathes of personal data, it's time we get used to a world where that option isn't always going to be available to us. </p>
<hr>
<p>Usual caveats apply. I am not a lawyer.</p>
<p>† <em>Yes, I know a small minority are, but they're a small minority. This might be one of the very few instances in which I'd recommend SFMC</em></p>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p><img alt="signature" src="https://www.jacquescorbytuech.com/images/jacques.png">
</p></div>
<div>
<h4>Subscribe for updates</h4>

<p>Updates, whenever I've got something valuable to say.</p>
</div>
</article>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jacquescorbytuech.com/writing/gdpr-email-tracking</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26164553</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 09:42:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Easy Forth: Learn forth with REPL in the browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 99 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26164275">thread link</a>) | @guerrilla
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://skilldrick.github.io/easyforth | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://skilldrick.github.io/easyforth">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>

        

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>This small ebook is here to teach you a programming language called Forth. Forth is a
language unlike most others. It’s not functional <em>or</em> object oriented, it doesn’t
have type-checking, and it basically has zero syntax. It was written in the 70s, but
is still used today for
<a href="http://www.forth.com/resources/apps/more-applications.html">certain applications</a>.</p>

<p>Why would you want to learn such an odd language? Every new programming
language you learn helps you think about problems in new ways. Forth is very
easy to learn, but it requires you to think in a different way than you’re used
to. That makes it a perfect language to broaden your coding horizons.</p>

<p>This book includes a simple implementation of Forth I wrote in JavaScript. It’s by
no means perfect, and is missing a lot of the functionality you’d expect in a real
Forth system. It’s just here to give you an easy way to try out the examples. (If
you’re a Forth expert, please
<a href="https://github.com/skilldrick/easyforth">contribute here</a> and make it better!)</p>

<p>I’m going to assume that you know at least one other programming language, and have
a basic idea of how stacks work as a data structure.</p>

<h2 id="adding-some-numbers">Adding Some Numbers</h2>

<p>The thing that separates Forth from most other languages is its use of the
stack. In Forth, everything revolves around the stack. Any time you type a
number, it gets pushed onto the stack. If you want to add two numbers together,
typing <code>+</code> takes the top two numbers off the stack, adds them, and puts
the result back on the stack.</p>

<p>Let’s take a look at an example. Type (don’t copy-paste) the following into the
interpreter, typing <code>Enter</code> after each line.</p>

<pre><code>1
2
3
</code></pre>



<p>Every time you type a line followed by the <code>Enter</code> key, the Forth interpreter
executes that line, and appends the string <code>ok</code> to let you know there were no
errors. You should also notice that as you execute each line, the area at the
top fills up with numbers. That area is our visualization of the stack. It
should look like this:</p>

<p>1 2 3 &lt;- Top</p>

<p>Now, into the same interpreter, type a single <code>+</code> followed by the <code>Enter</code> key. The top two
elements on the stack, <code>2</code> and <code>3</code>, have been replaced by <code>5</code>.</p>

<p>1 5 &lt;- Top</p>

<p>At this point, your editor window should look like this:</p>

<p>1  <span>ok</span>
2  <span>ok</span>
3  <span>ok</span>
+  <span>ok</span>
</p>

<p>Type <code>+</code> again and press <code>Enter</code>, and the top two elements will be replaced by 6. If
you type <code>+</code> one more time, Forth will try to pop the top two elements off the
stack, even though there’s only <em>one</em> element on the stack! This results in a
<code>Stack underflow</code> error:</p>

<p>1  <span>ok</span>
2  <span>ok</span>
3  <span>ok</span>
+  <span>ok</span>
+  <span>ok</span>
+  <span>Stack underflow</span>
</p>

<p>Forth doesn’t force you to type every token as a separate line. Type the
following into the next editor, followed by the <code>Enter</code> key:</p>

<pre><code>123 456 +
</code></pre>



<p>The stack should now look like this:</p>

<p>579 &lt;- Top</p>

<p>This style, where the operator appears after the operands, is known as
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reverse_Polish_notation">Reverse-Polish
notation</a>. Let’s try
something a bit more complicated, and calculate <code>10 * (5 + 2)</code>. Type the
following into the interpreter:</p>

<pre><code>5 2 + 10 *
</code></pre>



<p>One of the nice things about Forth is that the order of operations is
completely based on their order in the program. For example, when executing <code>5
2 + 10 *</code>, the interpreter pushes 5 to the stack, then 2, then adds them and
pushes the resulting 7, then pushes 10 to the stack, then multiplies 7 and 10.
Because of this, there’s no need for parentheses to group operators with lower
precedence.</p>

<h3 id="stack-effects">Stack Effects</h3>

<p>Most Forth words affect the stack in some way. Some take values off the stack,
some leave new values on the stack, and some do a mixture of both. These “stack
effects” are commonly represented using comments of the form <code>( before -- after
)</code>. For example, <code>+</code> is <code>( n1 n2 -- sum )</code> - <code>n1</code> and <code>n2</code> are the top two numbers
on the stack, and <code>sum</code> is the value left on the stack.</p>

<h2 id="defining-words">Defining Words</h2>

<p>The syntax of Forth is extremely straightforward. Forth code is interpreted as
a series of space-delimited words. Almost all non-whitespace characters are valid
in words. When the Forth interpreter reads a word, it checks to see if a
definition exists in an internal structure known as the Dictionary. If it is
found, that definition is executed. Otherwise, the word is assumed to be a
number, and it is pushed onto the stack. If the word cannot be converted to a
number, an error occurs.</p>

<p>You can try that out yourself below. Type <code>foo</code> (an unrecognized word)
and press enter.</p>



<p>You should see something like this:</p>

<p>foo  <span>foo ?</span></p>

<p><code>foo ?</code> means that Forth was unable to find a definition for <code>foo</code>, and it
wasn’t a valid number.</p>

<p>We can create our own definition of <code>foo</code> using two special words called <code>:</code>
(colon) and <code>;</code> (semicolon).  <code>:</code> is our way of telling Forth we want to create
a definition. The first word after the <code>:</code> becomes the definition name, and the
rest of the words (until the <code>;</code>) make up the body of the definition. It’s
conventional to include two spaces between the name and the body of the
definition. Try entering the following:</p>

<pre><code>: foo  100 + ;
1000 foo
foo foo foo
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Warning:</strong> A common mistake is to miss out the space before the <code>;</code> word. Because Forth
words are space delimited and can contain most characters, <code>+;</code> is a perfectly
valid word and is not parsed as two separate words.</p>



<p>As you’ve hopefully figured out, our <code>foo</code> word simply adds 100 to the value on
top of the stack. It’s not very interesting, but it should give you an idea of
how simple definitions work.</p>

<h2 id="stack-manipulation">Stack Manipulation</h2>

<p>Now we can start taking a look at some of Forth’s predefined words. First,
let’s look at some words for manipulating the elements at the top of the stack.</p>

<h3 id="dup--n----n-n-"><code>dup ( n -- n n )</code></h3>

<p><code>dup</code> is short for “duplicate” – it duplicates the top element of the stack. For example,
try this out:</p>

<pre><code>1 2 3 dup
</code></pre>



<p>You should end up with the following stack:</p>

<p>1 2 3 3 &lt;- Top</p>

<h3 id="drop--n----"><code>drop ( n -- )</code></h3>

<p><code>drop</code> simply drops the top element of the stack. Running:</p>

<pre><code>1 2 3 drop
</code></pre>

<p>gives you a stack of:</p>

<p>1 2 &lt;- Top</p>



<h3 id="swap--n1-n2----n2-n1-"><code>swap ( n1 n2 -- n2 n1 )</code></h3>

<p><code>swap</code>, as you may have guessed, swaps the top two elements of the stack. For example:</p>

<pre><code>1 2 3 4 swap
</code></pre>

<p>will give you:</p>

<p>1 2 4 3 &lt;- Top</p>



<h3 id="over--n1-n2----n1-n2-n1-"><code>over ( n1 n2 -- n1 n2 n1 )</code></h3>

<p><code>over</code> is a bit less obvious: it takes the second element from the top of the
stack and duplicates it to the top of the stack. Running this:</p>

<pre><code>1 2 3 over
</code></pre>

<p>will result in this:</p>

<p>1 2 3 2 &lt;- Top</p>



<h3 id="rot--n1-n2-n3----n2-n3-n1-"><code>rot ( n1 n2 n3 -- n2 n3 n1 )</code></h3>

<p>Finally, <code>rot</code> “rotates” the top <em>three</em> elements of the stack. The third
element from the top of the stack gets moved to the top of the stack, pushing
the other two elements down.</p>

<pre><code>1 2 3 rot
</code></pre>

<p>gives you:</p>

<p>2 3 1 &lt;- Top</p>



<h2 id="generating-output">Generating Output</h2>

<p>Next, let’s look at some words for outputting text to the console.</p>

<h3 id="n-----period"><code>. ( n -- )</code> (period)</h3>

<p>The simplest output word in Forth is <code>.</code>. You can use <code>.</code> to output the top of
the stack in the output of the current line. For example, try running this
(make sure to include all the spaces!):</p>

<pre><code>1 . 2 . 3 . 4 5 6 . . .
</code></pre>



<p>You should see this:</p>

<p>1 . 2 . 3 . 4 5 6 . . . <span>1 2 3 6 5 4  ok</span></p>

<p>Going through this in order, we push <code>1</code>, then pop it off and output it. Then
we do the same with <code>2</code> and <code>3</code>. Next we push <code>4</code>, <code>5</code>, and <code>6</code> onto the stack.
We then pop them off and output them one-by-one. That’s why the last three
numbers in the output are reversed: the stack is last in, first out.</p>

<h3 id="emit--c----"><code>emit ( c -- )</code></h3>

<p><code>emit</code> can be used to output numbers as ascii characters. Just like <code>.</code> outputs
the number at the top of the stack, <code>emit</code> outputs that number as an ascii
character. For example:</p>

<pre><code> 33 119 111 87 emit emit emit emit
</code></pre>



<p>I won’t give the output here so as to not ruin the surprise. This could also be
written as:</p>

<pre><code>87 emit 111 emit 119 emit 33 emit
</code></pre>

<p>Unlike <code>.</code>, <code>emit</code> doesn’t output any space after each character, enabling you
to build up arbitrary strings of output.</p>

<h3 id="cr-----"><code>cr ( -- )</code></h3>

<p><code>cr</code> is short for carriage return – it simply outputs a newline:</p>

<pre><code>cr 100 . cr 200 . cr 300 .
</code></pre>



<p>This will output:</p>

<p>cr 100 . cr 200 . cr 300 .<span>
100
200
300  ok</span></p>

<h3 id="section"><code>." ( -- )</code></h3>

<p>Finally we have <code>."</code> – a special word for outputting strings. The <code>."</code> word works
differently inside definitions to interactive mode. <code>."</code> marks the beginning of
a string to output, and the end of the string is marked by <code>"</code>. The closing <code>"</code>
isn’t a word, and so doesn’t need to be space-delimited. Here’s an example:</p>

<pre><code>: say-hello  ." Hello there!" ;
say-hello
</code></pre>



<p>You should see the following output</p>

<p>say-hello <span>Hello there! ok</span></p>

<p>We can combine <code>."</code>, <code>.</code>, <code>cr</code>, and <code>emit</code> to build up more complex output:</p>

<pre><code>: print-stack-top  cr dup ." The top of the stack is " .
  cr ." which looks like '" dup emit ." ' in ascii  " ;
48 print-stack-top
</code></pre>



<p>Running this should give you the following output:</p>

<p>48 print-stack-top <span>
The top of the stack is 48
which looks like '0' in ascii   ok</span></p>

<h2 id="conditionals-and-loops">Conditionals and Loops</h2>

<p>Now onto the fun stuff! Forth, like most other languages, has conditionals and
loops for controlling the flow of your program. To understand how they work,
however, first we need to understand booleans in Forth.</p>

<h3 id="booleans">Booleans</h3>

<p>There’s actually no boolean type in Forth. The number <code>0</code> is treated as false,
and any other number is true, although the canonical true value is <code>-1</code> (all
boolean operators return <code>0</code> or <code>-1</code>).</p>

<p>To test if two numbers are equal, you can use <code>=</code>:</p>

<pre><code>3 4 = .
5 5 = .
</code></pre>

<p>This should output:</p>

<p>3 4 = . <span>0  ok</span>
5 5 = . <span>-1  ok</span></p>



<p>You can use <code>&lt;</code> and <code>&gt;</code> for less than and greater than. <code>&lt;</code> checks to see if the
second item from the top of the stack is less than the top item of the stack, and
vice versa for <code>&gt;</code>:</p>

<pre><code>3 4 &lt; .
3 4 &gt; .
</code></pre>

<p>3 4 &lt; . <span>-1  ok</span>
3 4 &gt; . <span>0  ok</span></p>



<p>The boolean operators And, Or, and Not are available as <code>and</code>, <code>or</code>, and <code>invert</code>:</p>

<pre><code>3 4 &lt; 20 30 &lt; and .
3 4 &lt; 20 30 &gt; or .
3 4 &lt; invert .
</code></pre>

<p>The first line is the equivalent of <code>3 &lt; 4 &amp; 20 &lt; 30</code> in a C-based language.
The second line is the equivalent of <code>3 &lt; 4 | 20 &gt; 30</code>. The third line is the
equivalent of <code>!(3 &lt; 4)</code>.</p>

<p><code>and</code>, <code>or</code>, and <code>invert</code> are all bitwise operations. For well-formed flags
(<code>0</code> and <code>-1</code>) they’ll work as expected, but they’ll give incorrect results for
arbitrary numbers.</p>



<h3 id="if-then"><code>if then</code></h3>

<p>Now we can finally get onto conditionals. Conditionals in Forth can only be
used inside definitions. The simplest conditional statement in Forth is <code>if
then</code>, which is equivalent to a standard <code>if</code> statement in most languages.
Here’s an example of a definition using …</p></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://skilldrick.github.io/easyforth">https://skilldrick.github.io/easyforth</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://skilldrick.github.io/easyforth</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26164275</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 09:03:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[CTO Headaches: Top cloud-to-cloud migration woes (and how to solve them)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 64 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26163970">thread link</a>) | @llarsson
<br/>
February 17, 2021 | https://www.cncf.io/blog/2021/02/15/cto-headaches-top-5-cloud-to-cloud-migration-woes-and-how-to-solve-them/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cncf.io/blog/2021/02/15/cto-headaches-top-5-cloud-to-cloud-migration-woes-and-how-to-solve-them/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p><em>Guest post originally published on <a href="https://elastisys.com/top-5-cloud-to-cloud-migration-woes-and-how-to-solve-them/">Elastisys’s blog</a> by Lars Larsson, Senior Cloud Architect and Branch Manager</em> at <em>Elastisys</em></p>



<p>All companies that use cloud services do so for a reason. But those reasons may change. Whether motivated by the need for a multi-cloud strategy, expenditure minimization, legislative or regulatory demands, or simply to get closer to end users, many organizations find themselves migrating from one cloud to another. Cloud-to-cloud migration for a non-trivial application contains a lot of unknown unknowns. This causes stress and uncertainty for a CTO. To help shed some light based on years of experience in the field, we have asked senior cloud architect Lars Larsson at Elastisys, to list some of these issues.</p>



<h2>Executive summary</h2>



<ul><li>Cloud providers offer a wide range of services, each with their own associated costs. Make sure to fully understand the situation as you make your calculations.</li><li>Providers tend to lock in customers via well-integrated services. These may make migration more difficult.</li><li>Make clear inventory of features and functionality your application requires of a managed service. These may or may not match what other cloud providers offer.</li><li>Also make an inventory of the tools and services supporting your organizational processes.</li><li>Take all these inventories into account to calculate your total cost of ownership for any cloud-to-cloud migration.</li><li>Use cloud native technologies to decouple your application and organization from the services offered by a particular cloud provider. This makes migration easier in the future.</li></ul>



<h2>1. Pricing models vary wildly</h2>



<p>Most companies have been hit by that one cloud bill that surprised them. Some services or features wound up costing far more than originally anticipated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Are you considering a cloud-to-cloud migration to reduce operational costs? If so, please take a long and hard look at the various costs in each of the clouds. Because each service has a different cost model, making it very difficult to compare accurately. You really need to get to the bottom of it.</p>



<p>Compute and storage costs are often easy enough to compare, because those are the most obvious two. But what about other services? How much are you spending on, e.g., log handling or monitoring? Good services such as AWS CloudWatch come at a cost, especially if you use it for log handling too (AWS CloudWatch Logs). Are you heavily using a managed database service? A queueing or pub/sub service?</p>



<p>Avoid feeling like that one time the surprise cloud bill hit you in the face by doing your homework this time. You are wiser from the experience, after all.</p>



<p>Network transfers in and out of the cloud can also vary by quite a large amount. The three major providers will give you incoming network traffic for free, but charge you for the outgoing traffic. Smaller, regional, cloud providers will often have higher compute and storage costs, but not charge you for network traffic. Or include a much larger amount of it in a free tier offering.</p>



<p>Overwhelming? I get it. It sure looks that way at first glance! But it doesn’t have to be. My trick is to look at your past few detailed billing statements, and map those costs to your new cloud provider options.</p>



<ul><li><em>Key takeaway: Deeply take all aspects of your current cloud billing into account. Find the differences between offerings, and make a more informed decision.</em></li></ul>



<h2>2. Cloud vendor-specific integrations</h2>



<p>Tell me, did you adopt Kubernetes to make yourself less dependent on cloud providers? Reduce vendor lock-in? Are you now surprised at finding out that you are still locked in, but on a different level?</p>



<p>What I’ve seen is that most organizations will make sure they have highly portable application definitions. By relying on Kubernetes, the application definitions work across cloud providers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what I’ve also seen is that if you are using a managed Kubernetes service, your users and permissions handling is perhaps tied not to Kubernetes role-based access control (RBAC) features, but rather, to cloud-specific offerings. Like AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM). Great service, but ties you to the AWS platform.</p>



<p>Fully-managed Kubernetes services, if offered by cloud vendors themselves, serve to offer a highly integrated experience. The cost of that integration is that migration to another cloud provider becomes just that certain amount more difficult.</p>



<p>As a community, we’ve tried to fix this. But as a community of engineers, those fixes are technical. Kubernetes dictates standards for certain components or aspects. Networking has to work according to the Container Network Interface (CNI) standard. Storage according to Container Storage Interface (CSI). And so on. Great. But the business people have put in much more clever ways of locking you to the platform. This means that other less obvious aspects are more difficult to freely migrate from one cloud to another.</p>



<p>So what is the option? Do you have to manage Kubernetes yourself? No. Of course not. But it may make sense to investigate managed Kubernetes offerings that are not tied to a particular cloud provider to reduce the risk of vendor lock-in. Without having to take on the task of day-to-day operations on your own, of course.</p>



<ul><li><em>Key takeaway: Investigate the ways in which cloud providers make migration more difficult due to incompatible integrations. Choose third-party vendors that are not tied to any particular cloud provider, and can offer their services on top of other cloud providers if need be.</em></li></ul>



<h2>3. The devil is in the (technical) details</h2>



<p>Almost all organizations I’ve talked to say the same thing. They went to the cloud because they wanted to get infrastructure or platform functionality on an as-a-Service basis. That is the whole point of the cloud, is it not?</p>



<p>So, of course, all cloud providers will offer certain services. It used to be just infrastructure as a service (virtual machines, network, and storage) but we are starting to also take, e.g., object storage and queuing services for granted. Many such services will claim to offer an “S3 compatible API” or similar. And that is a great starting point! But beware, because what does such a compatibility claim really mean?&nbsp;</p>



<p>AWS S3, for example, was, until December 2020, merely eventually consistent. Since&nbsp;<a href="https://www.infoq.com/news/2020/12/aws-s3-strong-consistency/">their announcement</a>, it is read-after-write consistent (strong consistency). Which level of consistency would a service that is “S3 compatible” have? The old one? Or the new one? And do you have aspects of your applications that depend on that answer being one or the other? Would you know off-hand?</p>



<p>If you don’t, by the way, you’re in excellent company. Most people’s eyes gloss over when consistency guarantees are discussed. But then again, you don’t want to get bitten by a bug caused by wrongful assumptions, so somebody has to stay awake to figure this stuff out. Hopefully not past midnight!</p>



<p>Ready for another unexciting example? Queuing services, such as AWS SQS, offer certain delivery guarantees. SQS standard queues offer “at least once” guarantees. That means that a message can be delivered to your application more than once, and must have logic in place for dealing with duplicates. An application that is not prepared for this will start showing strange behavior. Especially under heavy load, because that is when the risk for multiple deliveries is higher. This is because high load means there is less time to do housekeeping for the queuing service. (Note that while SQS offers FIFO queues that have “exactly once”&nbsp;<strong>processing</strong>&nbsp;guarantees, however, that&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ably.io/blog/sqs-fifo-queues-message-ordering-and-exactly-once-processing-guaranteed">does not imply exactly once delivery</a>.) So confusing for an application that was coded with assumptions of RabbitMQ’s “at most once” delivery guarantees!</p>



<figure><div>
<blockquote data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Most people's eyes gloss over when consistency guarantees are discussed</p><p>Read the whole article "CTO Headaches: Top 5 cloud-to-cloud migration woes" for more<a href="https://t.co/exLGZu5SZG">https://t.co/exLGZu5SZG</a></p></div>— elastisys (@elastisys) <a href="https://twitter.com/elastisys/status/1358795732132769794?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 8, 2021</a></blockquote>
</div></figure>



<p>The point I am making here is that you must make an inventory of all the cloud services you use, and what features in these are key to your applications working the way they are intended. Because&nbsp;<strong>your</strong>&nbsp;use case is the one that matters.</p>



<p>Cloud providers offer services that make certain trade-offs to ensure the scalability and availability&nbsp;<em>of their service</em>. From the perspective of individual customers and applications, the ideal trade-off choice might have been different. If you use a software such as RabbitMQ, you can configure it perfectly for your use case and requirements. Not the ones of the cloud providers. There are companies that offer managed services in a cloud-agnostic way. Especially on top of Kubernetes, which deserve your consideration.</p>



<ul><li><em>Key takeaway: Make a clear inventory of all cloud services you use, along with the required features of each for your use case. To make a cloud-to-cloud migration easier, start depending on software not tied to any particular provider.</em></li></ul>



<h2>4. Tools supporting your processes (may) change</h2>



<p>Industry wisdom and rule of thumb says that&nbsp;<a href="https://www.econnectivity.se/app-maintenance-cost-can-be-three-times-higher-than-development-cost/">about 70% of software costs</a>&nbsp;are in maintenance. Not development. Just keeping the thing running as intended. How do you address that? My take on it is to rely on smart tools and automation as much as possible. The less your staff has to work on rote menial tasks, the better. Everything they do is a process. So let’s talk about those processes.</p>



<p>Operating your mission-critical cloud application? A bunch of processes. And most, if not all, of these are supported by tools. Continuous integration and deployment, monitoring, notifications and alerting. These are the tools your operations staff is using to analyze and optimize your application deployment.</p>



<p>Great tools like AWS CloudWatch offer insight into monitoring, logging (CloudWatch Logs), and containerized workloads (CloudWatch Container Insights). Your team probably depends on them. But they are specific to a particular cloud vendor.</p>



<p>If you …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.cncf.io/blog/2021/02/15/cto-headaches-top-5-cloud-to-cloud-migration-woes-and-how-to-solve-them/">https://www.cncf.io/blog/2021/02/15/cto-headaches-top-5-cloud-to-cloud-migration-woes-and-how-to-solve-them/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cncf.io/blog/2021/02/15/cto-headaches-top-5-cloud-to-cloud-migration-woes-and-how-to-solve-them/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26163970</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 08:20:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Kill the Alarm Clock (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 108 | Comments 164 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26163691">thread link</a>) | @aminozuur
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Kill_the_alarm_clock | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Kill_the_alarm_clock">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="mw-content-text" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p><small>This text is part of: "<i><a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Science_of_sleep" title="Science of sleep">Science of sleep</a></i>" by <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Piotr_Wozniak" title="Piotr Wozniak">Piotr Wozniak</a> (2017)</small>
</p>


<h2><span id="Kill_the_alarm_clock.21">Kill the alarm clock!</span></h2>
<h3><span id="Alarm_clock_epidemic">Alarm clock epidemic</span></h3>
<p>Few upwardly mobile people in the modern rat-race society can live without an alarm clock. With a shot of strong coffee and round-the-clock stress, most people learn to live and survive with an alarm clock. Half of the population wakes up with an alarm, 9% are woken by a partner, 4% by pets, 3% by children, etc. That leaves a minority that wake up naturally. Increasingly, time becomes the most precious commodity in society where achievement is often associated with speed and perfect time-management. However, alarm clocks introduce harmful side effects: stress, sleep debt, and worst of all, disruption of the natural physiological sleep function. At worst, those factors will result in physical damage to the brain (e.g. such sensitive structures as the hippocampus, your memory switchboard, may literally <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/If_you_do_not_sleep,_you_die!" title="If you do not sleep, you die!">lose neurons as a result of disrupted sleep</a>).
</p><p>The art of time-management makes it possible to live at a high speed with an alarm clock at your side, and still be free from <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Factors_that_affect_sleep#Stress" title="Factors that affect sleep">stress</a>. However, the societal damage inflicted by alarm clocks and <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Sleep_deprivation" title="Sleep deprivation">sleep deprivation</a> is unforgivable. An alarm clock that interrupts your sleep damages your memories, your ability to learn, your creativity, your mood and temper, your relationships with other people, your ability to focus, and your overall intellectual performance!
</p><p>Dr Robert Stickgold has shown that people who learn a skill during the day do not show significant improvement until they get 7-8 hours of good sleep<sup id="cite_ref-stickgold-2005_1-0"><a href="#cite_note-stickgold-2005-1">[1]</a></sup>. There was a noticeable correlation between the degree of improvement and the quality of sleep received. My own work with <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Sleep_habits#SleepChart_in_SuperMemo" title="Sleep habits">SleepChart</a> also shows that the <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Sleep_and_learning#Alarm_clock_vs._learning" title="Sleep and learning">use of alarm clocks can dramatically reduce memory recall and consolidation</a>. Forgetting is so painless that we rarely notice its effects. In a natural way, forgetting will proceed even if you get as much sleep as you need, and it is difficult to point to specific memories lost as a result of not sleeping enough. Moreover, <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Memory_optimization_in_sleep#Neural_optimization_in_sleep" title="Memory optimization in sleep">sleep deprivation may leave your memories intact while their storage will be sub-optimum</a>. The difference may be impossible to spot without measurement. We are more likely to notice sleepiness, reduced mental agility, or bad mood.
</p><p>Disrespect for sleep has reached biblical proportions. This is most noticeable in the US and other highly industrialized nations. <i>Men's Health's</i> Dan Vergano writing for <i>ABC News</i> in <i>"No More Rude Awakenings"</i> suggests a seven-day system for fighting sleepiness: <i>"The secret is to fuel that arousal system so it can <b>beat the pants off the sleep system</b>. By creating the kind of feel-good expectations that trigger hormones to wake the brain, you’ll override the need to sleep and be able to jump out of bed like a man on fire"</i>. The article suggests a "fresh" mind method that capitalizes on the fact that stress hormones help keep you alert. However, the only rational remedy for <i>"rude awakenings"</i> is simple: get enough sleep! Jumping <i>like a man on fire</i> is not likely to have a positive effect on your creative potential!
</p><p>You may often notice that waking up with an alarm clock gives you a jumpstart for the day. You may then come to believe that using the alarm clock might help you stay alert later in the day. This is not the case. The alarm signal simply scares your brain into wakefulness, disrupting the carefully planned process of <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Memory_optimization_in_sleep#Neural_optimization_in_sleep" title="Memory optimization in sleep">neural optimization</a> that occurs in sleep. As a result, you get an immediate injection of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adrenaline">adrenaline</a> and your levels of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ACTH">ACTH</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cortisol">cortisol</a> also increase. This is cortisol that peaks at awakening in natural sleeping rhythm that provides you with the fresh-mind impression. With passing time, this cheaply gained alertness will wear thin unless you continue abusing your physiology with more "remedies". You may use more scare tactics for keeping yourself alert, abuse caffeine, or even get a more profound effect with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modafinil">modafinil</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cocaine">cocaine</a>, or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amphetamines">amphetamines</a>. Alertness should be achieved with the help of sufficient sleep, not despite the lack of sleep! Apart from your reduced ability to learn new things, all unnatural anti-drowsiness methods will produce a great deal of side effects that can be pretty damaging to your health in the long run.
</p><p>All efforts to overcome sleepiness by means other than sleep itself can be likened to a chase of the first high in the use of psychoactive substances. If you drink buckets of coffee, do pushups, pour cold water over your head, or slap your face, you only dip into the last reserves of your alertness hormones that only worsen the effects of deprivation after the effects of the stimulation wear off, which is usually a matter of minutes. Rarely can you get a boost lasting more than an hour, and the more you perk up, the lower you fall in the aftermath.
</p>
<h3><span id="Insomnia_trap">Insomnia trap</span></h3>
<p>If your life without an alarm clock may seem like an impossibility, you will probably need to use all methods in the book to be sure you get enough sleep and minimize the damage. If you need to wake up early at the cost of your brain, avoid the <b><a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Insomnia" title="Insomnia">insomnia trap</a></b>! Insomnia trap is a vicious circle of:
</p>
<ol><li> going to sleep too early to get more sleep,</li>
<li> failing to fall asleep in time (or worse, waking up prematurely),</li>
<li> feeling even more tired on the next day, and</li>
<li> going to sleep even earlier on the next day to catch up with the lost sleep.</li></ol>
<p>It is better to go to sleep at a natural hour (i.e. a bit later), wake up early, suffer a degree of sleep deprivation, and hope for a phase reset that will make it possible to continue on the <a href="http://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2005/05/how-to-become-an-early-riser/">designer schedule</a>. For a solution to the insomnia trap see: <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Curing_DSPS_and_insomnia" title="Curing DSPS and insomnia">Curing DSPS and insomnia</a>.
</p><p>If you cannot reset your phase and still feel tired when getting up early on a regular basis, consider choosing a job that is acceptable for your body, not the other way around. Your long-term health and well-being is at stake. If you absolutely cannot live without an alarm clock, you can at least start from changing your mindset about the importance of sleep and ensure you do not impose wrong habits on your children. Perhaps the young ones will be lucky enough to work in a flex-time system that will make it possible to get sufficient amount of undisturbed sleep. At least, do not set a bad example!
</p>
<h3><span id="Wake_up_the_President">Wake up the President</span></h3>
<p>President Bill Clinton was woken up twice by telephone during the night of April 22, 2000 before the infamous I.N.S. raid on the home of Miami relatives of the young Cuban exile Elian Gonzales. He was probably the most often disrupted and sleep deprived president in history. Only after a heart surgery did Clinton take diet, sleep and (real) exercise seriously. Those interrupted nights would definitely influence his performance and the quality of his decisions! Has anybody thought of a rule: <i>Do not wake up the president?</i> A rule that could only be revoked in a true national emergency? President G. W. Bush (b. 1946) was woken up when an American spy plane landed in China in 2001. He was also woken up after a suicide bombing in Jerusalem in 2002. George H. W. Bush (b. 1924) and Hilary Clinton made "waking up in the middle of the night" part of their presidential campaign and prowess. It seems that only Ronald Reagan had pretty strong rules for protecting his own sleep. He also famously napped during some cabinet meetings. He slept through a couple of international events without an apparent negative impact on his somewhat delayed decision-making. Critics would say he slept through the entire <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iran%E2%80%93Contra_affair">Iran-Contra affair</a>. Was Reagan so protective of sleep because he understood the role of sleep better, or perhaps he was just a bit lazier than other presidents? I don't know. However, he sure set a good example.
</p>
<h3><span id="Alarm_clock_monsters">Alarm clock monsters</span></h3>
<p>Andrea K. wrote to me with skepticism: 
</p>
<blockquote><p><i>"Take the alarm clock away from a typical person and they won't just wake up on their own at their desired time and they will miss work, school, or whatever. An alarm clock can't be that bad for you because of the simple fact that most people use it and I never noticed any problem with them&nbsp;:) Everyone in my family has been using one since they were children, and no one suddenly went crazy or began to mutate into a monster (yet)!"</i></p></blockquote> 
<p>When you use an alarm early in the morning in order to get to work or to school, you cut off the later stages of sleep. If the intrusion into natural sleep is not large (e.g. from minutes to an hour), the damage may be limited and hard to notice. Alarm clock will do far more damage if it cuts deep into the middle of the night sleep. You can compare the use of alarm clocks to smoking or eating hot dogs. The harm is not great enough to be instantly noticeable. It took the public many years to largely accept that "smoking is bad" or "fast food is bad". It is hard to quantify the degree of damage. However, as we move to knowledge society where our intellectual performance becomes increasingly important, the effects of <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Sleep_deprivation" title="Sleep deprivation">sleep deprivation</a> will come under closer scrutiny and alarm clocks are bound to gradually fall out of favor. Unlike hot dogs, they are already universally hated by their users. Most people are able to somewhat adapt their sleep to their schedules if their routines are regular enough. When those people need to resort to the use of the alarm clock, they cut less of their sleep and the damage is proportionally smaller. Nevertheless, we should always strive at eliminating alarm clocks altogether. Most of all, we should protect our kids from suffering interrupted sleep!
</p>
<h2><span id="References">References</span></h2>
<ol>
<li id="cite_note-stickgold-2005-1"><span><a href="#cite_ref-stickgold-2005_1-0">↑</a></span> <span>Stickgold R., "<a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v437/n7063/full/nature04286.html">Sleep-dependent memory consolidation</a>," Nature / Volume 437 (October 27, 2005): 1272-1278</span>
</li>
</ol>

<!-- 
NewPP limit report
Cached time: 20210219073239
Cache expiry: 86400
Dynamic content: false
CPU time usage: 0.031 seconds
Real time usage: 0.035 seconds
Preprocessor visited node count: 56/1000000
Preprocessor generated node count: 158/1000000
Post‐expand include size: 1541/2097152 bytes
Template argument size: 438/2097152 bytes
Highest expansion depth: 4/40
Expensive parser function count: 0/100
-->

<!-- 
Transclusion expansion time report (%,ms,calls,template)
100.00%   14.983      1 - -total
 24.36%    3.650      1 - Template:Excerpt
 18.13%    2.716      1 - ArticleSleep
-->

<!-- Saved in parser cache with key supermem_kool_kids:pcache:idhash:1062-0!*!0!!en!*!* and timestamp 20210219073239 and revision id 14432
 -->
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Kill_the_alarm_clock</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26163691</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 07:28:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Database Inside Your Codebase]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 142 | Comments 82 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26160186">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
<div>
  <article>
    
      <p><img src="https://files.tanagram.app/file/tanagram-data/prod-feifans-blog/joshua-sortino-LqKhnDzSF-8-unsplash.jpg">
      </p>
<p>
Navigating codebases of any meaningful size is difficult. Most of a programmer’s time is spent jumping through the codebase, reading or skimming to build a mental model of the constructs and conventions within it. These constructs — among them: the DSLs, interfaces, and taxonomy of types that exist — are arguably the most important precursor to understanding where and how to make changes. But these constructs only exist in programmers’ heads. It’s difficult or impossible to navigate most codebases through the lens of those constructs; programmers lack “code browsers” that present the underlying code independently of files and the filesystem hierarchy. Yet code browsers that can do so — and we’ll look at some examples below — would be incredibly useful. This is because instances of these constructs can be thought of as records in a database, albeit an ad-hoc, poorly-specified database that can only be queried through carefully-crafted regexes<a href="#fn:1" id="fnref:1" title="see footnote">1</a>.</p>
<p>
In simple cases, some constructs manifest as naming conventions: prefixes in a name may be a rudimentary way to namespace classes<a href="#fn:2" id="fnref:2" title="see footnote">2</a>, while suffixes may be a rudimentary way to group classes or identify their type<a href="#fn:3" id="fnref:3" title="see footnote">3</a>. But these are easy examples; many patterns are much more subtle.</p>
<h2>
“Where is this used?”</h2>
<p>
Imagine figuring out “where is this used?”, for various types of “this”:</p>
<p>
Most code editors (perhaps paired with a <a href="https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/">language server</a>) can show you where local variables are used. This usually also works for finding where methods are invoked — although perhaps less reliably in dynamic-dispatch languages, or languages without types.</p>
<p>
What if you want to find where instances of a particular model get created? There may be multiple ways to create a model, so this isn’t super simple. In Rails, for example, there’s two built-in ways to create a model: you can either call <code>.new</code> to create a new instance in memory followed by <code>.save</code> to persist it to the database, or call <code>.create</code> to automatically do both. Your particular codebase might have additional wrappers for doing this that you’re supposed to use. Even worse, imagine that sometimes you create a <code>.new</code> instance, then set some properties on it over the next few lines, then finally call <code>.save</code>. Something like this:</p>
<pre><code>user = User.new
user.email = '<a href="https://feifan.blog/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection" data-cfemail="e68e838a8a89a6839e878b968a83c885898b">[email&nbsp;protected]</a>' unless self.anonymous?
user.save</code></pre>
<p>
Conceptually, that’s still code that creates an instance of a particular model. But with the intervening syntax, this would be a difficult case to find with <code>grep</code>.</p>
<h2>
Static config</h2>
<p>
At <a href="https://stripe.com/">Stripe</a>, where I work, we have a lot of code for jobs that need to run at certain times each day. For example, we might need to move funds from one financial partner to another at noon UTC each day. Each of these jobs has configuration code describing when and how it should be run, implemented as a <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/mps/concepts/domain-specific-languages/">DSL</a>. This config might look something like this:</p>
<pre><code>run_config RunConfig.new(
  job_name: 'partner-daily-funding',
  env_vars: self.config_env,
  cron: RunConfig::Cron.new(
    schedule: { hour: 12, minute: 0 }
  ),
  owning_team: Company::Team::Liquidity
)</code></pre>
<p>
In our codebase, we have hundreds of these jobs, each with their own <code>run_config</code>. If you look at this codebase as a database, you can imagine these jobs being rows in a <code>jobs</code> table, where the fields on each row correspond to the parameters provided to the <code>RunConfig</code> class. </p>
<p>
Wouldn’t it be great to be able to browse all these jobs in a table? Maybe you could perform some basic operations on this data: searching for specific jobs by name or owning team; sorting by the time-of-day they’re scheduled to run; filtering for jobs owned by your team that have errored in the past week. Maybe you could edit the <code>run_config</code> from that interface (like you might edit a spreadsheet) and have it automatically make the corresponding change in the source code (or open a PR). Maybe you could even compute some aggregations on this data — for example, if you’re introducing a new job that requires some expensive computation, maybe you’d like to know which hours have the fewest other jobs scheduled. And of course, this job browser should be bidirectional with respect to the codebase — there should be a button beside each entry that shows the code for the job inline or opens the corresponding code in your editor.</p>
<h2>
Diffused concepts</h2>
<p>
Codebases typically contain logical concepts that are implemented across multiple pieces of code. This is often the case when you need to create multiple files to implement a particular feature.</p>
<p>
For example, in Rails, a “resource” is collectively implemented across a line in the router, a model file, a controller file, and a bunch of view files. Rails even ships with a code generator to <a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/blob/5f3ff60084ab5d5921ca3499814e4697f8350ee7/railties/lib/rails/generators/rails/resource/USAGE">create some of these files</a> for you. But despite resources being a core concept when working with Rails, there’s no good way to browse the resources in your codebase<a href="#fn:4" id="fnref:4" title="see footnote">4</a>. There’s no good way to filter or query your codebase either — you can’t, for example, see which resources support JSON vs XML params. </p>
<p>
For another example, consider pubsub (aka emitter-consumer) pipelines. In web services, when you have processing that can happen “in the background”, one service will publish an event; another service subscribes to that event and will do the background processing on its own when it receives the event. Often, these will form event “pipelines” or trees where an event consumer will emit additional events that are consumed by yet other services. These pipelines are concepts that developers talk about (as in, the “account creation pipeline” or “funding reconciliation pipeline”), but in most codebases the pipeline itself isn’t declared or reified anywhere in the code.</p>
<p>
If you’re looking at code that emits an event, how do you find the consumers? If you’re lucky, the event has a unique, literal name and the consumer uses that name literally as well. But maybe some subscribers are using wildcard event names, or names generated by string concatenation, and that becomes a lot harder to grep for. Likewise, if you’re looking at a consumer of an event, how do you find the locations in the codebase that could emit that event<a href="#fn:5" id="fnref:5" title="see footnote">5</a>?</p>
<p>
Wouldn’t it be great to be able to browse those pipelines in a table or perhaps a directed graph<a href="#fn:6" id="fnref:6" title="see footnote">6</a>? Maybe that graph would support some basic operations on this data: searching for specific publishers or subscribers by class name or event name; filtering for pipelines that have run into errors; maybe even showing the flow of a particular event given an event ID<a href="#fn:7" id="fnref:7" title="see footnote">7</a>. And of course, this pipeline browser should be bidirectional with respect to the codebase — there should be a button beside each graph node that shows the code for the publisher or subscriber inline or opens the corresponding code in your editor.</p>
<p>
For a final example, consider code that has functionality inherited from elsewhere. Some environments let you see a <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/viewing-structure-of-a-source-file.html">list of inherited properties</a> or methods, but this isn’t possible for more specialized cases. At Stripe, we have code that implements shell scripts that can take command-line arguments and flags. These arguments are defined via a DSL in the implementing code, but these commands can be subclassed, and there’s no way to see what the available arguments are while working in the subclass.</p>
<h2>
Philosophy</h2>
<p>
I think it’s important to consider these problems not as disparate cases in need of bespoke tooling, but as a <em>class</em> of problems characterized by a lack of access to the data structures embedded within codebases. Just like SQL databases and spreadsheets provide a singular querying abstraction and a set of visualization primitives that can be applied to any kind of data, programming environments need a singular querying abstraction and set of visualization primitives that can be applied to the concepts lurking in codebases. Getting there does <em>not</em> mean using proprietary drag-and-drop visual programming interfaces where the introspection capabilities are limited to whatever the programming environment happens to have implemented. Just the opposite — you should still be able to do whatever you want with your code (including treating it as plain-text files), <em>and also</em> have access to more advanced introspection tools that can query and slice your code — tools that let you easily understand and navigate complex codebases to reduce the <em>incidental complexity</em> of building software.</p>
<h2>
Solutions</h2>
<p>
I don’t have a solution to sell you here (at least, not yet!). But <a href="https://twitter.com/hirday_g/status/1356657607381946369">by popular demand</a> I think it’s worthwhile to at least discuss principles that solutions should embody and directionally-related prior art. </p>
<p>
To start with a simple example, see <a href="https://ihp.digitallyinduced.com/">IHP</a>, a full-stack web framework similar to Rails. It comes with a web interface for manipulating your project’s codebase and database schema. <a href="https://youtu.be/UbDtS_mUMpI?t=102">One point in the introduction video</a> showed changes being made in the visual schema editor being automatically reflected in the SQL code that describes the database schema — and changes being made to the SQL code being bidirectionally reflected in the visual schema editor. </p>
<p>
For a more in-depth example, consider <a href="https://pharo.org/">Pharo</a>, a Smalltalk environment. “Environment” in this case means that it feels like you’re using a custom OS (including global menus, idioms, and keyboard and mouse conventions) designed specifically for browsing, writing, and debugging programs in the Smalltalk programming language<a href="#fn:8" id="fnref:8" title="see footnote">8</a>. The holistic integration of these tools is important. Unlike the programming environments we cobble for ourselves today — where the editor is agnostic of the language and runtime and other tools like debuggers, inspectors, and code browsers are tacked on (if they exist at all) — it’s worth thinking about what an entire computing experience <em>for</em> writing and building custom tools might look like<a href="#fn:9" id="fnref:9" title="see footnote">9</a>.</p>
<p>
Pharo is also interesting because of its Class Browser, which looks like this:</p>
<p>
  <img src="https://files.tanagram.app/file/tanagram-data/prod-feifans-blog/database-codebase-pharo-browser.png" alt="Pharo class browser">
</p>
<p>
This browser breaks free from the source code <em>file</em> as the atomic unit of browsing; instead, it allows the user to browse one method at a time. Making the “unit of browsing” …</p></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase">https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://feifan.blog/posts/the-database-inside-your-codebase</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26160186</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 23:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Clubhouse Bio Generator]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 230 | Comments 96 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26159405">thread link</a>) | @ChrisArchitect
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://perchance.org/owh9gelu4t | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://perchance.org/owh9gelu4t">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://perchance.org/owh9gelu4t</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26159405</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 22:11:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Simtel.net MS-DOS Collection]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 130 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26157165">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/index-msdos.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/index-msdos.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><table>
<tbody><tr><th></th><th><a name="0"> - 0 - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/00_info.html">00_info</a></b></td><td>Simtel.Net MS-DOS documentation, indexes</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/00_start.html">00_start</a></b></td><td>Essential info and utilities for beginners</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="4"> - 4 - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/4dos.html">4dos</a></b></td><td>4DOS shell - replacement for COMMAND.COM</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="A"> - A - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ada.html">ada</a></b></td><td>Ada programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ai.html">ai</a></b></td><td>Artificial Intelligence programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/animate.html">animate</a></b></td><td>Animation programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/apl.html">apl</a></b></td><td>The APL mathematics programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/arcers.html">arcers</a></b></td><td>Archiving and compressing programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/arcutils.html">arcutils</a></b></td><td>Utilities for using archives</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/asm_mag.html">asm_mag</a></b></td><td>The Assembly Language 'magazine'</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/asmutl.html">asmutl</a></b></td><td>Assembly language utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/astronmy.html">astronmy</a></b></td><td>Astronomical programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/autocad.html">autocad</a></b></td><td>Programs for Auto-CAD</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="B"> - B - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/basic.html">basic</a></b></td><td>BASIC programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/batchutl.html">batchutl</a></b></td><td>Batch utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bbs.html">bbs</a></b></td><td>BBS systems and support programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bbsdoors.html">bbsdoors</a></b></td><td>BBS 'door' interfaces</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bbslists.html">bbslists</a></b></td><td>BBS lists</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bible.html">bible</a></b></td><td>Bible and searching tools</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/binaryed.html">binaryed</a></b></td><td>Binary file editors</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/biology.html">biology</a></b></td><td>Biology programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/bootutil.html">bootutil</a></b></td><td>Controlling the booting process</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/borland.html">borland</a></b></td><td>Borland product support</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/business.html">business</a></b></td><td>Business-related Programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="C"> - C - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/c.html">c</a></b></td><td>C programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/cad.html">cad</a></b></td><td>Computer Aided Design</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/calculte.html">calculte</a></b></td><td>Calculators for math, finance, etc.</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/catalog.html">catalog</a></b></td><td>Disk catalog utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/cdrom.html">cdrom</a></b></td><td>CD-ROM utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/chemstry.html">chemstry</a></b></td><td>Chemistry programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/clipper.html">clipper</a></b></td><td>Clipper programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/clocks.html">clocks</a></b></td><td>Computer time utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/commprog.html">commprog</a></b></td><td>Terminal and file transfer programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/compress.html">compress</a></b></td><td>Compression utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/cpluspls.html">cpluspls</a></b></td><td>C++ programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/crossasm.html">crossasm</a></b></td><td>Cross-Assemblers</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="D"> - D - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/database.html">database</a></b></td><td>Databases and programs to create them</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/dayo.html">dayo</a></b></td><td>DAYO business and accounting software</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/decode.html">decode</a></b></td><td>Encode/decode binary files to/from text</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/deskaces.html">deskaces</a></b></td><td>Handy Desk-Top utilities and programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/deskpub.html">deskpub</a></b></td><td>Desktop publishing</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/desqview.html">desqview</a></b></td><td>DESQview utilities and programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/dirutl.html">dirutl</a></b></td><td>Directory utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/disasm.html">disasm</a></b></td><td>Disassemblers: Convert executables to ASM</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/diskutil.html">diskutil</a></b></td><td>Disk utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/dv_x.html">dv_x</a></b></td><td>Programs and utilities for DESQview-X</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="E"> - E - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/editor.html">editor</a></b></td><td>Text editors</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/educate.html">educate</a></b></td><td>Programs for education</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/eel.html">eel</a></b></td><td>Epsilon editor EEL extensions</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/electrcl.html">electrcl</a></b></td><td>Electrical engineering programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/emulate.html">emulate</a></b></td><td>Emulators</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/engin.html">engin</a></b></td><td>Engineering Programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/envutil.html">envutil</a></b></td><td>Manipulating environment variables</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/execomp.html">execomp</a></b></td><td>Compress EXE and COM files to save disk space</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="F"> - F - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/fileutil.html">fileutil</a></b></td><td>File management and conversion utils</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/finance.html">finance</a></b></td><td>Financial software</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/flowchrt.html">flowchrt</a></b></td><td>Flowchart Generators</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/foods.html">foods</a></b></td><td>Food recipes</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/forms.html">forms</a></b></td><td>Form Generators and Forms Entry Programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/forth.html">forth</a></b></td><td>Forth programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/fortran.html">fortran</a></b></td><td>FORTRAN programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/fossil.html">fossil</a></b></td><td>FOSSIL drivers and utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/freemacs.html">freemacs</a></b></td><td>Emacs-like editor (small)</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="G"> - G - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/genealgy.html">genealgy</a></b></td><td>Genealogy programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/geogrphy.html">geogrphy</a></b></td><td>Geography programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/geology.html">geology</a></b></td><td>Geology programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/gif.html">gif</a></b></td><td>Programs to make/view/print/convert GIF files</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/graph.html">graph</a></b></td><td>Graphing programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/graphics.html">graphics</a></b></td><td>Graphics programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="H"> - H - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/hamradio.html">hamradio</a></b></td><td>Ham Radio programs and information</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/handicap.html">handicap</a></b></td><td>Programs for the handicapped</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/health.html">health</a></b></td><td>Health, Fitness, and Medical</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/html.html">html</a></b></td><td>HTML Tools</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/hypertxt.html">hypertxt</a></b></td><td>Hyper-Text files and programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="I"> - I - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/imail.html">imail</a></b></td><td>IMAIL FidoNet echomail processor</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/info.html">info</a></b></td><td>Information and documentation files</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/install.html">install</a></b></td><td>Program installation utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/internet.html">internet</a></b></td><td>Programs and utils for use on the Internet</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/io_utils.html">io_utils</a></b></td><td>I/O Utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/irit.html">irit</a></b></td><td>Polygonal solid modeler &amp; C++ source</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="K"> - K - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/keyboard.html">keyboard</a></b></td><td>Keyboard utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="L"> - L - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/lan.html">lan</a></b></td><td>Programs for use on Local Area Networks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/langtutr.html">langtutr</a></b></td><td>Tutorials on foreign languages</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/laser.html">laser</a></b></td><td>Laser printer utilities and fonts</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/legal.html">legal</a></b></td><td>Law-related programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/lingstcs.html">lingstcs</a></b></td><td>Linguistics</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/literatr.html">literatr</a></b></td><td>Teach/learn literature</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="M"> - M - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mailnews.html">mailnews</a></b></td><td>E-mail and Usenet News programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mapping.html">mapping</a></b></td><td>Map programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/math.html">math</a></b></td><td>Mathematics programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mcintosh.html">mcintosh</a></b></td><td>Convert Macintosh files to DOS format</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/memutil.html">memutil</a></b></td><td>Computer memory info and management utils</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/menu.html">menu</a></b></td><td>Creating and using menus</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/microsft.html">microsft</a></b></td><td>Microsoft product support</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/misclang.html">misclang</a></b></td><td>Misc. program languages</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mmedia.html">mmedia</a></b></td><td>Multimedia Programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mormon.html">mormon</a></b></td><td>The Book of Mormon</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/mouse.html">mouse</a></b></td><td>Utilities for the mouse</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/music.html">music</a></b></td><td>Programs for writing and playing music</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/muslum.html">muslum</a></b></td><td>The Holy Book of Muslum</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="N"> - N - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/naplps.html">naplps</a></b></td><td>NAPLPS drawing program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ncsatlnt.html">ncsatlnt</a></b></td><td>NCSA Telnet TCP/IP package</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/nettamer.html">nettamer</a></b></td><td>Net-Tamer DOS PPP dial up access program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/network.html">network</a></b></td><td>Utilities for computer networks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/neurlnet.html">neurlnet</a></b></td><td>Neural Networks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/nfs.html">nfs</a></b></td><td>Network File System utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/notabene.html">notabene</a></b></td><td>Notabene word processor utils</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/novell.html">novell</a></b></td><td>Novell LAN utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="P"> - P - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/packet.html">packet</a></b></td><td>Programs for Packet Radio</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pascal.html">pascal</a></b></td><td>Pascal programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pcboard.html">pcboard</a></b></td><td>PC Board BBS software</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pcmag.html">pcmag</a></b></td><td>'PC Magazine' listings and utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pctech.html">pctech</a></b></td><td>'PC Tech Journal' listings and utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/perl.html">perl</a></b></td><td>Perl programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pgmtips.html">pgmtips</a></b></td><td>Programming Tips &amp; Tricks Magazine</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pgmutl.html">pgmutl</a></b></td><td>Programming utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/pktdrvr.html">pktdrvr</a></b></td><td>TCP/IP/IPX/ODI packet drivers</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/plot.html">plot</a></b></td><td>Programs for plotters</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/postscrp.html">postscrp</a></b></td><td>PostScript view/print utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/printer.html">printer</a></b></td><td>Printer utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/progjorn.html">progjorn</a></b></td><td>Programmers Journal</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/projmgmt.html">projmgmt</a></b></td><td>Project Management programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="Q"> - Q - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/qbasic.html">qbasic</a></b></td><td>Quick BASIC and QBasic programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/qmodem.html">qmodem</a></b></td><td>Qmodem comm program &amp; utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/qtrdeck.html">qtrdeck</a></b></td><td>Quarterdeck utilities and technical notes</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="R"> - R - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ramdisk.html">ramdisk</a></b></td><td>Memory resident disks</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/rbbs.html">rbbs</a></b></td><td>RBBS-PC BBS and support utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/recreatn.html">recreatn</a></b></td><td>Recreation and passtime-related programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="S"> - S - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/satelite.html">satelite</a></b></td><td>Communication satellite programs and listings</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/schedule.html">schedule</a></b></td><td>Schedule automatic program runs (like cron)</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/science.html">science</a></b></td><td>Miscellaneous science related material</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/screen.html">screen</a></b></td><td>Video screen utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/security.html">security</a></b></td><td>Improve computer security</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/semware.html">semware</a></b></td><td>SemWare editors, utilities and support files</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/simulatn.html">simulatn</a></b></td><td>Simulation programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sound.html">sound</a></b></td><td>Computer sound programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sports.html">sports</a></b></td><td>Sports programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/spredsht.html">spredsht</a></b></td><td>Spreadsheet programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/statstcs.html">statstcs</a></b></td><td>Statistics programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/surfmodl.html">surfmodl</a></b></td><td>Surface modeling programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/swap.html">swap</a></b></td><td>Free working memory by swaping to high mem</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sysinfo.html">sysinfo</a></b></td><td>Computer system information display programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/sysutl.html">sysutl</a></b></td><td>System utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="T"> - T - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tcpip.html">tcpip</a></b></td><td>TCP/IP programs (ka9q, etc.)</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/teaching.html">teaching</a></b></td><td>Programs to assist teachers</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/telegard.html">telegard</a></b></td><td>Telegard BBS program &amp; utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/telix.html">telix</a></b></td><td>Telix communications program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/termnate.html">termnate</a></b></td><td>Terminate Terminal/Communications program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tex.html">tex</a></b></td><td>TeX type setting program</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tiff.html">tiff</a></b></td><td>TIFF graphics format programs and information</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/torah.html">torah</a></b></td><td>Torah-related programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/travel.html">travel</a></b></td><td>Travel planning and information</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/tsrutil.html">tsrutil</a></b></td><td>Terminate and stay resident utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbo_c.html">turbo_c</a></b></td><td>Borland Turbo C programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbobas.html">turbobas</a></b></td><td>Borland's Turbo Basic programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbopas.html">turbopas</a></b></td><td>Borland Turbo Pascal programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/turbovis.html">turbovis</a></b></td><td>Turbo Vision programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/txtutl.html">txtutl</a></b></td><td>Text utilities</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="U"> - U - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/ubasic.html">ubasic</a></b></td><td>UBASIC: Ultra high-precision BASIC for math</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/uemacs.html">uemacs</a></b></td><td>MicroEmacs text editor</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/uucp.html">uucp</a></b></td><td>Unix to Unix Copy for MS-DOS</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="V"> - V - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/vga.html">vga</a></b></td><td>VGA monitor utilities</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/virus.html">virus</a></b></td><td>Virus detection and removal programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/visbasic.html">visbasic</a></b></td><td>Visual Basic programming language</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/viscii.html">viscii</a></b></td><td>Vietnamese character programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="W"> - W - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/waffle.html">waffle</a></b></td><td>Waffle bulletin board system</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/weather.html">weather</a></b></td><td>Weather forecasting</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/wordperf.html">wordperf</a></b></td><td>WordPerfect word processing</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/worldmap.html">worldmap</a></b></td><td>A digitized map of the world</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/wwiv.html">wwiv</a></b></td><td>WWIV BBS</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="X"> - X - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/x_10.html">x_10</a></b></td><td>X-10 Powerhouse computer programs</td></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/xwindows.html">xwindows</a></b></td><td>X Windows Server and Support Programs</td></tr>
<tr><th></th><th><a name="Z"> - Z - </a></th></tr>
<tr><td><b><a href="http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/zmodem.html">zmodem</a></b></td><td>Zmodem file transfer protocol</td></tr>
</tbody></table></p></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.lanet.lv/simtel.net/msdos/index-msdos.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26157165</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 18:36:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AirPods as a Platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 127 | Comments 133 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26156881">thread link</a>) | @sc90
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://julian.digital/2020/04/19/airpods-as-a-platform/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://julian.digital/2020/04/19/airpods-as-a-platform/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
 		
<p><span>01</span> Intro</p>



<p>One of the favorite activities of tech analysts, VCs and similar Twitter armchair experts is to predict what the next big technology platform might be.</p>



<p>The usual suspects that come up in these conversations are VR/AR, crypto, smart speakers and similar IoT devices. A new contestant that I’ve <a href="https://twitter.com/BrianNorgard/status/1108755070642880512">seen</a> <a href="https://www.aboveavalon.com/notes/2019/11/19/airpods-are-becoming-a-platform">come up</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/chrismessina/status/1177619897884368904">more</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/HarryStebbings/status/1215425809944543240">frequently</a> in these debates recently are Apple’s AirPods.</p>



<p>Calling AirPods “the next big platform” is interesting because at the moment, they are not even a small platform. They are no platform at all. They are just a piece of hardware. </p>



<p>But that doesn’t mean they can’t become platform.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/platform.png"></p><p><span>02</span> What is a platform?</p>



<p>Let’s first take a look at what a platform actually is.</p>



<p>At its core, a platform is something that others can build on top of. A classic example would be an operating system like iOS: By providing a set of APIs, Apple created a playground for developers to build and run applications on. In fact, new input capabilities such as the touch interface, gyroscope sensor and camera allowed developers to create unique applications that weren’t possible before. </p>



<p>Platforms are subject to network effects: More applications attract more users to the platform, while more users in turn attract more developers who build more apps. </p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/flywheel.png"></p><p>It’s a classic flywheel effect that creates powerful winner-takes-all dynamics. This explains why there are only two (meaningful) mobile operating systems – iOS and Android. </p>



<p>It also explains why everyone is so interested in upcoming platforms – and why Apple might be interested in making AirPods a platform.</p>



<p><span>03</span> Why AirPods aren’t a platform</p>



<p>In their current form, AirPods are not a platform. They don’t provide any unique input or output functionalities that developers could leverage. Active Noise Cancellation and Transparency Mode are neat but not new or Airpods-exclusive features – other headphones offer exactly the same. In either case, developers don’t have any control over them and thus can’t build applications that use these functionalities.</p>



<p>Some say that AirPods will give rise to more audio apps because they are “always in” which in turn will lead to more (and perhaps new forms of) audio content. That might be true – content providers are always looking for <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/01/26/newsletters-and-alternative-trade-routes/">alternative routes</a> to get consumers’ attention – but, again, it does not make AirPods a platform. You can use any other pair of headphones to use these audio apps as well.</p>



<p>If Apple wants to make AirPods a platform, it needs to open up some part of the AirPods experience to developers so that they can build new things on top of it.</p>



<p><span>04</span> On Siri &amp; Voice Platforms</p>



<p>The most obvious choice here is Siri, which is already integrated into every pair of AirPods.</p>



<p>In contrast to other voice assistants like Alexa and Google Assistant, Apple has never really opened up Siri for 3rd-party developers. If they did, it would create a new platform that could have its own ecosystem of apps and developers.</p>



<p>But I’m not convinced that this is Apple’s best option.<br>Let me explain why.</p>



<p>Opening up Siri wouldn’t make AirPods a platform, it would make Siri a platform. This might sound like a technicality, but I think it’s an important difference. As <a href="https://twitter.com/einkoenig">Jan König</a> <a href="https://context-first.com/alexa-please-send-this-to-my-screen-6f4839eb415a">brilliantly summarized in this article</a>, voice isn’t an interface for <em>one</em> device – it’s an interface <em>across</em> devices. It’s more of a meta-layer that should tie different products together to enable multi-device experiences.</p>



<p>This means Apple has little interest in making Siri an AirPods-exclusive. Voice-based computing works best when it’s everywhere. It’s about reach, not exclusivity. This is part of the reason why Google and Amazon excel at it.</p>



<p>At the moment, Siri’s capabilities are considerably behind those of Google Assistant and Alexa. Again, this isn’t overly surprising: Google’s and Amazon’s main job is finding the right answers to users’ questions. The required ML capabilities for a smart assistant are among the core competencies of these two companies.</p>



<p>But even Amazon and Google haven’t really figured out the platform part yet, as indicated by the lack of breakout 3rd-party voice applications. It seems like the two platforms are still looking for their product-market-fit beyond being just cheap speakers that you can also control with your voice.</p>



<p>This is partly because the above-mentioned use case of voice as a cross-device layer isn’t something developers can build with the current set of APIs. </p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/voiceonlyinterfaces-3.png"></p><p>The other big reason I see is that people are mistaking voice as a replacement for other interfaces. Movies like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ne6p6MfLBxc">Her</a> paint a future where human-computer-interaction primarily occurs via voice-powered smart assistants, but in reality, voice isn’t great as a primary or stand-alone interface. It works best as an *additional* input/output channel that augments whatever else you are doing.</p>



<p>Let me give you an example: Saying “Hey Google, turn up the volume” takes 10x longer than simply pressing the volume-up button on your phone. It only makes sense when your hands are busy doing other things (kitchen work, for example).</p>



<p>The most convincing voice app I have seen to date was at a hackathon where a team <a href="https://upsidelab.io/blog/design-voice-user-interface-starcraft/">used the StarCraft API to build voice-enabled game commands</a>. Not to replace your mouse and keyboard but to give you an additional input mechanism. Actual multitasking.</p>



<p><span>05</span> What Apple Should Build</p>



<p>I’m not against Apple opening Siri for developers. On the contrary, given that AirPods are meant to be worn all the time, a voice interface for situations that require multitasking is actually a very good idea. But voice input should remain the exceptional case. And it shouldn’t be what makes AirPods a platform.</p>



<p>Instead of voice, I’d love to see other input mechanisms that allow developers to build new ways for users to interact with the audio content they consume.</p>



<p>Most headsets currently on the market offer the following actions with one (or multiple) clicks of a physical button:</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/earpodsremote-1.png"></p><p>These inputs were invented a long time ago and there has been almost zero innovation since. <strong>Why has no one thought about additional buttons or click mechanisms that allow users to interact with the actual content?</strong></p>



<p>For example, when listening to podcasts I often find myself wanting to bookmark things that are being talked about. It would be amazing if I could simply tap a button on my headphones which would add a timestamp to a bookmarks section of my podcast app. <span>(Or better even, a transcript of the ~15 seconds of content before I pressed the button, which are then also automatically added to my notes app via an Apple Shortcut.)</span></p>



<p>Yes, you could build the same with voice as the input mechanism, but as we discussed earlier, saying <em>“Hey Siri, please bookmark this!”</em> just doesn’t seem very convenient.</p>



<p>While podcast apps might use the additional button as a bookmarking feature, Spotify could make it a Like button to quickly add songs to your Favorites playlist. Other developers could build completely new applications: Think about interactive audiobooks or similar two-way audio experiences, for example. </p>



<p>This is the beauty of platforms: You just provide developers with a set of tools and they will come up with use cases you hadn’t even thought about. Crowdsourced value creation.</p>



<p><span>06</span> Closing Thoughts</p>



<p>(1) The input mechanism I describe doesn’t have to be a physical button. In fact, gesture-based inputs might be even more convenient. If AirPods had built-in accelerometers, users could interact with audio content by nodding or shaking their heads. Radar-based sensors like Google’s Motion Sense could also create an interesting new interaction language for audio content.</p>



<p>(2) You could also think about the Apple Watch as the main input device. In contrast to the AirPods, Apple opened the Watch for developers from the start, but it hasn’t really seen much success as a platform. Perhaps a combination of Watch and AirPods has a better chance of creating an ecosystem with its own unique applications?</p>



<p>(3) One thing to keep in mind is that Apple doesn’t really have an interest in making AirPods a standalone platform. The iPhone (or rather iOS) will always be the core platform that Apple cares about. Instead of separate iPhone, Watch and AirPods ecosystems, think about Apple’s strategy as more of a multi-platform bundle. Even as a platform, AirPods will remain more of an accessory that adds stickiness to the existing iPhone ecosystem.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/fullcycle.png"></p>



<p>Do you have thoughts or feedback on this post?<br>If so, <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1251919017721421827">I’d love to hear it</a>!</p>



<p><span><i>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/einkoenig">Jan König</a> for reading drafts of this post.</i></span>
 	</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://julian.digital/2020/04/19/airpods-as-a-platform/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26156881</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 18:11:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bitcoin’s Overnight Collapse Probability Is About 50%]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 217 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26155158">thread link</a>) | @dgellow
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | http://www.tr0lly.com/bitcoin/bitcoins-overnight-collapse-probability-is-about-50/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.tr0lly.com/bitcoin/bitcoins-overnight-collapse-probability-is-about-50/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">

	<section id="primary">
		<main id="main">

			
<article id="post-1154">
	
	<div>
		
<p>If you ever had a look at <a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/trading/equity-index/us-index/bitcoin_quotes_globex.html">CME’s Bitcoin futures</a>, you might have noticed that there are multiple contracts – one for each month, and that they have different prices. Systematically, the futures contracts for months that are further away, are more expensive than those with closer expiration, and also cheaper than spot. When this happens for a commodity like oil, we’re talking about contango.</p>



<p>This is usually due to the fact that there’s a risk premium on the uncertainty of the future, and it costs a little bit to be sure of the price that you’ll pay for something three months from now. But for futures on financial products, it’s very rare. Currently, the premium for Bitcoin is a whopping 2% per month, and it’s a red warning sign.</p>



<h3>Term structure of Bitcoin futures</h3>



<p>The reason contango for commodities like oil is normal, is that you can’t arbitrage it. The way to arbitrage contango is to buy spot, short the future, wait till expiry, and collect the premium. But you can’t simply “wait” when you buy thousands of barrels of oil – you have to store those barrels somewhere, and it will cost you an arm and a leg. The storage costs will eat up your contango premium, plus some.</p>



<p>There were occurrences in the past where traders were able to arbitrage this premium, but the contango needed to be absolutely off-the-charts (“super-contango”). For instance, after the 2008 financial panic, the spread between spot and futures in the oil market was so big, <a href="https://doc.rero.ch/record/323428/files/TDIBM_Loris_Beltramello.pdf">traders would literally rent tankers and use them as storage facilities</a> for oil, waiting for their futures leg to mature.</p>



<p>The reason contango for financial products isn’t normal, is that you can arbitrage it very easily, as you don’t have storage costs. You buy Bitcoin spot, sell an April future for 4% more than spot, and simply wait two months.</p>



<figure><img src="http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35.png" alt="" srcset="http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35.png 952w, http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35-300x79.png 300w, http://www.tr0lly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Screen-Shot-2021-02-16-at-13.42.35-768x203.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 952px) 100vw, 952px"></figure>



<p>At expiry, you’ll sell your Bitcoin at a certain price, while the future will settle at the exact same price, and you’ll collect the premium. Your only cost is the carry, i.e. the interest you have forfeited on the cash you used to buy Bitcoin, but this is virtually zero today.</p>



<p>Why the premium, then? Why don’t hedge funds with hundreds of billions of dollars to spare don’t arbitrage the Bitcoin contango down to zero?</p>



<h3>Credit risk?</h3>



<p>One quick answer would be that you aren’t guaranteed to close your trade because of counterparty risk. This is what happened when Lehman went bust – all the hedge funds that had OTC derivatives positions with Lehman as one leg of a trade, suddenly saw the “Lehman leg” disappear, while the other leg was still there. Lehman going bust single handedly destroyed the convertible bonds market, as hedge funds who had bought convertible bonds and hedged their risks (credit, volatility, equity risks – you name it) with Lehman, suddenly were out of hedges, and had to sell their cash position (their convertible bonds) at literally any price.</p>



<p>But there is no counterparty risk here. You can’t lose your Bitcoins – you just keep them on chain, and no exchange going bust will affect your position. CME can’t go bust – it has margin calls, initial margin deposits, has a guarantee fund, and is almost explicitly guaranteed by the Fed because of its critical importance to financial markets.</p>



<p>So, again, why is nobody picking those hundred dollar bills lying on the street?</p>



<h3>Systemic risk</h3>



<p>There is one risk that you can’t edge – that of the world collapsing overnight, when there’s nobody left to pay you even if you win your bet. Imagine shorting USDT on Binance. What happens if you’re right and USDT goes to zero? Do you really think Binance will still be around to pay you?</p>



<p>You can always say, “bah, I’ll see it coming, the moment shit starts to hit the fan, I’ll close my positions”. But what if you don’t have the time to do so? What if a black swan event happens overnight?</p>



<p>This is the risk with Bitcoin. A whim from regulators, like passing the STABLE act, and all USDT exchanges go bust. What will happen to Bitcoin futures then? CME uses the “<a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/trading/cryptocurrency-indices.html">Bitcoin Reference Rate</a>” (BRR) to calculate the spot for its Bitcoin futures, which is a weighted average of the spots taken from multiple crypto exchanges, the list of which changes over time. What happens if the Bitcoin ecosystem collapses, the prices of Bitcoin on half of those exchanges go to 100,000 on paper because those exchanges become insolvent and people rush for the exits by buying Bitcoin to try and send it to their own wallets (as happened with MtGox)? Futures skyrocket because of a technicality, CME is slow to react, and you get wiped out on your “short futures” leg – while you can’t really sell the “long Bitcoin” leg either, because every exchange is on fire and nobody processes redemption requests.</p>



<h3>Implied probability of default</h3>



<p>This risk is rewarded handsomely – a big fat 2% per month. With interest rates at zero, we can borrow a formula from the Credit Default Swaps market to calculate the <a href="https://quant.stackexchange.com/questions/15986/how-to-compute-the-implied-probability-of-default-from-a-cds-spread#:~:text=Risk%2Dneutral%20default%20probability%20implied,R%20is%20the%20recovery%20rate.&amp;text=Hulls%20equation%20is%20a%20gross,works%20for%20all%20tenor%20points.">implied probability of default</a>, which we’ll <a href="http://nzz-files-prod.s3-website-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/files/4/1/2/cds+deutsche+bank+161214_1.18446412.pdf">simplify to the extreme</a>:</p>



<p><strong>p = S/(1-R)</strong></p>



<p>Where p is the probability of default, S the annual “swap rate” that compensates for that probability, and R the recovery rate, i.e. how much you can expect to recoup from your investment if a default occurs.</p>



<p>In our case, S = 24% (12 months in a year, at 2% for each month), and R ≈ 50% based on what happened after MtGox collapsed. This means that we assume you’ll be able to cash out in the event of an apocalypse with an average 50% loss. Remember, this is assuming that you are hedged!</p>



<p>This gives us an implied probability of default p ≈ 50% over the next year. Again, that’s the probability of the whole Bitcoin ecosystem collapsing overnight, not giving you the time to close your positions, cutting you off from exchanges, and where CME futures no longer trade.</p>



<p>This is the risk as it’s being priced by the market, on relatively liquid financial instruments. So the next time someone tries to explain to you that “Bitcoin is a store of value”, when the chances of it getting utterly destroyed overnight before the year is over are around 50/50, try not to shoot coffee through your nose laughing.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->

			
</article><!-- #post-${ID} -->

	<nav role="navigation">
		<h2>Post navigation</h2>
		
	</nav>
<!-- #comments -->

		</main><!-- #main -->
	</section><!-- #primary -->


	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.tr0lly.com/bitcoin/bitcoins-overnight-collapse-probability-is-about-50/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26155158</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 16:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Computers Aren't Fun Anymore (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26154754">thread link</a>) | @hacksilver
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://feifan.blog/posts/computers-arent-fun-anymore | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://feifan.blog/posts/computers-arent-fun-anymore">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
<div>
  <article>
    
      <p><img src="https://files.tanagram.app/file/tanagram-data/prod-feifans-blog/penny-farthing.jpeg">
      </p>
<p>
Throughout <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dream-Machine-M-Mitchell-Waldrop/dp/1732265119"><em>The Dream Machine</em></a>, a history of the early days of computing, tinkering and having fun was a recurring theme throughout the decades. I wasn’t around to experience the early days of computers myself, but they seemed to be genuinely exciting and rewarding. In the words of MIT sociologist Sherry Turkle: computers empowered their users, making them feel smart[er], “in control”, and “more fully participant in the future”. </p>
<p>
Those feel like odd descriptions for the modern computing experience. Using computers today doesn’t feel like￼ an empowering experience￼. Sometimes it’s mindless and distracting. Sometimes, when a redesign rolls out, or laptop doesn’t wake from sleep mode,￼ it’s downright hostile. The experience of using a computer in 2020 is a concoction of data silos, dinging notifications and reinvented wheels, presented in gratuitously bubble-wrapped UIs hyper-optimized by persnickety product managers and soulless A/B tests. </p>
<p>
For most people, the computing experience is <a href="https://feifan.blog/2020/06/22/no-one-cares-about-software-quality/">clicking around a lot</a>, typing into disparate apps in which your data is trapped except through narrowly-defined, bespoke integrations, and struggling to find <em>that thing you were just reading a few days ago</em> among all the silos. This doesn’t make anyone feel smarter or more in control. It’s simply frustrating.</p>
<p>
Software <em>development</em> is stuck in the doldrums too. A massive amount of cumulative engineering effort is spent rebuilding the same primitives<a href="#fn:1" id="fnref:1" title="see footnote">1</a> because the software engineering industry hasn’t convincingly developed platforms at higher levels of abstraction<a href="#fn:2" id="fnref:2" title="see footnote">2</a>. A significant portion of development effort goes to placating not-invented-here-ness, where companies feel the need to build their own version of every feature, each slightly different (user familiarity be damned). A lot of software is little more than looking up API documentation and plugging one into another. There’s a dearth of creativity, of joy and discovery, of inventing something interesting and new. </p>
<p>
To be fair, computers — both the desktop kind and various mobile kinds — enable<a href="#fn:3" id="fnref:3" title="see footnote">3</a> seemingly-impossible<a href="#fn:4" id="fnref:4" title="see footnote">4</a> things<a href="#fn:5" id="fnref:5" title="see footnote">5</a>. But it feels frustrating to see the pioneering spirit that originally led to the development of modern computers giving way to uninspired flat interfaces<a href="#fn:6" id="fnref:6" title="see footnote">6</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete">CRUD</a> SaaS apps. The things you can do are limited to bespokely-implemented features, dribbled out only as fast as a small team of designers and developers can think of and build them. Of course you have an extensive list of things you <em>wish</em> your phone/computer/most-used apps could do; everyone does. You know the majority of it will remain a wishlist; there’s almost no hope of the feature you really want being implemented<a href="#fn:7" id="fnref:7" title="see footnote">7</a>. This isn’t empowering. What’s more, new features tend to be one-off improvements and ungainly new ways for you to do more work<a href="#fn:8" id="fnref:8" title="see footnote">8</a> rather than adding or improving functionality in a generalized way so you can remix functionality and do things faster.</p>
<p>
For the people who’ve figured out the right incantations to type and buttons-buried-in-submenus to click, computers can automate administrivia, surface information, and make them feel “more fully participant in the future”. But getting there is an arduous journey, and many people get in a place where computers just make things harder. The experience of using computers is, in various ways, awkward and frustrating (and maybe even dangerous<a href="#fn:9" id="fnref:9" title="see footnote">9</a>) for everyone. Computers were supposed to be bicycles for the mind. So far we only have penny-farthings.</p>

  </article>
</div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://feifan.blog/posts/computers-arent-fun-anymore</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26154754</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 15:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Is Esbuild Fast?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 314 | Comments 165 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26154509">thread link</a>) | @mef
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      <p>This is a collection of common questions about esbuild. You can also ask questions on the <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues">GitHub issue tracker</a>.</p>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="#why-is-esbuild-fast">Why is esbuild fast?</a></li>
        <li><a href="#benchmark-details">Benchmark details</a></li>
        <li><a href="#upcoming-roadmap">Upcoming roadmap</a></li>
        <li><a href="#production-readiness">Production readiness</a></li>
      </ul>
      <h2 id="why-is-esbuild-fast">
        <a href="#why-is-esbuild-fast">#</a>
        Why is esbuild fast?
      </h2>
      <p>Several reasons:</p>
      <ul><li><p> It's written in <a href="https://golang.org/">Go</a> and compiles to native code. </p> <p> Most other bundlers are written in JavaScript, but a command-line application is a worst-case performance situation for a JIT-compiled language. Every time you run your bundler, the JavaScript VM is seeing your bundler's code for the first time without any optimization hints. While esbuild is busy parsing your JavaScript, node is busy parsing your bundler's JavaScript. By the time node has finished parsing your bundler's code, esbuild might have already exited and your bundler hasn't even started bundling yet. </p> <p> In addition, Go is designed from the core for parallelism while JavaScript is not. Go has shared memory between threads while JavaScript has to serialize data between threads. Both Go and JavaScript have parallel garbage collectors, but Go's heap is shared between all threads while JavaScript has a separate heap per JavaScript thread. This seems to cut the amount of parallelism that's possible with JavaScript worker threads in half <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/111#issuecomment-719910381">according to my testing</a>, presumably since half of your CPU cores are busy collecting garbage for the other half. </p></li><li><p> Parallelism is used heavily. </p> <p> The algorithms inside esbuild are carefully designed to fully saturate all available CPU cores when possible. There are roughly three phases: parsing, linking, and code generation. Parsing and code generation are most of the work and are fully parallelizable (linking is an inherently serial task for the most part). Since all threads share memory, work can easily be shared when bundling different entry points that import the same JavaScript libraries. Most modern computers have many cores so parallelism is a big win. </p></li><li><p> Everything in esbuild is written from scratch. </p> <p> There are a lot of performance benefits with writing everything yourself instead of using 3rd-party libraries. You can have performance in mind from the beginning, you can make sure everything uses consistent data structures to avoid expensive conversions, and you can make wide architectural changes whenever necessary. The drawback is of course that it's a lot of work. </p> <p> For example, many bundlers use the official TypeScript compiler as a parser. But it was built to serve the goals of the TypeScript compiler team and they do not have performance as a top priority. Their code makes pretty heavy use of <a href="https://mrale.ph/blog/2015/01/11/whats-up-with-monomorphism.html">megamorphic object shapes</a> and unnecessary <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/TypeScript/issues/39247">dynamic property accesses</a> (both well-known JavaScript speed bumps). And the TypeScript parser appears to still run the type checker even when type checking is disabled. None of these are an issue with esbuild's custom TypeScript parser. </p></li><li><p> Memory is used efficiently. </p> <p> Compilers are ideally mostly O(n) complexity in the length of the input. So if you are processing a lot of data, memory access speed is likely going to heavily affect performance. The fewer passes you have to make over your data (and also the fewer different representations you need to transform your data into), the faster your compiler will go. </p> <p> For example, esbuild only touches the whole JavaScript AST three times: </p> <ol> <li>A pass for lexing, parsing, scope setup, and declaring symbols</li> <li>A pass for binding symbols, minifying syntax, JSX/TS to JS, and ESNext-to-ES2015</li> <li>A pass for minifying identifiers, minifying whitespace, generating code, and generating source maps</li> </ol> <p> This maximizes reuse of AST data while it's still hot in the CPU cache. Other bundlers do these steps in separate passes instead of interleaving them. They may also convert between data representations to glue multiple libraries together (e.g. string→TS→JS→string, then string→JS→older JS→string, then string→JS→minified JS→string) which uses more memory and slows things down. </p> <p> Another benefit of Go is that it can store things as compactly in memory, which enables it to use less memory and fit more in the CPU cache. All object fields have types and fields are packed tightly together so e.g. several boolean flags only take one byte each. Go also has value semantics and can embed one object directly in another so it comes "for free" without another allocation. JavaScript doesn't have these features and also has other drawbacks such as JIT overhead (e.g. hidden class slots) and inefficient representations (e.g. non-integer numbers are heap-allocated with pointers). </p></li></ul>
      <p>Each one of these factors is only a somewhat significant speedup, but together they can result in a bundler that is multiple orders of magnitude faster than other bundlers commonly in use today.</p>
      <h2 id="benchmark-details">
        <a href="#benchmark-details">#</a>
        Benchmark details
      </h2>
      <p>Here are the details about each benchmark:</p>
      <figcaption>JavaScript benchmark</figcaption>
      <figure>
        <div>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <p>0.37s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>1.54s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>36.00s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>41.91s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>54.50s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>56.71s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>118.51s</p>
          <p>0s</p>
          <p>30s</p>
          <p>60s</p>
          <p>90s</p>
          <p>120s</p>
        </div>
      </figure>
      <p>This benchmark approximates a large JavaScript codebase by duplicating the <a href="https://github.com/mrdoob/three.js">three.js</a> library 10 times and building a single bundle from scratch, without any caches. The benchmark can be run with <code>make bench-three</code> in the <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild">esbuild repo</a>.</p>
      <table>
      <thead>
      <tr>
      <th>Bundler</th>
      <th>Time</th>
      <th>Relative slowdown</th>
      <th>Absolute speed</th>
      <th>Output size</th>
      </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild</td>
      <td>0.37s</td>
      <td>1x</td>
      <td>1479.6 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.80mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild (1 thread)</td>
      <td>1.54s</td>
      <td>4x</td>
      <td>355.5 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.80mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>rollup + terser</td>
      <td>36.00s</td>
      <td>97x</td>
      <td>15.2 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.81mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 4</td>
      <td>41.91s</td>
      <td>113x</td>
      <td>13.1 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.97mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 5</td>
      <td>54.50s</td>
      <td>147x</td>
      <td>10.0 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.84mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 2</td>
      <td>56.71s</td>
      <td>153x</td>
      <td>9.7 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.92mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 1</td>
      <td>118.51s</td>
      <td>320x</td>
      <td>4.6 kloc/s</td>
      <td>5.89mb</td>
      </tr>
      </tbody>
      </table>
      <p>Each time reported is the best of three runs. I'm running esbuild with <code>--bundle <wbr>--minify <wbr>--sourcemap</code> (the single-threaded version uses <code>GOMAXPROCS=1</code>). I used the <code>rollup-<wbr>plugin-<wbr>terser</code> plugin because Rollup itself doesn't support minification. Webpack uses <code>--mode=<wbr>production <wbr>--devtool=<wbr>sourcemap</code>. Parcel uses the default options. Absolute speed is based on the total line count including comments and blank lines, which is currently 547,441. The tests were done on a 6-core 2019 MacBook Pro with 16gb of RAM.</p>
      <p>Caveats:</p>
      <ul><li>Parcel 1: The bundle crashes at run time with <code>TypeError: <wbr>Cannot <wbr>redefine <wbr>property: <wbr>dynamic</code></li></ul>
      <figcaption>TypeScript benchmark</figcaption>
      <figure>
        <div>
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          
          <p>0.09s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>0.37s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>18.38s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>18.76s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>25.12s</p>
          
          
          
          <p>42.32s</p>
          <p>0s</p>
          <p>10s</p>
          <p>20s</p>
          <p>30s</p>
          <p>40s</p>
        </div>
      </figure>
      <p>This benchmark uses the <a href="https://github.com/facebookexperimental/rome">Rome</a> build tool to approximate a large TypeScript codebase. All code must be combined into a single minified bundle with source maps and the resulting bundle must work correctly. The benchmark can be run with <code>make bench-rome</code> in the <a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild">esbuild repo</a>.</p>
      <table>
      <thead>
      <tr>
      <th>Bundler</th>
      <th>Time</th>
      <th>Relative slowdown</th>
      <th>Absolute speed</th>
      <th>Output size</th>
      </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild</td>
      <td>0.09s</td>
      <td>1x</td>
      <td>1464.8 kloc/s</td>
      <td>0.97mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>esbuild (1 thread)</td>
      <td>0.37s</td>
      <td>4x</td>
      <td>356.3 kloc/s</td>
      <td>0.97mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 4</td>
      <td>18.38s</td>
      <td>204x</td>
      <td>7.2 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.26mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 1</td>
      <td>18.76s</td>
      <td>208x</td>
      <td>7.0 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.56mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>webpack 5</td>
      <td>24.57s</td>
      <td>273x</td>
      <td>5.4 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.26mb</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
      <td>parcel 2</td>
      <td>42.32s</td>
      <td>470x</td>
      <td>3.1 kloc/s</td>
      <td>1.68mb</td>
      </tr>
      </tbody>
      </table>
      <p>Each time reported is the best of three runs. I'm running esbuild with <code>--bundle <wbr>--minify <wbr>--sourcemap <wbr>--platform=<wbr>node</code> (the single-threaded version uses <code>GOMAXPROCS=1</code>). Webpack uses <code>ts-loader</code> with <code>transpileOnly: <wbr>true</code> and <code>--mode=<wbr>production <wbr>--devtool=<wbr>sourcemap</code>. Parcel 1 uses <code>--target <wbr>node --bundle-<wbr>node-<wbr>modules</code>. Parcel 2 uses <code>"engines": <wbr>"node"</code> in <code>package.json</code> and needs the <code>@parcel/<wbr>transformer-<wbr>typescript-<wbr>tsc</code> transformer to be able to handle the TypeScript code used in the benchmark. Absolute speed is based on the total line count including comments and blank lines, which is currently 131,836. The tests were done on a 6-core 2019 MacBook Pro with 16gb of RAM.</p>
      <p>The results don't include Rollup because I couldn't get it to work. I tried <code>rollup-<wbr>plugin-<wbr>typescript</code>, <code>@rollup/<wbr>plugin-<wbr>typescript</code>, and <code>@rollup/<wbr>plugin-<wbr>sucrase</code> and they all didn't work for different reasons relating to TypeScript compilation.</p>
      <h2 id="upcoming-roadmap">
        <a href="#upcoming-roadmap">#</a>
        Upcoming roadmap
      </h2>
      <p>These features are already in progress and are first priority:</p>
      <ul><li>Code splitting (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/16">#16</a>, <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/api/#splitting">docs</a>)</li><li>CSS content type (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/20">#20</a>, <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/content-types/#css">docs</a>)</li><li>Plugin API (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/111">#111</a>)</li></ul>
      <p>These are potential future features but may not happen or may happen to a more limited extent:</p>
      <ul><li>HTML content type (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/31">#31</a>)</li><li>Lowering to ES5 (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/297">#297</a>)</li><li>Bundling top-level await (<a href="https://github.com/evanw/esbuild/issues/253">#253</a>)</li></ul>
      <p>After that point, I will consider esbuild to be relatively complete. I'm planning for esbuild to reach a mostly stable state and then stop accumulating more features. This will involve saying "no" to requests for adding major features to esbuild itself. I don't think esbuild should become an all-in-one solution for all frontend needs. In particular, I want to avoid the pain and problems of the "webpack config" model where the underlying tool is too flexible and usability suffers.</p>
      <p>For example, I am <em>not</em> planning to include these features in esbuild's core itself:</p>
      <ul><li>Support for other frontend languages (e.g. <a href="https://elm-lang.org/">Elm</a>, <a href="https://svelte.dev/">Svelte</a>, <a href="https://vuejs.org/">Vue</a>, <a href="https://angular.io/">Angular</a>)</li><li>TypeScript type checking (just run <code>tsc</code> separately)</li><li>An API for custom AST manipulation</li><li>Hot-module reloading</li><li>Module federation</li></ul>
      <p>I hope that the extensibility points I'm adding to esbuild (<a href="https://esbuild.github.io/plugins/">plugins</a> and the <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/api/">API</a>) will make esbuild useful to include as part of more customized build workflows, but I'm not intending or expecting these extensibility points to cover all use cases. If you have very custom requirements then you should be using …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast">https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://esbuild.github.io/faq/#why-is-esbuild-fast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26154509</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 15:07:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Behold z, the unsung jewel that rethinks shell navigation]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 66 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26153401">thread link</a>) | @aymericbeaumet
<br/>
February 16, 2021 | https://aymericbeaumet.com/behold-z-the-unsung-jewel-that-rethinks-shell-navigation | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://aymericbeaumet.com/behold-z-the-unsung-jewel-that-rethinks-shell-navigation">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
<div>
<article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

<div itemprop="articleBody">
<p>I spend a fair amount of time wandering around in the terminal. The chances
are that you are too since you dared to open this story. My daily activities
led me to contribute to various kinds of projects (professional, personal and
open-source). For my sanity, I tend to follow strict rules to organize my
workspace, which helps me keep things tidied up and easily reachable. Or so I
thought.</p>
<p>I decided to arrange my projects by following the <a href="https://golang.org/doc/code.html#Workspaces">Go
philosophy</a>: make the
arborescence mirrors the urls where they are reachable. e.g.,
<code>~/Workspace/src/github.com/aymericbeaumet/dotfiles</code> would contain the
project <a href="https://github.com/aymericbeaumet/dotfiles">dotfiles</a> owned by
<a href="https://github.com/aymericbeaumet">@aymericbeaumet</a> and accessible at
<a href="https://github.com/">github.com</a>. That’s great, but I am now facing a complex
directory structure tedious to navigate quickly. Making it, in the end,
harder to access the resources I need.</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>pwd</span>
/Users/aymericbeaumet/Workspace/src/github.com/brigad/back-end
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Nobody wants to manually deal with this.</em></p>
<p>Remembering and typing the location of each project (even while leveraging
autocomplete) is time-consuming. Creating shell aliases is not scalable.
Instead, I would like to rely on the pseudo-unicity of each project name to
find it among all the directories on my computer.</p>
<h2 id="z">z?</h2>
<p>Several tools exist to tackle this problem. My favorite is
<a href="https://github.com/rupa/z"><em>z</em></a>. It follows the Unix philosophy by being
small, focused and interoperable. <em>z</em> allows jumping around swiftly,
automatically learning from your habits. The entries are ranked based on the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frecency">frecency</a> at which you access the
directories.</p>
<p>Let’s walk through the basics of this tool. Below is how I advise to install
it for Zsh on macOS (the install process should be similar for other shells
and operating systems):</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>brew <span>install </span>z
<span>$ </span><span>echo</span> <span>"source '</span><span>$(</span>brew <span>--prefix</span> z<span>)</span><span>/etc/profile.d/z.sh'"</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> ~/.zshenv
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Install z for Zsh on macOS.</em></p>
<p>Note how installing <em>z</em> is not enough to start using it. You have to source
<code>z.sh</code> at the beginning of each shell session to activate it. The <code>~/.zshenv</code>
configuration file is appropriate as Zsh <a href="http://zsh.sourceforge.net/Intro/intro_3.html">loads it in most
circumstances</a>, making the
tool accessible in a wide-variety of contexts (terminals, editors, IDEs,
scripts, etc.).</p>
<h2 id="lets-play">Let’s play</h2>
<p>Once the install and setup are complete: start a new shell session, <code>cd</code>
through some folders and execute <code>z</code> to confirm it has been accurately
tracking your activity:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>z | <span>sort</span> <span>-rn</span> | <span>head</span> <span>-3</span>
5331.72    /Users/aymericbeaumet/Workspace/src/github.com/brigad/back-end
637.255    /Users/aymericbeaumet/Workspace/src/github.com/brigad/ops
386.198 /Users/aymericbeaumet/.config/dotfiles
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Top 3 directories based on frecency.</em></p>
<p>As shown above, I spend quite some time navigating through
<a href="https://github.com/brigad">Brigad</a> projects, but it seems I also often
access my <a href="https://github.com/aymericbeaumet/dotfiles">dotfiles</a> to tweak
some configuration. The ranking score is volatile, and one could observe
significant changes in a brief amount of time.</p>
<p>Now that <em>z</em> has accumulated some knowledge try it by navigating to one of
the tracked folders. Navigating is as simple as executing the <code>z</code> command
followed by the directory name:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>z dotfiles
<span>$ </span><span>pwd</span>
/Users/aymericbeaumet/.config/dotfiles
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Navigating by matching with a whole directory name.</em></p>
<p>As a matter of facts, I do prefer to leverage partial matching (imagine <code>**</code>
surrounding your search pattern) to type fewer characters. Hence, <code>z dot</code> is
valid and should produce a similar behavior as <code>z dotfiles</code> (modulo possible
name collisions, but you get the idea). This works because <em>z</em> relies on
regular expressions. For example, the snippet below will navigate to the
directory ending with the letters “tmp” (with the highest score):</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>z tmp<span>$</span>
<span>$ </span><span>pwd</span>
/private/tmp
</code></pre></div></div>
<p><em>Navigating by matching with a regular expression.</em></p>
<p>Neat right? I guess you start seeing the possibilities of this tool. And we
have only scratched the surface of its capabilities. I suggest you dive in
its <a href="https://github.com/rupa/z/blob/master/README">documentation</a> to get an
idea of its full potential. Features such as autocomplete, subdirectories
matching, consecutive matching, etc. are a game changer.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p><em>z</em> is tremendous. This tool saves me a non-trivial amount of time every
single day. When one starts relying on it, there is no going back. And I hope
it’s going to fit your workflow as well as mine.</p>
<p>I would be grateful to hear any of your time-saving tricks. Feel free to
share your experiences!</p>
</div>


</article>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://aymericbeaumet.com/behold-z-the-unsung-jewel-that-rethinks-shell-navigation</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26153401</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 12:54:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[US Presidential Election $25k Database Bounty Review]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 144 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26149511">thread link</a>) | @mjangle1985
<br/>
February 15, 2021 | https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-02-15-election-bounty-review/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-02-15-election-bounty-review/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-cy="blog-post-text"><p>On December 14, we launched <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-12-16-data-bounties/">our first data bounty</a> to <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2020-12-14-make-money-data-wrangling/">earn a share of $25,000 by wrangling US Presidential Precinct-level data</a>. The bounty ended yesterday. How did it go? This blog entry will answer that question.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.doltdb.com/">Dolt</a> is a SQL database with Git-style versioning. It's the first SQL database you can branch and merge. <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/">DoltHub</a> is a place on the internet to share and collaborate on Dolt databases. Without both, data bounties would not be possible.</p>

<p>We built the <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results">best open database of US Precinct-level Election results</a> on the internet. </p>
<p>Here's some statistics:</p>
<ul>
<li>15.5M cells edited. 1.7GB of data collected</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+COUNT%28distinct%28state%29%29%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2016%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">All 51 "states" covered for 2016</a>. <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+COUNT%28distinct%28state%29%29%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2020%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">38 states covered for 2020</a>. </li>
<li><a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+sum%28votes%29%2F136669276%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2016%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">100% of the vote covered for 2016</a>. <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/repositories/dolthub/us-president-precinct-results/query/master?q=SELECT+sum%28votes%29%2F159633396%0AFROM+%60vote_tallies%60+where+election_year%3D2020%0ALIMIT+200%3B%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A%0A&amp;active=Tables">78% for 2020</a>.</li>
<li>75 Pull Requests (PRs) accepted across 6 bounty participants. </li>
<li>Top bounty participant earned over $10,000.</li>
</ul>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/0fcea/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Final Scoreboard" title="Final Scoreboard" src="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/0fcea/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png" srcset="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/a48b3/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png 214w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/47730/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png 428w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/4e02e3f4498d3a6b5bc56bd9f85cad81/0fcea/first-bounty-final-scoreboard.png 851w" sizes="(max-width: 851px) 100vw, 851px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>We're very excited to mail the checks to all the folks who worked hard to make this bounty a success.</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/2ad33/fat-check.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Fat Check" title="Fat Check" src="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/79a4e/fat-check.jpg" srcset="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/606a2/fat-check.jpg 214w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/65a3f/fat-check.jpg 428w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/79a4e/fat-check.jpg 856w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/99aeb/fat-check.jpg 1284w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/e88f6/fat-check.jpg 1712w,
https://www.dolthub.com/blog/static/9791bedbcbd3ed06e15435f17a7ff195/2ad33/fat-check.jpg 3851w" sizes="(max-width: 856px) 100vw, 856px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>

<p>Now that the bounty is complete, we must figure out what to do with this data. How do we get the most out of our investment in the data?</p>
<h2>Clean up the data we got</h2>
<p>Given the heavily keyed nature of this data, we decided early on to not accept PRs for standardization or normalization of things like party names. Because most columns are part of the primary key, any change looks like a deletion and corresponding addition to Dolt. Thus, changes like that give the corrector credit for the whole row in the bounty instead of just the cell he or she changed. We queued up a number of these types of changes and we'll execute them now that the bounty is over.</p>
<h2>Find some users</h2>
<p>We collected the best US presidential Precinct level results on the internet. Now, we want people to use it. We think potentially the data is good enough that an open data community could be bootstrapped around it. The people who use it would have incentive to finish it as new state level data is released. We will reach out to the people at <a href="http://openelections.net/">Open Elections</a> and <a href="https://electionlab.mit.edu/">MIT Elections Lab</a> and start a conversation. If you know anyone else who could use this data, <a href="https://discord.com/invite/RFwfYpu">come let us know in our Discord</a>.</p>
<h2>Run another bounty?</h2>
<p>We're still missing 12 states and about 22% of the vote from 2020. If we want to get complete data and an open data community can't be bootstrapped, we may run another bounty in a couple months to finish the dataset. Let us know if you'd be interested in another bounty or the complete dataset.</p>

<p>We think <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/bounties">DoltHub Bounties</a> may be the fastest, cheapest way to build databases from open data. For $25,000 and 8 weeks, we were able to assemble a 1.7GB database of election results. </p>
<p>Our plan is to run at least one bounty per month for the rest of the year across a number of distinct data disciplines. We're running a <a href="https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-01-14-hopsital-prices-bounty/">hospital price transparency bounty</a> right now. We'll be launching two more over the next month or so. Hang out in <a href="https://discord.com/invite/RFwfYpu">our Discord</a> to keep up to date. Start wrangling data as your new side hustle.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dolthub.com/blog/2021-02-15-election-bounty-review/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26149511</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:20:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Building Rich Terminal Dashboards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 489 | Comments 117 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26149488">thread link</a>) | @lumpa
<br/>
February 15, 2021 | https://www.willmcgugan.com/blog/tech/post/building-rich-terminal-dashboards/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.willmcgugan.com/blog/tech/post/building-rich-terminal-dashboards/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    

    
<p><a href="https://github.com/willmcgugan/rich">Rich</a> has become a popular (20K stars on GH) way of beautifying CLIs, and I'm pleased to see a number of projects using it.</p>
<p>Since Rich is mature and battle-tested now, I had considered winding-down development. Until, I saw this tweet:</p>
<h2>The Tweet</h2>
<blockquote><div lang="en" dir="ltr"><p>Do you want to see something really cool you can do with <a href="https://twitter.com/willmcgugan?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@willmcgugan</a> 's rich library? </p><p>Checkout ghtop <a href="https://t.co/mn7oLbpw8e">https://t.co/mn7oLbpw8e</a>. It's a really fun CLI tool that demonstrates the power of rich (and other things).</p><p>Examples below 🧵👇 (1/8)</p></div>— Hamel Husain (@HamelHusain) <a href="https://twitter.com/HamelHusain/status/1357771218095546368?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 5, 2021</a></blockquote> 
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/HamelHusain">@HamelHusain</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/jeremyphoward">@jeremyphoward</a> used Rich to enhance <a href="https://github.com/nat/ghtop">ghtop</a> (a repo owned by the CEO of Github, no less). Ghtop shows a realtime a stream of events from the Github platform. And it looks good! So good that I realised how much potential Rich has for these type of htop-like applications.</p>
<p>Hamel and Jeremy had to overcome a few technical hurdles to make that work. Fortunately this will no longer be required as the latest version of Rich has first-class support for full-screen interfaces via a new Layout system.</p>
<h2>Full-screen terminal interface</h2>
<p>Here's a video demonstration of a terminal interface built with Layout:</p>
<p>
<iframe width="auto" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/slrdSojCvlk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</p>
<h2>Layout API</h2>
<p>The API to create a flexible layout is surprisingly simple. You construct a <code>Layout()</code> object, then call <code>split()</code> to create sub-layouts. These sub-layouts may then be further divided. Layouts have a small number of settings which define their size relative to the terminal window. It's a simple system that can create terminal interfaces that almost resemble modern web apps.</p>
<div><figure> <img width="1140" height="724" title="layout_vscode.png" name="layout_vscode" data-md="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg" data-square="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.square.7.jpeg" data-xlg2x="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg2x.2.jpeg" data-lg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg" data-xlg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg.8.jpeg" data-author="© 2021 Will McGugan<br>all rights reserved" data-og_preview="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.og.preview.2.jpeg" data-height="2100" data-width="3308" data-toggle="tooltip" data-details=" " data-sm="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg" data-blur="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.blur.6.jpeg" data-slug="layout_vscode" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1170px, (min-width: 992px) 970px, (min-width: 768px) 750px" srcset="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg 1170w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg 970w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg 750w" src="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/a7ab7ab6-6fb0-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg"> 
<figcaption>
<p>© 2021 Will McGugan</p>


<p>A Rich layout in VSCode</p>


</figcaption>

</figure>
</div>
<h2>Finally, some code</h2>
<p>Here's how you would create a basic layout with a header, a footer, and two side-panels.</p>
<pre><code>from rich.console import Console
from rich.layout import Layout

console = Console()
layout = Layout()

# Divide the "screen" in to three parts
layout.split(
    Layout(name="header", size=3),
    Layout(ratio=1, name="main"),
    Layout(size=10, name="footer"),
)
# Divide the "main" layout in to "side" and "body"
layout["main"].split(
    Layout(name="side"),
    Layout(name="body", ratio=2),
    direction="horizontal"
)
# Divide the "side" layout in to two
layout["side"].split(Layout(), Layout())

console.print(layout)
</code></pre>
<p>Running the code above produces the following output:</p>
<div><figure> <img width="1140" height="739" title="layout.png" name="layout" data-md="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg" data-square="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.square.7.jpeg" data-xlg2x="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg2x.2.jpeg" data-lg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg" data-xlg="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.xlg.8.jpeg" data-author="© 2021 Will McGugan<br>all rights reserved" data-og_preview="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.og.preview.2.jpeg" data-height="1464" data-width="2258" data-toggle="tooltip" data-details=" " data-sm="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg" data-blur="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.blur.6.jpeg" data-slug="layout" sizes="(min-width: 1200px) 1170px, (min-width: 992px) 970px, (min-width: 768px) 750px" srcset="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg 1170w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.md.3.jpeg 970w, https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.sm.3.jpeg 750w" src="https://media.moyaproject.com/willmcgugan/uploads/thumbnails/techblog/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44.png/98f8e5f8-6fab-11eb-bc8d-f23c91845b44png.lg.3.jpeg"> 
<figcaption>
<p>© 2021 Will McGugan</p>


<p>Terminal split in to 5 sub-layouts. The boxes are placeholders, you can insert any content in their place.</p>


</figcaption>

</figure>
</div>
<p>Any renderable (text, table, progress bars etc) may be placed inside those sub-layouts.</p>
<p>We can now use the <a href="https://rich.readthedocs.io/en/latest/live.html">Live</a> class to create an application that adapts itself to the terminal window:</p>
<pre><code>from rich.live import Live
from time import sleep

with Live(layout, screen=True):
    while True:
        sleep(1)
</code></pre>
<p>In a real app, that do-nothing loop will be doing something useful like pulling data from the network to update contents.</p>
<p>See the <a href="https://rich.readthedocs.io/en/latest/layout.html">layout docs</a> for an in-depth tutorial.</p>
<h2>What's next?</h2>
<p>I think it's clear that Rich is acquiring more TUI (text user interface) features, and I've decided not to fight it. Rich's core purpose is still to beautify CLI output, but I think there is an opportunity here for a new way to create terminal apps. Ultimately it will be less like curses and more like HTML in a browser.</p>
<p>There are a number of things to do before Rich could replace a full TUI library (keyboard and mouse input for one) but the potential is there. Stay tuned for progress.</p>
<p>Follow <a href="https://twitter.com/willmcgugan">@willmcgugan</a> for more Rich related news.</p>



</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.willmcgugan.com/blog/tech/post/building-rich-terminal-dashboards/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26149488</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:16:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
