<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 08:40:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 08:40:47 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Functioning iPhone returned to owner after six months at bottom of lake]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 115 | Comments 75 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26372407">thread link</a>) | @Tiktaalik
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/cell-phone-recovered-from-harrison-lake-1.5937753?cmp=rss</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26372407</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 01:54:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: PrograMaker – Visual Programming Platform]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26369893">thread link</a>) | @kenkeiras
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://programaker.com/about | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://programaker.com/about">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://programaker.com/about</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26369893</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 19:38:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tech posers of the Bauhaus]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26366513">thread link</a>) | @amicoleo
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        




<article itemscope="" itemtype="https://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  


  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>The Bauhaus greatest achievement was to make artists interested in the creative use of technology, to design things that are useful and nice to use. And they did that without knowing a lot about tech.</p>

<hr>

<p>Product, experience, interaction, industrial designers, creative technologists. If somehow you are a creative interested in making things that are useful and nice to use, you owe that to the Bauhaus. It’s also because of that school and their influence on art education that we can enjoy things designed by people with an artistic sensibility. Rather than only having things designed by engineers.</p>

<p>At the time, few artists were willing to collaborate with the industry to create mass-manufactured objects. Architect Walter Gropius, founder and director of the school, was especially passionate about social architecture and in general in creating things for the common people. Mass-manufacturing technology could allow that at scale. So some years after the creation of the school, he adjusted the focus in the Bauhaus curriculum. And since 1925, when the Bauhaus moved to Dessau, the school new motto became ‘Art and technology: a new unity’.</p>

<hr>

<p>But despite the ambition of the Bauhaus to teach students how to design for the industry, few of the tutors at the time had experience in industrial production. The school method was still based on a combination of applied arts and academic education, and the students’ practical lessons were given by craftsmen whose experience was in making things by hand and not in designing for production.</p>

<p>For instance, in the metal workshop under Moholy-Nagy, students would handmade prototypes with a style they thought would be easy to reproduce industrially. For instance using spheres, cylinders and other basic shapes. Except that due to their ignorance of industrial processes, those objects were hard to make in a mass-production facility.</p>

<p>But the strongest critique of the Bauhaus lack of technological knowledge was Buckminster Fuller. Fuller was familiar with the work of the Bauhaus due to the Black Mountain College in the US, where he and other former Bauhaus tutors were teaching. According to him, the ‘International Style’ brought to the US by the Bauhaus, simple replaced the previous decorative style with a new simplified one made of basic shapes and colours. A new exterior, but that was leaving unchanged the structural and functional elements of the building.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>In short they only looked at problems of modifications of the surface of end-product, which end-products were inherently sub-functions of a technically obsolete world</p>
</blockquote>

<p>(Obviously, Bucky did all the things he was criticising Gropius and the Bauhaus about. But that’s a story I’ll save for some other time).</p>

<hr>

<p>The excitement of the Bauhauslers for new technologies is still present among designers now. And so is that limit in understanding fully a new innovation that can be used in a new product or service. I feel that every time I’m working with machine learning. But what the Bauhaus achieved was to get artists interested in bringing their sensibility in the creative use of technology. And whatever Bucky thinks, that remains.</p>

<p><strong>References</strong></p>

<p>Bauhaus - Madgalena Droste</p>

<p>Theory and Design in the First Machine Age - Reyner Banham</p>


  </div>

  
</article>



      </div>


    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.orgonomyproductions.info/notes/notes/2021/02/27/TechPosersBauhaus.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26366513</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 10:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Tell HN: I am doing online reading sessions on analytic number theory]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 99 | Comments 28 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=26366464">thread link</a>) | @susam
<br/>
March 6, 2021 | https://spxy.github.io/bc/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://spxy.github.io/bc/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p>
Welcome to the first edition of our online reading session. This is a
tiny book club. In the first edition, we will be diving into the
beautiful world of <em>number theory</em>.
</p>



<p>
  <small>
  †
  The Matrix room and Freenode channel are bridged together, so if you
  join one of them, you will automatically receive the updates and
  messages from the other one too. If you are not an active Freenode
  user, prefer joining the Matrix room because it is more convenient,
  e.g., you can close your browser or client and your chat session will
  still stay alive. You can connect back the next day and catch up with
  the messages. Doing that with Freenode IRC requires slightly more work
  (setting up IRC bouncers etc.).
  </small>
</p>


<h2 id="reference">Reference Material<a href="#reference"></a></h2>

<p>
The primary reference book for these meetings is going to be:
<em>Introduction to Analytic Number Theory</em> written by Tom M.
Apostol. Admittedly, the book is quite expensive but you may find a
relatively cheap paperback (softcover) copy on some websites. A DRM-free
PDF eBook is available for purchase at <a href="https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9780387901633">springer.com/gp/book/9780387901633</a>.
</p>

<p>
If you are unable to buy the reference book, you can still participate
in this book club activity by downloading freely available notes from
  the University of Illinois: <a href="https://faculty.math.illinois.edu/~hildebr/ant/main.pdf">main.pdf</a>.
</p>

<p>
For solutions to exercise problems, refer to this excellent PDF created
by Greg Hurst: <a href="https://greghurst.files.wordpress.com/2014/02/apostol_intro_to_ant.pdf">apostol_intro_to_ant.pdf</a>.
</p>


<h2 id="schedule">Schedule<a href="#schedule"></a></h2>

<p>
Here is the schedule for the upcoming planned meetings:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>
     04 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Introduction. Kick-starting chapter 1.
    (Pilot)
  </li>
  <li>
    05 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    06 Mar 2021 10:00-10:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    07 Mar 2021 10:00-10:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    08 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    09 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    10 Mar 2021 18:00-18:40 UTC: Chapter 1
  </li>
  <li>
    More sessions coming up later ...
  </li>
</ul>

<p>
Roughly speaking, the plan is to cover a chapter every one or two weeks.
</p>

<p>
If you have any questions, join our <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">Matrix room</a>
(or the corresponding Freenode channel) and discuss.
</p>

<p>
Also, <a href="https://twitter.com/intent/follow?screen_name=susam">follow me on
Twitter</a> where I will post upcoming reading session details.
</p>

<h2 id="faq">FAQ<a href="#faq"></a></h2>
<ol>
  <li id="faq-who">
    <h3>
      Who are you?
      <a href="#faq-who"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Hi! I am <a href="https://susam.in/">Susam</a>. I am just someone
      who enjoys mathematics, Lisp, and Emacs and wants to spread the
      joy of spending time with these beautiful things. I have been
      working as an information security professional for about 15
      years. Of these 15 years, close to 7 years were spent working with
      probability theory, calculus, and combinatorics, and another 3
      years in implementation of cryptographic utilities.
    </p>
    <p>
      I do a lot of teaching as hobby. This is my way of giving
      something back to the technology community. I have taught Common
      Lisp, Emacs, Python, C, Vim, and various areas of mathematics. In
      each one of my previous workplaces, I have created communities
      around mathematics, algorithms, and/or, cryptography. In the
      online world, I created the <a href="https://webchat.freenode.net/##algorithms">##algorithms</a>
      channel on Freenode IRC (my nick there is <code>spal</code>). What
      started as a tiny hobby club around algorithms 13 years ago is now
      a thriving community with over 200 members. (Disclosure: I don't
      participate in it anymore but a highly talented group of
      moderators helps maintain the channel).
    </p>
    <p>
      These hobbies of teaching and forming local and online communities
      have also led me to write some open source projects. Some are
      mildly popular and some not so popular but have managed to find
      its own niche community of users. For example, <a href="https://github.com/susam/texme">TeXMe</a> and <a href="http://mathb.in/">MathB.in</a> were born out of the need to
      share mathematics problems and solutions within these communities.
      <a href="https://github.com/susam/uncap">Uncap</a> was born when I
      used to teach Vim and I wanted Windows users to have a good
      ergonomic experience. Similarly, <a href="https://github.com/susam/emacs4cl">Emacs4CL</a> was born
      while teaching Common Lisp with Emacs and SLIME.
    </p>
    <p>
      To summarize, I work in information security by profession and I
      am an open source software developer by hobby. I want to use some
      part of my leisure time in hosting book club meetings where we
      pick up good books and work through them together.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-why">
    <h3>
      Why are you doing this?
      <a href="#faq-why"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      During the course of my career and hobbies, I have found
      Mathematics, Lisp, and Emacs to be extraordinarily elegant and
      beautiful and it is my goal to introduce as many people to these
      things as possible.
    </p>
    <p>
      Software development these days focus a lot around stitching
      together many libraries to accomplish complex tasks. I understand
      that this is more economical and productive. This approach has
      certainly made it possible to develop huge and complex
      software-based infrastructure that has changed the way we live.
      However, I think, in this fast-paced software development world,
      the simpler joys of devising or implementing algorithms from
      scratch and appreciating the underlying beauty of mathematics is
      taking a backseat. I intend to introduce more and more people to
      some of these simpler joys, especially, the joy of unravelling the
      mysteries of prime numbers, appreciating the simplicity and
      elegance of Lisp, experiencing the remarkable extensibility of
      Emacs, and so on.
    </p>
    <p>
      Also, the more I help others work though a formidable book like
      <em>Introduction to Analytic Number Theory</em>, the more it helps
      me too to appreciate some finer and deeper points that I may not
      have paid due attention to when I read the book for the first
      time. So I benefit from these reading sessions too. Similarly, the
      more I help someone with Common Lisp programming, the more I have
      to dive into the Common Lisp HyperSpec which often teaches me a
      few new things too, so I gain from the experience too.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-book">
    <h3>
      Have you read the entire book?
      <a href="#faq-book"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      No, I have read approximately half of the book (Introduction to
      Analytic Number Theory) and I am enjoying it so far. This means
      that I am a good number of chapters ahead of someone who has just
      begun reading this book, so I can maintain a steady pace in the
      reading sessions and also be able to tell if some topics or areas
      of confusion in an earlier chapter will be clarified in a later
      chapter.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-lisp">
    <h3>
      You mentioned Lisp. Can you do a book club for it?
      <a href="#faq-lisp"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Yes, Lisp and Emacs are two other areas at the top of my mind.
      Once there has been sufficient progress in the number theory book
      club, I plan to start a Lisp one next. Join the <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">Matrix
      room</a> or <a href="https://app.element.io/#/room/#susam:matrix.org">follow me
      on Twitter</a> to receive further updates about this.
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-but">
    <h3>
      But I want to do group reading sessions for another book!
      <a href="#faq-but"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Start your own book club around it! This is mine. I have chosen
      number theory as the topic of discussion for now. After a few
      months, I will move on to topics around Lisp and Emacs. If you
      have a different topic or book in mind, start your own book club
      for it. You can reuse my channels (see top of this page) for it or
      you can do it your own way. If you let me know about it and if I
      can find the time, I will join your book club too! I think, we
      need more book clubs, not less!
    </p>
  </li>
  <li id="faq-recording">
    <h3>
      Will these sessions be recorded?
      <a href="#faq-recording"></a>
    </h3>
    <p>
      Not at this time because we often refer to a few pages of the book
      via screen sharing during the reading session. I don't know the
      copyright implications of recording such sessions as videos and
      sharing them with everyone online. If you have expertise in this
      area, I would like to know if my concern is genuine and if there
      is a way to resolve it.
    </p>
  </li>


</ol></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://spxy.github.io/bc/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-26366464</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 10:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
