<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 5]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 5. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:47:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-5.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 12:47:45 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We Crush, Poison, and Destroy Insects at Our Own Peril]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 65 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25901384">thread link</a>) | @CapitalistCartr
<br/>
January 25, 2021 | http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
			<p><span>T</span>his past summer, my wife and I ventured to an area near Mount Adams in southwestern Washington state to census bumblebees. We camped there over the weekend as we took part in the Pacific Northwest Bumblebee Atlas survey. Scientists want to fill gaps in their knowledge about the bees. Learning about the relative number of different species, and their floral resources over a broad area, provides invaluable information, particularly when some species are in decline. I was helping to determine where conservation efforts may be needed. Survey participants choose a territory where they capture and photograph bumblebees on two occasions. I still marvel at the variety in the photos we took—bees with coloration incorporating rusty bands of hair, black stubby hairs, white patches, orange bands, and a brilliant, lemon-yellow covering of long hairs. <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/90/something-green/the-fungal-evangelist-who-would-save-the-bees" target="_blank">Bumblebees</a> are really quite beautiful when observed more closely.</p><figure data-alt="Hainze_BREAKER"><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18113_ca9eac0c76de0cab71d5b50951fe4c5f.png" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><span><strong>FIGHT OF THE BUMBLEBEE:</strong> A 2017 global study found that one-third of assessed bumblebee species were in decline. The U.S. is studying whether to place the western bumblebee on the endangered species list.</span><span>Stephen Ausmus, USDA ARS / Wikimedia</span></figcaption></figure><p>There is some risk involved, of course. Bumblebees have a painful sting and, unlike the honeybee, with its barbed stinger, the sharp, smooth bumblebee stinger can sting multiple times. Insect stings may serve two purposes. The first is to incapacitate prey. The second is to ward off predators. Bumblebees feed solely on pollen and flower nectar. So they would not sting to subdue prey. A bumblebee nest full of honey and nearly immobile larvae, though, is highly attractive to predators. The bumblebee sting is a weapon used for defense—a mechanism to escape predation from animals that may be 50,000 to 100,000 times their size.<sup>1</sup> And judging by the way most people respond, it works pretty well. The sting of the honeybee has been used as a reference point by sting pain connoisseur, Justin Schmidt. He rates the bumblebee and <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/3/in-transit/tracking-honeybees-to-save-them" target="_blank">honeybee</a> stings as a pedestrian 2 on his scale of 1-4.<sup>2</sup> But that’s a sufficient wallop for people to keep their distance from these bees—and that’s the way the bees like it.<br></p><p>The unparalleled success of insects as a group of organisms results from their ability to escape existential threats. They’re escape artists. They’ve evolved multiple means of eluding the larger animals that endanger them—by stinging, biting, flying, jumping, running, startling, hiding in crevices, and using camouflage as well as chemical defenses. Yet these masters at evading far larger animals face a threat more pernicious than predation today. The resulting decline in the number of insects and in the number of insect species is increasingly well documented. Why should this be alarming? Insects play significant roles as food or in the growth of food for many organisms, including human beings. Insects are also recyclers, decomposing plant matter and animal dung and contributing to the organic content of soils.</p><blockquote><p>It’s not all honey and butterflies in our relationship with insects.</p> </blockquote><p>It’s been said that if human beings disappeared, we would not be missed. Insects and other organisms would thrive. Yet we and many other animals <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/73/play/we-need-insects-more-than-they-need-us" target="_blank">would not survive were insects to disappear</a>. The plight of the island marble butterfly (<i>Euchloe ausonides insulanis</i>) and the western bumblebee (<i>Bombus occidentalis</i>) exemplify the multiple stressors on insect survival in the <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/90/something-green/dawn-of-the-heliocene" target="_blank">Anthropocene</a>, the proposed name for a new epoch in which human-generated change outstrips the effect of natural forces on the Earth. What responsibilities, if any, do we bear toward these insects? And what can each of us do to stem the tide of global insect decline?<br></p><p>In my recent book, <i>Nature Underfoot</i>, I argue that we crush, poison, and destroy insects and their habitat at our own peril. Yet reasons for acting to prevent insect decline run much deeper than self-interest. Humans cause habitat loss, produce pesticides, and import non-native species. We bear, according to certain strands of philosophical and religious thought, responsibility for the catastrophic losses insects experience today. Some say that insects have moral value since they strive to achieve their ends, just as we and other animals do. Others argue that insects have <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/72/quandary/human-exceptionalism-stifles-progress" target="_blank">moral value as a part of God’s creation</a>. Scientists point to the value of insects in global ecosystems, or the value implied by tens or hundreds of thousands of years involved in the evolution of an insect species.</p><p><span>T</span>he insect apocalypse has captured headlines, but the situation is more nuanced than that. Scientists find an increase in the overall numbers of arthropods in the Arctic, but a decline in diversity. Certain habitats in the Arctic are also affected more than others.<sup>3</sup> In Puerto Rico, insect declines initially attributed to climate change may have resulted instead from hurricanes.<sup>4</sup> Some insect species have even increased in numbers—mainly those that are tolerant of human activities or that benefit from associating with humans or from <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/78/atmospheres/is-net-zero-emissions-an-impossible-goal" target="_blank">climate change</a>.</p><p>Despite that, the general trend is negative as climate change, habitat destruction (in the form of deforestation, urbanization, and <a href="https://nautil.us/issue/66/clockwork/herbicide-is-whats-for-dinner" target="_blank">intensification of agriculture</a>), and pesticides take their toll. These forces are overtaking the insects. They are coming so quickly that even these spectacularly successful evolutionary improvisers do not have time to escape. It’s often difficult for scientists to identify a single contributing factor. A new paper, introducing a special issue on the plight of insects, published in the <i>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</i>, referred to the decline of these tiny creatures as “death by a thousand cuts.”<sup>5</sup></p><figure data-alt="Hainze_BREAKER-2"><img src="http://static.nautil.us/18112_d05c25e6e6c5d4898161e0aaf700d9c7.png" width="733" alt=""><figcaption><strong>EDGE OF EXTINCTION:</strong> The Lazarus-like return of the island marble butterfly is remarkable, but the pressures that endanger its prairie habitats remain.</figcaption></figure><p>There is a paucity of long-term records for insect populations. The best historical records are for moths and butterflies in Europe and North America. The story of the island marble butterfly, a grassland species, illustrates the myriad forces arrayed against insects. It was declared endangered in the United States in May of 2020. It is charmingly small—mostly white on the tops of the wings and mottled green, yellow, and white on the undersides. Perhaps its colorful camouflage is a way of escaping predation. This little butterfly was thought to be extinct since 1908, when it was last collected on Gabriola Island, British Columbia. Quite by accident 90 years later, while conducting a survey of butterflies in Puget Sound prairie habitats, a Washington state biologist, John Fleckenstein, collected two of these butterflies on San Juan Island. Neither Fleckenstein, nor his colleague, Ann Potter, could identify the butterflies as they reviewed his collection. So, Potter took the butterflies to a butterfly conference in Corvallis, Oregon, where experts were ecstatic to see the butterfly once thought extinct!<sup>6</sup><br></p><p>The Lazarus-like return of the island marble butterfly is remarkable, but the pressures that endanger it remain. The prairie habitats where the butterfly is found have been farmed, used for pasture, and developed for housing, destroying much of its original habitat. The butterfly caterpillars feed and develop on plants in the mustard family. The native mustard, Menzies’ pepperweed (<i>Lepidium virginicum</i> var. <i>menziesii</i>), that must have originally supported the butterfly, is often found surrounding lagoons on San Juan Island. These plants and the island marble butterfly are damaged by winter storm surges, which will become more serious as climate change causes sea levels to rise. Fortunately, the butterfly has adapted to feeding on two non-native plants, field mustard (<i>Brassica rapa</i>) and tumble mustard (<i>Sisymbrium altissimum</i>) that grow elsewhere on the island.</p><blockquote><p>We and many animals wouldn’t survive if insects disappeared.</p> </blockquote><p>Other invasive species have had a more deleterious effect on the island marble butterfly. The brown garden snail (<i>Cornu aspersum</i>), brought from Europe to the west coast as a source of escargot, competes with the island marble butterfly in consuming field mustard and tumble mustard. The European rabbit (<i>Oryctolagus cuniculus</i>) develops large populations in the San Juan Islands and also feeds on butterfly host plants. Deer, though native in the San Juans, are destructive of prairie habitat. Deer numbers are very high there because their predators, such as wolves, cougars, and bears, were eliminated by European settlers. Deer not only destroy island marble butterfly habitat, but they may ingest eggs and caterpillars in the process. Island marble butterflies also suffer from predation by native spiders and by a European paper wasp (<i>Polistes dominula</i>).<sup>7</sup><br></p><p>A vigorous and widely distributed population of butterflies could withstand the <a href="https://nautil.us/blog/fear-is-good-for-the-forest" target="_blank">pressure of predation</a>, but it poses a significant risk for the tiny, localized population of island marble butterflies. Death by a thousand cuts. Habitat destruction, loss of food plants, invasive species, climate change, and predation are primarily human-driven problems. Fortunately, what is believed to be the last island marble butterfly population falls within the boundaries of the San Juan National Historic Park. Here, the park service is actively rearing and releasing butterflies and making a significant effort to preserve their habitat. The island marble butterfly is in a fragile state but hopefully its new endangered status will yield another amazing recovery.</p><div>
<article>
<p><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/6/Secret%20Codes/learning-to-speak-shrub" data-trval="learning-to-speak-shrub" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">
<img src="http://static.nautil.us/1315_dfd7468ac613286cdbb40872c8ef3b06.png" alt="Sapolsky_TH-F1" width="314" height="177">
</a>
</p>
<div>
<p><span>
<span>

<span><a href="http://m.nautil.us/term/f/Environment">Also in Environment</a></span>&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>
</span></p><h4><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/6/Secret%20Codes/learning-to-speak-shrub" data-trval="learning-to-speak-shrub" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">Learning to Speak Shrub</a></h4>
<p>By Elizabeth  Preston</p>
<p>
Entomologist Richard Karban knows how to get sagebrush talking. To start the conversation, he poses as a grasshopper or a chewing beetle—he uses scissors to cut leaves on one of the shrubs. Lopping off the leaves entirely won’t fool the...<strong><a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/6/Secret%20Codes/learning-to-speak-shrub" data-trval="learning-to-speak-shrub" data-trlbl="foc_rec" data-tract="internal_art">READ MORE</a></strong>
</p>

</div>

</article>
</div><p>Bumblebees experience similar problems, and the citizen-science survey I described endeavored to generate information about wild bumblebee status—where they occur and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril">http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://m.nautil.us/issue/95/escape/we-crush-poison-and-destroy-insects-at-our-own-peril</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25901384</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 09:52:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Get started modding Factorio in TypeScript]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25899637">thread link</a>) | @cdaringe
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://cdaringe.github.io/factorio-type-kit/posts/get-started | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cdaringe.github.io/factorio-type-kit/posts/get-started">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p><strong>Of course</strong> we want type safety when programming Factorio mods. Unfortunately, Factorio's Lua modding API offers no such provisions. Good news! <a href="https://github.com/cdaringe/factorio-type-kit">factorio-type-kit</a> helps bridge that gap via TypeScript. While TypeScript doesn't offer
the strongest safety guarantees of any language under the sun, it does offer moderate safety, and works well
as a Lua replacement. The following steps are required to author factorio mods in TS:</p>
<h2>Factorio in TypeScript - Outline</h2>
<p>We will execute the following steps later, but at a glance, here are the general required steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Install <a href="https://nodejs.org/">node</a>. I recommend using <a href="https://github.com/Schniz/fnm#using-a-script-macoslinux">fnm</a> for installing and managing nodejs installations.</li>
<li>(optional) Install <a href="https://classic.yarnpkg.com/en/docs/install">yarn</a>. <code>npm</code> is the default package manager for nodejs, but the following document uses <code>yarn</code>. It takes only moments to install.</li>
<li>Setup a <code>nodejs</code> project</li>
<li>Install <a href="https://github.com/cdaringe/factorio-type-kit">factorio-type-kit</a>, <a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/#installation">typescript</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/TypeScriptToLua/TypeScriptToLua">TypeScriptToLua</a></li>
<li>Configure the typescript compiler to use TypeScriptToLua</li>
<li>Code</li>
<li>Package &amp; deploy the mod</li>
</ol>
<p>It is assumed that the reader has installed node &amp; yarn before proceeding further.</p>
<p>Let's get to work.</p>
<h2>Bootstrapping a barebones mod</h2>
<p>The following command can be run to bootstrap a fresh mod project <em>automatically</em>:</p>
<!-- <Shell children='$ yarn create factorio-mod <mod-name>' /> -->
<pre><code><span>$</span><span> yarn create factorio-mod &lt;mod-name&gt;</span></code></pre>
<p>For demonstration purposes, I will create a mod called <code>vroom</code>. This mod will make the character accelerate as he runs, allowing the player to travel at warp speed!</p>
<pre><code><span>$</span><span> yarn create factorio-mod vroom</span>
...
Victory! Your mod is ready to roll. Execute the following commands to get going:
  - cd "/Users/cdaringe/src/vroom"
  - yarn start
✨  Done in 5.75s.</code></pre>
<p>This step automatically installs the aforementioned dependencies and sets up the compiler toolchain.
If you want to do these steps manually, please see the <a href="https://github.com/cdaringe/vroom">vroom</a> codebase, and replicate the artifacts hosted there. <a href="https://mods.factorio.com/mod/vroom">@mods.factorio.com</a></p>
<h2>Understanding the barebones mod</h2>
<p>Let us <code>cd "path/to/vroom"</code>, and study the content. If you
are familiar with the <a href="https://wiki.factorio.com/Tutorial:Mod_structure">factorio mod directory stucture</a>,
this should look quite familiar.</p>
<pre><code>~/src/vroom via ⬢ v15.0.1
❯ ls -alh
Permissions Size User     Date Modified Name
.rw-r--r--   167 cdaringe 24 Jan 11:37  control.ts
.rw-r--r--   183 cdaringe 24 Jan 11:37  info.json
drwxr-xr-x     - cdaringe 24 Jan 11:37  node_modules
.rw-r--r--   247 cdaringe 24 Jan 11:37  package.json
.rw-r--r--   131 cdaringe 24 Jan 11:37  readme.md
.rw-r--r--   331 cdaringe 24 Jan 11:37  tsconfig.json
.rw-r--r--   35k cdaringe 24 Jan 11:37  yarn.lock</code></pre>
 <!-- `.trim()} /> -->
<ul>
<li><code>info.json</code> - the entrypont to all factorio mods, pre-populated with some essentials</li>
<li><code>control.ts</code> - this file will compile to <code>control.lua</code>, which Factorio uses to run your mod!</li>
<li><code>tsconfig.json</code> - typescript configuration, critically including <a href="https://typescripttolua.github.io/docs/configuration">TypescriptToLua configuration</a></li>
<li><code>package.json</code> &amp; <code>node_modules</code> - resources to support your TS development experience :)</li>
</ul>
<p>Let's open up <code>control.ts</code>:</p>
<pre><code><span>const</span> onTick = <span>(<span>_evt: OnTickPayload</span>) =&gt;</span> {
  game.print(serpent.block({
    <span>hello</span>: <span>"world"</span>,
    <span>its_nice</span>: <span>"to see you"</span>
  }));
};

script.on_event(defines.events.on_tick, onTick);</code></pre>
<ul>
<li><code>script.on_event</code> - typed</li>
<li><code>game</code> - typed</li>
<li><code>serpent</code> - typed</li>
<li><code>evt</code> - typed, via casting</li>
</ul>
<p>Boom! Types for everything!</p>
<p>...but not quite. The Factorio Lua documentation is <em>lossy</em>, and has many cases where we simply <em>cannot</em> parse correct type definitions from the Factorio website. Until the factorio development team publicly supports  machine-readable API documentation, <code>factorio-type-kit</code> TypeScript provisions will generally only be 70-80%+ complete. Thus, TypeScript users will be periodically disappointed to find <code>any</code> or <code>unknown</code> types in various interfaces. With that said, <code>factorio-type-kit</code> users are welcome to manually backfill essential definitions to make our community's development kit better.</p>
<h2>Starting the mod compiler</h2>
<pre><code><span>$</span><span> yarn start</span></code></pre>
<p>Momentarily after launching the watching compiler, <code>control.lua</code> should be emitted. Open it up:</p>
<pre><code>onTick = <span><span>function</span><span>(_evt)</span></span>
    game.<span>print</span>(
        serpent.block({hello = <span>"world"</span>, its_nice = <span>"to see you"</span>})
    )
<span>end</span>
script.on_event(defines.events.on_tick, onTick)</code></pre>
<p>The TypeScriptToLua compiler does a fanstastic job on producing readable Lua.</p>
<h2>Implementing vroom</h2>
<p>The very first thing the <code>vroom</code> mod needs to do is detect when the player is in motion.</p>
<p>Rather that pull up the documentation, I'll just open up another call <code>script.on_event</code>, then
begin typing in <code>defines.events.</code>. After intellisense presents me options, I will select <code>on_player_changed_position</code>. The type definitions tell me a callback is also required. I will enter in <code>onPositionChanged</code>.</p>
<pre><code>script.on_event(
  defines.events.on_player_changed_position,
  onPositionChange
);</code></pre>
<p><code>onPositionChange</code> is not defined yet. Let's discuss what it needs to do then draft it.
First, it needs to get the player's current speed. Next, the speed needs to increase when running. Because the purpose of the mod is to accelerate the user, we multiply the previous speed by a scalar every so often.</p>
<pre><code><span>const</span> onPositionChange = <span>(<span>evt: OnPlayerChangedPositionPayload</span>) =&gt;</span> {
  <span>const</span> player = game.get_player(evt.player_index);
  <span>if</span> (player.walking_state.walking) {
    
  }
};</code></pre>
<p>Immediately take note that we have manually specified the type of <code>evt</code> as <code>OnPlayerChangedPositionPayload</code>. All factorio script event types follow the event naming convention: <code>&lt;CamelCased-EventName&gt;Payload</code>. A future version may automatically apply types to the <code>on_event</code> callback, so you not need cast.</p>
<p>The first thing I noticed was that <code>evt</code> did not have a reference directly to the player I needed.
It does contain the <code>player_id</code> however, and with that ID we can call the <code>get_player</code> method on the global <code>game</code> instance. <code>get_player</code> returns an instance of a <code>LuaPlayer</code>, contains a <code>walking_state</code> property. Let's use <em>that</em>. We know that we <em>only</em> want to speed up the player if he is in motion, so let's further wrap our logic inside a conditional--<code>if (player.walking_state.walking) { ... }</code>.</p>
<p>Next up, how do we actually speed up the player? After searching the API documentation, I concluded that there was not a direct value specifying a velocity of the character. However, I did come across <code>character_running_speed_modifier</code>, which the type definitions told me is of type <code>number</code>. Unexpectedly, through trial and error, I learned that <code>character_running_speed_modifier</code> could be zero. <code>Speed * 0 = 0</code>, so Factorio likely does a 0 check internally before calculating the player's speed. We will have to do a similar check. Notice that typescript did not me help uncover my bug! Anything of type <code>number</code> can rightfully be zero, so shame on me! Defensive programmers everywhere are saying "you should have seen this coming", and they would be correct :). Equipped with this knowledge, let's fill in the rest.</p>
<pre><code><span>const</span> onPositionChange = <span>(<span>evt: OnPlayerChangedPositionPayload</span>) =&gt;</span> {
  <span>const</span> player = game.get_player(evt.player_index);
  <span>if</span> (player.walking_state.walking) {
    <span>const</span> lastSpeed = player.character_running_speed_modifier;
    <span>const</span> baseSpeed = lastSpeed == <span>0</span> ? <span>1</span> : lastSpeed;
    player.character_running_speed_modifier = baseSpeed * <span>1.01</span>;
  }
};</code></pre>
<p>When our player stops running, we want to restart the acceleration process for the next time he runs.
My original approach was to listen for <code>keyup</code> events. Alas, Factorio has no key events. How else could I determine if the player has stopped running, and thus safely reset the speed modifier? Easy! On every tick of the game, I can check all players for motion--and turn off the multiplier if they are stopped!</p>
<pre><code><span>const</span> onTick = <span>(<span>_evt: OnTickPayload</span>) =&gt;</span> {
  <span>Object</span>.entries(game.players).forEach(<span>(<span>[_id, player]</span>) =&gt;</span> {
    <span>if</span> (
      player.character_running_speed_modifier &gt; <span>0</span> &amp;&amp;
      !player.walking_state.walking
    ) {
      player.character_running_speed_modifier = <span>0</span>;
    }
  });
};</code></pre>
<p>That is, for every player, if there is a positive speed modifier and and the player is not walking, zero out the modifier.</p>
<p>Why didn't we just do a <code>game.players.forEach</code>? <code>game.players</code> isn't an array, so that won't work. TypeScript protected us from making that mistake! What about <code>Object.entries(game.players).forEach</code>? Yep, that worked! Why did we not do <code>Object.values(...)</code>? Because <code>game.players</code> is a <a href="https://lua-api.factorio.com/latest/LuaGameScript.html#LuaGameScript.players">special dictionary</a> in Lua. Not all iterables map cleanly between languages. <code>Object.values(...)</code> wouldn't have given us compiler error, but still would have failed. Improved typing is needed to protect against these failures. While TypeScriptToLua generally helps out a great deal protect us from writing erroneous code, it is only as good as its applied type constraints.</p>
<p>When using JS standard library provisions, as we did above, the compiler will add a typescript-lua polyfill, <code>lualib_bundle</code>. The emitted Lua perhaps is not as elegant:</p>
<pre><code><span>require</span>(<span>"lualib_bundle"</span>);

onTick = <span><span>function</span><span>(_evt)</span></span>
    __TS__ArrayForEach(
        __TS__ObjectEntries(game.players),
        <span><span>function</span><span>(____, ____bindingPattern0)</span></span>
            <span>local</span> _id = ____bindingPattern0[<span>1</span>]
            <span>local</span> player
            player = ____bindingPattern0[<span>2</span>]
            <span>if</span> (player.character_running_speed_modifier &gt; <span>0</span>) <span>and</span> (<span>not</span> player.walking_state.walking) <span>then</span>
                player.character_running_speed_modifier = <span>0</span>
            <span>end</span>
        <span>end</span>
    )
<span>end</span></code></pre>
<p>Even with the extra boilerplate generated, the code is still quite readable. Could be cleaner! Surely as the TypeScriptToLua compiler evolves in time, it will be.</p>
<h2>Deploy it</h2>
<p>I do not yet have clean, polished package &amp; deploy scripts, but I do have functional ones.
Do your best to cover your eyes. Running <code>yarn install_mod</code> syncs the mod into the local Factorio installation. Coupled with a watch script, every code change immediately syncs in the game folder, and requires only a scenario reload to exercise the new scripts.</p>
<pre><code>"scripts": {
  "clean:install": "rm -rf ~/Library/Application\\ Support/factorio/mods/vroom*",
  "copy:install": "VERSION=$(cat info.json | jq -r .version) &amp;&amp; rsync -r --exclude node_modules --exclude '.git*' --exclude build --exclude 'npm*' --exclude README.md --exclude package.json --exclude '*.lock'  ./ ~/Library/Application\\ Support/factorio/mods/vroom_$VERSION/",
  "install_mod": "run-s clean:install copy:install",
  "watch": "chokidar …</code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cdaringe.github.io/factorio-type-kit/posts/get-started">https://cdaringe.github.io/factorio-type-kit/posts/get-started</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cdaringe.github.io/factorio-type-kit/posts/get-started</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25899637</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 05:29:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How Did the Duck Hunt Gun Work?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25898452">thread link</a>) | @chovybizzass
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://briskreader.com/link/lMHe6J5Jpl2 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://briskreader.com/link/lMHe6J5Jpl2">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><img src="https://pocket-image-cache.com/1200x/filters:no_upscale():format(jpg):extract_cover()/https%3A%2F%2Fpocket-syndicated-images.s3.amazonaws.com%2Farticles%2F4809%2F1592846425_nintendo-zapper_7.jpg" alt="How Did the Duck Hunt Gun Work?"></p>
  <p>Added 2 days ago</p>
  <p><strong>Summary:</strong>
      The Duck Hunt gun, officially called the NES Zapper, seems downright primitive next to today’s technology. But in the late ’80s, it filled plenty of young heads with wonder.</p>
  
  <p><span>Sentiment:
      negative</span></p>
  <p>5 minute read</p>
  <p>3044 people have read this</p>
  
  
  
  
  <hr></div><article><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><div><div><section><div data-reactroot=""><p><img alt="nintendo-zapper_7.jpg" src="https://pocket-syndicated-images.s3.amazonaws.com/5ef0e861b7f06.jpg"></p><p><span><span> </span> <span>Caption</span></span><span>Photo by <span>(Xavi Gomez/Cover/Getty Images)</span></span></p></div><p>
    
                            For many children of the '80s, a good portion of your childhood probably revolved around sitting too close to the TV, clutching a plastic safety cone-colored hand gun and blasting waterfowl out of a pixilated sky in <em>Duck Hunt </em>(also, trying to blow that dog’s head off when he laughed at you). The <em>Duck Hunt</em> gun, officially called the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) Zapper, seems downright primitive next to the Nintendo’s Wii and Microsoft’s Kinect, but in the late 80s, it filled plenty of young heads with wonder. How did that thing work?
                        
</p><h4>Annie Get Your Zapper</h4><p>
    
                            The Zapper’s ancestry goes back to the mid 1930s, when the first so-called “light guns” appeared after the development of light-sensing vacuum tubes. In the first light gun game, <a href="http://www.pinrepair.com/arcade/rayolit.htm">Ray-O-Lite</a> (developed in 1936 by Seeburg, a company that made parts and systems for jukeboxes), players shot at small moving targets mounted with light sensors using a gun that emitted a beam of light. When the beam struck a sensor, the targets – ducks, coincidentally – registered the “hit” and a point was scored.
                        
</p><p>
    
                            Light guns hit home video game consoles with <em>Shooting Gallery</em> on the Magnavox Odyssey in 1972. Because the included shotgun-style light gun was only usable on a Magnavox television, the game flopped. The Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) Zapper then fell into the hands of American kids in October 1985, when it was released in a bundle with the NES, a controller and a few games. Early versions of the peripheral were dark gray, but the color of the sci-fi ray gun-inspired Zapper was changed a few years later when a federal regulation required that toy and imitation firearms be “blaze orange” (color #12199, to be exact) so they wouldn’t be mistaken for the real deal.
                        
</p><p>
    
                            While there were a number of Zapper-compatible games released for the NES (when I was a kid and my dad worked from home, we wasted plenty of afternoons away playing <em>Hogan’s Alley</em>), most lived in the shadow of the iconic <em>Duck Hunt</em>, the most recognizable and popular Zapper game.
                        
</p><h4>Gone in a Flash</h4><p>
    
                            While older light guns like the Ray-O-Lite rifle emitted beams of light, the Zapper and many other recent light guns work by receiving light through a photodiode on or in the barrel and using that light to figure out where on the TV screen you're aiming.
                        
</p><p>
    
                            This target flashing method helped Nintendo overcome a weakness of older light gun games: cheaters racking up high scores by pointing the gun at a steady light source, like a lamp, and hitting the first target right out of the gate.
                        
</p><p data-reactroot=""><i>Matt Soniak is a long-time mental_floss regular and writes about science, history, etymology and Bruce Springsteen for both the website and the print magazine. His work has also appeared in print and online for Men’s Health, Scientific American, The Atlantic, Philly.com and others. He tweets as @mattsoniak and blogs about animal behavior at mattsoniak.com.</i></p></section></div></div></article></div></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://briskreader.com/link/lMHe6J5Jpl2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25898452</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 02:42:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What Universal Human Experiences Are You Missing Without Realizing It? (2014)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25898133">thread link</a>) | @yarinr
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/What-Universal-Human-Experiences-Are-You-Missing-Without-Realizing-It | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/What-Universal-Human-Experiences-Are-You-Missing-Without-Realizing-It">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wikitext">

<p><span>March 17, 2014</span>
</p>
<p>Remember <a href="https://www.greaterwrong.com/lw/dr/generalizing_from_one_example/" rel="nofollow">Galton’s experiments on visual imagination?</a> Some people just don’t have it. And they never figured it out. They assumed no one had it, and when people talked about being able to picture objects in their minds, they were speaking metaphorically.
</p>
<p>And the people who <em>did</em> have good visual imaginations didn’t catch them. The people without imaginations mastered this “metaphorical way of talking” so well that they passed for normal. No one figured it out until Galton sat everyone down together and said “Hey, can we be really really clear about exactly how literal we’re being here?” and everyone realized they were describing different experiences.
</p>
<p>I thought about this recently during a conversation with Ozy:
</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Ozy:</strong> I am currently eating chickpeas and rice and I am <em>delighted</em> by the fact that I can eat this <em>whenever I want</em>. The nice thing about DISCOVERING YOUR FOOD PREFERENCES is that suddenly all the food in my cupboards is food I like and am looking forward to eating. And usually I get food I like by, like, luck? So this is excitement.
</p>
<p><strong>Scott:</strong> I don’t understand, why didn’t you buy things like that before?
</p>
<p><strong>Ozy:</strong> It took me a while to have enough of a sense of the food I like for “make a list of the food I like” to be a viable grocery-list-making strategy.
</p>
<p><strong>Scott:</strong> I’ve got to admit I’m confused and intrigued by your “don’t know my own preferences” thing.
</p>
<p><strong>Ozy:</strong> Hrm. Well, it’s sort of like… you know how sometimes you pretend to like something because it’s high-status, and if you do it well enough you <em>actually believe</em> you like the thing? Unless I pay a lot of attention <em>all</em> my preferences end up being not “what I actually enjoy” but like “what is high status” or “what will keep people from getting angry at me”
</p>
<p><strong>Scott:</strong> How does that apply to food?
</p>
<p><strong>Ozy:</strong> Well, sometimes people will tell you a certain food is high-status or healthy or a thing that everyone enjoys, and then I would like it. And a lot of times I just ate whatever was in front of me or ordered whatever the cheapest vegetarian thing on the menu was. And I… sort of vaguely had a sense that some things were more pleasurable to eat than other things but I didn’t like <em>keep track</em> of what they were or anything. Because if I knew I might like the <em>wrong things</em>. And also because I didn’t intuitively grasp that the “liking” thing everyone was talking about was related to pleasure and not to like popularity/status.
</p></blockquote>
<p>So the fact that people talk about what foods they like about a zillion times a day isn’t enough to make everyone realize liking foods is a thing.
</p>
<p>But it gets worse. A high school friend posted on Facebook a link to <a href="http://www.quora.com/Graduate-School/Is-going-for-a-Ph-D-worth-it-if-Im-extremely-passionate-about-a-field-but-dont-really-want-to-spend-my-20s-poor-toiling-away-in-a-lab-and-living-in-a-city-that-I-dont-particularly-want-to-live-in/answer/Mark-Eichenlaub?srid=slK&amp;share=1" rel="nofollow">a really interesting answer on Quora</a>. It makes you log on, so I’ll copy the relevant part below:
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I have anosmia, which means I lack smell the way a blind person lacks sight. What’s surprising about this is that I didn’t even know it for the first half of my life.
</p>
<p>Each night I would tell my mom, “Dinner smells great!” I teased my sister about her stinky feet. I held my nose when I ate Brussels sprouts. In gardens, I bent down and took a whiff of the roses. I yelled “gross” when someone farted. I never thought twice about any of it for fourteen years.
</p>
<p>Then, in freshman English class, I had an assignment to write about the Garden of Eden using details from all five senses. Working on this one night, I sat in my room imagining a peach. I watched the juice ooze out as I squeezed at the soft fuzz. I felt the wet, sappy liquid drip from my fingers down onto my palm. As the mushy heart of the fruit compressed, I could hear it squishing, and when I took that first bite I could taste the little bit of tartness that followed the incredible sweet sensation flooding my mouth.
</p>
<p>But I had to write about smell, too, and I was stopped dead by the question of what a peach smelled like. Good. That was all I could come up with. I tried to think of other things. Garbage smelled bad. Perfume smelled good. Popcorn good. Poop bad. But how so? What was the difference? What were the nuances? In just a few minutes’ reflection I realized that, despite years of believing the contrary, I never had and never would smell a peach.
</p>
<p>All my behavior to that point indicated that I had smell. No one suspected I didn’t. For years I simply hadn’t known what it was that was supposed to be there. I just thought the way it was for me was how it was for everyone. It took the right stimulus before I finally discovered the gap.
</p></blockquote>
<p>So I guess you can just <em>not be able to smell</em> and not know it.
</p>
<p>This makes me wonder what universal human experiences I and my friends are missing out on without realizing it.
</p>
<p>I know one friend’s answer. He discovered he was color-blind sometime in his teens. This still surprises me. People are always taking Ishihara tests (those colorful dotted circles with numbers inside of them) and discovering they’re color blind. Going through life with everyone else saying “The light was red, but now it’s green” and thinking it was weird that they were making such a big deal about subtle variations in shades of brownish-gray, but it was probably one of those metaphors.
</p>
<p>As for me? I took a surprisingly long time to realize I was asexual. When I was a virgin, I figured sex was one of those things that seemed gross before you did it, and then you realized how great it was. Afterwards, I figured it was something that didn’t get good until you were skilled at it and had been in a relationship long enough to truly appreciate the other person. In retrospect, pretty much every aspect of male sexual culture is a counterargument to that theory, but I guess it’s just really hard for my brain to generate “you are a mental mutant” as a hypothesis.
</p>
<p>But even bigger than that, I think I might not have had emotions, at least not fully, for about five years as a teenager when I was on SSRIs. I even sort of noticed myself not having emotions, but dismissed that as an odd thing to happen and probably other people were just being really overexuberant about things. Later I learned emotional blunting is a commonly reported side effect of SSRIs and I was probably just really not experiencing emotions. When I came off them it took me several years to get used to having normal-intensity feelings again, but it wasn’t a sudden revelation, like “Wow, I was missing a fundamental human experience for the past several years!” Just a sense of things being different which was hard to cash out.
</p>
<p>As always, I wonder if a lot of what other people interpret through vague social things might be biological, or at least more <em>complicatedly</em> social. I can’t enjoy jazz music even a little – the best I can do is pick up something sort of like a beat and half-heartedly feel like maybe I could snap my fingers to it if I could build up the energy. My brother fell in love with jazz as soon as he heard it and is now a professional jazz musician who has dedicated his life to it. Are we listening to the same thing when we hear a jazz tune? Or am I like a guy who can’t smell trying to appreciate perfume?
</p>


<p>1362 words
</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.slatestarcodexabridged.com/What-Universal-Human-Experiences-Are-You-Missing-Without-Realizing-It</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25898133</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 01:44:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Papercraft Models of Computers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 177 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25898063">thread link</a>) | @laurex
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | http://rockybergen.com/papercraft | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://rockybergen.com/papercraft">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="page" role="main" data-content-field="main-content">
      <!-- CATEGORY NAV -->
      
      <div data-type="page" data-updated-on="1592534389753" id="page-5c40ced8575d1f4191811561"><div><div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-0348a58188a4ef2cb7ff"><div><p>Construct the computer from your childhood or build an entire computer museum at home with these paper models, free to download and share.<br>Print, Cut, Score, Fold and Glue.</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="75" data-block-type="5" id="block-7348027484c80743e6ed"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751317778-HWMYNDK2JW0LTOB6EBZP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN_ZoNdj1kv_gIvm4zjH76N7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0n54Bn8e90W9qBf-smZxzROWPWatu8N4myd8qBOjLXoKr7eLilP27nxMq5hFavDR2g/IMG_3082.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751317778-HWMYNDK2JW0LTOB6EBZP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN_ZoNdj1kv_gIvm4zjH76N7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0n54Bn8e90W9qBf-smZxzROWPWatu8N4myd8qBOjLXoKr7eLilP27nxMq5hFavDR2g/IMG_3082.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x1786" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMG_3082.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40cf83352f5396d76f7ac3" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IMG_3082.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3fa377625522c866e7f3"><div><h3>AMIGA 500</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/1/15/amiga-500-papercraft-design">here</a>.                                                              German New Art Edition <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/8/8/amiga-500-new-art-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547751162669_11811"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751729623-C59CLX1IAXB7W7VT5Y32/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751729623-C59CLX1IAXB7W7VT5Y32/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-oregon-trail-alt.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40d12442bfc12f9674aa5a" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-oregon-trail-alt.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_24581"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1590325638875-4KWH1QV0IOF6T55KOG17/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGJPosOZKJ_5bTt_aoKLXvV7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmNO4gLeMELCxgbq9ZwIFBqyNnwMzbLyu6EqVFxy448Ac96U4dydQe93OYlnDwKBkA/Apple+Macintosh+128K+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1590325638875-4KWH1QV0IOF6T55KOG17/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGJPosOZKJ_5bTt_aoKLXvV7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmNO4gLeMELCxgbq9ZwIFBqyNnwMzbLyu6EqVFxy448Ac96U4dydQe93OYlnDwKBkA/Apple+Macintosh+128K+Model" data-image-dimensions="1126x1126" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Apple Macintosh 128K Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eca7180250a6a0b1a797f88" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_28199"><div><h3>Apple Macintosh 128K</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/5/22/apple-macintosh-128k-papercraft-design">here</a>.                                                                             </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592415789136_26033"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1592415990253-RN2H94KYOJUE65PPBML4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKAIkQk1kT2ThXQe37c2Cyd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1Ub-K2BP0W1-5FW-m4FzjPBuXfWKGAAA0gU_rp4yEhj2SOpYghpI-Ha_TwZsqqmJXng/BBC+Microcomputer+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1592415990253-RN2H94KYOJUE65PPBML4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kKAIkQk1kT2ThXQe37c2Cyd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1Ub-K2BP0W1-5FW-m4FzjPBuXfWKGAAA0gU_rp4yEhj2SOpYghpI-Ha_TwZsqqmJXng/BBC+Microcomputer+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2332x2332" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="BBC Microcomputer Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eea56aac4488718b636214d" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1592416156070_26814"><div><h3>BBC MicrocompUteR</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/6/17/bbc-microcomputer-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1588440149019_23238"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1588440199899-VSNOEOMJTK66IJ6W9RB4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGYKcJaEz4vNz2pgt2fQSqlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBgejzEWRPSQ4sX_EGpmnNOvTH6DYc2wKq80NTw9ecR6Vk-vvLi9jwd_7VQTLTqao/Commodore+VIC-20" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1588440199899-VSNOEOMJTK66IJ6W9RB4/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGYKcJaEz4vNz2pgt2fQSqlZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZUJFbgE-7XRK3dMEBRBhUpzBgejzEWRPSQ4sX_EGpmnNOvTH6DYc2wKq80NTw9ecR6Vk-vvLi9jwd_7VQTLTqao/Commodore+VIC-20" data-image-dimensions="695x695" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Commodore VIC-20" data-load="false" data-image-id="5eadac7d0ef55d3237cb1ad4" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1588440149019_29173"><div><h3>CoMMODORE VIC-20</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2020/5/2/commodore-vic-20-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_46583"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777663528-ODP80GVLTUA3SJ8S6CD2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777663528-ODP80GVLTUA3SJ8S6CD2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IBM-5100-Front-v003.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c4136514ae237dd786a3b4e" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IBM-5100-Front-v003.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_43244"><div><h3>IBM 5100 Portable computer</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/12/19/ibm-5100-portable-computer">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1553908991580_15079"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553909419711-DLINHA95G40WJTJ6B94E/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIuDfvWaFR2Iqed7asMOKyt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmT9vpqXpgR-5jHl5KNyQ_vOUsaE--K8qAsnBiQUVvocXgZXG9SlBsDZM_BtsjcH9x/IMSAI+8080-+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553909419711-DLINHA95G40WJTJ6B94E/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kIuDfvWaFR2Iqed7asMOKyt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmT9vpqXpgR-5jHl5KNyQ_vOUsaE--K8qAsnBiQUVvocXgZXG9SlBsDZM_BtsjcH9x/IMSAI+8080-+Model" data-image-dimensions="1483x1483" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMSAI 8080- Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c9ec6990d92972348b97907" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_164008"><div><h3>IMSAI 8080 (PCS-80 SYSTEM)</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/3/27/imsai-8080">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_30953"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777301331-LA12J4F2DIEBFGMU9166/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IMG_2254.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547777301331-LA12J4F2DIEBFGMU9166/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IMG_2254.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IMG_2254.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c4134f1352f53176e89c64d" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/IMG_2254.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_179064"><div><h3>Nintendo GAMECUBE</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/7/21/nintendo-gamecube-papercraft">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1558838880993_46488"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1558839026356-XPE1RQDGOLE6PZAL1UAC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sharp+X68000+Papercraft+Model+Pattern" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1558839026356-XPE1RQDGOLE6PZAL1UAC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sharp+X68000+Papercraft+Model+Pattern" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sharp X68000 Papercraft Model Pattern" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ce9fecce79c7041acbdfad7" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_142131"><div><h3>SHARP X68000</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/5/25/sharp-x68000-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_151289"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733683491-TX601XVQ4LT92TVKUWTO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/TRS-80+Model+III+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733683491-TX601XVQ4LT92TVKUWTO/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/TRS-80+Model+III+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="TRS-80 Model III Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ddc872ee9c9ef3d618bdab0" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_73296"><div><h3>TRS-80 Model III</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/11/12/trs-80-model-iii-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div></div><div><div data-aspect-ratio="75" data-block-type="5" id="block-8b4182343a2e489b8831"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751560304-UUUZ08G6JUN0O58IM2G7/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-1.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547751560304-UUUZ08G6JUN0O58IM2G7/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-1.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-1.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c40d0751ae6cf0259ec0e75" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-1.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-3aba1e0c24085fad1534"><div><h3>AmSTRAD CPC 464</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/11/30/amstrad-cpc-464-papercraft-20">here</a>.                                                                                 Prev: <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2017/1/21/amstradcpc">v1</a></p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_147172"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1571765716167-0UFNI66U7DBDC1LIEGNS/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Apple+-+Lisa+1" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1571765716167-0UFNI66U7DBDC1LIEGNS/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Apple+-+Lisa+1" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Apple - Lisa 1" data-load="false" data-image-id="5daf3dc5a50ae018ef6f1f2f" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_149636"><div><h3>APPLE - LISA 1</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/10/17/apple-lisa-1-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1549746001726_22861"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1549746395018-JW1I4T79NKIQLXYGD2SP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Atari+520+ST" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1549746395018-JW1I4T79NKIQLXYGD2SP/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Atari+520+ST" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Atari 520 ST" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c5f40bf8165f527b770bddb" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1590324703951_68471"><div><h3>ATARI 520ST</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/2/9/atari-520-st-papercraft-design">here</a>.    </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_7710"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547775762408-DNREFI406UJMGRBUDYAZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH7bcx_p807l_7aJvGUB_uN7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0moOD8BDhkEvmr_flZVBtwIChsuiQhyTIkjVQ5JuE40aqe9Md01nIM06lR7f9JJmiQ/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547775762408-DNREFI406UJMGRBUDYAZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kH7bcx_p807l_7aJvGUB_uN7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0moOD8BDhkEvmr_flZVBtwIChsuiQhyTIkjVQ5JuE40aqe9Md01nIM06lR7f9JJmiQ/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2499" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c412ecf4ae237dd7869e612" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/C64_Mini_Computer_Papercraft-Basic-2.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1549746001726_26611"><div><h3>COMMODORE 64</h3><p>Link to the latest model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/6/28/commodore-64-papercraft-v3">here</a>.                                                                             Prev: <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/3/30/c64minimonitor">v1</a>, <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/4/5/commodore-64-paper-craft">v2</a>, <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/6/14/commodore-1541-disk-drive-papercraft">v3</a> </p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_42967"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1563325867306-T0QGQTZZW2IN3FPM5NH6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM+5150+Personal+Computer" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1563325867306-T0QGQTZZW2IN3FPM5NH6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/IBM+5150+Personal+Computer" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="IBM 5150 Personal Computer" data-load="false" data-image-id="5d2e754e8f2287000141be63" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1571765454448_182957"><div><h3>IBM 5150 PERSONAL Computer</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/7/16/ibm-5150-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1553262122748_51565"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553262699056-FOSE3WO4IMXPUM9GEBK0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJNqsDNR92Zm0lZEzPpS63h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UaQfK7iYtFaG3VRabrZaB72zP5b12zwkFkkazYM2Ml-E3WUfc_ZsVm9Mi1E6FasEnQ/Nintendo+Advanced+Video+System" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1553262699056-FOSE3WO4IMXPUM9GEBK0/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kJNqsDNR92Zm0lZEzPpS63h7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UaQfK7iYtFaG3VRabrZaB72zP5b12zwkFkkazYM2Ml-E3WUfc_ZsVm9Mi1E6FasEnQ/Nintendo+Advanced+Video+System" data-image-dimensions="2375x2375" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Nintendo Advanced Video System" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c94e85b085229d4d73c7e67" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1563325615886_54104"><div><h3>Nintendo ADVANCED VIDEO SYSTEM (PROTOTYPE)</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="https://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/3/2/nintendo-avs-prototype-1983">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_143092"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733462182-PO1EQFO7VFZMCXO4TERQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sega+Master+System+Papercraft+Model" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1574733462182-PO1EQFO7VFZMCXO4TERQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/Sega+Master+System+Papercraft+Model" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sega Master System Papercraft Model" data-load="false" data-image-id="5ddc864af95aa874645141f9" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_145992"><div><h3>SEGA MASTER SYSTEM</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/11/14/sega-master-system-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1568075226922_49660"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1568075967367-ZG7V8Q7F3YITXZPQ2TJG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Sinclair+ZX+Spectrum" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1568075967367-ZG7V8Q7F3YITXZPQ2TJG/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0s0XaMNjCqAzRibjnE_wBlkZ2axuMlPfqFLWy-3Tjp4nKScCHg1XF4aLsQJlo6oYbA/Sinclair+ZX+Spectrum" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="Sinclair ZX Spectrum" data-load="false" data-image-id="5d76f0ab4daeac2b978c3f92" data-type="image">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_134908"><div><h3>Sinclair ZX Spectrum</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2019/8/17/sinclair-zx-spectrum-papercraft-design">here</a>.</p></div></div><div data-block-type="5" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1547775615568_28037"><div>








  

    
  
    <div data-test="image-block-inline-outer-wrapper">

      

      
        <figure>
          
        
        

        
          
            
          <p><img data-src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547776357981-CB2AMVR04ZPDOBNLYJPM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-2.png" data-image="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/564229dee4b0d16067409cb0/1547776357981-CB2AMVR04ZPDOBNLYJPM/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kNiEM88mrzHRsd1mQ3bxVct7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0topjEaZcWjtmMYdCWL4dkGbxs35J-ZjFa9s1e3LsxrX8g4qcOj2k2AL08mW_Htcgg/front-2.png" data-image-dimensions="2500x2500" data-image-focal-point="0.5,0.5" alt="front-2.png" data-load="false" data-image-id="5c41313e03ce6448e4275b88" data-type="image" src="http://rockybergen.com/front-2.png">
          </p>
        
          
        

        
      
        </figure>
      

    </div>
  


  


</div></div><div data-block-type="2" id="block-yui_3_17_2_1_1574732675505_149608"><div><h3>CONION C-100F</h3><p>Link to the model <a href="http://rockybergen.com/whatsnew/2018/8/11/conion-c-100f-papercraft">here</a>.</p></div></div></div></div></div>
    </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://rockybergen.com/papercraft</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25898063</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 01:33:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Universal basic income doesn’t impact worker productivity]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 46 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25897993">thread link</a>) | @CapitalistCartr
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://academictimes.com/universal-basic-income-doesnt-impact-worker-productivity/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://academictimes.com/universal-basic-income-doesnt-impact-worker-productivity/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="articleBody"><p dir="ltr"> workers with a universal basic income did not reduce the amount of effort they put into their work, according to an experiment conducted by Spanish economists, a sign that the policy initiative could help mitigate inequalities and debunking a common criticism of the proposal.</p><p dir="ltr">Examining a universal basic income worth about one-fifth of workers' median wages, the researchers also found that the threat of being replaced by robots did not impact workersâ€™ productivity, nor did a tax on firms when they replace a worker with a robot or automated process, though the latter successfully created a disincentive for managers.</p><p dir="ltr">Their <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41599-020-00676-8">research</a>, published last month in <em>Humanities and Social Sciences Communications</em>, utilized a behavioral economics lab set up by FundaciÃ³n COTEC, a nonprofit organization honorarily led by the king of Spain that promotes innovation as a driver of economic and social development. The foundation aimed to understand how automation and universal basic income may impact entrepreneurs, companies and the public sector.</p><p dir="ltr">Researchers recruited 900 individuals to take part in the experiment, 59% of whom were female and 98% of whom were university students. The average age was 21, with a minimum age of 19 and a maximum age of 30. Participants were asked to work on a set of tasks and were paid based on their performance. Researchers then introduced several different scenarios, such as replacing certain participants with robots and creating a universal basic income worth about one-fifth of the workersâ€™ median pay, to see how worker productivity was impacted.</p><p dir="ltr">Though it was a laboratory experiment, Angel SÃ¡nchez, a co-author of the research and professor at Universidad Carlos III de Madrid, said the researchers wanted to ensure their findings would be applicable in real-world situations, so the money given to participants had to be earned.</p><p dir="ltr">â€œItâ€™s not like I just give you money and then you donâ€™t feel you should care much about what to do with it,â€� SÃ¡nchez said. â€œNo â€” you earned it and youâ€™re going to feel itâ€™s yours and you donâ€™t want to throw it away. And thatâ€™s key in the experiment because thatâ€™s what we think gives external validity to the experiment.â€�</p><p dir="ltr">The researchers also vetted their experiment with the FundaciÃ³n COTEC board of trustees, many of whom are part of Spainâ€™s largest companies, â€œand they think this experiment made perfect sense, of course as a stylization of real life,â€� SÃ¡nchez said.</p><p dir="ltr">Though most of the experiment participants were university students, SÃ¡nchez said this, too, adds to the robustness of their methods â€” 40.9% of people under 25 in Spain are unemployed, according to the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development, the highest youth unemployment rate for OECD companies.</p><p dir="ltr">â€œSo we thought that they would be, for this particular problem, a very good audience because this is something that touches upon what they are going through now,â€� SÃ¡nchez said. â€œSo in that respect, Iâ€™m more confident.â€�</p><p dir="ltr">He added, though, that the results of the experiment are likely applicable outside Spain. Finland, for example, experimented in 2017 and 2018 with a universal basic income and <a href="https://www.kela.fi/web/en/news-archive/-/asset_publisher/lN08GY2nIrZo/content/results-of-the-basic-income-experiment-small-employment-effects-better-perceived-economic-security-and-mental-wellbeing">found</a> that it improved individualsâ€™ mental and economic well-being, though the employment effects were small, which SÃ¡nchez said disproves the common argument that a universal basic income would cause fewer people to work.</p><p dir="ltr">The Spanish government, in light of the COVID-19 pandemic, has <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-52707551">begun</a> its own nationwide experiment with a monthly basic income, providing approximately $500 to each adult in the program. Spain is prioritizing families, including single-parent households, and hopes to reach 1 million homes with the initiative.</p><p dir="ltr">Additionally, SÃ¡nchez said he hopes to see more research done on robots and automation, especially around how a tax on substituting a human with a robot might impact the economy.</p><p dir="ltr">â€œItâ€™s probably something governments could try at least on a smaller scale for some sectors and see what happens,â€� he said. â€œBecause this is something that, outside of this experiment, I havenâ€™t seen.â€�</p><p dir="ltr">Though a worker-replacement tax could help pay for a universal basic income, SÃ¡nchez and his colleagues also wrote in their research that an automation tax might impede technical change, which could pose long-term problems for society.</p><p dir="ltr">â€œSo other theoretical studies would be useful, too, in whatâ€™s the way to either prevent workers from being substituted by machines or to get money from the guys that are now using machines to compensate the workers that are laid off,â€� SÃ¡nchez said. â€œThese two schemes need a lot of research. Thereâ€™s very little done there.â€�</p><p dir="ltr"><em>The study â€œRobots, labor markets, and universal basic income,â€� published Dec. 16, 2020, in Humanities and Social Sciences Communications, was authored by Antonio Cabrales, Universidad Carlos III de Madrid; PenÃ©lope HernÃ¡ndez, Universitat de ValÃ¨ncia; and Angel SÃ¡nchez, Universidad Carlos III de Madrid.</em></p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://academictimes.com/universal-basic-income-doesnt-impact-worker-productivity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25897993</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 01:21:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Hacking Habit Development with iOS Shortcuts]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25897410">thread link</a>) | @kwerk
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://kylewill.blog/hacking-habit-development/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kylewill.blog/hacking-habit-development/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <h3 id="accidental-habit-development-a-year-of-walking">Accidental Habit Development: A year of walking</h3><p>I'm terrible at setting new habits. I've tried every habit app, journal method, hiding things, etc and I'm still at around 10% success rate of choosing a new habit and sticking to it.</p><p>One thing I've learned: I'm equally terrible at the habit of using habit apps.</p><p>Nearly by accident, I set a new habit in 2020 that has been consistent for 320 straight days: taking a walk. February last year, I set a (tiny) goal of walking for at least 10 minutes. Every day. I used the Streaks App, but connected to Apple Heatlh. Any time I started a walk on the Apple Watch, the time was automatically tracked in Streaks. No manual tracking required. Any time I completed a walk of 10 minutes or more, I'd get a push notification from Streaks happily encouraging me for completing my task and updating my progress.</p><p>When I first started, I was consistent because of a nascent willpower. I'd set a goal in a moment of aspriation and wanted it done. Walking 10 minutes was also <strong>easy</strong>: if I was close to missing a day, I'd feel silly not to walk 5 minutes away from my house and back. The Streaks app also acted as a safety net. If I hadn't completed a walk, I'd get a notification <strong>prompt</strong> that I was about to "break the streak". FOMO kicked in and I'd dutifully get up and start a brisk walk. It was also <strong>automated</strong>, I didn't have to build the habit of using a habit app, everything just worked. </p><p>Here's why:</p><ul><li><strong>Ease:</strong> Instead of trying to make a big change, the task was very achievable, even when motivation was low. It's more important to build consistency. The snowball rolling down the top of the mountain.</li><li><strong>Automated:</strong> The main value of a habit app is showing progress and keeping you honest (see prompts below). The problem is they require a separate behavior: tracking if your goal is done! Because the tracking is coupled with the behavior (taking a walk updates the Streaks app), all the value is received with no extra effort.</li><li><strong>Prompts: </strong>The system defaults to "internal" prompts: I should walk because I want to. But, if it's an off day or motivation is low, the Streaks app detects when a miss is imminent and sends a notification. It's like a safety net for habit development.</li></ul><p>Over time something changed... I wasn't doing the walk because it was easy. I was walking because it was just something I did."You're awake, time to walk." Walks became more than just a basic way to improve fitness. They became thinking time, time to call my Dad, or jot notes and thoughts. Now I walk 1-2 hours every morning (have had to wake up earlier for this) and can't imagine giving it up.</p><figure><img src="https://kylewill.blog/content/images/2021/01/Slice-1--52-.png"></figure><h3 id="how-does-behavior-science-explain-why-this-works">How does behavior science explain why this works?</h3><p>BJ Fogg founded the Behavior Design Lab at Stanford and has popularized the <a href="https://behaviormodel.org/">"Fogg Behavior Model" (FBM)</a>. The FBM states that each <strong>behavior</strong> consists of: sufficient <strong>motivation</strong>, sufficient <strong>ability</strong>, and the presence of a <strong>prompt</strong>. Without all three, the behavior doesn't happen. </p><figure><img src="https://kylewill.blog/content/images/2021/01/image.jpeg"><figcaption>Credit: BJ Fogg (behaviormodel.org)</figcaption></figure><blockquote>Behavior = Motivation + Ability + Prompt</blockquote><p>This explains why the walking habit stuck while others have not. The behavior required very little motivation or ability. Most importantly, loading the next prompt required zero behavior. The act of walking loaded up the next prompt and Streaks could know whether to alert to a potential miss. </p><p>What if I could apply the same principles to other habits? A system to <strong>automatically prompt</strong> <strong>easy</strong> habits?</p><h3 id="automated-information-diet-habits">Automated Information Diet Habits</h3><p>One key 2021 focus for me is my information diet. There's a glut of urgent, must-know-now, break-neck-paced news coming out the past year. And it's not slowing down. I want to stay informed, but doom-scrolling doesn't help.</p><p>The first part of improving my information diet involved setting limits on <strong>neutral-bad inputs: </strong>increase social media (Twitter/LinkedIn for me) use, mindless reddit browser, etc. h/t to Brendan Short's "<a href="https://whatilearned.substack.com/">What I Learned</a>" Substack for ideas to limit Screen Time. </p><p>The second part involves increasing input of <strong>good inputs.</strong> I'm trying to increase the time I spend reading books and long form articles. And I've found a system (10 days in) that uses the same principle as the walk habit.</p><p><strong>Here's how the system works high-level:</strong></p><figure><img src="https://kylewill.blog/content/images/2021/01/Slice-2--10-.png"></figure><ol><li>Whenever I open an app for long-form articles or books (Pocket, Kindle) a timer is started in Streaks automatically</li><li>When I close the app, the timer is stopped</li><li>When the cumulative goal time (10 minutes for now) is reached, the daily Streak is marked complete</li></ol><p>That's it. That's the system. It hits all the necessary ingredients:</p><ul><li><strong>Ease:</strong> The goals are simple 10 minutes reading a book and 10 minutes reading for learning. And since the goal is cumulative time, dropping into a book for 2 minutes still has positive reinforcement. </li><li><strong>Automatic: </strong>No need to separately track the goal. The act of doing the task is coupled with tracking the goal.</li><li><strong>Prompts:</strong> The Streaks app notifies externally if I'm about to miss a streak. But I'm also testing a new passive prompt: app recommendations. I've replaced half my home screen with a widget that displays "Siri recommended apps". Based on how you use your phone, apps are suggested to open. I'm noticing Kindle and Pocket showing up in this list more and more over the past ten days. </li></ul><p>So far, I'm 100% covering every day (even though not every day has been high motivation). Excited to share more as the habits build momentum.</p><hr><h3 id="how-exactly-the-system-works-and-how-you-can-use-it-too-">How exactly the system works. And how you can use it too.</h3><p>The secret to automatically tracking my reading involves the Streaks habit app, and Apple's built-in Shortcuts app. </p><p>Shortcuts allow for setting up workflows on your iPhone/iPad similar to IFTTT or Zapier but for apps. They also include "Personal Automations" that automatically run shortcuts when certain conditions are true: connecting to WiFi, arriving home, or (importantly) when certain apps are opened or closed. </p><p>I created two shortcuts that accept the name (or keyword) of a Timed Task in Streaks, and start or stop respectively the timer for that task. </p><p>For each app I want to trigger a Timed Task, I create a "Start" and "Stop" Personal Automation that includes the name (or keyword) of the desired Task and starts when a given app is opened or closed. </p><h3 id="running-this-yourself-">Running this yourself. </h3><figure><iframe width="356" height="200" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Ak0p6VFDT4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe><figcaption>How the automatic tracking looks at the end.</figcaption></figure><p><strong>Prerequisites</strong></p><ul><li>Install the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/streaks/id963034692?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4">Streaks App</a> and setup at least one <em>timed </em>task. I recommend starting small with "Read a Book" and a goal of 5-10 minutes a day. Something that would feel silly <em>not</em> to do if you missed it. </li><li>Open the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/shortcuts/id915249334">Shortcuts</a> app on your phone (built-in) and run at least one of the Shortcuts in the gallery. <em>Apple will not let you follow the below process until you've run at least one Shortcut.</em></li><li>Open Settings &gt; Shortcuts and select "Allow Untrusted Shortcuts". This allows you to preview and use the below pre-made shortcuts.</li></ul><p><strong>Enabling the Start Timer Automation</strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/826b1fbdbc3e42edb85742aab62e4834"><img src="https://kylewill.blog/content/images/2021/01/Start-Timer-Icon-1.png" alt="Start-Timer-Icon-1"></a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This is the automation that will (as the name implies) start tracking task completion when you open a specific app.</p><ol><li>Install this "<a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/826b1fbdbc3e42edb85742aab62e4834">Start Streak Timer</a>" Shortcut. You'll be able to review the entire logic before adding it to your library</li><li>Tap "Automation" &gt;&gt; "+" to create a new shortcut &gt;&gt;Choose "Create Personal Automation"</li><li>Scroll down and select "App" &gt;&gt; Choose the app to trigger the start time (e.g. Kindle) and make sure "is Opened" is selected &gt;&gt; Tap "Next"</li><li>Tap "Add Action" &nbsp;&gt;&gt; search for "Text", Tap "Text" under the "Actions" results &gt;&gt; Type a unique word from your Streak Task. In my case the Streak Task is "Read A Book" so I used the word "Book". This text is what's used to tell the "Start Streak Timer" shortcut which Task to start.</li><li>Tap the blue "+" to add another action. Search for "Shortcuts" and tap the "Shortcuts" App results &gt;&gt; Choose "Run Shortcut" &gt;&gt;Tap "Shortcut" in the new card that appears and search for "Start Streak Timer"</li><li>Tap "Next" in the top right &gt;&gt; Deselect "Ask before running" &gt;&gt; tap "Done"</li></ol><p><strong>Enabling the Stop Timer Shortcut</strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/165084c69cf544ce91b06856cd50dac3"><img src="https://kylewill.blog/content/images/2021/01/Stop-Timer-Icon.png" alt="Stop-Timer-Icon"></a></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>The process from stopping the timer is the exact same with changes noted in <strong>bold</strong></p><ol><li>Install this <strong>"<a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/165084c69cf544ce91b06856cd50dac3">Stop Streak Timer</a>"</strong> Shortcut. You'll be able to review the entire logic before adding it to your library</li><li>Tap "Automation" &gt;&gt; "+" to create a new shortcut &gt;&gt;Choose "Create Personal Automation"</li><li>Scroll down and select "App" &gt;&gt; Choose the app to trigger the start time (e.g. Kindle) and <strong>make sure "is Opened" is deselected and "is Closed" is selected &gt;&gt;</strong> Tap "Next"</li><li>Tap "Add Action" &nbsp;&gt;&gt; search for "Text", Tap "Text" under the "Actions" results &gt;&gt; Type a unique word from your Streak Task. In my case the Streak Task is "Read A Book" so I used the word "Book". This text is what's used to tell the "Start Streak Timer" shortcut which Task to start.</li><li>Tap the blue "+" to add another action. Search for "Shortcuts" and tap the "Shortcuts" App results &gt;&gt; Choose "Run Shortcut" &gt;&gt;Tap "Shortcut" in the new card that appears and search for <strong>"Stop Streak Timer"</strong></li><li>Tap "Next" in the top right &gt;&gt; Deselect "Ask before running" &gt;&gt; tap "Done"</li></ol>
            <section>
              <h2>Enjoying these posts? Subscribe for more</h2>
              <a href="https://kylewill.blog/subscribe/">Subscribe now</a>
              <br>
              <a href="https://kylewill.blog/signin/">Already have an account? Sign in</a>
            </section>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kylewill.blog/hacking-habit-development/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25897410</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:45:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The RustyHermit Unikernel]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 101 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25897117">thread link</a>) | @adamnemecek
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <main>
    

    

    <p><a href="https://github.com/hermitcore/rusty-hermit">RustyHermit</a> is a unikernel, which is completely written Rust. <a href="http://unikernel.org/">Unikernels</a> are application images that directly contain the kernel as a library, so they do not require an installed operating system (OS).&nbsp;They are typical used in virtualized environments, which build the backbone of typical cloud / edge infrastructures.</p>
<span id="continue-reading"></span>


<h2 id="virtualization-designs">Virtualization Designs</h2>
<p>Common virtualized environments are based on classical <strong><em>virtual machines</em></strong>. In this case, complete machines are emulated or virtualized and common operating systems are running on both host and guest site:</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/common_vm.png" alt="Structure of a common virtualitation environment"></p>
<p>This technique is established (VMware, Hyper-V, etc.) and widely used. However, it introduces additional overhead especially regarding memory consumption and performance.</p>
<p>An alternative approach to common virtual machines is <strong><em>OS-level
virtualization</em></strong>, where the&nbsp;kernel&nbsp;allows the existence of multiple
isolated&nbsp;user space&nbsp;instances. These isolated instances are also known
as container. A typical representative is LXC or Docker and promise less
overhead in comparison to common virtual machines. However, the
isolation between the processes is weaker and may provide less security.</p>
<h2 id="unikernels">Unikernels</h2>
<p>Often only one application (e.g. a web server) is running in the container or the virtual machine. In this case, a <em>unikernel</em> is an attractive solution. The kernel is provided as static library and linked to the application. As the images directly contain the OS kernel, unikernels can directly be booted inside a virtual machine and do not require the typical software stack containing a Linux kernel and its userland within the VM.</p>
<p>Unikernels do not provide system calls in the classical sense, as everything is running with the privilege level of a kernel and what is typically done via system calls is provided via a common function call. At first glance, this sounds more insecure than previous approaches. However, these kernels are expected to run within a virtual machine, which isolates the application from the real system. In addition, common compiler analysis is used to check the complete software stack and unneeded components can even be removed, which can reduce the attack surface of the application.</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/libos.png" alt="Structure of a library operating system"></p>
<p>Well known unikernels are kernels such as <a href="https://mirage.io/">MirageOS</a>
and <a href="http://www.unikraft.org/">Unikraft</a>. MirageOS is written in OCaml,
while Unikraft still uses C as programming language. In contrast to these
kernels, RustyHermit is completely written in Rust to benefit from
Rust's performance and security behavior.</p>
<h2 id="rustyhermit">RustyHermit</h2>
<p>In principle, every existing
Rust application can be built on top of RustyHermit. However, unikernels
are a single tasking operating system. Consequently, the support of the
system call <code>fork</code> and inter-process communication are missing. In
addition, a classical C library is missing, which is typical used as
interface to the operating system. Every crate, which bypasses the
standard runtime and tries to communicate directly to operating system
does not work without modifications. However, many applications do not
depend on these features and work on RustyHermit.</p>
<h3 id="performance">Performance</h3>
<p>Unikernels can be highly optimized. For instance, we optimized the
network stack of RustyHermit. RustyHermit uses
<a href="https://github.com/smoltcp-rs/smoltcp">smoltcp</a> as network stack, which
is completely written in Rust. As interface between guest and host
operating system, we use
<a href="https://www.linux-kvm.org/page/Virtio">Virtio</a>, which is in a
para-virtualized driver for KVM and widely used in virtualized Linux
environments.</p>
<p>The following figure compares Linux with RustyHermit,
where both are running as guests inside a virtual machine running on top
of a Linux-based host system:</p>
<p><img src="https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/bandwidth.png" alt="Bandwidth of the RustyHermit's exerimental network interface"></p>
<p>Especially for small messages RustHermit
is faster in than Linux.</p>
<h3 id="research">Research</h3>
<p>RustyHermit is also a research project to evaluate new operating
system designs, which improves the scalability and the security of operating systems in cloud environments. For instance, RustyHermit provides classical
techniques to improve the security behavior like stack guards and
separating the application stack from the libOS stack. However, a
library operating system typically uses a common function call to enter
the kernel. A classical separation of user- and kernel space by
entering a higher privilege level is missing.</p>
<p>We presented in a
<a href="https://www.ssrg.ece.vt.edu/papers/vee20-mpk.pdf">paper</a> a modified
version of RustyHermit, which provides an intra-unikernel isolation with
<em>Intel Memory Protection Keys</em> (MPK). MPK is a relatively new hardware
primitive that provides per-thread permission control over groups of
pages in a single address space with <a href="https://www.usenix.org/conference/atc19/presentation/park-soyeon">negligible switching overhead</a>,
making it a compelling candidate for use in unikernels.</p>
<p>MPK is requiring modification of page tables at a small performance cost. Four previously-unused bits of each page table entry (the 62nd to the 59th on x86-64) are exploited by MPK. Since MPK exploits four bits of the page table entry, it supports up to 15 protection keys.
MPK controls per-thread permission on groups of pages. Each core has a PKRU register (32 bits) containing a permission value. The value of the PKRU register defines the permission of the thread currently running on that core for each group of pages containing a protection key in their page table entries. Unlike page-table-level permission, MPK provides thread-local memory permission.</p>
<p>We provide user / kernel separation so we simply see the entire application as an untrusted component, independently of application-specific characteristics such as the language it is written in or the level of skill of the application’s programmer. In addition, we divide the kernel code into trusted and untrusted components. Trusted kernel components represent pieces of code written with a memory-safe language, i.e., offering strong security guarantees. Untrusted kernel components correspond to code written either in memory-unsafe languages or in unsafe Rust code blocks.</p>
<p>By entering the library operating system through the application binary interface the protection keys will be automatically changed, which allows access to the kernel stack and the kernel heap. Unauthorized access from within the application will trigger a pagefault, which will be handled by the library operating system.</p>
<h3 id="example-project">Example Project</h3>
<p>To give you an example on how to build an RustyHermit application, lets create a new cargo project:</p>
<pre><code><span>cargo</span><span> new hello_world
</span><span>cd</span><span> hello_world
</span></code></pre>
<p>RustyHermit currently requires the nightly versions of the Rust toolchain.
To simplify the workflow, we recommend to create the configuration
<em>rust-toolchain</em> as follows to define the required components and to
tested version of nightly compiler:</p>
<pre><code><span>[toolchain]
</span><span>channel </span><span>= "</span><span>nightly-2020-12-23</span><span>"
</span><span>components </span><span>= [ "</span><span>rustfmt</span><span>", "</span><span>rust-src</span><span>", "</span><span>llvm-tools-preview</span><span>"]
</span><span>targets </span><span>= [ "</span><span>x86_64-unknown-hermit</span><span>" ]
</span></code></pre>
<p>The configuration file specifies the required components and the version of the nightly compiler to use.</p>
<p>The RustyHermit's target <code>x86_64-unknown-hermit</code> is part of Rust
supported platforms, but doesn't belong to the <em>tier 1</em> platforms,
which means that official binary releases aren't available and the
standard runtime must be build from scratch.
To simplify this build process, we recommend to create the configuration
file <code>.cargo/config</code> as follows:</p>
<pre><code><span>[unstable]
</span><span>build-std </span><span>= ["</span><span>std</span><span>", "</span><span>core</span><span>", "</span><span>alloc</span><span>", "</span><span>panic_abort</span><span>"]

[build]
</span><span>target </span><span>= "</span><span>x86_64-unknown-hermit</span><span>"
</span></code></pre>
<p>To bind the library operating system to the application, we have to add the crate <a href="https://crates.io/crates/hermit-sys"><code>hermit-sys</code></a> to the dependencies in the file <code>Cargo.toml</code>:</p>
<pre><code><span># Cargo.toml

</span><span>[target.'</span><span>cfg(target_os = "hermit")</span><span>'.dependencies]
</span><span>hermit-sys </span><span>= "</span><span>0.1.*</span><span>"
</span><span>features </span><span>= ["</span><span>smoltcp</span><span>"]
</span></code></pre>
<p>The feature <code>smoltcp</code> is required if your application tries
to establish a TCP connection. In this case, the library operating systems
includes the TCP/stack <a href="https://github.com/smoltcp-rs/smoltcp">smoltcp</a>.
In addition <em>hermit-sys</em> depends on the tool <a href="https://crates.io/crates/cargo-download">cargo-download</a> to download required components and must be installed with the command <code>cargo install cargo-download</code>.
Finally, the application can be build with the common command <code>cargo build</code>.</p>
<p>The result is a 64-bit excutable in the <a href="https://refspecs.linuxfoundation.org/elf/elf.pdf">executable link format</a> (ELF).
To start the application within a common virtual machine, a loader is required, which initialize the processor and start the applications.
We provide a simple loader on <a href="https://github.com/hermitcore/rusty-loader">GitHub</a>.
A makefile to build the loader is part of the project.
After that, Qemu can be used to start RustyHermit in a VM as follows:</p>
<pre><code><span>qemu-system-x86_64 -display</span><span> none</span><span> -smp</span><span> 1</span><span> -m</span><span> 64M</span><span> -serial</span><span> stdio</span><span>  -kernel</span><span> path_to_loader/rusty-loader</span><span> -initrd</span><span> path_to_app/app</span><span> -cpu</span><span> qemu64,apic,fsgsbase,rdtscp,xsave,fxsr
</span></code></pre>
<p>To improve the performance, KVM can be used to use the virtualization extension of modern processors.</p>
<pre><code><span>qemu-system-x86_64 -display</span><span> none</span><span> -smp</span><span> 1</span><span> -m</span><span> 64M</span><span> -serial</span><span> stdio</span><span>  -kernel</span><span> path_to_loader/rusty-loader</span><span> -initrd</span><span> path_to_hello_world/hello_world</span><span> -enable-kvm -cpu</span><span> host
</span></code></pre><h3 id="roadmap">Roadmap</h3>
<p>For the near future, we plan to stabilize the interface to the hardware.
For instance, the support of <a href="https://virtio-fs.gitlab.io/">Virtio-fs</a>
is in an early stage. In addition, the integration into Rust standard
library isn't finalized yet and the current version runs only on x86. In the
future, we want to also support aarch64 as processor architecture.</p>


    

    
</main>

            
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rust-osdev.com/showcase/rusty-hermit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25897117</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 23:01:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Creating iOS Application Icons with SwiftUI]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25896655">thread link</a>) | @eneko
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://www.enekoalonso.com/articles/creating-ios-application-icons-with-swiftui | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.enekoalonso.com/articles/creating-ios-application-icons-with-swiftui">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">  <section itemprop="articleBody"> <p>SwiftUI was introduced to the world at WWDC in June 2019. While the main goal for SwiftUI is to build rich user interfaces on iOS and other Apple platforms, it can also be used to do other fun things.</p> <p>I couldn’t resist using SwiftUI from the command line, and I wrote about it in <a href="https://medium.com/@eneko/rasterizing-swiftui-views-from-the-command-line-80d974356c4a">Rasterizing SwiftUI views from the command line</a> to showcase how to generate static images (PNG, JPEG, etc). I published the code in GitHub at <a href="https://github.com/eneko/ConsoleUI">ConsoleUI</a>.</p> <p>Last December I used this same technique to generate social media preview images for this blog. I wrote <a href="https://www.enekoalonso.com/articles/issue-13">Generating Social Media preview images with SwiftUI and GitHub Actions</a> so other people like you could do it too.</p> <p>Today, I’m writing about generating application icons for iOS with SwiftUI. You guessed it: from the command line.</p> <h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2> <p>You can start by cloning my <a href="https://github.com/eneko/ConsoleUI">ConsoleUI</a> repo, which I have updated today to run on Xcode 12.4 with the latest SwiftUI available. Feel free to begin with an empty project too. If you do this, you’d probably want to follow the steps on the README file from that repo, or refer back to my first article on this topic.</p> <p>Xcode does not support live previews on Swift packages yet (FB8979344). To allow for realtime previews follow these steps:</p> <ol> <li>Generate an Xcode project (<code>swift package generate-xcodeproj</code>)</li> <li>Add a macOS target to the project</li> <li>Add your view to the macOS target (target <code>Foo</code> on the screenshot below)</li> </ol> <p>The generated project and target files don’t need to be committed to your repository, but you can do it if that makes it easier for later use.</p> <p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32922/105608907-b6c90800-5d5a-11eb-80d9-32de73138e75.png" alt="MySwiftUIView"></p> <p>If you cloned <code>ConsoleUI</code>, at this point you should be able to run the following commands:</p> <div><div><pre><code>swift build                  <span># build project</span>
swift run <span>&amp;&amp;</span> open test.png   <span># rasterize image and open in Preview app</span>
swift <span>test</span>                   <span># run tests</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <h2 id="drawing-app-icons">Drawing App Icons</h2> <p>This is why we are here, right? Let’s draw some cool app icons for iOS.</p> <p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32922/105609174-5935bb00-5d5c-11eb-92d9-90e73f3b2629.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 9 21 05 AM"></p> <p><a href="https://developer.apple.com/design/human-interface-guidelines/ios/icons-and-images/app-icon/">App Icon Design Guidelines</a> state icons should be a PNG image with the largest size of 1024 x 1024 pixels (@1x) for the App Store.</p> <p>We will update our view to match those dimensions, both on the rasterization code and the SwiftUI preview:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>let</span> <span>wrapper</span> <span>=</span> <span>NSHostingView</span><span>(</span><span>rootView</span><span>:</span> <span>MySwiftUIView</span><span>())</span>
<span>wrapper</span><span>.</span><span>frame</span> <span>=</span> <span>CGRect</span><span>(</span><span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>y</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>width</span><span>:</span> <span>1024</span><span>,</span> <span>height</span><span>:</span> <span>1024</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <div><div><pre><code><span>#if DEBUG</span>
<span>struct</span> <span>MySwiftUIView_Previews</span> <span>:</span> <span>PreviewProvider</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>static</span> <span>var</span> <span>previews</span><span>:</span> <span>some</span> <span>View</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>MySwiftUIView</span><span>()</span>
            <span>.</span><span>frame</span><span>(</span><span>width</span><span>:</span> <span>1024</span><span>,</span> <span>height</span><span>:</span> <span>1024</span><span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>#endif</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>We now should have a nice square to draw on.</p> <p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32922/105609268-ff81c080-5d5c-11eb-95e1-326db1a5c820.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 9 25 48 AM"></p> <p>Equally, running <code>swift run</code> from the terminal should now generate a 1024 x 1204 PNG image as output.</p> <h2 id="gradient-backgrounds">Gradient Backgrounds</h2> <p>It’s pretty common for app icons to have a gradient background. <a href="https://www.hackingwithswift.com/quick-start/swiftui/how-to-render-a-gradient">Gradients are pretty easy to do in SwiftUI</a>, lets add some:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>struct</span> <span>MySwiftUIView</span> <span>:</span> <span>View</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>gradientStart</span> <span>=</span> <span>Color</span><span>(</span><span>#</span><span>colorLiteral</span><span>(</span><span>red</span><span>:</span> <span>0.9098039269</span><span>,</span> <span>green</span><span>:</span> <span>0.4784313738</span><span>,</span> <span>blue</span><span>:</span> <span>0.6431372762</span><span>,</span> <span>alpha</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>gradientEnd</span> <span>=</span> <span>Color</span><span>(</span><span>#</span><span>colorLiteral</span><span>(</span><span>red</span><span>:</span> <span>0.3647058904</span><span>,</span> <span>green</span><span>:</span> <span>0.06666667014</span><span>,</span> <span>blue</span><span>:</span> <span>0.9686274529</span><span>,</span> <span>alpha</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>

    <span>var</span> <span>body</span><span>:</span> <span>some</span> <span>View</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>ZStack</span> <span>{</span>
            <span>LinearGradient</span><span>(</span><span>gradient</span><span>:</span> <span>Gradient</span><span>(</span><span>colors</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>gradientStart</span><span>,</span> <span>gradientEnd</span><span>]),</span>
                           <span>startPoint</span><span>:</span> <span>.</span><span>top</span><span>,</span> <span>endPoint</span><span>:</span> <span>.</span><span>bottom</span><span>)</span>
            <span>Text</span><span>(</span><span>"Hello, world!"</span><span>)</span>
                <span>.</span><span>foregroundColor</span><span>(</span><span>.</span><span>white</span><span>)</span>
                <span>.</span><span>font</span><span>(</span><span>.</span><span>largeTitle</span><span>)</span>
        <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32922/105609873-feeb2900-5d60-11eb-8781-5f2f1c281ef9.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 9 33 58 AM"></p> <h2 id="drawing-paths">Drawing Paths</h2> <p>Drawing paths in SwiftUI is a pleasure. There are pretty good articles with great examples online (some examples: <a href="https://schwiftyui.com/swiftui/paths-in-swiftui/">Paths in SwiftUI</a>, <a href="https://www.objc.io/blog/2019/08/20/paths-vs-shapes/">SwiftUI: Paths vs. Shapes</a>).</p> <p>Here is an example of drawing overlapping squares, as illustrated by Paul Hudson on <a href="https://www.hackingwithswift.com/quick-start/swiftui/how-to-draw-a-custom-path">How to draw a custom path</a>.</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>struct</span> <span>SpiroSquare</span><span>:</span> <span>Shape</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>func</span> <span>path</span><span>(</span><span>in</span> <span>rect</span><span>:</span> <span>CGRect</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>Path</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>var</span> <span>path</span> <span>=</span> <span>Path</span><span>()</span>

        <span>let</span> <span>rotations</span> <span>=</span> <span>5</span>
        <span>let</span> <span>amount</span> <span>=</span> <span>.</span><span>pi</span> <span>/</span> <span>CGFloat</span><span>(</span><span>rotations</span><span>)</span>
        <span>let</span> <span>transform</span> <span>=</span> <span>CGAffineTransform</span><span>(</span><span>rotationAngle</span><span>:</span> <span>amount</span><span>)</span>

        <span>for</span> <span>_</span> <span>in</span> <span>0</span> <span>..&lt;</span> <span>rotations</span> <span>{</span>
            <span>path</span> <span>=</span> <span>path</span><span>.</span><span>applying</span><span>(</span><span>transform</span><span>)</span>
            <span>path</span><span>.</span><span>addRect</span><span>(</span><span>CGRect</span><span>(</span><span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>-</span><span>rect</span><span>.</span><span>width</span> <span>/</span> <span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>y</span><span>:</span> <span>-</span><span>rect</span><span>.</span><span>height</span> <span>/</span> <span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>width</span><span>:</span> <span>rect</span><span>.</span><span>width</span><span>,</span> <span>height</span><span>:</span> <span>rect</span><span>.</span><span>height</span><span>))</span>
        <span>}</span>

        <span>return</span> <span>path</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>struct</span> <span>MySwiftUIView</span> <span>:</span> <span>View</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>gradientStart</span> <span>=</span> <span>Color</span><span>(</span><span>#</span><span>colorLiteral</span><span>(</span><span>red</span><span>:</span> <span>0.9098039269</span><span>,</span> <span>green</span><span>:</span> <span>0.4784313738</span><span>,</span> <span>blue</span><span>:</span> <span>0.6431372762</span><span>,</span> <span>alpha</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>gradientEnd</span> <span>=</span> <span>Color</span><span>(</span><span>#</span><span>colorLiteral</span><span>(</span><span>red</span><span>:</span> <span>0.3647058904</span><span>,</span> <span>green</span><span>:</span> <span>0.06666667014</span><span>,</span> <span>blue</span><span>:</span> <span>0.9686274529</span><span>,</span> <span>alpha</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>

    <span>var</span> <span>body</span><span>:</span> <span>some</span> <span>View</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>ZStack</span> <span>{</span>
            <span>LinearGradient</span><span>(</span><span>gradient</span><span>:</span> <span>Gradient</span><span>(</span><span>colors</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>gradientStart</span><span>,</span> <span>gradientEnd</span><span>]),</span>
                           <span>startPoint</span><span>:</span> <span>.</span><span>top</span><span>,</span> <span>endPoint</span><span>:</span> <span>.</span><span>bottom</span><span>)</span>
            <span>SpiroSquare</span><span>()</span>
                <span>.</span><span>stroke</span><span>(</span><span>lineWidth</span><span>:</span> <span>8</span><span>)</span>
                <span>.</span><span>frame</span><span>(</span><span>width</span><span>:</span> <span>600</span><span>,</span> <span>height</span><span>:</span> <span>600</span><span>)</span>
                <span>.</span><span>offset</span><span>(</span><span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>300</span><span>,</span> <span>y</span><span>:</span> <span>300</span><span>)</span>
        <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>When we run our rasterizer from the command line with <code>swift run</code>, we get this pretty icon:</p> <p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32922/105609630-73bd6380-5d5f-11eb-84b3-6652fca591f5.png" alt="Generated App Icon"></p> <h2 id="drawing-shapes">Drawing Shapes</h2> <p>Besides paths, we can also use shapes to compose our icon.</p> <p>For example, using rounded rectangle, we can replicate (to some extent) the Photos app icon shape:</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>struct</span> <span>MySwiftUIView</span> <span>:</span> <span>View</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>gradientStart</span> <span>=</span> <span>Color</span><span>(</span><span>#</span><span>colorLiteral</span><span>(</span><span>red</span><span>:</span> <span>0.9098039269</span><span>,</span> <span>green</span><span>:</span> <span>0.4784313738</span><span>,</span> <span>blue</span><span>:</span> <span>0.6431372762</span><span>,</span> <span>alpha</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>gradientEnd</span> <span>=</span> <span>Color</span><span>(</span><span>#</span><span>colorLiteral</span><span>(</span><span>red</span><span>:</span> <span>0.3647058904</span><span>,</span> <span>green</span><span>:</span> <span>0.06666667014</span><span>,</span> <span>blue</span><span>:</span> <span>0.9686274529</span><span>,</span> <span>alpha</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>))</span>
    <span>let</span> <span>petalLength</span><span>:</span> <span>CGFloat</span> <span>=</span> <span>400</span>

    <span>var</span> <span>body</span><span>:</span> <span>some</span> <span>View</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>ZStack</span> <span>{</span>
            <span>LinearGradient</span><span>(</span><span>gradient</span><span>:</span> <span>Gradient</span><span>(</span><span>colors</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>gradientStart</span><span>,</span> <span>gradientEnd</span><span>]),</span>
                           <span>startPoint</span><span>:</span> <span>.</span><span>top</span><span>,</span> <span>endPoint</span><span>:</span> <span>.</span><span>bottom</span><span>)</span>

            <span>ForEach</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>..&lt;</span><span>8</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span> <span>index</span> <span>in</span>
                <span>RoundedRectangle</span><span>(</span><span>cornerRadius</span><span>:</span> <span>petalLength</span> <span>/</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span>
                    <span>.</span><span>frame</span><span>(</span><span>width</span><span>:</span> <span>petalLength</span><span>,</span> <span>height</span><span>:</span> <span>petalLength</span> <span>/</span> <span>2</span><span>)</span>
                    <span>.</span><span>offset</span><span>(</span><span>x</span><span>:</span> <span>petalLength</span> <span>/</span> <span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>y</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span>
                    <span>.</span><span>opacity</span><span>(</span><span>0.7</span><span>)</span>
                    <span>.</span><span>rotationEffect</span><span>(</span><span>Angle</span><span>(</span><span>degrees</span><span>:</span> <span>Double</span><span>(</span><span>index</span><span>)</span> <span>*</span> <span>45</span><span>))</span>
            <span>}</span>
        <span>}</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Live preview:</p> <p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32922/105609830-bdf31480-5d60-11eb-9e9c-1556278fcca8.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 9 50 43 AM"></p> <p>And generated PNG icon image:</p> <p><img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/32922/105609832-c1869b80-5d60-11eb-9a26-8f6112024936.png" alt="Generated App Icon"></p> <p>There you go, hope you found this useful. If you do and end up using this technique, please ping me on Twitter, I cannot wait to see the app icons you create in SwiftUI.</p> <hr> <div> <p>This article was written as an issue on my Blog repository on GitHub (see <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/eneko/Blog/issues/24">Issue #24</a>)</p> <p>First draft: 2021-01-23</p> <p>Published on: 2021-01-23</p> <p>Last update: 2021-01-23</p> </div> </section>  </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.enekoalonso.com/articles/creating-ios-application-icons-with-swiftui</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25896655</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 22:08:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bell Labs Holmdel Is Now Mainly a Food Court]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25896189">thread link</a>) | @aj7
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://bell.works/new-jersey/on-the-block/#eat | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bell.works/new-jersey/on-the-block/#eat">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

            <div>

                

                <div>
    
        

                    <!-- <div class="animate__animated animate__fadeInDown page-hero"> -->
            <div>
                <p><img width="2560" height="1710" src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/OBP_8460-1-1-scaled.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
				            </div>
        
        
                <section>

                    
                        

                    
                </section>

                
            
                <section>

                    
                        

                    
                </section>

                
            
                <section>

                    
<h4>Everything you’d find in a great downtown.</h4>



<p>The Block at Bell Works is home to a diverse, growing roster of retailers and restaurants, all centered around its dramatic, quarter-mile atrium, which has been repurposed as an enclosed pedestrian street we call “The Block.” Visitors can stroll along the thriving, climate-controlled avenue that offers all the appeal of an urban ‘main street’, including an expansive food hall, pour-over coffee bar, and an array of retailers. The Block also hosts the monthly pop-up Bell Street Farmer’s Market, where local artists, artisans and other vendors put their unique creations on display.</p>













                </section>

                
            
                <section id="shop">

                                                <div>
                                
<h4>Something for everyone.</h4>
<p>There’s something for everyone on The Block. Our weekly farmer’s market welcomes a host of local artists, artisans and craftsmen offering unique, specialty goods you can’t find anywhere else. The Gathering Shops, our rotating pop up retail store, offers digitally native brands a traditional store display for shoppers to experience in person. No matter what you’re looking for you’re bound to find something special on The Block.</p>
                            </div>
                        
                        <div>

                            
                                <div>

                                    
                                        <div>

                                            <div>

                                                                                                    
                                                                                                
                                                <div>

                                                    <p><a href="https://thegatheringshops.com/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/gathering-1.png" alt="" width="300" height="300"></a></p>
<p>A retail service company that is putting a spin on the traditional “pop-up” concept across apparel, jewelry, beauty, wellness and home goods. The vision is to unite talented, up-and-coming designers with eager shoppers seeking something new and different.</p>

                                                                                                            <div>
                                                            <p><strong>Hours:</strong></p>
                                                            <table>
                                                                
                                                                    <tbody><tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Monday</span><span>Mon</span></td>
                                                                        <td>11:00 am - 3:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Tuesday</span><span>Tue</span></td>
                                                                        <td>11:00 am - 3:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Wednesday</span><span>Wed</span></td>
                                                                        <td>11:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Thursday</span><span>Thu</span></td>
                                                                        <td>11:00 am - 6:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Friday</span><span>Fri</span></td>
                                                                        <td>11:00 am - 3:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Saturday</span><span>Sat</span></td>
                                                                        <td>11:00 am - 3:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Sunday</span><span>Sun</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                                                                            </tbody></table>
                                                        </div>
                                                    
                                                </div>

                                            </div>

                                        </div>

                                    
                                        <div>

                                            <div>

                                                                                                    
                                                                                                
                                                <div>

                                                    <p><a href="https://oceanfirst.com/locations/NJ/Holmdel/bell-works/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/oceanfirst-300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300"></a></p>
<p>A community bank offering commercial and residential financing solutions, wealth management, and deposit services. OceanFirst is the largest and oldest community-based financial institution headquartered in Ocean County.</p>

                                                                                                            <div>
                                                            <p><strong>Hours:</strong></p>
                                                            <table>
                                                                
                                                                    <tbody><tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Monday</span><span>Mon</span></td>
                                                                        <td>9:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Tuesday</span><span>Tue</span></td>
                                                                        <td>9:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Wednesday</span><span>Wed</span></td>
                                                                        <td>9:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Thursday</span><span>Thu</span></td>
                                                                        <td>9:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Friday</span><span>Fri</span></td>
                                                                        <td>9:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Saturday</span><span>Sat</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Sunday</span><span>Sun</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                                                                            </tbody></table>
                                                        </div>
                                                    
                                                </div>

                                            </div>

                                        </div>

                                    
                                        <div>

                                            <div>

                                                                                                    
                                                                                                
                                                <div>

                                                    <p><a href="https://www.alchemistjewelers.com/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/alchemist-300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300"></a></p>
<p>Full Service Jeweler specializing in custom made pieces, including engagement rings and wedding bands. Watchmaker on site to handle Rolex, Omega, Cartier, Breitling. Onsite lab for all your jewelry repair needs.</p>

                                                                                                            <div>
                                                            <p><strong>Hours:</strong></p>
                                                            <table>
                                                                
                                                                    <tbody><tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Monday</span><span>Mon</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Temporarily Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Tuesday</span><span>Tue</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Temporarily Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Wednesday</span><span>Wed</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Temporarily Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Thursday</span><span>Thu</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Temporarily Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Friday</span><span>Fri</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Temporarily Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Saturday</span><span>Sat</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Temporarily Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Sunday</span><span>Sun</span></td>
                                                                        <td>Temporarily Closed</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                                                                            </tbody></table>
                                                        </div>
                                                    
                                                </div>

                                            </div>

                                        </div>

                                    
                                        <div>

                                            <div>

                                                                                                    
                                                                                                
                                                <div>

                                                    <p><img loading="lazy" src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/at-your-convenience-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300"></p>
<p>A store offering a variety of everyday items, including snacks, select groceries, toiletries, newspapers, and more.</p>

                                                                                                            <div>
                                                            <p><strong>Hours:</strong></p>
                                                            <table>
                                                                
                                                                    <tbody><tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Monday</span><span>Mon</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Tuesday</span><span>Tue</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Wednesday</span><span>Wed</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 5:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Thursday </span><span>Thu</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 9:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Friday</span><span>Fri</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 9:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Saturday</span><span>Sat</span></td>
                                                                        <td>12:00 pm - 8:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Sunday</span><span>Sun</span></td>
                                                                        <td>12:00 pm - 8:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                                                                            </tbody></table>
                                                        </div>
                                                    
                                                </div>

                                            </div>

                                        </div>

                                    
                                </div>

                            
                        </div>

                    
                </section>

                
            
                <section>

                    
                                                    <p><img src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bell-works-shopping-for-drinks.jpg" alt="">
                            </p>
                        
                        
                </section>

                
            
                <section id="eat">

                                                <div>
                                
<h4>Not your normal lunch break.</h4>
<p>Whatever you’re craving, you’ll find it on The Block. Our expansive dining hall, Bell Market, features a full roster of dining options, whether you’re in the mood for pizza, sushi or a fully-stacked deli sandwich. The options continue with Mexican restaurant Estrella Azul, Italian restaurant Mezza Luna, or The Hummus &amp; Pita Co.’s homemade fresh Mediterranean cuisine and, if you’re ready for dessert, local-favorite Jersey Freeze has you covered.</p>
                            </div>
                        
                        <div>

                            
                                <div>

                                    
                                        <div>

                                            <div>

                                                                                                    
                                                                                                
                                                <div>

                                                    <p><a href="https://www.booskerdoo.com/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/booskerdoo-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300"></a></p>
<p>Our little Booskerdoo coffee stand is all grown up. Check out Booskerdoo’s new storefront in Bell Works for locally roasted brews and awesome bakery snacks!</p>

                                                                                                            <div>
                                                            <p><strong>Hours:</strong></p>
                                                            <table>
                                                                
                                                                    <tbody><tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Monday</span><span>Mon</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 4:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Tuesday</span><span>Tues</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 4:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Wednesday</span><span>Wed</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 4:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Thursday</span><span>Thur</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 4:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Friday</span><span>Fri</span></td>
                                                                        <td>8:00 am - 4:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Saturday</span><span>Sat</span></td>
                                                                        <td>9:00 am - 4:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                
                                                                    <tr>
                                                                        <td><span>Sunday</span><span>Sun</span></td>
                                                                        <td>9:00 am - 4:00 pm</td>
                                                                    </tr>

                                                                                                                            </tbody></table>
                                                        </div>
                                                    
                                                </div>

                                            </div>

                                        </div>

                                    
                                        <div>

                                            <div>

                                                                                                    
                                                                                                
                                                <div>

                                                    <p><a href="https://www.bellmarketnj.com/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://bell.works/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bell-market-square-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300"></a></p>
<p>A food hall helmed by restaurant chef Richard J. Corbo and sommelier Chantelle Corbo, that brings a culinary …</p></div></div></div></div></div></section></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://bell.works/new-jersey/on-the-block/#eat">https://bell.works/new-jersey/on-the-block/#eat</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bell.works/new-jersey/on-the-block/#eat</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25896189</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 21:20:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Proof of X]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25895996">thread link</a>) | @dguo
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
 		
<p><span>01</span> Intro</p>



<p>Sparked by <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr/status/1273307320911450112">an interesting Twitter discussion</a>, I’ve spent a lot of time recently thinking about different proof-of-work mechanisms. </p>



<p>When I say proof-of-work, I’m not talking about consensus algorithms like the ones that some crypto currencies use. I’m talking about social networks.</p>



<p>At their core, social networks are primarily about one thing: Building social capital through signaling. As I wrote in <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/03/28/signaling-as-a-service/">Signaling as a Service</a>, signaling can be broken down into three different components:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Signaling Message</strong><br>A hidden status subtext you’re trying to convey about yourself</li><li><strong>Signaling Distribution</strong><br>The channel through which you’re communicating your signaling message</li><li><strong>Signaling Amplification</strong><br>Ways to boost your signaling message to compete against status rivals</li></ul>



<p>For example: A Patagonia vest signals both a prosocial attitude (<em>“I care about the environment</em>“) as well as wealth (“<em>I can afford to spend $500 on a jacket</em>“). Depending on where you live, it might also signal something about <a href="https://vcstarterkit.com/">your occupation</a>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/patagucci.png"></p><p>In order to signal these messages to others and build actual social capital you need a signaling distribution channel. One option would be to wear the vest in public where others can see it – but there are obvious physical constraints to the size of the audience you’d be able to reach.</p>



<p>This is where social networks come in.</p>



<p>Their primary role is to distribute signaling messages at scale and transform them into quantifiable social capital (in the form of likes and followers).</p>



<p>As social networks grow, they increase the potential reach of your signaling messages – but they also get crowded with status rivals. This is why social networks typically provide you with a set of signaling amplification tools. These tools help you boost your signaling messages and stand out from the crowd.</p>



<p>In <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/03/28/signaling-as-a-service/">Signaling as a Service</a> I compared signaling amplification to <a href="https://www.eugenewei.com/blog/2019/2/19/status-as-a-service">Eugene Wei’s idea of proof-of-work hurdles</a>, which he describes as follows:</p>



<p><i>Almost every social network of note had an early signature proof of work hurdle. For Facebook it was posting some witty text-based status update. For Instagram, it was posting an interesting square photo. For Vine, an entertaining 6-second video. For Twitter, it was writing an amusing bit of text of 140 characters or fewer. Pinterest? Pinning a compelling photo. You can likely derive the proof of work for other networks like Quora and Reddit and Twitch and so on. Successful social networks don’t pose trick questions at the start, it’s usually clear what they want from you.</i></p>



<p>But the more I think about it, the less I like the comparison. I actually think that Eugene’s proof-of-work theory only scratches the surface of what social networks actually do.</p>



<p>Let me explain.</p>



<p><span>02</span> A closer look at proof mechanisms</p>



<p>Take a look at this very cliché Instagram picture. The photographer clearly put a lot of thought and effort into its composition and applied different filters and editing tools to make it look nicer.</p>



<figure>
<img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/creativework.png">
<figcaption><span>Full disclosure: I actually took this picture from Unsplash. No influencers were harmed during the production of this blog post.<br></span>
</figcaption></figure>



<p>It’s a perfect example of Eugene’s definition of proof-of-work. <br>Proof-of-<strong><em>creative</em></strong>-work, to be more exact. </p>



<p>Editing your photo helps to amplify your signaling message and sets you apart within Instagram’s status arena (aka the newsfeed). It also adds additional signaling messages to your post: <em>“Look how great a photographer I am”</em> or <em>“I’m a creative person”</em>.</p>



<p>But those are not the main signaling messages you are communicating here. What you really want to tell your followers with this photo is something along the lines of <em>“I’m a world-traveler”</em> and <em>“I’m in a happy relationship”</em> <span>(which in turn are also just signaling proxies for wealth and mating worthiness)</span>. </p>



<p>The photo and the location tag are your proof points.</p>



<figure><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/igexample02-1.png">
<figcaption><span>If you look closely, you’ll notice additional hidden signaling messages in the form of Allbirds sneakers and what’s most likely a Patagonia vest → proof-of-ownership<br></span>
</figcaption></figure>



<p>Social networks are therefore not only signaling distribution (and amplification) networks – they also allow users to prove their signaling messages. </p>



<p>The creative proof-of-work is just pretext and helps to boost your post. What’s more important are the additional proof mechanisms that social networks provide. In the case of Instagram those are photos and location tags.</p>



<p>Instagram is essentially “pics or it didn’t happen”-as-a-service.</p>



<p><span>03</span> Implications for new social networks</p>



<p>When new social networks emerge they have to introduce new proof mechanisms to differentiate themselves from existing incumbents. These can either be novel proof-of-creative-work hurdles or completely new proof-of-x mechanisms.</p>



<p>TikTok is a good example for proof-of-<em>creative</em>-work innovation. The app provides creators with a powerful set of video editing tools that have opened a whole new level of creativity. </p>



<p>The cost to participate in TikTok’s status game is a lot higher than Instagram’s <span>(compare a well-made dance choreography on TikTok to your median Instagram travel post)</span> – but its powerful feed algorithms also make discovery easier and thus reward users faster and with more social capital. </p>



<p>TikTok doesn’t add any new proof points beyond its novel creative work hurdle though. You can signal and prove your creativity but you could achieve the same by uploading your video to Instagram.</p>



<p>Strava, on the other hand, introduced an entirely new proof mechanism: Proof-of-physical-activity. By using your phone’s GPS sensor (or a 3rd-party fitness tracker), users can actually prove how much and fast they ran or cycled. In contrast to <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2017/10/20/grounded-private-jet-hire-helps-russians-fake-lavish-lifestyles/">Instagram</a> <a href="https://www.vice.com/da/article/wdaqgw/instagrams-ballers-discount-private-jets-324">photos</a>, Strava’s proof mechanism is a lot harder to fake <span>(though there are <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=fake+strava+5k+downhill&amp;oq=fake+strava+5k+downhill">exceptions</a>)</span>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/stravaproof.png"></p><p>What’s great about Strava is that it reinforces a behavior that’s actually good for you: While the status game that initially got you into the app might be zero sum, the actual physical exercise you have to put in to compete has a very positive, compounding effect.</p>



<p>The question is: What other social networks should we build that could have similar positive feedback loops? And what are their proof mechanisms?</p>



<p><span>04</span> Strava for X</p>



<p>Let’s start with the two examples in <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr/status/1273307320911450112">this tweet</a>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/tweetstrava.png"></p><p>I love the idea of a <strong>Strava for Cooking</strong> – but I’m very skeptical that it can be built. Why? Because the necessary proof mechanisms don’t exist.</p>



<p>The primary metric you optimize on when cooking is taste. But how would you measure or quantify taste? The closest proxy to taste that we have is optics: How good does the meal that you cooked look? This can easily be proved with a photo .. but that’s a proof-of-work mechanism that Instagram already offers (including filters to make your food look nicer). As long as no one comes up with a better proof mechanism for cooking, I think it’s unlikely that we will see a successful social network in the space.</p>



<p>I’m more optimistic about <strong>Strava for Learning</strong>.</p>



<p>While the activity of learning itself might be hard to quantify, you can measure the outcome of learning: knowledge. Has anyone built a multiplayer version of <a href="https://apps.ankiweb.net/">Anki</a> yet? Flash cards would be a perfect proof-of-knowledge mechanism and could easily be turned into a game where you compete against friends.</p>



<p>Similar to physical activity in the Strava example, learning is not something that most people enjoy doing. As TikTok founder <a href="https://youtu.be/wTyg2E44pBA?t=245">Alex Zhu points out</a>, education goes a little against human nature. In combination with a strong enough signaling mechanism however, you can get users to participate. It’s kind of the opposite of <a href="https://cdixon.org/2015/01/31/come-for-the-tool-stay-for-the-network">Chris Dixon’s famous “Come for the tool, stay for the network” strategy</a>. Come for the status, stay for the tool.</p>



<p>A related product I’d love to see is <strong>Strava for Reading</strong>. Imagine an eBook reader that not only tracks how much time you spend reading but also *what* you are reading. Based on these proof-of-(reading)-work mechanisms you could build streaks or GitHub-contributions-like visualizations that incentivize users to read more (and more regularly).</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/githubforreading.png"></p><p>You could even build leaderboards for different topics based on the content of the books and articles you read. Or think about a score that indicated how balanced your reading behavior per topic was (to incentivize users to read takes on political topics from different perspectives).</p>



<p>Unfortunately, I think it’s unlikely that we will see a product like I described anytime soon. <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1086659965719404544">The world’s largest bookstore, most popular eBook reader, and biggest social network for books</a> are all owned by a company that has very little competency in design and user-facing product innovation.</p>



<p>(Side note: Amazon’s monopoly on books might be the most underrated sub-optimal equilibrium in tech.)</p>



<p>Another app that would be interesting is a social investing app. Think “Robinhood but as a social network”. It seems like investing is already quite a social activity – just look at <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-02-26/reddit-s-profane-greedy-traders-are-shaking-up-the-stock-market">communities like r/wallstreetbets</a>. As <a href="https://twitter.com/patio11/status/1250703738634829824">patio11 pointed out</a>, Robinhood already feels more like a game than a finance app.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/robinhood.png"></p><p>So why not build an investing app that opens with a feed of all your friends’ investments and their returns over time? Instead of sharing screenshots on Reddit and Instagram you could prove your investments right in the app.</p>



<p><strong>Note that an app like this would not be about signaling wealth. It’s about signaling <em>being right</em> and the ability to prove it</strong>. This is probably an even stronger and more engaging mechanism than signaling wealth – and the reason why I’m still bullish on prediction markets.</p>



<p>Perhaps a well-designed, consumer-friendly prediction market app would be the ultimate proof-of-x social network. <strong>Strava for being right.</strong></p>



<p><span>05</span> A Closing Ask</p>



<p>While we are on the topic of being right: Do you agree with my thoughts in this post? What other social networks and proof-of-x mechanisms would you like to see?</p>



<p>Please leave <a href="https://twitter.com/lehrjulian/status/1291397928788135942">your comments here</a>.</p>







<p><em>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/dwr">Dan Romero</a>, <em><a href="https://twitter.com/destraynor">Des Traynor</a>,</em></em> <em><a href="https://twitter.com/einkoenig">Jan König</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/cutler_max">Max …</a></em></p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/">https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://julian.digital/2020/08/06/proof-of-x/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25895996</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 21:02:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Moderna Vaccine Manufacturing Tracker]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25895813">thread link</a>) | @phrogdriver
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | http://eqvanalytics.com/moderna-vaccine-tracker.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://eqvanalytics.com/moderna-vaccine-tracker.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<div>
			
			<center>
				<a target="_blank" href="http://eqvanalytics.com/images/moderna-production-through-2020-01-24A.png">
					Click to view full-size<br>
					<img src="http://eqvanalytics.com/images/moderna-production-through-2020-01-24A.png"><br>
				</a>
			</center>
			<p><span>
				<p>
					<span>UPDATE JAN 24, 2021:</span><br>Over the weekend Moderna announced the release of lot number 013M20A, manufactured approximately January 21st (according to our estimate based on each lot's expiration date). For more on how we arrive at these estimates, see <em>Where The Data Comes From</em>, below.
					
					Moderna's U.S. COVID-19 vaccine delivery rate averaged 476,000 doses per day during the latter half of December, but has dropped substantially in the new year, currently averaging just 301,000 doses per day since January 1. To put this in perspective: the company would need to sustain a manufacturing rate of 1.1 <em>million</em> doses per day in order to fulfill its commitment to deliver 100 million doses by the end of March...a goal that currently looks unachievable.
				</p>
				<p>
					<span>TECH NOTE: A LOT OF TROUBLE</span><br>
					Moderna's vaccine lot number 041L20A <a target="_blank" href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2021-01-18/moderna-vaccine-allergic-reaction-california-batch">made the news</a> last week when a cluster of 6 vaccine recipients in San Diego developed severe allergic reactions, prompting the state of California to place a temporary hold on vaccinations using that lot. Moderna and the FDA are currently investigating the issue.
				</p>
				<p>
					From our perspective as dose-trackers, that event provided both some new information <em>and</em> some additional uncertainty. Our estimates of the number of US doses delivered by Moderna hinge on our assumption regarding lot sizes - how many doses of vaccine bear the same lot number. We base our estimate of that number on <a target="_blank" href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/moderna-provides-covid-19-vaccine-supply-update">Moderna's own statement</a>, on January 4, that <em>"approximately 18 million doses have been supplied to the U.S. Government to date,"</em> plus its report of 26 lots delivered up to that time, enabling us to calculate an average of 692,000 doses delivered to the US government per lot.
				</p>
				<p>
					Last week's news regarding lot 041L20A thus surprised us, when <a target="_blank" href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/statement-california-department-public-health-cdph-report">Moderna revealed</a> that the lot in question comprised 1.27 million doses, of which 964,900 had been delivered to the government.
				</p>
				<p>
					For the moment we have chosen to stick with our initial estimate of an average of 692,000 doses delivered to the government per lot, rather than the number revealed this week for lot 041L20A (965,000 doses) because the former is based on the average of 26 lots, whereas the latter is based on a single lot. We will continue to monitor information from several sources, including Moderna itself, and may adjust our lot size estimate in future, as warranted by available evidence.
				</p>
				<p>
					<span>WHY THE SLOWDOWN?</span><br>Moderna has not yet publicly discussed the dial-back in its U.S. manufacturing rate, so we're left to speculate. Our best guess is supply chain issues.
				</p>
				<p>
					Previously, Moderna's vaccine was produced exclusively by contract manufacturer <a target="_blank" href="https://www.lonza.com/">Lonza</a> at its Portsmouth NH facility. But that changed this week when Lonza gained <a target="_blank" href="https://www.reuters.com/article/health-coronavirus-swiss/lonza-gets-swiss-ok-to-start-moderna-vaccine-production-paper-idUSKBN29808X">approval</a> from Switzerland's regulatory agency, Swissmedic, to begin manufacturing at its huge Visp, Switzerland facility as well. Lonza's <a target="_blank" href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1682852/000168285220000023/lonzamodernagltafullye.htm">contract</a> with Moderna stipulates that <em>"In no event will LONZA or its Affiliates ship, or be instructed to ship, to the United States any Product Manufactured at any Facility outside of the United States."</em> That means that raw materials like the specialty lipids that go into Moderna's vaccine, which may be in short supply, are now needed by two facilities, only one of which makes vaccine for the U.S. market. The data we report here reflects only U.S. production.
				</p>
		
				<p><span>WHERE THE DATA COMES FROM:</span><br>Pharmaceutical companies normally treat their manufacturing data like state secrets, sharing them with the FDA only because they are required to, and even then only in strictest secrecy, out of the public eye. But these aren't normal times, and so the public has an unusual opportunity to track <a target="_blank" href="https://www.modernatx.com/">Moderna Therapeutics</a>' COVID-19 vaccine production rate with unprecedented clarity.</p>
			
				<p>The company's RNA-based COVID-19 vaccine, authorized by the FDA on December 20th of last year, was rushed to market long before the company knew for sure just how long the product's shelf life would be. At the time, ongoing testing had already established that its shelf life was <em>at least</em> 6 months, but still more testing would be required to reveal how much <em>longer</em> than that it might be safely stored before losing potency. That's a critical void in our knowledge for a vaccine that is America's best hope (so far) for stemming the pandemic that has already killed more than a third of a million Americans. So Moderna took the unusual step of printing no expiration dates on its vaccine vials, instead providing <a target="_blank" href="https://www.modernatx.com/covid19vaccine-eua/providers/vial-lookup">a page on its web site</a> where pharmacists and other interested parties can search for a vial's lot number and learn the company's current best guess regarding its expiration date. That's helpful because the product's current six month shelf life is likely to be found in the near future to be considerably longer than that, so this web page enables the company to revise each production lot's expiration date as future data provides deeper insight.</p>
			
				<p>But that same expiration look-up page also (and apparently unwittingly) reveals to the educated eye everything we need to know in order to track Moderna's vaccine manufacturing pace <em>in real time</em>, eliminating our dependence on the company or the federal government for answers to the critical question of how rapidly it is is cranking out the life-saving vaccine doses that will ultimately bring this deadly pandemic to an end. When you type in a vaccine lot number and click the page's 'Submit' button, Moderna's web server (housed by Amazon Web Services) replies to that query with <a target="_blank" href="https://lnl-dl.s3.amazonaws.com/Moderna/expiry.json">a JSON file</a> listing every lot of vaccine the company has released so far, along with each lot's current expiration date. Back-calculating from that expiry date, using the current 6-month shelf life figure for the vaccine, thus enables us to determine each lot's manufacturing date. And finally, we know how many doses an average lot of vaccine includes, based on the company's <a target="_blank" href="https://investors.modernatx.com/news-releases/news-release-details/moderna-provides-covid-19-vaccine-supply-update">January 4th announcement</a> that <em>"approximately 18 million doses have been supplied to the U.S. Government to date."</em> The company had produced 26 lots of vaccine in the U.S. by that date, thus allowing us to calculate that an average production lot amounts to about 692,000 doses.</p>
			</span>
		</p></div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://eqvanalytics.com/moderna-vaccine-tracker.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25895813</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 20:46:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A new newsletter on database engines, streaming systems, query planning]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25894881">thread link</a>) | @jamii
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/a-new-newsletter/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/a-new-newsletter/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
  <p>Dan Luu has been trying for months to persuade me that I should start a paid newsletter so that I can spend more time researching and writing interesting things. He hardly ever even mentions the existence of his own <a href="https://www.patreon.com/danluu/posts">private patreon posts</a> and still manages to make decent pocket money out of them, so this doesn't seem like an unreasonable idea.</p>
<p>I produce a lot of writing that mostly just gets sent to friends or left to rot on my hard drive. When I get around to turning something into a blog post it <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/from?site=scattered-thoughts.net">tends to end up on the Hacker News front page</a>. It still seems kind of crazy to me that anyone might want to pay for my writing, but it also used to seem crazy to me that people would pay for my code. Maybe I'm just not very good at capitalism.</p>
<p>So I'm going to give this a go - any <a href="https://github.com/sponsors/jamii">github sponsors</a> at any tier will get access to all the new posts. Using github instead of substack is maybe a weird choice, but I want to be able to embed katex and interactive demos in the posts and provide code alongside for examples and case studies. I also expect to be releasing more open-source software this year as a side-effect of doing less consulting.</p>

<p>Here are the kinds of things that I might be working on and writing about this year:</p>
<ul>
<li>Big projects 
<ul>
<li>Past examples - <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/a-practical-relational-query-compiler-in-500-lines/">A practical relational query compiler in 500 lines of code</a>, <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/relational-ui/">A UI library for a relational language</a>, <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/julia-as-a-platform-for-language-development/">Julia as a platform for language development</a>, <a href="https://kevinlynagh.com/reltron/">A UI for exploring relational databases</a></li>
<li>Designing a database query language that supports abstraction. An <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/imp-intro/">ongoing</a> project which is 80% done and just needs a sustained slog to finish the last 80% and produce a clear writeup and demo.</li>
<li>Building a text editor from scratch. An <a href="https://git.sr.ht/%7Ejamii/focus">existing project</a>, already in daily use. Posts will start with absolute basics (eg how to render simple UI in opengl) and eventually catch up to ongoing development (currently working on editing 1gb files at 60 fps without dropping frames).</li>
<li>Benchmarking streaming systems. A new project for 2021. Existing streaming benchmarks suffer from problems like <a href="https://github.com/frankmcsherry/blog/blob/master/posts/2015-01-15.md">measuring how well they can parallelize the overhead they added to the original problem</a>, <a href="https://github.com/frankmcsherry/blog/blob/master/posts/2018-02-11.md">mostly measuring distributed json de/serialization</a> or even just <a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2015/10/5/your-load-generator-is-probably-lying-to-you-take-the-red-pi.html">quietly ignoring pauses</a>. I want to figure out how to measure these systems correctly, begin to map out the space of engineering tradeoffs and try to extract some lessons for designers of future systems.</li>
<li>Building an embedabble relational database with incrementally maintained views. Another new project for 2021. An attempt to place the ideas from <a href="https://github.com/TimelyDataflow/differential-dataflow/">differential dataflow</a> into a <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/why-isnt-differential-dataflow-more-popular/">more accessible</a> form.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Little projects
<ul>
<li>Past examples - <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/staged-interpreters-in-rust/">Staged interpreters in Rust</a>, <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/zero-copy-deserialization-in-julia/">Zero-copy deserialization in Julia</a>, <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/open-multiple-dispatch-in-zig/">Open multiple dispatch in zig</a>, <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/pinephone-first-steps/">Writing a simple app for the pinephone</a>, <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/vive-experiments/">Vive experiments</a></li>
<li>Ideas for 2021:
<ul>
<li>See if the <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9152719">IJON fuzzer</a> can discover new planning bugs in SQL databases</li>
<li>Record my screen for an entire week long coding project. Find out where the time goes and what the bottlenecks are.</li>
<li>Figure out how to measure the battery usage of desktop programs on linux, and find the biggest offenders.</li>
<li>Figure out how to execute arbitrary zig expressions when debugging a running program. Maybe <a href="https://frida.re/">frida</a> can inject them?</li>
<li>There's some folk wisdom that <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1803.09930">multiway join algorithms</a> are more robust to planning errors than traditional binary joins. Is this true? Why?</li>
<li>Experiment with using <a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/2020/02/securing-firefox-with-webassembly/">embedded wasm sandboxes</a> to prevent memory safety bugs from escalating into vulnerabilities.</li>
<li>Figure out how to systematically avoid common benchmarking mistakes eg is it possible to eg combine <a href="https://github.com/plasma-umass/coz">coz</a> and <a href="https://people.cs.umass.edu/%7Eemery/pubs/stabilizer-asplos13.pdf">stabilizer</a> or will they interfere with each other?</li>
<li>Can differential dataflow handle late-arriving data by using bitemporal timestamps?</li>
<li>Document how to use the <a href="https://github.com/wolfpld/tracy">tracy profiler</a> via C bindings.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://distill.pub/2017/research-debt/">Distilling</a> existing research in my own field eg:
<ul>
<li>Why don't existing query planners work well for streaming systems?</li>
<li>How can we optimize query plans for worst-case performance over a range of input sizes, rather than best-case performance over the current input sizes?</li>
<li>Why do modern databases contain compilers?</li>
<li>How does <a href="https://github.com/TimelyDataflow/differential-dataflow/">differential dataflow</a> work? How does it differ from <a href="https://github.com/janestreet/incremental">Incremental</a>? Which approach is better for which problems?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Reading
<ul>
<li>Literature reviews, mostly focused on databases, query languages, query planning (especially in streaming systems), compilers, incremental view maintenance, self-adjusting computation</li>
<li>Book summaries. I <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/notes.html">used to publish</a> summaries of everything I read. Even though they aren't linked from anywhere anymore google still sends a few thousand people to them each month, so I guess they must be useful. I typically read <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/scattered-thoughts">~100 books</a> per year, of which ~25 are non-fiction, mostly tech, cognitive science, economics, sociology etc. </li>
<li>Other curiosity-driven binges eg <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/qnd-review-of-ppig-1989-2015/">reading every paper ever published in the Psychology of Programming Interest Group</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Random musings eg <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/small-tech/">Small tech</a>, <a href="https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/frugality-is-non-linear/">Frugality is non-linear</a></li>
</ul>
<p>I've spent the last 7 years building database engines, query planners, compilers, developer tools and interfaces for <a href="https://materialize.com/">Materialize</a>, <a href="https://www.relational.ai/">RelationalAI</a>, <a href="https://developer.logicblox.com/technology/">LogicBlox</a> and <a href="http://witheve.com/">Eve</a>, as well as various smaller consulting gigs and personal research projects. I expect to be informative when talking about those subjects, and at least entertaining when talking about other subjects.</p>
<p>Some of the posts will also be published on this blog. Others will be exclusive to the newsletter. I expect the schedule to consist of bursts of activity interspersed with weeks of frustrated silence.</p>
<p>It may seem strange, but this is one of the most frightening things I've done in years. I can only see that as a good sign.</p>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://scattered-thoughts.net/writing/a-new-newsletter/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25894881</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 19:20:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why do so many brands change their logos and look like everyone else?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25894543">thread link</a>) | @_Microft
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://velvetshark.com/articles/why-do-brands-change-their-logos-and-look-like-everyone-else | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://velvetshark.com/articles/why-do-brands-change-their-logos-and-look-like-everyone-else">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A few months ago, I received an email from Revolut (a British fintech company) in which they proudly unveiled their new logo. Previously, Revolut had a distinct and instantly recognizable logo. They replaced it with… something I was sure I had seen before.</p><figure id="w-node-3786e8b28af7-27e1f180"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fb51cf030355219306e8edf_revolout-logo-old-new.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><p>The previous Revolut logo had a unique font, a recognizable color gradient, and it was slanted. If you were to put 100 financial or tech companies’ logos next to each other, the old logo would be easy to find at a glance.</p><p>If you put the new one in the same 100 logos pile, it would drown in the sea of sameness.</p><h2>Sans serif invasion</h2><p>There is a trend in logo design that started around 2017-2018. It’s as if many companies decided that being unique was a handicap and that it was better to be like everyone else. Or at least, that’s how it feels to me.</p><p>The trend started with fashion logos. Many iconic fashion companies ditched their recognizable logos and switched to a bland and very similar version of a sans serif font.</p><p>The technology sector followed soon after.</p><figure id="w-node-519323ea72d8-27e1f180"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fb51d96d2b8eae559c71d90_tech-fashion-logos-sans-serif.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><p>All the quirks, peculiarities, and idiosyncrasies of both tech and fashion logos were dropped and replaced with a simple sans serif font.</p><p>It looked like two huge industries decided to use the services of one designer, and not a particularly inventive one at that.</p><p>The tech industry is in slightly better shape because they didn’t go all in, and at least they kept the colors. With the colors, there’s at least <em>some </em>variability:</p><figure id="w-node-1efc3a7d060a-27e1f180"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fb51dc4daea171c45c758db_tech-logos-color.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><p>Variability in new fashion logos, in full color:</p><figure id="w-node-b31dea70a84e-27e1f180"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fb51dd2ab19486dcee8bcea_fashion-logos-color.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><h3>Serif and sans serif—what’s the difference?</h3><p>First, what’s the difference between serif and sans serif fonts?</p><figure id="w-node-7e6a894d6cf3-27e1f180"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fb51e06556217fb8d809964_serif-sans-serif.gif" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><p>The small features on the ends of strokes in some fonts are known as ‘serifs’.</p><p>Fonts without those small features are called ‘sans serif’ (<em>‘sans’</em> means <em>‘without’</em> in French).</p><p>Sans serifs are missing a few of the typical anatomical features (serifs, spurs, swashes and other flourishes). Because of that, this typeface lacks the level of detail and design differentiation that serif typefaces can have.</p><p>While the simplicity of sans serif fonts makes them readable and versatile, it has its drawbacks. Without additional details and features, sans serif fonts have far fewer options for differentiation. While you can vary things like the height, weight, and slant, sans serif fonts simply have fewer features to work with than their more intricate fellow fonts.</p><p>This results in logos that look very similar. Gone are all the elaborate little details of the previous era.</p><p>When you add brands’ tendency to go black-and-white, you end up with a sea of logo sameness which is the opposite of what logos should be.</p><p>The purpose of a logo is to be instantly recognizable, different, memorable, and, if possible, to refer to the brand’s values. Blending into everyone else’s achieves none of these things.</p><h3>Sans serif history</h3><p>Sans serif lettering and fonts, first created in 1816, were popular for their clarity and legibility at a distance in advertising and display use when printed very large or small.</p><p>Because sans serif type was often used for headings and commercial printing, many early sans serif designs did not feature lowercase letters.</p><p>Simple sans serif capitals, without the use of lowercase, became very common in uses such as tombstones of the Victorian period in Britain.</p><p>Also, a significant reason for serif faces in the older days of imprecise letterpress and less consistent paper surface sizing was to compensate for ink spread and aberrations. Serifs on the fonts helped in cases where corners would otherwise fail to fully imprint.</p><h2>Possible reasons</h2><p>What are the possible reasons for this sans serif trend taking over? And why do hardly any of them matter?</p><h3>‘Modern utility’</h3><p>Branding specialists point to the practical benefits of what they call the ‘modern utility’ of sans serif typefaces. Cleaner and more legible, they are better suited to a variety of media and work particularly well online. The purity of these fonts allows the brands to be an empty vessel, ready to accommodate rapidly shifting trends.</p><p><strong>Counterpoint:</strong> That may be true, but isn’t the whole value of a brand to <em>not</em> be an empty vessel? The big brands have worked decades for their identity and recognition, only to throw most of it away?</p><h3>Simplification</h3><p>Another reason cited by brand specialists is that it’s a natural step for brands to take as they grow from scrappy startups into established brands. The goals have shifted from making noise and standing out to being a trusted, dependable part of people’s everyday lives. That heartfelt personality and idiosyncrasy that defined a brand as they started out, and won over their early adopters, can be a limitation as they aim for broad appeal and bigger revenue.</p><p><strong>Counterpoint:</strong> Simplification as a reason to blend in for broad appeal? I don’t buy it. Logos should be simple, yes, but they should be simple in a memorable way. Think more in terms of Nike swoosh (simple, memorable),&nbsp; and less in a one-size-fits-all sans serif font.</p><h3>Brands are more than logos now</h3><p>People at the head of these powerful brands know that they are not defined by their logo anymore but by the product or service they provide. They are strong thanks to what they allow <em>you</em> to do with them.</p><p>Before, logo designers would look for a ‘concept’ when designing a logo. That is not necessary anymore: <em>The brand is the concept</em>.</p><p>Their thinking goes that logos may look similar, but what they offer is completely different and effective, and that’s what ultimately counts for the consumer.</p><p>As some brands become words (or even better, verbs) in our daily language (to Google, to Uber, to Skype), they have a lesser need for a recognizable logo. Many of those brands now spend on designing custom typefaces instead of logos: a custom typeface becomes their recognizable voice on every platform or device.</p><p><strong>Counterpoint:</strong> Some big brands may indeed have a lesser need for a very distinct logo but that doesn't mean that they should get rid of an important differentiator. You don’t see Nike replacing their swoosh logo with sans serif <strong>NIKE</strong> text. If you have something valuable that you <em>can</em> live without, it doesn’t mean that you <em>must</em>.</p><h3>Readability</h3><p>One of the main reasons for the sans serif logo trend is readability. Especially on mobile, but everywhere else as well: from huge billboards to tiny footer links at the bottom of mobile websites.</p><p>After all, that’s the very reason why sans serif fonts were invented: for better readability in advertising headlines.</p><p><strong>Counterpoint:</strong> Readability is obviously important. Mobile too—it’s where everything happens nowadays. But this is becoming less of an issue with improvements in technologies like retina displays and 4k screens becoming popular.</p><figure id="w-node-38988d1753c7-27e1f180"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fb51e96e07b893538cbb00b_sans-serif-logos-on-iphone-11.png" loading="lazy" alt=""></p><figcaption>Here’s how a bunch of logos looks on my iPhone 11</figcaption></figure><p>If it’s easy to fit 30 decently looking logos on one-third of a phone screen, it should be trivial to make one logo, however quirky, look perfect on mobile.</p><p>Revolut seems to be torn here. They did replace the logo everywhere inside the app, but how does their new app icon look like?</p><figure><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fb51ed3fd0200eeffdc690d_revolut-app-icon.jpg" loading="lazy" alt=""></p></figure><h2>What next?</h2><p>There’s nothing bad in wanting your logo to look simpler, better, mobile-ready, or universal enough to appeal to the broadest possible audience.</p><p>But don't throw the baby out with the bathwater.</p><p>Shoot for simplicity and legibility, but keep your distinguishing features. Don’t throw away what the brand has been working on for decades.</p><p>Otherwise, you may end up in a situation where you could slap any logo on any product and hardly anyone would notice a difference:</p><figure id="w-node-01df0773e426-27e1f180"><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5f1b01fee505292d2d6a6979/5fbf32ea6160018ba6a9cb84_sans-serif-bags.jpg" loading="lazy" alt=""></p><figcaption>One of these bags is real.</figcaption></figure></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://velvetshark.com/articles/why-do-brands-change-their-logos-and-look-like-everyone-else</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25894543</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:47:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Our experience with the Fediverse, and why we left]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 202 | Comments 193 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25894414">thread link</a>) | @dsego
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody"><p>The “Fediverse” is a loose aggregation of federated servers that mainly speak the ActivityPub protocol. One of the most famous services in the Fediverse is “Mastodon.” We joined the Fediverse in the early days of Mastodon to share short-lived information that didn’t fit into a separate article on our website.</p><h2 id="the-issues-that-we-discussed-earlier-this-year">The issues that we discussed earlier this year</h2><p>In May, <a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-05-31-monthly-review/#fediverse">we reconsidered our presence in the Fediverse</a>. Back then, the main issues for us were:</p><ol><li>You can’t migrate your posts if you need to migrate to another Mastodon server.</li><li>You can’t update your posts without losing shares and comments.</li><li>All posts have a character limit, so we can’t say everything we want in a single post.</li><li>Many Fediverse users claim to be the “better and open-minded alternative to Twitter.” We think that this doesn’t reflect reality, as explained below.</li></ol><p>In June, we addressed issues 1 to 3 by introducing a “News” section on our website.</p><h2 id="further-issues-in-the-fediverse-and-other-social-networks">Further issues in the Fediverse and other social networks</h2><p>We also participated in discussions and tried to encourage dialogs in the Fediverse and other forums instead of only posting information. However, these discussions revealed consistent issues:</p><h3 id="the-toxic-us-vs-them-ideology">The toxic “us vs. them” ideology</h3><p>For some groups, it is vital to make a bogeyman out of opposing parties. In the Fediverse, some individuals and groups continuously spread misinformation about “the others” to gain likes and followers. While most of the toxic behavior targets the big tech companies in the USA, some individuals targetting us.</p><h3 id="the-reverse-burden-of-proof">The “reverse burden of proof”</h3><p>When discussing with others, we often encountered the “reverse burden of proof.” Somebody posts negative claims about a product or service. Instead of providing (technical) proof for the claim, the only supporting “fact” is, “everybody knows that this is true.” On the contrary, this person doesn’t accept any (technical) proof that debunks their initial claim. For us, it looks like you don’t need to provide any real facts as long as you satisfy the ideology of some people.</p><h3 id="the-i-read-headlines-only-problem">The “I read headlines only” problem</h3><p>Many people read the headlines of a post and then guess what is written in the remaining article. Such behavior results in misinterpreted information and persistent myths. On the other hand, it became a standard tool for some blogs to gain more readers: Writing, “Critical security vulnerability could leak all of your data” results in more clicks and shares than, “Company fixed potential security vulnerability months ago, which could have leaked some of your data if ever exploited.” This problem kills meaningful discussions instantly.</p><h3 id="the-security-and-privacy-by-assumption-problem">The “security and privacy by assumption” problem</h3><p>Most of you know “security by obscurity,” when security relies on keeping the implementation secret. We see another common issue: “security and privacy by assumption.” Many people share security and privacy tips without ever checking whether these tips work. They just assume that somebody else checked it before.</p><h3 id="and-finally-comparing-apples-to-oranges">And finally, “comparing apples to oranges”</h3><p>For instance, some people claim the Signal messenger became insecure after introducing the Signal PIN because a server-side attacker could now access your data. The base for this claim is the assumption that a server-side party extracts encrypted information from the volatile main memory of a server, exploits an unpatched security vulnerability in Intel CPUs to extract a key, and successfully guesses a user-provided password.</p><p>While the attack looks anything but trivial as these people describe it, they then argue that their favorite messenger is far more secure due to being decentralized. They compare the encryption mechanism of instant messenger A with something else. Suppose you look at the same feature of their favorite messenger. In that case, you see that their messenger doesn’t offer any server-side protection. In their case, a server-side party can directly access your data in cleartext—this is trivial.</p><h3 id="im-privacy-friendly-please-donate">“I’m privacy-friendly; please donate”</h3><p>The issues mentioned above are also prevalent on other social networks like Twitter. Just like on Twitter, you see “privacy-friendly” companies trying to gain more paying customers or some bloggers heavily involved in influencer marketing. While most of them claim that this is for a “good cause,” it is ultimately all about money.</p><h3 id="decentralization-still-isnt-a-privacy-feature">Decentralization still isn’t a privacy feature</h3><p>Now, some people may insist that at least security and privacy are far better “due to the decentralized nature” of the Fediverse. As we wrote several times before, “decentralization” isn’t a privacy feature.</p><p>Search engines like Google can discover and index all of your public posts in the Fediverse. By default, you can see the social graphs of all accounts, as followers are public. Especially Mastodon servers come with privacy policies that don’t meet the European GDPR requirements. Many (Mastodon) servers seem to run an outdated version, indicating inadequate security practices.</p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>Should you become part of the Fediverse by creating an account? It isn’t up to us to decide this, of course.</p><p>If you only want to read the content of others, we recommend subscribing to their RSS feeds. Your RSS subscriptions are private and more decentralized than any Fediverse account. And you need to manage one account less on the internet.</p><p>If you want to be an active part of the Fediverse, be prepared for the same problems as on any other social network. We decided to leave the Fediverse for now.</p><h2>Read also</h2><ul><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-20-contact-and-feed/">On contacting us, and subscribing to our RSS feed</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-11-08-rss-update/">Update of our RSS/Atom feed</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-08-02-tls-insights/">TLS usage of InfoSec Handbook readers</a></li><li><a href="https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-08-01-introducing-the-news-section/">Introducing the 'News' section</a></li></ul></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://infosec-handbook.eu/news/2020-12-05-leaving-the-fediverse/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25894414</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:33:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Quebec researchers say they have found an effective drug to fight Covid-19]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 8 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25894283">thread link</a>) | @wstrange
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://montreal.ctvnews.ca/quebec-researchers-say-they-have-found-an-effective-drug-to-fight-covid-19-1.5279310 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://montreal.ctvnews.ca/quebec-researchers-say-they-have-found-an-effective-drug-to-fight-covid-19-1.5279310">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>MONTREAL -- 
	A team of researchers from the Montreal Heart Institute believe they have found an effective weapon against COVID-19: colchicine, an oral tablet already known and used for other diseases.</p>
<p>
	For Dr. Jean-Claude Tardif, who led the study, this is a "major scientific discovery," he said. Colchicine is the first "effective oral drug to treat out-of-hospital patients."</p>
<p>
	"To be able to offer this, from Quebec, and for the planet, we are very happy," said Tardif.</p>
<p>
	<a href="https://www.colcorona.net/" target="_blank">The ColCorona study</a> involved 4,159 patients whose diagnosis of COVID-19 had been confirmed by a nasopharyngeal test (PCR).</p>

<p>
	Analysis of the study found that colchicine resulted in reductions in hospitalizations by 25 per cent, the need for mechanical ventilation by 50 per cent, and deaths by 44 per cent.</p>
<p>
	"This is the first hope for patients who have COVID, who are worried and who hope that they will not have complications," said Tardif. Previously, "there were no tablets that could be taken by mouth and reduce the risks."</p>
<p>
	Tardif said he believes that prescribing the drug could help reduce congestion in hospitals quickly and reduce health-care costs in Quebec and elsewhere.</p>
<p>
	"Our study showed the effectiveness of treatment using colchicine to prevent the phenomenon of the major inflammatory storm and reduce complications related to COVID-19," he said.</p>
<p>
	As colchicine is a well-understood drug, it could be used very quickly to treat people with COVID-19, the researcher says.</p>
<p>
	"Colchicine is old as it is -- we've been treating gout with it for hundreds of years -- so it's available in pharmacies," Tardif said, speaking in French.</p>
<p>
	"So any doctor, tomorrow, who reads this can definitely decide to prescribe if he wants."</p>
<p>
	On Friday evening, Quebec Premier Francois Legault called the study "big news" on social networks.</p>
<p>
	In the spring, Legault said the Colcorona study was one of the largest studies in the world researching ways to fight the virus.</p>
<p>
	The randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study was deployed in Canada, the United States, Europe, South America and South Africa.</p>
<p>
	"It was a double-blind study, meaning neither the patient, nor the team that ran the study, including me, knew whether the patient was taking the placebo or the drug," explained Tardif.</p>
<p>
	"There was just one group, independent from us, which was aware."</p>
<p>
	He said the team is "very proud of the work accomplished -- it is a clinically convincing result," adding that he assembled a spectacular team from all over Quebec including microbiologists, intensive care specialists, statisticians, computer scientists and epidemiologists.</p>
<p>
	The Centre de Coordination des Essais Cliniques de Montréal (MHICC) of the Montreal Heart Institute coordinated the study.</p>
<p>
	<em>This report by The Canadian Press was first published Jan. 23, 2021.</em></p>
                                              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://montreal.ctvnews.ca/quebec-researchers-say-they-have-found-an-effective-drug-to-fight-covid-19-1.5279310</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25894283</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Analyzing the Words Used to Describe the January 6 Capitol Attack]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 7 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25893887">thread link</a>) | @amoorthy
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://blog.thefactual.com/insurrection-siege-riot-the-words-describe-capitol-attack | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.thefactual.com/insurrection-siege-riot-the-words-describe-capitol-attack">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<div>


<p><span id="hs_cos_wrapper_post_body" data-hs-cos-general-type="meta_field" data-hs-cos-type="rich_text"><p>The words media outlets use to describe events play a large role in shaping public perception of those events. As January 6 unfolded on Capitol Hill, there was a rapid shift in language, from “<a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/gop-senators-reverse-objections-electoral-college-certification-protesters/story?id=75099780" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>protesters</span></a>,” “<a href="https://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Politics/2021/0112/How-a-mob-stormed-the-Capitol-and-how-to-stop-another-assault" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>supporters</span></a>,” and “<a href="https://theconversation.com/nonprofits-helped-organize-the-pro-trump-rally-before-the-capitol-siege-but-they-probably-wont-suffer-any-consequences-153271" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>rally</span></a>” to “<a href="https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/news/congress-combat-veteran-military-experience" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>siege</span></a>,” “<a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/ex-firefighter-robert-sanford-arrested-for-allegedly-hurling-fire-extinguisher-at-cops-during-capitol-riots" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>rioters</span></a>,” and “<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2021/01/08/1015929/archive-capitol-insurrection-trump-maga-footage/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>insurrection</span></a>.” These choices — on the day of the attack and in its aftermath — matched the descent of a seemingly peaceful protest into a violent and dangerous attack on the seat of the U.S. federal government.&nbsp;</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Using 5,057 article titles about the Capitol Riot from 398 sources across the political spectrum, The Factual examined how the events and aftermath of January 6 are most commonly described in U.S. and global media. This includes the differences in language between left- and right-leaning publications, as well as how the terminology used compares to <a href="https://blog.thefactual.com/protest-riot-headlines-george-floyd" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>our analysis</span></a> of coverage of the George Floyd protests this summer.&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Note: An article’s title is not always a perfect representation of its content, but titles matter deeply in shaping readers’ perceptions of what media outlets are writing, whether there are contrasting views between political parties, and whether/how an event matters — especially in the social media era.</em></p>
<h4><strong>The Words Used to Describe January 6</strong></h4>
<p>The U.S. media ecosystem includes hundreds of outlets, reflecting the myriad ideologies, political alignments, and niche areas of interest that motivate the American populace. They help define the core issues that drive American political and social discourse, and the words they use are central to how Americans understand current events. It should be no surprise, then, that the ways the media talks about the events of January 6 are key to building a consensus about what happened and unpacking how such an event may impact the U.S. going forward.</p>
<p>While there are some clear differences in the way the left and right talk about the Capitol Riot, instances of agreement are a good place to start. For example, there seems to be broad consensus that January 6 constituted a <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/capitol-police-intelligence-report-before-capitol-breach-warned-congress-itself-could-be-targeted" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>riot</span></a>, not something less intense like a <a href="https://theprint.in/world/terrorism-or-protest-how-the-us-media-saw-the-siege-of-the-capitol/582443/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>protest</span></a> or something more intense like a <a href="https://theconversation.com/was-it-a-coup-no-but-siege-on-us-capitol-was-the-election-violence-of-a-fragile-democracy-152803" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>coup</span></a>. Around 40% of article titles from both left-leaning (41.3%) and right-leaning (38.2%) outlets in our sample used the term “riot.” While the term “protest” was twice as likely to appear in titles from the right, the term appeared in just 5.5% of all articles, demonstrating that the term was inadequate to capture the day’s events. Meanwhile, “rally,” the purported nature of the <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/stop-the-steal-organizer-gop-members-helped-him-plan-rally-2021-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>pro-Trump gatherings</span></a> prior to the riot, appeared in just 1.2% of titles.</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png?width=417&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 6.34.06 PM" width="417" srcset="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png?width=209&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png 209w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png?width=417&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png 417w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png?width=626&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png 626w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png?width=834&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png 834w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png?width=1043&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png 1043w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png?width=1251&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.06%20PM.png 1251w" sizes="(max-width: 417px) 100vw, 417px"></p>
<p>Other words were used with roughly similar frequency regardless of the publisher’s political bias. Reporting from across the political spectrum mentions “violent” or “violence,” “siege,” and “police” about the same amount, reflecting at least a partial shared understanding of the lengthy clashes between police and the numerous rioters. Further, just 16 of the 5,057 article titles included the word “peaceful.”</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png?width=410&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 6.34.16 PM" width="410" srcset="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png?width=205&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png 205w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png?width=410&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png 410w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png?width=615&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png 615w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png?width=820&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png 820w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png?width=1025&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png 1025w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png?width=1230&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.16%20PM.png 1230w" sizes="(max-width: 410px) 100vw, 410px"></p>
<p>A third of article titles on the left (33%) and a quarter of those on the right (26%) mention Trump, highlighting a shared understanding of his proximity to the events of January 6. However, there are some clear differences in usage. While many of the article titles from the right are <a href="https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/news/donald-trump-pressure-condemn-violence-capitol-twitter-rage" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>ambiguous</span></a> about Trump’s role, articles from the left directly accentuate his <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-55574780" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>connection</span></a> to the riot, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/13/us/politics/trump-video-capitol-riot.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>slow condemnation</span></a> of the violence, and <a href="https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2021/01/trump-capitol-attack-impeachment-evidence-insurrection.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>culpability</span></a> in the aftermath.<img src="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png?width=403&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 6.34.26 PM" width="403" srcset="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png?width=202&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png 202w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png?width=403&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png 403w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png?width=605&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png 605w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png?width=806&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png 806w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png?width=1008&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png 1008w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png?width=1209&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.26%20PM.png 1209w" sizes="(max-width: 403px) 100vw, 403px"></p>
<div><p>Language also varied when discussing the behavior of the rioters. Article titles on the left were more likely to mention “mob,” “attack,” and “insurrection,” zeroing in on how pro-Trump supporters engaged in <a href="https://www.axios.com/mob-violence-trump-republicans-condemn-d508f105-aa77-435f-bd81-f4e74b011694.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>violent action</span></a> against DC Capitol Police and invaded the Capitol building.</p><p><img src="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png?width=409&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 6.34.33 PM" width="409" srcset="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png?width=205&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png 205w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png?width=409&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png 409w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png?width=614&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png 614w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png?width=818&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png 818w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png?width=1023&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png 1023w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png?width=1227&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.33%20PM.png 1227w" sizes="(max-width: 409px) 100vw, 409px"></p></div>
<div><p>Overall, these differences in terminology reflect the political landscape in the aftermath of January 6 in two ways: (1) a central consensus clearly labels the event as a riot and shares some broad interpretations of the day’s events, and (2) on average, left-leaning interpretations accentuate the violent, seditious nature of events while right-leaning publications take a softer tone.</p></div>
<h4><strong>How These Words Compare to the George Floyd Protests</strong></h4>
<p>Just as many saw fundamentally different responses to the George Floyd protests and the Capitol Riot, The Factual’s data reveals a few differences in the way these events were described in the media. (This analysis uses an <a href="https://blog.thefactual.com/protest-riot-headlines-george-floyd" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>earlier study</span></a> we conducted based on a similarly sized dataset of 4,958 article titles from the 10 days following George Floyd’s killing.)</p>
<p>Most prominently, the George Floyd protests were far more likely to be described using the word “protest” (44.9%) and far less likely to involve “riot” (2.9%) than the Capitol Riot. The events on Capitol Hill were 10 times as likely to be described as an “attack,” while the George Floyd protests were 5 times more likely to be described as “peaceful.” This makes intuitive sense since the George Floyd protests encompass hundreds of separate events and were <a href="https://time.com/5886348/report-peaceful-protests/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>93% peaceful</span></a>. The Capitol Riot, on the other hand, refers specifically to a single event where numerous <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/injured-police-officers-were-evacuated-from-capitol-hill-protests-2021-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>violent incidents</span></a> took place. Importantly, however, this highlights that efforts to equate the Capitol Riot with the George Floyd protests — for whatever purpose — are of <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/false-equivalency-black-lives-matter-capitol-siege-experts/story?id=75251279" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>limited use</span></a>.</p>
<p><br><img src="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png?width=537&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 6.34.42 PM" width="537" srcset="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png?width=269&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png 269w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png?width=537&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png 537w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png?width=806&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png 806w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png?width=1074&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png 1074w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png?width=1343&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png 1343w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png?width=1611&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.42%20PM.png 1611w" sizes="(max-width: 537px) 100vw, 537px"></p>
<p>There is also generally more agreement between left- and right-leaning outlets about what terminology to use to describe the Capitol Riot. <a href="https://blog.thefactual.com/protest-riot-headlines-george-floyd" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Our analysis</span></a> of coverage of the George Floyd protests showed larger divergences between left and right, for example, in terms of usage of “protest” or “riot”:</p>
<p>[A]rticles from outlets on the right featured “riot,” “riots,” or “rioting” in 12.9% of all article titles, while only 2.6% of article titles on the left featured those terms. Similarly, article titles on the right were twice as likely (8.1%) to use some variation of the word “loot” than the left (3.8%). Conversely, articles on the left were 10% more likely (43.7%) to feature a variation of the term “protest” than those on the right (33.8%), and 7.8% of articles on the left featured the term “non-violent,” which didn’t appear in any article titles on the right.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Though Trump played a prominent role during the George Floyd protests, particularly relating to his use of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/02/us/politics/trump-walk-lafayette-square.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>federal forces</span></a> like the National Guard, he was in retrospect a secondary player in the national upheaval over institutional racism and police brutality; he was mentioned in 9.4% of article titles from that period. By contrast, he was three times as likely to be mentioned in titles related to the Capitol Riot (31.1%). Conversely, the police were mentioned repeatedly during the George Floyd protests (40.5%), unsurprising given their centrality to the upheaval, but were mentioned with less frequency in relation to the Capitol Riot. Despite their varied interactions both <a href="https://reason.com/2021/01/07/capitol-police-failed-to-contain-a-riot-then-killed-a-woman-in-the-chaos/" rel="noopener" target="_blank">fighting</a> and <a href="https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/news/capitol-police-chief-several-officers-suspended-siege" rel="noopener" target="_blank">assisting</a> the rioters, “police” only appeared in 10.9% of all articles related to the events in DC.&nbsp;</p>
<p><img src="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png?width=556&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 6.34.53 PM" width="556" srcset="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png?width=278&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png 278w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png?width=556&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png 556w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png?width=834&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png 834w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png?width=1112&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png 1112w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png?width=1390&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png 1390w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png?width=1668&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.34.53%20PM.png 1668w" sizes="(max-width: 556px) 100vw, 556px"></p>
<div><p>A further way media coverage has differed is through the words that fail to appear in coverage of the events on Capitol Hill. For example, instances of looting during this summer’s protests were used by some to try to delegitimize the entire Black Lives Matter movement. In our sample about the George Floyd protests, “looting” — to "steal goods from (a place), typically during a war or riot"<span>&nbsp;—</span> was mentioned in 3.4% of article titles, slightly more than the 2.9% of articles that mentioned “riot.” By contrast, though 39.1% of article titles about January 6 included the word “riot” and even as assailants broke into the Capitol building, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jackbrewster/2021/01/08/clyburns-ipad-laptop-from-pelosis-office-items-stolen-destroyed-in-capitol-attack/?sh=37d9d46d5963" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>stole government property</span></a>, and evidence was <a href="https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2021/jan/9/horned-man-west-va-lawmaker-man-holding-pelosis-le/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>widely published</span></a> of them doing so, there wasn’t a single mention of “looting” in the 5,057 article titles in our sample.&nbsp;</p></div>
<img src="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png?width=803&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2021-01-23 at 6.35.17 PM" width="803" srcset="https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png?width=402&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png 402w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png?width=803&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png 803w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png?width=1205&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png 1205w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png?width=1606&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png 1606w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png?width=2008&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png 2008w, https://blog.thefactual.com/hs-fs/hubfs/Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png?width=2409&amp;name=Screen%20Shot%202021-01-23%20at%206.35.17%20PM.png 2409w" sizes="(max-width: 803px) 100vw, 803px">

<h4><strong>How Far Apart</strong></h4>
<p>Regardless of the words one uses to describe the political division in the U.S., it is apparent that there is some distance between the left and right on the future of the country, the optimal direction for policy, and especially how to think about the last four years. However, the words used to describe the Capitol Riot suggest more unity than one might expect, at least in terms of the media’s portrayal of what will likely be the most memorable day of the Trump administration. Media coverage from across the political spectrum is certainly in greater agreement about the character of events in DC than it was about the George Floyd protests this summer. If the desire is to rein in partisan division, coming to a set of common terms to describe the events of January 6 is a good start.</p>
<h4><br>Appendix</h4>
<p><span>This appendix shows each of the articles used to inform the findings of this article, as well as how the articles scored according to The Factual's credibility algorithm. To learn more, read our&nbsp;</span><a href="https://www.thefactual.com/how-it-works.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>How It Works</span></a><span>&nbsp;page.</span></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<p><span>Title</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Author</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Publisher</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Publisher Bias</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Credibility Grade</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="5">
<p><strong><span>Left</span></strong></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/ex-firefighter-robert-sanford-arrested-for-allegedly-hurling-fire-extinguisher-at-cops-during-capitol-riots" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Retired Firefighter Arrested for Allegedly Hurling Fire Extinguisher at Cops During Capitol Riots</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Pilar Melendez</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Daily Beast</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>89%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-55574780" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Capitol riots: World media see Trump ignite an 'insurrection'</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>N/A</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>BBC</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Moderate Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>83%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2021/01/trump-capitol-attack-impeachment-evidence-insurrection.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Congress Has All the Impeachment Evidence It Needs</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>William Saletan</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Slate</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>81%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/gop-senators-reverse-objections-electoral-college-certification-protesters/story?id=75099780" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Some GOP senators reverse objections to Electoral College certification after protesters storm Capitol</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Haley Yamada</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>ABC News</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Moderate Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>81%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/stop-the-steal-organizer-gop-members-helped-him-plan-rally-2021-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Stop the Steal' organizer Ali Alexander says 3 GOP congressmen helped him plan the rally that preceded the storming of the Capitol</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Sarah Al-Arshani</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Business Insider</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Moderate Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>81%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://abcnews.go.com/US/false-equivalency-black-lives-matter-capitol-siege-experts/story?id=75251279" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>False equivalency between Black Lives Matter and Capitol siege: Experts, advocates</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Kiara Brantley-Jones</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>ABC News</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Moderate Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>76%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/injured-police-officers-were-evacuated-from-capitol-hill-protests-2021-1" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Multiple police officers were seen being evacuated with injuries after clashes with pro-Trump rioters on Capitol Hill</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Madison Hall</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Business Insider</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Moderate Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>76%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/02/us/politics/trump-walk-lafayette-square.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>How Trump’s Idea for a Photo Op Led to Havoc in a Park</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Peter Baker et al.</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>New York Times</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Moderate Left</span></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>75%</span></p>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/13/us/politics/trump-video-capitol-riot.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"><span>Under Heavy Pressure, Trump Releases Video Condemning Capitol Siege</span></a></p>
</td>
<td>
<p><span>Maggie …</span></p></td></tr></tbody></table></span></p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.thefactual.com/insurrection-siege-riot-the-words-describe-capitol-attack">https://blog.thefactual.com/insurrection-siege-riot-the-words-describe-capitol-attack</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.thefactual.com/insurrection-siege-riot-the-words-describe-capitol-attack</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25893887</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 17:38:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A 10B Pixel Scan of Vermeer’s Masterpiece]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 44 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25892840">thread link</a>) | @parisianka
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.micro-pano.com/pearl/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25892840</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 15:35:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My Apple IIE: Nearly 30 Years Later (2012)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 28 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25891740">thread link</a>) | @AlexeyBrin
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | http://www.leucht.com/blog/2012/10/my-apple-iie-nearly-30-years-later/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.leucht.com/blog/2012/10/my-apple-iie-nearly-30-years-later/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>We bought a new house last year and as I was moving my old Apple IIe computer from my old attic over to my new attic, I thought it would be fun to hook it up and see if it still worked.&nbsp; To make a long story short … it worked!&nbsp; (Scroll down to see some pictures and even a video clip of my working Apple IIe.)</p>
<p><strong>To make a long story even longer … here are all the gory and geeky details:</strong></p>
<p>Back in 1983, when I was only 13 years old and in 8th grade in Central Illinois, my parents bought me an Apple IIe computer for Christmas.&nbsp;&nbsp; At that time I had no computer training but I think there were a couple of APPLE II computers in my school.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/1983-christmas-apple-iie-unwrapping-scaled.jpg"><img src="http://www.leucht.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/1983-christmas-apple-iie-unwrapping-400x303.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="303" srcset="http://www.leucht.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/1983-christmas-apple-iie-unwrapping-400x303.jpg 400w, http://www.leucht.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/1983-christmas-apple-iie-unwrapping-1024x775.jpg 1024w, http://www.leucht.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/1983-christmas-apple-iie-unwrapping-768x581.jpg 768w, http://www.leucht.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/1983-christmas-apple-iie-unwrapping-1536x1162.jpg 1536w, http://www.leucht.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/1983-christmas-apple-iie-unwrapping-2048x1550.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px"></a></p>
<p>Well, now that I look at the photo of my sister and I unwrapping it, I guess it was technically a gift for the both of us.&nbsp; But I think we both knew it was really mine!&nbsp; 🙂</p>
<p>Here’s an old and humorous Apple II commercial:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/05M80HHNB6s?rel=0" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Purchase Details:</strong></p>
<p>The cost of my Apple IIe computer in November of 1983 was $995 plus $115 for the standard green phosphor monitor for a grand total of $1,165 including 5% sales tax.&nbsp; That translates to nearly $2,700 in 2012 dollars.&nbsp; Yes, that’s a lot of money for a 13 year old kid’s Christmas present.&nbsp; The Apple IIe had only been on the market for less than a year when I got mine so it was not extremely popular yet. To hook it up to your own television, you would pay $70 for a modulator rather than $115 for the green monitor, but the resolution would not be as sharp on a television screen as it was on the computer monitor.&nbsp; We eventually did get the TV modulator, though, so I could use the computer in full color.&nbsp; Full color for an Apple IIe was only 15 colors, by the way.</p>
<p>My parents bought the computer from Wallace Micro-Mart on University Street in Peoria, Illinois.&nbsp; I believe the salesman there, who was listed as “Howell” on the hand written carbon receipt, lived in our same home town.&nbsp; At the bottom of the receipt it says that “Wallace has been serving the Peoria Community for over 10 years”.</p>
<p>I google’d Wallace Micro-Mart and all I found was this old commercial for an Apple Lisa computer:</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/3R8fArhOWso?rel=0" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Geeky Specs:</strong></p>
<p>The Apple IIe came with 64KB of memory standard, but it was expandable to 1 Megabyte and also had lots of expansion slots for various accessories.&nbsp; It ran at a screaming 1 Megahertz and had an 8 bit data bus.&nbsp; It had 2 text display modes and 4 graphics display modes.&nbsp; The text modes were 40 or 80 columns at 24 lines.&nbsp; The graphics modes were 40×48 or 80×48 block low resolution modes and 280×192 or 560×192 pixel high resolution modes.&nbsp; For comparison, the Apple IIe high res graphics modes were about the same pixel resolution as your most common cell phones used in the year 2005 … and those old cell phones definitely had way more memory than the Apple IIe.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Apple IIe contained Applesoft BASIC in ROM and booted into it if no floppy disk was found during boot.</p>
<p><strong>Unboxed Nearly 30 Years Later:</strong></p>
<p>Here is a photo of the computer in 2011 when I unboxed it during the move.&nbsp; It is basically a big case containing a keyboard, power supply, motherboard and that’s about it.&nbsp; It did not come with a mouse, nor did any of the Apple software support a mouse for the Apple II series of computers.&nbsp; I believe the Apple IIe came with one floppy drive and I think we bought the second one later.</p>
<p>The keys on the keyboard had some serious friction resistance and the keys were not very easy to push down.&nbsp; I think the key wiggle tolerances were pretty tight and the plastic-to-plastic friction caused quite a bit of resistance if you didn’t push the keys in the exact proper direction.&nbsp; Typing on this keyboard was seriously loud.&nbsp; Click, click, click!</p>
<p>There were some unique keys on these old Apple keyboards.&nbsp; Notice the outlined apple key which was called the open-apple and the solid white apple key which was called the closed-apple or solid-apple.&nbsp; The key sequence of simultaneous Control-OpenApple-Reset would reboot the machine immediately.&nbsp; Control-ClosedApple-Reset would enter BIOS setup before rebooting.&nbsp; Control-ClosedApple-OpenApple-Reset would perform a self test during reboot.&nbsp; Those are some crazy key sequences.</p>
<p>(Click on any photo to see it in full resolution.)</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/01" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/01.JPG?m=1440971768" alt="" width="640" height="480"></a></p>
<p>Here is the green phosphor “Monitor II”, as Apple called it.&nbsp; It had one single RCA style input connector and that’s it.&nbsp; No audio jacks, no output jacks, nothing.&nbsp; This thing was pretty old school and very basic.&nbsp; The serial number on this monitor is actually written by hand.&nbsp; The one cool feature was that the actual glass CRT was mounted on an axis that tilted up and down for a more direct viewing angle.&nbsp; The user just pushed on the darker green plastic frame around the glass CRT to tilt the glass up and down.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/02" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/02.JPG?m=1440971774" alt="" width="640" height="480"></a></p>
<p>Here is what the motherboard looks like inside the case.&nbsp; The lid was basically held down with a couple of hard plastic velcro type devices.&nbsp; There are 8 expansion slots and I was using four of them when I packed mine up for storage back in the late 80s.</p>
<p>The tiny card on the far left is the 80 column card and it is plugged into the auxiliary slot.&nbsp; This card just let the computer display 80 columns rather than the default 40 columns.&nbsp; This card also added more memory to the computer.</p>
<p>The long card on the left in slot 1 is the parallel interface card.&nbsp; It sure took a lot of electronics to interface to a parallel printer back then!</p>
<p>The short card in the middle in slot 4 is a Covox sound card.&nbsp; This card intercepted the sound going from the motherboard (yellow and red wires ) to the built-in speaker (black wires).&nbsp; The built-in speaker is mounted under the keyboard pointing straight down.&nbsp; This Covox sound card also had a headphone jack mounted directly on the card itself.&nbsp; I thought that was terribly inconvenient, so I de-soldered it from the card and mounted it into the plastic hole cover on the back of the computer.&nbsp; The brown wires are connecting the card to the headphone jack.&nbsp; I was pretty handy with a soldering iron, even when I was young.&nbsp; 🙂</p>
<p>The medium length card on the right in slot 6 is the floppy disk drive controller.&nbsp; Both disk drives are connected to that card using standard flat ribbon cables and nothing else.&nbsp; PC users are used to connecting power cables separately from data cables, but the power and data are both in these ribbon cables.&nbsp; Convenient … and also just a little scary.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/3.JPG?m=1440971950" alt="" width="480" height="640"></a></p>
<p>This is a 5 and a quarter inch magnetic floppy disk that holds the operating system.&nbsp; Do you remember these floppy disks?&nbsp; Some floppy disks were double sided, so you could flip them over and use the other side and get twice the data onto them.&nbsp; You had to punch out a notch in a specific place on the disk in order to make it read-only.&nbsp; Then you had to put a sticker over that hole in order to write to it again.&nbsp; Computer stores sold special notch cutters, but most of us users just used a standard hole punch numerous times until we got the notch created in the right place in order to open up the microswitch in the disk drive.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/4.JPG?m=1440971830" alt="" width="480" height="640"></a></p>
<p>30 years ago, I loved that Apple gave stickers away with their hardware and they still do it today and I still love it!&nbsp; This was a folder containing the receipt and some manuals and it also contained some really cool full color apple logo decals.&nbsp; I never used the decals.&nbsp; I just checked EBay and people are selling these vintage rainbow Apple stickers for 20 bucks each!&nbsp; Wow.&nbsp; I guess they are a true collectors item now that they are 30 years old.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/5" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/5.JPG?m=1440971903" alt="" width="480" height="640"></a></p>
<p>The owners manual was spiral bound.&nbsp; It took you though the internals for a computer and then walked you through the DOS command line commands and also introduced you to Applesoft BASIC programming.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/6.JPG?m=1440971927" alt="" width="480" height="640"></a></p>
<p>Ah, the good old dot matrix printer.&nbsp; Man, these things were loud.&nbsp; And how annoying was it to keep these things feeding the paper properly?&nbsp; These things were part typewriter and part printer.&nbsp; When somebody invented laserjets, we never looked back, did we?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/10.JPG?m=1440971781" alt="" width="640" height="480"></a></p>
<p>I actually still had an un-opened ribbon for the dot matrix printer.&nbsp; It probably dried out a year after I packed this thing up and went to college, though.&nbsp; I don’t remember how much these ribbons cost, but I do remember trying to squeeze every last drop of ink out of them.&nbsp; We used to reuse them multiple times and some people went as far as trying to re-ink them.&nbsp; I guess we still do the same thing today with our inkjet cartridges and our toner cartridges, though.&nbsp; The more things change, the more they stay the same!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/11" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/11.JPG?m=1440971788" alt="" width="480" height="640"></a></p>
<p>Here is a photo of the command line after one of my personal boot disks had been booted up.&nbsp; This was just a disk that had some small Applesoft BASIC programs on it.&nbsp; This particular program printed some text to the screen and exited.&nbsp; Very much beginner stuff.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/20.JPG?m=1440971794" alt="" width="640" height="480"></a></p>
<p>If you typed CATALOG from the command line, the computer would show you the list of files on the floppy disk.&nbsp; File type (A=Applesoft BASIC, B=Binary, I=Integer Basic, T=Text) and file size (disk sectors) and file name were shown.&nbsp; Notice that file names can have spaces.&nbsp; UNIX did not allow this initially and neither did the early DOS for PCs, but Apple did.&nbsp; Now pretty much every OS does allow it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/index.php/appleiie/21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img title="image 1" src="http://www.leucht.com/photos-new/var/resizes/appleiie/21.JPG?m=1440971803" alt="" width="640" height="480"></a></p>
<p>This image shows a listing of a small Applesoft BASIC program.&nbsp; It was written on the command line, line for line, then it was tested and if it worked, it was written to the disk as a file.&nbsp; In Applesoft BASIC you did not start with an empty file on disk and write characters to that file.&nbsp; You created your program directly in the computer’s memory and copied it to disk later.&nbsp; There was no plain text editor app that I’m aware of.&nbsp; No computer manufacturer does that anymore, for good reasons.</p>
<p>In this particular program, it draws some boxes on the screen with the HPLOT commands.&nbsp; Then it creates an artificial delay using the old school empty for/next loop.&nbsp; Then it repeats the box drawing sequence three times with a for/next loop, part of which has scrolled off the screen.&nbsp; After three cycles of the box drawing sequence, it runs a subroutine, which is not necessary in this case since it is only called once.&nbsp; But …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.leucht.com/blog/2012/10/my-apple-iie-nearly-30-years-later/">http://www.leucht.com/blog/2012/10/my-apple-iie-nearly-30-years-later/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.leucht.com/blog/2012/10/my-apple-iie-nearly-30-years-later/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25891740</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 13:10:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cathedrals, Bazaars, and Fusion Reactors]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25891438">thread link</a>) | @mpereira
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://www.murilopereira.com/cathedrals-bazaars-and-fusion-reactors/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.murilopereira.com/cathedrals-bazaars-and-fusion-reactors/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Open source took over the world, but it still struggles. How to make it more sustainable?</p><div><figure><img src="https://www.murilopereira.com/iter_fusion_reactor_plasma.jpg" alt="Figure 1: Inside the Korean tokamak KSTAR (NFRI)"><figcaption><p>Figure 1: Inside the Korean tokamak <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KSTAR">KSTAR</a> (NFRI)</p></figcaption></figure><p>With corporations like Microsoft, Oracle, and Google truly reinventing
themselves to adapt to an open source world, and typical open source
projects moving towards—oftentimes centralized—governance models, the
<a href="http://www.catb.org/~esr/writings/homesteading/cathedral-bazaar/">Cathedral–Bazaar</a> dichotomy feels increasingly less relevant.</p><p>It was met with
<a href="https://firstmonday.org/article/view/708/618">criticism</a>
even back in the 90s.</p><p>While being an entertaining piece of history with useful takeaways, its
most important achievement was arguably helping create a sense of identity
for hacker culture via the revolutionary Open Source movement, and
promoting the value of the Internet for software development.</p><p>In the Cathedral-Bazaar continuum, contemporary projects like Kubernetes,
Chromium, and VSCode are <i>fusion reactors</i>.</p><p>They have the backing of heavily invested companies with virtually infinite
capital, who are able to staff highly competent teams that not only work
full-time on these projects, but also have enough personpower to maximally
leverage the benefits brought by a gigantic user base.</p><p>Like with fusion power, they seem to be able to leverage a high amount of
energy to generate even more.</p><p>Sometimes, their user base includes <i>other</i> organizations with
endless resources: by means of its success, VSCode is getting
<a href="https://visualstudiomagazine.com/articles/2019/11/21/fb-vs-code.aspx">sizable contributions</a> from Facebook, for example.</p><p>In contrast, the vast majority of open source projects depend almost
exclusively on decentralized volunteer efforts from people sacrificing time
out of their busy schedules and lives to move things forward.</p><p>And yet, projects following this style of development can end up becoming
backbones of modern computing:</p><blockquote><p>The OpenSSL project has been around since 1998. Since the project is open
source, it is an informal group comprised primarily of about a dozen
members throughout the world, most of whom have day jobs, and some of whom
work on a volunteer basis. Being open source, the OpenSSL project’s code
has always been public facing. Any person could download it and modify it
or implement it in their own software.</p><p>[…]</p><p>The fascinating, mind-boggling fact here is that you have this critical
piece of network infrastructure that really runs a large part of the
internet, and there’s basically one guy working on it full time.</p><p>— <a href="https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/otm/articles/ssl-heartbleed">Steve Marquess in “It’s Not A Fun Week To Work at OpenSSL, The Mostly
Volunteer Project Responsible for the Heartbleed Bug”, (2014)</a></p></blockquote><p>Heartbleed is a symptom of an ever-existing problem: corporations profit
massively by leveraging typically under-resourced open source projects
while not giving back proportionally, or (most commonly) at all; either
with money or people.</p><figure><img src="https://www.murilopereira.com/xkcd_load_bearing_open_source.png" alt="Figure 2: &amp;ldquo;Load-Bearing Internet People&amp;rdquo;"><figcaption><p>Figure 2: <a href="https://xkcd.com/2347/">“Load-Bearing Internet People”</a></p></figcaption></figure><p>After Heartbleed the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Core_Infrastructure_Initiative">Core Infrastructure Initiative</a>
was created to support software essential to the "functioning of the
Internet and other major information systems".</p><p>Less critical software like Emacs also follows this decentralized
development style, and similarly, lacks resources.</p><blockquote><blockquote><p>So if Emacs wants to compete with these tools then it has to have
seamless, context aware code completion and refactoring support, and GNU
tools has to provide Emacs the necessary information to implement these
features.</p></blockquote><p>I agree. But to have that, the only way is to have motivated volunteers
step forward and work on these features. Otherwise we will never have them.</p><p>Right now, no one is working on that, though everyone is talking. [T]he
same as with weather.</p><p>— <a href="https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2015-10/msg00646.html">Eli Zaretskii in “Re: IDE” (2014)</a></p></blockquote><p>One way to incentivize contributions is by funding developers. Some (most?)
open source contributors would gladly take income to fund their work.</p><blockquote><p>Long-term my big dream has always been to accumulate enough backing to be
able to work full-time on open-source projects, but whether I’ll achieve
this dream or not is entirely up to you.</p><p>— <a href="https://emacsredux.com/blog/2020/09/13/patronage-revisited/">Bozhidar Batsov in “Patronage Revisited” (2020)</a></p></blockquote><p>While others feel that accepting funding would degrade their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drive:%5FThe%5FSurprising%5FTruth%5FAbout%5FWhat%5FMotivates%5FUs">intrinsic
motivation</a> to contribute.</p><blockquote><p>I can’t speak for all FLOSS developers, but I can speak for myself: I don’t
want monetary rewarding from users. Mainly for the reason, that I don’t
want to change the relationship with my users. Currently it is mostly a
team attitude, we’re working together to solve the problem. And there is
also no legal obligation for me to work on something I don’t like.</p><p>If I accepted contributions I think many users would get a “but I paid for
that, so do what I want” attitude. I definitely don’t want that. I do FLOSS
in my free time to do something that matters, and for my personal
fulfillment, not for money.</p><p>It will also get harder to do the right thing (in contrary to doing what
the users want) since the users can stop the payments.</p><p>So, no payments for me, thanks.</p><p>— <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/6pjbn0/sustainable%5Femacs%5Fdevelopment%5Fsome%5Fthoughts%5Fand/">cjk101010 in “Sustainable Emacs development - some thoughts and
analysis” (2017)</a></p></blockquote><p>Which is fair: with compensation comes responsibility, timelines,
expectations, and things can get complicated. From the point of view of the
project, there doesn’t seem to be a conflict: capture funding to enable those
who need (or want) it, while still empowering those who don’t, to contribute
on their own terms.</p><p>Not everyone is in a position to spend unpaid time on open source,
especially consistently. “Free” time <a href="https://www.rightattitudes.com/2017/08/08/opportunity-cost/">isn’t free</a>—<em>it costs life</em>. By
funding work, a project might get to see contributions from talented folks
passionate about it who wouldn’t be able to volunteer their time.</p><p>And sometimes, the reason why your PR isn't getting immediate attention
is that the maintainer is busy literally
<a href="https://github.com/fre5h/DoctrineEnumBundle/pull/12#issuecomment-33023169">fighting</a>
a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revolution_of_Dignity">revolution</a>.</p><p>For Emacs specifically, one problem is that there’s no clear way of funding
“Emacs”. Sending money to the FSF doesn’t guarantee that it will fund Emacs
development. <em>Even if there was</em> a way of “funding Emacs”, the Emacs
community—like many things in life—seems to be roughly divided in two
sides: those who prioritize <em><a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html">freedom</a></em>, and those who prioritize <em>progress</em>. So
one would potentially want to fund one side or the other, depending on their
values.</p><p>In the excellent “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/0578675862/">Working in Public</a>: The Making and Maintenance of Open
Source Software”, Nadia Eghbal calls attention to a shift in how
individuals support open source. Similarly to platforms like Twitch, more
and more people are funding creators directly instead of projects, as a way
of “incentivizing the ongoing creation of creative work” from developers
who produce things that are in their interests.</p><p>Maintainers of popular Emacs packages, for example, have their own <a href="https://github.com/tarsius/elisp-maintainers">separate
streams of patronage</a>, which receive varying levels of support depending on
their popularity and the value added by what they create.</p><p>For efforts that involve multiple people, like maintaining and evolving
Emacs itself, services like <a href="https://opencollective.com/">Open Collective</a> could be of great assistance by
helping on three fronts:</p><ol><li>providing a legal banking entity</li><li>recurrently collecting funds from individuals and companies</li><li>distributing funds to contributors</li></ol><p>Funds can be transparently collected, and dispersed for specific contract
work, infrastructure costs, and even developer salaries. Take for example
the <a href="https://opencollective.com/babel">Babel</a> project, which draws in enough recurrent income to finance
multiple contractors and a full-time developer earning a San Francisco
salary. An Emacs Open Collective could not only be an answer to “how can I
fund Emacs development?” but also a way to financially support developers
working on it.</p><p>The Clojure community seems to be doing an excellent job at not only
<a href="https://www.clojuriststogether.org/news/q4-2020-funding-announcement/">funding</a>
efforts that are making the whole Clojure ecosystem
better but also at surveying and
<a href="https://www.clojuriststogether.org/news/q3-2020-survey-results/">responding</a>
accordingly to user
feedback.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/sponsors">GitHub Sponsors</a> is another great example of developer empowerment. With it,
not only does GitHub equip people to:</p><ul><li>be more productive by providing great code hosting, bug tracking, wiki,
code reviewing and merging, project management, continuous integration,
documentation, artifact hosting, etc.</li><li>have a broader impact by giving projects more visibility and standardized
workflows that are familiar to others already on the platform</li></ul><p>It also makes it possible for its <a href="https://octoverse.github.com/">40 million users</a> to frictionlessly fund
work on open source, and for a large number of maintainers to be
conveniently compensated for their labor. I just started sponsoring someone
with literally two clicks!</p><p>The power of platforms can’t be understated.</p><p>Whether you like GitHub or not, it’s undeniable that it has, and continues
to revolutionize Open Source, simply by providing a significantly better
and unified experience for all aspects of building software.</p><div><p>When there are people making over
<a href="https://changelog.com/posts/i-just-hit-100000-per-year-on-github-sponsors">100k/year</a>
on GitHub Sponsors, you better have a great reason to <b>not</b> try to
<a href="https://github.com/sponsors/neovim">take advantage</a>
of it.</p><p>In the case of Emacs, the reason is <i>freedom</i>.</p></div><p>I wouldn’t mind if Emacs development moved to GitHub, but <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/repo-criteria-evaluation.en.html">I don’t think
it’s ever going to happen</a>. Maybe for good reason: GitHub is backed by a
for-profit corporation and is far from perfect, both in <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/9/20906213/github-ice-microsoft-software-email-contract-immigration-nonprofit-donation">moral</a> and <a href="https://github.com/isaacs/github/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+sort%3Areactions-%2B1-desc">technical</a>
terms. It might be a great tool today, but being a proprietary platform,
its users are at their complete mercy.</p><p>I should point out that from my perspective GitHub has been for the
most part a force for
<a href="https://github.blog/2020-11-16-standing-up-for-developers-youtube-dl-is-back/">good</a>.</p><p>It would be great if main development at least moved from a
mailing-list-driven process to a modern <em>forge</em> style of contribution. It
<a href="https://emba.gnu.org/emacs/emacs">seems that it <em>might</em></a>, but whether or not it will is still <a href="https://gitlab.com/gitlab-org/gitlab/-/issues/28152">unclear</a>.</p><p>In the same way that corporations extract value out of open source, open
source projects should as much as possible leverage “energy” generated by
corporations. In this new open source world, companies have their workforce
contributing millions of person-hours to projects that benefit everyone.
LLVM equips people to build programming languages. LSP gives people potent
software development capabilities. Rails empowers people to build powerful
web applications.</p><blockquote><p>More than 3,000 people have committed man-decades, maybe even
man-centuries, of work for free. Buying all that effort at market rates
would have been hundreds of millions of dollars. Who would have been able
to afford funding that?</p><p>That’s a …</p></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.murilopereira.com/cathedrals-bazaars-and-fusion-reactors/">https://www.murilopereira.com/cathedrals-bazaars-and-fusion-reactors/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.murilopereira.com/cathedrals-bazaars-and-fusion-reactors/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25891438</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 12:19:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Introduction: User's Guide to Empire (1991)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25891262">thread link</a>) | @segfaultbuserr
<br/>
January 24, 2021 | https://www.empire.cx/infopages/Guide.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.empire.cx/infopages/Guide.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">

<h2>Basic</h2>
<pre>|                                                                              |
|    ***       ***                                                             |
|    ***       ***                                   *                         |
|    ***       ***    ******    ******    ** ****     *    ******              |
|    ***       ***   **        **    **   ****  **   *    **                   |
|    ***       ***    *****    *******    **               *****               |
|    ***       ***        **   **         **                   **              |
|    ***       ***   ******     ******    **              ******               |
|     ***     ***                                                              |
|      *********     ++++  +   +  +++++  ++++   +++++      +++++   +++         |
|                   +      +   +    +    +   +  +            +    +   +        |
|                   +  ++  +   +    +    +   +  +++          +    +   +        |
| ************      +   +  +   +    +    +   +  +            +    +   +        |
| ***********        +++    +++   +++++  ++++   +++++        +     +++         |
| ***                                                                          |
| ***           *** ****  ****    ********    *********   ********    *******  |
| *******       *****  ****  ***  ***    **     *****     ***   ***  ***   *** |
| ***           ****    **    **  ***     **     ***      ***   ***  ********  |
| ***           ***     **    **  ***    **      ***      ********   ***       |
| ***********   ***     **    **  ********      *****     ***   ***  ***   *** |
| ************  ***     **    **  ***         *********   ***    ***  *******  |
|                                 **                                           |
|                                                           By Geoff Cashman   |


User's Guide to Empire							 1

                    Preface to the Wolfpack Edition

This is Geoff Cashman's venerable User's Guide to Empire.  It was written
in 1991, and Empire has evolved quite a bit since then.  Nevertheless, many
players have found it useful through the years, so here it is.  We
reproduce it verbatim except for this preface and corrections of a few
editing mistakes.


			       Copyright

Copyright (C) 1991-2017 Geoff Cashman.  This is free documentation; see the
source for copying conditions.  There is NO warranty; not even for
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.


User's Guide to Empire							 2

				Preface

This guide's intended audience is the beginning player and those players
who have played a game or three and would like to have some insight on some
more subtle aspects of the game.  Some experienced players may find some 
benefit from reading this guide as well.  While you may feel you are an
expert, it is always possible to learn.  Nothing in this guide is intended 
to be difficult to understand, and every effort has been made to make this
guide an easy learning tool. 
				   
This publication is current to Berkeley version 1.1 patch level 5




User's Guide to Empire							 3

				Foreword

It has been over a year now since I first sat down and thought in a serious
way about writing this guide.  It has been a long trip with many interesting
turns and developments.  When I first started, the version of Empire that
this guide has ultimately been written for had not yet been released.  Now,
with this project nearing release I find that yet another new version of
Empire is coming out.  I look on in near despair as I realize that this guide
may very well soon be outdated.  Nevertheless, I feel compelled to release
this information in what might be considered a final form.  

However, I hope that this is not the final form.  With new versions of
Empire coming out in the very near future I hope that some other potential
author steps forward and takes up the banner of educating the new player. 
I caution you though that such a work as this takes quite an effort. 

To the reader and any critics or even cynics that might be reading, I say
that I am not writer.  I never was, and I never intend to be.  There are
certainly enough writers in the world to write almost everything the world
could want to know about in print.  I was never skilled in the art of proper
style for any sort of writing.  Please, be kind and keep this in mind.

I wrote this guide because I felt there was a great need for something of
this nature.  I have watched so many players come to the network looking
for information on Empire, such as the rules, or information on how to play.
One can get information about the various commands available to oneself
within the game, but to understand how to use those commands effectively
and get skilled at running a country is a far greater task.  Many new
players have despaired after playing their first game for lack of the
requisite knowledge to play effectively.  Some come back fighting hard
in the next game, but many just disappear never to be heard from again.
This guide was written with the hope that if the new player is supplied
with the basics, they can advance in skill more quickly than previously
possible and not despair at their first defeat. 

I am hoping that within the near future two other companion guides to 
this one will be written and released to the net.  These two guides will
be intended to make the average player a better player or even expert,
and to teach fledgling deities how to compile and establish a, solicit 
entries for , and effectively run, a game.  Some people have commented
to me that the time spent on these guides would be better spent if I 
were to spend time programming for Empire instead.  It is my belief that
in teaching players to be better players, and teaching deities how to be 
a deity should that guide be released, the potential pool for
programmers of Empire will increase.  

I can not take credit for the idea of this guide.  The need for such
a guide I think was painfully obvious to a great many players.  Some in
fact did engage in projects to fill that need.  Every such attempt has
fallen short, in my humble opinion.  Witness the large number of people


User's Guide to Empire							 4

who still ask the network, "How do I play?" and even more importantly
the lack of sufficient answer to such people's questions.  In my highest
hopes, I dream that someday soon that answer will be "Get a copy of the
User's Guide to Empire, which is available via FTP from xx.xx.xx".

This work was made possible by the contributions of several Empire players.
This work would not have been completed without the insights and assistance 
of many Empire players and deities.  To the Empire community as a whole,
I say thank you for your priceless contributions. 




--------------------------------------------------------------------------------


User's Guide to Empire							 5

	       		   *** Contents ***

Preface
Foreword
1.  What is Empire? . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .  6
2.  How to get into a game of Empire. . . . . . . . . . . . . . .  8
3.  The primitive basics. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 16
4.  Geography in Empire.  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 18
5.  The beginning phases of Empire. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 21
6.  Diplomacy.  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 28
7.  Setting up your defenses. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 33
8.  Nuclear warfare.  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 38
9.  Technology. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 42
10. The economy.  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 45
11. War.  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 54
12. Other helpful or not so helpful hints.  . . . . . . . . . . . 57
13. Some tricks and subtle tactics. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 59
14. Tools.  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 63

Appendices
 a) glossary
 b) known bugs
 c) ftp sites
 

Figures:
	1.  Sample of how to FTP and compile a client program
	2.  Killing a process on a remote Empire host
	3.  Example of an Empire map
	4.  Realistic version of an Empire map
	5.  Table of sector types and designations 
	6.  Unexplored island prior to breaking sanctuary
	7.  Island showing exploration using theory 1
	8.  Island showing exploration using theory 2
	9   Island showing exploration using theory 3
	10. Results from 'show planes capability'
	11. Results from a 'nation' report
	12. Map of region hit by nuclear weapon
	13. Table of types of commodities in Empire
	14. Sample output of 'prod' command
	15. Results of a 'census' command of a library
	16. Map of area requiring some distribution
	17. Results of a distribution command
	18. Map of an area requiring delivery path


User's Guide to Empire							 6

Chapter 1 :-: What is Empire?

	Empire is a game in which you are pitted against several other
	players in a country vs. country format.  There are economies to
	run, armies to support, policies to generate, and allies and
	enemies to make.  The game supports various features that make
	certain aspects of the game seem to parallel the "realistic"
	world.  These include satellites, planes, banks, parks, etc.
	
	Empire, in the version herein described, is a very complex 
	game.  The closest game that most people will know that is 
	analogous to it is the game known as Risk.  However, Empire is 
	more complex by a factor of at least one hundred.  Nevertheless, 
	as a result of the computer aiding you every step of the way, the 
	game is not difficult to play, though it can be difficult to 
	learn.  If you read this guide thoroughly, and use it as a 
	continuing resource, you can help make learning this game a lot 
	easier. 

	It should be noted that in learning to play this game, you
	may become frustrated or feel daunted by its complexity. 
	Several players have noted that they almost gave up on Empire,
	until one day when everything seemed to start to make sense.
	…</pre></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.empire.cx/infopages/Guide.html">https://www.empire.cx/infopages/Guide.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.empire.cx/infopages/Guide.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25891262</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 11:42:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Jeff Bezos and Amazon do not want their workers voting by mail on unionization]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 40 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25889838">thread link</a>) | @jimmy2020
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
		

		
		<div itemprop="articleBody">
			



<p>Jeff Bezos — a strong Democratic supporter — and Amazon are aiming to postpone a unionization vote at one of its warehouses in Alabama, the <em>Wall Street Journal</em> <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/amazon-seeks-to-postpone-alabama-unionization-vote-11611339250?mod=e2tw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reports</a>. Interestingly, Amazon has requested that the National Labor Relations Board reconsider allowing mail-in voting, claiming that the mail-in voting process has “serious and systemic flaws.”</p>
<p>Got that? Bezos and Amazon are doing all they can to prevent any shady activity when workers cast their ballots for unionization, and they are particularly concerned about the integrity of mail-in ballots.</p>
<p>You are likely trying to figure out how that adds up, right? The <em>Washington Post</em>, owned by Bezos, called any claims of mail-in voter fraud by Donald Trump and his supporters dangerous and inexcusable. Amazon even banned Parler from its servers, in part to ensure no one could claim voter fraud occurred from mail-in ballots back in November.</p>
<p>But stop trying to make it make sense. It is not supposed to add up.</p>
<p>In this case, mail-in voting is disadvantageous for Bezos and his e-commerce behemoth. Therefore, they now consider mail-in voting seriously flawed.</p>
<p>An Amazon spokesperson <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/01/22/tech/amazon-nlrb-union-election/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tells</a> CNN the company is seeking a “valid, fair and successful election” and suggests that only in-person voting can ensure that. Hmm, interesting perspective.</p>
<p>Amazon has, thus far, fended off unions in the United States. If a majority of ballots vote in favor of unionization, hourly Amazon workers would send an L right up to Bezos’ office.</p>
<p>Bamazonunion.com explains that a union at Amazon would “give us the right to collectively bargain over our working conditions including items such as safety standards, training, breaks, pay, benefits, and other important issues that would make our workplace better.”</p>
<p>The NLRB says, “A mail ballot election will enfranchise employees who cannot enter the voting location for health reasons or due to positive COVID tests.” Fearing an unfavorable outcome, however, Amazon now insists that current COVID outbreaks aren’t dangerous enough to warrant this NLRB decision.</p>
<p>Amazon says that Lisa Henderson, NLRB’s Acting Regional Director “reached the remarkable conclusion that any level of infection or potential infection among employees counts as an ‘outbreak.'” <em>O</em><em>nly</em> 218 people employees, 2.88%, at its Bessemer facility tested positive during the 14-day period ending on January 7, which Amazon does not consider an “outbreak” apparently. This is quite the change of perspective. Imagine the coverage from the <em>Washington Post</em> if similar questions had been asked before November.</p>
<p>Mail-in voting has never been about the health of Americans or ensuring that each voice counts. As always, our country’s most powerful figures in both Washington and Silicon Valley base their opinions solely on the outcomes that increase their own power, finances, and flexibility.</p>
<p>Hypocritical, but sadly, all too predictable.</p>
		</div>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.outkick.com/jeff-bezos-amazon-mail-in-votes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25889838</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 06:30:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Visual Sentence Composer for Japanese]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 35 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25888468">thread link</a>) | @sova
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://japanesecomplete.com/visual-composer | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://japanesecomplete.com/visual-composer">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page-wrapper">

			<!-- Header -->
				

			<!-- Features -->
				<section id="features">
					<div>
						<div>
							<div>

								<!-- Feature #1 -->
									<section>
										<a href="#"><img alt="Koi swimming" src="https://jpc0.b-cdn.net/img/daruma-dolls.jpg"></a>
										
										<h2>Start Generating Real Japanese, Visually!</h2>
										<p>
											Sign up today to be notified when we release our Point-and-Click interface for composing Japanese visually.</p>
										<p>Japanese Grammar is quite different from English Grammar, and now we take the stress and anxiety out of learning the language and generating authentic Japanese with our Visual Sentence Builder.  You can rest assured that what you generate is following Japanese grammar rules, although nailing the meaning you want is still up to you.</p>
										<p> Create some posts in Japanese and share them with your friends!</p>
										<p>This is yet another tool we are developing to help people learn to think in Japanese.  And best of all, the Visual Sentence Composer is free!  Although, subscribers will get extra bells and whistles to play with.</p>
										
										<p>Sign up today to be notified when the Visual Sentence Composer is ready.  Coming soon to a screen-device near you.</p>
										
										
									</section>

							</div>
						</div><!--endrow-->
					</div><!--endcontainer>-->
					<div>
						<div>
							<div>

								<!-- Feature #2 -->
									<section>
										<a href="#"><img alt="Build Japanese Sentences Visually with the Japanese Complete Sentence Composer." src="https://jpc0.b-cdn.net/img/mf-composer-004.png"></a>
										<h2>Four Simple Steps to Generating Real Japanese</h2>
										<p>
											We take the guess work out of grammar by providing a clean interface that limits the acceptable next input based on Japanese grammatical rules.
										</p>
										<p>Just follow the four easy steps and you're making real Japanese.  Choose a noun, then choose the correct corresponding particle, repeat steps one and two until you have all the <em>who, what, when, where, and hows</em> of your sentence, and finally select the correct verb for the sentence.  すごい！ [sugoi!]  Brilliant!</p>
										<p>We plan to offer translations of your creations inline so you can verify that you are <strong>meaning what you say and saying what you mean.</strong></p>
									</section>

							</div>
						</div><!--endrow-->
					</div><!--endcontainer>-->
					<div>
						<div>
							<div>

								<!-- Feature #3 -->
									<section>
										<a href="#"><img alt="In four easy steps, write real Japanese that obeys Japanese grammar rules!" src="https://jpc0.b-cdn.net/img/mf-composer-002.png"></a>
										<h2>Point, Click, Post, Share!</h2>
										<p>Part of learning a language to mastery is being able to generate fresh thoughts and ideas on your own.  With our visual sentence composer you'll be able to create fresh statements and share them with your friends.</p>
										<p>Other users on the platform will be able to see your posts and give you encouragement with a "like" or a "re-wag" (similar to a "retweet" in Twitterland.) </p>
										<p>People will be able to see your unique statements made from real Japanese, and we plan to offer inline translations of the posts so others can follow along in English and so that you can be sure your statement means what you want it to mean.</p>
									</section>

							</div>
						</div><!--endrow-->
					</div><!--endcontainer>-->
				</section>
				<!--boxes-->
				




				<section id="content2">
					<div>
						<div>
							<div>


								<!-- Feature #4 -->
									<section>
										
										<a href="#"><img alt="Sacred Mountain Fuji as framed by cherry blossoms." src="https://jpc0.b-cdn.net/img/fujicherry.jpg"></a>
										<h2>Master Japanese with Ease</h2>
										<p>
											Japanese, just like any other skill, takes practice to master.  Start your immersion experience in a fun and social way -- by creating real Japanese and sharing it with others, so you can encourage one another on your path to mastery!</p>
										<p>There are many ways to get exposed to Japanese via media, music, shows, and immersion, but relatively few ways to practice language generation in a way that makes sure you won't habituate to making the same mistakes over and over again.  We are changing this with our Visual Sentence Composer.  <a href="#signup">Sign up today to be notified when it's available for free!</a></p>
									</section>

							</div>

						</div>
					</div>
				</section>
			<!-- -->
			<!-- Features -->
			

	


			<!-- Footer -->
				

			<!-- Copyright -->
				<p>
					© Japanese Complete 2019, 2020, 2021. All rights reserved.
				</p>

		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://japanesecomplete.com/visual-composer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25888468</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 02:32:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pip has dropped support for Python 2]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 755 | Comments 644 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25888249">thread link</a>) | @groodt
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<li><p><strong>PROCESS</strong> Version numbers are now simply <code><span>X.Y</span></code> where the leading <code><span>1</span></code>
has been dropped.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> Dropped support for Python 3.1.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> Removed the bundle support which was deprecated in
1.4. (#1806)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> File lists generated by <cite>pip show -f</cite> are now
rooted at the location reported by show, rather than one (unstated)
directory lower. (#1933)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> The ability to install files over the FTP protocol
was accidentally lost in pip 1.5 and it has now been decided to not restore
that ability.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>BACKWARD INCOMPATIBLE</strong> PEP 440 is now fully implemented, this means that
in some cases versions will sort differently or version specifiers will be
interpreted differently than previously. The common cases should all function
similarly to before.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--download-cache</span></code> and
<code><span>pip</span> <span>wheel</span> <span>--download-cache</span></code> command line flags have been deprecated and
the functionality removed. Since pip now automatically configures and uses
it’s internal HTTP cache which supplants the <code><span>--download-cache</span></code> the
existing options have been made non functional but will still be accepted
until their removal in pip v8.0. For more information please see
<a href="https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/reference/pip_install.html#caching">https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/reference/pip_install.html#caching</a></p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--build</span></code> and <code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--no-clean</span></code> are now
<em>NOT</em> deprecated.  This reverses the deprecation that occurred in v1.5.3.
(#906)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>DEPRECATION</strong> Implicitly accessing URLs which point to an origin which is
not a secure origin, instead requiring an opt-in for each host using the new
<code><span>--trusted-host</span></code> flag (<code><span>pip</span> <span>install</span> <span>--trusted-host</span> <span>example.com</span> <span>foo</span></code>).</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the new <code><span>--trusted-host</span></code> flag to also disable TLS verification for
a particular hostname.</p></li>
<li><p>Added a <code><span>--user</span></code> flag to <code><span>pip</span> <span>freeze</span></code> and <code><span>pip</span> <span>list</span></code> to check the
user site directory only.</p></li>
<li><p>Silence byte compile errors when installation succeed. (#1873)</p></li>
<li><p>Added a virtualenv-specific configuration file. (#1364)</p></li>
<li><p>Added site-wide configuration files. (1978)</p></li>
<li><p>Added an automatic check to warn if there is an updated version of pip
available. (#2049)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>wsgiref</cite> and <cite>argparse</cite> (for &gt;py26) are now excluded from <cite>pip list</cite> and
<cite>pip freeze</cite>. (#1606, #1369)</p></li>
<li><p>Add <code><span>--client-cert</span></code> option for SSL client certificates. (#1424)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip show --files</cite> was broken for wheel installs. (#1635, #1484)</p></li>
<li><p>install_lib should take precedence when reading distutils config.
(#1642, #1641)</p></li>
<li><p>Send <cite>Accept-Encoding: identity</cite> when downloading files in an attempt to
convince some servers who double compress the downloaded file to stop doing
so. (#1688)</p></li>
<li><p>Stop breaking when given pip commands in uppercase (#1559, #1725)</p></li>
<li><p>pip no longer adds duplicate logging consumers, so it won’t create duplicate
output when being called multiple times. (#1618, #1723)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip wheel</cite> now returns an error code if any wheels fail to build. (#1769)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip wheel</cite> wasn’t building wheels for dependencies of editable requirements.
(#1775)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the use of <code><span>--no-use-wheel</span></code> within a requirements file. (#1859)</p></li>
<li><p>Attempt to locate system TLS certificates to use instead of the included
CA Bundle if possible. (#1680, #1866)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow use of Zip64 extension in Wheels and other zip files. (#1319, #1868)</p></li>
<li><p>Properly handle an index or --find-links target which has a &lt;base&gt; without a
href attribute. (#1101, #1869)</p></li>
<li><p>Properly handle extras when a project is installed via Wheel. (#1885, #1896)</p></li>
<li><p>Added support to respect proxies in <code><span>pip</span> <span>search</span></code>.
(#1180, #932, #1104, #1902)</p></li>
<li><p><cite>pip install --download</cite> works with vcs links. (#798, #1060, #1926)</p></li>
<li><p>Disabled warning about insecure index host when using localhost. Based off of
Guy Rozendorn’s work in #1718. (#1456, #1967)</p></li>
<li><p>Allow the use of OS standard user configuration files instead of ones simply
based around <code><span>$HOME</span></code>. (#2021)</p></li>
<li><p>When installing directly from wheel paths or urls, previous versions were not
uninstalled. (#1825, #804, #1838)</p></li>
<li><p>Detect the location of the <code><span>.egg-info</span></code> directory by looking for any file
located inside of it instead of relying on the record file listing a
directory. (#2075, #2076)</p></li>
<li><p>Use a randomized and secure default build directory when possible.
(#1964, #1935, #676, #2122, CVE-2014-8991)</p></li>
<li><p>Support environment markers in requirements.txt files. (#1433, #2134)</p></li>
<li><p>Automatically retry failed HTTP requests by default. (#1444, #2147)</p></li>
<li><p>Handle HTML Encoding better using a method that is more similar to how
browsers handle it. (#1100, #1874)</p></li>
<li><p>Reduce the verbosity of the pip command by default. (#2175, #2177, #2178)</p></li>
<li><p>Fixed <a href="https://github.com/pypa/pip/issues/2031">#2031</a> - Respect sys.executable on OSX when installing from
Wheels.</p></li>
<li><p>Display the entire URL of the file that is being downloaded when downloading
from a non PyPI repository. (#2183)</p></li>
<li><p>Support setuptools style environment markers in a source distribution. (#2153)</p></li>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pip.pypa.io/en/stable/news/#id1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25888249</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 02:01:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Software engineering topics I changed my mind on]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 1093 | Comments 657 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25887373">thread link</a>) | @goostavos
<br/>
January 23, 2021 | https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><article><p><img alt="image" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1440px.jpeg" srcset="https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1440px.jpeg 1440w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-1200px.jpeg 1200w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-960px.jpeg 960w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-720px.jpeg 720w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-480px.jpeg 480w, https://s3.amazonaws.com/awsblogstore/articles/162da1cd/5cfd8e9f-image-240px.jpeg 240w"></p><p><sup>Published: 2021-01-23</sup></p><h2>Things I've changed my mind on:</h2><p>Things I now believe, which past me would've squabbled with:</p><ul><li>Typed languages are better when you're working on a team of people with various experience levels</li><li>Standups are actually useful for keeping an eye on the newbies.</li><li>Sprint retrospectives have their place so long as they're for actual course correction (i.e. "holy shit, <i>that</i> went poorly!") and not some god awful&nbsp; 'agile' / 'scum master' driven waste of everyone's time</li><li>Software architecture probably matters more than anything else. A shitty implementation of a good abstraction causes no net harm to the code base. A bad abstraction or missing layer causes everything to rot. &nbsp;</li><li>Java isn't that terrible of a language.</li><li>Clever code isn't usually good code. Clarity trumps all other concerns.</li><li>Bad code can be written in any paradigm</li><li>So called "best practices" are contextual and not broadly applicable. Blindly following them makes you an idiot</li><li>Designing scalable systems when you don't need to makes you a <i>bad engineer</i>.</li><li>Static analysis is useful</li><li>DRY is about avoiding a specific problem, not an end goal unto itself.</li><li>In general, RDBMS &gt; NoSql</li><li>Functional programming is another tool, not a panacea.</li></ul><h2>Opinions I've picked up along the way</h2><ul><li>YAGNI, SOLID, DRY. In that order.</li><li>Pencil and paper are the best programming tools and vastly under used</li><li>Trading purity in exchange for practicality is usually a good call</li><li>Adding more technology is rarely a good call</li><li>Talking directly to the customer always reveals more about the problem, in less time, and with higher accuracy</li><li>The word "scalable" has a mystical and stupefying power over the mind of the software engineer. Its mere utterance can whip them into a depraved frenzy. Grim actions have been justified using this word</li><li>Despite being called "engineers," most decision are pure cargo-cult with no backing analysis, data, or numbers</li><li>90% – <i>maybe</i> 93% – of project managers, could probably disappear tomorrow to either no effect or a net gain in efficiency.</li><li>After performing over 100 interviews: interviewing is thoroughly broken. I also have no idea how to actually make it better.</li></ul><h2>Old opinions unchanged:</h2><ul><li>People who stress over code style, linting rules, or other minutia are insane weirdos</li><li>Code coverage has absolutely nothing to do with code quality</li><li>Monoliths are pretty good in most circumstances</li><li>TDD purists are just <i>the worst</i>. Their frail little minds can't process the existence of different workflows.</li></ul><p>&nbsp; We'll see which of these have flipped or changed at year 10.</p></article></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25887373</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:02:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
