<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 12:25:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 12:25:41 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Structured Concurrency]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25032133">thread link</a>) | @ingve
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>TL;DR: <strong>“Structured concurrency” refers to a way to structure async computations so that child operations are guaranteed to complete before their parents, just the way a function is guaranteed to complete before its caller.</strong> This sounds simple and boring, but in C++ it’s anything but. Structured concurrency — most notably, C++20 coroutines — has profound implications for the correctness and the simplicity of async architecture. It brings the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cpp/cpp/welcome-back-to-cpp-modern-cpp?view=msvc-160">Modern C++ style</a> to our async programs by making async lifetimes correspond to ordinary C++ lexical scopes, eliminating the need for reference counting to manage object lifetime.</p>
<h2>Structured Programming and C++</h2>
<p>Back in the 1950’s, the nascent computing industry discovered structured programming: that high-level programming languages with lexical scopes, control structures, and subroutines resulted in programs that were far easier to read, write, and maintain than programming at the assembly level with test-and-jump instructions and <code>goto</code>. The advance was such a quantum leap that nobody talks about structured programming anymore; it’s just “programming”.</p>
<p>C++, more so than any other language, leverages structured programming to the hilt. The semantics of object lifetime mirror — and are tied to — the strict nesting of scopes; i.e., the <em>structure</em> of your code. Function activations nest, scopes nest, and object lifetimes nest. Objects’ lifetimes end with a scope’s closing curly brace, and objects are destroyed in the reverse order of their construction to preserve the strict nesting.</p>
<p>The Modern C++ programming style is built on this structured foundation. Objects have <em>value semantics</em> — they behave like the ints — and resources are cleaned up in destructors deterministically, which guarantees structurally that resources aren’t used after their lifetimes have ended. This is <em>very</em> important.</p>
<p>When we abandon this strict nesting of scopes and lifetimes — say, when we reference count an object on the heap, or when we use the singleton pattern — we are fighting against the strengths of the language rather than working with them.</p>
<h2>The Trouble With Threads</h2>
<p>Writing correct programs in the presence of concurrency is far more difficult than in single-threaded code. There are lots of reasons for this. One reason is that threads, like singletons and dynamically allocated objects, scoff at your puny nested scopes. Although you can use the Modern C++ style <em>within</em> a thread, when logic and lifetimes are scattered across threads, the hierarchical structure of your program is lost. The tools we use to manage complexity in single-threaded code — in particular, nested lifetimes tied to nested scopes — simply don’t translate to async code.</p>
<p>To see what I mean, let’s look at what happens when we take a simple synchronous function and make it asynchronous.</p>
<pre>void computeResult(State &amp; s);

int doThing() {
  State s;
  computeResult(s);
  return s.result;
}
</pre>
<p><code>doThing()</code> is simple enough. It declares some local state, calls a helper, then returns some result. Now imagine that we want to make both functions async, maybe because they take too long. No problem, let’s use Boost futures, which support continuation chaining:</p>
<pre>boost::future&lt;void&gt; computeResult(State &amp; s);

boost::future&lt;int&gt; doThing() {
  State s;
  auto fut = computeResult(s);
  return fut.then(
    [&amp;](auto&amp;&amp;) { return s.result; }); // OOPS
}
</pre>
<p>If you’ve programmed with futures before, you’re probably screaming, <em>“Nooooo!”</em> The <code>.then()</code> on the last line queues up some work to run after <code>computeResult()</code> completes. <code>doThing()</code> then returns the resulting future. The trouble is, when <code>doThing()</code> returns, the lifetime of the <code>State</code> object ends, <em>and the continuation is still referencing it</em>. That is now a dangling reference, and will likely cause a crash.</p>
<p>What has gone wrong? Futures let us compute with results that aren’t available yet, and the Boost flavor lets us chain continuations. But the continuation is a separate function with a separate scope. We often need to share data across those separate scopes. No more tidy nested scopes, no more nested lifetimes. We have to manage the lifetime of the state manually, something like this:</p>
<pre>boost::future&lt;void&gt;
computeResult(shared_ptr&lt;State&gt; s); // addref
                                    // the state

boost::future&lt;int&gt; doThing() {
  auto s = std::make_shared&lt;State&gt;();
  auto fut = computeResult(s);
  return fut.then(
    [s](auto&amp;&amp;) { return s.result; }); // addref
                                       // the state
}
</pre>
<p>Since both async operations refer to the state, they both need to share responsibility to keep it alive.</p>
<p>Another way to think about this is: <em>what is the lifetime of this asynchronous computation?</em> It starts when <code>doThing()</code> is called, but it doesn’t end until the continuation — the lambda passed to <code>future.then()</code> — returns. <em>There is no lexical scope that corresponds to that lifetime.</em> And that is the source of our woes.</p>
<h2>Unstructured Concurrency</h2>
<p>The story gets more complicated yet when we consider executors. Executors are handles to executions contexts that let you schedule work onto, say, a thread or thread pool. Many codebases have some notion of an executor, and some let you schedule things with a delay or with some other policy. This lets us do cool things, like move a computation from an IO thread pool to a CPU thread pool, or retry an async operation with a delay. Handy, but like <code>goto</code> it is a very low-level control structure that tends to obfuscate rather than clarify.</p>
<p>For instance, I recently came across an algorithm that uses executors and callbacks (called Listeners here) that retries the async allocation of some resource. Below is a greatly abridged version. It is described after the break.</p>
<pre>// This is a continuation that gets invoked when
// the async operation completes:
struct Manager::Listener : ListenerInterface {
  shared_ptr&lt;Manager&gt; manager_;
  executor executor_;
  size_t retriesCount_;

  void onSucceeded() override {
    /* ...yay, allocation succeeded... */
  }
  void onFailed() override {
    // When the allocation fails, post a retry
    // to the executor with a delay
    auto alloc = [manager = manager_]() {
      manager-&gt;allocate();
    };
    // Run "alloc" at some point in the future:
    executor_.execute_after(
      alloc, 10ms * (1 &lt;&lt; retriesCount_));
  }
};

// Try asynchronously allocating some resource
// with the above class as a continuation
void Manager::allocate() {
  // Have we already tried too many times?
  if (retriesCount_ &gt; kMaxRetries) {
    /* ...notify any observers that we failed */
    return;
  }

  // Try once more:
  ++retriesCount_;
  allocator_.doAllocate(
    make_shared&lt;Listener&gt;(
      shared_from_this(),
      executor_,
      retriesCount_));
}
</pre>
<p>The <code>allocate()</code> member function first checks to see if the operation has already been retried too many times. If not it calls a helper <code>doAllocate()</code> function, passing in a callback to be notified on either success or failure. On failure, the handler posts deferred work to the executor, which will call <code>allocate()</code> back, thus retrying the allocation with a delay.</p>
<p>This is a heavily stateful and rather circuitous async algorithm. The logic spans many functions and several objects, and the control and data flow is not obvious. Note the intricate ref-counting dance necessary to keep the objects alive. Posting the work to an executor makes it even harder. Executors in this code have no notion of continuations, so errors that happen during task execution have nowhere to go. The <code>allocate()</code> function can’t signal an error by throwing an exception if it wants any part of the program to be able to recover from the error. Error handling must be done manually and out-of-band. Ditto if we wanted to support cancellation.</p>
<p>This is <strong>unstructured concurrency</strong>: we queue up async operations in an <em>ad hoc</em> fashion; we chain dependent work, use continuations or “strand” executors to enforce sequential consistency; and we use strong and weak reference counts to keep data alive until we are certain it’s no longer needed. There is no formal notion of task A being a child of task B, no way to enforce that child tasks complete before their parents, and no one place in the code that we can point to and say, “Here is the algorithm.”</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>If you don’t mind the analogy, the hops through the executor are a bit like <code>goto</code> statements that are non-local in both time and space: “Jump to this point in the program, <em>X</em> milliseconds from now, on this particular thread.”</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>That non-local discontinuity makes it hard to reason about correctness and efficiency. Scale unstructured concurrency up to whole programs handling lots of concurrent real-time events, and the incidental complexity of manually handling out-of-band asynchronous control and data flow, controlling concurrent access to shared state, and managing object lifetime becomes overwhelming.</p>
<h2>Structured Concurrency</h2>
<p>Recall that in the early days of computing, unstructured programming styles rapidly gave way to structured styles. With the addition of coroutines to C++, we are seeing a similar phase shift happening today to our asynchronous code. If we were to rewrite the above retry algorithm in terms of coroutines (using Lewis Baker’s popular <a href="https://github.com/lewissbaker/cppcoro">cppcoro</a> library), it might look something like this:</p>
<pre>// Try asynchronously allocating some resource
// with retry:
cppcoro::task&lt;&gt; Manager::allocate() {
  // Retry the allocation up to kMaxRetries
  // times:
  for (int retriesCount = 1;
       retriesCount &lt;= kMaxRetries;
       ++retriesCount) {
    try {
      co_await allocator_.doAllocate();
      co_return; // success!
    } catch (...) {}

    // Oops, it failed. Yield the thread for a
    // bit and then retry:
    co_await scheduler_.schedule_after(
      10ms * (1 &lt;&lt; retriesCount));
  }

  // Error, too many retries
  throw std::runtime_error(
    "Resource allocation retry count exceeded.");
}
</pre>
<blockquote>
<p>Aside: This replaces the <code>executor_</code> with a <code>scheduler_</code> that implements cppcoro’s <a href="https://github.com/lewissbaker/cppcoro#delayedscheduler-concept">DelayedScheduler</a> concept.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Let’s …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/">https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ericniebler.com/2020/11/08/structured-concurrency/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25032133</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 07:15:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I'm going to experiment by being Blind and Alone for 24 Hours]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031774">thread link</a>) | @Osiris30
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-896">

	
	<!-- .entry-header -->


			<div>

			
<figure><img data-attachment-id="901" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/bird-box/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg" data-orig-size="2000,1050" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="bird-box" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=760" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=1024" alt="" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=150 150w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=300 300w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg?w=768 768w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/bird-box.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"></figure>



<p>For 24 hours I will be blind and alone in my apartment. I eventually want to try being blind for a week, but I’ll need seven days with no other obligations, and I won’t have that for a while. For now, I’ll suffice with a smaller-scale experiments with a few extra provisions for added difficulty.</p>







<ol type="1"><li>I must leave my blindfold on for 24 hours.<ul><li>If I remove the blindfold, I have failed the experiment</li><li>If the blindfold falls off or I can get partial sight, I have failed the experiment.</li><li>I am only allowed to readjust my blindfold if I can see light.</li></ul></li><li>I must not be in contact with any other people for 24 hours.<ul><li>I cannot answer my phone or any other messaging system.</li><li>I cannot receive in-person visitors.</li><li>If someone knocks at the door, I cannot answer verbally or physically.</li></ul></li><li>I will set an alarm for 24 hours. I cannot set any other alarms or use any other means to ascertain the time.<ul><li>It is up to me to keep my phone charged so the alarm goes off.</li></ul></li><li>I cannot leave my apartment.</li></ol>











<p>I have no good reason. I just want to see if I am capable of doing it and what will happen. Some things I’m curious about:</p>



<ul><li>Do I have the willpower to get through the experiment?</li><li>Will I become disoriented from losing all sense of time?</li><li>Will I be able to stave off boredom with podcasts, audiobooks, and music on my phone?</li><li>Will I enter some sort of meditative state due to a lack of sensory input?</li><li><a href="https://www.discovermagazine.com/the-sciences/scientists-made-people-wear-blindfolds-for-4-days-the-resulting-hallucinations-were-incredible">Will I hallucinate</a>?</li><li>Will my non-sight senses heighten?</li><li>Will I hurt myself by falling or banging into something?</li><li>Will I sleep?</li><li>Will I eat? Is consuming caffeine a good idea (for entertainment) or a bad idea (energy with no direction)?</li><li>Will this experience make me more interested in being blind for a week? Or less?</li></ul>



<figure><img src="https://digitalimpact.io/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Blind.png" alt="Modern CEOs Are Blindfolded - Digital Impact"></figure>







<p>Attempt One started at 10:30 AM and failed at 1:13 PM. I purposefully took off my blindfold because I was worried that my multiple failures to input my Iphone’s password had resulted in a permanent lock or data wipe. But the password screen was just locked for a minute and all was well.</p>



<p>Given that I failed in the early afternoon, I considered restarting the experiment on another day in the morning. But I had already carved out a 24 hour period when I wouldn’t do any work or be disturbed, and it might have been a week or two longer before I got that opportunity again.</p>



<p>So I checked my messages, briefly went on Reddit, and then restarted.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="903" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/t86752/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg" data-orig-size="521,610" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;CSA Images \/ CSA Images&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;Blindfolded Woman&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;\u00a9 CSA Images \/ CSA Images&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;T86752&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="T86752" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=256" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=521" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=521" alt="" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg 521w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=128 128w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blindfold-2.jpg?w=256 256w" sizes="(max-width: 521px) 100vw, 521px"></figure></div>







<p>Attempt Two was successful. I put on my blindfold at 1:23 PM on Thursday, November 5, 2020. I removed it at 1:28 PM on Friday, November 6.</p>



<p>It was an… interesting experience. I don’t recommend it, but I’m glad I did it. I’m not sure where to begin in describing it, especially since I couldn’t take notes, and part of the challenge was being confused. But I’ll do my best to break down the experience.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0818/3417/products/Les_Sublimes_Cashmere_Scarf_Dark_Blue_packshot_2048x.jpg?v=1539973736" alt="Large Cashmere Scarf in Dark Blue | Les Sublimes" width="427" height="427"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Blindfold</span></strong></h2>



<p>To simulate blindness, I used a dark blue scarf as a blindfold. One layer wasn’t quite dark enough, so I folded it in half for extra light defense.</p>



<p>With the blindfold securely on, my vision was the same whether my eyes were open or closed. I kept my eyes closed 99.9% of the time since it was usually more comfortable and helped limit light. I occasionally opened my eyes to check the brightness level and to… I guess you could call it <em>stretch my eyelids.</em> They don’t feel good if you leave them closed for too long.</p>



<p>I couldn’t get a perfect scarf seal around my eyes, so sometimes when I tilted my head back while sitting I noticed a little light come into the bottom of my vision. To limit this, I often pinched the scarf around my nose in that position. But many/most blind people can see some light anyway, so I don’t think this was a significant violation of the experiment.</p>



<p>My eyes got quite dry under the scarf, so I applied moisturizer to this lids and sockets four or five times. I wanted to use eyedrops too, but there was no way to do so without failing the experiment.</p>



<figure><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="906" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/image/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg" data-orig-size="225,225" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="image" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=225" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=225" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=225" alt="BLACK N BLACK - #blackouttuesday ✊🏻✊🏼✊🏽✊🏾✊🏿 | Facebook" width="786" height="786" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg 225w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/image.jpeg?w=150 150w" sizes="(max-width: 786px) 100vw, 786px"></figure>



<h2><strong><span>Blindness</span></strong></h2>



<p>Initially, everything was black, but as the day went on and the sun went down, I could tell it was nighttime even through two layers of scarf and my eyelids. I’m not sure if I could tell because my eyes had adjusted to become extremely sensitive to light, or if there were other subtle signals (ie. noises, air temperature, circadian rhythms, etc.) which my body picked up on. As evidence of the latter, I could not see any difference between the tv being on or off, nor the refrigerator being opened or closed, even when I was sitting right in front of either.</p>



<p>What I saw depended on how I applied my focus. If I did focus on my vision, I’d see the typical blackness you get from closing your eyes, but it was never perfectly black nor uniform; there was always some odd movement and occasional coloring (whiteness, pale blue, or sometimes red). The most common distortions were a swirling or flowing whiteness, sort of like cream in coffee. I hoped that being blindfolded for so long would make the distortions more extreme, but for the most part it looked no different than what you’d see if you closed your eyes right now for ten minutes.</p>



<p>There was one exception. It must have been about 20+ hours into the experiment, and my eyes were itching, so I rubbed both of them at the same time over the scarf. If you rub your closed eyes and focus on your sight any time you can see some weird stuff, but this was far more extreme than usual. I remember my entire vision filling up with white bubbles which then broke and briefly returned to black. Then white lightning bolt shapes stretched across my sight, expanded to make my vision purely white, and then slowly faded back to black. The strangest thing about it was the <em>brightness</em>. I literally felt like I was staring into lights despite being blindfolded in a dark room. Unfortunately, it only lasted about 30 seconds, but my heart was racing.</p>



<p>More notable than what I saw was what I didn’t see. By default, I was lost in thought and I focused on nothing. In such a state, I didn’t even register my vision or notice the darkness. I <em>think</em> this made my imagination and mental visualization more acute. On occasion, I’d be deep in thought and I’d get the <em>brightness</em> sensation again because I’d be mentally picturing something so vividly that the inevitable return to darkness felt like shutting off the lights in my brain. I’ll explain more about this in the <strong>Three Phases</strong> section.</p>



<p>Sadly, I did not hallucinate, or at least not as far as I could tell.</p>



<figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/www.intelligentliving.co/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/sloth-sleeping.jpg?fit=1024%2C698&amp;ssl=1" alt="Fighting Bacteria With Sloth Fur"></figure>



<h2><strong><span>Energy</span></strong></h2>



<p>This was the most surprising aspect of the experiment.</p>



<p>I read that <a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Health/story?id=117902&amp;page=1#:~:text=Without%20light%20cues%20that%20the,as%20a%20result%2C%20researchers%20say.">blind people have trouble getting to sleep</a> because they don’t access any/enough light for their circadian rhythms. I seem to have the exact opposite problem. Without light, my body always thinks it’s time to sleep and has trouble doing anything else. Throughout most of the experiment, I felt extremely lethargic, lazy, and had to fight to stay awake.</p>



<p>I started my first failed experiment attempt at 10:30 AM. I had gotten 7.5 solid hours of sleep, I hadn’t done anything tiring the previous day, and I generally felt fine. Then I put on my blindfold, and within thirty minutes I was nodding off. I semi-slept for two hours before deciding to get an energy drink to get myself out of the funk. That worked, but as soon as it wore off, I was back in semi-sleep mode.</p>



<p>Even when I was firmly awake, I generally felt weak and lethargic. Movement around the apartment was annoying of course, but made so much more difficult by my energy levels. I ended up lying perfectly still in my comfy computer chair with my feet on a table 95% of the time. That is, when I wasn’t lying in bed.</p>



<p>On the other hand, when I removed my blindfold after 24 hours, I experienced a <em>burst</em> of energy. Seriously, it was like I had downed a double shot of espresso. It was like a switch had been flicked. The haziness and cobwebs were gone in an instant, and I felt the energy coursing through my body. I guess light has a big impact on me.</p>



<div><figure><img data-attachment-id="908" data-permalink="https://dormin.org/blind-man-2/" data-orig-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg" data-orig-size="615,479" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1604789422&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="blind-man-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=615" src="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=615" alt="" srcset="https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg 615w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=150 150w, https://dorminorg.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/blind-man-2.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 615px) 100vw, 615px"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Movement</span></strong></h2>



<p>I moved exactly how you’d expect… clumsily.</p>



<p>For the most part, I slowly walked around my apartment with a hand out to feel for walls and edges. Sometimes I’d get lazy and crawl just so it was easier. I know my apartment well enough that it wasn’t hard to get around, but every once in awhile I’d lose track of where I was and would be left slowly swinging my arm around searching for anything. It’s not a pleasant sensation.</p>



<p>Before the experiment, I had planned to pace around for fun, or maybe even do some exercise with the free time. But the confusion and especially the lethargy stopped all that. I just sat in my chair and didn’t move unless I needed to get a drink, go to the bathroom, or sleep.</p>



<p>I kind of wish I had done the experiment in an unfamiliar environment to add to the movement challenge, but oh well.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://secure.img1-fg.wfcdn.com/im/99629273/compr-r85/1167/116715839/dual-flush-elongated-one-piece-toilet-seat-included.jpg" alt="DeerValley Dual-Flush Elongated One-Piece Toilet (Seat Included) &amp; Reviews  | Wayfair" width="729" height="729"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Necessities</span></strong></h2>



<p>For food, I ate a big lunch at 10 AM before the experiment and then munched on dark chocolate throughout the night. I felt the heavy lethargy well before the lack of calories was an issue. I probably should have put some prepackaged meals in my fridge to eat, but I was worried about making a mess and not being able to clean up. Do I want ants? Because that’s how I get ants.</p>



<p>For drinks, I could manage to get to the kitchen and fill a cup with water when I needed to. I never took a full cup back to my chair just in case I knocked it over (clean up would be a nightmare). I also had some diet coke to serve as entertainment and put a little caffeine in me.</p>



<p>For the bathroom, I (a man) peed sitting down. I’m not ashamed to admit it.</p>



<div><figure><img src="https://imgaz2.staticbg.com/thumb/large/oaupload/banggood/images/F2/09/b934b522-e3e3-491d-b758-d0b92c259f0c.jpg" alt="Novel surreal melting distorted wall clock surrealist salvador dali style  wall clock amazing home decoration gift Sale - Banggood.com" width="802" height="801"></figure></div>



<h2><strong><span>Time</span></strong></h2>



<p>As part of the experiment, I never knew what time it was. This was intended to confuse me throughout the 24 hours, and it did, but it may have helped too. With no sense of time, it was easy to sit back and not think about it. Time drifted by and I existed. That was that.</p>



<p>I actually did ask Siri for the time once… it was late in the experiment, and it felt like I had put on the blindfold forever ago. As you’d expect, …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/">https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dormin.org/2020/11/08/the-blind-alone-and-confused-for-24-hours-challenge/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031774</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 05:39:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Start with pen and paper]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 72 | Comments 32 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031483">thread link</a>) | @sethetter
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://sethetter.com/posts/start-with-pen-and-paper/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sethetter.com/posts/start-with-pen-and-paper/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
            


<article>
    
    <section>
        <p>tl;dr — If you feel unfocused, grab a pen and paper and start writing your thoughts down.</p>
<p>Is there a question you are stuck on? A ambiguous goal you're trying to accomplish? Maybe a task you know you need to do but from which you keep getting distracted?</p>
<p><strong>Nothing will provide focus like pen and paper.</strong></p>
<p>It's all too easy these days to have a clear intention only to be sidetracked by the whirlpool of apps and services clawing for our attention on our devices.</p>
<p>It helps to take the time to groom our notification settings for importance and timeliness, but a digital device that we can use to complete nearly any task will never stand up to pen and paper in terms of it's ability to provide focus.</p>
<p>My thoughts are a constant whirlwind, I'm certainly more distractible than most, and interacting with nearly any online service only fuels that fire. So how can I get anything done if I'm unable to control my focus?</p>
<p><strong>Pen and paper.</strong> Whenever I catch myself stuck in the whirlpool, feeling not-great because I <em>know</em> I'm not doing what I want to be doing, or what I should be doing, I step away, grab pen and paper, and start writing.</p>
<p>The simple act of writing can focus my thoughts and attention in a way that nothing else can. Free from distractions, just a canvas to pour my thoughts into, and turn them into something with a sense of direction and purpose.</p>
<p>Writing is like a superpower to me. If there's any task I want to accomplish, the first step is always to write it down. Anytime I need to recenter myself on that task, I simply return to paper.</p>
<p>Throughout my life I've found that the simplest solutions are often the most powerful. So far I've found no simpler solution to start tackling any problem than to simply write it down, and then keep on writing.</p>

    </section>
</article>


        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sethetter.com/posts/start-with-pen-and-paper/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031483</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 04:33:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Cool Machine Learning Books]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 101 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031455">thread link</a>) | @ridddle
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | http://matpalm.com/blog/cool_machine_learning_books/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://matpalm.com/blog/cool_machine_learning_books/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
  <p>awhile ago i posted
   <a href="http://matpalm.com/blog/2010/08/06/my-list-of-cool-machine-learning-books/">my list of cool machine learning books</a>,
   but it's been awhile so it's probably time to update it...
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/mml.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://mml-book.github.io/">Mathematics for Machine Learning</a>
   by Marc Peter Deisenroth, A. Aldo Faisal &amp; Cheng Soon Ong.</b>
</p>
<p>this is my personal favorite book on the general math required for machine learning,
   the way things are described really resonate with me.
   available as a free pdf but i got a paper copy to support the authors after reading the
   first half.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/laalfd.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="http://math.mit.edu/~gs/learningfromdata/">Linear Algebra and Learning from Data</a>
   by Gilbert Strang.</b>
</p>
<p>this is gilbert's most recent work. it's really great, he's such a good teacher, and
   <a href="https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/mathematics/18-065-matrix-methods-in-data-analysis-signal-processing-and-machine-learning-spring-2018/">his freely available lectures</a>
   are even better. it's a shorter text than his other classic intro below with
   more of a focus on how things are connected to modern machine learning techniques.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/itla.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://math.mit.edu/~gs/linearalgebra/">Introduction to Linear Algebra</a>
   by Gilbert Strang.</b>
</p>
<p>this was my favorite linear algebra book for a long time before his 'learning from
   data' came out. this is a larger book with a more comprehensive view of linear algebra.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/ts.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://greenteapress.com/wp/think-stats-2e/">Think Stats: Probability and Statistics for Programmers</a> by Allen Downey.</b>
</p>
<p>this book focuses on practical computation methods for probability and statistics.
   i got a lot out of working through this one.
   it's all in python and available for free.
   ( exciting update! as part of writing this post i've discovered there's a new edition
   to read!)
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/dbda.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/doingbayesiandataanalysis/">Doing Bayesian Data Analysis</a>
   by John Kruscgke</b>
</p>
<p>on the bayesian side of things this is the book i've most enjoyed working through.
   i've only got the first edition which was R and
   <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenBUGS">BUGS</a> but i see
   the second edition is R,
   <a href="http://mcmc-jags.sourceforge.net/">JAGS</a> and
   <a href="https://mc-stan.org/">Stan</a>.
   it'd be fun i'm sure to work through it doing
   everything in <a href="https://github.com/pyro-ppl/numpyro">numpyro</a>. i might do that in all
   my free time. haha. "free time" hahaha. sob.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/eosl.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~hastie/ElemStatLearn/">The Elements of Statistical Learning</a>
   by Hastie, Tibshirani and Friedman</b>
</p>
<p>this is still one of the most amazing fundamental machine learning books i've ever had.
   in fact i've purchased this book <em>twice</em> and given it away both times :/ i might buy another
   copy some time soon, even though it's been freely available to download for ages. an
   amazing piece of work.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/pgm.jpg"></p>
<p><b>
   <a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/probabilistic-graphical-models">Probabilistic Graphical Models</a>
   by Daphne Koller &amp; Nir Friedman</b>
</p>
<p>this is an epic textbook that i'd love to understand better. i've read a couple of sections in
   detail but not the entire tome yet.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/praml.jpg"></p>
<p><b>
   <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/people/cmbishop/prml-book/">Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning</a>
   by Christopher Bishop</b>
</p>
<p>this is probably the best overall machine learning text book i've ever read. such a beautiful book
   and <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/uploads/prod/2006/01/Bishop-Pattern-Recognition-and-Machine-Learning-2006.pdf">the pdf is FREE FOR DOWNLOAD!!!</a>
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/mlapp.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/machine-learning-1">Machine Learning: A Probabilistic Perspective</a> by Kevin Murphy</b>
</p>
<p>this is my second favorite general theory text on machine learning.
   i got kevin to sign my copy when he was passing my desk once but
   someone borrowed it and never gave it back :(
   so if you see a copy with my name on the spine let me know!
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/homl.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/hands-on-machine-learning/9781492032632/">Hands-On Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn, Keras, and TensorFlow</a> by Aurélien Géron</b>
</p>
<p>this is the book i point most people to when they are interested in getting up
   to speed with modern applied machine learning without too much concern for the
   theory. it's very up to date (as much as a book can be) with the latest libraries
   and, most importantly, provides a good overview of not just neural stuff but fundamental
   <a href="https://scikit-learn.org/stable/">scikit-learn</a> as well.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/mle.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="http://www.mlebook.com/wiki/doku.php">Machine Learning Engineering</a> by Andriy Burkov</b>
</p>
<p>a great book focussing on the operations side of running a machine learning system. i'm a bit
   under half way through the free online version and very likely to buy a physical copy to finish
   it and support the author. great stuff and, in many ways, a more impactful book than any of
   the theory books here.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/itdm.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar001/dmbook/index.php">Introduction to Data Mining</a>
   by Pang-Ning Tan, Michael Steinbach &amp; Vipin Kumar</b>
</p>
<p>this is another one that was also on my list from ten years ago and though it's section
   on neural networks is a bit of chuckle these days there is still a bunch of really
   great fundamental stuff in this book. very practical and easy to digest. i also see there's
   a second edition now. i reckon this would compliment the "hands on" book above very well.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/salp.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://web.stanford.edu/~jurafsky/slp3/">Speech and Language Processing</a>
   by Dan Jurafsky &amp; James Martin</b>
</p>
<p>still the best overview of NLP there is (IMHO). can't wait to read the 3rd edition which
   apparently will cover more modern stuff (e.g. transformers) but until then, for the
   love of god though, please don't be one of those "this entire book is
   irrelevant now! just fine tune BERT" people :/
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/no.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007/978-0-387-40065-5">Numerical Optimization</a>
   by Jorge NocedalStephen J. Wright</b>
</p>
<p>this book is super hard core and maybe more an operations
   research book than machine learning. though i've not read it cover to cover the
   couple of bits i've worked through really taught me a lot. i'd love to understand
   the stuff in this text better; it's so so fundamental to machine learning (and more)
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/dl.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.deeplearningbook.org/">Deep Learning</a>
   by Ian Goodfellow</b>
</p>
<p>writing a book specifically on deep learning is very dangerous since things move so fast but
   if anyone can do it, ian can... i think ian's approach to explaining neural networks
   from the ground up is one of my favorites. i got the first edition hardback but it's free to
   download from the website.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/pr.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/probabilistic-robotics">Probabilistic Robotics</a>
   by Sebastian Thrun, Wolfram Burgard and Dieter Fox</b>
</p>
<p>when i first joined a robotics group i bought a stack of ML/robotics books and this
   was by far the best. it's good intro stuff, and maybe already dated in places given
   it's age (the 2006 edition i have) but i still got a bunch from it.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/tml.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/tinyml/9781492052036/">TinyML</a>
   by Pete Warden &amp; Daniel Situnayake</b>
</p>
<p>this was a super super fun book to tech review! neural networks on microcontrollers?!?
   yes please!
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/ec.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Evolutionary+Computation%3A+Toward+a+New+Philosophy+of+Machine+Intelligence%2C+3rd+Edition-p-9780471669517">Evolutionary Computation</a> by David Fogel</b>
</p>
<p>this is still by favorite book on evolutionary algorithms; i've had this for a loooong
   time now. i still feel like evolutionary approaches are due for a big big comeback
   any time soon....
</p>
<hr>


<h2>in the mail...</h2>
<p>the good thing about writing a list is you get people telling you cool ones you've missed :)
</p>
<p>the top three i've chosen (that are in the mail) are...
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/ciis.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="http://bayes.cs.ucla.edu/PRIMER/">Causal Inference in Statistics</a> by
   Judea Pearl, Madelyn Glymour &amp; Nicholas P. Jewell</b>
</p>
<p>recommended by <a href="https://twitter.com/animesh_garg">animesh</a> who quite rightly points out
   the lack of causality in machine learning books in the books above.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/itiala.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.cambridge.org/au/academic/subjects/computer-science/pattern-recognition-and-machine-learning/information-theory-inference-and-learning-algorithms?format=HB&amp;isbn=9780521642989">Information Theory, Inference and Learning Algorithms</a> by David MacKay</b>
</p>
<p>i've seen this book mentioned a number of times and was most recently recommended by
   my colleague <a href="https://twitter.com/danesherbs">dane</a> so it's time to get it.
</p>
<hr>
   <p><img src="http://matpalm.com/blog/imgs/2020/mlb/bmlpa.jpg"></p>
<p><b><a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/building-machine-learning/9781492045106/">Building Machine Learning Powered Applications</a> by Emmanuel Ameisen</b>
</p>
<p>a number of people i worked with have enjoyed this. first recommended by another
   colleague <a href="https://twitter.com/davidcolls">dave</a>.
   looks to be on the practical side rather than the theory but that's ok some times :)
</p>

  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://matpalm.com/blog/cool_machine_learning_books/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031455</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 04:26:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How does the event loop work in JavaScript? [video]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031384">thread link</a>) | @krayonatan
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://yonatankra.com/how-does-the-event-loop-work/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yonatankra.com/how-does-the-event-loop-work/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="primary"><main id="main" role="main"><article id="post-599"><div><!-- .entry-meta --><div> <p><span><span>Estimated Reading Time: </span> <span>&lt; 1</span> <span>minute</span></span></p><figure><p><span><iframe width="640" height="360" data-src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nqx3rtv_dko?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;fs=1&amp;hl=en-US&amp;autohide=2&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups allow-presentation"></iframe></span></p><figcaption>The event loop and your code talk from WarsawJS</figcaption></figure><p>On august 2020 I spoke at <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://warsawjs.com/" data-type="URL" data-id="https://warsawjs.com/" target="_blank">WarsawJS</a>, explaining about the event loop and how it works.  I hope you will enjoy this talk.</p><p>If you prefer to read – <a href="https://yonatankra.com/the-event-loop-and-your-code/" data-type="post" data-id="299">here’s the blog post this talk is based on</a>.</p><p id="jp-relatedposts"><h3><em>Related</em></h3></p></div><!-- .entry-content --><!-- .entry-footer --></div></article><!-- #post-## --><p><h3>Enjoyed the article?</h3><h4>Sign up to my newsletter to enjoy more content:</h4></p>  <nav role="navigation" aria-label="Posts"><h2>Post navigation</h2></nav><!-- #comments --></main><!-- #main --></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yonatankra.com/how-does-the-event-loop-work/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031384</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 04:12:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A fun website that simulates fluid]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25031304">thread link</a>) | @svikashk
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                        <p>Try Fluid Simulation app!</p>
                        <p><a id="apple_link" target="_blank">
                                <img alt="Download on the App Store" src="https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/app_badge.png">
                            </a>
                            <a id="google_link" target="_blank">
                                <img alt="Get it on Google Play" src="https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/gp_badge.png">
                            </a>
                        </p>
                    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://paveldogreat.github.io/WebGL-Fluid-Simulation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25031304</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 03:54:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Attention Is My Most Valuable Asset for Productivity as a Software Developer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 226 | Comments 89 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25030938">thread link</a>) | @zwbetz
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://zwbetz.com/attention-is-my-most-valuable-asset-for-productivity-as-a-software-developer/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://zwbetz.com/attention-is-my-most-valuable-asset-for-productivity-as-a-software-developer/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-content">
      <div>
        <div>
          <div>
            
  
  
  <p>
    
    
    
    <strong>Published: </strong>2020-11-08

    
    
      
      
        • <strong>Lastmod: </strong>2020-11-09

      
    
    
    
    
      <br>
      <span>
        <strong>Tags: </strong>
        
          
          
          
        
          
          
          
        
          
          
          
        
        <a href="https://zwbetz.com/tags/life/">life</a> • <a href="https://zwbetz.com/tags/attention/">attention</a> • <a href="https://zwbetz.com/tags/productivity/">productivity</a>
      
    </span>
  </p>
  
  
  
  

<p>Like a tightly written function, I prefer to exit early if no work should be done. So, if you disagree with these definitions and assumptions, now’s a good time to stop reading.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sustainable productivity:</strong> The maximum rate of quality work output, without loss to the wellbeing of the developer</li>
<li><strong>Quality work:</strong> Software that meets requirements, is valuable to users, is maintainable, and is as bug free as possible</li>
<li><strong>Attention:</strong> The limited mental capacity to focus on a task</li>
<li>Sustainable productivity is desired</li>
<li>Attention is essential to sustainable productivity</li>
</ul>
<p>My high-level workflow looks something like this: identify the problem to solve; think on the problem and let ideas percolate; research, discuss, and experiment with these ideas; implement and test the solution; deliver and maintain the solution.</p>
<p>This cycle could repeat many times in a day. Or I could spend days stuck on a single cycle step. Every step in this cycle requires attention. The more attention I can devote, the more cycles I can complete, and the more productive I am.</p>
<p>How long you can focus on a task varies by person. Some people are very good at it out of the box, some people, not so much. Regardless of the hand you were dealt, I believe that focus (the act of devoting your attention) is a skill, and like any skill, can be improved with practice.</p>
<p>So, how can you increase your attention reserves? The most bang for your buck is to organize your outside world in such a way that it’s distraction free as possible. Once you do that, you’ll have more time to practice, and therefore more time to get better.</p>
<p><strong>Build physical strength.</strong> The damage done by sitting 8+ hours a day is underrated. You need a way to offset this damage, especially if you plan to work in this field for decades. Opinions abound on this topic, but I personally prefer deadlifts. There are few movements more primal than picking a heavy object off the ground and standing up with it. You can <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wYREQkVtvEc">learn correct technique in little time</a>. I most like deadlifts because you can do them safely, at high weights, into old age. I also like the hand, back, and hip strength they give, to make it that much harder for sitting damage to have its way with you.</p>
<p><strong>Make your place of work boring and tidy.</strong> My office is a spare bedroom. The walls are blank. There’s no tv. There’s a desk, chair, laptop, laptop stand, keyboard, mouse, and mouse pad. There’s a window, which lets enough light in so that I don’t feel like I’m missing a beautiful day, but not too much light to cause screen glare. If I need to work with paper, it’s immediately filed somewhere when done. Like I said, boring and tidy.</p>
<p><strong>Make your smart phone dumb.</strong> My phone has all notifications disabled, except for calls and text messages. Well, and National Hurricane Center alerts, since I live in Louisiana. Unless you’re my wife, you know that I don’t respond to text messages immediately, that’s just how it is. I disabled my social media accounts some time ago. But if you have them, turning off notifications should help curve the urge to compulsively check them.</p>
<p><strong>Be an OS minimalist.</strong> Apps I use less commonly are a keypress combo away. Given this, my dock has only the apps I use on a daily basis:</p>
<ul>
<li>File system explorer</li>
<li>Internet browser</li>
<li>Terminal</li>
<li>Text editor for front-end code and notes</li>
<li>IDE for back-end code</li>
<li>IDE for database</li>
<li>Visual file differ for version control</li>
<li>Email client</li>
<li>Instant message client</li>
</ul>
<p>My desktop alternates between clean and dirty states. Files I’m currently working with live on the desktop. Then they’re filed away into sensible folders when done.</p>
<p><strong>Organize your browser bookmarks.</strong> When I read something useful that I may need to reference later, I file it under a general archive folder. Then more specific items get their own folders. Frequently accessed links are visible on my bookmarks bar under their own folder.</p>
<p><strong>Minimize meetings.</strong> Look, I know some things make sense to discuss face to face, or voice to voice. But if they don’t, then you don’t need a meeting. An email or instant message will suffice.</p>
<p><strong>Finally, use the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_management#The_Eisenhower_Method">The Eisenhower Method</a> to categorize your tasks.</strong> Imagine a grid of 4 quadrants:</p>
<ul>
<li>Important and Urgent</li>
<li>Important and Not Urgent</li>
<li>Not Important and Urgent</li>
<li>Not Important and Not Urgent</li>
</ul>
<p>Important and Urgent tasks have to be dealt with. For me, these are usually major production issues.</p>
<p>Important and Not Urgent tasks should absorb the bulk of your time. For me, this is the plain old development work of implementing features, fixing bugs, and making existing code more maintainable and performant. Also included are building relationships with others and planning ahead.</p>
<p>Not Important and Urgent tasks are nasty attention thieves. They shout out to you in immediacy, but offer little value in return. You know what these are for you. For me, these are most often lazily asked questions, where the asker did not do their due diligence, and expects a top-notch answer immediately. Also included are last-minute meetings, and over-talkative coworkers.</p>
<p>Not Important and Not Urgent tasks are usually not known to your users. Take internal documentation updates as an example. Thing is, they’re an investment in yourself, which means a more productive future “you”. So don’t forget to show them some love in your spare moments.</p>
<p><strong>Further reading.</strong> If you don’t know who Cal Newport is, you’re missing out. He has a whole blog dedicated to this type of thing, and has written books such as <em>Deep Work</em> and <em>Digital Minimalism</em>. Here are some of my favorite articles by him:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2009/02/04/have-we-lost-our-tolerance-for-a-little-boredom/">Have We Lost Our Tolerance For a Little Boredom?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2010/06/10/is-allowing-your-child-to-study-while-on-facebook-morally-equivalent-to-drinking-while-pregnant/">Is Allowing Your Child to Study While on Facebook Morally Irresponsible?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2008/04/07/monday-master-class-how-to-reduce-stress-and-get-more-done-by-building-an-autopilot-schedule/">Monday Master Class: How to Reduce Stress and Get More Done By Building an Autopilot Schedule</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2009/11/24/are-passions-serendipitously-discovered-or-painstakingly-constructed/">Are Passions Serendipitously Discovered or Painstakingly Constructed?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2018/06/08/jerry-seinfelds-closed-door/">Jerry Seinfeld’s Closed Door</a></li>
</ul>



  
  
  

  
  




          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://zwbetz.com/attention-is-my-most-valuable-asset-for-productivity-as-a-software-developer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25030938</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 02:39:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Restoring a 37 Year-Old IBM F Mechanical Keyboard]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 55 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25029571">thread link</a>) | @opsdisk
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://blog.opsdisk.com/restoring-a-37-year-old-ibm-model-f-mechanical-keyboard.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.opsdisk.com/restoring-a-37-year-old-ibm-model-f-mechanical-keyboard.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <p>I wanted to share my journey from start to finish to restore a 1983 IBM Model F XT mechanical keyboard to it's former glory.  It includes the steps, mistakes, and additional hardware required to make it functional with a modern computer.  This blog post is dedicated to my dad for teaching me about computers.</p>
<p><img alt="original.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/original.jpg"></p>

<p>A few months ago, my dad asked if I was interested in taking ownership of his <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_Personal_Computer">IBM model 5150 PC</a>.  Without hesitation, I said "yes!".  The first project I wanted to tackle was to restore the
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model_F_keyboard">1983 Model F XT mechanical keyboard</a> keyboard.  In a sentimental and
journeyman/apprentice-sense, it felt like my dad was passing on the tools of his craft to continue the family line of
computer work and I couldn't pass that up.</p>
<p><img alt="datestamp.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/datestamp.jpg"></p>

<p>For those of you unfamiliar with the IBM Model F, <a href="https://www.modelfkeyboards.com/">modelfkeyboards.com</a> summarizes it
nicely:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The IBM Model F keyboards not only used the best switches, the materials used in their production (well over 5lbs of
steel and other metals) means they will be working as good as new when it’s time to pass it on to your grandchildren.
The problem...they just aren't made that way any more.  The IBM Model F was discontinued in the 1980's.  If you do
find a Model F, it will be some combination of dirty, broken and/or expensive, requiring hours of work to get it
working again!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This tank of a keyboard weighs in at over 6 pounds, sounds like <a href="https://youtu.be/XTVeSCqYSmE?t=7">this</a>, and at the
time of production, retailed for $300-400 in 1982 ($800-1000 dollars adjusted in today's dollars!) according to this
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y9Jds326gks">review</a>.</p>
<p>The restoration did take a few hours and fortunately none of it involved a soldering iron or replacing any of the
electrical or physical components because it was already in great functioning shape...a true testament to the design.
Even cooler, this blog post was typed up using the restored Model F keyboard!</p>

<p>Before beginning the project, I discovered <a href="https://www.clickykeyboards.com/">ClickyKeyboards</a>, a site "Specializing in
the restoration and collection of model M keyboards", the successor to the Model F.  On ClickyKeyboards, there is a
section dedicated to the adapters and converters that may be required to make older 5-pin DIN plug keyboards compatible
with modern USB ports.  One of the companies mentioned on ClickyKeyboards is
<a href="https://www.hagstromelectronics.com/">Hagstrom Electronics</a>, which sells keyboard encoders and protocol converters.
Without looking too closely at the other products, I quickly purchased the
<a href="https://www.hagstromelectronics.com/keyboard-encoder-ke18-xtat-ps2-shp.html">KE18-XTAT-PS/2</a> which "converts an XT
keyboard into a PS/2 protocol keyboard" for $55.  I was ecstatic that there was at least something to get me into PS/2
land, because at that point I knew I could easily find a PS/2 to USB converter.</p>
<p>After the KE18-XTAT-PS/2 arrived, I quickly fired up an ancient box (yes, that is Windows 2000!) with a PS/2 input on
the motherboard.  I tested all the keys to ensure they still worked and they did!  With confirmation that the keyboard
still worked, it was time to start the restoration.</p>
<p><img alt="win2000.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/win2000.jpg"></p>

<p><img alt="original2.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/original2.jpg"></p>
<p>The first step was to remove the metal casing and see what the state of the board was underneath the keys.  There was
years worth of debris, coffee stains, and gunk that had to be removed.  In addition, there were a few spots with
corrosion on the board that needed to be addressed.</p>
<p><img alt="preclean.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/preclean.jpg"></p>
<p>Once the casing was off, I utilized compressed air to clean out the key bunkers and get rid of any loose nastiness.
Next, I tried using rubbing alcohol and Q-tips to try and remove some of the stickier stuff, but that didn't
really work.</p>

<p>I borrowed a rotary tool to buff out the corrosion.  I used one of the provided bits that had soft plastic tentacles to
try and buff out the corroded spots as gently as possible.  There are likely better and more appropriate bits, but it
did the job.  The rotary tool's power and RPMs were a bit overkill even on the lowest setting.  Ideally, I would have
used one with fewer minimum RPMs and a more precise bit to get all the spots.</p>
<p><img alt="buffing_tool_and_bit.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/buffing_tool_and_bit.jpg"></p>
<p><img alt="bit.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/bit.jpg"></p>
<p>I was using the rotary tool under a bright overhead desk lamp, and with the way the light was reflecting, I didn't
notice it was taking off the black finish and revealing the silver metal base.  At that point, I just decided to buff
off the finish where I could to make it look more uniform.  The silver metal is visible when the keys and cover are back
on it, but it looks fine.  Unfortunately, with the rotary head and bit size, I wasn't able to buff every last square
inch of the board, but I knew it'd be covered so I wasn't too concerned with it looking perfect.</p>
<p><img alt="allbuffed.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/allbuffed.jpg"></p>

<p><img alt="postbuffing.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/postbuffing.jpg"></p>
<p>There was still some residue stuck to the board that I wanted to remove.  I started out using a small eye glass
screwdriver to scrape it off, but it took some of the black finish off as well and didn't look that nice.  At that point,
a chemical pivot was required and I reached for the <a href="https://googone.com/">Goo Gone</a>, which I should have done from the
beginning.  The Goo Gone and a bit of elbow grease with Q-Tips did the trick in removing the stubborn gunk on the board.</p>
<p><img alt="postgoogone.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/postgoogone.jpg"></p>

<p>With the board in good shape, it was time to tackle the actual keys.  I first gave them a good wipe-down using desk
cleaning wipes, which removed most of the discoloration and stains.  However, they still didn't look as good as they
could, and I read that just soaking them in a bowl of dish soap and water for a few hours can do wonders...and it did.
They keys look brand new.</p>
<p><img alt="keybath.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/keybath.jpg"></p>
<p>One mistake I made after washing them was to not let them completely dry on the inside.  I placed the keys back on the
board too soon, and some water leaked onto a few of the springs causing a small amount of rusting (slightly visible in
the post-Goo Gone image).  I gave them another soap soak and used the compressed air to really get out the water.  I
also let them air dry for 1-2 days before putting them back on the board.</p>

<p>After successfully testing the actual keyboard and the restoration almost complete, it was time to search for a PS/2 to
USB cable.  On a whim, I was back on the Hagstrom Electronic site and noticed they already had a small box, the
<a href="https://www.hagstromelectronics.com/ke-xtusb-keyboard-encoder-shp.html">KE-XTUSB</a>, that converted the XT signal to USB,
and it was the same price.  They graciously allowed me to return the KE18-XTAT-PS/2 in exchange for the KE-XTUSB which
was the same price.  A few days later the KE-XTUSB arrived in the mail and I eagerly connected it to my current computer.</p>
<p><img alt="xtusb.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/xtusb.jpg"></p>

<p>Everything worked beautifully except for two keys.  The "s" key's spring mechanism would either not detect a key press
or would be stuck in the depressed state blasting "sssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssssss" across the screen.  With a
bit of finagling, I got the key cap placed correctly so now it works like a champ.  The other key that has issues is the
accountant's "+" near the 10 key pad.  The spring had come off somehow and I super glued it back, but something still
isn't right and it fails to register key strokes.  Not a huge loss since "+" can be achieved with another key
combination.</p>
<p>Overall, I'm really impressed with how it looks and, when comparing it to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E2bAhxK76hc">this</a>
unboxing video of a never before opened Model F, it looks about the same!</p>
<p>If you have any questions or comments, hit me up on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/opsdisk">@opsdisk</a>.</p>
<p><img alt="final.jpg" src="https://blog.opsdisk.com/images/keyboard/final.jpg"></p>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.opsdisk.com/restoring-a-37-year-old-ibm-model-f-mechanical-keyboard.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25029571</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 22:09:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Took a Break from Ham Radio and Why I Came Back]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25029459">thread link</a>) | @parsecs
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://www.kj7nzl.net/blog/3-reasons-why-i-took-a-break-from-ham-radio-why-i-came-back/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.kj7nzl.net/blog/3-reasons-why-i-took-a-break-from-ham-radio-why-i-came-back/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="content-pane">
  <div>
    
    <p>About three months ago I unconsciously or perhaps consciously lost interest in ham radio. This isn’t the first time this has happened to me, in fact this was what lead me to allow my license to lapse the first time in 2016. If it weren’t for a new coworker of mine showing interest in ham radio again after a twenty-five year absent; I presumably wouldn’t be writing this post now. His excitement about all of the recent advances that have been made since he was first license reminded me of the things I missed about ham radio. This forced me to reflect on the reasons that I stepped away from the hobby for nearly three months. After some time I narrowed it down to three primary reasons. Without further ado I present to you my three reasons I took a break from ham radio.</p>
<h2 id="1-2020-amsat-board-of-directors-election">1. 2020 AMSAT Board of Directors Election</h2>
<p>I love satellite operations! It was my primary reason for returning to the hobby earlier this year. Shortly after becoming licensed I joined AMSAT to support amateur radio in space. Little did I know there was an ongoing dispute among two newly elected board members and the rest of the board of directors. Apparently the dispute was over the access of to AMSAT’s finical records with the lengthy ordeal playing out like some pollical scandal with lawyers and secret audio recordings. The board of directors went as far as <a href="https://www.amsat.org/amsat-leadership-explains-2018-2020-legal-expenses/">releasing a statement</a> that was full of contempt for the two new directors. In turn Patrick Stoddard WD9EWK, one of the individuals at that center of this controversy <a href="http://amsat.wd9ewk.net/">released his own statement</a> on the events that transpired. All of this drama culminated with those who sided with Mr. Stoddard attempting replace three of the existing board members with there of their own candidates. Ultimately they were unsuccessful in their coup attempt, and I’ve exhausted all interest in being a part of AMSAT.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.kj7nzl.net/img/satellites/amsat-fm-0001.webp" alt="KJ7NZL working AO-92."> <figcaption>
            <p>KJ7NZL working AO-92</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="2-limited-radio-budget--limited-operating-options">2. Limited Radio Budget = Limited Operating Options</h2>
<p>Whether you want to admit it or not, ham radio is an expensive hobby. Sure you can purchase a Baofeng handheld for thirty-five dollars, but to really take advantage of all your license privileges you need to shell out some cold hard cash for either an HF rig or an all mode VHF/UHF radio. Initially, I wanted to get on the air as quickly and cheaply as possible to try my hand at working a few of the FM satellites, as a result I purchased an Arrow Antenna II and the Wouxun KG-UV8D Plus. To make a long story short, the Wouxun radio was garbage. Don’t believe me <a href="https://www.kj7nzl.net/blog/wouxun-kg-uv8d-plus-fm-satellites/">check out my review of the Wouxun KG-UV8D Plus</a>. After some time of fooling around with that dumb thing, I decided to purchase a Yaesu FT3D and I’m glad I did. On a side note, I should absolutely do a review of that thing since I’ve had it for about three months now and I’ve explored most everything the radio has to offer. With the KG-UV8D I was limited in how I could operate. With just supporting FM I really only could use the thing for satellites outside of using it to connect to any of the local repeaters in the area. On the other hand the Yaesu FT3D allowed me the ability to expore APRS and C4FM AKA System Fussion. This however came at the cost of three times the price of the KG-UV8D. All told, even after selling my KG-UV8D, I am about $600 into the hobby with an Arrow Antenna II, Yaesu FT3D, and Comet Dual Band HT antenna. Even with this setup I’m only able play around with FM satellites, APRS, and simplex/repeaters. I would have loved exploring some of the other areas of the hobby when I jumped back in the spring of this year, but discretionary funds were spread out among different things at the time.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.kj7nzl.net/img/aprs/aprs-001.webp" alt="KJ7NZL's Trip to Antelope Island State Park"> <figcaption>
            <p>KJ7NZL’s Trip to Antelope Island State Park</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="3-life-just-got-in-the-way">3. Life Just Got in the Way</h2>
<p>This year 2020 has been an unusual year for me. Between a global pandemic and finishing some of my basement, I’ve been very busy. As a result I’ve had little free time. What free time I’ve possessed has been divided between multiple hobbies with amateur radio taking a back seat most of the time. It’s my own fault really since I set out earlier this year with the goal of exclusively working FM satellites. I initial assumed it would be effortless to make time through out my day for a quick ten to fifteen minute pass. It made sense at the time; take a brief break, make a couple of contacts, and back to what I was doing before hand. But it turns out that FM satellite QSOs are hard work This in turn lead me to get frustrated very quickly and wish I could operate at my own pace whenever I felt like it. Just so you know, rarely do two FM satellite passes line up back to back when you want them two giving you a thirty to forty minute window of time in which to have fun. Looking back on my journey into ham radio, both the first time and second time, I should have just gone the HF route from the get go. Since I didn’t, I feel like I set myself up for disappointment. With very little motivation and other competing priorities it’s no wonder why I stepped away from ham radio as long I did.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://www.kj7nzl.net/img/radios/yaesu-ftdx-3000.webp" alt="Yaesu FTDX 3000"> <figcaption>
            <p>Yaesu FTDX 3000</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h3 id="moving-forward">Moving Forward</h3>
<p>So what does the future hold for me now that I’m interested in ham radio again? Well, Santa is coming to town, and he’s going to have a new Yaesu FTDX 3000 wrapped up under three for me. I’ll finally be able to dive head first into the world of HF. I have some ambitious plans too. I’d like to explore some of the lesser used digital modes like Hellschreiber, Olivia, and Contestia. I’ll still jump on the FT8 bandwagon, but ultimately I want to explore all the digital modes. I also want to <a href="https://www.kj7nzl.net/blog/learning-morse-code-series/">learn morse code</a>, which I’ve unsuccessfully started and begin working som CW. The Yaesu FTDX 3000 contains some exceptionally attractive features for CW operations that I really want to take advantage of. Another area that I’m going to focus on coming up soon will be building a MMDVM hotspot. Sure I could merely purchase a prebuilt one, but what the fun in that? All in all I think the rest of this year and next year is shaping up to be a excellent time for me to get back into ham radio.</p>

  </div>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.kj7nzl.net/blog/3-reasons-why-i-took-a-break-from-ham-radio-why-i-came-back/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25029459</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 21:56:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[About iSH’s pending removal from the App Store]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 640 | Comments 369 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25028252">thread link</a>) | @tbodt
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://ish.app/app-store-removal | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ish.app/app-store-removal">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
        

<p><strong><span>Update</span></strong>: We got a call this evening from someone who runs App Review. They apologized for the experience we had, then told us they've accepted our appeal and won't be removing iSH from the store tomorrow. We'll stay in contact with them to work out details. Thanks everyone for your support!
</p>


<p>On Monday, October 26th, just four days after we launched iSH on the App Store, we received a call from Apple informing us that they had found our app noncompliant with section 2.5.2 of the App Store Review Guidelines and that they would remove the app from sale if we did not submit a satisfactory update within two weeks. Despite our best efforts, we do not believe we will be able to bring iSH into compliance by tomorrow, the conclusion of this 14 day period, and we expect iSH to no longer be available to download from the App Store after that time. We are working our hardest to get iSH back on the App Store as soon as possible and hope for your understanding and support as we navigate our next steps in this process.</p>

<p>Thanks for using iSH!<br>
Theodore Dubois, Saagar Jha &amp; Martin Persson</p>

<h2 id="why-is-ish-being-removed">Why is iSH being removed?</h2>
<p>Apple believes iSH is not compliant with section 2.5.2 of the App Store Review Guidelines, which governs applications which download and run executable code. Specifically, they believe that iSH “is not self-contained and has remote package updating functionality”, and suggest that we should “remove the remote network activity functionality which could allow for remote code importing into the app, such as wget or curl, or other remote network commands”. Additional communication with Apple has indicated that they believe that iSH is a security concern if we allow any sort of code importing by the user.</p>

<p><strong>We believe iSH is fully compliant with the App Store Review Guidelines.</strong> <a href="https://saagarjha.com/blog/2020/11/08/fixing-section-2-5-2/">Saagar has written</a> a more detailed analysis of why we believe this rejection is incorrect, how we believe Apple has misinterpreted and misapplied this rule to our app, and describe how 2.5.2’s poor wording coupled with the review team being unable to review functionality of scripting applications leads to mistaken classifications like these. At a high level, Apple has selectively targeted iSH using section 2.5.2 without fullying understanding our application, their own guidelines, or the consequences of what they are asking and how they affect the App Store ecosystem as a whole. <strong>Consistent enforcement of Apple’s incorrect interpretation would require the removal of all scripting apps, including many of the most popular applications in the App Store and some of Apple’s own applications.</strong></p>

<h2 id="what-have-we-done-to-get-ish-back-on-the-app-store">What have we done to get iSH back on the App Store?</h2>
<p>We’ve been working for the last two weeks to try to keep iSH available without interruptions. We have drafted numerous appeals, requests for clarifications, rule modifications, and explanatory emails. We’ve been on the phone with Apple for hours. Unfortunately, even with this we have been unable to resolve the issue, and the process has been significantly more stressful than we would have liked it to be. Theodore, the primary iSH liaison to Apple, <a href="https://tbodt.com/2020/11/08/app-review-experiences.html">has written about</a> how this process should be improved.</p>

<p>Our first interaction with the App Store review team actually dates back to May, not October: we wanted to know what Apple thought of iSH, since we weren’t sure how the rules would be enforced for it. Of course, iSH complies with the letter of the guidelines, but review found it to violate 2.5.2 because it could download Linux executable code. The problem appeared that apk lets you install packages, so we decided to remove it and work on other features to make the app more useful in its absence. We submitted this updated build in October and this was what is currently on the App Store.</p>

<p>After our build was flagged for noncompliance, we went through the usual review process: we first asked for clarification, and then after we realized that the rule was being misapplied we submitted a rule change request and of course appealed the decision as well. As the deadline approached we sent off an email to Phil Schiller as well detailing our situation. Unfortunately none of this led anywhere, which brings up to our current situation today.</p>

<h2 id="does-this-mean-i-cant-use-ish-anymore">Does this mean I can’t use iSH anymore?</h2>
<p>No, not at all. However, it will mean that you will no longer be able to get iSH from the App Store, which is something which we would still like to be able to provide. The App Store remains the easiest and most popular method of software distribution on iOS, and we’re working hard to save iSH’s listing because we think the app should have a permanent spot there for users who prefer this method of distribution.</p>

<p>Removal of iSH’s listing on the App Store should not affect your use of iSH if you download the app before it is removed. We have not received any compliance messages from Apple regarding <a href="https://testflight.apple.com/join/97i7KM8O">our TestFlight beta</a>, so we plan to continue offering prerelease versions of iSH there for up to 10,000 beta testers.</p>

<p>Precompiled builds of iSH (distributed as IPA files) will <a href="https://github.com/ish-app/ish/releases">remain available on GitHub</a> for <a href="https://ish.app/altstore">installation through AltStore</a> and for jailbroken users. Advanced users are welcome to <a href="https://github.com/ish-app/ish#build-for-ios">build iSH</a> themselves—it’s free and open source and always will be!</p>

<p><strong><span>Update</span>: <a href="https://twitter.com/a_Shell_iOS/status/1325526061099196416">a-Shell has mentioned</a> that they have received a similar rejection notice. Apple may be running extra review for scripting apps.</strong></p>

        <hr>
        <p><a href="https://ish.app/">Return home</a> | 2020-11-08</p>
    

</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ish.app/app-store-removal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25028252</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 19:33:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We Pay for Software]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 19 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25027907">thread link</a>) | @aberoham
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/pay | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/pay">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
    <h3>how we pay for software</h3>

    <p>Quality software costs money to make.</p>

    <p>The tech industry has backed itself into a corner in the last couple decades by implying to users that software doesn’t cost much. Google led the charge here, by providing a series of useful and well-made applications like Gmail, Google Maps, and its core search product for free. They aren’t free, of course: users ”pay“ with their attention and personal data for advertisements.</p>

    <p>Paying with attention and personal data is probably a good trade for search and maps, maybe less so for email. But it’s not a model that fits professional and creative tools.</p>

    <p>Here are three proven models for paying for software:</p>

    <ul>
      <li><p><strong>Ad-supported software.</strong> Only really appropriate for pure-consumer products that are attention-oriented to begin with (e.g. social media). Requires huge scale since <a href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-Twitters-ARPU-average-revenue-per-user">each user is only worth a few bucks</a>. Because the user is the product rather than the customer, the user’s needs are not the priority of the business.</p></li>
      <li><p><strong>Software bundled with hardware or content.</strong> End users seem to be fine with paying directly for hardware (smartphone, laptop) or content (Netflix, Spotify). In these examples the software is a huge part of what you’re paying for—a Mac without macOS is just an overpriced PC, and Netflix without its excellent browsing and playback software is just cloud storage media stocked with MP4 files. Yet few people think of themselves as paying for macOS or Netflix’s app.</p></li>
    </ul>

    <figure>
      <img src="https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/spotify-pricing.png" alt="pricing page for Spotify">

      <figcaption>
        <svg width="50" height="10" viewBox="0 0 50 10" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
          <rect width="50" height="10" rx="2.5" fill="#298070"></rect>
        </svg>

        <p><a href="https://www.spotify.com/us/premium/">Spotify’s pricing</a> demonstrates the common price range for individually-purchased subscriptions: $5/month on the low end, $15/month on the high end.</p>
      </figcaption>
    </figure>

    <ul>
      <li><p><strong>B2B SaaS.</strong> ”Business-to-business software-as-a-service“ is a mouthful, but represents a a beautiful, pure, and simple payment model for software. A business has a problem; a software creator offers a web-based product that solves the problem; the business purchases directly from the creator, and continues to pay as long as they have the problem and the product is good. Interests are aligned, and the no-middleman nature of the web means software creators have a direct relationship with their customers. Everybody wins. That’s why there’s so many success stories here: Slack, GitHub, Mailchimp, Atlassian, Zoom, Notion, and Carta just to name a few.</p></li>
    </ul>

    <p>I seek a world with a great diversity of lovingly-crafted software for niche audiences. But niche is not possible with ad-supported which requires huge scale to work, and hardware and content licensing have massive up-front capital costs that imply financing models not compatible with small-scale.</p>

    <p>Happily, B2B SaaS is having its <a href="https://microconf.com/">revolution for small independents</a> right now. So what’s the equivalent of that for pro creator tools like <a href="http://www.telestream.net/screenflow/overview.htm">video editing</a> or <a href="https://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener/overview">writing</a> or <a href="https://www.devontechnologies.com/apps/devonthink">knowledge management</a>? Can we have something as beautiful and pure as B2B SaaS but for individuals as well as businesses, and for desktop, mobile, and other native apps?</p>

    <p>And indeed there does seem to be movement toward subscription-priced prosumer products in the $5 –&nbsp;$15/month range. See
      established players like
      <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/individual/plans-comparison">Dropbox</a>,
      <a href="https://evernote.com/compare-plans">Evernote</a>,
      <a href="https://ulysses.app/get/">Ulysses</a> and
      <a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus/buy/">OmniFocus</a>;
      plus up-and-comers like
      <a href="https://hey.com/pricing/">HEY</a>,
      <a href="https://roamresearch.com/">Roam</a>,
      <a href="https://www.descript.com/pricing">Descript</a>, and my own venture <a href="https://museapp.com/">Muse</a>.
    </p>

    <figure>
      <img src="https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/calendly-pricing.png" alt="pricing for Calendly">

      <figcaption>
        <svg width="50" height="10" viewBox="0 0 50 10" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
          <rect width="50" height="10" rx="2.5" fill="#298070"></rect>
        </svg>

        <p><a href="https://calendly.com/pages/pricing">Calendly’s pricing</a> is similar to other prosumer products.</p>
      </figcaption>
    </figure>

    <p>As a <strike>user</strike> customer, I like the idea of finding a few great tools that empower my work and paying for them directly. That gives me confidence the product will serve my needs long-term, because I’m the customer.</p>

    <p>And this doesn’t mean a bigger budget for my tech product purchases overall: I can subtract these subscriptions from the money I previously spent on a new phone and laptop every two years, then buy new hardware a little less often. Right now I think great software is more important than hardware advances, much as I love shiny new devices.</p>

    <p>As a software creator, I love the idea of serving a niche of customers who are deeply connected with the product I’m making and get lots of value from it. It has that pure, direct, and personal relationship we see in B2B SaaS, but maybe even more initimate because these are personal tools.</p>

    <p>Ok sounds good—but now the next problem with a direct-payment model. If we’re going to make software subscriptions work, we as creators have to address the sharp edges and <a href="https://www.matthewball.vc/all/misnomers">subscription fatigue</a> people may experience maintaining a stack of software subscriptions.</p>

    <p>Individuals are cautious about recurring billing due to poorly-designed—even <a href="https://help.nytimes.com/hc/en-us/articles/360003499613-Cancel-your-subscription">borderline scammy</a>—subscription buying, renewal, and canceling experiences. The reference worst-case scenario are gym memberships or mobile phone contracts: being trapped in a recurring payment that no longer fits your needs, and being forced to navigate a customer service maze to try to downgrade or cancel.</p>

    <p>So how can we give customers a great experience with subscriptions? A few proposals:</p>

    <ul>
      <li><p>Treat the <strong>buying experience as part of your product</strong>. Make it easy for prospective customers to see what they will get; making buying easy and fun; show them love afterward, not just a ”you’re all set“ dialog and nothing else.</p></li>
    </ul>

    <figure>
      <img src="https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/gumroad-pay.png" alt="paying for a product on Gumroad">

      <figcaption>
        <svg width="50" height="10" viewBox="0 0 50 10" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
          <rect width="50" height="10" rx="2.5" fill="#298070"></rect>
        </svg>

        <p><a href="https://gumroad.com/">Gumroad</a> offers <a href="https://gumroad.com/l/NlhpD">a great buying experience</a> with a minimum of fuss.</p>
      </figcaption>
    </figure>

    <ul>
      <li><p>Make it <strong>easy to cancel</strong> at any moment. Canceling should be as smooth as purchasing initially. For bonus points, give a refund for any unused portion of purchased time.</p></li>
      <li><p>For longer-cycle payments (e.g. annual), give <strong>heads-up notifications before payment</strong> so that users are not surprised. Direct them on how they can cancel with just a couple of clicks. You shouldn’t want any money from someone who is no longer getting value from your product.</p></li>
    </ul>

    <figure>
      <img src="https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/hey-cancel.png" alt="canceling your subscription on HEY">

      <figcaption>
        <svg width="50" height="10" viewBox="0 0 50 10" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
          <rect width="50" height="10" rx="2.5" fill="#298070"></rect>
        </svg>

        <p>HEY makes canceling easy: just two clicks. The confirmation dialog is clear on exactly what happens next.</p>
      </figcaption>
    </figure>

    <ul>
     <li><p>Don’t lock users out of their data, even if their trial runs out or their subscription ends. Make it easy to <strong>get at their data and export</strong> for use in other places.</p></li>
      <li><p>Don’t treat lapsed or canceled subscriptions as strangers or defectors. Instead, <strong>consider them alumni and offer them your respect</strong> and maybe even some extra perks. They’ve been customers in the past, so be thankful for that. Remember they might return as a customer in the future or refer other potential customers.</p></li>
    </ul>

    <figure>
      <img src="https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/slack-credit.png" alt="a credit for inactive users on Slack">

      <figcaption>
        <svg width="50" height="10" viewBox="0 0 50 10" fill="none" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg">
          <rect width="50" height="10" rx="2.5" fill="#298070"></rect>
        </svg>

        <p>Slack delights and surprises with their <a href="https://slack.com/intl/en-de/help/articles/218915077-Fair-Billing-Policy">fair billing policy</a>.</p>
      </figcaption>
    </figure>

    <p>Beyond prosumer subscriptions, I’m happy to see products experimenting with models appropriate to their domain, like the ski app <a href="https://twitter.com/parrots/status/1314192830500347906">Slopes offering</a> packs of day passes; time-based notes app <a href="https://medium.com/@drewmccormack/cash-cow-revisited-4c2185e2b3d8">Agenda</a> with feature unlock based on subscription time windows; and <a href="https://www.komoot.com/product">Komoot</a> with hiking region budles for sale.</p>

    <p>One last one I find especially promising is the half-crowdfunding, half-early-purchase model that’s seen success with <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/earlyaccessfaq/?snr=1_200_200_Early+Access">video games</a>, <a href="https://www.studiobinder.com/blog/kickstarter-film-projects/">films</a>, and <a href="https://www.futurefonts.xyz/about">typefaces</a>. This blurs the distinctions between customer, investor, and donor. When you buy a Steam Early Access game you’re saying not just ”I want to purchase this product“ but also ”I believe in this product and the team behind it; I want it to exist; and I’m willing to risk a bit of my money to make that happen.“ And maybe: ”I like getting to give early feedback and influence the outcome of the finished product.“ <a href="https://wikimediafoundation.org/support/">Wikipedia with its pure patronage model</a> and <a href="https://www.are.na/roadmap">Are.na with its earnings transparency</a> are variations on this theme.</p>

    <p><strong>The world we have:</strong> Almost all software is paid for by (1) ads and selling personal data (2) bundling software with hardware or content or (3) business-purchased subscriptions. As a result, the type of software we have is limited to what will fit in those boxes.</p>

    <p><strong>The world I want:</strong> A wide diversity of funding and payment models for pure software products. Prosumer subscriptions are commonplace; users feel great about buying tools that matter to them; and they get a great experience when buying and canceling. Crowdfunding, patronage, and many other models flourish and individual products can choose the model that best fits them and their customers.</p>
  </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://adamwiggins.com/making-computers-better/pay</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25027907</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 18:51:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[It’s OK to Not Care About Politics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25027906">thread link</a>) | @freediver
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://www.meta-nomad.net/its-ok-to-not-care-about-politics/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.meta-nomad.net/its-ok-to-not-care-about-politics/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1182">

	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	<div>

		<p><span>During recent research into the life of Machiavelli something began to become quite clear to me. We weren’t always, universally, socially, communally or even personally, political. That is to say, it’s only recently that it’s become commonplace to declare oneself as left, right, Republican, Democrat, Labour, Conservative, Centrist, Reactionary, Socialist, Red, Blue, x-pilled, y-pilled etc. In terms of human history this way of </span><span><em><span>being</span></em></span><span> – as a political-being, or even as homo-politicus – is </span><span><em><span>extremely</span></em></span><span> new. The very idea of a left/right split/spectrum comes from where people sat during the French Revolution, when members of the National Assembly divided themselves into those in support of the king (right) and supporters of the Revolution (left). Arguably this is one and only time that the idea of a left/right spectrum has ever made sense. Since then </span><span><em><span>both</span></em></span><span> ‘directions’ signal virtue to various camps and striate one into relatively specific ways of thinking. The year we’re roughly talking about here is 1789, that’s round that all up and say – for clarity’s sake – we’ve been political ‘beings’ for just over 200 years. Once again, humans in their current evolutionary iteration have been around for 200,000 years. So we’ve had this political chip on our shoulders for roughly 0.1% of our entire lifetime. Of course, you could argue that for a large amount of that time we haven’t exactly had the infrastructure to allow for what we now commonly understand as politics or political economy, but we </span><span><em><span>have</span></em></span><span> had that for a few thousand years at least, so even going by that metric, the notion of a political-being or of a political-human is still quite new. </span></p>
<p><span>It seems to me the reason for the original (non) position, wherein man wasn’t apolitical, nor anti-political, but simply detached from the political, wasn’t due to some oppression (though some would argue otherwise)[1], nor was it really to do with any ignorance; it was largely because in relation to man’s daily life, the specific political on-goings didn’t matter to him. I would argue that this is still true, we’re just all caught up in status and popularity games. </span></p>
<p><span>The very idea that within contemporary (Western) society one could be ‘detached’ from politics seems absurd, that’s how tight of a grasp it has on our lives. A grasp which is ever-tightened by the popular rhetoric surrounding politics. Society in general seems to unconsciously believe that they now have some kind of duty to </span><span><em><span>be</span></em></span><span> political, they must be in a certain camp, they must have certain opinions on various matters, and most of all, they must </span><span><em><span>care</span></em></span><span> in a specifically political way. I’m here to say that this way of thinking and being is complete bullshit, and it slowly leads one to misery and submission. There are a lot of factors as to why someone might feel compelled to constantly </span><span><em><span>be</span></em></span><span> political, largely emanating from one’s perpetual attachment to media. The two most heinous forms of media are – of course – social and mainstream. Primarily because, once you actually begin to think about what these terms actually mean, like most things in modernity, they no longer make any sense whatsoever. Let’s begin with ‘social media’.</span></p>
<p><span>We all apparently ‘know’ what social media is, which is another way of saying we understand it. I’ll admit, I don’t really understand social media, and I never have. The basic reasons as to why it’s so popular are of course clear, on average humans quite like attention, they quite like having a say and they quite like boasting about their lives. However, I would ask this? If it wasn’t </span><span><em><span>for</span></em></span><span> social media, and its invasive societally pressuring structures, would you actually </span><span><em><span>want</span></em></span><span> to express certain opinions? Would you even have them? Would you have even thought about them? Maybe you would, maybe you wouldn’t, be honest with yourself. If no one was looking, and you had no proof anyone </span><span><em><span>had</span></em></span><span> looked, would you expend energy on the various political and social tasks you do? Ok, so this then begs the question, why the hell </span><span><em><span>do</span></em></span><span> we want to express these opinions? Well, for that you need a mainstream current which tells you the correct, conventional and confirmative way to </span><span><em><span>be.</span></em></span><span> Enter the mainstream media. Such an idea of a ‘mainstream’ is already idiotic. There can’t be such a thing because we all live in different areas of the world, within different cultures, within different families, with different values, within different contexts, and so, the job the mainstream media then is to subsume all of these alternative ways of being and differing value systems into one relatively homogenous lump, which is then there’s to mold as they wish. I’d insert here Ted Kaczynski’s ‘critique’ of ‘multiculturalism’, though it’s less a critique and more of a deconstruction. Kaczynski’s point is that there isn’t really any such thing as ‘multiculturalism’ as it’s sold to us. The overt idea is that multiple diverse cultures live amongst one another, learn from each other and share their cultures for the betterment of all. Kaczynski makes it clear that this is </span><span><em><span>not</span></em></span><span> what happens within contemporary multiculturalism, all that really happens is that every culture is subsumed into the exact same culture of middle-class consumerist aspiration, and perhaps allowed to retain any cultural aesthetic which might be deemed profitable by their new culture of consumerist aspiration. The exact same thing happens with mainstream media. One begins with a variety of views, opinions, values, outlooks, perspectives and contexts which have been grown organically, from their local surroundings and upbringing, these are then pushed through the conformity thresher of mainstream media, cherry-picked for their applicability for submission, and what’s left are deemed dangerous, archaic, bad, fascist, radical, silly, absurd, weird, not-normal, odd or perhaps just too common-sensical for them to remain.</span></p>
<p><span>Now, the </span><span><em><span>exact</span></em></span><span> same process happens with the idea of a ‘political-human’ with a few minor alterations. Much like homo-criminalis, or homo-economicus, once the suffix is assumed </span><span><em><span>a priori</span></em></span><span> as a </span><span><em><span>way</span></em></span><span> of being – man </span><span><em><span>can</span></em></span><span> be a criminal, or man </span><span><em><span>can</span></em></span><span> be economical. There’s no longer such a thing as a man detached entirely from criminality or the economy, there is only a man who is </span><span><em><span>not</span></em></span><span> a criminal, or a man who acts within the economy in a </span><span><em><span>different</span></em></span><span> way than what is preferred. The exact same thing happens with political man. Once a political-outlook, a political-perspective or a political-reality is assumed as the given reality, everything is then filtered through politics in some manner. Then there is no longer such a thing as a entirely unpolitical man, only a man who is deemed ignorant of politics, someone who is seen as turning a blind eye or as simply too lazy to investigate that which they </span><span><em><span>should</span></em></span><span> be. The language here is the problem. Foucault makes this point clear with homo-criminalis and homo-economicus, once the ontology is taken as a given, no one is </span><span><em><span>not</span></em></span><span> of it, but simply seen as not part of a certain section of it. Men are not men, they are either criminals or </span><span><em><span>not-</span></em></span><span>criminals, we are not ourselves we are either economizing or </span><span><em><span>not-</span></em></span><span>economizing, either way, we’re still tethered to a way of being we had no say in.</span></p>
<p><span>Well I’m here to say that this is complete and utter crap. If you want to go get involved in politics, then be my guest, but do NOT assume that just because I don’t care about a certain topic, opinion or perspective that I am immediately the antagonist of that position. There is a difference between a hostile apathy, in which one truly doesn’t care about the plight of others and a detachment within one simply is not involved. Of course, any </span><span><em><span>involved</span></em></span><span> are going to disagree. ‘It’s your duty!’ they will cry. ‘Do you not care about the world!’ they will shriek. ‘How can you just do nothing?’ they will plead. Actually, I am doing something, I’m not expending my energy on a status game which largely exists to inflate various egos and create jobs. Lest we forget that politicians are </span><span><em><span>workers</span></em></span><span>, to be a politician is a </span><span><em><span>job</span></em></span><span>, and by the looks of it, quite a cushy one at that. </span></p>
<p><span>Being </span><span><em><span>detached</span></em></span><span> from politics isn’t </span><span><em><span>not caring</span></em></span><span> about those things you left behind, in fact, it’s arguably the opposite. As soon as a charitable organization, a communal effort or a group event becomes politicized, I am instantly skeptical of its agenda, why? Well, because since when did helping others, loving thy neighbor or creating something helpful </span><span><em><span>have</span></em></span><span> to be seen through a political lens. Call me a soppy-sod, but buying a homeless person some food, donating to a local charity or helping out in a local event isn’t – and doesn’t have to be – a specifically political move or motivation, and if it is, you’re doing so to cater to your own narcissism. What </span><span><em><span>are</span></em></span><span> these acts then? Well, they are what they are. You help someone because they need help, you do something because it needs doing, you create because something needs creating; once sincere acts are filtered through the malicious gauze of politics they are usually lost entirely, abused into a self-congratulatory mutation. </span></p>
<p><span>Ok, maybe you’re with me, but you’re starting to think…’Ok, so what do I…</span><span><em><span>do?</span></em></span><span>‘ Isn’t that the point? Up until now, for many people, each and every act they undertook was done primarily from a political position as opposed to the multitude of other (healthier) perspectives that exist. What do you do? Do what you’d like and what you understand to be right. </span></p>
<p><span>“Ah yes Meta, but if we ‘do nothing’ as you propose, wont we be simply bolstering support for whichever party is in the running to win?” You’re still thinking politically, why does it </span><span><em><span>actually</span></em></span><span> matter to you? If I support X I’ve entered into a system which is so unfathomably corrupt, confused and rife with personality that I will never </span><span><em><span>truly</span></em></span><span> know what it is my vote is doing. It is NOT an apathy, an ignorance or a superiority. It is a detachment. It is one unclipping themselves from a perspective they never asked for in the first place. The years upon years spent drooling …</span></p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.meta-nomad.net/its-ok-to-not-care-about-politics/">https://www.meta-nomad.net/its-ok-to-not-care-about-politics/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.meta-nomad.net/its-ok-to-not-care-about-politics/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25027906</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 18:51:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[When “Progress” Is Backwards]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 19 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25027462">thread link</a>) | @pmarin
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://sabotage-linux.github.io/blog/8 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sabotage-linux.github.io/blog/8">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>When "progress" is backwards</h2>

<p>20 Oct 2020 15:58 UTC</p>
<p>Lately I see many developments in the linux FOSS world that sell themselves as progress, but are actually hugely annoying and counter-productive.</p>

<p>Counter-productive to a point where they actually cause major regressions, costs, and as in the case of GTK+3 ruin user experience and the possibility that we'll ever enjoy "The year of the Linux desktop".</p>

<h2>Showcase 1: GTK+3</h2>

<p>GTK+2 used to be <em>the</em> GUI toolkit for Linux desktop applications.
It is highly customizable, reasonably lightweight and programmable from C, which means almost any scripting language can interface to it too.</p>

<p>Rather than improving the existing toolkit code in a backwards-compatible manner, <a href="https://www.freedesktop.org/">its developers</a> decided to introduce many breaking API changes which require a major porting effort to make an existing codebase compatible with the successor GTK+3, and keeping support for GTK+2 while supporting GTK+3 at the same time typically involves a lot of #ifdef clutter in the source base which not many developers are willing to maintain.</p>

<p>Additionally GTK+3 made away with a lot of user-customizable themeing options, effectively rendering useless most of the existing themes that took considerable developer effort for their creation.
Here's a <a href="https://ubuntu-mate.community/t/gtk3-regressions-from-a-gtk2-perspective/19511">list of issues</a> users are complaining about.</p>

<p>Due to the effort required to port a GTK+2 application to use GTK+3, many finished GUI application projects will never be ported due to lack of manpower, lost interest of the main developer or his untimely demise.
An example of such a program is the excellent audio editor <a href="http://www.metadecks.org/software/sweep/">sweep</a> which has seen its last release in 2008.
With Linux distros removing support for GTK+2, these apps are basically lost in the void of time.</p>

<p>The other option for distros is to keep both the (unmaintained) GTK+2 and GTK+3 in their repositories so GTK+2-only apps can still be used, however that causes the user of these apps to require basically the double amount of disk and RAM space as both toolkits need to live next to each other. Also this will only work as long as there are no breaking changes in the Glib library which both toolkits are built upon.</p>

<p>Even worse, due to the irritation the GTK+3 move caused to developers, many switched to QT4 or QT5, which requires use of C++, so a typical linux distro now has a mix of GTK+2, GTK+3, GTK+4, QT4 and QT5 applications, where each toolkit consumes considerable resources.</p>

<p>Microsoft (TM) knows better and sees backwards compatibility as the holy grail and underlying root cause of its success and market position. Any 25 year old Win32 GUI application from the Win95 era still works without issues on the latest Windows (TM) release. They even still support 16bit MS-DOS apps using some built-in emulator.</p>

<p>From MS' perspective, the freedesktop.org decision makers played into their hands when they decided to make GTK+3 a completely different beast.
Of course, we are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanlon%27s_razor">taught to never believe in malice but in stupidity</a>, so it is unthinkable that there was actually a real conspiracy and monetary compensations behind this move.
Otherwise we would be conspiracy theorist nuts, right ?</p>

<h2>Showcase 2: python3</h2>

<p>Python is a hugely successful programming/scripting language used by probably millions of programmers.</p>

<p>Whereas python2 development has been very stable for many years, python3 changes at the blink of an eye. It's not uncommon to find that after an update of python3 to the next release, existing code no longer works as expected.</p>

<p>Many developers such as myself prefer to use a stable development environment over one that is as volatile as python3.</p>

<p>With the decision to <a href="https://mail.python.org/archives/list/python-announce-list@python.org/thread/OFCIETIXLX34X7FVK5B5WPZH22HXV342/">EOL python2</a> thousands of py2-based applications will experience the same fate as GTK+2 applications without maintainer: they will be rendered obsolete and disappear from the distro repositories. This may happen quicker than one would expect, as python by default provides bindings to the system's OpenSSL library, which has a history of making backwards-incompatible changes. At the very least, once the web agrees on a new TLS standard, python2 will be rendered completely useless.</p>

<p>Porting python2 to python3 isn't usually as involving as GTK+2 to GTK+3, but due to the dynamic nature of python the syntax checker can't catch all code issues automatically so many issues will be experienced at runtime in cornercases, causing the ported application to throw a backtrace and stopping execution, which can have grave consequences.</p>

<p>Many companies have <a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/jpmorgans-athena-has-35-million-lines-of-python-code-and-wont-be-updated-to-python-3-in-time/">millions of line of code still in python2</a> and will have to produce quite some sweat and expenses to make it compatible to python3.</p>

<h2>Showcase 3: ip vs ifconfig</h2>

<p>Once one had learned his handful of ifconfig and route commands to configure a Linux' box network connections, one could comfortably manage this aspect across all distros. Not any longer, someone had the glorious idea to declare ifconfig and friends obsolete and provide a new, more "powerful" tool to do its job: <code>ip</code>.</p>

<p>The command for bringing up a network device is now <code>ip link set dev eth1 up</code> vs the older <code>ifconfig eth1 up</code>. Does this really look like progress?
Worst, the documentation of the tool is non-intuitive so one basically has to google for examples that show the translation from one command to the other.</p>

<p>The same critics apply to <code>iw</code> vs <code>iwconfig</code>.</p>

<h2>Showcase 4: ethernet adapter renaming by systemd/udev</h2>

<p>Latest systemd-based distros come up with network interface names such as <code>enx78e7d1ea46da</code> or <code>vethb817d6a</code>, instead of the traditional <code>eth0</code>.
The interface names assigned by default on Ubuntu 20 are so long a regular human can't even remember them, any configuration attempt requires one to copy/paste the name from <code>ip a</code> output.
Yet almost every distro goes along with this <a href="https://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/systemd/PredictableNetworkInterfaceNames/">Poettering/freedesktop.org-dictated</a> nonsense.</p>

<h2>Showcase 5: CMake, meson, and $BUILDSYSTEMOFTHEDAY</h2>

<p>While the traditional buildsystem used on UNIX, <code>autoconf</code>, has its warts, it was designed in such a way that only the application developer required the full set of tools, whereas the consumer requires only a POSIX compatible shell environment and a <code>make</code> program.</p>

<p>More "modern" build systems like <code>cmake</code> and <code>meson</code> don't give a damn about the dependencies a user has to install, in fact according to <a href="https://kevstras.com/programming/2017/12/18/meson.html">this</a>, <code>meson</code> authors claimed it to be one of their goals to force users to have a bleeding edge version of python3 installed so it can be universally assumed as a given.</p>

<p><code>CMake</code> is written in C++, consists of 70+ MB of extracted sources and requires an impressive amount of time to build from source. Built with debug information, it takes up 434 MB of my harddisk space as of version 3.9.3.
It's primary raison-d'etre is its support for the Microsoft (TM) Visual Studio (R) (TM) solution files, so Windows (TM) people can compile stuff from source with a few clicks.</p>

<p>The two of them have in common that they threw over board the well-known user interface to configure and make and invented their own NIH solution, which requires the user to learn yet another way to build his applications.</p>

<p>Both of these build systems seem to have either acquired a cult following just like systemd, or someone is paying trolls to show up on github with pull requests to replace GNU autoconf with either of those, for example <a href="https://github.com/containers/crun/issues/495">1</a> <a href="https://github.com/karelzak/util-linux/pull/968">2</a> .
Interestingly also, GNOME, which is tightly connected to freedesktop.org, has made it one of its goals to <a href="https://wiki.gnome.org/Initiatives/GnomeGoals/MesonPorting">switch all components to meson</a>.
Their porting effort involves almost every key component in the Linux desktop stack, including cairo, pango, fontconfig, freetype, and dozens of others. What might be the agenda behind this effort?</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>We live in an era where in the FOSS world one constantly has to relearn things, switch to new, supposedly "better", but more bloated solutions, and is generally left with the impression that someone is pulling the rug from below one's feet.
Many of the key changes in this area have been rammed through by a small set of decision makers, often closely related to Red Hat/Gnome/freedesktop.org.
We're buying this "progress" at a high cost, and one can't avoid asking oneself whether there's more to the story than meets the eye.
Never forget, Red Hat and Microsoft (TM) are <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/partners/microsoft">partners</a> and might even have the same shareholders.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sabotage-linux.github.io/blog/8</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25027462</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 18:02:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How active noise cancellation for automotive works]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 65 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026841">thread link</a>) | @giuliomagnifico
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://www.silentium.com/advanced-broad-band-active-noise-cancellation-now-available-in-cars/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.silentium.com/advanced-broad-band-active-noise-cancellation-now-available-in-cars/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
				<div id="mk-page-id-6588">
					<div itemprop="mainEntityOfPage">
							
	<article id="6588" itemscope="itemscope" itemprop="blogPost" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

	<div><p><a title="Advanced, broad-band active noise cancellation now available in cars" href="https://www.silentium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/silentium-anc-system.jpg">&nbsp;</a><img alt="Advanced, broad-band active noise cancellation now available in cars" title="Advanced, broad-band active noise cancellation now available in cars" src="https://www.silentium.com/wp-content/uploads/bfi_thumb/dummy-transparent-oj3yxgsoeorp9werpevcwqrlmj5p4y57n6vjhiqmq0.png" data-mk-image-src-set="{&quot;default&quot;:&quot;https://www.silentium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/silentium-anc-system.jpg&quot;,&quot;2x&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;mobile&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;responsive&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}" width="800" height="500" itemprop="image"></p></div>				
	





<div itemprop="mainEntityOfPage">
	<p>Silentium has introduced advanced, broad-band active road noise cancellation to the auto industry for the first time.</p>
<p>After several years in development, Jaguar and Land Rover are the first carmakers to integrate Silentium’s ‘Active Acoustics’ software in three of their new vehicles, meaning the technology is now available for car buyers to experience. Active road noise cancellation removes 90% of unwanted noise across a broad band of frequencies – from 20Hz up to 1kHz – providing a quieter and more refined experience for occupants, and therefore preventing driver fatigue.</p>
<p>In addition to wellbeing benefits, Silentium’s Active Acoustics technology offers vehicle manufacturers a way to reduce their reliance on costly passive noise damping and insulation materials, and reduce vehicle weight – an increasingly important R&amp;D factor as the industry enters a new era of electro-mobility.</p>
<p>Anthony Manias, Head of Automotive at Silentium, commented: “<em>Active Acoustics will change the way car manufacturers reduce, cancel and enhance sound inside their vehicles, and how customers perceive and interact with these sounds. Silentium has proven that it can make broadband in-car noise cancellation work – now the duty is on carmakers to adopt the technology and ensure their customers can enjoy the benefits.”</em></p>
<p><img src="https://www.silentium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/graphic-silentium1.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="756" srcset="https://www.silentium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/graphic-silentium1.jpg 1000w, https://www.silentium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/graphic-silentium1-300x227.jpg 300w, https://www.silentium.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/graphic-silentium1-768x581.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px"></p>
<p><strong>How active noise cancellation works</strong></p>
<p>Silentium’s industry-first technology is similar to that found in a pair of high-end noise-cancelling headphones, but more advanced as it manipulates a larger amount of air. Up to six strategically positioned accelerometers on a vehicle’s chassis monitor unwanted road noise and send a signal to an on-board control unit with Silentium’s software, which plays an equivalent anti-noise signal through the vehicle’s speaker system. The pressure waves from both the unwanted exterior noise and manufactured anti-noise reach occupants’ eardrums at exactly the same time and cancel each other out.</p>
<p>Silentium’s Active Acoustics software can reduce, cancel and enhance sound inside any vehicle, improving occupant comfort, safety and wellbeing, and creating a more enjoyable environment for all.</p>
<p><iframe title="Silentium Active Acoustics on road noise" width="1140" height="641" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5x9NEpfRZuc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><iframe title="Silentium Active Acoustics with road noise and music" width="1140" height="641" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uDzSkaWBD7E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
</div>



</article>

							
											</div>
										
				</div>
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.silentium.com/advanced-broad-band-active-noise-cancellation-now-available-in-cars/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026841</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 16:35:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Using Alfred to open your GitHub repositories in the browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026757">thread link</a>) | @mmazzarolo
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://mmazzarolo.com/blog/2020-09-28-alfred-github-repos/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mmazzarolo.com/blog/2020-09-28-alfred-github-repos/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>One thing I do multiple times a day is browsing my company’s GitHub organization repositories.<br>
My process for opening these repositories in the browser is:</p>
<ul>
<li>Open Chrome</li>
<li>Press <kbd>Command</kbd> + <kbd>L</kbd> to focus the address bar</li>
<li>Start typing the GitHub repository name</li>
<li>Look for the page suggestion and click on it</li>
</ul>
<p>This flow works well for repositories that I have starred as bookmarks or that I browsed recently…<br>
…But because I’m a total sucker for Alfred, today I wasted almost an hour moving this process into an Alfred workflow.</p>
<p><span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="alfred" title="alfred" src="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/f6b79b275f646159f864ae32c3d83508/fcda8/alfred.png" srcset="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/f6b79b275f646159f864ae32c3d83508/12f09/alfred.png 148w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/f6b79b275f646159f864ae32c3d83508/e4a3f/alfred.png 295w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/f6b79b275f646159f864ae32c3d83508/fcda8/alfred.png 590w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/f6b79b275f646159f864ae32c3d83508/efc66/alfred.png 885w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/f6b79b275f646159f864ae32c3d83508/c83ae/alfred.png 1180w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/f6b79b275f646159f864ae32c3d83508/7ef4c/alfred.png 1748w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></p>
<h2>The Action Plan</h2>
<p>Knowing that:</p>
<ul>
<li>The entire repository list is huge and doesn’t change often</li>
<li>I wanted the Alfred repository search result to be instant</li>
</ul>
<p>Making an API request to filter the repositories each time I invoke the Alfred workflow wasn’t an option.</p>
<p>So I decided to 1) download the entire repository list into a JSON file, 2) transform it into an Alred-compatible format, and 3) use the <a href="https://github.com/deanishe/alfred-fuzzy" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Alfred’s fuzzy search helper</a> to filter the results.</p>
<h2>Creating the GitHub repository list</h2>
<p>First of all, I <a href="https://github.com/settings/tokens/new" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">created a GitHub API token with a scope to access the repositories list</a>.</p>
<p><span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="github repo access" title="github repo access" src="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5debf06855fa8eef2379c163d8d95943/fcda8/github-repo-access.png" srcset="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5debf06855fa8eef2379c163d8d95943/12f09/github-repo-access.png 148w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5debf06855fa8eef2379c163d8d95943/e4a3f/github-repo-access.png 295w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5debf06855fa8eef2379c163d8d95943/fcda8/github-repo-access.png 590w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5debf06855fa8eef2379c163d8d95943/efc66/github-repo-access.png 885w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5debf06855fa8eef2379c163d8d95943/69476/github-repo-access.png 926w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p>TIL: Selecting all the “repo” sub-scopes is not the same as selecting the entire scope — which is needed to use the API token to get the list of all the private repositories.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The GitHub API pagination has a limit of 200 items per page. I needed to fetch way more than 200 repositories, so I modified <a href="https://gist.github.com/mbohun/b161521b2440b9f08b59" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">this cool (but outdated) bash script</a> to fetch all of them in a single command and print them out to the console:</p>
<div data-language="bash"><pre><code><span>#!/bin/bash</span>

<span>if</span> <span>[</span> <span>${<span>#</span>@}</span> -lt <span>2</span> <span>]</span><span>;</span> <span>then</span>
    <span>echo</span> <span>"usage: <span>$0</span> [your github credentials as 'user:token'] [REST expression]"</span>
    <span>exit</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
<span>fi</span>

<span>GITHUB_CREDENTIALS</span><span>=</span><span>$1</span>
<span>GITHUB_API_REST</span><span>=</span><span>$2</span>

<span>GITHUB_API_HEADER_ACCEPT</span><span>=</span><span>"Accept: application/vnd.github.v3+json"</span>

<span>temp</span><span>=</span><span><span>`</span><span>basename</span> $0<span>`</span></span>
<span>TMPFILE</span><span>=</span><span><span>`</span>mktemp /tmp/$<span>{</span>temp<span>}</span>.XXXXXX<span>`</span></span> <span>||</span> <span>exit</span> <span>1</span>

<span>function</span> <span>rest_call</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>curl</span> -s -u <span>$GITHUB_CREDENTIALS</span> <span>$1</span> -H <span>"<span>${GITHUB_API_HEADER_ACCEPT}</span>"</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> <span>$TMPFILE</span>
<span>}</span>


<span>last_page</span><span>=</span><span><span>`</span><span>curl</span> -s -I -u $GITHUB_CREDENTIALS <span>"https://api.github.com<span>${GITHUB_API_REST}</span>?per_page=200"</span> -H <span>"<span>${GITHUB_API_HEADER_ACCEPT}</span>"</span> <span>|</span> <span>grep</span> <span>'^Link:'</span> <span>|</span> <span>sed</span> -e <span>'s/^Link:.*page=//g'</span> -e <span>'s/&gt;.*$//g'</span><span>`</span></span>


<span>if</span> <span>[</span> -z <span>"<span>$last_page</span>"</span> <span>]</span><span>;</span> <span>then</span>
    
    rest_call <span>"https://api.github.com<span>${GITHUB_API_REST}</span>?per_page=200"</span>
<span>else</span>
    
    <span>for</span> <span>p</span> <span>in</span> <span><span>`</span><span>seq</span> <span>1</span> $last_page<span>`</span></span><span>;</span> <span>do</span>
        rest_call <span>"https://api.github.com<span>${GITHUB_API_REST}</span>?per_page=200&amp;page=<span>$p</span>"</span>
    <span>done</span>
<span>fi</span>

<span>cat</span> <span>$TMPFILE</span></code></pre></div>
<p>I named the script <code>githubapi-get.sh</code> and used it this way:</p>
<div data-language="bash"><pre><code>
githubapi-get.sh <span>"{USERNAME}:{TOKEN}"</span> <span>"/orgs/{ORGANIZATION}/repos"</span> <span>&gt;</span> ~/my-company-repos.txt</code></pre></div>
<p>FYI, you can also run it this way to get all the repositories you have access to (both on your personal account and on other organization accounts):</p>
<div data-language="bash"><pre><code>
githubapi-get.sh <span>"{USERNAME}:{TOKEN}"</span> <span>"/user/repos"</span> <span>&gt;</span> ~/my-github-repos.txt</code></pre></div>
<h2>Making the repository list compatible with Alfred</h2>
<p>To populate the Alfred list filter, for each repo I extracted the following information:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>uid</code>: Unique identifier for the item which allows Alfred to learn about this item for subsequent sorting and ordering of the user’s actioned results. I used the repository ID (<code>id</code>).</li>
<li><code>arg</code>: The argument which is passed through the workflow to open it in the browser. I used the repository URL (<code>html_url</code>).</li>
<li><code>title</code>: The title displayed in the result row. I used the repository name (<code>name</code>).</li>
<li><code>subtitle</code>: The subtitle displayed in the result row. I used the repository description (<code>description</code>).</li>
</ul>
<p>Using the following <code>jq</code> script:</p>
<div data-language="bash"><pre><code><span>cat</span> ~/my-company-repos.txt <span>|</span> jq -s <span>'.[] | map({ arg: .html_url, uid: .id, title: .name, subtitle: .description }) | { items: . }'</span> <span>&gt;</span> ~/my-company-repos.json</code></pre></div>
<p>The <code>jq</code> script generates a <code>~/my-company-repos.json</code> file compatible with the <a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/help/workflows/inputs/script-filter/json/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Alfred Script Filter JSON format</a>.</p>
<h2>Creating the Alfred workflow</h2>
<p>The Alfred standard script filtering doesn’t have a good fuzzy search option — which I really wanted given the huge amount of repositories.</p>
<p>As a workaround, I used <a href="https://github.com/deanishe/alfred-fuzzy" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">alfred-fuzzy</a>, a Python helper script for Alfred that replaces the “Alfred filters results” option with fuzzy search.</p>
<p>Here’s what I did, step by step:</p>
<ol>
<li>Create a new empty Alfred workflow</li>
<li>Right-click on the created workflow ⭢ “Open in Finder”</li>
<li>In the workflow directory, copy and paste both <a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/deanishe/alfred-fuzzy/master/fuzzy.py" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">fuzzy.py</a> and <code>my-company-repos.json</code>.</li>
<li>In the workflow, create the following “Script Filter”:
<span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="workflow 0" title="workflow 0" src="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/79ea20fa5f1577ca4cb07a0fd9329861/fcda8/workflow-0.png" srcset="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/79ea20fa5f1577ca4cb07a0fd9329861/12f09/workflow-0.png 148w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/79ea20fa5f1577ca4cb07a0fd9329861/e4a3f/workflow-0.png 295w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/79ea20fa5f1577ca4cb07a0fd9329861/fcda8/workflow-0.png 590w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/79ea20fa5f1577ca4cb07a0fd9329861/efc66/workflow-0.png 885w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/79ea20fa5f1577ca4cb07a0fd9329861/c83ae/workflow-0.png 1180w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/79ea20fa5f1577ca4cb07a0fd9329861/2b608/workflow-0.png 1540w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></li>
<li>In the workflow, create the following “Open URL” action:
<span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="workflow 1" title="workflow 1" src="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5f157cd5f9d5e2e8f928074cc6d37708/fcda8/workflow-1.png" srcset="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5f157cd5f9d5e2e8f928074cc6d37708/12f09/workflow-1.png 148w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5f157cd5f9d5e2e8f928074cc6d37708/e4a3f/workflow-1.png 295w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5f157cd5f9d5e2e8f928074cc6d37708/fcda8/workflow-1.png 590w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5f157cd5f9d5e2e8f928074cc6d37708/efc66/workflow-1.png 885w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5f157cd5f9d5e2e8f928074cc6d37708/c83ae/workflow-1.png 1180w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/5f157cd5f9d5e2e8f928074cc6d37708/7960f/workflow-1.png 1274w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></li>
<li>In the workflow, connect the “Script Filter” to the “Open URL” action:
<span>
      <span></span>
  <img alt="workflow 2" title="workflow 2" src="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/ca9a91ea4b4aed993050fc92f0780f4d/fcda8/workflow-2.png" srcset="https://mmazzarolo.com/static/ca9a91ea4b4aed993050fc92f0780f4d/12f09/workflow-2.png 148w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/ca9a91ea4b4aed993050fc92f0780f4d/e4a3f/workflow-2.png 295w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/ca9a91ea4b4aed993050fc92f0780f4d/fcda8/workflow-2.png 590w,
https://mmazzarolo.com/static/ca9a91ea4b4aed993050fc92f0780f4d/8ae3e/workflow-2.png 756w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
    </span></li>
</ol>
<p>That’s it.
I can now invoke the workflow using the keyword set in the “Script Filter” action and fuzzy search the repo I’m interested in.</p>
<p>Alfred is also smart enough to keep track of my workflow usage, surfacing the most clicked results to the top of the list 💥</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Yes, the workflow can be improved in several ways (e.g.: auto-update the repository list after n days)… but I’m happy enough with the current result for now.</p>
</blockquote></section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mmazzarolo.com/blog/2020-09-28-alfred-github-repos/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026757</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 16:24:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I made a website to guess tomorrow’s Covid-19 case count]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 22 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026666">thread link</a>) | @nathell
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | http://blog.danieljanus.pl/2020/11/08/coronalotto/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://blog.danieljanus.pl/2020/11/08/coronalotto/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Before</h2><p>It seems so obvious in hindsight. Here in Poland, people have been guessing it ever since the pandemic breakout: in private conversations, in random threads on social media, in comments under governmental information outlets. It seemed a&nbsp;matter of time before someone came up with something like this. In fact, on one Sunday evening in October, I&nbsp;found myself flabbergasted that apparently no one yet has.</p><p>I&nbsp;doled out $4 for a&nbsp;domain, <a href="http://koronalotek.pl/">koronalotek.pl</a> (can be translated as “coronalotto” or “coronalottery” – occurrences of the name on Twitter date back at least as far as April), and fired up a&nbsp;REPL. A&nbsp;few hours and 250 Clojure LOCs later, the site was up.</p><p>I&nbsp;wanted it to&nbsp;be as simple as possible. A&nbsp;form with two fields: “your name” and “how many cases tomorrow?” A&nbsp;top-ten list of today’s winners, sorted by the absolute difference between the guess and the actual number of cases, as <a href="https://twitter.com/mz_gov_pl">reported daily on Twitter</a> by the Polish Ministry of Health. The official number, prominently displayed. And that’s all.</p><p><img src="http://blog.danieljanus.pl/img/blog/koronalotek.png"></p><p>On 17 October, I&nbsp;posted the link on my Facebook and Twitter feeds, and waited. The stream of guesses started to&nbsp;trickle in.</p><h2>After</h2><p>It never grew to&nbsp;be more than a&nbsp;stream, but it hasn’t gone completely unnoticed either.</p><p><img src="http://blog.danieljanus.pl/img/blog/koronalotek-g1.png"></p><p>The above plot shows daily number of accepted guesses (i.e., those that were used to&nbsp;generate the next day’s winners) over time – a&nbsp;metric of popularity. Each day’s number means guesses cast in the 24 hours up until 10:30 (Warsaw time) on that day, which is when the official numbers are published by the Ministry of Health.</p><p>I’ve been filtering out automated submissions, as well as excess manual submissions by the same IP that seemed to&nbsp;skew the results too much – I’ve arbitrarily set the “excess” threshold at 10. The missing datapoint for 19 October is not a&nbsp;zero, but a&nbsp;N/A: I’ve lost that datapoint due to&nbsp;a&nbsp;glitch. More on this below.</p><p>The interest peaked on October 23, with more than a&nbsp;thousand guesses for that day (I&nbsp;think it was reposted by someone with a&nbsp;significant outreach back then), and has been slowly declining since.</p><p>I&nbsp;have privately received some feedback. One person has pointed out that they found the site distasteful and that making fun of pandemic tragedies made them uncomfortable. (I&nbsp;empathise; for me it’s not so much making fun as it is a&nbsp;coping mechanism—a&nbsp;way to&nbsp;put distance between my thoughts and the difficult times we’re in and to&nbsp;keep fears at bay.) Some people, however, have thanked me for making them smile when they guessed more or less correctly.</p><p>Back to&nbsp;data. Being a&nbsp;data junkie, I&nbsp;looked at what I&nbsp;had been collecting. First things first: how accurate is the collective predictive power of the guessers?</p><p><img src="http://blog.danieljanus.pl/img/blog/koronalotek-g2.png"></p><p>Quite accurate, in fact! Data for this plot has only been slightly preprocessed, by filtering out “unreasonable” guesses that don’t fall within the range <code>[100; 50000]</code>.</p><p>People have over- and underguesstimated the number of new cases, but not by much. There were only a&nbsp;few occasions where the actual case count didn’t fall within one standard deviation of the mean of guesses (represented by the whiskers around blue bars on the plot). Granted, the daily standard deviation tends to&nbsp;be large (on the order of a&nbsp;few thousand), but still, I’m impressed. A&nbsp;paper on estimating the growth of pandemic based on coronalottery results coming soon to&nbsp;a&nbsp;journal near you! ;-)</p><p>Just for the heck of it, I’ve also been looking at individual votes. Specifically, names. Here’s a&nbsp;snapshot of unique guessers’ names sorted by decreasing length, on 23 October. (NSFW warning: expletives ahead!)</p><p><img src="http://blog.danieljanus.pl/img/blog/koronalotek-names.jpg"></p><p>Let me translate a&nbsp;few of these for those of you who don’t speak Polish:</p><p>1 is “Sasin has fucked over 70 million zlotys for elections that didn’t take place and was never held responsible.” This alludes to&nbsp;the <a href="https://notesfrompoland.com/2020/05/27/70-million-zloty-bill-for-polands-abandoned-presidential-election/">ghost election in Poland</a> from May. This news had gone memetic, going so far as Minister Sasin’s name being ironically used as a&nbsp;dimensionless unit of 70 million (think Avogadro’s number). You’ll discover the same theme in #2, #3, #5, and others.</p><p>6 is “CT {Constitutional Tribunal}, you focking botch, stop repressing my abortion”. Just a&nbsp;day before, the Polish constitutional court (whose current legality is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constitutional_Tribunal_(Poland)#2015%E2%80%93present:_Polish_Constitutional_Court_crisis">disputed at best</a>) has <a href="https://notesfrompoland.com/2020/10/22/constitutional-court-ruling-ends-almost-all-legal-abortion-in-poland/">decreed a&nbsp;ban on almost all legal abortion</a> in Poland, giving rise to&nbsp;<a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2020/10/31/europe/poland-abortion-protests-scli-intl/index.html">the biggest street protests in decades</a>.</p><p>Not all is political: 4 is “Why study for the exam if we’re not gonna survive until November anyway?”. I&nbsp;hope whoever wrote this is alive and well.</p><p>Corollary? Give people a&nbsp;text field, and they’ll use it to&nbsp;express themselves: politically or otherwise.</p><p>In fact, I&nbsp;have taken the liberty of chiming in. Shortly after, I&nbsp;altered the thank-you page (which used to&nbsp;just say “thanks for guessing”) to&nbsp;proudly display one of the emblems of the Women’s Strike, along with a&nbsp;link to&nbsp;a&nbsp;<a href="https://zrzutka.pl/kasa-na-aborcyjny-dream-team-55g5gx">crowdfounding campaign</a> for an NGO that supports women needing abortion.</p><p><img src="http://blog.danieljanus.pl/img/blog/koronalotek-thanks.jpg"></p><h2>Inside out</h2><p>I’m not much of a&nbsp;DevOps person, so I&nbsp;deployed it the quick and dirty way, not caring about scalability or performance. The maxim “make it as simple as possible” permeates the setup.</p><p>I&nbsp;just started a&nbsp;REPL within a&nbsp;<code>screen</code> session on the tiny Scaleway C1 server that also hosts this blog and some of my other personal stuff. I&nbsp;launched a&nbsp;Jetty server within it, and set up a&nbsp;nginx proxy. And that’s pretty much it. I&nbsp;liberally tinker with the app’s state in “production,” evaluating all kinds of expressions when I&nbsp;feel like it.</p><p>Code changes are deployed by <code>git pull</code>ing new developments and doing <code>(require 'koronalotek.core :reload)</code> in the REPL.</p><p>Someone tried a&nbsp;SQL injection attack. This is doomed to&nbsp;fail because there’s no SQL involved. In fact, there’s no database at all. The entire state is kept in an in-memory atom and periodically synced out to&nbsp;an EDN file. In addition, state is reset and archived daily at the time of announcing winners. (I’ve added the archiving after forgetting it on one occasion – hence the lack of data for 19 October.)</p><p>I&nbsp;also don’t yet have a&nbsp;mechanism of automatically pulling in the Ministry of Health’s data. Every morning, I&nbsp;spend two minutes checking if there’s excess automatic votes, removing them if any, and then filling in the blanks:</p><pre><code>(new-data! #inst "2020-11-08T10:30+01:00" 24785)
</code></pre><p>For all the violations of good practices in this setup, it has worked out surprisingly well so far. I’ve resorted to&nbsp;removing automated votes a&nbsp;handful of times, and blacklisting IPs of voting bots in the nginx setup twice, but otherwise it’s been a&nbsp;low-maintenance toy. People seem to&nbsp;be willing to&nbsp;have fun, and I’m just not interfering.</p><h2>Takeaways</h2><ol><li>You should call on your country’s authorities to&nbsp;exert pressure on the Polish government to&nbsp;respect women’s choices and stop actively repressing them.</li><li>Give people a&nbsp;text field, and they’ll use it to&nbsp;express themselves.</li><li>Release early, release often.</li></ol></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://blog.danieljanus.pl/2020/11/08/coronalotto/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026666</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 16:13:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Problem Solving Techniques]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 162 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026561">thread link</a>) | @denvaar
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://denvaar.github.io/articles/problem_solving_example.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://denvaar.github.io/articles/problem_solving_example.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>âœ�ï¸� Going meta - Working through a programming problem to understand problem solving techniques.</p><div>
        <p>The technical skills of computer programming fall under two broad categories, in my opinion.</p>
<p>The first category includes things like learning language syntax, constructs, and patterns. I would summarize it as the ability to connect and utilize the myriad, "tools of the trade" -- languages, frameworks, APIs, libraries -- to create software. There's usually tutorials for these things.</p>
<p>The second category includes things that are a little bit harder to put your finger on, but can probably be best described as problem solving. It's the ability to analyze, troubleshoot, debug, or solve a problem. It's the ability to reason with abstract ideas and turn them into code.</p>
<p>There is for sure some overlap between these two categories, but this is how I like to think about it.</p>
<p>It's hard to be specific about what it takes to be good at problem solving. I believe that's because we all have a slightly different perception of the world around us. Everyone learns differently. There must, however, be at least some techniques that I might learn from you, and vice versa.</p>
<p>Problems like the one I am about to share can be great tools for learning about problem solving. This one's from Project Euler. My intention is not to simply spoil the answer. I want to share my process of figuring it out, with the hope of being able to pinpoint some specific strategies that can be used to solve all kinds of problems.</p>
<h2 id="thechallenge">The challenge</h2>
<p>You can find the original problem statement <a href="https://projecteuler.net/problem=79">here</a>. It's short, so take a moment to read through.</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_0.png" alt=""></p>
<p>The challenge is to determine what the shortest possible secret number is. Here's an excerpt from the keylogger file.</p>
<pre><code>...
160
689
716
731
736
...
</code></pre>
<h2 id="firststeps">First steps</h2>
<p>I began by sitting down with pencil and paper to write some numbers from the list. Writing helps me begin to think about the problem.</p>
<p>I thought about what these numbers in the list could tell me about the secret number. Maybe I could find a way to at least figure out its length. There are about fifty numbers in the list, so maybe that number is somehow correlated to the secret number.</p>
<p>These were a few of the questions going through my head. If the answers seem super obvious to you, then congratulations, you might be smarter than me. What's most important during the first steps is that you ask questions.</p>
<p>I realized pretty quickly that no, the length of the list I was given didn't tell me much, but you've got to start somewhere. Next, my thoughts turned to the fact that each number was three digits long.</p>
<p><em>What if I was given a list of two-digit numbers, or even a list of just one-digit numbers? What could that tell me about the length of the secret number? Is there something special about three-digit numbers in particular?</em> These were valuable questions to ask, because it helped me to simplify the problem.</p>
<p>I made a list of one-digit numbers and tried to think about how I might be able to solve the same problem with that instead.</p>
<pre><code>6
2
1
0
</code></pre>
<p>Given a list like this as clues, I could say for certain that the secret number has at least a 6,2,1, and 0, but I also loose essential information about the problem: The order that the numbers appear in. A list of one-digit numbers is too ambiguous. The secret number could be <code>6210</code>, <code>2601</code>, or any other combination, and I would have no way of knowing which one is correct.</p>
<p>A list of two-digit numbers might be nice. It's less to think about, yet is still able to convey the needed information. From this point forward, I decided to think about the list as two-digit numbers, rather than three-digit numbers.</p>
<h2 id="possibleoptionmaintainasortedarray">Possible option: Maintain a sorted array</h2>
<p>At this point, I still wasn't sure how to solve the problem on paper, so I decided to try and work backwards. I wrote down a random number and then picked a few pairs of digits from it to try and reconstruct my own version of the problem. I decided to go through each number in the list and write down the digits as if they were being inserted into some kind of array.</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_1.png" alt=""></p>
<p>I realized an approach like this would not be very practical because it still leaves room for ambiguity.</p>
<p>In the example above, its clear that 5 is before 2, but if I continue to add the digits from the next number, I can't tell if the 1 should come before or after the 5. It's the same problem for the 8: I know it should come before the 2, but the data says nothing about if it should be before or after the 1, or the 5.</p>
<p>Even if I had another data point to disambiguate the clues -- <code>51</code>, for example -- sure, it would tell me that the 1 is in the correct spot between 5 and 2, but I already get the feeling that trying to write code to account for switching numbers around in an array is not going to be practical, and that there is probably an easier way.</p>
<p>Writing it out this way helped me realize that the help of some sort of data structure would be useful for solving this problem.</p>
<p>So now the question is, <em>what kind of data structure could help model this problem?</em> To help with this decision, I thought about what data is actually provided in the problem. Using the example above, the list of numbers reads as:</p>
<ul>
<li>5 "comes before" 2</li>
<li>1 "comes before" 2</li>
<li>8 "comes before" 2</li>
</ul>
<p>Each number in the list provides helpful clues, but the problem is that it's difficult to keep track of how each clue ultimately fits together. I tried to think of some kind of data structure that would be able to represent each clue individually, but also as a whole.</p>
<p>A directed graph seems to be a pretty natural fit to represent this information. Each node could be a digit, and the edges between nodes could represent the relationship between them.</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_2.png" alt=""></p>
<p>I felt good about using a graph to solve the problem, but there were still some questions that I had to figure out.</p>
<ul>
<li>How would I know when the graph has enough information to to be able to get the secret number? In other words, how can I know when my answer is conclusive?</li>
<li>How could the graph be read or interpreted programmatically to produce the secret number?</li>
<li>What if a secret number had more than one of the same digit? Would that ruin my approach?</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="howtoknowwhentheanswerisconclusive">How to know when the answer is conclusive</h2>
<p>To help answer this question I used the same technique of creating a simplified version of the problem and working backwards. Pretend now that 157 is the secret number. How many edges between the nodes would it take to definitively say that 1 comes before both 5 and 7, and 5 comes before 7? The answer is three edges for this particular graph.</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_3.png" alt=""></p>
<p>In this example, the order is known when number of edges are equal to the number of nodes. <em>Is it that simple? Can we know what the secret number is if the number of edges are equal to the number of nodes?</em></p>
<p>In this example, yes, but it doesn't hold true for the general case. By creating more examples, I start to find a relationship between the number of nodes, and the number of edges. Have a look at what four and five-digit secret numbers look like as a graph:</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_4.png" alt=""></p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_5.png" alt=""></p>
<p>After drawing a few of these, I could begin to see a pattern emerge. As the number of nodes increase, the number of edges increase like, <code>1, 3, 6, 10, 15, 21, 28, ..</code>.</p>
<p>It can be helpful to look for patterns, because it means that there's an equation which can be used to represent some aspect of the problem. Here the pattern showed me what condition to use in order to know when my answer could be considered conclusive. This is the equation that represents that pattern, where n is the number of nodes in the graph.</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_6.png"></p>
<h2 id="readingthegraphtofindtheanswer">Reading the graph to find the answer</h2>
<p>A hand-drawn graph helps to visualize the approach of solving this problem, but I knew that I would also need to keep in mind how the graph could be represented with code. Specifically, how to programmatically traverse the graph to produce a result.</p>
<p>After staring at the examples for a bit longer, I realized an obvious and helpful property about the graph.</p>
<p>The nodes with the most outward edges come before those with less outward edges. Additionally, the number of edges for each node differ by exactly one. This means that the first digit of the secret number should have the most outward edges, while the last digit would not have any outward edges.</p>
<p>This property made logical sense to me, and was something that could be easily translated into code.</p>
<h2 id="duplicatedigits">Duplicate digits</h2>
<p>A secret number with more than one of the same digit could cause problems with my approach. This was something that worried me as I was working, because it was not clear how to know which two nodes to put the edge between. For example, take a look at 1030 as the secret number, and imagine the digits given in the following order:</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_7.png" alt=""></p>
<p>There are multiple ways to draw the graph because there are two 0's. There should still be only one "correct" way. Creating a correct graph might depend on the order in which the digits are given. I might need to think of some way to backtrack and re-connect nodes in order to end up with the correct graph.</p>
<p>The correct and incorrect graphs can be compared to understand how exactly they differ. The incorrect graph has a circular dependency: 3 comes before both the orange and blue 0's, but then the blue 0 comes before 3, which is contradictory.</p>
<p>Another difference is that the correct version is the only one that satisfies the property mentioned above, where the number of each node's edges differ by exactly one. This property should always be true for any secret number modeled with the graph.</p>
<p><img src="https://denvaar.github.io/assets/secret_number_8.png" alt=""></p>
<p>At this point, I decided to put the question of duplicate digits on hold. It looked like this would break the approach that I had planned to use. I think its possible to figure out, but it was unclear if this use case needed to be supported at all.</p>
<p>My plan was now to turn my ideas into code to see if it would produce the correct answer.</p>
<h2 id="translateideastocode">Translate ideas to code</h2>
<p>This part went by pretty quickly because I had formed a good understanding of the problem, as well as an approach for how to solve it. I picked Python for no particular reason, …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://denvaar.github.io/articles/problem_solving_example.html">https://denvaar.github.io/articles/problem_solving_example.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://denvaar.github.io/articles/problem_solving_example.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026561</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 15:57:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Making a programming language using Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 182 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026419">thread link</a>) | @azhenley
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://arzg.github.io/lang/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://arzg.github.io/lang/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>A series about making a programming language called <a href="https://github.com/arzg/eldiro">Eldiro</a> using the <a href="https://rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> programming language.</p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/9/">Part Nine: Function Calls</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/8/">Part Eight: Function Definitions</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/7/">Part Seven: A REPL</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/6/">Part Six: Blocks</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/5/">Part Five: Binding Usages</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/4/">Part Four: Backtracking</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/3/">Part Three: Defining Variables</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/2/">Part Two: Whitespace Support</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/1/">Part One: A Basic Parser</a></p><p><a href="https://arzg.github.io/lang/0/">Part Zero: Getting set up</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://arzg.github.io/lang/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026419</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 15:41:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Google Cloud IAM for Security Teams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 11 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026227">thread link</a>) | @gbrindisi
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://cloudberry.engineering/article/google-cloud-iam-security-guide/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cloudberry.engineering/article/google-cloud-iam-security-guide/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
    <div>
        <div>
            <p>Identity and Access Management (IAM) is an important piece of the cloud puzzle and it’s usually a source of headaches from a security point of view. Let’s try to give some pointers from a blue team perspective.</p>

<p>If you are a security team that just inherited a bunch of Google Cloud Platform (GCP) accounts, this guide is for you.</p>

<h2 id="identities-and-roles">Identities and Roles</h2>

<p>IAM revolves around the concept of <strong>identity</strong>: an (authenticated) entity to which authorization grants are applied.</p>

<h3 id="members">Members</h3>

<p>In Google Cloud, identities are called <strong>members</strong> and are the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>A <strong>User</strong>: defined by a Google Account</li>
<li>A <strong>Group</strong>: defined by a Google Group</li>
<li>A <strong>domain</strong>: a super group representing all accounts under a gsuite/workspace domain</li>
<li>A <strong>Service Account</strong>: an account for an application rather than an end user</li>
</ul>

<p>To make things spicier, there are also two special members that you are going to hate and you want to make sure they will <em>never be used</em> (unless valid business reasons):</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>allAuthenticatedUsers</strong>: a special group comprised of everyone on earth with a google account (yes)</li>
<li><strong>allUser</strong>: anyone on the internet, authenticated or not</li>
</ul>


<div><p>
Pro Tip:</p>

<ul>
<li>scan your IAM policies and make sure that <code>allAuthenticatedUsers</code> and <code>allUsers</code> are never used</li>
<li>or even better, set up an organizational policy to only allow members from your gsuite/workspace domain</li>
</ul>
</div>


<h3 id="roles">Roles</h3>

<p>You assign (bind) a Role to a Member to grant that identity access to a resource. An example role is  <code>resourcemanager.projectCreator</code>:</p>

<pre><code>$ gcloud iam roles list
…
---
description: Access to create new GCP projects.
etag: AA==
name: roles/resourcemanager.projectCreator
stage: GA
title: Project Creator
---
…
</code></pre>

<p>Roles are a set of <em>permissions</em> grouped together, each one representing a fine grained operation. You can’t assign permissions directly to members.</p>

<p>An example permission would be <code>resource manager.projects.create</code>:</p>

<pre><code>$ gcloud iam roles describe roles/resourcemanager.projectCreator
description: Access to create new GCP projects.
etag: AA==
includedPermissions:
- resourcemanager.organizations.get
- resourcemanager.projects.create
name: roles/resourcemanager.projectCreator
stage: GA
title: Project Creator
</code></pre>

<p>Usually, every cloud service will come with a dedicated set of Roles (<a href="https://cloudberry.engineering/article/stricter-access-control-to-gcr/">not for Google Container Registry</a>).</p>

<h3 id="custom-roles">Custom Roles</h3>

<p>As a rule of thumb <strong>stick to standard roles</strong>, but if you have to bind a role to a member in a high level policy you might want to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/iam/docs/creating-custom-roles">use a custom role</a>. Custom Roles allows you to group together the specific set of permissions you need.</p>

<p>They are helpful to maintain least privilege because a role bind on a high level policy (like the Organization one) will affect way more resources.</p>


<div><p>
Pro Tip:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use standard roles when the number of affected resources is limited</li>
<li>Use custom roles when the authorization grant affect too many resources</li>
</ul>
</div>


<h3 id="primitive-roles">Primitive Roles</h3>

<p>There are a bunch of roles you should be wary of: <em>primitive roles</em>. These are <code>Owner</code>, <code>Editor</code> and <code>Viewer</code>. When they are bind on the Project IAM policy they translate to admin, write and read access to everything inside that project.</p>

<p>You want to be wary for two reasons:</p>

<ol>
<li>The set of permissions change over time: when Google release new cloud services, permissions for such services are included in the primitive roles. This means <strong>you have an authorization grant that change over time and you have no control over</strong>. No bueno.</li>
<li><strong>They are a bridge to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/access-control/lists">Access Control List</a></strong> (ACL). ACL are the legacy authorization system for some storage services such as Buckets and Bigquery. In such resources you can assign ACL grants to whoever is bind to a primitive role in the Project. This relationship <strong>adds complexity when trying to understand the <a href="https://cloudberry.engineering/article/lateral-movement-cloud/">blast radius</a></strong> of a member.</li>
</ol>

<p>If you can’t escape using a primitive role, bind them to members that you will use only in “break the glass” scenarios. In practice, you don’t want a team doing their day to day operations as <code>Owners</code>.</p>


<div><p>
Pro Tip:</p>

<ul>
<li>Avoid primitive roles</li>
<li>Do not use Access Control Lists (ACL)</li>
</ul>
</div>


<h2 id="iam-policies-and-where-to-find-them">IAM Policies (and where to find them)</h2>

<p>Roles are bind to members in an IAM Policy. Policies are organized in hierarchical layers (from top to bottom):</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Organization</strong></li>
<li><strong>Folder</strong></li>
<li><strong>Project</strong></li>
<li>Specific Resources.</li>
</ul>

<p>Bindings will be inherited from top to bottom.</p>

<p>So if you assign <code>Storage Admin</code> to a service account in the Organization IAM Policy, the same grant will be applied to everything down (don’t do that).</p>

<p>You obviously want to be extra careful when binding roles high in the hierarchy as the authorization grant will be quite large. That’s why it’s a good idea to use custom roles to shrink it to just the permissions you need.</p>

<p>Some specific cloud resources, such as Buckets, have their own IAM policy. These are easy to overlook because they don’t have a consistent place in the google cloud admin interface.</p>

<p>The best way to <strong>get visibility over all IAM policies</strong> is to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/asset-inventory/">create a Cloud Asset Inventory (CAI) dump</a>. CAI is, in my opinion, <strong>the most useful thing in GCP</strong>. It’s an API that will generate a json (or bigquery) dump of all the resources and IAM Policies you are currently running.</p>

<p>The best thing you can do on day one is to set up periodical CAI dumps, and then build your detections on top of them.</p>

<h3 id="maintain-the-principle-of-least-privilege">Maintain the principle of least privilege</h3>

<p>The second best thing is to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/iam/docs/recommender-overview">use the IAM Recommender</a>: a service that monitors how role bindings are actually used to make sure you are not over granting them.</p>

<p>Another helpful trick to know is that you can <a href="https://cloud.google.com/iam/docs/conditions-overview">attach conditions to role bindings</a>. For example you can set an expiration time, or you can scope down the binding to affect only certain resources matching a pattern.</p>


<div><p>
Pro Tip:</p>

<ul>
<li>The higher in the IAM hierarchy, the wider the scope of the authorization grant: use sporadically, be a gatekeeper.</li>
<li>Set up Cloud Asset Inventory to not miss anything</li>
<li>Use the IAM Recommender</li>
<li>Use IAM Conditions</li>
</ul>
</div>


<h2 id="notes-on-service-accounts">Notes on Service Accounts</h2>

<p>Service accounts can be of two types: google managed and user managed.</p>

<p>A user managed service account is one you manually create. To use it, you need to create a private key and embed it into your application. A service account can have multiple keys.</p>

<p><strong>Service Account keys lifecycle is your responsibility</strong>: they never really expires, are hard to audit (you don’t see which key has been used from the audit logs). From day one you should start thinking how to keep track of them.</p>

<p>Personally I am a fan of wrapping keys creation into an internal service for your developers to use, but I understand it’s not always possible.</p>

<p>The best alternative is to <strong>use google managed service accounts</strong>. For example each project will come with a default service account that is used by Google Compute Engine (GCE) services (if the GCE API is enabled).</p>

<p>This means that virtual machines will transparently be identified by that service account, and they are authorized to request short-lived authorization tokens from the internal metadata service. You can configure them to use a service account of your choice and <strong>no keys are involved</strong>.</p>


<div><p>
Pro tip:</p>

<ul>
<li>Become a gatekeeper for provisioning Service Accounts keys</li>
<li>Use the identity of the virtual machines whenever possible</li>
<li>Are you running Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE)? Take a look at <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/how-to/workload-identity">Workload Identity</a></li>
<li>Follow <a href="https://cloudberry.engineering/article/google-cloud-service-accounts-security-best-practices/">service accounts best practices</a></li>
</ul>
</div>


<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>To recap:</p>

<ul>
<li>scan your IAM policies and make sure that <code>allAuthenticatedUsers</code> and <code>allUsers</code> are never used</li>
<li>or even better, set up an organizational policy to only allow members from your gsuite/workspace domain</li>
<li>Use standard roles when the number of affected resources is limited</li>
<li>Use custom roles when the authorization grant affect too many resources</li>
<li>Avoid primitive roles</li>
<li>Do not use Access Control Lists (ACL)</li>
<li>The higher in the IAM hierarchy, the wider the scope of the authorization grant: use sporadically, be a gatekeeper.</li>
<li>Set up Cloud Asset Inventory to not miss anything</li>
<li>Adhere to the least privilege principle with the IAM Recommender and IAM Conditions</li>
<li>Become a gatekeeper for provisioning Service Accounts keys</li>
<li>Use the identity of the virtual machines whenever possible</li>
<li>Are you running Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE)? Take a look at <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/how-to/workload-identity">Workload Identity</a></li>
<li>Follow <a href="https://cloudberry.engineering/article/google-cloud-service-accounts-security-best-practices/">service accounts best practices</a></li>
</ul>

<p>There is a lot more to say about IAM governance and security best practices. This article’s purpose is to give a high level overview of the main security considerations.</p>

<p>If you are looking for specific advices, <a href="mailto:hello@cloudberry.engineering">let me know</a>. I might have some.</p>

<p>Finally, I highly recommend this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YGT_AmCA-eA&amp;feature=youtu.be">fantastic talk by Kat Traxler</a> about primitive roles and IAM quirks in GCP.</p>
        </div>
        
    </div>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cloudberry.engineering/article/google-cloud-iam-security-guide/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026227</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 15:13:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[BGP Lego Bricks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 34 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026189">thread link</a>) | @bitcynth
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://blog.cynthia.re/post/bgp-lego | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.cynthia.re/post/bgp-lego">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<h3>Nov 8 2020</h3>


<p>Since I was 7 years old, I have wanted a LEGO Mindstorms robot. I will admit that in the later years it was mainly that I wanted to prove to myself that I got somewhere as it seemed so infinitely expensive back when I was younger…</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/bitcynth/status/1319956429252513792" title="Tweet about it"><img src="https://blog.cynthia.re/asset/g1ZkG7sMAD" alt="LEGO Robot Inventor"></a></p>

<p>Well I finally got one!</p>

<p>I knew this thing had some capability to run <a href="https://micropython.org/">MicroPython</a> since that was mentioned in the product description quite predominantly, which sounded like a pretty hackable platform.</p>

<p>However, shortly after opening the box, I realized that this wasn’t at all just an update to the <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/product/lego-mindstorms-ev3-31313">Mindstorms EV3</a>. Apparently the Robot Inventor was a slightly more expensive thing with less features and using a LiPo battery instead of AA cells.</p>

<p>Luckily I ordered it via the store’s website which means that by law I can return it within 14 days for any reason, and it allows me to open the box for inspection.</p>

<p>So after convincing some stubborn store employee that this is not a consumable product (which would remove my right to open the box), I got it returned and ordered the EV3.</p>

<p>Then two days later I finally had the thing which I have wanted for so long.</p>

<p>While I was waiting for the EV3, I was looking around at how it did MicroPython as it had this paragraph on the downloads page.</p>

<pre><code>You can now use your EV3 Brick to unleash the power of Python programming using MicroPython. Simply install the EV3 MicroPython image onto any micro SD card and boot up your EV3 Brick from it to start programming straight away. 
</code></pre>

<p>After just a few minutes of searching I found <a href="https://www.ev3dev.org/">ev3dev</a> which is an open source community project that allows you to run Debian on it!</p>

<p>It appears to be really well made and apparently good enough for LEGO to provide <a href="https://education.lego.com/en-us/support/mindstorms-ev3/python-for-ev3">official builds</a> of it, which is what they use for MicroPython support.</p>

<p>So I just went ahead and downloaded and flashed the disk image to a microSD card with <code>dd</code>.
I then plugged in the microSD card into the EV3 controller and turned it on…</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.cynthia.re/asset/rC3JqPiBNA" alt="EV3 kernel dmesg"></p>

<p>To my surprise, after applying power I was pleased to see kernel dmesg output scrolling out on the LCD of the EV3 on the first try!</p>

<pre><code>robot@ev3dev:~$ uname -a
Linux ev3dev 4.14.117-ev3dev-2.3.5-ev3 #1 PREEMPT Sat Mar 7 12:54:39 CST 2020 armv5tejl GNU/Linux

robot@ev3dev:~$ cat /etc/os-release 
PRETTY_NAME="ev3dev-stretch"
NAME="ev3dev-stretch"
ID=ev3dev
ID_LIKE=debian
HOME_URL="http://www.ev3dev.org"
SUPPORT_URL="http://www.ev3dev.org/support"
BUG_REPORT_URL="https://github.com/ev3dev/ev3dev/issues"
</code></pre>

<p>After playing around with it for about two minutes, I realized something… this thing runs Debian with a pretty damn complete package repository (it has ~64000 packages and normal amd64 Debian has ~66000 packages), can this thing run BIRD?</p>

<p>I assumed that if the ARM926EJ-S CPU can run Debian and stuff it can probably run a very minimal BIRD config, however I wasn’t so sure about the 56MB of RAM.</p>

<p>But well you won’t know if you don’t try :p</p>

<p>So I just went ahead and typed <code>sudo apt install bird</code> and pressed enter…</p>

<pre><code>robot@ev3dev:~$ sudo apt install bird
Reading package lists... Done
Building dependency tree       
Reading state information... Done
Suggested packages:
  bird-doc
</code></pre>

<p>(this was actually painfully slow as this thing doesn’t have a powerful CPU in the slightest)</p>

<p>As soon as I saw <code>bird-doc</code> I realized that yes it did at least have BIRD in the repo so that was a good first step.</p>

<p>I am only installing BIRD 1.6.3 here as it will probably use less resources than BIRD 2 if I only run the IPv6 daemon and disable the IPv4 daemon.</p>

<p>I then wrote a <a href="https://blog.cynthia.re/asset/gv3GvwzBGH">quick little bird config</a> to let the EV3 (AS202314) announce 2a0d:1a45:666::/48 to my home router (AS210089), and the home router will then deal with the rest.</p>

<p>I applied that and wrote the other end of the config on my home router and applied that too.</p>

<p>Then I went to the <a href="http://lg.ring.nlnog.net/">NLNOG RING Looking Glass</a> and I saw the /48 show up as announced by AS202314!</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.cynthia.re/asset/KVCU9bynjB" alt="NLNOG RING Looking Glass"></p>

<p>I then sent it to a friend who pointed out only about half of his sources could see the route, and well turns out I forgot to give AS202314 an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_Public_Key_Infrastructure">RPKI ROA</a> for the prefix, so I added that.</p>

<p>Then just for demo purposes I installed nginx which worked surprisingly well, so then I had a website I could access at http://[2a0d:1a45:666::]/ <sup><a href="#fn1">[1]</a></sup>.</p>

<p>This was surprisingly easy to get working. Hats off to the <a href="https://www.ev3dev.org/">ev3dev</a> people for making this Debian derivative for the EV3.</p>

<p>While having the EV3 sitting there announcing a /48 of IPv6 is not useful in itself, this shows off how flexible the platform is. The fact that I can do this silly thing means that I can do much cooler things that don’t involve BGP on this, like running web servers and other things.</p>

<hr>

<p>If this was to your liking then maybe you will find my other posts interesting, and you can also find my smaller projects and ramblings on twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/bitcynth">@bitcynth</a>.</p>

<p>Thank you to <a href="https://twitter.com/Benjojo12">Ben Cox</a> and <a href="https://www.mollymiller.net/">Molly Miller</a> for the help in editing this blog post.</p>

<p><sup><a name="fn1">[1]</a></sup>: no longer online</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.cynthia.re/post/bgp-lego</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026189</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 15:06:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[macOS file diff app, Kaleidoscope, acquired by Letter Opener GmbH]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 59 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25026070">thread link</a>) | @dplgk
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://kaleidoscope.app/release-notes | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://kaleidoscope.app/release-notes">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="macos"><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.3.4<p>November 6 2020</p></h3><p>build 1444 (Direct)</p><ul><li>Fixed some potential bugs hiding behind warnings.</li><li>Fixed missing update functionality of version 2.3.2.</li><li><strong>Note:</strong> If you installed version 2.3.2 please download manually the latest version.</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.3.3<p>October 24 2020</p></h3><p>build 1443.1 (Mac App Store)</p><ul><li>Update contact information to support@kaleidoscope.app, don't be shy and say hi!</li><li>Fixed newsletter sign-up in the Help &gt; Getting Started window.</li></ul><h3>Change of ownership<p>October 9 2020</p></h3><ul><li>Letter Opener GmbH acquired Kaleidoscope from Hypergiant LLC.</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.3.2<p>April 17 2020</p></h3><p>build 1442 (Direct) / 1442.1 (Mac App Store)</p><ul><li><strong>Note:</strong> build 1442 (Direct) was pulled because it is missing update functionality. If you installed version 2.3.2 please download manually the latest version.</li><li>Fixed bug in integration window</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.3.1<p>April 7 2020</p></h3><p>build 1441 (Direct) / 1441.2 (Mac App Store)</p><ul><li>Fixed a crash caused by opening a zero-length text file</li><li>Improved scrolling performance when using Find to search for text</li><li>Minor bug fixes</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.3<p>February 21 2020</p></h3><p>build 1438 (Direct)</p><ul><li>Improved macOS Catalina compatibility</li><li>Notarized builds for improved security</li><li>Fixed blurred scrollbar endcap issue on Retina displays</li><li>Updated crash analytics package</li><li>Minor bug fixes</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.2.2<p>November 7 2017</p></h3><p>build 1376 (Direct) / 1376.01 (Mac App Store)</p><ul><li>Bug Fixes.</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.2.1<p>August 9 2017</p></h3><p>build 1158 (Direct) / 1158.01 (Mac App Store)</p><ul><li><strong>Note:</strong> Kaleidoscope now requires macOS 10.12 or above.</li><ul><li>Fixed crashes related to future macOS releases.</li><li>Fixed an issue where the user is unnecessarily prompted to update ksdiff.</li><li>Updated documentation.</li><li>Added analytics to help our developers improve future releases.</li></ul></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.2<p>May 3 2017</p></h3><p>build 439 (Direct) / 439.01 (Mac App Store)</p><ul><li><strong>New:</strong> Added support for recent macOS updates.</li><ul><li>Overhauled the interface to better reflect the contemporary Mac environment.</li><li>Added stability with multiple under-the-hood improvements.</li><li>Modernized the codebase to make future work more manageable.</li><li>Fixed various issues related to macOS Sierra.</li></ul></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.1.1<p>June 9 2015</p></h3><p>build 219 (Direct)</p><ul><li><strong>Note:</strong> We are working to get version 2.1.1 into the Mac App Store. For now, please <a href="http://www.kaleidoscopeapp.com/download">download</a> the direct sale version. Your purchase will carry over.</li><li>Fixed a couple issues with our Bazaar integration instructions.</li><li>⌘-D now triggers the Don't Resolve button when dismissing a merge warning.</li><li>Improved automatic graphics switching support (Early 2011 or newer MacBooks Pro): Kaleidoscope will now only use the discrete GPU when necessary.</li><li>Updated our mechanism for purchasing a Kaleidoscope registration.</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.1<p>April 30 2014</p></h3><p>build 134 (Direct) / 133.01 (Mac App Store)</p><ul><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Added support for ignoring whitespace (leading, trailing and line ending) in text comparisons.</li><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Added an indicator to display remaining unresolved conflicts in a merge document.</li><li><strong>Text Scope</strong><ul><li>Added dropdown menus on either side of Choose Left/Choose Right buttons to make “Choose Both” options more discoverable.</li><li>Added better tooltips for the “Copy to” buttons when in Unified view.</li><li>Fixed various issues with Dark Theme which made text difficult to read.</li><li>Fixed issue where selecting different text scope views on one window could affect copy right/left buttons on other windows.</li><li>Fixed issue where holding option to modify the behavior of copy right/left buttons on one window could affect other windows.</li><li>Fixed issue that could prevent Kaleidoscope from picking up changes made to a document open in more than one window.</li><li>Fixed issue that could prevent Kaleidoscope from picking up changes made to documents externally, especially on the MAS build.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Folder Scope</strong><ul><li>Fixed issue where sometimes Folder Scope copies would not show up correctly after the copy had taken place.</li><li>Fixed issue where Folder Scope would not pick up external additions of empty files or directories.</li><li>Fixed issue that caused the app to reject dragging of folders to the dock icon.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Integration</strong><ul><li>Fixed issue that caused git integration to fail on 10.9 Mavericks.</li><li>Fixed issue where ksdiff was sometimes not able to connect to Kaleidoscope after reboots with window restoration enabled.</li><li>Fixed issue that where Kaleidoscope would not allow quitting when choosing “Review Conflicts” on a modified document.</li></ul></li><li><strong>General Improvements</strong><ul><li>Updated Automator actions to categorize correctly in Automator.</li><li>Added support for copy/paste shortcuts in the crash reporter window.</li><li>Kaleidoscope now avoids saving files without changes.</li><li>Kaleidoscope will now disallow edits to files that can be read but not written to (e.g. docx files).</li><li>Kaleidoscope now better remembers size and position of your windows.</li><li>Fixed issue that stopped the comparison windows from minimizing when double clicking their title bar.</li><li>Fixed issue where the path bar area could fail to update correctly when switching tabs.</li><li>Fixed issue where clicking the dock icon would not restore minimized documents.</li><li>Fixed issue where dragging a group of files that were already open in Kaleidoscope could cause issues resulting in not all new files being added.</li><li>Fixed issue that made it possible for the comparison window to grow vertically offscreen on 10.9 leaving you with a window you could not reposition afterwards.</li><li>Fixed issue that made it impossible to bring up the open dialog by clicking on an empty tab when fullscreen in 10.9.</li><li>Fixed issue where sometimes full-screen windows would not be full-screen.</li><li>Fixed small visual issues with the Ignored Files dialog window.</li><li>Fixed documentation issues with ksdiff help.</li><li>Improved Help Documentation.</li><li>Various performance and stability fixes.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.0.2<p>October 23 2013</p></h3><p>build 116</p><ul><li>Improved compatibility with OS X 10.9 Mavericks</li><li>Improved stability</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.0.1<p>February 19 2013</p></h3><p>build 114</p><ul><li><strong>Text Scope</strong><ul><li>Tweaked the visual appearance of the change count stepper in Text Scope.</li><li>Fixed the "Reset Selection" menu item in Text Scope to enable and disable properly.</li><li>The Save menu is now properly disabled when comparing text snippets.</li><li>Fixed a bug where the summary text in document titles and tabs might not properly update.</li><li>The Resolved document in Three Way Blocks now has better alignment with similar content in A and B.</li><li>Kaleidoscope can now properly diff .textClipping documents.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Folder Scope</strong><ul><li>User-defined system date formats will now be properly used.</li><li>Fixed a bug that prevented Folder Scope from having the correct keyboard focus by default.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Image Scope</strong><ul><li>Kaleidoscope now handles different color spaces more reliably in Image Scope.</li><li>Kaleidoscope now properly accounts for camera orientation when displaying images in Image Scope.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Changesets</strong><ul><li>Improved keyboard navigation in changesets.</li><li>Unsaved files will now be properly marked as dirty in changesets.</li><li>Changesets now properly select the list of files on the left when opening, allowing you to quickly review changes.</li></ul></li><li><strong>General Improvements</strong><ul><li>Direct Sale fulfillment emails will now properly activate Kaleidoscope for users with diacritics in their names.</li><li>Kaleidoscope will no longer move itself to ~/Applications if that folder exists. It will now move to /Applications in all cases.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused temporary licenses to expire one day earlier than they should have.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused the corner radii of windows in Full Screen to not match.</li><li>Fixed an issue that sometimes led to poor vertical alignment in the File Shelf.</li><li>Dragging files to Kaleidoscope will properly open to a comparison document and will no longer leave the launch window open in the background.</li><li>Fixed a bug that caused accessing files from the Recents list to sometimes stop working.</li><li>Improved the messaging if Kaleidoscope is unable to open a document that was previously available via AFP.</li></ul></li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.0<p>January 17, 2013</p></h3><p>build 107</p><ul><li>Resets trial period for users whose trial period expired during beta</li></ul><h3>Kaleidoscope 2.0<p>January 17, 2013</p></h3><p>build 104</p><ul><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Added support for merging text documents using a Two-Way interface in Text Scope.</li><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Added version control integration for merging and resolving conflicts using a Three-Way interface in Text Scope.</li><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Folder Scope — now you can spot the differences between folders and copy files and folders between them. Double click any row to open a new comparison and look at any pair of files or folders more closely.</li><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Kaleidoscope Snippets and Services</li><ul><li>You can now drag text and images directly into the Kaleidoscope window, or the Kaleidoscope dock icon, to create Snippets. This lets you quickly compare content without having to save and name files. Try dragging images or text directly from Safari or an email message!</li><li>Kaleidoscope now includes OS X System Services to make you more productive. They are enabled by default, but you can manually turn them On or Off in the Keyboard section of System Preferences. You can also set global keyboard shortcuts for them in the Keyboard pane of System Preferences if you want to get to these even faster.</li><li>Open in Kaleidoscope: Right click on any files or folders in Finder, and compare them in a single Kaleidoscope tab. This is the easiest way to compare folders!</li><li>Text and Image Compare: Right click on text or images and send them directly to Kaleidoscope as Snippets. Try this by selecting and right clicking on any text in TextEdit, then select “Compare Text in Kaleidoscope” from the Services menu.</li></ul><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Clipboard Support</li><ul><li>You can use the new "Edit -&gt; Paste as File" and "File -&gt; New from Clipboard" menu items to compare directly from the Clipboard. This works similarly to the drag and drop Snippets functionality. Use this to quickly create a new comparison document or to add existing text or images to an open document.</li></ul><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Kaleidoscope now supports resolving merge conflicts for images.</li><li><strong>New Feature:</strong> Added support for Full Screen on Lion and Mountain Lion.</li><li>Full support for Macs with Retina displays.</li><li>Substantially updated and modernized user interface.</li><li>Added support for sending arbitrary changesets and partial changsets with ksdiff.</li><li>Added support for arbitrary merges and diffs using ksdiff.</li><li>Integration with third-party tools now requires installation of the ksdiff command-line tool from the Integration …</li></ul></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://kaleidoscope.app/release-notes">https://kaleidoscope.app/release-notes</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://kaleidoscope.app/release-notes</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25026070</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 14:44:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Can we talk about failure?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 17 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25025819">thread link</a>) | @mqsley
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://www.mquinn.online/blog/can-we-talk-about-failure | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.mquinn.online/blog/can-we-talk-about-failure">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>For the longest time felt like I didn’t fail at things. I was brought up with the mindset that if something is doable, it cannot be hard. A mindset which compels you to find harder and harder challenges.</p><p>That all changed when Flex, the Techstars company I co-founded didn’t work out. It broke me.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p>What surprised me was that the network, “give first” and all of the opportunity that comes with it is great when you’re on the up but awkward, uncomfortable and at times “crickets” on the down.</p><p>Part of this I now realise is because when you’re in failure mode, you’re insufferable to everyone around you.</p><p>You carry this huge weight on your shoulders that you put on others every time you meet like a wounded animal, limping around looking to be put down.</p><p>I’m not sure if everyone has gone through this, but for me I suffered through thoughts like:<br>Will I be ever successful?<br>Will I ever be happy?<br>Will I ever have another good idea?<br>Was my idea good?<br>Can I have good Ideas?<br>Can I be good at anything?</p><p>I came to learn these can be called cognitive distortions, and the best way to stop them is to write them down and use reason and logic to disprove them.</p><p>Everyone just tells you its okay, put in their perspective, you’ll work it out - This whole experience was incredibly frustrating, how could a non founder possibly relate to the level of aspiration I had taken away from me. What is a well meaning attempt at helping often comes across as people shrugging you off.</p><p>There was a limit to what my coach could do because I convinced myself he hadn’t experienced it. How could he possibly understand what was left behind after this huge emotional debt bubble deflated.</p><p>I sought out others who’s companies had died, or who had been ousted from their own boards but it was hard to match with other failures because it was either a sufferfest of two people feeling sorry for themselves or one of you values success more than the other and you judge the others’ failure.</p><p>I didn't grieve, I tried to re-inflate the bubble inside me.</p><p>I didn’t get angry, I just wanted to get better, I just wanted to feel better without putting in the work.</p><p>I turned to reading, thinking that with over a century of modern business practices surely titans have recovered from this. Reading a gazillion business biographies, literature I now know to pop science schlop, did not help. In fact it made it worse.&nbsp;</p><p>I remember reading Lean In and it slid me into depression. How did Sheryl Sandberg career magically line up at the end? Was I on the right track? How do I get on track? Where is the track? What is the track?</p><p>I would openly talk about imposter syndrome to explain why I approached work and decisions the way I did, and came to learn that:</p><ul><li>Outside of tech many people have never heard of the concept<br></li><li>People who had, did not understand it<br></li><li>Many people thought imposter syndrome was in fact the Dunning Kruger effect and thus I was admitting to them I was a fraud.&nbsp;</li></ul><p>For me, the voices in my head eventually did die off. Normalcy came about a year later when I realised I was talking about and writing about my experiences from a perspective of wisdom rather than re-hashing scar tissue.</p><p>Serendipitously after this point, I was gifted the book - <a href="https://www.amazon.com/When-Smart-People-Fail-Rebuilding/dp/0140178112" target="_blank">When Smart People Fail </a>by another Techstars founder whose grandmother had gifted her the book after she had experienced a set back. A set back which ultimately led to the founding of her Techstars company.</p><p>Where was this book when I failed? While a subjectively unnecessary read, I read it anyway. In my personal opinion, it was probably the best thing I’ve ever read on dealing with personal failure.</p><p>I think it would have saved me months of anguish had I read it earlier, and while I truly love helping entrepreneurs and makers - my goto advice now, when someone has experienced failure and is looking for guidance is - read this book.</p><p>I think Techstars should gift this to every founder that fails, whether they leave their company, are forced out or go insolvent.</p><p>Between stories of failure, to understanding the core stages of grief that one must go through - there is something in the book for everyone.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p>Key things the book taught me:</p><ul><li>Failure is subjective to the victim</li><li>Failure has stages of grief that you must go through - if you skip any, you will experience prolonged pain. I can first hand attest to this.</li><li>If we treat success as a binary outcome, everything we sacrifice in the pursuit of success is meaningless when we fail.</li></ul><p>The third point is something I embraced over the year that followed. Clearly others think I have experience/advice/wisdom/ideas to share so there is value there and it made it all much less painful. If success is binary, those of us who don’t make it, lose many years of our lives for nothing.</p><p>This is a stance I fully reject and I thank Jen and the book for really teaching me this.</p><p>In full realisation of this final point - <a href="https://www.mquinn.online/failures.html">I’m committing to my failures in public.</a> We’ll see how long I can keep it up for, but for every project that didn’t hit the goal, the ideas that crash landed and the products that went unloved I’m keeping a record because these failures are not a waste of life, they are the stepping stones that when looking back in 20 years will all make sense.</p><p>Show me someone without failure and I’ll show you someone without learning.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p>Thanks to everyone that listened to me moan for a year about my failures.</p><p>A special thanks to fellow Techstars founder Sarah Tuneberg who gave me perspective through the journey, <span>Techstars founder&nbsp;</span>Jen Saxton who gifted me “When smart people fail” and my wife for supporting me while I put myself back together.&nbsp;</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.mquinn.online/blog/can-we-talk-about-failure</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25025819</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 13:54:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Clues to identify a destructive leader]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 247 | Comments 106 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25025363">thread link</a>) | @BossingAround
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://articles.tilt365.com/identify-destructive-leadership-patterns/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://articles.tilt365.com/identify-destructive-leadership-patterns/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-main">
    <div>

        <article>

            

            <figure>
                <img srcset="https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/size/w300/2020/11/sharks-in-the-water-1.png 300w,
                            https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/11/sharks-in-the-water-1.png 600w,
                            https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/11/sharks-in-the-water-1.png 1000w,
                            https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/11/sharks-in-the-water-1.png 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 400px,
                        (max-width: 1170px) 1170px,
                            2000px" src="https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/size/w2000/2020/11/sharks-in-the-water-1.png" alt="4 Clues to Identify a Destructive Leader">
            </figure>

            <section>
                <div>
                    <p>In many aspects of our lives, we rely on those in positions of power to lead us. The role of leaders becomes especially salient in times of uncertainty. Throughout your life, you’ve probably seen several ways leaders can respond to challenging and ambiguous situations. A transformational leader can see the opportunities in turmoil and inspire people to follow them to a better future. On the other hand, an incompetent leader will leave you to deal with everything alone. In the worst-case scenario, a destructive leader will see the potential for self-enhancement and exploit others to maximize their gain. </p><figure><img src="https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/2020/11/four-patterns-of-destructive-leadership.png" alt="" srcset="https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/size/w600/2020/11/four-patterns-of-destructive-leadership.png 600w, https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/size/w1000/2020/11/four-patterns-of-destructive-leadership.png 1000w, https://articles.tilt365.com/content/images/2020/11/four-patterns-of-destructive-leadership.png 1069w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"><figcaption>4 Clues to Identify a Destructive Leader</figcaption></figure><h3 id="people-leave-managers-not-companies-">People leave managers, not companies.</h3><p>Incompetent and destructive leaders both create negative consequences, but the distinction between the two is essential. An incompetent leader may lack the compelling charisma to engage others to follow, but we wouldn’t call someone lacking charisma actively destructive. A <a href="https://www.oxfordhandbooks.com/view/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199755615.001.0001/oxfordhb-9780199755615-e-014">destructive leader</a> intentionally and systematically behaves in a way that violates the organization’s members and stakeholders’ best interests. The extent of damage that a destructive leader can cause often goes unnoticed until it is too late (e.g., Enron), but there are clues you can look for to help you identify destructive leaders earlier. These clues reflect behaviors and attitudes that can reveal the destructive nature of an otherwise seemingly competent leader.</p><h3 id="what-causes-destructive-leadership-patterns">What causes destructive leadership patterns?</h3><p>Everyone has some characteristics that are annoying to someone who prefers a different way of behaving and working. These characteristics are inherited in our DNA and influenced by the environment in which we grew up. The genetic influence was passed down from generation to generation and is a product of evolution that helped your ancestors survive the environments they encountered. And they can help you too, as long as they don’t become distorted from early experiences of chronic fear. </p><p>In destructive leadership, typical behavior patterns become distorted into extremes powered by the brain’s more primitive parts under such circumstances. When this happens, we are in fear-mode, and a blend of fear reactions becomes our norm. These distorted patterns become habitual, and our responses to others become unhealthy. For example, suppose we experienced excessive criticism in our early development. In that case, our ego will record a perception of being diminished by important caregivers and sense that our very survival depends on not being criticized. In this case, we may learn to strive excessively for superiority to alleviate the fear of feeling inferior in our assessment of ourselves.</p><p>While a reactive pattern like this helped us survive the precise environment we were born into, in a global world, that same pattern may not. The brain’s brilliant design constructs a set of behaviors that will ensure our survival in whatever we experience in the development years to maturity. But if we move to an entirely new environment as an adult, the patterns that served us before may not translate into helpful practices somewhere else. </p><h3 id="the-reason-anxiety-and-stress-are-at-an-all-time-high-">The reason anxiety and stress are at an all-time high.</h3><p>In the last century, this phenomenon has become even more complicated. With the advancement of technology comes exposure to human systems all over the world. Transportation enables moving to any part of the globe in a day or two. As we move about rapidly from one culture to another, we find ourselves unable to understand why we are perceived positively in one environment and the opposite in another. No wonder anxiety and stress are at an all-time high, especially for those who interact in global companies. Adaptation to other cultures becomes a necessity, making self-awareness and emotional intelligence some of the most critical skill sets of our time. </p><h3 id="first-look-for-the-underlying-intention-">First, look for the underlying intention.</h3><p>Because all human systems are imperfect, and most parents do the best they can do, many of us have traces of fear behaviors that can drive others nuts. There are a few prototypical examples of these types of behaviors, including, but not limited to </p><ul><li>The constant worrier who is always second-guessing themselves,</li><li>The storyteller who seems to live in an ideal world no one else can relate to,</li><li>The dominant driver who wants everything to go their way,</li><li>The prideful judge who doesn’t realize they can’t possibly know everything there is to know about everything. </li></ul><p>When we’re talking about destructive leadership, we’re not merely referring to annoying habits unless they have become very extreme or painfully frequent. Destructive leaders have little interest in how they are perceived, so they are rarely interested in how they could improve. </p><h3 id="destructive-leaders-are-single-mindedly-self-interested-">Destructive leaders are single-mindedly self-interested.</h3><p>Generally, healthy leaders may have annoying habits, but when you look beneath the surface, two things are different: </p><ol><li>They adopt a mindset that conveys they care about their impact on others and are willing to listen, learn, and exert the choice and character to change.</li><li>They hold a positive intention toward others and work for the good of the mission and the enterprise they serve. </li></ol><p>On the other hand, destructive leaders are either:</p><ol><li>Un-coachable because they adopt a rigid mindset that conveys they don’t care about their impact on others and will use their authority to manipulate others to bend to their will. They imply, “I am who I am, so deal with it.”</li><li>They have a hidden ulterior motive for wanting and using power to serve themselves at the expense of others, the mission, or the enterprise. </li></ol><p>So, as we lay out the four clues of destructive leaders, keep two things in mind. Do you have a hunch that they are well-intended, and are they willing to work on themselves? If the answer to both is affirmative, they are probably not destructive, but just like you and me, they are trying to serve their company and grow as best they can. In these circumstances, we can mind our own business and work on our self-improvement plan rather than thinking about how annoying they are. After all, it’s temporary unless they are genuinely destructive. And then you must do everything in your power to remove them from your company, or they could take the whole thing down. </p><h3 id="clue-1-behaviors-or-words-that-imply-i-m-kind-of-a-big-deal-">Clue 1: Behaviors or words that imply “I’m kind of a big deal!”</h3><p><strong>Excessive fabrication and exaggeration that is nowhere near the truth. </strong></p><p>This destructive pattern arises from an inner identity that seeks to resolve a childhood dilemma about not getting enough attention from caregivers, so they do not feel special. This dilemma results in insatiable attention-seeking and an inflated need to be special, unique, or novel. The inner fear is feeling trapped in the loneliness or sadness of not being “special” enough to those who matter. Because they perceive being attention-deprived or unworthy, they feel shame, and it becomes so painful, they rebel from authority figures whom they believe could not be trusted. Instead of following appropriately, they become rebellious and provocative, conning others to go along with their fantastic plans. </p><h3 id="clues-you-will-notice-">Clues you will notice: </h3><ul><li>Exaggeration of the truth to the point of fantasy</li><li>Unapologetic self-promoting and self-aggrandizing</li><li>Excessive talking to dominate others</li><li>Pontification and fabrication of elaborate stories</li><li>Disrespect for authority figures</li><li>Disregard for rules that are contrary to their aims</li><li>Automatically dismiss ideas from others</li><li>An insatiable need to be the center of attention</li><li>Terminally individualistic, unique, or novel</li><li>External image is unusually extreme in some way</li></ul><h3 id="results-in-a-chaotic-climate">Results in a Chaotic Climate</h3><p>These destructive leaders are challenging to work with because they demand attention but don’t want the restrictions that come with being front and center. When they are in the limelight, it can be exceedingly uncomfortable because they also unconsciously fail to believe they are impressive enough. So they attract attention, initiate excessive activity, and then thwart the attention this draws. This pattern makes them unpredictable, so the shadow of the climate they create around them is chaotic and confusing for others. </p><h3 id="clue-2-behaviors-or-words-that-imply-none-of-this-is-my-fault-">Clue 2: Behaviors or words that imply “None of this is my fault!”</h3><p><strong>Excessive conflict-avoidance by deflecting personal responsibility. </strong></p><p>This destructive pattern arises from an inner identity that seeks to resolve a childhood dilemma about not getting enough approval and acceptance. This dilemma results in insatiable approval-seeking and an excessive need to be liked by everyone, even strangers. The inner fear is to be rejected or ridiculed by others as unlovable by those who matter. Because they perceive being unacceptable to others, they feel powerless and unworthy of care. This experience can become painful and they are unable to communicate or ask others for what they need because they don’t feel they deserve it. They defer to those in authority roles and suffer quietly in dependence, hopelessness, and seen as “needy” for any shred of approval. </p><h3 id="clues-you-will-notice--1">Clues you will notice:</h3><ul><li>Complaining, blaming, gossiping about others</li><li>Disgruntled resentment of those in authority</li><li>Giving up their power and being dependent on others</li><li>Come across as “needy” and draining</li><li>Asking others to decide and then resenting it</li><li>Avoiding leadership to avoid culpability later</li><li>Unconsciously inviting others to dominate them</li><li>Blaming others for being the “bully”</li><li>Desire to be the “nice” or “good” one</li><li>An insatiable need to be liked, accepted, included</li></ul><h3 id="results-in-a-conflict-averse-climate">Results in a Conflict Averse Climate </h3><p>These destructive leaders are challenging to work with because they put extreme energy into taking care of or helping others with an unstated expectation that there will be a reward in return. For example, they take care of someone with the expectation that the other person will take the responsibility of making decisions for them. However, they may not tell the other person this expectation. There is an unconscious …</p></div></section></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://articles.tilt365.com/identify-destructive-leadership-patterns/">https://articles.tilt365.com/identify-destructive-leadership-patterns/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://articles.tilt365.com/identify-destructive-leadership-patterns/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25025363</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 12:30:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[One Week of NixOS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 238 | Comments 153 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25024639">thread link</a>) | @jaemoe
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://jae.moe/blog/2020/11/one-week-of-nixos/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jae.moe/blog/2020/11/one-week-of-nixos/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <h4>One week of NixOS</h4><p>
            Reading time: 4 minutes.
            </p><p>As you may have seen I on Mastodon, I am testing NixOS for over a week now and here is a few comments about how the distro works and what doesn’t work for me.</p>










<p>First, everything is NixOS is declared in a configuration file located at <code>/etc/nixos/configuration.nix</code> where you declare packages you want to install, services to start, udev rules, ECT, you get it.</p>
<p>This is the first very weird thing as you don’t really install packages with the CLI directly (even if you can), instead you modify the config file and rebuild the system with <code>nixos-rebuild switch</code>.</p>
<p>NixOS is made in such a way that everything aims to be reproducible. An example: if you want to get the exact same setup as I have, you can just take <a href="https://forge.tedomum.net/jae/nixos-configs">my configs repo</a>, clone it on your NixOS installation, run <code>nixos-rebuild switch</code> and voilà, you will have the exact same programs as me installed in the same way with the same version (roughly).</p>
<p>In this distro, adding a user is really easy and goes like this:</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span> 1
</span><span> 2
</span><span> 3
</span><span> 4
</span><span> 5
</span><span> 6
</span><span> 7
</span><span> 8
</span><span> 9
</span><span>10
</span><span>11
</span><span>12
</span><span>13
</span><span>14
</span><span>15
</span><span>16
</span><span>17
</span><span>18
</span><span>19
</span><span>20
</span><span>21
</span><span>22
</span><span>23
</span><span>24
</span><span>25
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="nixos"><span>{</span> <span>config</span><span>,</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>,</span> <span>...</span> <span>}:</span>

<span>{</span>

    <span>users</span><span>.</span><span>groups</span><span>.</span><span>plugdev</span> <span>=</span> <span>{};</span>

    <span>users</span><span>.</span><span>users</span><span>.</span><span>jae</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>isNormalUser</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span><span>;</span>
        <span>extraGroups</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>"wheel"</span> <span>"docker"</span> <span>"adbusers"</span> <span>"plugdev"</span> <span>];</span>
        <span>shell</span> <span>=</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>.</span><span>zsh</span><span>;</span>
        <span>packages</span> <span>=</span> <span>with</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>;</span> <span>[</span>
            <span># Games</span>
            <span>minetest</span> <span>stepmania</span> <span>lutris-free</span> <span>pcsx2</span>
            <span># Misc audio / video / image</span>
            <span>pulseeffects</span> <span>ffmpeg-full</span> <span>obs-studio</span> <span>inkscape</span> <span>krita</span>
            <span># Useful software</span>
            <span>mumble</span> <span>qbittorrent</span> <span>libreoffice</span> <span>ledger-live-desktop</span>
            <span># Dev</span>
            <span>jetbrains</span><span>.</span><span>idea-community</span> <span>lazygit</span> <span>gnome3</span><span>.</span><span>zenity</span> <span>insomnia</span> <span>jetbrains</span><span>.</span><span>rider</span> <span>mono</span> <span>msbuild</span> <span>dotnet-sdk_3</span> <span>ganttproject-bin</span> <span>kubectx</span>
            <span># SDR</span>
            <span>rtl-sdr</span> <span>gqrx</span> <span>gpredict</span> <span>noaa-apt</span> <span>welle-io</span>
        <span>];</span>
    <span>};</span>
    <span>users</span><span>.</span><span>extraGroups</span><span>.</span><span>vboxusers</span><span>.</span><span>members</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>"jae"</span> <span>];</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div>
<p>Let’s see what everything does!</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span>1
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="nixos"> <span>users</span><span>.</span><span>groups</span><span>.</span><span>plugdev</span> <span>=</span> <span>{};</span></code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div><p>
Creates a group named <code>plugdev</code>, don’t pay attention to it, it is just a test for the Ledger Live application.</p>
<p>
Tells the os that the current user is a normal one. It will create a home folder and set the default shell.</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span>1
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="nixos"> <span>extraGroups</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span> <span>"wheel"</span> <span>"docker"</span> <span>"adbusers"</span> <span>"plugdev"</span> <span>];</span></code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div><p>
Here, we are setting the groups the user is in to grant special permissions.</p>
<p>
As you may have guessed it, we are setting the default user shell to ZSH.</p>
<div><div>
<table><tbody><tr><td>
<pre><code><span> 1
</span><span> 2
</span><span> 3
</span><span> 4
</span><span> 5
</span><span> 6
</span><span> 7
</span><span> 8
</span><span> 9
</span><span>10
</span><span>11
</span><span>12
</span></code></pre></td>
<td>
<pre><code data-lang="nixos"> <span>packages</span> <span>=</span> <span>with</span> <span>pkgs</span><span>;</span> <span>[</span>
            <span># Games</span>
            <span>minetest</span> <span>stepmania</span> <span>lutris-free</span> <span>pcsx2</span>
            <span># Misc audio / video / image</span>
            <span>pulseeffects</span> <span>ffmpeg-full</span> <span>obs-studio</span> <span>inkscape</span> <span>krita</span>
            <span># Useful software</span>
            <span>mumble</span> <span>qbittorrent</span> <span>libreoffice</span> <span>ledger-live-desktop</span>
            <span># Dev</span>
            <span>jetbrains</span><span>.</span><span>idea-community</span> <span>lazygit</span> <span>gnome3</span><span>.</span><span>zenity</span> <span>insomnia</span> <span>jetbrains</span><span>.</span><span>rider</span> <span>mono</span> <span>msbuild</span> <span>dotnet-sdk_3</span> <span>ganttproject-bin</span> <span>kubectx</span>
            <span># SDR</span>
            <span>rtl-sdr</span> <span>gqrx</span> <span>gpredict</span> <span>noaa-apt</span> <span>welle-io</span>
        <span>];</span></code></pre></td></tr></tbody></table>
</div>
</div><p>
There, we are installing per-user packages because yes, NixOS supports that, any user can have its own packages that others users can’t access.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Correction from <em>hvdijk</em> on Hacker News, “<em>Other users can access those packages if they want to. Those packages won’t show up in other users' $PATH, so other users will not be affected by them, but they could see what’s in /nix/store if they wanted to. This matters when you’re thinking of putting private data (such as an encryption key) in a package: it’s vital that you don’t do that on a multi-user system.</em>”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Configuring NixOS for a daily use is at the end very easy (although I am getting some trouble to get Ledger Live working; which is the biggest problem I’ve had so far).</p>
<p>Now, let’s talk about where I got some trouble.
As you may know it, I am a dev and every day I need to compile, test, run and so on.
NixOS gave me some trouble to only run some programs from source such as <a href="https://element.io/">Element Desktop</a> or <a href="https://img.tedomum.net/">TeDomum IMG</a> as the way the system is built, lots of directories are read-only and programs can’t be installed globally through NPM or PIP.
I ended up using Docker to build the apps (even if it took a bit more time).</p>
<p>Needless to say, almost every other project worked.
If you want NodeJS to start a project for instance, you can just do <code>nix-shell -p nodejs</code> and here you go, a shell with nodejs installed, ready to do what you want.</p>
<p>At the end, NixOS brings very interesting concepts such as a really great reproducibility but new users can feel lost as its way to work is really different from conventional Linux distributions.
I’ll give NixOS more time and write a follow-up in some time to see how everything went.</p>
<p>If you want to give it a shot, the <a href="https://nixos.org/">official NixOS website awaits you</a>!</p>
<p>That’s all for today,
I’ll see you next time!
If you like my content, <a href="https://jae.moe/blog/index.xml">don’t forget to subscribe through RSS</a>!</p>

            
                <p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25024639">Talk about it on Hacker News!</a>
            
        </p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jae.moe/blog/2020/11/one-week-of-nixos/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25024639</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 10:17:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pro Rata and User Centric Distribution Models: A Comparative Study (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 83 | Comments 85 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25024552">thread link</a>) | @iamacyborg
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | http://www.digitalmedia.fi/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/UC_report_final_171213.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.digitalmedia.fi/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/UC_report_final_171213.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.digitalmedia.fi/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/UC_report_final_171213.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25024552</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 10:01:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pongmechanik]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25024499">thread link</a>) | @remix2000
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | http://cyberniklas.de/pongmechanik/indexen.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://cyberniklas.de/pongmechanik/indexen.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://cyberniklas.de/pongmechanik/indexen.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25024499</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 09:52:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PostgreSQL Configuration for Humans]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 245 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25024224">thread link</a>) | @sharjeelsayed
<br/>
November 8, 2020 | https://postgresqlco.nf/en/doc/param/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://postgresqlco.nf/en/doc/param/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <div>
    <div id="welcome">
      
      <div lang="en">
        <h4><p>Your postgresql.conf documentation and recommendations.</p><p>Our mission is to help you tune and optimize your PostgreSQL configuration.</p><p>With around 270 configuration parameters in <span>postgresql.conf</span>, plus all the knobs in pg_hba.conf, it is definitely a difficult task!</p><p>How many parameters do you tune? 1? 8? 32? Ever tuned more than 64? We aim to make PostgreSQL configuration possible for HUMANS.</p></h4>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://postgresqlco.nf/en/doc/param/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25024224</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 08:52:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Embed Gravity programming language into your code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25023836">thread link</a>) | @creolabs
<br/>
November 7, 2020 | https://marcobambini.github.io/gravity/#/embedding | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://marcobambini.github.io/gravity/#/embedding">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://marcobambini.github.io/gravity/#/embedding</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25023836</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 07:25:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Parsing the Infamous Japanese Postal CSV]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 119 | Comments 18 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25023673">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
November 7, 2020 | https://www.dampfkraft.com/posuto.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dampfkraft.com/posuto.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dampfkraft.com/posuto.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25023673</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 06:52:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I wrote JavaScript to avoid JavaScript]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25023594">thread link</a>) | @asaaki
<br/>
November 7, 2020 | https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Web technologies have come so far, that you realize: not everything needs to be done in JavaScript nowadays anymore.</p><blockquote><p><em>»Life is really simple, but we insist on making it complicated.« — Confucius</em></p></blockquote><p>My initial headline would have been:</p><p><em>How I wrote more JavaScript in the backend to eliminate JavaScript in the frontend.</em></p><p>But that's already a mouthful and also would have revealed too much and you might not have clicked my slightly clickbait-y title, right?</p><p>So here is my Public Service Announcement:</p><p> 📣 <strong>This site does not use any frontend JavaScript.<sup>*</sup></strong></p><p><em><small>*) There are only tiny exceptions on 2 pages, but for a good reason. More on that later.</small></em></p><p>First of all I am not against JavaScript (<span>JS</span>) at all. If you're building a web <strong>application</strong>, then this is not only totally fine but most likely a core requirement.</p><p>But I do have my pet peeve with <span>JS</span> for plain websites and blogs. Currently there is still such a strong draught in the static site generator world, telling us all our sites should be some kind of React or other frontend framework based project (looking at you, Gatsby, Next, Nuxt, VuePress, …). That you need to have that plentyful of code running in the browser of your visitors to have a smooth and <em>feels like a native app</em> user experience. That a site should be a <em>Single Page Application (SPA).</em> I can tell you, a plain HTML+CSS website does it really well, too. Surprise!</p><p>While on one hand the browser vendors add more and more <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API">Web APIs</a>, we also got a lot of improvement in the HTML and CSS area. Usually there is no big hype train around them, unless you are very enthusiastic and live in that niche.</p><p>Take a look at <a href="https://caniuse.com/">caniuse.com</a> to get an idea what is possible today and what might come tomorrow. <em>Did you know that HTML5 is still iterated on and we're moving towards <a href="https://www.w3.org/TR/html53/">version 5.3</a>?</em> On the other hand »HTML 5« is also used as an umbrella term for a <a href="https://spec.whatwg.org/" title="WHATWG Standards">wide variety of standards</a>. Also for CSS the story got very interesting: while CSS until 2.1 was a single specification, since CSS 3 there is a whole potpourri of recommendations and drafts. The <a href="https://wiki.csswg.org/spec">wiki of the CSS Working Group</a> might be a good starting point for further discovery.</p><p>But I want to give you some more practical examples and an experience report:</p><h2 id="sticky-navigation-bar">Sticky navigation bar</h2><p>This is something you can observe here on this blog:</p><video autoplay="" loop="" muted="" playsinline=""><source src="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/pos-sticky.hvec.mp4" type="video/mp4; codecs=hvc1"><source src="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/pos-sticky.hvec.mp4" type="video/mp4; codecs=hevc"><source src="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/pos-sticky.h264.mp4" type="video/mp4; codecs=avc1"><source src="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/pos-sticky.webm" type="video/webm; codecs=vp9"></video><p>The key ingredient is the CSS <code>position: sticky</code> <a href="https://caniuse.com/css-sticky">🛈</a>. Even though most of them are labeled as <em>partial support,</em> this property value can be used in most scenarios except in some table related cases. If you want a sticky menu after scrolling and use only elements like <code>div</code> everything is just fine. I could throw away all the code for that after I realized that none of the common and modern browsers had any blocking issues. So I did. The only real latecomers were the web view components, no big deal for me here.</p><h3 id="before">Before</h3><h4 id="javascript">JavaScript</h4><pre><code><span>const </span><span>navbar </span><span>= </span><span>document</span><span>.querySelector(</span><span>'.navbar'</span><span>);
</span><span>let </span><span>sticky </span><span>= </span><span>navbar.offsetTop;
</span><span>const </span><span>navbarScroll </span><span>= </span><span>() </span><span>=&gt; </span><span>{
  </span><span>if </span><span>(</span><span>window</span><span>.pageYOffset </span><span>&gt;= </span><span>sticky) {
    navbar.classList.add(</span><span>'sticky'</span><span>)
  } </span><span>else </span><span>{
    navbar.classList.remove(</span><span>'sticky'</span><span>);
  }
};

</span><span>window</span><span>.onscroll </span><span>= </span><span>navbarScroll;
</span></code></pre><h4 id="stylesheet">Stylesheet</h4><pre><code><span>.navbar </span><span>{
  </span><span>position</span><span>: </span><span>relative</span><span>;
}
</span><span>.sticky </span><span>{
  </span><span>position</span><span>: </span><span>fixed</span><span>;
  </span><span>top</span><span>: </span><span>0</span><span>;
  </span><span>left</span><span>: </span><span>0</span><span>;
}
</span></code></pre><h3 id="after">After</h3><h4 id="javascript-1">JavaScript</h4><pre><code><span>// nope
</span></code></pre><h4 id="stylesheet-1">Stylesheet</h4><pre><code><span>.navbar </span><span>{
  </span><span>position</span><span>: </span><span>sticky</span><span>;
  </span><span>top</span><span>: </span><span>0</span><span>; </span><span>/* it does not reposition right away,
             but determines at which point it sticks */
</span><span>}
</span></code></pre><h3 id="resolution">Resolution</h3><p>The workaround with <span>JS</span> is no more. Yay!</p><p>Also notice how little code is actually needed now? Two CSS properties and the job is done.</p><hr><h2 id="service-workers">Service Workers</h2><p>Also in 2018 I played with <a href="https://markentier.tech/posts/2018/04/progressive-web-app/">Progressive Web Apps (PWA)</a>. The whole blog was one. A few days ago I teared down all of it. At the core of PWAs sit <a href="https://serviceworke.rs/">Service Workers (SW)</a>, though you can use SW also without building an app. And that's what I was aiming for, but in the end my home-grown dynamic cache solution was more annoying to me than helpful for anyone else. Every time I updated anything here, I had to wait and/or force refresh to see the result. I'm sure some people probably see visual inconsistencies due to a still running service worker in their browser. If you do, try to force clear all data for this website.</p><p>Long story short: if you do not build a web <strong>app</strong>, you most likely do not need service workers. So yet another thing down from the <span>JS</span> list.</p><p>No <em>before/after</em> comparison here, but several precious kilobytes of JavaScript shaved off by removing them.</p><hr><h2 id="sqip-svg-lqip">SQIP (SVG LQIP)</h2><p><em>Woa, what are all these random acronyms here?</em> Don't worry, the simple answer is:</p><p>If you have images and they are not very small in file size, you maybe want to provide a temporary placeholder with very low resolution and quality. This is pretty useful for slow internet connections; living here in Germany I know how difficult this situation can be. That thing called internet is still very Neuland to us. 🤦</p><p>Anyway, <code>SQIP</code> can be translated with »<code>SVG</code>-based <code>LQIP</code>.«</p><p><code>SVG</code> are Scalable Vector Graphics, an image format I really love a lot, my logo is done with it (<a href="https://markentier.tech/posts/2018/05/minimalism-focus-clean-redesign/">I wrote about it a while ago</a>).</p><p>LQIP finally stands for <em>»Low Quality Image Placeholders«</em> and is based on an algorithm to find primitive shapes to describe the source image. Basically try to find only a few triangles, rectangles, circles, ellipsis, and other low poly shapes. It is also an art form in its own, you can enjoy some <a href="https://github.com/fogleman/primitive#static-animation">nice examples there</a>. The advantage of SVG is that it is made to encode such figures in very few characters of human readable text, so a less complex image for a placeholder can be written in one kilobyte or less.</p><p>Compared to the original high resolution image which can easily weigh half a megabyte and more this is great. You can reserve the space in your page and very early in the loading process display some visual hint that there will be a proper picture soon. Especially for types which do not support progessive loading (as JPEG can) using SQIP/LQIP placeholders makes a lot of sense.</p><p>In this scenario at first it was not really about saving frontend <span>JS</span>, more about saving it on the backend site and replacing it with something else. Unfortunately in between some code creeped into the frontend anyway.</p><p>But what happened that this beautiful technique fell out of favor with me?</p><h3 id="picture"><code>&lt;picture&gt;</code></h3><p>Enter another interesting HTML tag combo: <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/picture"><code>&lt;picture&gt;</code></a> with <code>&lt;source&gt;</code>.</p><p>So one reason to use small low quality placeholders is because before such tags became a thing we solely relied on a single <code>&lt;img&gt;</code> and some trickery with CSS (and sometimes aided by sprinkles of JavaScript). I tried to avoid <span>JS</span> completely, but of course I had to use some styling hacks eventually.</p><p>The essence of it was some style attached to the image in question:</p><pre><code><span>&lt;</span><span>img </span><span>src</span><span>=</span><span>"highres-and-heavy.png"
     </span><span>style</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>background-size</span><span>: </span><span>cover</span><span>;
            </span><span>background-image</span><span>: </span><span>url</span><span>(</span><span>'data:image/svg+xml;base64,PHN2…'</span><span>);</span><span>"</span><span>&gt;
</span><span>&lt;!-- Usually in some post processing all style attributes were collected
     into a &lt;style&gt; tag or CSS file. --&gt;
</span></code></pre><p>The JavaScript entered this scenery at one point: after I used images with transparency. Sadly with this background image workaround you would've seen the low quality placeholder through the transparent parts, and this was extremly ugly to be honest. I could not stand it and deployed some snippet to trigger a background removal once the actual image was loaded:</p><pre><code><span>// remove the background image styling, so transparent images won't have
// strange SQIP artefacts shining through
</span><span>document</span><span>.querySelectorAll(
  </span><span>"img[loading=lazy][class]:not(.thumbnail):not(.loaded)"
</span><span>).forEach((</span><span>img</span><span>) </span><span>=&gt; </span><span>{
  </span><span>img</span><span>.</span><span>onload </span><span>= </span><span>(</span><span>_event</span><span>) </span><span>=&gt; </span><span>img.className </span><span>= </span><span>"loaded"</span><span>;
});
</span><span>document</span><span>.querySelectorAll(
  </span><span>"img[loading=lazy].thumbnail:not(.loaded)"
</span><span>).forEach((</span><span>img</span><span>) </span><span>=&gt; </span><span>{
  </span><span>img</span><span>.</span><span>onload </span><span>= </span><span>(</span><span>_event</span><span>) </span><span>=&gt; </span><span>img.className </span><span>= </span><span>"thumbnail loaded"</span><span>;
});
</span></code></pre><p>Theoretically it would have been tolerable, but I noticed some strange behaviour once I started wrapping my images into <code>picture</code> tags.</p><p>Let's <a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/yak_shaving">shave the yak</a> a bit further to understand why.</p><h4 id="webp-and-avif">WEBP and AVIF</h4><p><em>Come on, more acronyms?</em> I'm sorry, the web is a place with a lot of them.</p><p>All you need to know for now is that both of them are pretty modern image formats with quite good (lossy) compression rates while keeping a respectable quality. <a href="https://caniuse.com/webp"><code>WEBP</code></a> has been around for some time and most of the browsers do support it. <a href="https://caniuse.com/avif"><code>AVIF</code></a> is extremly new and right now only Chrome since version 85 and Opera 71 can display them. Firefox has a configuration flag, maybe they will enable it by default pretty soon.</p><p>So the current situation is that I have my original image (PNG or JPEG in most cases), a WEBP version, an AVIF version, and the SQIP placeholder. How do I deal with it? Back to our <code>&lt;picture&gt;</code> tag:</p><pre><code><span>&lt;</span><span>picture</span><span>&gt;
  &lt;</span><span>source </span><span>srcset</span><span>=</span><span>"./cover.avif" </span><span>type</span><span>=</span><span>"image/avif"</span><span>&gt;
  &lt;</span><span>source </span><span>srcset</span><span>=</span><span>"./cover.webp" </span><span>type</span><span>=</span><span>"image/webp"</span><span>&gt;
  &lt;</span><span>img </span><span>src</span><span>=</span><span>"./cover.png"
       </span><span>style</span><span>=</span><span>"</span><span>/* SQIP data: see example above */</span><span>"</span><span>&gt;
&lt;/</span><span>picture</span><span>&gt;
</span></code></pre><p>You can also use source sets for different view sizes based on media queries, but in my case I'm mainly concerned about supporting different image formats. My idea is to prioritize the formats with the smallest file size first, and given the compression ratios the order is usually: AVIF, WEBP, PNG/JPG. Not in every case will this be true; WEBP does not always have better savings then a decently compressed JPEG for example. AVIF has not disappointed so far, but sadly a part of my visitors will not see the effect yet.</p><p>What did not really happen anymore was a display of the placeholder before the final image was loaded. I experimented for quite some time until I realized that I do not want to spent more energy any further.</p><p><picture><source srcset="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/sizes-png-webp-avif.w.avif" type="image/avif"><source srcset="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/sizes-png-webp-avif.w.webp" type="image/webp"><img src="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/sizes-png-webp-avif.w.png" alt="Size comparison of an example image; PNG original (22 KB), WEBP (14 KB, 37% saved), AVIF (7.3 KB, 67% saved)" width="1024" height="120" loading="lazy"></picture></p><p>I made a <em>risk-return tradeoff</em> compromise and got rid of SQIP altogether. For the growing number of AVIF support the images are sometimes significantly smaller which makes it acceptable to allow for some display delay anyway.</p><p>In the following screenshot the JPEG was the source photo. The PNG was created for some transparency stuff; of course, for photos this format does not really make a lot of sense in general. Sadly also WEBP fails to compete in this scenario. That's why I have to make this picture group generation a bit smarter soon to reorder based on the actual file …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/">https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://markentier.tech/posts/2020/10/wrote-javascript-to-avoid-javascript/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25023594</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 06:30:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Stack Videos Horizontally, Vertically, in a Grid With FFmpeg]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 215 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25022665">thread link</a>) | @rrao84
<br/>
November 7, 2020 | https://ottverse.com/stack-videos-horizontally-vertically-grid-with-ffmpeg/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ottverse.com/stack-videos-horizontally-vertically-grid-with-ffmpeg/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<figure>
<img src="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/stacking-videos.png?resize=678%2C381&amp;ssl=1" alt="stack videos using ffmpeg" title="stacking-videos" data-src="https://i0.wp.com/ottverse.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/stacking-videos.png?resize=678%2C381&amp;ssl=1" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==">
</figure>


<p>Often times, when you want to compare two videos side-by-side or you want to create an effect during post-processing, you might want to stack videos together. It can get expensive if you end up buying a tool to do this, but, guess what? </p>



<p><strong>FFmpeg offers a variety of tools to help stack videos together – horizontally, vertically, or in a grid fashion. In this tutorial, let’s learn about FFmpeg’s <code>hstack</code> and <code>vstack</code> filters for stacking videos. </strong></p>



<hr>




<h2><span id="How_to_Stack_Videos_Horizontally_using_FFmpeg"></span><strong>How to Stack Videos Horizontally using FFmpeg?</strong><span></span></h2>



<p>“Horizontally stacking videos” refers to placing videos side-by-side (one on the left and the other on the right). </p>



<p>Before you do this, there are a couple of points that you need to consider. </p>



<ol><li>The videos that you want to stack need to have the same height. </li><li> The videos need to have the same pixel format. </li></ol>



<p>The command line is shown below where we try and stack two <code>mp4</code> videos. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg -i input0.mp4 -i input1.mp4&nbsp;-filter_complex hstack=inputs=2 horizontal-stacked-output.mp4</code></pre>



<p>The <code>hstack</code> filter has a simple format. You need to specify the number of inputs and it parses that from the beginning portion of the commandline. The order of stacking follows the order of inputs. </p>



<p>Here is a screenshot of what it looks like. </p>



<figure><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/4FwbqByqDpDpOGTNvpSWSOh6RVE9yzesrQyAyGvaOF1ZjVsycKOlQUjrTmdJRFJWblHjC9gF6zMds0s5w2Yy2w6CVXXme-H-zF8nYoJ496khN0aHXHaWbnwEe41BYmu6c2mdoQb8" alt="stack videos using ffmpeg" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>And, here is a video! </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475731721" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>







<p>Here is another use case. Companies or teams working on video compression often like to compare videos side-by-side in the lab or showcase their work in conferences. FFmpeg’s horizontal stacking is an easy way to do this and achieve a very good result. </p>



<p>Below are two videos encoded at different video quality settings and stacked horizontally. Comparison made simple, right? <em>(note: Vimeo’s choise of bitrate might mess with the comparison, but, when done offline (downloaded), the <code>hstack</code> filter makes comparisons easy!)</em></p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/476095363" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2><span id="Stacking_Videos_Vertically_using_FFmpeg"></span><strong>Stacking Videos Vertically using FFmpeg</strong><span></span></h2>



<p>“Vertically stacked videos” results in placing videos one below the other. Unlike in horizontal stacking, inputs need to be having the same width. The command is as shown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For vertical stacking, we need to use the <code>vstack</code> filter whose syntax is similar to the <code>hstack</code> filter we used in the previous horizontal stacking example.</p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg -i input0.mp4 -i input1.mp4&nbsp;-filter_complex vstack=inputs=2 vertical-stack-output.mp4</code></pre>



<figure><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/qtyxioWFR54pqwZhX7jgX6HkSG7gCw840GdK78HGHHP7X3sv3fr3Pou9hOMFu2O-e6O7nmCith3U6CM1SpDanhwmIFIBzZUQyaG4T0BJaF9QCdMIPrmMmH0qc9WTK5f-5Nf4-92y" alt="stack videos using ffmpeg" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>



<p>Both functions pretty much use the same commands with a simple distinction, the <a href="https://ffmpeg.org/ffmpeg-filters.html#hstack" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>hstack</code></a> and the <a href="https://ffmpeg.org/ffmpeg-filters.html#vstack" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>vstack</code></a> under the <code>-filter_complex</code> argument.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here’s a video of stacking two videos vertically using FFmpeg. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475731607" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2><span id="Stacking_Videos_of_Different_Lengths"></span><strong>Stacking Videos of Different Lengths</strong><span></span></h2>



<p>Well, there’s a really nifty ability for both of these to prioritize the length of the shortest video. And as luck would have it the parameter is named <code>shortest</code>, and it’s applicable to both the horizontal and vertical stacking filters. Using <code>shortest=1</code> ensures the shortest length is used. </p>



<p>For example – </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg -i input0.mp4 -i input1.mp4 -filter_complex hstack=inputs=2:shortest=1 shortest-output.mp4</code></pre>



<p>As a <b>side note</b>, if you run into an error that claims frames are being duplicated, the easiest workaround is to slip the <code>vsync 2</code> parameter into your command, and it worked like a charm.</p>



<h3><span id="Stacking_Videos_of_Different_Lengths_Without_the_shortest_parameter"></span>Stacking Videos of Different Lengths Without the <code>shortest</code> parameter<span></span></h3>



<p>To test what happens in this situation, let’s stack two videos vertically – a 10 second clip and an 18 second clip. You’ll see that the shorter clip just stops after it completes, but the output video continues till the longest of the input clips complete.  </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475731684" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>











<p>If you want to truncate the clips to the length of the shortest clip, then you need to use the <code>shortest=1</code> parameter. Let’s look at that in the next section.</p>



<h3><span id="Stacking_Videos_of_Different_Lengths_With_the_shortest=1_parameter"></span>Stacking Videos of Different Lengths With the <code>shortest=1</code> parameter<span></span></h3>



<p>In this example, we use the <code>shortest=1</code> command-line parameter and as you can see, the length of the final video is truncated to the length of the shortest of the inputs. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475731643" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2><span id="2%C3%972_Grid_of_Videos_using_FFmpeg"></span><strong><strong>2×2 Grid of Videos using FFmpeg</strong></strong><span></span></h2>



<p>We can achieve a 2×2 grid of videos using a combination of the <code>hstack</code> and <code>vstack</code> filters. Let’s start by looking at the command-line and then break it down. It’s actually pretty simple! </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg \
-i input0.mp4 -i input1.mp4 -i input2.mp4 -i input3.mp4 \
-filter_complex \
"[0:v][1:v]hstack=inputs=2[top]; \
[2:v][3:v]hstack=inputs=2[bottom]; \
[top][bottom]vstack=inputs=2[v]" \
-map "[v]" \
finalOutput.mp4</code></pre>



<p>What’s happening here?</p>



<ul><li>firstly, you need to provide 4 input videos with the same height and width</li><li>next, you stack the first two videos horizontally and call it “top” i.e. <code>[0:v][1:v]hstack=inputs=2[top]</code></li><li>then, you you stack the next two videos horizontally and call it “bottom” i.e. <code>[2:v][3:v]hstack=inputs=2[bottom]</code></li><li>then, you stack <code>top</code> and <code>bottom</code> vertically to create a 2×2 grid. — <code>[top][bottom]vstack=inputs=2[v]</code></li><li>then using the <code>map</code> command, we can extract and push the video track to the output container. </li></ul>



<p>Here is what the video looks like. </p>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475771172" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2><span id="3%C3%972_Grid_of_Videos_using_FFmpeg"></span><strong>3×2 Grid of Videos using FFmpeg</strong><span></span></h2>



<p>Along the same lines, here is a 3×2 grid of videos using <code>hstack</code> and <code>vstack</code> filters. </p>



<pre><code>ffmpeg \
-i input0.mp4 -i input1.mp4 \
-i input2.mp4 -i input3.mp4 \
-i input4.mp4 -i input5.mp4 \
-filter_complex \
"[0:v][1:v][2:v]hstack=inputs=3[top];\
[3:v][4:v][5:v]hstack=inputs=3[bottom];\
[top][bottom]vstack=inputs=2[v]" \
-map "[v]" \
finalOutput.mp4</code></pre>



<p><iframe frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" data-src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/475780643" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw=="></iframe></p>



<hr>



<h2><span id="Conclusion"></span>Conclusion<span></span></h2>



<p>That’s it folks. Now you know how to stack videos together horizontally, vertically, and in a grid. This is very useful in comparing videos and also creating fun effects along the way! </p>



<p>If you enjoyed this post, do check out the rest of<a href="https://ottverse.com/category/ffmpeg/"> <strong>OTTVerse’s FFmpeg tutorials</strong></a> to learn more about this amazing media editing and compression software!  </p>

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ottverse.com/stack-videos-horizontally-vertically-grid-with-ffmpeg/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25022665</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 03:36:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
