<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 10]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 10. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 12:30:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-10.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 12:30:20 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Things I Learned to Become a Senior Software Engineer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24397269">thread link</a>) | @janvdberg
<br/>
September 7, 2020 | https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>In 2018, I started working at Bloomberg. Things have changed a lot since. I’m not the most junior member in the company anymore and I’ve mentored quite a few new engineers, which has been amazing. It helped me observe how others differ from me, absorb their best practices, and figure out things I’ve unconsciously been doing pretty well.</p>

<p>Yearly work reviews are a good way to condense these lessons I’ve learned.  They’re valuable for pattern matching, too. Only when I zoom out do certain patterns become visible. I can then <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/the-human-log.html">start tracking these patterns consciously</a>.</p>

<p>The broad theme for this year is zooming out and challenging the boundaries. It’s also about zooming in, and adding nuance to the sections from last year. It’s more fun if you’ve <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/year-in-review-2019.html">read last year’s review first</a>: You can then diff my growth.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2">1</a></sup></p>

<p>It all began with a question: How do I grow further?</p>





<nav>

  <h4>Table of Contents</h4>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction" id="markdown-toc-growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction">Growing using different ladders of abstraction</a></li>
  <li><a href="#learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing" id="markdown-toc-learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing">Learning what people around me are doing</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#learning-good-habits-of-mind" id="markdown-toc-learning-good-habits-of-mind">Learning good habits of mind</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#thinking-well" id="markdown-toc-thinking-well">Thinking Well</a></li>
      <li><a href="#strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective" id="markdown-toc-strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective">Strategies for making day-to-day more effective</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#acquiring-new-tools-for-thought--mental-models" id="markdown-toc-acquiring-new-tools-for-thought--mental-models">Acquiring new tools for thought &amp; mental models</a></li>
  <li><a href="#protect-your-slack" id="markdown-toc-protect-your-slack">Protect your slack</a></li>
  <li><a href="#ask-questions" id="markdown-toc-ask-questions">Ask Questions</a></li>
  <li><a href="#noticing-confusion" id="markdown-toc-noticing-confusion">Noticing Confusion</a></li>
  <li><a href="#force-multipliers" id="markdown-toc-force-multipliers">Force multipliers</a></li>
  <li><a href="#on-ownership" id="markdown-toc-on-ownership">On Ownership</a></li>
  <li><a href="#embrace-fear" id="markdown-toc-embrace-fear">Embrace fear</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#adding-nuance" id="markdown-toc-adding-nuance">Adding nuance</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#writing-code" id="markdown-toc-writing-code">Writing Code</a></li>
      <li><a href="#testing" id="markdown-toc-testing">Testing</a></li>
      <li>
<a href="#design" id="markdown-toc-design">Design</a>        <ul>
          <li><a href="#gathering-requirements" id="markdown-toc-gathering-requirements">Gathering Requirements</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#some-hacks-that-have-worked-very-well-for-me" id="markdown-toc-some-hacks-that-have-worked-very-well-for-me">Some hacks that have worked very well for me</a></li>
  <li><a href="#super-powers" id="markdown-toc-super-powers">Super powers</a></li>
  <li>
<a href="#some-gotchas-with-growing" id="markdown-toc-some-gotchas-with-growing">Some gotchas with growing</a>    <ul>
      <li><a href="#sometimes-i-feel-i-need-to-know-the-answer-to-everything" id="markdown-toc-sometimes-i-feel-i-need-to-know-the-answer-to-everything">Sometimes, I feel I need to know the answer to everything</a></li>
      <li><a href="#sometimes-i-lose-my-cool" id="markdown-toc-sometimes-i-lose-my-cool">Sometimes, I lose my cool</a></li>
      <li><a href="#neophilia" id="markdown-toc-neophilia">Neophilia</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a href="#questions" id="markdown-toc-questions">Questions</a></li>
</ul>

</nav>

<!-- works only once jQuery is loaded -->


<h2 id="growing-using-different-ladders-of-abstraction">Growing using different ladders of abstraction</h2>

<p>Entering my second year, I had all the basics in place. I had picked all the low hanging fruit, and my rate of growth slowed down. Not good. The big question in my mind was “How do I grow further?”</p>

<p>There was only so much I could do to improve my coding skills. Most blogs epousing techniques to write cleaner code, repeating yourself, not repeating yourself, etc. are micro-optimisations. Almost none of them would make me instantly impactful.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3">2</a></sup></p>

<p>However, I did figure out something insightful. I’m working inside the software development lifecycle, but this lifecycle is part of a bigger lifecycle: the product and infrastructure development lifecycle. I decided to go broader instead of deeper. Surprisingly, the breadth provided more depth to what I knew.</p>

<p>I zoomed out in 3 broad directions: learning what people around me are doing, learning good habits of mind, and acquiring new tools for thought.</p>

<h2 id="learning-what-people-around-me-are-doing">Learning what people around me are doing</h2>

<p>Since we’re not in a closed system, it makes sense to better understand the job of the product managers, the sales people, and the analysts. In the end it’s a business making money through products. The goal isn’t to write code, it’s to be a profitable business.<sup id="fnref:15"><a href="#fn:15">3</a></sup></p>

<p>Most big companies aren’t doing just one thing, which means there are different paths to making money in the same company. Everyone is on at least one path - if they weren’t, they wouldn’t be here.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">4</a></sup> Tracking these paths, and the path I’m on was pretty valuable. It helped me see how I matter, and what levers I can pull to become more effective. Sometimes, it’s about making the sales jobs easier, so they can make more sales. Other times, it’s about building a new feature for clients. And some other times, it’s about improving a feature that keeps breaking.</p>

<p>Product managers are the best source for this. They know how the business makes money, who are the clients, and what do clients need.</p>

<p>Over the year, I setup quite a few meetings with everyone on my path. A second benefit this gave me was the context of other’s jobs. It helped me communicate better. Framing things in the right way is powerful.</p>

<p>For example, one conversation helped me appreciate why Sarah in Sales wants a bulk update tool. Some companies have lots of employees, and  updating them one by one is a pain. The code I write would literally ease Sarah’s pain.</p>

<!-- More recently, I got a chance to sit in on a few product scoping meetings between teams. This gave me a lot more appreciation for the job my PM and TLs do. Communication is surprisingly hard, and aligning different teams takes skill. -->

<!-- Force multiplier in team vs force multiplier in the entire chain. -->

<h2 id="learning-good-habits-of-mind">Learning good habits of mind</h2>

<p>Software engineering entails thinking well and making the right decisions. Programming is implementing those decisions.</p>

<p>A habit of mind is something your brain does regularly. This could be thinking of X whenever you see Y happen, or applying thinking tool X to problem Y. In short, habits of mind facilitate better thinking.</p>

<p>I suspected if I learn the general skill, I should be able to apply it better to software engineering.</p>

<h3 id="thinking-well">Thinking Well</h3>

<p>Software engineering is an excellent field to practice thinking well in. The feedback loops are shorter, and gauging correctness doesn’t take too long.</p>

<p>I dived into cognitive science studies. It’s a permanent skill that’s worth exploring - a force multiplier for whatever I end up doing, and pays dividends throughout my life. One output was <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/Bayes-Theorem-Framework-for-Critical-Thinking.html">a framework for critical thinking</a>. It’s compounding, <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/year-in-review-2019.html#compounding-is-powerful-building-intuition-for-compounding-even-more-so">and compounding is powerful</a>.</p>

<p>There’s lots of good things that came out of this, which I’ll talk about in a bit. They deserve their own section.</p>

<h3 id="strategies-for-making-day-to-day-more-effective">Strategies for making day-to-day more effective</h3>

<p>The other side of the coin is habits that allow you to think well. It starts with noticing little irritations during the day, inefficiencies in meetings, and then figuring out strategies to avoid them. These strategic improvements are underrated.</p>

<p>You decide what to do, and then let it run on automatic, freeing up the brain to think of more fun stuff. Of course, that’s what a habit is, too.</p>

<p>Some good habits I’ve noticed:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Never leave a meeting without making the decision / having a next action</li>
  <li>Decide who is going to get it done. Things without an owner rarely get done.</li>
  <li>Document design decisions made during a project</li>
</ul>

<p>This pattern became visible during the review, so I’m keen to pay attention and collect more strategies next year. Having an excellent scrum master who holds me accountable has helped me get better at following these strategies.</p>



<p>New tools for thought are related to thinking well, but more specific to software engineering. Tools for thought help me think better about specific engineering problems.</p>

<p>I’ve adopted a just-in-time approach to this. I look for new tools only when I get stuck on something, or when I find out my abstractions and design decisions aren’t working well.</p>

<p>For example, I was recently struggling with a domain with lots of complex business logic. Edge cases were the norm, and we wanted to design a system that handles this cleanly. That’s when I read about <a href="https://amzn.to/2FdCYUQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Domain Driven Design</a><sup id="fnref:25"><a href="#fn:25">5</a></sup>. I could instantly put it to practice and make a big difference. Subsequently, I grasped these concepts better. I acquired a new mental model of how to create enterprise software.</p>

<p>The second way I keep learning and acquiring new mental models is via reading what surfaces on Hacker News. They are interesting ideas, some of which I’ve put to practice, but this is a lot less effective than the technique above. The only reason I still do this is to <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/rationality.html#map-and-the-territory">map the territory</a> - it keeps me aware of techniques that exist, so when I face a problem, I know there’s a method that might help.</p>

<p>The final way I acquire better mental models is by learning new diverse languages. The diversity bit is important. Learning yet another dialect of lisp has a lot less benefit than say, learning C++03, a functional programming language, a dynamic typed language, and a lisp. Today, <a href="https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/j-notation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">J seems interesting</a>, and one I might consider learning. It’s a thinking model I haven’t used before.</p>

<p>I’ve gotten lots of value from doing this. Each language has its own vocabulary and grammar, and <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/vocabulary-mental-model.html">vocabulary is a meta-mental model</a>. It’s a new lens to look at how to do things.</p>

<p>When memory management is in your control, you understand how pointers and allocators work. When Python then abstracts this away, you appreciate the complexity reduction. When maps and filters in a functional language show up, you appreciate how Python’s for loops can be improved. Indeed, that’s what list comprehensions are. And then you notice how some things are easier with object oriented programming. There’s no one magic tool that fits everything well. And then you understand that despite this, you don’t have to switch tools. You can adapt best practices from one into another to solve your problems: like writing functional javascript. It’s the principles that matter more than their expression.</p>

<figure>
    
    <img src="https://neilkakkar.com/assets/images/divider.jpg" alt="">
    
    
    
</figure>

<p>Broadly, that’s all I did this year. What follow are insights that sprang forth thanks to zooming out.</p>

<h2 id="protect-your-slack">Protect your slack</h2>

<p>When I say slack, I don’t mean the company, but the adjective.</p>

<p>One thing that gives me high output and productivity gains is to “slow down”. Want to get more done? Slow down.</p>

<p>Caveats apply, but here’s what I mean:</p>

<p>I’ve noticed people rush to solve problems. It can be something they’ve done before, or something we have a template for. It feels pretty good to smash through things. I’ve done that before, too! However, there’s very specific cases where this makes sense.<sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11">6</a></sup></p>

<p>Whenever I’m working on something new, I take the time to learn things about the system I’m working on, and things closely related to it. If it’s too massive, I optimise for learning as much as I can. Every time I revisit the system, I aim to learn more.</p>

<p>When <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/yLLkWMDbC9ZNKbjDG/slack" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there is slack</a>, you get a chance to experiment, learn, and think things through. This means you get enough time to get things done.</p>

<p>When there is no slack, deadlines are tight, and all your focus goes into getting shit done.</p>

<p>Protecting your slack means not letting deadlines wrap tight around you. Usually, this is as simple (or hard) as communicating.<sup id="fnref:16"><a href="#fn:16">7</a></sup></p>

<p>Slack might have a negative connotation with “slackers”, but protecting slack is a super power. It’s a long term investment into building yourself up at the cost of short term efficiency.</p>

<p>When I’m quickly dishing out stories, I also have a much harder time fixing bugs. I don’t take the time to create proper mental models of the system, which means my assumptions don’t match the code, and this mismatch is where most bugs lie.</p>

<p>I protect my slack, so I can take the time out to prioritise …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html">https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://neilkakkar.com/things-I-learned-to-become-a-senior-software-engineer.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24397269</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 07:11:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Never Lose a Part Again, with the Ultimate Component Storage System]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24396611">thread link</a>) | @kevinqqsam
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://www.hackster.io/news/never-lose-a-part-again-with-the-ultimate-component-storage-system-00987cde6744 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hackster.io/news/never-lose-a-part-again-with-the-ultimate-component-storage-system-00987cde6744">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><section><div><p><span>The creator of </span><a href="https://www.instructables.com/id/The-Ultimate-Component-Storage-System/" rel="nofollow">this project</a><span>, APTechnologies, came up with the idea for the storage cabinet by observing that he would run into trouble when organizing his component library. Rather than having to go across the workshop to get each part, he wanted a way to consolidate everything into one place for easy finding. The system works by first having the user search for a part on an adjacent screen, and then the associated bin will light up if the component is found in the system.</span></p><h3 id="toc-designing-the-cabinet-0"><a href="#toc-designing-the-cabinet-0"><i></i></a><span>Designing the Cabinet</span></h3><p>The storage solution is comprised of a 35 x 12 grid of drawers, which gives ample space for parts. The drawers are laid out according to the spacing between the LEDs in the strip (30 LEDs/meter). They are meant to be printed individually and then slotted in, plus they come in several different sizes.</p><h3 id="toc-fabrication-1"><a href="#toc-fabrication-1"><i></i></a><span>Fabrication</span></h3><p>Each drawer was 3D-printed on a Prusa Mk2S with PLA filament at a .2mm layer height. In order to minimize filament consumption, wall thicknesses are kept very thin, but even with this savings, 5kg of filament was required to fabricate the parts. There is also a small articulating arm that juts out from the side for the HDMI display.</p><h3 id="toc-software-2"><a href="#toc-software-2"><i></i></a><span>Software</span></h3><p>The primary way to interact with the system is through the terminal, which runs a Python 3 script. It begins by checking the text file for data integrity, where it then gets parsed and loaded into an object. Data is stored in CSV-style fashion, with the ID being the first column, the associated LEDs in the second, and finally the quantity in the third column. All subsequent values are optional and simply loaded by the user when the parts is located. A regex is used to parse the user's request, including searching for a component, changing its quantity, adding a new part, and removing a component.</p><h3 id="toc-electronics-3"><a href="#toc-electronics-3"><i></i></a><span>Electronics</span></h3><p>According to the project's creator, the choice for hardware components was quite straightforward. He used a Raspberry Pi 4 Model B in conjunction with a generic HDMI monitor to show the command line interface. For power delivery, he opted for a simple 5V adapter to power both the Raspberry Pi 4 and NeoPixel strip. Since the Pi outputs 3.3v signals from its GPIO pins, a level-shifter is needed, in this case a 74AHCT125. There is an option to use an Arduino Uno via UART if the NeoPixel strip is too unreliable, since the Arduino Uno can supply stricter timings.</p><h3 id="toc-usage-4"><a href="#toc-usage-4"><i></i></a><span>Usage</span></h3><p><span>To add a new part, the command </span><code>PI&lt;ledn&gt;:PI&lt;ledn+k&gt;, &lt;quantity&gt;[, optional parameters]:add</code><span> is sent, which adds a new component to the library. Other commands such as ID&lt;id number&gt; (search for part by ID) and ID&lt;id number&gt;:rm (remove part with that ID) exist to manage added components in the library.</span></p><h3 id="toc-possible-additions-5"><a href="#toc-possible-additions-5"><i></i></a><span>Possible Additions</span></h3><p>Although the system works well for one place and a small collection of components, it tends to scale poorly when there's a large library or multiple users want to interact with it. One way to solve this issue is to replace the single text file with a relational database such as MySQL, where parts can be stored and indexed in a single table, and other data can be referenced. This gives a very powerful interface for the software to easily search, add, and modify parts without having to read and rewrite the text file constantly.</p></div></section><section></section><div><div><a href="https://www.hackster.io/gatoninja236"></a><div><p><span><a href="https://www.hackster.io/gatoninja236">Arduino “having11” Guy</a><span></span></span></p><p>18 year-old IoT and embedded systems enthusiast. Also an interned at Hackster.io and love working on projects and sharing knowledge.</p></div></div></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hackster.io/news/never-lose-a-part-again-with-the-ultimate-component-storage-system-00987cde6744</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24396611</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 04:21:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[My thoughts about editors in 2020]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 36 | Comments 48 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395863">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><h2><em>editor, vim, neovim, atom, vs-code, emacs, intellij-idea</em></h2><h2>2020-09-07 00:03:00 UTC, by Dimitri Sabadie — <a href="https://phaazon.net/blog/feed">feed</a></h2><hr><div><p>I have been trying a lot of editors lately. When I say “trying”, I really meant I spent some time configuring and using those editors. The ones I spent time using are:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://neovim.io/">neovim</a>, my main, daily editor I use for pretty much almost all projects I work on.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/idea">IntelliJ IDEA</a>, that I currently use at work to hack on Java codebases.</li>
<li><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">VS Code</a>, that I have been trying mainly in Rust, TOML and Markdown.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs">emacs</a>, that I highly hacked around to play on my Haskell and Rust codebases (and YAML / Markdown / TOML too).</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/hlissner/doom-emacs">DOOM Emacs</a>, that I tried when I saw a colleague in a previous company I worked in (I was impressed by the “united” feeling of the UI and by how everything looked so slick). So I gave it a try.</li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/">atom</a>, <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a>’s take on editors. Same thing, mostly Rust, Haskell, etc.</li>
<li>A bunch of others that I won’t talk about because I quickly stopped using.</li>
</ul>
<p>The goal of this article is to create a temporal “snapshot” of my views on editors and what I think about the current situation. I have been using vim and especially neovim for more than a decade. I need to explain about my current workflow and what I cherish in editing before talking about each editors. Expect a point of view from a neovimer which is looking around at lots of editors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is only a personal workflow / point of view that works well <em>for me right now</em>. It doesn’t mean it will for you and it doesn’t mean a different workflow would be worse.</p>
</blockquote>
<!-- vim-markdown-toc GFM -->
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-think-powerful-editing-should-be">What I think powerful editing should be</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#keyboard-layout">Keyboard layout</a></li>
<li><a href="#modal-editors">Modal editors</a></li>
<li><a href="#how-i-like-to-move-around">How I like to move around</a></li>
<li><a href="#all-the-other-modal-candies">All the other modal candies</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#the-editors">The editors</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#neovim">neovim</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#my-neovim-setup">My neovim setup</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-neovim">What I like about neovim</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-neovim">What I dislike about neovim</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#intellij-idea">IntelliJ IDEA</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-intellij-idea">What I like about IntelliJ IDEA</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-intellij-idea">What I dislike about IntelliJ IDEA</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#vs-code">VS Code</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-vs-code">What I like about VS Code</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-vs-code">What I dislike about VS Code</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#emacs-and-doom-emacs">emacs and DOOM emacs</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-emacs--doom-emacs">What I like about emacs / DOOM emacs</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-emacs--doom-emacs">What I dislike about emacs / DOOM Emacs</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#atom">atom</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#what-i-like-about-atom">What I like about atom</a></li>
<li><a href="#what-i-dislike-about-atom">What I dislike about atom</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="#wrap-it-up">Wrap it up</a></li>
</ul>
<!-- vim-markdown-toc -->

<h2 id="keyboard-layout">Keyboard layout</h2>
<p>I am French and I’m using a keyboard layout that is made to type very quickly in French and to code. With hindsight, since I type more often in English than in French, maybe I should have picked another keyboard layout, but the coding experience in my keyboard layout is really great, so I stick around.</p>
<p>The keyboard layout is <strong>bépo</strong>. I learned bépo the “recommended” way — i.e.&nbsp;you have to practice <em>typing</em> (« dactylographie » in French). It means that I use all my fingers to type on a keyboard, and that each key on the keyboard is assigned <em>a single finger</em> that will press it. That helps a lot with muscle memory and to reduce wrist pain (my wrists barely move when I type on a keyboard), among other things. The typing speed is a side-effect of being accurate and having good comfort (if you are curious, I’m pretty fast but there are faster people — I type at around 120 to 130 words per minute). Because I think the speed doesn’t matter when programming, I think the most important part to remember here is the comfort: the wrists don’t move and my fingers fly around the keyboard, whatever the speed.</p>
<h2 id="modal-editors">Modal editors</h2>
<p>I think a modal editor is superior, for various reasons. The first one is that I truly <strong>hate</strong> having to use a <em>mouse</em> for something that can be done without having to move around hundred of pixels with your cursor and clicking on buttons. For instance, running an application, on my current machines, is simply typing <code>alt d</code>, the name of the program (I typically use completion, so I never type fully the name of the program) and hit enter. All this without moving my hands from the keyboard. And I do that for programs like <code>firefox</code>, <code>kdenlive</code>, etc. but for terminal applications, I simply type and complete them in my terminal, which I open simply with <code>alt return</code>.</p>
<p>So, using a mouse to move around a cursor in an editor feels like completely suboptimal to me, especially because we write code (i.e.&nbsp;we type on a keyboard) most of the time, so moving around with the mouse implies several back and forth movements between the keyboard and the mouse. Maybe you don’t care and it’s cool to you, but to me, this is truly <em>horror land</em>. I feel <em>very</em> uncomfortable when doing this.</p>
<p>Also, <em>modern editors</em> that are not modal typically make people move by using the arrows keys, which are either far on your keyboard, or — like my keyboard, a 60% home made one — not in direct access and then require a function key to enable them.</p>
<p>So that’s the first reason why I like modal editors. They make a smarter use of your keyboard for simple yet recurrent features, like moving around — e.g.&nbsp;<code>h j k l</code>. The second reason why I like them is because of the facts they have a completely new mode for non-modal editor (i.e.&nbsp;the <em>normal</em> mode), you have a whole keyboard / lots of keys to bind actions to and do lots of things people usually do with the mouse. Being able to split an editor into several buffers, move around the buffers, go at the beginning of the paragraph, search and replace, register actions into macros and replay them, etc. All this without even moving the wrists. The learning curve is steep if you’re used to the mouse, but once you’ve passed the mental barrier, really, and this is a personal opinion, but I truly think that using the mouse again after that feels like handicap to me.</p>
<h2 id="how-i-like-to-move-around">How I like to move around</h2>
<p>When I look at people coding, I see several kind of programmers:</p>
<ul>
<li>The ones who move with the arrows or with <code>h j k l</code> in modal editors. You can spot them very easily at how the cursor moves in a document. It typically implies keeping a key pressed until the cursor reach a given row, then pressing another key until the cursor reach a given column and then adjust if they went passed the location they had in mind.</li>
<li>People using the mouse, by clicking at the place they want to put the cursor at.</li>
<li>People using <em>relative numbers</em>. That’s an enhancement of the first group: they typically use relative numbers to know which lines they want to jump to very quickly, so that they don’t have to press the up / down keys for ages until reaching the line they want to. Instead, they look at the number on the lines, press that number, and the direction, and bam, they are on the lines. They then use typical motions from vim like <code>$</code> (go to end of line), <code>f</code> (go to the first occurrence of the next character typed after <code>f</code>, like <code>f(</code> will make your cursor go to the next <code>(</code>), <code>%</code> (go to the matching delimiter) or <code>w</code> (go to the beginning of the next word) / <code>b</code> (go to the beginning of the previous word), etc. to move faster on the same line (it works across lines too).</li>
</ul>
<p>I think that represents 99,9% of what I see people do. Obviously, you will get that I don’t belong to the second set of people… but I don’t really belong to any, actually. How I move is, I guess, convoluted for most people and I know some people won’t understand how it can feel. I use <code>h j k l</code> and all the motions from vim described in the third group (and even more; I full lecture of four hours would be required to explain all of them :D), but it all depends on the <em>distance</em> I need to travel. If my cursor is on a word and I want to move to the beginning of a word located very closely to my cursor on the same line, I’ll simply type <code>www</code> if it’s three words apart (or <code>3w</code> if I’m feeling funny). If the distance is higher, I use a tool called [EasyMotion].</p>
<p>Easymotion really is a wonderful tool. The idea is that it has several modes, depending on the kind of move you want to perform:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>By lines</em>: this mode allows you to jump to any line in the current (or all open) buffers.</li>
<li><em>By words</em>: tihs mode allows you to jump to any “word” in the current (or all open) buffers.</li>
<li><em>By characters</em>: when the <em>word</em> mode doesn’t help with jumping to a special operator or character (because it’s not recognized as a word), this mode allows you to jump to any character in the current or (or all open) buffers.</li>
<li>It has other modes but I have never really found useful cases for them.</li>
</ul>
<p>The way I typically do it is by mapping the three modes to <code>&lt;leader&gt;l</code>, <code>&lt;leader&gt;w&gt;</code> and <code>&lt;leader&gt;c</code> (in my case, <code>&lt;leader&gt;</code> is the <em>space</em> key).</p>
<p>Typing <code>SPC l</code> in my current buffer results in this:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://phaazon.net/media/uploads/easymotion_lines.png" alt=""><figcaption>EasyMotion lines</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Typing any highlighted character will make my cursor jump to it. The same applies for words, with <code>SPC w</code>:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://phaazon.net/media/uploads/easymotion_words.png" alt=""><figcaption>EasyMotion words</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>For the <em>character</em> mode, after pressing <code>SPC c</code>, I have to press another character (the one I want to jump to). Let’s say we want to jump to a <code>#</code> (which is not part of words): <code>SPC c #</code>:</p>
<figure>
<img src="https://phaazon.net/media/uploads/easymotion_chars.png" alt=""><figcaption>EasyMotion characters</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>This way of moving is not intuitive at first, but once you get used to it… it’s a <em>must have</em>.</p>
<h2 id="all-the-other-modal-candies">All the other modal candies</h2>
<p>Among all the things that I like about modal editing, here is a non-exhaustive list of features I expect to have around my fingers:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>C-i</code> and <code>C-o</code>: those allows me to jump to something / a file / a place in a buffer and then go back to where I was right before with <code>C-o</code> (read it like <em>out</em>) or go back again with <code>C-i</code> (read it like <em>in</em>).</li>
<li>Macros and registers: those allow me to yank content into different registers (like clipboards) by assigning a single key to paste their content. For instance, I can put a few lines in my <code>t</code> register with <code>"tyi(</code> (“put in the <code>t</code> register the <code>y</code>ank <code>i</code>nside matching <code>(</code>), and paste that content later with <code>"tp</code>. Macros allow more powerful editing control by assigning a key to set of actions with the <code>q</code> keyword (<code>qa</code> will register all the next keystrokes and actions into the <code>a</code> macro). Then simply replay the macro with <code>@a</code>, for instance.</li>
<li>Obviously, all the basic vim motions, like <code>d</code> to delete, <code>y</code> to yank, <code>c</code> to change, <code>t</code> to go to the character right before the one you search, <code>%</code> to go to the other delimiter, etc. And more complex text manipulation, such as “Let’s change what’s inside this function parameter list, delimited by <code>(</code>”: <code>ci(</code>.</li>
</ul>
<p>It would take too much time to list everything, but the main idea is: I need the modal features when editing code.</p>

<p>So let’s talk about the list of editors I mentioned in the preface. The idea is to give <em>my own opinion</em> on those …</p></div></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020">https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://phaazon.net/blog/editors-in-2020</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395863</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:50:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PostgreSQL B-Tree index deduplication]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 127 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395825">thread link</a>) | @petergeoghegan
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    <p>By Ryan Lambert -- Published September 06, 2020</p><p>PostgreSQL 13 development is coming along nicely, Postgres 13 Beta3 was
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/about/news/2060/">released on 8/13/2020</a>.
The Postgres Beta 1 and 2 releases were released in May and June 2020.
One of the features that has my interest in Postgres 13 is the B-Tree deduplication effort.  B-Tree indexes are the default indexing method
in Postgres, and are likely the most-used indexes in production 
environments.
Any improvements to this part of the database are likely to have wide-reaching benefits.
Removing duplication from indexes keeps their physical size smaller,
reduces I/O overhead, and should help keep <code>SELECT</code> queries fast!</p>
<!--endteaser-->

<blockquote>
<p>This post is part of the series <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2018/06/pg-series-toc"><em>PostgreSQL:  From Idea to Database</em></a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There is a good summary of the what and how of this improvement
in <a href="https://www.cybertec-postgresql.com/en/b-tree-index-deduplication/">Laurenz Albe's post</a> from early in June 2020, presumably using
Pg13 Beta1.  <a href="https://www.highgo.ca/2020/07/06/features-in-pg13-deduplication-in-b-tree-indexes/">Hamid Akhtar's post in July</a>
covered this feature using Pg13 Beta2 and a different approach including
a look at the performance using <code>EXPLAIN</code>.
This post takes yet another look at this improvement using Pg13 Beta3.
I intend to see how well this improvement pans out on a data set I use in production.  For that task my go-to is
<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap</a> data loaded to Postgres/PostGIS <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/01/postgis-osm-load-2020">using osm2pgsql</a>.</p>
<h2>Install Postgres 13 Beta 3</h2>
<p>The first step is to install the two versions of Postgres (12 and 13beta3) 
on a single Ubuntu 18 host.  In the past when I have tested pre-production
releases I have built Postgres from source instead of using <code>apt</code>.
This time around I decided to use <code>apt install</code>, so am including the
basic process for that.</p>
<p>The advised way to install PostgreSQL is from the pgdg (PostgreSQL Global Development Group) repositories,
see <a href="https://wiki.postgresql.org/wiki/Apt">the Postgres wiki</a> for more.
To enable the beta versions, the line needed in <code>/etc/apt/sources.list.d/pgdg.list</code> is:</p>
<pre><code>deb http://apt.postgresql.org/pub/repos/apt/bionic-pgdg main 13
</code></pre>
<p>With that in place, update the sources and install Postgres and PostGIS.</p>
<pre><code>sudo apt update
# Postgres 12
sudo apt install postgresql-12 postgresql-12-postgis-3
# Postgres 13 (Currently Beta)
sudo apt install postgresql-13 postgresql-13-postgis-3
</code></pre>
<p>On Ubuntu, installing multiple versions will create multiple instances running on different ports. The test server I'm using to write this post
currently has three versions of Postgres installed, only two are currently running. Postgres 12 was installed first so "won" the default port of 5432.  Postgres 11 was installed second and was assigned 5433, and Pg13 beta 3 was installed last and was assigned port 5434.  The <code>pg_lsclusters</code> is avaiable on Debian/Ubuntu hosts as part of the wrapper around <code>pg_ctl</code>.</p>
<pre><code>sudo -u postgres pg_lsclusters
Ver Cluster Port Status Owner    Data directory              Log file
11  main    5433 down   postgres /var/lib/postgresql/11/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-11-main.log
12  main    5432 online postgres /var/lib/postgresql/12/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-12-main.log
13  main    5434 online postgres /var/lib/postgresql/13/main /var/log/postgresql/postgresql-13-main.log
</code></pre>
<blockquote>
<p>This post does not use Postgres 11 beyond this example.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When working with multiple versions installed it is helpful to verify
versions match what you expect them to be.
First, the port 5432 for Postgres 12 version.</p>
<pre><code>psql -d pgosm -p 5432 -c "select version();"
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚                                   version                                    â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ PostgreSQL 12.4 (Ubuntu 12.4-1.pgdg18.04+1) on x86_64-pc-linux-gnu, compiledâ€¦â”‚
â”‚â€¦ by gcc (Ubuntu 7.5.0-3ubuntu1~18.04) 7.5.0, 64-bit                          â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<p>Now, port 5434 for Postgres 13 version.</p>
<pre><code>psql -d pgosm -p 5434 -c "select version();"
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚                                   version                                    â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ PostgreSQL 13beta3 (Ubuntu 13~beta3-1.pgdg18.04+1) on x86_64-pc-linux-gnu, câ€¦â”‚
â”‚â€¦ompiled by gcc (Ubuntu 7.5.0-3ubuntu1~18.04) 7.5.0, 64-bit                   â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h2>Create Indexes</h2>
<p>Both versions of Postgres were loaded with the same Colorado OpenStreetMap
data loaded <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/01/postgis-osm-load-2020">using osm2pgsql</a>.
The osm2pgsql does not create any B-Tree indexes on its own, only the GIST
indexes on geometries.
For this post, we examine B-Tree index sizes created on four columns:
<code>osm_id</code>, <code>highway</code>, <code>waterway</code>, and <code>natural</code>.
Looking at the stats on the <code>public.planet_osm_line</code> table I can make 
a couple guesses where we will and will not see gains based on <code>n_distinct</code>.
I can guess we will not see major gains in the
<code>osm_id</code>, there is only a small amount of duplication in those values.
The other three columns (<code>highway</code>, <code>natural</code> and <code>waterway</code>) have a small number of distinct values
and varying amounts of <code>NULL</code> values.  These three columns would all
be candidates for partial indexes to avoid indexing the <code>NULL</code> values,
thus reducing the size of the created index.
I have hopes to see the benefits in Postgres 13 on these columns, possibly
making the use of partial indexes less frequent.</p>
<pre><code> SELECT attname, n_distinct, null_frac
    FROM pg_catalog.pg_stats
    WHERE tablename = 'planet_osm_line'
        AND attname IN ('osm_id', 'highway', 'waterway', 'natural')
;

â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ attname  â”‚ n_distinct â”‚ null_frac  â”‚
â•žâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•ªâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•ªâ•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•�â•¡
â”‚ osm_id   â”‚  -0.833553 â”‚          0 â”‚
â”‚ highway  â”‚         26 â”‚ 0.41616666 â”‚
â”‚ natural  â”‚          4 â”‚      0.994 â”‚
â”‚ waterway â”‚          9 â”‚     0.6663 â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h3>Index on <code>osm_id</code></h3>
<p>First up is the <code>osm_id</code> column, a nearly unique set of positive and 
negative values.  The index to create in both versions:</p>
<pre><code>CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_osm_id ON public.planet_osm_line (osm_id);
</code></pre>
<p>The following query is used throughout to report out index sizes.
The query itself will not be repeated, as only the filter would change.</p>
<pre><code>SELECT ai.schemaname AS s_name, ai.relname AS t_name,
        ai.indexrelname AS index_name,
        pg_size_pretty(pg_relation_size(quote_ident(ai.schemaname)::text || '.' || quote_ident(ai.indexrelname)::text)) AS index_size,
        pg_relation_size(quote_ident(ai.schemaname)::text || '.' || quote_ident(ai.indexrelname)::text) AS index_size_bytes
    FROM pg_catalog.pg_stat_all_indexes ai
    WHERE ai.indexrelname LIKE 'ix_osm_line%'
    ORDER BY index_name
;
</code></pre>
<p>Due to the low number of duplicates, it is no surprise that the
show only a tiny reduction in the size.  The reduction
would not be detectable from only the <code>index_size</code> column (in MB), the
<code>index_size_bytes</code> shows the slight reduction in size (29,515,776 bytes vs. 29,384,704 bytes).</p>
<p>Pg 12.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€[ RECORD 1 ]â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ s_name           â”‚ public             â”‚
â”‚ t_name           â”‚ planet_osm_line    â”‚
â”‚ index_name       â”‚ ix_osm_line_osm_id â”‚
â”‚ index_size       â”‚ 28 MB              â”‚
â”‚ index_size_bytes â”‚ 29515776           â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<p>Pg 13.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€[ RECORD 1 ]â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”�
â”‚ s_name           â”‚ public             â”‚
â”‚ t_name           â”‚ planet_osm_line    â”‚
â”‚ index_name       â”‚ ix_osm_line_osm_id â”‚
â”‚ index_size       â”‚ 28 MB              â”‚
â”‚ index_size_bytes â”‚ 29384704           â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”´â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
</code></pre>
<h3>Index on <code>highway</code></h3>
<p>The <code>highway</code> data in the <code>planet_osm_line</code> data is a good example of when
a
<a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/indexes-partial.html">partial index</a>
might typically be a good idea to minimize index size.  My hunch (and hope)
is that the de-duplication will make a partial index here a moot point by reducing the size required to index a large number of <code>NULL</code> values.</p>
<p>Create two indexes, one partial covering the non-<code>NULL</code> values and one full
index on the entire table.</p>
<pre><code>CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_highway_partial 
    ON public.planet_osm_line (highway)
    WHERE highway IS NOT NULL;
CREATE INDEX ix_osm_line_highway_full
    ON public.planet_osm_line (highway);
</code></pre>
<p>The two indexes in Postgres 12, notice the partial index cuts out about 1/3 of the size from the full index.</p>
<pre><code>â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”¬â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”…</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup">https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.rustprooflabs.com/2020/09/postgres-beta3-btree-dedup</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395825</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:39:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Introduction to Computational Thinking]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 159 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395700">thread link</a>) | @guiambros
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<!-- Content appended here -->
<div>
<p>Welcome to the new course <strong>MIT 18.S191</strong>, the debut edition, <strong>Fall 2020</strong>!</p>
<p> This is an introductory course on Computational Thinking. We use the <a href="http://www.julialang.org/">Julia programming language</a> to approach real-world problems in varied areas applying data analysis and computational and mathematical modeling.  In this class you will learn computer science, software, algorithms, applications, and mathematics as an integrated whole.</p>
<p>Topics include:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Image analysis</p>
</li>
<li><p>Particle dynamics and ray tracing</p>
</li>
<li><p>Epidemic propagation</p>
</li>
<li><p>Climate modeling</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="professors"><a href="#professors">Professors</a></h2>
<p><a href="http://math.mit.edu/~edelman">Alan Edelman</a>, <a href="http://sistemas.fciencias.unam.mx/~dsanders/">David P. Sanders</a>, <a href="https://www.3blue1brown.com/about">Grant Sanderson</a>, &amp; <a href="https://eapsweb.mit.edu/people/jars">James Schloss</a></p>
<h2 id="introduction_video"><a href="#introduction_video">Introduction video</a></h2>
<iframe id="course-intro" width="800" height="474" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vxjRWtWoD_w" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h2 id="logistics"><a href="#logistics">Logistics</a></h2>
<p>Course materials will be published on the accompanying website: <a href="https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/">https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/</a></p>
<p>TR 2:30–3:30pm EST, online (Go to the lecture page on this site to stream it.)</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Tuesdays: Prerecorded videos, released on YouTube and played live on this site.</p>
</li>
<li><p>Thursdays: Live sessions (same YouTube link 2:30–3) and MIT-only discussion (3-3:30); link to follow</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Start date: September 1, 2020</p>
<p>Office hours TBD.</p>
<h3 id="discussion_forum_and_homework_submission"><a href="#discussion_forum_and_homework_submission">Discussion forum and homework submission</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://discord.gg/Z5qnVf8">Discord</a>: discussion (we encourage you to hang out here during class!)</p>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://piazza.com/class/kd33x1xnfyq3b1">Piazza</a>: (MIT only) allows for anonymity to other students, discussion</p>
</li>
<li><p><a href="https://canvas.mit.edu/courses/5637">Canvas</a>: (MIT only) homework submission. If you're a non-MIT student, please find a partner to cross-grade homeworks via Discord.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="evaluation"><a href="#evaluation">Evaluation</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><p>12 weekly problem sets with equal weight; your lowest score will be dropped. </p>
</li>
<li><p>Released on Thursdays and due before the following Thursday's class. (No problem set during Thanskgiving week.)</p>
</li>
<li><p>No exams</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Problem sets consist of code. MIT students enrolled in the course must submit homeworks via Canvas. If you are not a student then we encourage you to join the Discord and find a cross-grading partner.</p>
<div>
  <p>
    Last modified: September 08, 2020. Website built with <a href="https://github.com/tlienart/Franklin.jl">Franklin.jl</a>.
  </p>
</div>
</div><!-- CONTENT ENDS HERE -->

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mitmath.github.io/18S191/Fall20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395700</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Elixir Is Erlang, not Ruby]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 290 | Comments 115 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395695">thread link</a>) | @stanislavb
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
              
              <p>Try to remember the first time you heard about this fascinating language called <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Elixir</a>. Chances are, you had by the time been developing software using Ruby. If that's the case, Elixir seems to have appeared out of nowhere until suddenly, it became the solution for all your previous problems. It is fast, clean, scales extremely well. It was <strong>almost</strong> like the Ruby you've always wanted to have, but never got.</p><p>I say <strong>almost</strong>, because as much as you want it to be, <strong>Elixir is not Ruby</strong>. The familiar syntax has definitely helped the language win the hearts of the broader developer community. Yet, under the hood, <strong>Elixir is all about Erlang.</strong> The <a href="https://elixir-lang.org/">Erlang</a> that everyone tells stories about, as if it were some mythical creature, but no one dares to touch.</p><figure><img src="https://preslav.me/content/images/2020/09/book-cover.png" alt="" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>Elixir for Non-Ruby Programmers</figcaption></figure><p>Why am I saying all of this? First, because I would love to see greater adoption of Elixir outside Ruby/Rails community. It was among that group of people where the idea first sparked, and I fully respect the fact. Nevertheless, I would love to see it growing out. As someone who discovered Elixir after years of doing Java, &nbsp;.NET and more recently, Go, I can say that there is enough goodness in it for everyone. Moreover, bringing people with different backgrounds (both technical and non-technical) will lead to an explosion of new ideas. Having more diverse minds will help us better understand and make use of the elephant in the room-Erlang.</p><p>This brings me to my second point. Erlang is not obscure at all, once you give it enough attention. It is actually oddly satisfying, once you start reading code written in it. I have had my few a-ha moments, when I figured the original inspiration for most constructs in Elixir. The point is, we shouldn't fear Erlang, but try to understand it. This applies both to when things go well, as well as when they go south.</p><p>My biggest hope of all is that by understanding Erlang well enough, the Elixir community will start looking for new uses for it. Uses that go beyond being a scalable replacement for Rails apps. More daring and more ambitious uses, where Erlang's resilience model can prove to be critical for the success of the mission. I'd love to see it used in transportation, space, as well as the domain that started it all- telecommunications.</p><blockquote>“Shoot for the moon. Even if you miss it you will land among the stars.”<br><strong>Les Brown</strong></blockquote>
                <section>
                  
                  <ul>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/elixir/" title="Elixir">Elixir</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/programming/" title="Programming">Programming</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/ruby/" title="Ruby">Ruby</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/erlang/" title="Erlang">Erlang</a>
                      </li>
                      <li>
                        <a href="https://preslav.me/tag/2-cents/" title="2 Cents">2 Cents</a>
                      </li>
                  </ul>
                </section>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://preslav.me/2020/09/06/elixir-is-not-ruby-elixir-is-erlang/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395695</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:07:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Lending app publicly shames you when you’re late on loan payment]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 67 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24395363">thread link</a>) | @danso
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://restofworld.org/2020/okash-microlending-public-shaming/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://restofworld.org/2020/okash-microlending-public-shaming/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			
<p><span>T</span>he only person David Kiragu lied to about the texts was his mom. To those close to him, like his partner, friends, former schoolmates, and work colleagues, he explained what was going on. To more distant contacts, including annoying relatives, he said nothing.</p>



<p>His mother probably knew he was lying — mothers often do — but she let it slide.</p>



<p>“I couldn’t tell her the truth,” Kiragu said to me last December. “So I told her it was one of those prison scams and she should ignore it.”</p>



<p>He owed money. Not a lot of it, but that didn’t matter. His fintech creditor was still telling everyone in Kiragu’s inner circle that he was a deadbeat.</p>



<p>It happened like this: Toward the end of March 2018, Kiragu found himself in a bind. At 32, he earned a solid income as a manager at an iNGO in Nairobi. But for the first time in his life, he couldn’t make rent.</p>



<p>His choices were limited. He could always borrow the remainder from friends, family, or somebody else in his network. The problem was that if he did, people would know he was living beyond his means.</p>



<p>But then one morning Kiragu logged into his Facebook account and saw an ad for a fintech app called OKash that promised to be the discreet friend who would spot him some cash and never mention it again. Offering the ability to “process loans in seconds,” OKash is one of many fintech apps that have sprung up in Kenya since 2012. All he needed to do was download the app, enter his financial details, and let the algorithm generate a credit rating. He would get the money he needed and could pay it back once he was liquid.</p>



<p>He doesn’t remember that day too well now, but Kiragu thinks it took just minutes to apply for his loan. His money arrived right away, so he paid his bills and moved on. “I started with about $15, which I repaid [on time], and my loan limit expanded. Then I borrowed about $35, which I also repaid,” he told me as we sat on the balcony of a chic restaurant in a mall outside Nairobi.</p>



<p>It was the third loan that upended his life. He needed it to top up his rent, because by then a vicious cycle had begun, wherein he would pay off his loan then borrow again to fill the hole that the last payment had left in his finances.</p>



<p>Kiragu started getting calls even before that deadline passed.</p>



<p>“Will you repay your OKash loan?” Kiragu remembers a caller asking him, before warning that if he missed a payment, the company would notify everyone on his contact list. In texts he showed me on his phone, an OKash representative had written an hour before the deadline lapsed, “Despite several polite reminders on your OKash loan . . . No PAYMENT received yet . . . Note that we are going to invade your privacy according to Terms of Service clause 8, IF NOT CLEARED BY 4PM.” The clause in question reads as follows: “In the event we cannot get in contact with you or your emergency contact, you also expressly authorise us to contact any and all persons in your contact list.”</p>



<p>In the days after the deadline, debt collectors hounded Kiragu, calling three to four times every hour. They also cast a wide net. “They texted just about everyone I know,” Kiragu says. His parents and many friends got messages. One of his colleagues even shared a screenshot of a text from OKash in an office-wide WhatsApp Group.</p>



<p>“Some [people] sympathized with me,” Kiragu wrote in a Facebook post about the experience. “Some were laughing at me and some were actually very annoyed that OKash is exposing and shaming me . . . Even my boss called me to ask if everything is okay.”</p>



<p>But his colleagues weren’t his main concern. What worried him more was what his parents would think. After an estranged aunt shared the message within his village, Kiragu’s father accused him of bringing shame on the family.</p>



<p>This was nearly two years ago, but the memory is still raw, so much so that Kiragu asked to use a pseudonym for this article. “If you pay on time, they are angels,” Kiragu said as he sipped his tea and stared at a potted plant behind me. “They keep texting you to take out another loan with them. If you do and won’t or can’t pay, then it’s pretty simple: Pay or we damage what you value most.”</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/h_21.00183863-scaled-1-40x27.jpg" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/h_21.00183863-scaled-1-648x432.jpg" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/h_21.00183863-scaled-1-2560x1575.jpg 2560w, https://restofworld.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/h_21.00183863-scaled-1-648x432.jpg 648w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, calc(100vw - 40px)" alt="A M-Pesa kiosk in Nairobi in 2014.

Credit:
Sven Torfinn/Panos Pictures Panos/Redux

Naomi Wanjiku, a M-Pesa agent, arranges a customer's transaction at a M-Pesa kiosk in South B, a residential area of the city. M-Pesa, (M for mobile, pesa is Swahili for money), is a Kenyan cellphone-based money transfer service. The majority of its customers have no bank accounts, but they withdraw cash and make payments or send money using their cell phones. A network of appointed agents, scattered all over the country, provide the cashing handling services. 
 
Creation Date: Kenya">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder">Sven Torfinn/Panos Pictures Panos/Redux</span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>In 2007, Safaricom</strong>, Kenya’s biggest telecoms provider, launched M-Pesa, a mobile wallet that allowed users to send and receive money and buy airtime. Smartphones were just becoming popular, so Safaricom tailored its fintech product to the basic cell phones most Kenyans already owned. It was immediately hailed as a revolutionary way to bring millions of “unbanked” customers into the formal financial sector. The Clinton Global Initiative and other major philanthropic organizations were vocal supporters, and it was soon being taught as a case study in business schools around the world. It was also a success on the ground: Safaricom aimed to sign up 350,000 M-Pesa users by the end of 2007, but by November it had already attracted over 1 million. From there, it only continued to grow. As of last September, 23.6 million Kenyans — nearly half of the country’s population — were using it regularly.</p>



<p>M-Pesa was initially meant to be a microfinance project; its first sales pitch to users was “Send Money Home.” It was banking on the fact that while working-class Kenyans who lived away from home wanted to support their families, cash is expensive. This was not a new concept; among Somalis, the Hawala system exists to address this same problem. If you want to send money to someone, you give it to a local agent, who then contacts a second agent located in the same area as the intended recipient, and that agent then disburses the money. Both agents earn a small commission, and they sort each other out.</p>



<p>In Kenya, there were several factors behind M-Pesa’s rapid ascent. One was that 2007 was an election year, and when violence erupted over the results, having a way to transfer money without leaving the house felt to Kenyans like a godsend. Another, more structural, reason was that before M-Pesa, the country’s banking sector served only a portion of the population. Kenya’s economy collapsed four times between the mid-1980s and the early 2000s, by which point the banks were heavily regulated. It was nearly impossible for low-income Kenyans, including millennials, to get loans. No such legal barriers applied to fintech.</p>



<p>When fintech took off, banks, Silicon Valley–backed products, private-equity products, and Kenyan companies all began competing for the same clients. One of the first savings-and-lending apps, called M-Shwari, was launched in 2012 through a partnership between a local bank and Safaricom. Some of its earliest users were Kenyans in the informal economy. In a 2017 social media post, for example, a business journalist noted that “up to a third of loans are taken between the hours of 3am and 5am. Most are repaid within twenty-four hours.” When the Central Bank looked into what was going on, they discovered that a typical user was a market seller who would wake up early and borrow enough money to pay everybody in her supply chain that day. She would then work until evening, pay back the loan, and repeat the cycle again the next morning.</p>



<p>Within a few years, credit-app use had started to spread throughout Kenyan society. Over a 13-year period, financial inclusion<a href="https://fsdkenya.org/publication/finaccess2019/"> jumped</a> from nearly 27 percent, in 2006, to almost 83 percent. And the product side grew as well. As of September 2018, according to a report from Financial Sector Deepening Kenya (FSD), the two main app stores offered 110 credit apps.</p>



<p>Almost all of these companies make their money by providing short-term loans with high interest rates. But that’s often where transparency around the business model ends. Since there is no regulatory framework governing fintech, it is hard to know who exactly owns an app or even where the money is coming from. The absence of regulation has many perks for the sector and one major liability: As companies soon discovered, if a user does not pay back what they have borrowed, plus interest, there is little a digital lender can do. Users can simply delete the app and move on. One solution to this problem has been to flag defaulters to one of Kenya’s three credit reference bureaus (CRBs), effectively locking them out of the credit market. It’s unclear how effective this strategy is, but it’s frequently used. Between 2014 and 2017, about 2.7 million Kenyans were negatively listed with a CRB, 15 percent of them for defaulting on loans of less than about $2. Last year, “how to check CRB status” was among the most-Googled questions in Kenya, between “how to be successful in life” and “how to get pregnant.”</p>



<p>Before long, digital lenders started looking into other methods of recouping their investments. Skip tracing, the ancient art of finding someone who owes you money and making them pay, was virtually nonexistent among fintech companies until early 2018. Coincidentally, that was the same year that Opay, a fintech company partially owned by the software-maker Opera, launched OKash in Kenya. The majority of Opera’s operations had been bought by a consortium of Chinese investors two years earlier, and shortly afterward, the company went on an expansion spree, announcing plans to invest $100 million in East Africa. While Opera’s then managing director, a former banker&nbsp; named Edward Ndichu, said at the time that the app would protect users’ personal information, he never explained how the company planned to safeguard its financial investment. But the answer was buried in OKash’s terms and conditions: When users download the app, they give it permission to access their contacts.</p>


		<figure>
			<div>
				<p><img src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Contact-List-2-40x29.png" data-src="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Contact-List-2-590x432.png" data-srcset="https://149346090.v2.pressablecdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Contact-List-2-590x432.png 590w, " sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, (max-width: 992px) calc(100vw - 40px), (max-width: 1140px) calc(100vw - 290px), calc(100vw - ((100vw - 640px)/2))" alt="">
					
				</p>
			</div>
						<figcaption itemprop="caption description">
				
				<span itemprop="copyrightHolder"><a href="https://www.simoulalva.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Simoul Alva for Rest of World</a></span>
			</figcaption>
		</figure>


<hr>



<p><strong>Reports of OKash</strong> using social shaming started to surface almost as soon as the app went live. And people immediately felt the fallout. A University of Nairobi …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://restofworld.org/2020/okash-microlending-public-shaming/">https://restofworld.org/2020/okash-microlending-public-shaming/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://restofworld.org/2020/okash-microlending-public-shaming/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24395363</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 23:06:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[CubeSat interplanetary exploration is heating up]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24392811">thread link</a>) | @tectonic
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | http://orbitalindex.com/archive/2020-09-02-Issue-80/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://orbitalindex.com/archive/2020-09-02-Issue-80/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div replace-ids="_main" link-selector="a[href]:not([href*='/assets/']):not(.external):not(.no-push-state)" duration="250" script-selector="script:not([type^='math/tex'])" prefetch=""><main id="_main" role="main" data-color="#4fb1ba" data-theme-color="black" data-image="/assets/img/sidebar-bg.jpg" data-overlay=""><article class="page" role="article"><header></header><div id="mc-archive"> <center> <!--[if (gte mso 9)|(IE)]><table align="center" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="600" style="width:600px;"><tr><td align="center" valign="top" width="600" style="width:600px;"> <![endif]--><table><tbody><tr><td id="templatePreheader"></td></tr><tr><td id="templateHeader"><div> <!--[if mso]><table align="left" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%" style="width:100%;"><tr> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]><td valign="top" width="600" style="width:600px;"> <![endif]--><div><div><p>Issue No. 80&nbsp;|&nbsp;Sep 2, 2020</p><p>   <span>🚀 🌍 🛰</span></p></div></div><!--[if mso]> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]></table><![endif]--></div></td></tr><tr><td id="templateBody"><div> <!--[if mso]><table align="left" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%" style="width:100%;"><tr> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]><td valign="top" width="600" style="width:600px;"> <![endif]--><div><p><a href="#cubesat-interplanetary-exploration-is-heating-up">¶</a><strong id="cubesat-interplanetary-exploration-is-heating-up">CubeSat interplanetary exploration is heating up.</strong> The twin <a href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/cubesat/missions/marco.php" target="_blank">MarCO 6U cubesats</a> (<a href="https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/resources/2373/marco-3d-model/" target="_blank">3D model</a>) made history when they <a href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/spaceimages/details.php?id=PIA22833" target="_blank">flew past Mars</a> and successfully relayed Mars InSight’s landing in real time (+ speed-of-light delay, natch). Now, many more lunar and interplanetary CubeSats are under development. From NASA comes <a href="https://www.jpl.nasa.gov/cubesat/missions/lunar_flashlight.php" target="_blank">Lunar Flashlight</a>, <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/goddard/2019/lunar-icecube-mission-to-locate-study-resources-needed-for-sustained-presence-on-moon" target="_blank">Lunar IceCube</a>, and <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/content/nea-scout/" target="_blank">NEAScout</a> (a <em>solar sailing</em> small near-Earth asteroid explorer). ESA is working on <a href="http://www.esa.int/ESA_Multimedia/Images/2017/06/M_Argo" target="_blank">M-ARGO</a>, to explore small, rapidly spinning asteroids, and <a href="https://www.esa.int/Safety_Security/Hera/CubeSats_joining_Hera_mission_to_asteroid_system" target="_blank">2 cubesats that will tag along with their Hera mission</a> to the Didymos/Didymoon system (which will have already been attacked by NASA’s <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/planetarydefense/dart" target="_blank">DART kinetic impactor</a> along with its <a href="https://www.argotec.it/online/liciacube-nasa-choose-italian-excellence-to-monitor-a-space-impact-between-a-satellite-and-an-asteroid/" target="_blank">LICIACube</a> companion CubeSat). Caltech is working on <a href="https://trailblazer.caltech.edu/" target="_blank">Lunar Trailblazer</a> to map the lunar water cycle, while University of Arizona’s <a href="https://lunahmap.asu.edu/" target="_blank">LunaH-Map</a> will perform a high resolution search for water in permanently shadowed regions on the Moon’s poles. CubeSats can also enable less resourced countries and private entities to do deep space exploration. Poland and Virgin Orbit <a href="https://virginorbit.com/satrevolution-virgin-orbit-and-polish-universities-establish-mars-consortium/" target="_blank">are collaborating on a Mars cubesat</a>. <a href="https://www.theverge.com/21292753/rocket-lab-nasa-capstone-moon-mission-photon-hypercurie-engine" target="_blank">Rocket Lab is planning a mission to the Moon next year</a> (check out <a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/lunar/" target="_blank">Rocket Lab’s lunar site</a>), and Rocket Lab CEO Peter Beck is even <a href="https://www.space.com/rocket-lab-private-venus-mission-2023.html" target="_blank">investigating a private mission to Venus</a>—the upgraded Electron should be able to deliver around 25 kg to Mars or Venus (Venus requires an additional ∆v of ~1,000 m/s according to the handy chart at the end of this issue, ignoring aerobraking). Slightly larger upcoming vehicles like Firefly's Alpha and Relativity Space’s Terran 1 “<a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2020/07/how-small-satellites-are-radically-remaking-space-exploration/2/" target="_blank"><em>probably could put CubeSats beyond the asteroid belt, toward Jupiter or beyond.</em></a>” Related: JPL’s "Honey, I Shrunk the NASA Payload" challenge <a href="https://www.herox.com/NASApayload/131-meet-the-winners" target="_blank">recently ended with awards for miniaturized lunar payloads</a>. Also Related: Astrobotic’s <a href="https://www.astrobotic.com/2019/10/2/astrobotic-s-cuberover-program-awarded-2-million-contract-by-nasa" target="_blank">CubeRover</a> is pretty cute.</p></div><!--[if mso]> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]></table><![endif]--></div><div> <!--[if mso]><table align="left" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%" style="width:100%;"><tr> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]><td valign="top" width="600" style="width:600px;"> <![endif]--><div><p><a href="#a-busy-weekend-in-launch">¶</a><strong id="a-busy-weekend-in-launch">A Busy Weekend in Launch. </strong>ULA, Rocket Lab, and SpaceX all had scheduled launches over the weekend. ULA kicked the weekend off with a Delta IV Heavy launch of an NRO spy satellite. The aging heavy lifter, which will be phased out and replaced by <a href="https://www.ulalaunch.com/rockets/vulcan-centaur" target="_blank">Vulcan</a> over the next few years, had a <a href="https://twitter.com/torybruno/status/1299623698090135552" target="_blank">T-3 sec hotfire abort</a> complete with a dramatic fireball (<a href="https://youtu.be/1jkjgo0Cs_8" target="_blank">video</a>). The rocket and payload are undamaged, but launch is delayed a week or more while expendable ground systems are replaced. Next up was SpaceX, launching <a href="https://space.skyrocket.de/doc_sdat/saocom-1.htm" target="_blank">SAOCOM-1B</a> into a polar orbit, the <a href="https://www.nasaspaceflight.com/2020/08/spacex-polar-cape-50-years/" target="_blank">first such southward flight path from Florida since 1969</a> when <a href="http://www.digitaljournal.com/tech-and-science/science/herd-shot-around-the-world-the-last-east-coast-polar-launch/article/567614" target="_blank">booster debris landed on Cuba</a> and <a href="https://www.mapfreglobalrisks.com/risks/images/Seguros_de_satelites_ENU_tcm1366-435032.pdf" target="_blank">killed a cow named Rufina</a> 🐮. Returning to this flight path was only possible due to the Falcon 9’s automated self-destruct systems—rocket exhaust in this flight path can block manually radioed abort messages. This launch was also temporarily halted due to its overflight of ULA’s aborted NROL-44 payload (expensive!) and required last minute approval from the NRO. To cap the weekend off,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.rocketlabusa.com/missions/completed-missions/i-cant-believe-its-not-optical/" target="_blank">Rocket Lab returned to flight with their 14th mission</a> (and announced that they will be conducting a first soft ocean splashdown of the booster for their 17th mission). Their&nbsp;<em>I Can’t Believe It’s Not Optical</em> mission was a dedicated launch for <a href="https://www.capellaspace.com/technology" target="_blank">Capella Space</a>, a startup focused on capturing 0.5 m resolution <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synthetic-aperture_radar" target="_blank">synthetic aperture radar</a> (SAR) data as a service, the first of an eight satellite constellation. (<em>Ed., amusingly, this satellite was originally supposed to launch as a rideshare with SAOCOM-1B, but when that mission was delayed, Capella switched to Rocket Lab, which was then delayed by a July 4th failure, eventually launching just a few hours after the original mission. You just can’t get ahead. </em>🤷‍♂️)</p></div><!--[if mso]> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]></table><![endif]--></div><div> <!--[if mso]><table align="left" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%" style="width:100%;"><tr> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]><td valign="top" width="600" style="width:600px;"> <![endif]--><div><p><a href="#etc">¶</a><strong id="etc">Etc.</strong></p><ul><li>Explore Mars has <a href="https://www.exploremars.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/H2MR_2020_Web_v1.pdf" target="_blank">released their annual Humans to Mars report</a> detailing progress towards human exploration of the planet in the 2030s.</li><li>The US Department of Education has&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ctemissioncubesat.com/" target="_blank">announced a CubeSat mission design and prototyping challenge for High School students</a>. Project submission is October 16th, with a Phase 2 scheduled for January.</li><li>Chris Cassidy shared <a href="https://twitter.com/Astro_SEAL/status/1298703689960443904" target="_blank">dramatic views of Hurricane Laura from the ISS</a>.</li><li> <a href="https://www.tylermw.com/a-step-by-step-guide-to-making-3d-maps-with-satellite-imagery-in-r/" target="_blank">A Step-by-Step Guide to Making 3D Maps with Satellite Imagery in R</a>.</li><li><a href="https://ideas.esa.int/servlet/hype/IMT?documentTableId=45087622658433786&amp;userAction=Browse&amp;templateName=&amp;documentId=3817af91809ba52ab7cd2323267d5582" target="_blank">Submit new space mission ideas and concepts to ESA.</a></li><li>Cave of the Winds (<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/files/Cave_of_the_Winds.pdf" target="_blank">pdf</a>) is a book about the history of NASA Langley’s <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/centers/langley/news/factsheets/30X60.html" target="_blank">Full-Scale Wind Tunnel</a>, which was in operation for 64 years until it closed in 1995. It was “<em>used to test everything from World War II fighters, to submarines, to the Mercury capsule to concepts for a supersonic transport.</em>”</li><li> <a href="https://satnogs.org/2020/08/introducing-the-brand-new-satnogs-db/" target="_blank">SatNOGS DB launched with a new UI</a>, you can use it to learn about all the satellites they track.</li><li> <a href="https://history.nasa.gov/afj/ap11fj/cm-107_graffiti.html" target="_blank">Analysis of Handwritten Notes Inside the Cabin of Apollo 11 Spacecraft CM-107 "Columbia"</a>. The level of detail is wonderful.</li><li> <a href="http://beza1e1.tuxen.de/lore/moon_phases.html" target="_blank">Software that failed based on the phase of the Moon</a> at CERN: “<em>A few desperate engineers discovered the truth; the error turned out to be the result of a tiny change in the geometry of the 27km circumference ring, physically caused by the deformation of the Earth by the passage of the Moon!</em>”</li></ul></div><!--[if mso]> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]></table><![endif]--></div><div> <!--[if mso]><table align="left" border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="100%" style="width:100%;"><tr> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]><td valign="top" width="600" style="width:600px;"> <![endif]--><div><p><a href="#jobs">¶</a><strong id="jobs">Jobs</strong>.</p><ul><li>The newly launched <a href="https://spacetalent.org/" target="_blank">SpaceTalent.org</a> is a clearing house for finding a job in the industry, including resources for making the switch into aerospace.</li><li> <a href="https://www.pldspace.com/es/" target="_blank">PLD Space</a>, a European NewSpace startup working on reusable liquid fueled micro launchers, is <a href="https://twitter.com/pld_space/status/1300478458888290310?s=21" target="_blank">hiring a Senior Propulsion Engineer</a>.</li><li>NASA is seeking their <a href="https://twitter.com/Interplanetypod/status/1300816238873137153" target="_blank">next class of Flight Directors for Human Spaceflight missions</a>.</li></ul></div><!--[if mso]> <![endif]--> <!--[if mso]></table><![endif]--></div></td></tr><tr></tr></tbody></table><!--[if (gte mso 9)|(IE)]></table><![endif]--> </center></div></article></main><hy-drawer threshold="10" touch-events="" prevent-default=""></hy-drawer> </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://orbitalindex.com/archive/2020-09-02-Issue-80/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24392811</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 17:07:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Motion sensing using the doppler effect in browser]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24392808">thread link</a>) | @smusamashah
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://danielrapp.github.io/doppler/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://danielrapp.github.io/doppler/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
      
      <p>
        Recently I stumbled upon <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/groups/cue/publications/guptasoundwavechi2012.pdf">an interesting paper</a> for
        implementing motion sensing requiring no special hardware, <i>only a speaker and mic</i>! Unfortunately the paper didn't include
        code to test it, so I decided to reproduce it here on the web!
      </p>
      <video muted="" autoplay="autoplay" loop="loop" controls="" width="700" height="300">
        <source src="https://danielrapp.github.io/doppler/example.ogv" type="video/ogg">
      </video>

      <h2>What is the doppler effect?</h2>
      <p>
        First of all, what is the doppler effect?
        The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doppler_effect">doppler effect</a> is a physical phenomenom which affects waves in motion.
        The standard example is the effect on a fire engine siren as it quickly drives
        past. When it moves <i>towards</i> you the sound waves are compressed, and so the
        frequency becomes <i>higher</i>, and
        when it moves <i>away</i> from you the frequency becomes <i>lower</i>.
      </p>
      
      <p>
        This phenomenon actually has really wonderful applications in astronomy for figuring the speed
        at which galaxies are moving towards or away from us by looking at the frequency shift of light,
        but I digress.
      </p>
      <p>
        Anyway, it's important to realize that the doppler effect would also occur
        if you were to run towards the siren, rather than the siren moving towards you.
        We'll use this principle in the next section.
      </p>

      <h2>Measuring the doppler effect</h2>
      <p>
        In order to measure the doppler effect for motion detection on a conventional computer,
        what you can do is send out a sinusoid at some known (inaudible) frequency, say, 20 kHz.
        If something is moving in the room, then, after the sinusoid has bounced around on the walls and into the microphone, the
        sound will shift in frequency. This can be measured by looking at the frequency spectrum
        in the nearby region of the 20 kHz tone.
      </p>
      
      <p>
        <span>Note that you'll need to run Chrome with a fairly high speaker-volume for this to work optimally.</span>
      </p>
      <p>
        The frequency spectrum of the microphone input is plotted above. The peak towards the right
        is due to the 20 kHz tone we're sending out. Try <span data-note="440">whistling</span> to see the spectrum change.
      </p>
      
      <p>
        Here's a closer look, zooming in on the 20 kHz region.
        Try moving your hand <i>towards</i>
        the mic/computer to see the bulge shift to <i>higher</i> frequencies, and
        <i>away</i> from the computer to see it shift to <i>lower</i> frequencies.
      </p>

      <h2>Applications</h2>
      <p>
        Now for the fun applications!
      </p>

      <h3>Motion sensing</h3>
      <p>
        The most obvious application for this is motion sensing.
        Below I've calculated the left and right bandwidth of the 20 kHz
        region (defined as the number of frequencies to the left and right
        that are within 99.9% in amplitude of the 20 kHz tone).
        I've then attached their difference to the size of the box.
      </p>
      <canvas id="ball" width="700" height="100"></canvas>
      <p>
        The effect this produces is that when you move your hand <i>towards</i>
        the microphone, the box becomes smaller (you're <i>pushing</i>
        it inwards), and if you move your hand <i>away</i> from the microphone,
        the box becomes larger (you're <i>pulling</i> it outwards).
      </p>

      <h3>Scrolling</h3>
      
      <p>
        A cool application to motion sensing, as suggested by the
        <a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/um/redmond/groups/cue/publications/guptasoundwavechi2012.pdf">SoundWave paper</a>,
        is scrolling (see the video above). Click below to try it out.
      </p>
      
      <p>
        This implementation doesn't have the double-tap feature for reversing
        the scrolling-direction, instead it's just using the left and right bandwidth-difference.
        Thus if you want to scroll down you have to move your hand
        <i>quickly towards</i> the computer, and <i>slowly away</i> from the computer.
      </p>

      <h3>Theremin</h3>
      
      <p>
        We can also create an instrument with this by simply modulating
        the frequency of some base-tone, say at 440 Hz, based on the
        difference between the left and right bandwidth!
      </p>
      
      <p>
        This is reminiscent of a Theremin, in that you can contol
        sound by moving your hands in free space, yet different
        in that the Theremin is able to measure absolute distance from the base,
        whereas we can only measure relative motion.
      </p>

      <h2>Library</h2>
      <p>
        Did this give you any ideas? I also created <a href="https://github.com/DanielRapp/doppler">a small library</a> to play around with this.
        Just run
      </p>
        <pre><code>
  doppler.init(function(bandwidth) {
    var diff = bandwidth.left - bandwidth.right;
  });
        </code></pre>
      <p>
        to start experimenting.
      </p>

      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://danielrapp.github.io/doppler/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24392808</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 17:05:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Attention is your scarcest resource]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 544 | Comments 136 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24391686">thread link</a>) | @adambyrtek
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://www.benkuhn.net/attention/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.benkuhn.net/attention/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>Like many people, I have most of my best ideas in the shower.</p><p>This is sometimes annoying: I could use more than one shower’s worth of good ideas a day, but I’d rather not end up as a shrivelled yet insightful prune. Mostly, though, shower ideas are the incentive that keeps me smelling okay, so I grudgingly accept the constraint.</p><p>The time when it was most constraining was the first time I became a manager. I only had a few reports, so managing them wasn’t a full-time job. But I was very bad at it, and so it <em>should have</em> been what I spent all my shower insights on.</p><p>Unfortunately, I was spending my non-management time on programming. And even if I tried to use my showers to think about my thorny and awkward people issues, my mind somehow always wandered off to tackle those nice, juicy software design problems instead.</p><p>Management Attempt #1 didn’t go very well; being distracted by programming, I made lots of embarrassing mistakes that made my reports’ lives harder, which in turn made me feel stressed and guilty. I ended up bouncing back to being an individual contributor after a few months.</p><p>That experience of mine resonates strongly with Byrne Hobart’s <a href="https://diff.substack.com/p/the-future-of-remote-work-is-not" target="_blank">observation about focus in knowledge work</a>:</p><blockquote><p>The output of knowledge workers is extremely skewed based on focus. The productivity tiers seem to be:</p><ol><li><p>&lt;10% focused on the job at hand: meaningful risk of getting fired.</p></li><li><p>10-50% focus: “meets expectations,” gets regular raises.</p></li><li><p>50%+ focus: superstar, 10x engineer, destined for greatness.</p></li></ol></blockquote><p>“50%+ focus” is roughly when something becomes <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/top.html" target="_blank">the top idea in your mind</a>. It’s when you start caring enough to think about it in the shower. It’s when you start habitually asking “how could this go faster?” It’s when you get <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/relres.html" target="_blank">relentlessly resourceful</a>. It’s around when you start <a href="https://www.benkuhn.net/impatient/">annoying your coworkers and/or significant other</a>, although that part is avoidable with practice.</p><p>Most importantly, you can only be 50%+-focused on one thing at a time—or zero, in bad cases. That makes it critical to conserve your attention, so that you can spend it on what matters.</p><p>I’ve found a few different strategies that help me with this:</p><h3 id="care-viscerally">Care viscerally</h3><p>It’s hard to recruit 50%+ of your brain to work on something just because you feel like you “should” do it. Your superego might listen to this newfangled “logic” and “reason” stuff, but the monkey-era parts of your brain can’t be fooled so easily. To be reliably able to focus on something, you need to be intuitively, emotionally invested in the outcome.</p><p>For me, that’s not automatic—for instance, even though <a href="https://www.benkuhn.net/work/">I’m incredibly excited about what Wave is doing</a>, my day-to-day motivation gets worse if I work remotely for too long without visiting our operations in Senegal. Unless I can periodically see for myself that people are using the things we’re building, it starts feeling a little bit fake, like the so-called “real world” is a simulation that I can only communicate with via Slack channels and <code>git push</code>.</p><h3 id="monotask">Monotask</h3><p>As a programmer, I tried to make sure that I was only ever working on one thing at a time. Even if I got stuck on that one thing—say I was blocked on waiting for a tech partner to give me API documentation—I’d let myself stay stuck instead of sliding off to work on something else.</p><p>In the short term, this made me less efficient, because I’d spend less time programming and more time staring vacantly at the ceiling. But if I stared vacantly for long enough, I’d eventually get mad enough to, e.g., reverse-engineer the partner’s API in a fit of rage. This resulted in me shipping my most important projects faster, hence getting <a href="https://www.benkuhn.net/impatient/#startups">faster compounding growth</a>.</p><h3 id="evade-obligations">Evade obligations</h3><p>As a manager, it became impossible to “only work on one thing:” there were too many small tasks and too many projects going on in parallel. But I have a similar principle: I can only have one <em>obligation to other people</em>. “Give advice on this project?” Whenever you want! “Review my 1,000-line change?” Only if review isn’t blocking you from shipping it. “Check in every so often to make sure this doesn’t go off the rails?” Sorry, I have to, uh, powder my nose. “Figure out what the process should be?” I’ll get back to you in a couple years. (The best process is no process, right?)</p><p>During Management Attempt #1, my programming project distracted me so much because other people cared a lot that I finished it—if I ever had to de-prioritize it, I would make those people sad. This made it take up my attention (by worrying about letting people down) even when I wasn’t working on it. Unfortunately, since management work comes in urgent bursts, I’d often end up in a situation where I had to delay either the programming or the management—i.e., choose between making two different sets of people sad—and in those cases it was very hard for me to control my focus.</p><p>Now that I’ve noticed this, I allow myself to contribute to multiple things in parallel, as long as they don’t tax my object permanence skills—if I totally forgot about this project today, would anything bad happen? As long as the answer is no (usually because someone else is the one taking initiative to move things forward), I can be pretty sure that project won’t try to colonize my brain in the shower.</p><h3 id="timebox-bullshit">Timebox bullshit</h3><p>Even if I have only one major project that other people depend on, I somehow always end up with a bunch of minor chores to do—responding to emails, deflecting secondary obligations, buying household necessities, powdering my nose, filing expense reports, etc.</p><p>For these, I employ a “bullshit timebox”—a one-hour period a few times a week when I do <a href="http://paulgraham.com/vb.html" target="_blank">all the things life is too short for</a>. During the remaining 165 hours per week, I do my resolute best not to think about any of the bullshit, no matter how much people bug me about whether a <a href="https://thume.ca/2019/03/03/my-tungsten-cube/" target="_blank">1.5” tungsten cube</a> is really a legitimate work expense.</p><p>In order for bullshit not to distract me for the rest of the week, I try to minimize my number of “open loops”—projects or processes that I’ve started but not completed. Much like how I single-task on programming until it’s done, I’ll make phone calls instead of email threads, or, God forbid, texts or instant messaging. It took a while for me to train my friends not to instant message me, but by now they remember my rants about how distracting it is, practically word-for-word.</p><hr><p>Management Attempt #2 didn’t go great for me either. But I finally did an okay job at Management Attempt #3. Part of this was because I avoided repeating the particular mistakes of Attempts #1 and #2. But part of it was that on Attempt #3, our engineering team grew quickly enough that I went from “no managing” straight to “full-time managing” with no transitional period in which to be distracted, screw up and be miserable.</p><p>Once I was full-time managing, I had no shiny distractions and was able to spend my showers focusing on how to be a better manager. And once I was 50%+ focused, well, I haven’t become a “superstar 10x manager” yet, but I quickly stopped being 0.1x.</p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.benkuhn.net/attention/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24391686</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 14:46:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Understanding OAuth2 and OpenID Connect]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 121 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24391612">thread link</a>) | @bswamina
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://www.polarsparc.com/xhtml/OAuth2-OIDC.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.polarsparc.com/xhtml/OAuth2-OIDC.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <br>
    
    
    <p>Understanding OAuth2 and OpenID Connect</p>
    <br>
    
    <hr>
    
    <p>Overview</p>
    <div id="para-div">
      <p>There seems to be a lot of confusion around <span>OAuth2</span> and <span>OpenID Connect</span>
        (<span>OIDC</span> for short). In this article, we will go on a journey to understand and clarify what
        OAuth2 and OIDC really are.</p>
      <p>Alice is hosting a party and wants to send an invite a select group of friends. She plans to send a digital invitation via
        a site called <span>KoolInvitez</span>. The site needs a list of emails to send out the invitation. Alice stores
        all her contacts (as a collection of groups) in a site called <span>EzGroupContacts</span>. How should Alice
        provide access to the group called 'CloseFriends' in EzGroupContacts to KoolInvitez to send the invites ??? Should Alice
        provide her credentials for EzGroupContacts to KoolInvitez so it can access the contacts in the group 'CloseFriends' ???
        This is a security <span>anti-pattern</span> and *<span>NOT</span>* recommended. This is
        where OAuth2 comes in handy. Think of OAuth2 as a way of handing someone a <span>Valet</span> key, who will
        have limited access to perform their task. In other words, OAuth2 is an open standard for users to grant access to their
        information on a site or application to another site, but without revealing their credentials.</p>
      <p>OIDC, on the other hand, is an extension on top of OAuth2, that is used to verify the identify of a user (authentication)
        in a standard way. As an example, there are many sites that do not have any user registration and rely on Google or Facebook
        for identity verification (authentication).</p>
    </div>
    <p>Before we go any further, let us define some terms that will be useful in the context of OAuth2 and OIDC as follows:</p>
    <table id="col2-table">
      <thead><tr>
        <th>Term</th>
        <th>Description</th>
      </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Resource</span></td>
          <td>Data or information that a user owns (Ex: the contact list 'CloseFriends')</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Resource Owner</span></td>
          <td>The owner of a Resource (Ex: Alice)</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Resource Server</span></td>
          <td>The server where the Resource is hosted (Ex: EzGroupContacts)</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Client</span></td>
          <td>An application or a site that needs access to a user Resource (Ex: KoolInvitez)</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Authorization Server</span></td>
          <td>The OAuth2/ODIC server where a user grants a consent to a Client, to access their Resource(s)</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Access Token</span></td>
          <td>A security token which the Client can present to the Resource Server to get access to a user's
            Resource</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Front Channel</span></td>
          <td>Requests coming from a user agent (such as a web browser) to a server</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><span>Back Channel</span></td>
          <td>Requests coming from a server to another server. This is done for security reasons</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
    <p>The basic *<span>FUNDAMENTAL</span>* flow of OAuth2 is referred to as the <span>Autorization
        Code</span> flow and all the other flows are variations of this basic flow. The Auorization Code flow works as follows:</p>
    <div id="para-div">
      <ul id="blue-sqr-ul">
        <li>
          <p><span>1</span> :: the Resource Owner launches the Client to initiate the flow</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>2</span> :: the Client makes a request to the Authorization Server from the Front Channel for an
            authorization code (<span>/auth_code</span>) passing in an URL to respond back to (<span>/callback
            </span>) at the Client</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>3</span> :: the Authorization Server redirects the Resource Owner to the Resource Server for user
            authentication and access grant</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>4</span> :: the Resource Owner enters valid credentials that is verified by the Resource Server and
            redirects back to the Authorization Server</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>5</span> :: the Authorization Server generates an Authorization Code and responds back to the Client
            with the authorization code on the Back Channel at the specified URL (<span>/callback</span>)</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>6</span> :: the Client makes a request to the Authorization Server for an Access Token through the
            Back Channel</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>7</span> :: the Authorization Server responds back to the Client with an Access Token on the Back
            Channel</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>8</span> :: the Client uses the Access Token to make a request to access the Resource at the Resource
            Server</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p><span>9</span> :: the Resource Server responds with the data associated with the Resource</p>
        </li>
      </ul>
    </div>
    <p>The following diagram illustrates the basic Authorization Code flow:</p>
    <br>
    <div id="img-outer-div"> <p><img src="https://www.polarsparc.com/xhtml/images/oauth-01.png" alt="Basic Flow"></p><p>Figure.1</p>
    </div>
    
    <p><span>NOTE</span> :: In some cases, the Authorization Server and the Resource Server may be ONE.</p>
    <p>Installation and Setup</p>
    <div id="para-div">
      <p>The installation will be on a <span>Ubuntu 20.04 LTS</span> based Linux desktop.</p>
      <p>Ensure <span>Docker</span> is installed on the system. Else, follow the instructions provided in the article
        <a href="https://www.polarsparc.com/xhtml/Docker.html" target="_blank"><span>Introduction to Docker</span></a>
        to complete the installation.</p>
    </div>
    <p>There are few open source implementations of the Authorization Server that implement the OAuth2/OIDC standards as follows:</p>
    
    <div id="para-div">
      <p>For our setup and demonstration, we will use the <span>Keycloak</span> Authorization Server in conjuction
        with the <span>PostgreSQL</span> database.</p>
      <p>Check the latest stable version for <a href="https://hub.docker.com/_/postgres" target="_blank"><span>Postgres
        </span></a> docker image. Version <span>12.4</span> was the latest at the time of this article.</p>
      <p>To download the latest docker image for <span>Postgres</span>, execute the following command:</p>
    </div>
    <p>$ docker pull postgres:12.4</p>
    <p>The following would be a typical output:</p>
    <div id="out-div">
      <h4>Output.1</h4>
      <pre>12.4: Pulling from library/postgres
bf5952930446: Pull complete 
9577476abb00: Pull complete 
2bd105512d5c: Pull complete 
b1cd21c26e81: Pull complete 
34a7c86cf8fc: Pull complete 
274e7b0c38d5: Pull complete 
3e831b350d37: Pull complete 
38fa0d496534: Pull complete 
c989da35e5c0: Pull complete 
26dc6fdd7b2d: Pull complete 
3c5032512cf3: Pull complete 
26910ececf99: Pull complete 
0339413523e8: Pull complete 
d61df7db53da: Pull complete 
Digest: sha256:9f325740426d14a92f71013796d98a50fe385da64a7c5b6b753d0705add05a21
Status: Downloaded newer image for postgres:12.4
docker.io/library/postgres:12.4</pre>
    </div>
    <div id="para-div">
      <p>Check the latest stable version for <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/jboss/keycloak" target="_blank"><span>
        Keycloak</span></a> docker image. Version <span>11.0.1</span> was the latest at the time of this article.</p>
      <p>To download the latest docker image for <span>Keycloak</span>, execute the following command:</p>
    </div>
    <p>$ docker pull jboss/keycloak:11.0.1</p>
    <p>The following would be a typical output:</p>
    <div id="out-div">
      <h4>Output.2</h4>
      <pre>11.0.1: Pulling from jboss/keycloak
41ae95b593e0: Pull complete 
f20f68829d13: Pull complete 
6c304f8c55f0: Pull complete 
7db1d4725e09: Pull complete 
59cf4c955406: Pull complete 
Digest: sha256:d7cb114cdb5dcc4b2c9b56ac7b827249596491db02bb82177edb42413056aa13
Status: Downloaded newer image for jboss/keycloak:11.0.1
docker.io/jboss/keycloak:11.0.1</pre>
    </div>
    <p>To create a new bridge network called <span>my-iam-net</span>, execute the following command:</p>
    <p>$ docker network create my-iam-net</p>
    <p>The following would be a typical output:</p>
    <div id="out-div">
      <h4>Output.3</h4>
      <pre>64852330d28ade21943e0d8acfcf91fe4037c4f378d40c97f5b902e70674003d</pre>
    </div>
    <div id="para-div">
      <p>We will store the database files in the directory <span>$HOME/Downloads/DATA/postgres</span> on the host.</p>
      <p>To start the Postgres database, execute the following command:</p>
    </div>
    <p>$ docker run -d --rm --name postgres --net my-iam-net -e POSTGRES_DB=keycloak -e POSTGRES_USER=keycloak -e POSTGRES_PASSWORD=keycloak\$123 -p 5432:5432 -v $HOME/Downloads/DATA/postgres:/var/lib/postgresql/data postgres:12.4</p>
    <p>The following would be a typical output:</p>
    <div id="out-div">
      <h4>Output.4</h4>
      <pre>26e000434238aea7a1f6cace9be81d243a3a37f6ab7cfdef3625ed03b0e296f1</pre>
    </div>
    <p>To check the Postgres database logs, execute the following command:</p>
    <p>$ docker logs postgres</p>
    <p>The following would be a typical output:</p>
    <div id="out-div">
      <h4>Output.5</h4>
      <pre>...
...
...
PostgreSQL init process complete; ready for start up.

2020-08-29 17:07:00.296 UTC [1] LOG:  starting PostgreSQL 12.4 (Debian 12.4-1.pgdg100+1) on x86_64-pc-linux-gnu, compiled by gcc (Debian 8.3.0-6) 8.3.0, 64-bit
2020-08-29 17:07:00.296 UTC [1] LOG:  listening on IPv4 address "0.0.0.0", port 5432
2020-08-29 17:07:00.296 UTC [1] LOG:  listening on IPv6 address "::", port 5432
2020-08-29 17:07:00.299 UTC [1] LOG:  listening on Unix socket "/var/run/postgresql/.s.PGSQL.5432"
2020-08-29 17:07:00.316 UTC [65] LOG:  database system was shut down at 2020-08-29 17:07:00 UTC
2020-08-29 17:07:00.321 UTC [1] LOG:  database system is ready to accept connections</pre>
    </div>
    <br>
    <div id="warn-div">
      <h4>!!! ATTENTION !!!</h4>
      <pre>Logs in the article have been trimmed to just show the pieces relevant to the context<br>The lines with three dots '...' indicates code that has been truncated</pre>
    </div>
    <p>To start the Keycloak OAuth2/ODIC server, execute the following command:</p>
    <p>$ docker run --name keycloak --net my-iam-net -e DB_VENDOR=POSTGRES -e DB_DATABASE=keycloak -e DB_SCHEMA=public -e DB_ADDR=postgres -e DB_PORT=5432 -e DB_USER=keycloak -e DB_PASSWORD=keycloak\$123 -e KEYCLOAK_USER=admin -e KEYCLOAK_PASSWORD=kc_admin\$123 -p 8080:8080 jboss/keycloak:11.0.1</p>
    <p>The following would be a typical output:</p>
    <div id="out-div">
      <h4>Output.6</h4>
      <pre>Added 'admin' to '/opt/jboss/keycloak/standalone/configuration/keycloak-add-user.json', restart server to load user
-b 0.0.0.0
=========================================================================

  Using PostgreSQL database

=========================================================================

17:12:51,436 INFO  [org.jboss.modules] (CLI command executor) JBoss Modules version 1.10.1.Final
17:12:51,486 INFO  [org.jboss.msc] (CLI command executor) JBoss MSC version 1.4.11.Final
17:12:51,494 INFO  [org.jboss.threads] (CLI command executor) JBoss Threads version 2.3.3.Final
17:12:51,585 INFO  [org.jboss.as] (MSC service thread 1-2) WFLYSRV0049: Keycloak 11.0.1 (WildFly Core 12.0.3.Final) starting
17:12:51,668 INFO  [org.jboss.vfs] (MSC service thread 1-7) VFS000002: Failed to clean existing content for temp file provider of type temp. Enable DEBUG level log to find what caused this
...
...
...
The batch executed successfully
17:12:55,936 INFO  [org.jboss.as] (MSC service thread 1-3) WFLYSRV0050: Keycloak 11.0.1 (WildFly Core 12.0.3.Final) stopped in 14ms
=========================================================================

  JBoss Bootstrap Environment

  JBOSS_HOME: /opt/jboss/keycloak

  JAVA: java

  JAVA_OPTS:  -server -Xms64m -Xmx512m …</pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.polarsparc.com/xhtml/OAuth2-OIDC.html">https://www.polarsparc.com/xhtml/OAuth2-OIDC.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.polarsparc.com/xhtml/OAuth2-OIDC.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24391612</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 14:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Meta-Layer for Notes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24391166">thread link</a>) | @julian_digital
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://julian.digital/2020/09/04/a-meta-layer-for | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://julian.digital/2020/09/04/a-meta-layer-for">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
 		
<h3>What’s the digital equivalent of sticky notes?</h3>



<p><span>01</span> Hey</p>



<p>This was originally supposed to be a blog post about <a href="https://www.hey.com/">Hey</a>. I wanted to write a longer essay about Basecamp’s new email tool and test if the app actually lives up to its hype.</p>



<p>After playing around with it for a few weeks, my conclusion is this: <strong>Hey’s most interesting aspect is not its radical approach to email – but its fresh approach to note taking!</strong></p>



<p>We have long treated notes as a distinct silo in our productivity stack, when we should have integrated them right into our workflows instead. While email might need an overhaul, I see a way bigger opportunity in rethinking digital note taking.</p>



<p>So instead of my Hey review, let’s talk about notes and my idea for a radically new kind of note taking app.</p>



<p><span>02</span> A Closer Look at Notes in Hey</p>



<p>Hey has two interesting notes features.</p>



<p>The first are so-called <a href="https://hey.com/features/thread-notes/">Thread Notes</a>. These are basically emails to yourself within an email thread that only you can see. You might have seen similar internal notes features in shared inbox tools like Zendesk or Front. Thread Notes in Hey are effectively the single player version of those.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/threadnotes.png"></p><p>I’d find Thread Notes super useful in combination with snoozed emails: <em>“Show me this email again in [insert time] and remind me of [insert note]”</em></p>



<p>This feels like a way better workflow than adding a note in a separate reminder, to-do, CRM, or note taking app.</p>



<p>a) Because there’s no need for context/app switching.<br>b) You might not even remember that you took a note related to an email when it resurfaces in your inbox a few weeks later.</p>



<p>To-do and reminder apps (and calendars!) work great for tasks that are tied to a specific day or time. But many tasks – and especially notes – are not dependent on time. Their relevance is based on other trigger points. Only when certain conditions are met, should these notes resurface: <em>“If [insert event] is true, then show [note]”</em></p>



<p>In the case of our email, the note becomes relevant in <em>[insert snooze time]</em> or whenever the recipient replies to the email thread. The fact that many tasks have external dependencies (which are usually linked to an email thread)  is one of the reasons I believe that your email inbox should also be the place where you manage your to-dos. <a href="http://julian.digital/2020/01/17/superhuman-the-productivity-meta-layer/">You shouldn’t need a separate to-do app</a>.</p>



<center>—</center>



<p>The second note feature in Hey are <a href="https://hey.com/features/inbox-notes/">Inbox Notes</a>.</p>



<p>As the name suggests, these notes are added to individual emails in your inbox. Similar to Thread Notes, you can use them to quickly jot down things you need to remember, but they also help you to highlight specific emails.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/inboxnotesimp.png"></p><p>Thread Notes and Inbox Notes feel similar, but they serve two slightly different use cases. Thread Notes work more like reminders (<em>“Don’t forget X when you reply”</em>), whereas Inbox Notes feel more like bookmarks that highlight the most important messages in a long list of emails. </p>



<p>Together, they remind me of one of my all-time favorite note taking tools: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Post-it_Note">Post-it Notes</a>.</p>



<p><span>03</span> Post-it Notes</p>



<p>I’m a huge fan of physical note taking and there are two writing tools that I use every single day: A physical notebook (for longer thoughts, including first drafts of my blog posts) and post-it notes (for all kinds of quick notes).</p>



<p>(Disclaimer: When I say “post-it notes” I’m referring to all types of sticky notes, not just those sold by 3M.)</p>



<p>Post-it notes serve two of the same functions that Hey’s note features offer: highlights and reminders.</p>



<p>One of the reasons I still read a lot of non-fiction in physical book form is because it’s easier to bookmark and annotate passages that I quickly want to find again later. Similar to Thread Notes, sticky note bookmarks help me <strong>highlight</strong> the most important items in a long list.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/postithighlight-1.png"></p><p>Apart from helping you find important passages in a book later on, sticky note bookmarks also allow you to add additional context to the section you highlighted (e.g. *why* you bookmarked a particular section or thoughts you had about it). </p>



<p>You could write down notes like this in a separate notebook, but then you’d lose the connection to the source they are based on. <strong>What makes post-it notes so interesting is the spatial relationship between the notes and their respective context.</strong></p>



<p>It’s this spatial relationship that also make post-it notes great <strong>reminders</strong>.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/postitreminders.png"></p><p>Post-it note reminders are similar to Hey’s Thread Notes in that they are triggered not based on time but on events that don’t have a (forecastable) deadline. They are essentially like notifications that appear when you look at specific objects.</p>



<p>A post-it note on your front door, for example, is like a notification that pops up when you’re about to leave the house: <em>“Before you go, don’t forget to [insert note]”</em>. A shopping list on your fridge is a data request notification that surfaces when you are most likely to have new items to add to your list.</p>



<p>Together, post-its essentially become a notes layer that augments the real world. Instead of a physical notebook that lists all your notes and tasks in chronological order, post-it notes are scattered around your house but tied to specific places or objects where they are most relevant.</p>



<p>The question is: <strong>Why isn’t there a digital note taking tool that works like this?</strong></p>



<p><span>04</span> A Spatial Note Taking Layer</p>



<p>There are dozens of great note taking apps out there: Evernote, Google Keep, Apple Notes, Workflowy, Notion, Roam … the list goes on and on. Every one of these tools has its own unique angle on note taking, but they all have one thing in common: They are stand-alone apps.</p>



<p>This strikes me as suboptimal. Neither the creation nor the consumption of notes should be treated as separate workflows.</p>



<p>As John Palmer points out in his brilliant posts on <a href="https://darkblueheaven.com/spatialinterfaces/">Spatial Interfaces</a> and <a href="https://darkblueheaven.com/spatialsoftware">Spatial Software</a>, “Humans are spatial creatures [who] experience most of life in relation to space”. Post-it notes are so powerful because they have a spatial relationship to their context.</p>



<p>Many notes shouldn’t live in a dedicated note taking app that you explicitly have to open and search. Notes should emerge automatically whenever and *wherever* they are most relevant.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/statusquonotes-1.png"></p><p>As long as note taking remains separated, users constantly have to switch back and forth between different applications, which is not ideal. It reminds me of <a href="https://kwokchain.com/2019/08/16/the-arc-of-collaboration/">the recent discussion around productivity and collaboration</a> – which have historically also been treated as two separate, isolated workflows:</p>



<p><i>The platonic flow of productivity should minimize time spent not productive, with collaboration as aligned and unblocking with that flow as possible. By definition, any app that requires you to switch out of your productivity app to collaborate is blocking and cannot be maximally aligned. It’s fine to leave your productivity app for exceptions and breaks. But not ideal when working.</i></p>



<p>The same applies to notes. You shouldn’t have to switch apps and context to take or consume notes. It should stay within the same workflow!</p>



<p>(Side Note: You could argue that note taking is essentially single-player collaboration where you communicate with your future self – but that’s a whole new discussion I’ll save for another blog post.)</p>



<p>Natively built in note taking features like email notes in Hey feel like a good step in the right direction – but email is just one distinct silo in your productivity stack. Imagine you had to buy different sets of post-it notes for every single room or object in your house.</p>



<p>What we need instead is a spatial meta layer for notes on the OS-level that lives across all apps and workflows. This would allow you to instantly take notes without having to switch context. Even better yet, the notes would automatically resurface whenever you revisit the digital location you left them at.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/noteslayer-1.png"></p><p>Let’s look at a few examples.</p>



<p><span>05</span> Examples</p>



<p>One use case that immediately came to mind when I thought about spatial notes is bookmarking.</p>



<p>Most of us don’t use just one bookmarking app for everything. We use different bookmarking apps or bookmarking features depending on the type of object we want to save for later: Podcasts are usually saved in a dedicated podcast app, for example. Articles are bookmarked in Pocket, books on Goodreads, songs on Spotify, places on Foursquare, products on Amazon … you get my point.</p>



<p>Bookmarks are great to remember *what* you want to revisit later – but not *why* you saved something in the first place. I would love to be able to add notes to my bookmarks directly in each app so that I have some context on why these objects are important when I return to them later.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/podcastnote.png"></p><p>Ideally, these notes wouldn’t just show up in the one place I originally left them, but across all apps and websites that reference the (semantic) object I bookmarked. A note attached to a book I want to read in Goodreads, for example, should also emerge when I see that book in my Amazon search results – or when someone mentions it in my Twitter timeline.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/goodamznnotes.png"></p><p>People are a similar type of semantic object you could tie notes to. Instead of a stand-alone CRM tool, you would leave a note attached to a person straight from your current workflow (e.g. your email client). That note would then automatically re-surface whenever the person it references becomes relevant again:</p>



<ul><li>When you’re in an email thread with them</li><li>When you add them to a calendar event</li><li>When you’re visiting their LinkedIn page</li><li>When you look them up in your phone book</li><li>etc</li></ul>



<center>—</center>



<p>Another use case for spatial notes are instructions on how to use specific software features or improve workflows. These could be quick reminders to add permissions to new calendar events or to use Filtered Views in Google Sheets. You could also use these notes to train users on keyboard shortcuts.</p>



<p><img src="https://julian.digital/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/relief.png"></p><p>You could imagine employers shipping corporate laptops with pre-installed notes to make it easier to transfer (previously tacit) knowledge and thus improve the onboarding process for new hires.</p>



<p><span>06</span> Closing Notes</p>



<p>I could go on and on …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://julian.digital/2020/09/04/a-meta-layer-for">https://julian.digital/2020/09/04/a-meta-layer-for</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://julian.digital/2020/09/04/a-meta-layer-for</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24391166</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:31:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Unlearning The 'Nation State']]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 41 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24391129">thread link</a>) | @softwaredoug
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://softwaredoug.com/unlearning/2020/09/05/unlearning-the-nation-state.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://softwaredoug.com/unlearning/2020/09/05/unlearning-the-nation-state.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	  <p>As the 2020 US Presidential election grinds on, it makes me wonder if we need to unlearn the idea of a Nation State. The assumption that geographically collocated people share the same core identity and values seems quaint in just about every nation state these days. If we unlearn this increasingly fallacious idea, we might open ourselves up to something new.</p>

<p>I live in a small, Virginia college town, Charlottesville. We share increasingly little in common with people living 30 miles away. With no shared values, not even a shared perspective of what’s true, it makes little sense to share political institutions. We live in different worlds - I bet many Charlottesvillians could navigate the London Tube with greater ease than the streets of nearby Dillwyn or Buena Vista. The interaction between these groups occurs purely on economic lines, often in <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/the-avenue/2019/09/10/america-has-two-economies-and-theyre-diverging-fast/">two parallel economies</a>.</p>

<p>Even more, if you put me in a room with a random Berliner or Londoner, It’s likely we would share a similar positive attitude towards diversity and inclusion. We’d enjoy similar sources of culture and entertainment, perhaps even curious about each other’s weird sports. There’s probably even a greater likelihood we’d discuss political ideas with an open mind. Indeed, I’ve had more conversations about Brexit with a British person than about Trump with a Trump supporter. Increasingly, we have a shared outlook with other educated, urban places around the world. We feel alien to fellow Americans, Brits, or Germans that live a stone’s throw away.</p>

<p>Instead of different nation states, the world’s turning into one big emerging city with a large, vast, global hinterland. With the Internet and easy air travel - Manhattan, SOHO, and Pankow feel like different neighborhoods in the same global city – not identical, but increasingly cut from a similar cloth. All supporting increasingly culturally aligned knowledge workers. Some places (like a college town, or small city) feel less ‘central’ to the emerging one-global-city, similar to an outer suburb. Some places seem much more central (Manhattan?). And certainly the ‘neighborhoods’ I know about are more culturally nearby. But that will certainly change over the 21st century as places (and people) sort themselves closer or farther from the center. (And even in a ‘remote centric’ world, this’ll be true, as we need places with good Internet and comparable social values)</p>

<p>The hinterlands deeply resent the emerging, educated, cosmopolitan one-global-city. Certainty, this had a lot to do with Trump being elected. Fear that a multicultural knowledge economy might trump nation state protected privileges runs deep. This fear underpins much of the anti-intellectualism and anti-immigration extremism in these groups. Notably Trump also seems to evoke a kind of nostalgia about an 80s era strong American nation state and criticizes opponents for supporting “open borders” and not being “true Americans”. This division between one-global-city nation-state-first perspectives goes beyond the US. It’s happening in Poland, Turkey, Germany and just about everywhere.</p>

<p>If we unlearn the nation state, we might begin to see this emerging, new society. Some might be brave enough to embrace it as an explicit, core ideology. This might let us build new institutions centered on this one-global-city. The closest institutions we have right now are heavily globalized tech companies . They explicitly work to build multi-national workforces, heavily aware of the inclusion and multiculturalism needed to pull something like this off. Certainly methods of collaborating in tech, such as sharing code on Github, and participating in common communities also underpins the one-global-city. Social media might provide a kind of hub for the one-global-city (as well as the disaffected).</p>

<p>But there’s reasons to be skeptical too. As the one-global-city develops, it will push more and more marginalized people out to the hinterlands. A one-global-city with aligned / same political institutions is perhaps an educated elite fiction. Or if it exists, it’s not morally superior to a nation state that looks out for all it’s citizens. A one-global-city might turn into a caste society, with upper class tech / knowledge workers and then everyone else. We’ll continue to live in an awkward economic sybmiosis. Like two species that both need and hate each other. Always at low-level of conflict, but not enough to blow out into some massive war.</p>

<p>Maybe, in the end, it’s the one-global city – the globalized, neo-liberal, New World Order that will need to be unlearned. Perhaps, it’s the hinterlands that will tame their elites - attenuating their ability to connect with the rest of the world. Nation states reassert themselves as explicitly anti-intellectual, parochial entities. Sometimes choosing ignorance and isolation to maintain national sovereignty.</p>

<p>Who knows? It’ll be interesting to observe the rest of my life to maybe find out?</p>

      
      <p><small>

      Special Thanks to
       
      <a href="http://blog.jnbrymn.com/">John Berryman</a>

      
      for reviewing this post and giving substantive edits and feedback!
      </small>
      


	  </p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://softwaredoug.com/unlearning/2020/09/05/unlearning-the-nation-state.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24391129</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:23:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Common color mistakes and how to avoid them]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 734 | Comments 111 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24391049">thread link</a>) | @hunvreus
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
            <p><img alt="header image" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors34.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors34.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors34.png"></p>
<p>Choosing good colors for your charts is hard. This article tries to make it easier.</p>
<p>I want you to feel more confident in your color choices. And if you have no sense for colors at all, here’s my attempt to help you find good ones anyway. We’ll talk about common color mistakes I see out there in the wild, and how to avoid them.</p>
<p>This is not the right article for you if you’re trying to find good gradients or shades. But if you need to find beautiful, distinctive colors for different <strong>categories (e.g. continents, industries, bird species)</strong> for your line charts, pie charts, stacked bar charts, etc., read on.</p>
<p><img alt="different data visualizations" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors-f.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors-f.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors-f.png"><em>Visualized categories by <a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-56-best-and-weirdest-charts-we-made-in-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FiveThirtyEight</a>, <a href="https://whydocatsanddogs.com/cats" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nadieh Bremer</a>, <a href="https://congress.pudding.cool/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Pudding</a>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/10/14/us/politics/democrats-political-facebook-ads.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">New York Times</a>, <a href="https://infographics.economist.com/2019/AChristmasGiftForYou/AYearInGraphicDetail.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Economist</a> and <a href="https://medium.com/accurat-studio/beautiful-reasons-c1c6926ab7d7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Akkurat</a></em></p>
<h4 id="Index">Index</h4>
<p><a href="#0"><b>00</b> Before we start…</a><br>
<a href="#1"><b>01</b> Broaden your understanding of colors</a><br>
<a href="#2"><b>02</b> Don’t dance all over the color wheel</a><br>
<a href="#3"><b>03</b> Use saturation and lightness to make your hues work</a><br>
<a href="#4"><b>04</b> Use warm colors &amp; blue</a><br>
<a href="#5"><b>05</b> When using green, make it a yellow or blue one</a><br>
<a href="#6"><b>06</b> Avoid pure colors</a><br>
<a href="#7"><b>07</b> Avoid bright, saturated colors</a><br>
<a href="#8"><b>08</b> Combine colors with different lightness</a><br>
<a href="#9"><b>09</b> Make your colors similarly “colorful”</a><br>
<a href="#10"><b>10</b> Avoid too little contrast to the background</a><br>
<a href="#11"><b>11</b> Avoid too much contrast to the background</a><br>
<a href="#12"><b>12</b> Choose a background that’s desaturated enough</a><br>
<a href="#13"><b>13</b> Copy colors, or understand them</a></p>

<h4 id="Before-we-start…">Before we start…</h4>
<p>I will mention saturation, brightness and hue a lot. The HSB (<strong>H</strong>ue, <strong>S</strong>aturation, <strong>B</strong>rightness) or HSV (<strong>H</strong>ue, <strong>S</strong>aturation, <strong>V</strong>alue) color spaces work fairly well to check them:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Hue</strong> ranges from 0° to 360°…that’s your typical color wheel: <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span></li>
<li><strong>Saturation</strong> ranges from 0% (grey) to 100% (super duper colorful!!): <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span></li>
<li><strong>Brightness/Value</strong> ranges from 0% (black) to 100% (the actual color): <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span></li>
</ul>
<p>To convert your colors from HEX (e.g. <code>#cc0000</code>) or RGB (e.g. <code>rgb(207, 176, 58)</code>) to HSB/HSV, use a tool like <a href="http://colorizer.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>colorizer.org</strong></a>.</p>
<p>A relative of HSB/HSV is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HCL_color_space" target="_blank" rel="noopener">HCL</a> color space. It uses the same parameters (<strong>H</strong>ue, <strong>C</strong>hroma = saturation, <strong>L</strong>ightness), but is closer to “how we really see colors”. <a href="https://academy.datawrapper.de/article/255-how-to-pick-colors-in-datawrapper" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>Datawrapper</strong> uses the HCL color space</a> for its color picker:</p>
<p><img alt="HCL color picker in Datawrapper" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors31.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors31.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors31.png"></p>
<p>But since you won’t find HCL in Adobe Photoshop or <a href="http://colorizer.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">colorizer.org</a>, every time I mention degrees (like 0°) or percentages, I’ll be talking about the HSB/HSV color space.</p>
<p>Alright, let’s do this:</p>

<h4 id="Broaden-your-understanding-of-colors">Broaden your understanding of colors</h4>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors30.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors30.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors30.png"></p>
<p>You might think like this: “I need five colors for my chart. So I use green and yellow and blue and red. And …um…maybe orange? Or purple!”</p>
<p>If you haven’t thought much about colors since you were a kid coloring out your coloring book, this thought makes sense. So today I’m here to tell you: They are more colors than that.</p>
<p>Look at this graphic and compare them with the basic colors <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>:</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors13.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors13.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors13.png"><em><a href="https://whydocatsanddogs.com/cats" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Why do Cats and Dogs?</a> by Nadieh Bremer</em></p>
<p>They’re different. The red that Nadieh uses <span>⬤</span> is different from your typical red <span>⬤</span>. The green <span>⬤</span> is…can you even call it a green <span>⬤</span>?</p>
<p>So before we impose rules that limit us, let me freak you out a bit: There are thousands of colors you can use. There is yellow-ish red <span>⬤</span> and blue-ish red <span>⬤</span> and everything in between. There is grey <span>⬤</span>, but there is also cold grey <span>⬤</span> and there is warm grey <span>⬤</span>. And then there is blue. So much blue! Like this <span>⬤</span>, this <span>⬤</span>, this <span>⬤</span>, this <span>⬤</span> and this <span>⬤</span>. And we haven’t even talked about orange and yellow.</p>
<p>You have <em>lots</em> of options. Which means you can stay in a small area of the color wheel and still have many options. Which means:</p>

<h4 id="Don’t-dance-all-over-the-color-wheel">Don’t dance all over the color wheel</h4>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors28.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors28.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors28.png"></p>
<p>There’s no need to rely on hues from all around the color wheel like <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span> for your visualizations. It will look more professional – and therefore more trustworthy – when it only uses a few hues and their neighbors.</p>
<p>Here’s where it becomes a good idea to actually look at a color wheel. You can use <a href="https://color.adobe.com/create/color-wheel" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Adobe Color</a> or <a href="https://www.sessions.edu/color-calculator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Color Calculator</a> to do so.</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors21.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors21.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors21.png"><em><a href="https://www.sessions.edu/color-calculator/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Color Calculator</a> harmonies</em></p>
<p>Lots of these tools let you choose different harmonies. One of them is called “square” or “tetradic”. <strong>Don’t use it.</strong> It will result in too many hues –&nbsp;and we’re on a mission to avoid that.</p>
<video autoplay="" loop="" muted="">
  <source src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/200805_goodcolors20.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<p>In the video above, I used the color tool <a href="https://paletton.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paletton</a> to start with a tetradic harmony and then decrease the distance. Note how more beautiful the color combinations become.</p>
<p>If the distance becomes small enough, you’re basically using <strong>complementary</strong> colors. And that’s a great choice! Lots of complementary color pairs work awesome together. <strong>If in doubt, use complementary colors and their neighbors.</strong></p>
<p>So let’s do this –&nbsp;this time with Adobe Color:</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors22.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors22.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors22.png"><em>Our complementary colors in <a href="https://color.adobe.com/create/color-wheel" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Adobe Color</a></em></p>
<p>Our colors are opposite each other on the color wheel, so they’re clearly complementary. Yay! But they’re also unusable: The two oranges are way too similar. And everything looks so…bright.</p>
<p>There’s where we need to change the saturation and lightness:</p>

<h4 id="Use-saturation-and-lightness-to-make-your-hues-work">Use saturation and lightness to make your hues work</h4>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors27.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors27.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors27.png"></p>
<p>Saturation and brightness are as important as hue. In fact, you can create new colors when you just change the saturation and brightness. Here are two color pairs with the same hue, just different saturation and lightness: <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span> / <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>. (If you change the hue just a tiny bit, you’ll achieve even better results: <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span> / <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>.)</p>
<p>Let’s come back to our color combination: <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>. After playing around with the saturation and darkness, it becomes this:</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors23.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors23.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors23.png"><em>Our better (!) complementary colors in <a href="https://color.adobe.com/create/color-wheel" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Adobe Color</a></em></p>
<p>I desaturated the light blue <span>⬤</span> and the lighter orange <span>⬤</span> and made every color darker except the lighter orange. Heck yeah, we can work with that!</p>
<p>So if your color combination doesn’t look awesome yet, don’t immediately add another hue. <strong>Change the saturation and lightness first and see if that’s better.</strong></p>
<p>That’s what I did to all of these color palettes: <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span> and <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span> and <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>. They’re all roughly complementary, and they all come with different saturations and lightness. That’s what makes them work.</p>

<h4 id="Use-warm-colors-blue">Use warm colors &amp; blue</h4>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors29.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors29.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors29.png"></p>
<p>There’s a complementary color combination that is especially loved by data visualization designers: <strong>yellow/orange/red and blue</strong>. Scroll through graphics portfolios like the one from the <a href="https://multimedia.scmp.com/culture/article/SCMP-printed-graphics-memory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">South China Morning Post</a> or this one by <a href="https://infographics.economist.com/2019/AChristmasGiftForYou/AYearInGraphicDetail.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Economist (PDF)</a> and you’ll notice that they use these colors far more often than colors like purple or green.</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors19.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors19.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors19.png"><em><a href="https://multimedia.scmp.com/culture/article/SCMP-printed-graphics-memory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Three pages by The South China Morning Post</a></em></p>
<p>That’s because these warm colors and blue are super versatile for categories. Yellow and orange and red look very pleasing together, but people will still perceive them as different colors: <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span> –&nbsp;which is exactly what we want for categorical colors. And blue is more flexible than any other hue: Lots of blues, no matter if dark <span>⬤</span> or light <span>⬤</span> or saturated <span>⬤</span> or not saturated <span>⬤</span>, look pleasing, calming and professional.</p>
<p>And they are accessible: colorblind people can easily distinguish blue and orange/red from each other.</p>
<p>So if in doubt, use an orange/red with blue.</p>

<h4 id="When-using-green-make-it-a-yellow-or-blue-one">When using green, make it a yellow or blue one</h4>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors26.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors26.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors26.png"></p>
<p>Forest green covers a full sixth on the color wheel, from approximately 90° <span>⬤</span> to 150° <span>⬤</span>, with 120° as its peak <span>⬤</span>. However, you will find few well-designed visualizations that use it. Why is that?</p>
<p>First, forest green is just very dark. And lightening up the forest green means going into an awkward neon <span>⬤</span>. So you need to lighten up <em>and</em> desaturate green enormously – more than other colors –&nbsp;to get to a nice one. That’s exactly what the Washington Post does with their green <span>⬤</span> here:</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors17.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors17.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors17.png"><em><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/politics/trump-rolling-back-obama-rules/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">How Trump is rolling back Obama’s legacy<br>
</a> by The Washington Post</em></p>
<p>It’s a 142° green, but only 14% saturated. Here’s what the same hue with the same brightness would look like 100% saturated: <span>⬤</span>. Yikes.</p>
<p>And remember our colorblind friends: A pure green in combination with red, orange or brown is hard for them to distinguish.</p>
<p>So when using green, make it a bit yellow or a bit blue. You can see this in the examples at the top of this article: All of the greens except FiveThirtyEight’s one <span>⬤</span> have a hue greater than 160° (=bluer) <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span> or lower than 60° (=more yellow) <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>. Nadieh uses both yellow green and blue green in this project we’ve already seen:</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors13.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors13.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors13.png"><em><a href="https://whydocatsanddogs.com/cats" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Why do Cats and Dogs?</a> by Nadieh Bremer</em></p>
<p>Looks like you can use them in your visualization as two different colors as Nadieh does: Win-win!</p>

<h4 id="Avoid-pure-colors">Avoid pure colors</h4>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors5.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors5.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors5.png"></p>
<p>“Pure” hues are the ones that are located at exactly 60°, 120°, 180°, 240°, 300° or 360°/0° in the color wheel:</p>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors7.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors7.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors7.png"></p>
<p>Here’s an example: In HSV/HSB, the <strong>H</strong>ue value of this bright blue <span>⬤</span> is 180°, the <strong>S</strong>aturation value is 67% and the <strong>L</strong>ightness value is 91%. You can also check the RGB values of your color: If at least two of the values are the same, they’re “pure”. For example, our <span>⬤</span> is a <code>rgb(77, 232, 232)</code>.</p>
<p>To make your colors look more natural and pleasing to the eyes of your readers, you can either tune down the saturation of pure colors or make them darker. <strong>If you want to have bright, saturated colors, rely on mixed colors</strong> that are at least 5-10° away from the pure colors.</p>
<p>In the image above, the red and orange, the blues and the greens have the same saturation and lightness. The only difference is the hue: The red <span>⬤</span> (0°), blue <span>⬤</span> (240°) and green <span>⬤</span> (120°) look more colorful than the orange <span>⬤</span> (40°), medium blue <span>⬤</span> (211°) and blue-ish green <span>⬤</span> (170°).</p>

<h4 id="Avoid-bright-saturated-colors">Avoid bright, saturated colors</h4>
<p><img alt="" data-src="/img/full-200805_goodcolors4.png" data-src-thumb="/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors4.png" src="https://blog.datawrapper.de/img/thumb-200805_goodcolors4.png"></p>
<p>Neon colors will definitely attract the attention of readers. But these readers won’t thank you. Most of us get a bit stressed out when we see them: “Highly saturated, light colors will NOT be appropriate [to communicate] Serious or Trust, or Calm,” as Bartram, Patra &amp; Stone explain in their paper “Affective Color in Visualization” from 2017 (<a href="https://research.tableau.com/sites/default/files/Affective%20Color%20CHI%202017.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PDF</a>).</p>
<p>If your colors come close to 100% saturation <strong>and</strong> 100% brightness, it’s likely your colors are too colorful. That’s definitely the case for pure colors like <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>.</p>
<p>“But I’ve seen such crazy colors before, and they look good,” you might say, and refer to projects like these ones:</p>

<p>If you compare the colors from these examples with colors like <span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span><span>⬤</span>, you see how they former ones are all less saturated or darker. A 100% saturated and 100% bright green <span>⬤</span> becomes less saturated in the New York Times <span>⬤</span>, and less saturated <em>and</em> darker in both the Bloomberg article <span>⬤</span> and the Pudding article <span>⬤</span>.</p>
<p>They…</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/">https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.datawrapper.de/beautifulcolors/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24391049</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:05:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[MCPU emulator and ATTiny85 port]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 14 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24390956">thread link</a>) | @stevekemp
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | http://jborza.com/emulation/2020/09/05/mcpu-emulator.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://jborza.com/emulation/2020/09/05/mcpu-emulator.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <h2 id="mcpu-emu--an-emulator-for-mcpu">mcpu-emu : an emulator for MCPU</h2>

<p>MCPU is a neat minimal 8-bit CPU (CPU design by Tim Boescke in 2001, cpldcpu@opencores.org) - see its <a href="https://opencores.org/projects/mcpu">opencores project file</a> and <a href="https://github.com/cpldcpu/MCPU">GitHub repo</a>. It fits into 32 macrocells on a CPLD and can operate on 64 bytes of RAM.</p>

<p>Being a minimal CPU it supports only four 8-bit instructions, that consist of 2 bit opcode and 6 bit address/immediate field.</p>

<p>It has two registers - an 8-bit accumulator and 6-bit program counter. MCPU supports 64 bytes of RAM shared between program and data.</p>

<p>The instruction set is:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>mnemonic</th>
      <th>opcode</th>
      <th>description</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>NOR</td>
      <td>00AAAAAA</td>
      <td>Acc = Acc NOR mem[AAAAAA]</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>ADD</td>
      <td>01AAAAAA</td>
      <td>Acc = Acc +  mem[AAAAAA], update carry</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>STA</td>
      <td>10AAAAAA</td>
      <td>mem[AAAAAA] = Acc</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>JCC</td>
      <td>11AAAAAA</td>
      <td>PC = AAAAAA if carry = 0, clear carry</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>I’ve also added an “OUT” instruction according to Jean-Claude Wippler’s <a href="https://jeelabs.org/2017/11/tfoc---a-minimal-computer/">TFoC - A minimal computer</a> article, with the opcode of 0xFF that prints the accumulator to the standard output.</p>

<h2 id="the-emulator">The emulator</h2>

<div><div><pre><code><span>typedef</span> <span>struct</span> <span>mcpu_state</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>accu</span> <span>:</span> <span>8</span><span>;</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>carry</span> <span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>pc</span> <span>:</span> <span>6</span><span>;</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>MEM_SIZE</span><span>];</span>
<span>}</span> <span>mcpu_state</span><span>;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then the emulation loop dispatches to instruction handlers based on the first two bits of the opcode.</p>

<p>I decided to represent the state of the CPU with a bitfield structure:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>//Acc = Acc NOR mem[AAAAAA]</span>
<span>void</span> <span>nor</span><span>(</span><span>mcpu_state</span><span>*</span> <span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>uint8_t</span> <span>opcode</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>accu</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>accu</span> <span>|</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>opcode</span><span>])</span> <span>^</span> <span>0xFF</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>//Acc = Acc +  mem[AAAAAA], update carry</span>
<span>void</span> <span>add</span><span>(</span><span>mcpu_state</span><span>*</span> <span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>uint8_t</span> <span>opcode</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>immediate</span> <span>=</span> <span>opcode</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>0x3f</span><span>;</span>
	<span>//update carry first</span>
	<span>uint16_t</span> <span>result</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>accu</span> <span>+</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>immediate</span><span>]);</span>
	<span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>carry</span> <span>=</span> <span>result</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> <span>8</span><span>;</span>
	<span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>accu</span> <span>=</span> <span>result</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>//mem[AAAAAA] = Acc</span>
<span>void</span> <span>sta</span><span>(</span><span>mcpu_state</span><span>*</span> <span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>uint8_t</span> <span>opcode</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>immediate</span> <span>=</span> <span>opcode</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>0x3f</span><span>;</span>
	<span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>immediate</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>accu</span><span>;</span>

<span>}</span>

<span>//PC = AAAAAA if carry = 0, clear carry</span>
<span>void</span> <span>jcc</span><span>(</span><span>mcpu_state</span><span>*</span> <span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>uint8_t</span> <span>opcode</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>immediate</span> <span>=</span> <span>opcode</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>0x3f</span><span>;</span>
	<span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>opcode</span> <span>==</span> <span>0xFF</span><span>)</span> <span>//output pseudo-instruction 0xFF</span>
		<span>printf</span><span>(</span><span>"%d</span><span>\n</span><span>"</span><span>,</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>accu</span><span>);</span>
	<span>else</span> <span>if</span> <span>(</span><span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>carry</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
		<span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>pc</span> <span>=</span> <span>immediate</span><span>;</span>
	<span>}</span>
	<span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>carry</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>One can optionally print out the currently executed instruction with a small disassembler:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>void</span> <span>disassemble</span><span>(</span><span>mcpu_state</span> <span>*</span><span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>char</span><span>*</span> <span>str</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>opcode</span> <span>=</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>pc</span><span>];</span>
	<span>uint8_t</span> <span>immediate</span> <span>=</span> <span>opcode</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>0x3f</span><span>;</span>
	<span>switch</span> <span>(</span><span>opcode</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> <span>6</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
	<span>case</span> <span>MATCH_NOR</span><span>:</span>
		<span>sprintf</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>,</span> <span>"NOR $%2X [%2X]"</span><span>,</span> <span>immediate</span><span>,</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>immediate</span><span>]);</span>
		<span>break</span><span>;</span>
	<span>case</span> <span>MATCH_ADD</span><span>:</span>
		<span>sprintf</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>,</span> <span>"ADD $%2X [%2X]"</span><span>,</span> <span>immediate</span><span>,</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>immediate</span><span>]);</span>
		<span>break</span><span>;</span>
	<span>case</span> <span>MATCH_STA</span><span>:</span>
		<span>sprintf</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>,</span> <span>"STA $%2X"</span><span>,</span> <span>immediate</span><span>);</span>
		<span>break</span><span>;</span>
	<span>case</span> <span>MATCH_JCC</span><span>:</span>
		<span>sprintf</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>,</span> <span>"JCC $%2X"</span><span>,</span> <span>immediate</span><span>);</span>
		<span>break</span><span>;</span>
	<span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="getting-some-test-programs">Getting some test programs</h3>

<p>The <a href="https://jeelabs.org/2017/11/tfoc---a-minimal-computer/">TFoC - A minimal computer</a> article comes with two code examples, with the code formatted as a hexdump</p>

<div><div><pre><code>3E 45 7F C2 C4 FA 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00
00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00
00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00
00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 FF 01
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I converted this to a binary file (easier to consume by the C emulator)  with a following bash script that replaces the newlines with spaces, then gets rid of double spaces left by \r\n conversion and finally uses <code>xxd</code> to perform a “reverse hexdump”:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>#/!bin/bash</span>
<span>cat</span> <span>$1</span> | <span>tr</span> <span>'\r\n'</span> <span>' '</span>  | <span>sed</span> <span>-e</span> <span>'s/[[:blank:]]\+/ /g'</span> | xxd <span>-r</span> <span>-p</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>$2</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Using a disassembler and tweaking the output a bit  yields the following code</p>

<div><div><pre><code> <span>0</span><span>:</span>     <span>3</span><span>E</span>      <span>NOR</span> <span>$</span><span>3</span><span>E</span>    <span>; acc = 0    (from address 3E)</span>
 <span>1</span><span>:</span>     <span>45</span>      <span>ADD</span> <span>$</span> <span>5</span>    <span>; acc += 250 (from address 5)</span>
 <span>2</span><span>:</span>     <span>7</span><span>F</span>      <span>ADD</span> <span>$</span><span>3</span><span>F</span>    <span>; acc += 1   (from address 3F)</span>
 <span>3</span><span>:</span>     <span>C2</span>      <span>JCC</span> <span>$</span> <span>2</span>    <span>; if carry occurred, jump to line 2</span>
 <span>4</span><span>:</span>     <span>C4</span>      <span>JCC</span> <span>$</span> <span>4</span>    <span>; endless loop, jump to itself</span>
 <span>5</span><span>:</span>     <span>FA</span>      <span>-------</span>    <span>; literal 250</span>
<span>...</span>
<span>3</span><span>E</span><span>:</span>     <span>FF</span>      <span>-------</span>    <span>; literal 255</span>
<span>3</span><span>F</span><span>:</span>      <span>1</span>      <span>-------</span>    <span>; literal 1</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Notice that there are no immediate values, one can only work with what’s already in the memory, hence the literals 1, 250 and 255 need to exist somewhere within the RAM.</p>

<p>Stepping through the program shows it behaves as expected:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>NOR $3E [FF]          A:00 C:0 PC:01
ADD $05 [FA]          A:FA C:0 PC:02
ADD $3F [01]          A:FB C:0 PC:03
JCC $02               A:FB C:0 PC:02
ADD $3F [01]          A:FC C:0 PC:03
JCC $02               A:FC C:0 PC:02
ADD $3F [01]          A:FD C:0 PC:03
JCC $02               A:FD C:0 PC:02
ADD $3F [01]          A:FE C:0 PC:03
JCC $02               A:FE C:0 PC:02
ADD $3F [01]          A:FF C:0 PC:03
JCC $02               A:FF C:0 PC:02
ADD $3F [01]          A:00 C:1 PC:03
JCC $02               A:00 C:0 PC:04
JCC $04               A:00 C:0 PC:04
JCC $04               A:00 C:0 PC:04
.. [JCC $04 repeats in an endless loop]
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It seemed it would be a useful thing to add a simple infinite loop detection - if the JCC instruction is jumping to its own address, there is no escape from this state as it won’t change the carry flag.</p>

<p>A second example - printing out prime numbers that fit into 8-bit number (up to 251) is more complex. It also required adding the special output opcode as mentioned earlier to see the results.</p>

<h3 id="porting-to-a-potato-microcontroller">Porting to a <del>potato</del> microcontroller</h3>

<p>What’s the best way to appreciate an emulator for a minimal chip published almost 20 years ago? Porting and running it on the smallest CPU I have at home - an ATTiny85 chip, which has 512 bytes of RAM and runs at 16 MHz in the form of the <a href="http://digistump.com/products/1">Digispark USB development board</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://jborza.com/assets/mcpu-digistump.jpg" alt="digistump"></p>

<p><em>Figure 1: The dev board sitting on top of the MCPU paper</em></p>

<p>There are two things that won’t work straightforward - there’s no filesystem to read the RAM/ROM binary from and  and there’s also no standard output.</p>

<h4 id="loading-the-binaries">Loading the binaries</h4>

<p>We can solve the first problem by including the emulated image to the source as a C array, <code>hexdump</code> can help producing the 0x-encoded bytes we need from the binary file:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>hexdump <span>-ve</span> <span>'1/1 "0x%.2x,"'</span> prog_test.bin
0x3e,0x45,0x7f,0xc2,0xc4,...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This way we can directly use a byte array as the ROM/RAM image.</p>

<h4 id="output">Output</h4>

<p>We can solve the second problem by exploiting the fact that the DigiStump with ATTiny85 can act as an USB keyboard - so we just let it type out the output to the text editor of our choice.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>//using this instead of printf() or Serial.print()</span>
<span>DigiKeyboard</span><span>.</span><span>println</span><span>(</span><span>"NOR"</span><span>);</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>A 3-second delay after initializing the board helped get me ready to switch to a different text editor to capture the output instead of overwriting the source code :).</p>

<h4 id="code-golfing-to-trim-the-binary-size">Code golfing to trim the binary size</h4>

<p>The code also required some golfing as the maximum binary size for my ATTiny board is 6 kb. The tricks I used to slim down the compiled version included:</p>
<ul>
  <li>inlining some functions</li>
  <li>simplifying the disassembler</li>
  <li>loading only the non-zero part of the binary</li>
</ul>

<p>Slimming the disassembler down:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>char</span><span>*</span> <span>mnemonics</span><span>[]</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span><span>"N"</span><span>,</span><span>"A"</span><span>,</span><span>"S"</span><span>,</span><span>"J"</span><span>};</span>

<span>void</span> <span>disassemble</span><span>(</span><span>mcpu_state</span><span>*</span> <span>state</span><span>,</span> <span>char</span><span>*</span> <span>str</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>uint8_t</span> <span>opcode</span> <span>=</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>pc</span><span>];</span>
  <span>uint8_t</span> <span>immediate</span> <span>=</span> <span>opcode</span> <span>&amp;</span> <span>0x3f</span><span>;</span>
  <span>sprintf</span><span>(</span><span>str</span><span>,</span> <span>"%s $%02X [%02X]"</span><span>,</span> <span>mnemonics</span><span>[</span><span>opcode</span> <span>&gt;&gt;</span> <span>6</span><span>],</span> <span>immediate</span><span>,</span> <span>state</span><span>-&gt;</span><span>memory</span><span>[</span><span>immediate</span><span>]);</span>
<span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h5 id="random-code-golfing-tidbits">Random code golfing tidbits:</h5>

<ul>
  <li>Printing the newline as a part of string and using <code>DigiKeyboard.print</code> instead of <code>DigiKeyboard.println</code> saves 14 bytes</li>
  <li>using <code>#define</code> instead of variables saves bytes</li>
  <li>replacing <code>sprintf()</code> with a series of <code>DigiKeyboard.print</code> calls saved 1.4 kb of the binary size!</li>
  <li>replacing <code>sprinf()</code></li>
  <li>loading the binary as a sequence of <code>state-&gt;memory[0] = 0x3e;</code> calls is shorter than initializing an array, and copying to CPU memory by a for loop in case of short binaries (8 bytes)</li>
</ul>

<p>That meant I had enough space to add blinking a LED and making a “tick” sound on a buzzer on every clock cycle! 
I ended up with a final binary size of <strong>4498 bytes</strong> for the prime-calculating binary with just the number as the output and <strong>4858 bytes</strong> with disassembler and status information in.</p>

<p>It’s also painfully slow - the delay between the first few and the last prime numbers is noticeable and it takes around 300 ms to calculate and print the very last primes (up to 255).</p>

<h3 id="sources">Sources</h3>

<p><a href="https://github.com/jborza/mcpu-emu">mcpu-emu on GitHub</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/jborza/mcpu-emu/tree/master/mcpu-digistump">ATTiny85 / Arduino port</a></p>

  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://jborza.com/emulation/2020/09/05/mcpu-emulator.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24390956</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 12:43:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Fairness Definitions Explained [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 18 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24390752">thread link</a>) | @Anon84
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | http://www.ece.ubc.ca/~mjulia/publications/Fairness_Definitions_Explained_2018.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.ece.ubc.ca/~mjulia/publications/Fairness_Definitions_Explained_2018.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.ece.ubc.ca/~mjulia/publications/Fairness_Definitions_Explained_2018.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24390752</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 11:57:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Ocean Is Struggling to Breathe, Too]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 77 | Comments 12 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24390568">thread link</a>) | @dnetesn
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/613/the-ocean-is-struggling-to-breathe-too | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/613/the-ocean-is-struggling-to-breathe-too">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
        <p><span>P</span>eople afflicted by Covid-19, particularly those with bad cases, experience difficulty breathing.&nbsp; We need oxygen in our tissues to keep our bodies working and our brains clear; viral damage to our lungs deprives bodies of this vital dissolved gas.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p>

<p>	This oxygen-starved condition is called hypoxia, and itâ€™s also a serious condition in many parts of the worldâ€™s ocean, as well as in estuaries, lagoons, rivers, and lakes. Marine hypoxia receives much less public attention than ocean acidification or warming—but in many parts of the world its effects may be just as profound, and the problem is worsening.</p>
<p>	The causes of marine hypoxia are twofold. The first, which has been studied the most, is the too-much-of-a-good-thing problem of nutrient over-enrichment. Vast loads of nutrients are applied to farm fields as fertilizers, spill from our sewage and septic systems, and waft from the tailpipes of automobiles. Inevitably some of these make their way into water, stimulating blooms of tiny plankton that eventually die and decay.&nbsp;The process of decaying consumes the oxygen, and hypoxia ensues. Wastewater treatment plants have helped but are not enough. Some nutrient-loaded hypoxic waters are now-infamous â€œdead zones,â€� such as the northern Gulf of Mexico, the Chesapeake Bay, and Lake Erie most summers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>	The other major cause is global warming.&nbsp;Warmer water canâ€™t hold as much dissolved oxygen as colder water. Itâ€™s lighter, too, and therefore tends to float above cooler layers, cutting them off from atmospheric exchange so that they eventually become deoxygenated as well. This phenomenon isnâ€™t directly associated with nutrient over-enrichment, but can exacerbate and intensify dead zones and impact deep ocean waters that have few nutrients. Warming is a global problem affecting the oxygen status of all waters—and it also fuels blooms of algae that die and decay, again setting off the cycle of oxygen loss.</p>
<p>	The general public—and even many scientists—are unaware of the rapidly expanding scale of deoxygenation. Among the first researchers to describe it were marine ecologists Bob Diaz and Rutger Rosenberg, who in the 1980s began to study the impacts on bottom-dwelling organisms in estuaries and coastal seas. In 1995 they wrote, "There is no other environmental variable of such ecological importance to coastal marine ecosystems that has changed so drastically in such a short period as dissolved oxygen." &nbsp;</p>
<p>	In 2008, Diaz and Rosenberg published a landmark study in the journal <em>Science</em>, documenting over 400 such zones and showing that their growth was exponential.&nbsp;By 2019 their tally exceeded 700, and possibly as many as 1000, coastal dead zones.&nbsp;If we make a chart of the known history of increase and color-code it by Gross World Product, an index of global economic output, we can appreciate the linkage of these dead zones to human activity:</p>
<figure><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/nautilus-vertical/oceans_423219c2026b77bfba722aa122b966a6.jpg" alt="dead zones and GWP chart"><figcaption><span>Growth in the number of coastal marine ecosystems classified as â€œdead zonesâ€� by Diaz and Rosenberg (2008) and Diaz et al. (2019).  The colors indicate levels of Gross World Product (GWP), and show that as economic output has increased exponentially, so has the number of polluted, deoxygenated dead zones. </span><br><span>GWP data: World Bank and CIA Factbook (compiled in Wikipedia).</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Deoxygenation in open oceans, away from coasts, extends farther and deeper, and is largely caused by the aforementioned tendency of warm water to seal off the cool waters below. The extent and spread of these so-called oxygen minimum zones wasnâ€™t fully appreciated until around 15 years ago, when improved instrumentation allowed scientists to measure them.&nbsp;Ten years ago their total area was estimated at 8 percent of Earth's ocean surface area—11.7 million square miles altogether, an area larger than North America and comparable in size to the entire African continent. That area is expanding today.<br></p>
<p>Brief periods of hypoxia—or even no oxygen, a phenomenon called anoxia—are common in nature and many organisms adapt by moving away or going temporarily dormant.&nbsp;A very few species are exceptionally tolerant and even have specialized metabolic pathways to cope in these circumstances.&nbsp;As the scale of deoxygenation increases, however, we see low-oxygen events so large and long that even highly mobile organisms, like fish, canâ€™t always escape.&nbsp;Some may be able to survive but become so weak that they have difficulty moving and finding food, let alone digesting it.&nbsp;Think of the Covid-19 sufferers who are so exhausted from lack of oxygen that they can barely move.&nbsp;Itâ€™s the same basic issue.&nbsp;As scientists study the problem of marine deoxygenation, we are increasingly seeing the effects on everything from fish growth to reproductive impairment. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Although most of the studies on biotic effects of deoxygenation have taken place in laboratories, my colleague Ben Walther and I, together with our students and colleagues, have learned to decipher signs of hypoxia exposure that are â€œrecordedâ€� in tiny bones within fish heads, called otoliths or ear-stones.&nbsp;These calcium carbonate deposits grow incrementally and take up various trace elements including the element manganese, which becomes available only at very low oxygen concentrations.&nbsp;By studying the lifetime uptake of manganese, biologist Michele Casini and I showed that periods of intense hypoxia have profound impacts on the growth and health of Atlantic cod in the Baltic Sea. With less oxygen available, cod have less energy for foraging and fighting off parasites and infections. As a result, they are unhealthy and shrunken compared to cod living in better environments. By age three, cod with high levels of hypoxia exposure are one-third smaller than healthy cod from oxygen-rich waters. Multiply that by population size and you have an epic loss of biomass. This has direct economic consequences and likely causes enormous suffering for the fish themselves.</p>
<figure><img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/nautilus-vertical/oceans_15b7f377d5e469878f05995df3610167.jpg" alt="Cod before-and-after"><figcaption><span>Left: Cod caught in 1981 off the island of Gotland, Sweden. Right: Cod caught in 2020 in the same vicinity. Baltic cod today are affected by several stressors, foremost among them hypoxia. </span><br><span>K. Limburg and Y. Heimbrand</span></figcaption></figure>
<p>Deoxygenation impacts ripple through entire ecosystems, too.&nbsp;Recent work has shown that in large stretches of the ocean even zooplankton, the microscopic animals who feed fish, often live on the edge of metabolic collapse. A study in the eastern tropical North Pacific oxygen minimum zone found that zooplankton there migrate in and out of microhabitats with extremely low oxygen; they are among the most hypoxia-tolerant organisms, yet are already at their metabolic limits. Projected further declines in oxygen may put them over the edge, with important consequences for carbon cycling and other biogeochemical processes in the open ocean.&nbsp;Food webs become compromised, particularly those on sea bottoms; there are many documented cases of sensitive invertebrate communities falling victim to hypoxic events since they cannot flee. Hypoxia has even been found to cause mass mortality in coral reef ecosystems, and in some instances may play as important a role as the better-known culprit of elevated water temperatures. Even open-water ecosystems change as the volume of healthy habitat shrinks and species crowd together, leading to novel food-web interactions. Covid-19â€™s web of long-term complications presents an uncanny parallel.<br></p>
<p>	Fortunately for humanity, a vaccine for Covid-19 should be available in 2021.&nbsp;The outlook for the oceans is not so optimistic, but neither is it hopeless.&nbsp;Think about the initial response to the virus, which was hamstrung by shortages of necessary medical supplies and technology, including masks and respirators; once the issues were recognized, it became possible to prioritize production to deal with the problem.&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the case of coastal hypoxia, nutrient pollution reductions coupled with wetland and seagrass restoration are akin to masks and respirators. They help protect the ecosystems and build up their resiliency. Those approaches resulted in greatly improved water quality and subsequent return of biodiversity in the waters off Tampa Bay, Florida, for example. And after decades of nutrient management, some parts of the Baltic Sea and Chesapeake Bay are beginning to show signs of recovery.&nbsp;</p>
<p>	The looming, elephant-in-the-room challenge is to deal with global warming, which will require new economic policies at national and global scales and the commitment of governments and citizens everywhere. Although overshadowed in the news cycle by Covid-19, global warming is still on the rise, fueled by human outputs of greenhouse gases.&nbsp;We <em>must</em> bend the curve on greenhouse gas emissions, just as we must flatten the Covid-19 curve. Without such change, we are headed in a dark, scary direction where nobody really wants to go.</p>

<ul><li> is a professor of Environmental Biology at the State University of New York College of Environmental Science and Forestry, and also a visiting professor at the Department of Aquatic Resources, Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences.</li></ul>
<p>Lead image: Each summer an oxygen-starved zone, shown in red, forms in the Gulf of Mexico. Almost nothing can live beneath surface waters. Credit: NOAA</p>
    </article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://oceans.nautil.us/feature/613/the-ocean-is-struggling-to-breathe-too</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24390568</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 11:14:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[WSL for Development in Windows 10 Is the New Kool-Aid. Still Not Using It?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 74 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24390390">thread link</a>) | @sirkarthik
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://blog.codonomics.com/2020/09/wsl-for-development-in-windows-10-is.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.codonomics.com/2020/09/wsl-for-development-in-windows-10-is.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-3190033996434970517" itemprop="articleBody">
<div>
  <p>I had been a happy-go Java developer on Windows platform. And then I had to ride the Ruby-on-Rails wave over Linux platform, only to realize how much I didn't know about productivity with automation. Later I moved onto MacOS to experience bliss before starting to hate it for one thing after the other; right from their buggy operating system upgrades to Apple not providing power cable compatible to Indian market resulting in earthing issues. Out of frustration I jumped back to Ubuntu and now back on Windows after long years.&nbsp;</p><p>Getting onto Windows was more out of necessity than interest and I started to explore how much things have changed in the Windows world. It wasn't a smooth return for me but the teething period is over and I'm loving Windows again. If you are onto Windows 10 Pro edition, and wanting to get the best of both worlds (Windows and Linux), this post is for you. I am jotting down ProTips to experience delight and productivity at development work.</p>
<ol><li>Use WSL 2 instead of WSL 1, for the former is far less resource intensive by integrating natively with Windows 10 Hyper-V virtualization stack, and thus phenomenally faster too. If you are on Windows 10 Home edition, you need to upgrade it to Windows 10 Pro edition and it is worth it, for you can get it at half the price upon upgrade.</li><li>Do not mount windows native formatted drive (NTFS) onto WSL for code that can be developed both in WSL environment and Windows. While this works, it is snail paced and you will frustrated too soon. I tried this out of curiosity and frustrated beyond my anticipation. If you are still wanting this, you will have to first format the storage drive in DOS format (as FAT32), so that it works well with your WSL and host Windows operating systems. This is possible the best middle-ground that you can hit upon.</li><li>Use <a href="https://aka.ms/terminal" target="_blank">Windows Terminal</a>&nbsp;instead of&nbsp; <a href="https://blog.codonomics.com/2020/09/Cmder" target="_blank">Cmder</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/Maximus5/ConEmu" target="_blank">ConEmu</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/mintty/mintty" target="_blank">Mintty</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cygwin.com/" target="_blank">Cygwin</a> or any other console emulators. Why? You can customize it with default settings for each of WSLs, Windows Command Prompt, Powershell or other terminals integrated with it. Also Windows Terminal is lightweight and faster.</li><li>When you start your development server in WSL 2, try testing it in your browser with <b><i>localhost</i></b>, it won't work. WSL is one proper sandboxed environment or VM. You need to port forward localhost settings for this to work. This can be done by adding the line like below in your <b><i>.wslconfig</i></b> file in your windows <b><i>$HOME</i></b> directory.<br>--
 --<br>
 </li><li>WSL 2 can consume all of your host memory. You can set limits to it by appending the line&nbsp;<b><i>memory=16GB</i></b> in your <b><i>.wslconfig</i></b> file.</li><li>Do install <a href="https://github.com/ohmyzsh/ohmyzsh" target="_blank">Oh-My-ZSH</a> to use zsh shell instead of the default bash. You get bunch of goodies like pre-configured aliases for Git and more by way of its plugins that you can configure to your preference.</li><li>If you are into using <a href="https://github.com/tmux/tmux/wiki" target="_blank">tmux</a>, you can use that too in your WSL 2, and power it up with <a href="https://github.com/erikw/tmux-powerline" target="_blank">tmux-powerline</a>.</li><li>You can change the location of your WSL 2 distribution's virtual hard drive.&nbsp;I keep all of my VMs (and now WSL 2 virtual hard drives) in <b><i>D:\VMs\&lt;platform&gt;\&lt;distribution name&gt;</i></b>. Run the following commands in PowerShell - replacing distribution name and preferred location: <br>----<br> Also at the time of writing, when you import a distribution, you may need to tell WSL 2 to start the distribution using the Linux user account you created when you first created the distribution. Thanks to <a href="https://www.58bits.com/blog/2020/05/30/wsl-2-setup-development">58bits.com </a> that you can run the below PowerShell script that imports the distribution, and resets the default user as you would like it to be. <br>-- --<br> Note that if your import fails with 'Unspecified error' (or other) - you may need to limit the amount of memory allocated to <b><i>vmmem</i></b>. You can do this with WSL2 config to limit memory as mentioned in ProTip 5 above.</li><li>If you are into using VS-Code as your IDE for development, you can launch the one you installed on your host Windows 10 OS from WSL 2 bash in your project's root folder and executing <b><i>`code .`</i></b>. With this you can work on your windows operating system launching your development servers in WSL environment, thus getting the best of both the worlds. Additionally, you can install your vs-code extensions on remote wsl as well as on host OS, all from within your IDE.</li><li>And <a href="https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-windows/install/" target="_blank">Docker Desktop for Windows</a> works well with your WSL2 too. You just can extract the best from everything.&nbsp;</li></ol><p>Windows 10 is super cool again with WSL 2. Whether you are a Windows buff wanting to leverage Linux goodies, or a Linux buff wanting to draw upon Windows 10 strengths, you can have it all. Happy coding!!..
</p></div><p><b>References</b></p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.codonomics.com/2020/09/wsl-for-development-in-windows-10-is.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24390390</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 10:36:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[AIX or Linux on Power]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 12 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24389922">thread link</a>) | @indigodaddy
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | http://gibsonnet.net/blog/cgaix/html/AIX%20or%20Linux%20on%20POWER.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://gibsonnet.net/blog/cgaix/html/AIX%20or%20Linux%20on%20POWER.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><span lang="EN-AU">IBM made some announcements today relating to
their latest POWER7 server offerings. The new line of systems includes new
entry level systems and the highly anticipated high-end system, the POWER7 <a href="http://www-01.ibm.com/common/ssi/cgi-bin/ssialias?subtype=ca&amp;infotype=an&amp;appname=iSource&amp;supplier=897&amp;letternum=ENUS110-158">795</a>!
<span></span>They also officially outlined some of
the new features available in AIX 7.1. You can review the details <a href="http://www-01.ibm.com/cgi-bin/common/ssi/ssialias?infotype=an&amp;subtype=ca&amp;htmlfid=897/ENUS210-200&amp;appname=isource&amp;language=enus">here</a>.
Ive discussed some of these new features </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://gibsonnet.net/blog/cgaix/entry/aix_7_open_beta_is_live_it_s_time_to_test?lang=en"><span>here</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">
and </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://gibsonnet.net/blog/cgaix/entry/creating_an_aix_5_2_wpar_on_aix_7?lang=en"><span>here</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">.
The official AIX 7.1 announcement details are available </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www-03.ibm.com/systems/power/news/announcement/20100817_annc.html"><span>here</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">The announcement got me thinking about my
recent customer engagements and why some have chosen to deploy AIX into their
IBM POWER environments, while others are considering a Linux on POWER solution.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">Ive found that it usually comes down to a
skills decision more than anything else. Most customers are happy to either
continue working with AIX (if they are existing AIX users) or migrate from
another UNIX OS to AIX. Ive seen very few customers actually migrate to Linux
on POWER, but Ive worked with several that have seriously considered it. Those
that have chosen to deploy Linux are doing so purely because they have in-house
Linux skills. They are concerned that migrating to AIX may be too big a jump
for their technical staff. I find this thinking interesting, as most of the
customers Ive dealt with who run other UNIX OSs like Tru64, Solaris or HP-UX
are more than happy to migrate to AIX. They believe the move is relatively
minor and doesnt require massive re-training of their UNIX admins. I tend to
agree.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">For me, <b>AIX</b>
is my preferred Enterprise class UNIX Operating System. Notice Im prefacing
this with the words <b><i>Enterprise class</i></b>. Dont get me wrong, I have worked with Linux
systems in both small and large customer environments. It is a great OS. But
Ive found that it really only fits into environments that have a relatively
small number of users and where significant downtime can be tolerated for
things like operating system maintenance. This doesnt fit the Enterprise class
of UNIX server OSs that Im thinking of here. When I contemplate the word <i>Enterprise</i>, I think of servers and
operating systems that can respond to business demands in terms of performance,
reliability, stability and availability. An Enterprise UNIX can provide all of
these things without compromise. Linux can offer performance and reliability
(in my opinion). However, from what Ive seen, it lacks features &amp; functions
in the areas of stability and availability. AIX on the other hand ticks all the
boxes. Again, this is just my opinion based on my experiences with both AIX and
Linux in the Enterprise landscape. Others will no doubt have their own
experiences that may or may not match my own.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">So when Im designing an Enterprise UNIX
server environment for a customer, I always start with an AIX on POWER base. If
the customer wants Linux, sure I can look at that too, but I strongly recommend
AIX as my preferred choice for large systems. Most of my customers are running
relatively large SAP/Oracle systems. AIX on POWER is a great combination for
large Enterprise systems. If you need to deploy large database systems that
must service tens of thousands of users (like a big SAP system), then I believe
AIX is the perfect OS on which to provide a platform for these large scale
systems.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">AIX is a very mature and powerful UNIX OS. It
has been a major player in the UNIX server market for over 20 years (as shown
below). Some people are just not aware of how mature, robust and stable the AIX
OS has become over the years. There are many impressive aspects of the OS in
the areas of performance, scalability, reliability, management and
administration. <o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-AU"><o:p></o:p></span><a href="https://www.ibm.com/developerworks/mydeveloperworks/blogs/cgaix/resource/BLOGS_UPLOADED_IMAGES/aix_evolution.gif" target="_blank"><img alt="image" src="https://www.ibm.com/developerworks/mydeveloperworks/blogs/cgaix/resource/BLOGS_UPLOADED_IMAGES/aix_evolution.gif"></a> </p>





<p><span lang="EN-AU">Just looking at some of the administration
capabilities built into AIX are enough for me to always recommend AIX over
Linux (or any other UNIX OS), when it comes to large Enterprise servers.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">For example, the System Management Interface Tool (</span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/aix/library/au-smit/index.html"><span>SMIT</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">) can make the UNIX admins life a lot simpler.
This is an interactive tool that is part of the AIX OS. Almost all tasks that
an AIX administrator may need to perform can be executed using this tool. It is
a text-based tool (there is also an X interface but I recommend sticking with
the text-based menus). Everything it does, it does through standard AIX
commands and Korn shell functions. This feature is especially useful when you
need to automate a repetitive task; you can have SMIT create the proper
command-line sequence, and you can then use those commands in your own script.
My compatriot, Anthony English, has a nice intro to </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://gibsonnet.net/blog/AIXDownUnder/entry/smitty_to_his_friends20?lang=en"><span>SMIT</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU"> on his AIX blog. <o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">The
<b>AIX Logical Volume Manager</b> (</span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www.redbooks.ibm.com/redpapers/pdfs/redp0106.pdf"><span>LVM</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">)
is built into the OS, for free. AIX LVM helps UNIX system administrators </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/aix/library/au-aixstorage/index.html"><span>manage their
storage</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU"> in a very flexible manner. LVM allows logical
volumes to span multiple physical volumes. Data on logical volumes appears to
be contiguous to the user, but might not be contiguous on the physical volume.
This allows file systems, paging space, and other logical volumes to be resized
or relocated, span multiple physical volumes, and have their contents
replicated for greater flexibility and availability. It provides capabilities
for mirroring data across disks, migrating data across disks &amp; storage
subsystems, expand/shrink filesystems and more.......all of which can be
performed dynamically.....<b>no downtime</b>
required. The concept, implementation and interface to the AIX LVM is one of a
kind. All of its features support the continuous availability philosophy. <o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">One of the biggest reasons that I love AIX
over Linux is the <b>mksysb</b>. Its built
into the OS and allows you to create a bootable image of your AIX system. This
image can be used to restore a broken AIX system or for cloning other systems.
The cloning feature is truly amazing. You can take an image created on a
low-end system and deploy it on any POWER system, all the way up to the
high-end POWER boxes. This simplifies the installation and cloning processing
when you need to install and manage many AIX LPARs. By using an SOE mksysb
image you can deploy consistent AIX images across your Enterprise POWER server
environment.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">This brings me to another wonderful feature of
AIX, the <b>Network Installation Manager</b>
(</span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www.redbooks.ibm.com/abstracts/sg247296.html?Open"><span>NIM</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">).
NIM is powerful network installation tool (comparable to Linux Kickstart).
Using NIM you can backup/restore, update and upgrade one or more AIX systems
either individually or simultaneously. This can all be achieved over a network
connection, removing the need for handling physical installation media forever.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">Another fine example of AIXs superior OS management tools is </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www.ibmsystemsmag.com/aix/aprilmay08/tipstechniques/20226p1.aspx"><span>multibos</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">. This tool allows an AIX administrator to
create and maintain two separate, bootable instances of the AIX OS within the
same root volume group (rootvg). This second instance of rootvg is known as a
standby Base Operating System (BOS) and is an extremely handy tool for
performing AIX TL and Service Pack (SP) updates. Multibos lets you install,
update and customize a standby instance of the AIX OS <b>without impacting</b> the running and active production instance of the
AIX OS. This is valuable in environments with tight maintenance windows. <o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">When it comes to upgrading the OS to a new
release of AIX, the </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/aix/library/au-migrate_nimadm/index.html"><span>nimadm</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">
utility can assist the administrator greatly in this task. </span><span lang="EN-AU">The <b><span>nimadm</span></b>
utility offers several advantages. For example, a system administrator can use <b><span>nimadm</span></b> to create a copy of a
NIM client's rootvg and migrate the disk to a newer version or release of AIX.
All of this can be done <b>without
disruption</b> to the client (there is no outage required to perform the
migration). After the migration is finished, the only downtime required will be
a single scheduled reboot of the system.</span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">AIX
6.1 introduced new capability that most UNIX operating systems are still
working on. </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://www-01.ibm.com/support/docview.wss?rs=0&amp;context=SG11G&amp;dc=DB520&amp;uid=isg3T1012104&amp;loc=en_US&amp;cs=utf-8&amp;lang=#concurrent"><span>Concurrent
Updates of the AIX Kernel</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">.....<b>without a reboot</b>! IBM is always working hard at making AIX an OS
that can provide <b>continuous availability</b>,
even if it needs to be patched. AIX now has the ability to update certain kernel
components and kernel extensions in place, without needing a system reboot. In
addition, concurrent updates can be removed from the system without needing a
reboot. Can you do this with other UNIX OSs? <o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">And thats just some of the features that make
AIX <b>the</b> only UNIX OS that I recommend
for Enterprise systems. There are many more tools and features that I couldnt
live without (like alt_disk_install, savevg, installp, WPARs, etc, the list
goes on). If you are new to AIX and you are considering what your next UNIX OS
should be, then I recommend you take a <b>very</b>
close look at </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://ibm.com/aix"><span>AIX</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU">.
<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">And finally, the support provided by IBM, is
first class. Whenever Ive needed assistance with an AIX issue or query, I have
always received timely, professional and useful advice. On the rare occasions
where Ive uncovered a new bug, IBM AIX support have always been quick to
provide me with an interim fix to resolve or workaround a problem. Thats the
sort of support youd expect for an Enterprise UNIX OS, isnt it? Whats the
support like from your current UNIX (or Linux) OS vendor?<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">Linux is still a viable UNIX operating system.
However, I think its more suited to certain workloads like small to medium
size mail, web and other utility servers and services. AIX, however, would be
my platform of choice for my 10TB Oracle database running SAP ERP, not just for
performance reasons, but primarily because of the system administration
features of AIX that allow me to support and manage the system without
impacting my customers or enforcing reboots/outages whenever I need to change
something on the system.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">All IBM need to do is create their own Linux
distribution (Blue Linux perhaps?)
that has all the features of AIX built in and then Im sold! But why would
they? We already have AIX.<o:p></o:p></span></p>



<p><span lang="EN-AU">Follow me on Twitter:</span><span lang="EN-AU"> </span><span lang="EN-AU"><a href="http://twitter.com/cgibbo"><span>http://twitter.com/cgibbo</span></a></span><span lang="EN-AU"><o:p></o:p></span></p>







</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://gibsonnet.net/blog/cgaix/html/AIX%20or%20Linux%20on%20POWER.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24389922</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 08:29:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[LO-FI player - Interact with objects and create your own music]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 40 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24389748">thread link</a>) | @kooskoos
<br/>
September 6, 2020 | https://magenta.github.io/lofi-player/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://magenta.github.io/lofi-player/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="interpolation-div">
              <h3>Melody Interpolation</h3>
              <p>
                Create your melodies by mixing two melodies together!
                <a href="https://magenta.tensorflow.org/music-vae" target="_blank">
                  How does this work?</a>
                <a href="https://magenta.tensorflow.org/2016/06/10/recurrent-neural-network-generation-tutorial" target="_blank">
                  What is RNN?</a>
              </p>
              

              

              <canvas id="melody-canvas"></canvas>
            </div><div id="info-div">
              <h3>Lo-Fi Player</h3>
              <p>
                Welcome to our magical room! By interacting with elements in the room, you can build
                your own custom music stream. Built by
                <a href="https://vibertthio.com/portfolio/" target="_blank">Vibert Thio</a>, intern
                on the Google Brain team. Powered by magic from
                <a href="https://magenta.tensorflow.org/" target="_blank">Magenta</a>.
              </p>
              
              <p>
                Read our
                <a href="https://g.co/magenta/lofi-player" target="_blank">blog</a> for more info.
                Or, play it on
                <a href="https://goo.gl/magenta/lofi-stream" target="_blank">YouTube</a> with
                others.
              </p>
              <br>
              <h3>Credits</h3>
              <p>
                Thanks
                <a href="https://soundcloud.com/cone-head" target="_blank">Conehead</a>
                and
                <a href="https://soundcloud.com/eveyichenmusic" target="_blank">E V E</a>
                for the counsel on music. Thanks
                <a href="https://stiong124.wixsite.com/shynha/animation" target="_blank">@Sheena Tiong</a>
                for the sunset animated gif.
              </p>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://magenta.github.io/lofi-player/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24389748</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 07:43:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Daniel J. Bernstein's IM2000 email proposal is not a good idea]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 61 | Comments 51 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24389143">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
September 5, 2020 | https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/IM2000NotGoodIdea | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/IM2000NotGoodIdea">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h2>Daniel J. Bernstein's IM2000 email proposal is not a good idea</h2>

	<p><small>September  6, 2020</small></p>
</div><div><p>A long time ago, Daniel J. Bernstein wrote a proposal for a new
generation of Internet email he called <a href="https://cr.yp.to/im2000.html">IM2000</a>, although it never went anywhere.
Ever since then, a significant number of people have idealized it
as the great white 'if only' hope of email (especially as the
solution to spam), in much the same way that people idealized Sun's
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NeWS">NeWS</a> as the great 'if only'
alternative to X11. Unfortunately, IM2000 is not actually a good
idea.</p>

<p>The core of <a href="https://cr.yp.to/im2000.html">IM2000</a> is summarized by Bernstein as follows:</p>

<blockquote><p>IM2000 is a project to design a new Internet mail infrastructure
around the following concept: Mail storage is the sender's
responsibility.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The first problem with this is that it doesn't remove the fundamental
problem of email, which is (depending on how you phrase it) that
email is an <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/EmailVsModernProtocols"><em>anonymous push</em> protocol</a>
or that it lacks <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/SignedEmailWrongProblem"><em>revocable authorization</em> to send you things</a>. In IM2000, random strangers on the
Internet are still allowed to push to you, they just push less data
than they currently do with (E)SMTP mail.</p>

<p>The idea that IM2000 will deal with spam rests on the idea that
forcing senders to store mail is difficult for spammers. Even a
decade ago this was a questionable assumption, but today it is
clearly false. A great deal of serving capacity is yours for the
asking (and someone's credit card) in AWS, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Cloud_Platform">GCP</a>, Azure, OVH,
and any number of other VPS and serverless computing places.  In
addition many spammers will have a relatively easy time with
'storing' their email, because their spam is already generated from
templates and so in IM2000 could be generated on the fly whenever
you asked for it from them. We now have a great deal of experience
with web servers that generate dynamic content on demand and it's
clear that they can run very efficiently and scale very well,
provided that they're designed competently.</p>

<p>(I wrote about this a long time ago <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/spam/SenderStorageHelpsSpammers">here</a>, and things have gotten much
easier for spammers since then.)</p>

<p>At the same time, IM2000 is catastrophic for your email privacy.
People complain vociferously about 'tracking pixels' in HTML email
that betray when you open and read the email from someone; well,
IM2000 is one giant tracking pixel that reliably reports when and
where you read that email message. IM2000 would also be a terrible
email reading experience, because it's like a version of IMAP where
message retrieval has random delays and sometimes fails entirely.</p>

<p>(As far as spam filtering your incoming IM2000 messages goes, IM2000
gives you far less up front information than you currently get with
SMTP email. I wrote up this and other issues a long time ago in an
entry about <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/spam/SenderStorageProblems">the technical problems of such schemes</a>. Some of those problems are no longer
really an issue more than a decade later, but some continue to be.)</p>

<p>At a broader 'technical choices have social impacts' level, IM2000
would create a very different experience than today's email systems
if implemented faithfully, one where 'your' email was actually not
yours but was mostly other people's because other people are storing
it. Those other people can mostly retract individual messages by
deleting them from their servers (you would still have the basic
headers that are pushed to you), and they can wipe out large sections
of your email by deleting entire accounts (and the sent messages
associated with them), or even by going out of business or having
a data loss incident. Imagine a world where an ISP getting out of
the mail business means that all email that its customers have sent
from their ISP email accounts over the years just goes away, from
everyone's mailbox.</p>

<p>(If 'ISP' sounds abstract here, substitute 'Yahoo'. Or 'GMail'.)</p>

<p>In addition, in some potential realizations of IM2000, email would
become mutable in practice (even if you weren't supposed to in
theory), because once again the sender is storing the message and
is in a position to alter that stored copy. Expect that capability
to be used sooner or later, just as people silently revise things
posted on the web (including official statements, perhaps especially
including them).</p>

<p>Some of these social effects can be partially avoided by storing
your own local copies of IM2000 messages when you read them, but
there are two issues. The first is pragmatic; the more you store
your own copies and the earlier you make them, the more IM2000 is
SMTP in a bad disguise. The second is social; in the IM2000 world
the server holds the authoritative copy of the message, not you,
so if you say the message says one thing (based on your local copy)
and the server operator says it says something else (or doesn't
exist), the server operator likely wins unless you have very strong
evidence.</p>

<p>In general, I think that IM2000 or anything like it would create
an 'email' experience that was far more like the web, complete with
the experience of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Link_rot">link rot</a>
and <a href="https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/CoolUrlsChange">cool messages changing</a>, than today's
email (where for better or worse you keep your own full record of
what you received, read and reread it at your leisure, and know
that it's as immutable as you want it to be). And it would still
have the problem that people can push stuff in front of you, unlike
the web where you usually at least have to go looking for things.</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/tech/IM2000NotGoodIdea</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24389143</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 05:13:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Revived my personal website to join the nostalgia]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 106 | Comments 38 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24389036">thread link</a>) | @xisnextbigthing
<br/>
September 5, 2020 | https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="maintextbox">
		<p>This is home of user friendly, web standarts compatible, unique websites provider Web/beW. You can access our infos, portfolio and some of our articles and experiments, can make a job contract with us and contact us.				</p>
		<p><a href="#aboutus_link" title="Permalink to About us" rel="#aboutus" id="outus_link" name="aboutuskutu"><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/aboutusrplc.png" alt="About Us"></a>
		<a href="#portfolio_link" title="Permalink to Portfolio" rel="#portfolio" id="rtfolio_link" name="portfoliokutu"><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/portfoliorplc.png" alt="Portfolio"></a>
		<a href="#stuffs_link" title="Permalink to Stuffs" rel="#stuffs" id="uffs_link" name="stuffskutu"><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/stuffsrplc.png" alt="Stuffs"></a>
		<a href="#contactcontract_link" title="Permalink to Contact|Contract" rel="#contactcontract" id="ntactcontract_link" name="contactcontractkutu"><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/contactcontractrplc.png" alt="Back to Contact|Contract"></a>
	</p></div><div id="aboutus">
		<div id="aboutustextbox">
			
			<p><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/whoarewerplc.jpg" alt="About Us"></p><p>Websites looks same. Before, because internet speed and web technologies weren't advanced as now webpages were in some specified shapes. Nowadays, as a result of web's gaining print media's properties there is a "staining", but as a result of increase of ready to shallow pile type design, behavior and content management packets there is a boring "ordinarity".							</p>
			<p>Producing our clients demands far from this ordinarity is our duty. We are serving with guarantee of client satisfaction from concept to last product in all stages; creating design, converting it to standart comptiable and maximum browser supporting (x)html and css codes, turning it to front and back-end rich application.							</p>
			<p><a href="#main_link" title="Back to Main" rel="#aboutus" id="aboutussagmainback" name="aboutuskutu"><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/sagmainbackrplc.png" alt="Back to Main"></a>
			<a href="#services_link" title="Permalink to Services" rel="#services" id="rvices_link" name="serviceskutu"><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/servicesrplc.png" alt="Services"></a>
		</p></div>


		<div id="services">
			<div id="servicestextbox">
				<ul>
					<li><a href="#tabs-4">Services</a></li>
					<li><a href="#tabs-5">Design</a></li>
					<li><a href="#tabs-6">(x)Html/Css</a></li>
					<li><a href="#tabs-7">Javascript/Ajax</a></li>
					<li><a href="#tabs-8">Php/Sql</a></li>
					<li><a href="#tabs-9">Cms Integrate</a></li>
					<li><a href="#tabs-10">Content/SEO/Host</a></li>
				</ul>
				<div id="tabs-4">
					
					<p><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/ourservicesisthekeyrplc.jpg" alt="Services"></p><p>We're providing all essential services to create anything that can be seen in a web browser. Maybe you want to have your website developed from stratch, maybe get some tweaks done on a prepared webpage. Maybe you just want to have some interesing feautures added to your websites behavior layer.								</p>
					<p>As everything has a science, we are doing your works done with sector accepted principles and steps. With close contact and revisions, our purpose is to not leave a single unhappy client behind.								</p>
					<p>You can read details about our services to clicking their titles.								</p>
				</div>
				<div id="tabs-5">
					
					<p>Web design trend differenting in every two years. Even the design out of current trend comes to eyes dull, company profile suitable designs can create a brandface. Well analyzing our clients demands we target to create not stereotyped products, but looking familiar and even unique designs. These are our expertise and the options we serve in this area:								</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Css frameworks compitable designs (Like <a href="http://960.gs/" title="960 Grid System">960.gs</a>)</li>
						<li>Creating designs as Adobe PSD or Corel PSP files.</li>
						<li>Consistently contact during concept, mood creating steps of design.</li>
						<li>Unique design ideas that suits your needs.</li>
						<li>User friendly interfaces.</li>
					</ul>
				</div>
				<div id="tabs-6">
					
					<p>We're coding (x)Html and css web standarts compitable, semantic and at maximum browser support. Here is our list:								</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Truly cascading stylesheets</li>
						<li>Dividing design and structure apart (we don't using tables for structure)</li>
						<li>Coding semantic markup</li>
						<li>Nonperishable structures at different zoom levels</li>
						<li>Support to IE6/7/8, Firefox 3/3.5+, Opera 9+/10+, Safari, Google Chrome</li>
						<li>Slicing designs to converting them (x)html/css (PSD2XHTML)</li>
						<li>Creating css framework speacial for you</li>
					</ul>
				</div>
				<div id="tabs-7">
					
					<p>We prepare your rich interactive webpages, your special demands using native javascript and jquery libary. With advance of both computer and browser technologies interesting features can be added without using flash.								</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Codes with native javascript and jQuery libary</li>
						<li>Cross-browser support</li>
						<li>Solutions your problems that can't solved with (x)html and css</li>
						<li>Make rich user interfaces posibble</li>
						<li>Troubleless ajaxfied, php integrated applications</li>
					</ul>
				</div>
				<div id="tabs-8">
					
					<p>We're providing solutions for server-side interactivity.								</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Applications that suits your needs.</li>
						<li>Codes that special just for you</li>
						<li>Maximum security</li>
						<li>Efficient database structures</li>
						<li>Optimized applications</li>
					</ul>
				</div>
				<div id="tabs-9">
					
					<p>We're integrate (your) designs to content management systems (cms). As this could be common packages like wordpress, joomla!, it could special packages too.								</p>
					<p>If common packages are enough for your needs, you can turn to practic solutions differenting at design stage with save on time and expenditures. Ease of use with familiar user interface, widely avaiable extension support are advantages of this systems; been open to everyone of their source code are their deadvantages.								</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Integrating from (x)html/css to cms (PSD2CMS)</li>
						<li>High level wordpress customization and special wordpress themes</li>
						<li>Joomla! integration and special joomla! templates</li>
					</ul>
				</div>
				<div id="tabs-10">
					
					<p>We can undertake data entry of your website. We can help to you about creating it's content. We're doing placing content according to SEO principles considering known factors valuable by algorhitms of search engines. We're also offering reasonable priced hosting.								</p>
					<ul>
						<li>Data Entry</li>
						<li>Making your page's codes SEO compitiable.</li>
						<li>Determining keywords of your content</li>
						<li>Placing your content according to SEO principles</li>
						<li>Registering to search engines</li>
						<li>Google Adwords advertise program consulting</li>
						<li>Reasonable priced hosting with unlimited subdomain, database and email</li>
					</ul>
				</div>
				<p><a href="#aboutus_link" title="Back to About Us" rel="#services" id="servicessagaboutus" name="serviceskutu"><img src="https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/media/img/sagaboutusrplc.png" alt="Back to About Us"></a>
			</p></div>
		</div>

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://gasoved.github.io/webbew/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24389036</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 04:44:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Last Gunsmiths of the Khyber Pass]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 103 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24388849">thread link</a>) | @mmm_grayons
<br/>
September 5, 2020 | https://silahreport.com/2019/08/23/the-last-gunsmiths-of-the-khyber-pass/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://silahreport.com/2019/08/23/the-last-gunsmiths-of-the-khyber-pass/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-3339">
	<div>
		<div>
						<div>
																		<div>
						<div>
							<p>Fog clings to a never-ending row of low-rise buildings down the length of a dusty road, it’s early, around eight o’clock on a cool April morning. The fog clears and voices breakthrough and you see the first glimpses of the large bazaar, sounds of shutters slamming open, doors being unlocked and people greeting each other as their day starts. The occasional chatter of gunfire can be heard as firearms are test fired nearby.</p>
<p><em>Darra Adam Khel</em>. This bustling town is situated in modern-day <em>Pakistan</em>, a stone’s throw from the Pak-Afghan border. <em>What makes it so special?</em> You may ask and the answer lies within the myriad of myths and legends put out over the years.</p>

<p><span><iframe width="1160" height="653" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J-f7j-RlN_Q?version=3&amp;rel=1&amp;fs=1&amp;autohide=2&amp;showsearch=0&amp;showinfo=1&amp;iv_load_policy=1&amp;wmode=transparent" allowfullscreen="true"></iframe></span></p>
<p>As of this year, 2019, <em>Darra</em> is the last main tribal arms market and manufacturing town that remains in the Pak-Afghan FATA region (Federally-Administered Tribal Region – FATA pronounced Faa-Thaa locally), the last vestige of old-world freedom in the area. Over the last few years, the other manufacturing hubs and markets in towns like <em>Landi Kotal</em>, just a few minutes’ drive from <em>Torkham</em> border on the <em>Khyber Pass</em>, have finally died out leaving a handful of shops and a couple of gunsmiths who repair the large number of firearms still found across the region. <em>Peshawar’s</em> massive arms bazaars have also disappeared leaving a few licensed manufacturers in a small industrial estate on its outskirts and a few licensed dealers scattered throughout the city.</p>
<p><em>Darra</em> held out against the threat of the <em>Taliban</em> in the early 2010s, fighting them off on a number of occasions seeing as they had the arms, supplies and manpower to fend for themselves. They are no friend to these <em>Taliban</em> as you can see even though they have been linked by a few journalistic sources with selling them an enormous number of arms and ammunition. Contrary to popular belief that the market is now dead or not operating, the bazaar still thrives with many firearms bought and sold daily in its now-legendary bazaar. Yes, there were times were the shutters ere down but this was always just a façade, something that happened on the face and business continued in the back alleys and dusty basements.</p>
<p>However, the town of thousands of arms dealers and manufacturing workshops has been relegated to around a thousand of both due to the global war on terror and its impact on the global arms trade and international smuggling routes. They do not get as much as they used to though they still have a steady but small supply of items that get through to them even to this day. Due to this war on terror, the FATA area – which for many years managed to retain its autonomy, was regulated to prohibit the sale and ownership of explosive type ordnance and large-caliber arms such as HMG’s (e.g: DsHK / KPV) and up to the general population there. Fortunately, <em>Darra</em> still maintains its hold on the trade of tribal arms throughout the now regulated tribal areas and still holds a monopoly on arms manufactured there that are sold within <em>Pakistan</em> and <em>Afghanistan</em> too.</p>
<p>The war on terror has a lot of detriments with the main one being that it has increased the price of arms so much; that now an AK rifle which would have cost approximately Rs10,000 (~£55/~$67), around fifteen years ago, now costs a minimum of around ten times that. Yes, as with all markets, prices do fluctuate depending on many local and regional factors but prices still remain relatively high due to this. Genuine, original factory-made arms command a high premium on the market as a whole throughout the Pak-Afghan region and this has meant that locally made arms are sold more than originals due to the somewhat extortionate prices that can be seen. Due to soaring inflation and prices of raw material, locally made arms now cost the same as originals were only a decade or so ago.</p>
<div id="attachment_3346"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3346" data-attachment-id="3346" data-permalink="https://silahreport.com/20190414_101021-min/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?fit=5312%2C2988&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="5312,2988" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20190414_101021-min" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?fit=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=1160%2C653" alt="20190414_101021-min" width="1160" height="653" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?w=5312&amp;ssl=1 5312w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=89%2C50&amp;ssl=1 89w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=650%2C366&amp;ssl=1 650w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=1000%2C563&amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?resize=50%2C28&amp;ssl=1 50w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?w=2320&amp;ssl=1 2320w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101021-min.jpg?w=3480&amp;ssl=1 3480w" sizes="(max-width: 1160px) 100vw, 1160px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p><p id="caption-attachment-3346">Right face: Three samples of SMLE rifles produced in Darra, New and used examples shown.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3345"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3345" data-attachment-id="3345" data-permalink="https://silahreport.com/20190414_101054/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?fit=5312%2C2988&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="5312,2988" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.9&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;SM-G920F&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1555236654&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.3&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.02&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="20190414_101054" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?fit=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=1160%2C653" alt="20190414_101054" width="1160" height="653" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?w=5312&amp;ssl=1 5312w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=89%2C50&amp;ssl=1 89w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=650%2C366&amp;ssl=1 650w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=1000%2C563&amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?resize=50%2C28&amp;ssl=1 50w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?w=2320&amp;ssl=1 2320w, https://i2.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_101054.jpg?w=3480&amp;ssl=1 3480w" sizes="(max-width: 1160px) 100vw, 1160px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p><p id="caption-attachment-3345">Left face: Three samples of SMLE rifles produced in Darra, New and used examples shown.</p></div>
<p>Some older background information would be needed to understand why such a place even exists on such a scale as it is or even was. During the British Raj period of the 1800s where the British Empire ruled over these tribal areas, small workshops opened up in many areas across the region to produce exact copies of arms used by the British to fight back against them. Gunsmiths started with muskets and then progressed onto Lee-Enfield action rifles and that was their mainstay for a lengthy period continuing to upgrade and produce newer variations, turning those small shops into larger ones. That is how <em>Darra</em> and many other manufacturing towns and bazaars got their start and from then, the markets grew and grew becoming what they then were known as. <em>Darra’s</em> second major call to fame was that it supplied arms and ammunition to the <em>Mujahideen</em> in <em>Afghanistan</em> during the 1979-1989 Soviet-Afghan War, some say it was even supported by the federal government too at this point. More recently, <em>Darra’s</em> notoriety came to surface as ill-informed people conducting poor journalism claimed it was a black market and that the gunsmiths manufactured guns in mud huts, with basic tools using their bare hands. Putting this to rest, let me start with calling it a black market; this is incorrect as the areas where these markets were/are based comes under its own tribal laws and governance much different to the rest of <em>Pakistan</em>, they are operating well within their own laws therefore it is not a black market in any sense within these borders. There is an element of truth to the thought of mud huts, bare hands and rudimentary methods but the times long past, when this was the norm, are not an indication of how things are in this day and age. Yes, some processes such as heat-treating and finishing are done in so-called mud huts and outdoors under makeshifts structures (this is much needed for ventilation) however the actual workshops are almost always in brick structures and the gunsmiths utilize milling machines, CNC machines and other tools to make their products. Yes, they do use basic tools but those are used to fit and finish the firearm and not to actually manufacture or produce it.</p>
<div id="attachment_3350"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3350" data-attachment-id="3350" data-permalink="https://silahreport.com/2019/08/23/the-last-gunsmiths-of-the-khyber-pass/20190414_110542-min/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?fit=5312%2C2988&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="5312,2988" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20190414_110542-min" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?fit=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=1160%2C653" alt="20190414_110542-min" width="1160" height="653" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?w=5312&amp;ssl=1 5312w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=89%2C50&amp;ssl=1 89w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=650%2C366&amp;ssl=1 650w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=1000%2C563&amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?resize=50%2C28&amp;ssl=1 50w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?w=2320&amp;ssl=1 2320w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110542-min.jpg?w=3480&amp;ssl=1 3480w" sizes="(max-width: 1160px) 100vw, 1160px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p><p id="caption-attachment-3350">Right face: An Enfield produced Martini Henry type rifle, a Darra STEN copy and a Darra Martini Henry action type rifle.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3351"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3351" data-attachment-id="3351" data-permalink="https://silahreport.com/2019/08/23/the-last-gunsmiths-of-the-khyber-pass/20190414_110604-min/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?fit=5312%2C2988&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="5312,2988" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="20190414_110604-min" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?fit=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=1160%2C653" alt="20190414_110604-min" width="1160" height="653" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?w=5312&amp;ssl=1 5312w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=89%2C50&amp;ssl=1 89w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=650%2C366&amp;ssl=1 650w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=1000%2C563&amp;ssl=1 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?resize=50%2C28&amp;ssl=1 50w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?w=2320&amp;ssl=1 2320w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/20190414_110604-min.jpg?w=3480&amp;ssl=1 3480w" sizes="(max-width: 1160px) 100vw, 1160px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p><p id="caption-attachment-3351">Left face: An Enfield produced Martini Henry type rifle, a Darra STEN copy and a Darra Martini Henry action type rifle.</p></div>
<p>A negative misconception in regards to the firearms produced is the thought that they aren’t heat-treated or are of poor quality. This isn’t true for the most part as they do go through a heat-treating process, however the detractor is that the method of heat-treating leaves a lot to be desired, especially in the cheaper copies. Many users of lower quality copies complain of metal warping and deformation causing a firearm to become inoperable or dangerous to use, this is what leads to people surmising that all arms made in such areas are no good. This is an issue for lower quality copies, a lower quality firearm will have its flaws as it is not built using quality material and to the same tolerances as a firearm made to exact specs with all care taken in production. At the end of the day, you must repeat the same phrase to people who ask why a cheap item is no good; you get what you pay for – if you want a cheap item, you will get a cheap item that will end up having issues or breaking much like any cheap thing you buy.</p>
<p>Moving away from the negatives, let us talk about positives. Apart from the exquisite food that the food gurus cook up there, <em>Darra</em> is also famous for some of the firearms designs to come out of its shops – most notable is the infamous AKMSU which resides in the Royal Armouries, Leeds, UK. Even though that particular firearm could have been made elsewhere in FATA or <em>Afghanistan</em> by a number of other gunsmiths, it has been linked to <em>Darra</em> due to the town being the main source of arms for sale and the similar types of AK designed copies/modifications known to have come out of there. I could list an almost infinite number of firearms designs displaying their know-how such as the modified SKS made to resemble an AK, or the well-known 8mm bolt-action faux AK and even the more recent AK M4geries. Forget all of those firearms, the gunsmiths themselves are the ones to keep this market and tradition alive, it’s them you have to appreciate as without them there would be more-or-less nothing left of the industry. The ingenuity and skill they have has made <em>Darra</em> a household name throughout the region and extending to much of the world, even to those who are not versed on firearms.</p>
<div id="attachment_2986"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2986" data-attachment-id="2986" data-permalink="https://silahreport.com/2019/07/25/when-darra-gunsmiths-went-mainstream-the-akmsu/attachment/111/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111.jpg?fit=900%2C334&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="900,334" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;11&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS DIGITAL REBEL&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;315532888&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;31&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.0166666666667&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111.jpg?fit=300%2C111&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111.jpg?fit=900%2C334&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111.jpg?resize=900%2C334" alt="" width="900" height="334" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111.jpg?w=900&amp;ssl=1 900w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111.jpg?resize=300%2C111&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/silahreport.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/111.jpg?resize=768%2C285&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" data-recalc-dims="1"></p><p id="caption-attachment-2986">AKMSU – Royal Armouries, Leeds, UK. Image courtesy of Rob stott (AK Catalogue)</p></div>
<p><em>Darra</em> has managed to stand against the tide of time and change in an increasingly connected world and holds its own against all odds but has still found a way to use newer technologies and retain its own methods &amp; procedures of manufacturing in its regular business. Even with all that, there is now news that changes things, FATA and Darra with it, will finally be incorporated into the neighboring <em>KPK</em> (<em>Khyber</em> <em>Pakhtunkhwa</em>) province of <em>Pakistan</em>. Regrettably, this means that their own tribal laws will now be abolished and government/regional laws and regulations will be implemented in its place there. The whole town’s industry will be made to register for licenses in either manufacturing or dealing sectors or be shut down. It is said that they will have easier access to raw materials and the costs of business will hopefully decrease, this is something that we can only hope does not destroy this historic industry. <em>Darra</em> will move into the new age with much newer equipment and tooling plus workshops and industrial estates that are planned to be built there and in other places with support of the current federal government of <em>Pakistan</em>. It is planned that arms manufactured there will be available to international markets via some …</p></div></div></div></div></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://silahreport.com/2019/08/23/the-last-gunsmiths-of-the-khyber-pass/">https://silahreport.com/2019/08/23/the-last-gunsmiths-of-the-khyber-pass/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://silahreport.com/2019/08/23/the-last-gunsmiths-of-the-khyber-pass/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24388849</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 03:54:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Principles for Better Design]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 24 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24388753">thread link</a>) | @Ninroot
<br/>
September 5, 2020 | https://reflexio.debec.eu/principles-for-better-design | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://reflexio.debec.eu/principles-for-better-design">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

        
        <figure>
            <img alt="cover" src="https://reflexio.debec.eu/assets/windmill.svg">
            <figcaption><a href="https://www.pinterest.fr/pin/642044490609394018/" target="_blank">credit</a></figcaption>
            
        </figure>
        
        <p>Design is a broad topic. This post won’t approach the adjective qualifying a style with simple forms and a pure appearance. No. Design is broader than a sleek car or an harmonious living room.</p>

<p>Design is a creative activity that aims to invent, improve and solve problems. Life is full of them, in various domains, which pushes people to eventually become a designer of something. Whether you’re conceiving a recipe, an apartment layout, a software or a rocket you are designing. By learning the fundamentals, you will arm yourself for various situations. Here is a list of the best pragmatic principles I’ve learned to better design. In spite of their obviousness and renown, my experience has shown me that some of these principles are often forgotten.</p>

<p><strong>Fun fact</strong>: In english, <em>to design</em> means both <em>to draw</em> and <em>to conceive according to a plan</em>. Similarly in French, the word <em>dessin</em> (a drawing) derives its etymology from the word <em>dessein</em> (have the intention).</p>

<h2 id="incremental-improvement">Incremental improvement</h2>

<p>Believing you can do it right the first time is naive at best, pretentious at worst. <strong>You will fail and have to accept it</strong>. Do not postpone but instead <strong>release fast</strong>, get feedback early and iterate to make it better. You will find many references, notably on Lean Startup, DevOps culture or Site Reliability Engineering, which encourage <strong>a quick redesign capability rather than a perfect design at the first place</strong>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>To write clean code, you must first write dirty code and then clean it. […]
Learning to write clean code is hard work. It requires more than just the knowledge of principles and patterns. You must sweat over it. You must practice it yourself, and watch yourself fail. Robert C. Martin — Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="reuse-what-exists">Reuse what exists</h2>

<p>It is unlikely that the problem you face is fundamentally new. Before making any effort, look for <strong>existing solutions</strong> or proven practices. <strong>Be humble</strong> and accept you can’t compete with years of expertise on a subject. If so, the motivation to develop the new model must come from reaching the limits of the previous one. In software engineering for instance, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_design_pattern">design patterns</a> are formalized best practices that the programmer can use to solve common problems when designing an application or system.</p>

<p>Don’t limit yourself to the area of the original problem, sometimes a similar problem has been found and solved long before in <strong>a different field</strong>. Learn about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queueing_theory">queuing theory</a> will help you to write an operating system scheduler as well as being frustrated in a supermarket queue. Solutions come from fields of experiences and theories that you would not necessarily expect.</p>

<h2 id="five-whys">Five whys</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_whys">Five whys technique</a>, originally developed by Toyota, has been mostly used for exploring the root cause of a defect in a system. It involves asking the relevant question starting with a why in order to find the source which cause the failure. Adapt this technique to find out what really matter in our design. For example, “<em>We need a program which exports our documentation to PDF</em>”:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Why? - So the export can go on the website.</li>
  <li>Why? - Because our customers has to read it.</li>
  <li>Why? - Because they require it to maintain the software.</li>
  <li>Why (don’t they have access to the documentation like everyone else)? - Because they haven’t been integrated into our platform.</li>
  <li>Why? Because they have never been on-board on the platform.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Decision</strong>: instead of developing a complex program which exports PDF, write a simple on-boarding guide for the customers.</p>

<p>This situation often occurs when the given requirement includes the design. Before answering the question <em>“How do we do it?”</em> directly, the first and most important step is to remember “<em>Why do we do it?</em>”. Once you have understood the <strong>root reasons</strong> and constraints for the requirement, it clears the path on how to get there and can <strong>prevent</strong> you from taking <strong>very long detours</strong> in addition to <strong>simplifying</strong> the design.</p>

<h2 id="keep-it-simple-stupid">Keep it simple stupid</h2>

<p><strong>Resolve problems, don’t create them</strong>. You should be suspicious of providing a solution that makes the overall system more complicated than before. Remember: You’ll have to maintain everything you build, so you’d better build as little and simply as possible.</p>

<p>Simple designs are easy to <strong>learn</strong>, easy to <strong>teach</strong>, easy to <strong>use</strong> and therefore easily <strong>appeal</strong> to customers. It forces the design to be intuitive and obvious, reducing the learning curve and facilitates the adoption. Like Denis Diderot says in Pensées sur l’interprétation de la nature:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>These books [of Sthal and Newton] were just waiting to be heard, to be valued for what they were worth; and it would not have cost their authors more than a month to make them clear; that month would have spared three years of labor and exhaustion to a thousand good spirits.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>But what is a simple design? In the <a href="https://landing.google.com/sre/sre-book/chapters/simplicity/">Simplicity chapter of the Site Reliability Engineering</a> book of Google, they mention a great quote from the French poet Antoine de Saint Exupery about perfection which could fit very well with simplicity:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>perfection is finally attained not when there is no longer more to add, but when there is no longer anything to take away - A. de Saint Exupéry, Terre des Hommes</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="perfect-is-the-enemy-of-good-enough">Perfect is the enemy of good enough</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.pinterest.de/pin/397724210839705109/"><img src="https://reflexio.debec.eu/assets/moka-pot.svg" alt="moka"></a></p>

<p>The moka coffee maker may not produce perfect coffee, but it requires so little maintenance compared to a large coffee machine with radiators, pipes, grinder, etc. that it makes the compromise “complexity / coffee taste” great.</p>

<p>Remember the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_principle">Pareto principle</a>: in general <strong>80% of a things can be done in 20%</strong> of the total allocated time. Conversely, the hardest <strong>20% left takes 80%</strong> of the time. Perfection requires infinite time and energy. This is impossible and therefore should not be part of your design.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Beware of the perfection pitfall and design your architecture only as good as necessary and not as good as ultimate possible. - Ralf S. Engelschall</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="postpone-complexity">Postpone complexity</h2>

<p>Simplicity and incremental improvement principles give birth to a another principle: <strong>Postpone complexity</strong>. Complexity lies in early optimization, as Donald E. Knuth points out in his article <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/pdf/10.1145/361604.361612?download=true">Computer Programming as Art</a> with “<em>premature optimization is the root of all evil</em>”. Focus on designing something that works instead of something finely tune that does not.</p>

<p>Complexity lies also in early generalization. Focus on designing something that works in a single use case rather than something that will not work in many. When designing a coffee machine, first design something that makes a simple black coffee. If you plan ahead to include all extra options for latte, cappuccino or irish coffee you will end up not making a simple back coffee. As elegantly summarized by Ralf S. Engelschall: “<em>Use before reuse</em>”.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>Do you think there’s a principle missing? Send me your comments! This list will certainly be extended and refined, subscribe to the <a data-formkit-toggle="78a863d4eb" href="https://reflexio-debec.ck.page/78a863d4eb">newsletter</a> if you wish to be notified about it. In the meantime, how are you going to ensure that you do not forget to implement the principles you have just learned?</p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://reflexio.debec.eu/principles-for-better-design</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24388753</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 03:31:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PDP 11/70 Emulator (2020)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 56 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24388412">thread link</a>) | @threeme3
<br/>
September 5, 2020 | https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
    <div>
      <div>
        
        <p>digital equipment corporation • maynard, massachusetts</p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div>
      

        <div>
          <p><img src="https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11-70.svg" alt="pdp11-70" width="114px"></p>
          
          
        </div>

        

        
      </div>
    </div>

    <p>console
      <br>
      
      <br>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
    </p>
     <p><label>Paper tape reader file</label>
     </p>
    <br>
    
    <br>
    
    <br>
    
    
    <br>
    <h3>PDP 11/70 Emulator - v3.1 August 2020</h3>
    <p>
      This emulator came about because years ago I was a programmer for RSTS/E on a PDP 11/45 and had admired the console idle loop light pattern - but I couldn't quite remember how it looked. Given the unavailability of real systems it became time to write
      an emulator!
    </p>
    <p>
      I was going to start with a PDP 11/45 emulator but the extra memory of a PDP 11/70 became far too attractive (a whole 4MB!). It took some time before I finally produced a
      <a href="https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11-45.html">PDP 11/45</a> version.
    </p>
    <p>
      I have met my core objective - I can now see the RSTS/E console light pattern that I was looking for, and found that newer versions (eg v9.6) have a different light pattern. Also I have now seen some of the light patterns for other OSes. RSX and BSD 2.11
      have their own different patterns and Unix V5 and Ultrix operate with absolute minimum light movement (I'm assuming they operates mostly in WAIT mode).
    </p>
    <p>
      Getting all of the operating systems used here presents its own set of challenges - one of which is finding the software in the first place. But one of the most interesting was RSTS/E V06C which has its own
      <a href="https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/RSTSv06c.html">story</a>.
    </p>
    <p>
      Note: The boot code in this emulator is a custom PDP 11 program running with it's own set of light patterns. It is initially loaded at address 140000 and has a LIGHTS command which operates by mapping and executing a WAIT instruction from a pattern of virtual addresses located in Supervisor
      mode. You can also use the BOOT command to start one of the guest operating systems listed below, or the ODT command to start a version of the Octal Debugging Tool.
    </p>
    <p>
      However boot code like this was not part of early PDP 11s. These systems had no BIOS or other software to help get the bare metal started. If you were lucky perhaps the previous boot code would still be intact in non-volatile magnetic core memory, but in general booting the system required toggling in a small bootstrap loader from the front panel. There are listings of bootstrap loaders for various devices
      <a href="https://www.sydney.edu.au/science/psychology/pdp-11/bootstraps.html">here</a>.
      If you are a purist don't use the boot code! Instead find the bootstrap code for the device you want to boot from and toggle it in through the switches. However be warned - the boot program will not work unless toggled in perfectly which often takes a few goes.
    </p>
    <p>
      Here is an example of the switch commands for booting from an RK05 where the value at address 1002 selects the unit number (rk0, rk1, rk2, etc). Goodluck!
    </p>
    <pre><b>
Address Data    Code           Switch commands
</b>
                               HALT, 001000, LOAD ADDRESS
001000  012737  mov #unit,rkda 012737, DEPOSIT
001002  000000                 000000, DEPOSIT or 020000 for rk1, 040000 for rk2, etc
001004  177412                 177412, DEPOSIT
001006  012700  mov #rkwc, r0  012700, DEPOSIT
001010  177406                 177406, DEPOSIT
001012  012710  mov #-256,(r0) 012710, DEPOSIT
001014  177400                 177400, DEPOSIT
001016  012740  mov #5,-(r0)   012740, DEPOSIT
001020  000005                 000005, DEPOSIT
001022  105710  tstb (r0)      105710, DEPOSIT
001024  100376  bpl .-2        100376, DEPOSIT
001026  005007  clr pc         005007, DEPOSIT
                               001000, LOAD ADDRESS, ENABLE, START
</pre>
    <p>
      If you wish to toggle in a simple light chaser to the front panel then here are some switch commands which can be used:
    </p>
    <pre><b>
Address Data    Code        Switch commands
</b>
                            HALT, 001000, LOAD ADDRESS
001000  012700  mov #1,r0   012700, DEPOSIT
001002  000001              000001, DEPOSIT
001004  006100  rol r0      006100, DEPOSIT
001006  000005  reset       000005, DEPOSIT
001010  000775  br .-4      000775, DEPOSIT
                            001000, LOAD ADDRESS, ENABLE, START
</pre>
To restart the initial boot code (if it has not been overwritten) use the switch commands:
    <pre>HALT, 140000, LOAD ADDRESS, ENABLE, START
</pre>
    <p>
      If you plan to run the emulator repeatedly or for a project, consider downloading the emulator to your own machine or server.
      This will <b>significantly</b> speed any of the emulator disk accesses and response times. All files and emulator OS
      disks can be found in the top level folder of
      <b><a href="https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/">http://skn.noip.me/pdp11/</a></b> or in the zip file
      <b><a href="https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11.zip">pdp11.zip</a></b> Please note that browser security
      policy may prevent local emulator pages from booting disk images so please read the information in <b>StartChrome.cmd</b>
    </p>
    <p>
      If you are interested in how the emulator works then you can browse the source files on
      <b><a href="https://github.com/paulnank/nankervis-pdp11-js">Github</a></b>.
      The main Javascript files are pdp11.js, fpp.js and iopage.js
    </p>
    <p>
      There are many PDP emulators out there and I have never seen what I consider to be a complete list. Some of the really interesting ones can be found by googling terms such as "vhdl pdp 11". However the gold standard is SIMH at
      <a href="http://simh.trailing-edge.com/">Trailing Edge</a>.
      A different approach to Javascript PDP 11 emulation can be found at
      <a href="http://www.pcjs.org/devices/pdp11/">www.pcjs.org</a>.
    </p>
    <p>
      I believe that the first PDP 11 emulator would be SIM-11 written in FORTRAN before the first PDP 11/20 hardware was even built - see
      <a href="http://www.hampage.hu/pdp-11/birth.html"> How the PDP-11 Was Born</a>. There is more PDP 11 history at
      <a href="http://www.hampage.hu/pdp-11/main.html">www.hampage.hu</a>.
    </p>
    <p>
      Of course if you want your own PDP 11/70 front panel you might consider a
      <a href="http://obsolescence.wixsite.com/obsolescence/pidp-11">PiDP-11</a>.
    </p>
    <p>
      Happy emulating!
    </p>
    <p>
      Paul Nankervis
    </p>
    <p>
      This emulator matches approximately the following SIMH configuration:
    </p>
    <pre>set cpu 11/70 1912K nofpp  !1912K is not actually SIMH legal - use 2M instead
set clk 50hz
attach rk0 rk0.dsk  !RK05 image of Unix V5
attach rk1 rk1.dsk  !RK05 image of RT11 v4.0
attach rk2 rk2.dsk  !RK05 image of RSTS V06C-03
attach rk3 rk3.dsk  !RK05 image of XXDP
attach rk4 rk4.dsk  !RK05 image of RT-11 3B
attach rk5 rk5.dsk  !RK05 image of RT-11 V5.4F
set rl0 RL02
attach rl0 rl0.dsk  !RL02 image of BSD 2.9
set rl1 RL02
attach rl1 rl1.dsk  !RL02 image of RSX 11M v3.2
set rl2 RL01
attach rl2 rl2.dsk  !RL01 image of RSTS/E v7.0
set rl3 RL02
attach rl3 rl3.dsk  !RL02 image of XXDP+
set rp0 RP06
attach rp0 rp0.dsk  !RP06 image of ULTRIX-11 V3.1
set rp1 RP06
attach rp1 rp1.dsk  !RP06 image of BSD 2.11
set rp2 RP04
attach rp2 rp2.dsk  !RP04 image of RSTS/E v9.6
set rp3 RP04
attach rp3 rp3.dsk  !RP04 image of RSX 11M v4.6
set rp4 RP04
attach rp4 rp4.dsk  !RP04 image of RSTS/E v10.1
attach tm0 tm0.tap  !Backup of RSTS 4B-17
attach tm1 tm1.tap  !Distribution for RSTS V06C-03
attach tm2 tm2.tap  !Distribution for RSTS V7.0
</pre>
    <h3>List of guest OS's:
    </h3>
    <table>
      <tbody><tr>
        <td>
          <b>Disk
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>
          <b>OS
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>
          <b>Comment
          </b>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RK0
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>Unix V5
        </td>
        <td>Boot using:
          <b>unix
          </b> then login as
          <b>root
          </b>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RK1
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RT11 v4.0
        </td>
        <td>The lightest/fastest OS here
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RK2
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RSTS V06C-03
        </td>
        <td>Boot and login as
          <b>1,2
          </b> with password
          <b>SYSTEM
          </b> or as
          <b>11,70
          </b> using
          <b>PDP
          </b>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RK3
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>XXDP
        </td>
        <td>Diagnostic OS and utilities
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RK4
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RT-11 3B
        </td>
        <td>Distribution for RT-11 Version 3B
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RK5
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RT-11 V5.4F
        </td>
        <td>Distribution for RT-11 Version 5.4F
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>TM0
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RSTS 4B-17
        </td>
        <td>Boot ROLLIN from TM0 and restore DK0 with "DK:&lt;MT:VIXEN/REW". Reboot from DK0 with "/BO:DK" to auto-login as
          <b>1,2
          </b> (password is
          <b>SYSTEM
          </b>) Relogin as
          <b>11,70
          </b> with password
          <b>PDP
          </b> Commands are case sensitive.
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RL0
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>BSD 2.9
        </td>
        <td>Boot using:
          <b>rl(0,0)rlunix
          </b> &nbsp; CTRL/D to exit single user and start multiuser - login as
          <b>root
          </b> (no password)
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RL1
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RSX 11M v3.2
        </td>
        <td>Login as
          <b>1,2
          </b> with password
          <b>SYSTEM
          </b>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RL2
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RSTS/E v7.0
        </td>
        <td>Option: &lt;LF&gt; Suboption: &lt;LF&gt; ... Login as
          <b>1,2
          </b> using
          <b>SYSTEM
          </b> or
          <b>11,70
          </b> using
          <b>PDP
          </b>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RL3
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>XXDP
        </td>
        <td>Larger version of diagnostics - including PDP 11/70 utilities
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RP0
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>ULTRIX-11 V3.1
        </td>
        <td>CTRL/D to enter multiuser mode. Login as
          <b>root
          </b> with no password
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RP1
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>BSD 2.11
        </td>
        <td>Will autoboot and enter multiuser mode. Login as
          <b>root
          </b> with no password
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RP2
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RSTS/E v9.6
        </td>
        <td>Answer boot questions and login as
          <b>1,2
          </b> (password
          <b>SYSTEM
          </b>) or
          <b>11,70
          </b> (no password)
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RP3
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RSX 11M v4.6
        </td>
        <td>Starts logged in as
          <b>1,2
          </b> (password
          <b>SYSTEM
          </b>) - user accounts
          <b>200,1
          </b> (no password) or
          <b>11,70
          </b> (password
          <b>PDP
          </b>)
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>
          <b>RP4
          </b>
        </td>
        <td>RSTS/E v10.1
        </td>
        <td>Answer boot questions and login as
          <b>1,2
          </b> (password
          <b>SYSTEM
          </b>) or
          <b>11,70
          </b> (no password)
        </td>
      </tr>
    </tbody></table>
    <p>
      <b>Note:
      </b> Disks are shown in approximately order size. The
      <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RK05">RK05
      </a> disks at the top are small …</p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11.html">https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://skn.noip.me/pdp11/pdp11.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24388412</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 02:03:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
