<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 12:26:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 12:26:48 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Real World Haskell]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25005525">thread link</a>) | @Fiveplus
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://mmhaskell.com/real-world | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mmhaskell.com/real-world">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div data-block-type="44" id="block-yui_3_17_2_5_1512885228788_3774"><div>
<p>In <a href="https://www.mmhaskell.com/real-world/databases">part 1</a> of this series, we'll use the Persistent library and Template Haskell to create a simple database schema. This will enable us to run migrations with ease. It will also allow us to write some simple type safe SQL queries!</p>

<p>Once we have our database set up, we'll want to serve the information we're storing over a web API. We'll do this with the Servant library. Servant allows us to build endpoints that retrieve their query parameters in a type-safe way! Find out how in <a href="https://www.mmhaskell.com/real-world/servant">part 2</a> of the series!</p>

<p>Now that we have our API set up, we'll see how we can make it faster by adding a Redis cache! We'll learn how to use the Redis bindings for Haskell so we can avoid using the database for some of our queries! See how it all works in <a href="https://www.mmhaskell.com/real-world/redis">part 3</a>.</p>

<p>Our end-to-end system is now quite complicated, so testing it is difficult for a variety of reasons. In <a href="https://www.mmhaskell.com/real-world/docker">part 4</a>, we'll see some techinques to test our web API. We'll also use Docker to make this process easier.</p>

<p>In the <a href="https://www.mmhaskell.com/real-world/esqueleto">final part</a> of our Real World Haskell series, we'll learn some more about advanced SQL queries. We'll extend our schema and use the Esqueleto library to perform type safe joins between our different data types!</p>

<p>This series goes over some cool libraries, but there's still so much more to explore! Check out our <a href="https://www.mmhaskell.com/production-checklist">Production Checklist</a> and explore a ton of other libraries you can use for various tasks when making a production system in Haskell!</p>
</div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mmhaskell.com/real-world</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25005525</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 06:43:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Helsinki Relocation Package: City as a Service]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 494 | Comments 436 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25003999">thread link</a>) | @mannylopez
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/90-day-finn/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/90-day-finn/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main" data-scroll-offset="52">

	<div id="after_submenu"><div><div><div><div>

<section itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div itemprop="text"><p>A world-leading technology hub in a value-driven society. A well-organized, stable and caring democracy where everything just works. A place that lets you live more and worry less.</p>
<p>This is your call for a 90-day audition in Helsinki, featuring an unseen level of work-life balance!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/90-day-finn-application/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Apply for 90 days in Helsinki &gt;</a></p>
</div></section>

</div></div></div><!-- close content main div --></div></div><div id="package"><div><div><div><div>
<div id="RelocationPackage"><h2 itemprop="headline">Helsinki Relocation Package: City as a Service</h2></div>
<section itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div itemprop="text"><p>City as a Service is an all-inclusive service bundle that unlocks the entire city, built to help international talent feel at home in Helsinki.</p>
<p>We will provide selected applicants with a free 90-day relocation package for the entire family. We’ll arrange your housing, daycare, schooling, everything you need – the real deal, just like a Finn.</p>
<p>In contrast to ‘Golden Visa’ programs, no charges or investments are required. We’re not after your money but all about lasting relationships. The real question is: are you up to try a life that’s utopia to many, reality for Finns?</p>
<p>Building on a <a href="https://helsinkiasaservice.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">successful demo run in 2019</a>, you’re now invited to audit for Season 1!</p>
</div></section>
<div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><header><h3 itemprop="headline">Always Available: Freemium Package 0 €</h3></header><div itemprop="text"><ul>
<li>Hang out with the happiest folks in the world</li>
<li>Breathe the cleanest air and enjoy the nature – free for all to access</li>
<li>Secure a free top-class education for your children</li>
<li>Enjoy the healthiest work-life balance worldwide</li>
<li>Benefit from a highly ranked – and free – health care system</li>
<li>Roam around the capital region with efficient public transport</li>
<li>Sweat in the Finnish sauna, perhaps with a dip into the frozen Baltic Sea</li>
<li>Experience four seasons: changes in weather and daylight are a feature and not a bug</li>
<li>Live in a city where everything simply works</li>
<li>Stay safe with science-driven COVID19 response – yes, we’re open and yes, we wear masks!</li>
</ul>
</div></div></article></div><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><header><h3 itemprop="headline">Limited Time Offer: Full Package 0 € / 90 Days</h3></header><div itemprop="text"><ul>
<li>All the documentation needed for a 90-day stay</li>
<li>Airport pickup and orientation services to get settled and up to speed</li>
<li>Housing arrangements to find a place that’s just right for you and your family</li>
<li>School/daycare arrangements for children (daycare is cheap, school is free!)</li>
<li>Top-notch facilities for efficient remote work and study</li>
<li>Relocation consultation during the whole stay</li>
<li>In-person introductions to technology hubs and business networks in the Helsinki region</li>
<li>Get-togethers and Finnish experiences during the 90 days</li>
<li>Support to apply for permanent residency and everything needed for a longer stay – we bet this will come in handy!</li>
</ul>
</div></div></article></div>

</div></div></div><!-- close content main div --></div></div><div id="av_section_4" data-section-bg-repeat="no-repeat"><p>© Jussi Hellsten / Torikorttelit</p></div><div id="after_section_4"><div><div><div><div>

<section itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><p>A good question. After all, this world is full of busy-bee tech hubs and colossal metropolises. Those are in their own league – and so are we: the planet’s happiest capital now provides you with all the features of good life in one easy-going package. Helsinki is not busy, it’s cozy and safe. No red flags!</p></section>
<div><ul id="avia-icongrid-5fa7e40fa0045">
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1 </h4><h6>Happiest country in the world</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1</h4><h6>Best city for work-life balance</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1 </h4><h6>The best country for expat families</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1</h4><h6>The best digital public service</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1</h4><h6>The best education system in the world</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1</h4><h6>Environmentally Healthy Country in the World</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#3</h4><h6>Least corrupted country in the world</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#4</h4><h6>Emerging Startup Ecosystem Globally</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1</h4><h6>most innovative ecosystem in the world</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
<li><div><article itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div><div><header><h4 itemprop="headline">#1</h4><h6>Finland is attracting the most VC Investments in Europe</h6></header></div></div></article></div></li>
</ul></div>


</div></div></div><!-- close content main div --></div></div><div id="people"><div><div><div><div>


<div><section itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><p itemprop="text"><h3>Want to know more?</h3>
</p></section><br>
<div itemprop="image" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/ImageObject"><div><p><a href="https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/people/panu-maula/"><img width="180" height="180" src="https://mlfa7nspfe08.i.optimole.com/8a2fooM-La_oAgXw/w:180/h:180/q:eco/https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Johanna-Huurre-web.png" alt="" title="Johanna Huurre web" itemprop="thumbnailUrl" data-opt-src="https://mlfa7nspfe08.i.optimole.com/8a2fooM-La_oAgXw/w:180/h:180/q:auto/rt:fill/g:ce/https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Johanna-Huurre-web.png" data-old-src="https://mlfa7nspfe08.i.optimole.com/8a2fooM-La_oAgXw/w:180/h:180/q:eco/https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Johanna-Huurre-web.png"></a></p></div></div><br>
<section itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork"><div itemprop="text"><h3>Johanna Huurre</h3>
<p>Marketing and Communications Director</p>
<p>+358 400 211 251<br>
johanna.huurre@hbh.fi</p>
</div></section></div>

</div></div></div><!-- close content main div --> <!-- section close by builder template -->		</div><!--end builder template--></div><!-- close default .container_wrap element -->				<!-- end main -->
		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.helsinkibusinesshub.fi/90-day-finn/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25003999</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 01:35:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Whistleblower: UN actively passing names of Uighur dissidents to Chinese regime]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 69 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25002904">thread link</a>) | @rbecker
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://www.i24news.tv/en/news/international/1604309404-un-actively-passing-names-of-uighur-dissidents-to-chinese-regime-whistleblower | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.i24news.tv/en/news/international/1604309404-un-actively-passing-names-of-uighur-dissidents-to-chinese-regime-whistleblower">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.i24news.tv/en/news/international/1604309404-un-actively-passing-names-of-uighur-dissidents-to-chinese-regime-whistleblower</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25002904</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 22:43:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Martin Gurri and the ungovernable public]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25001645">thread link</a>) | @deepbow
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://www.thepullrequest.com/p/the-prophet-of-the-revolt | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.thepullrequest.com/p/the-prophet-of-the-revolt">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.katiasobolski.com/"><img src="https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F8e6ed065-7822-4aba-bcd3-effe79e3f542_1200x1072.jpeg" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/8e6ed065-7822-4aba-bcd3-effe79e3f542_1200x1072.jpeg&quot;,&quot;height&quot;:1072,&quot;width&quot;:1200,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:203241,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/jpeg&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:&quot;https://www.katiasobolski.com/&quot;}" alt=""></a></p><p>                                                                                         portrait by <a href="https://www.katiasobolski.com/">Katia Sobolski</a></p><p><em>“Sometimes, by sheer luck, you are in a high place and can see the shape and character of the approaching trouble, while those in the flatlands have no idea of what’s coming.&nbsp; That was me at the global media analysis section of CIA.&nbsp; And I was not alone.&nbsp; A group of us were obsessed with the same drama.&nbsp; We watched the digital tsunami tear its way around the world, and we observed, amazed, a tremendous spike in social and political turbulence behind it.&nbsp; We all asked the same question:&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; What does information technology have to do with politics?</em></p><p><em>That was the seed out of which <a href="https://amzn.to/3c8Nk4E">The Revolt of the Public</a> grew.”</em></p><p><strong>Martin Gurri was formerly a member of CIA’s global media analysis team, and in 2014 he self-published a book that feels like it was written last week. Republished by Stripe Press in 2018, it soon became a must-read inside Silicon Valley, particularly among those astonished at how they themselves had become the central story to the central challenges in the West. This spy from the Beltway made a victory lap in Silicon Valley, where I met him at a book launch dinner. Aside from the usual Cuban-exile plotting, we’ve been kibbitzing about tech and media ever since.</strong></p><p><strong>This Q&amp;A was conducted over email, and Gurri’s answers are unedited.</strong></p><div><p><strong>'<a href="https://amzn.to/2Fp9Av6">Revolt of the Public</a>' is an obvious play on <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/gasset/">Ortega y Gassett's</a> <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/the-smartest-book-about-our-digital-age-was-published-in-1929">'Revolt of the Masses' </a>(which I think you credit). In a sense, it's an updated version of Ortega's book, but this time the 'mass man' has smartphones and an even bigger entitlement chip on their shoulder. <p>That said, I find the eponymous reference here to be Lasch's <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Lasch#The_Revolt_of_the_Elites:_And_the_Betrayal_of_Democracy">'The Revolt of the Elites'</a>. Your book seems a closing parenthetical bookend to that classic work. To very briefly summarize, Lasch predicted that the formerly aristocratic WASP elites, who considered the US their personal political project which they took on with a considerable sense of duty and noblesse oblige, would be replaced by a grasping and transactional neoliberal elite utterly indifferent to the plight of those outside the new economic order. In short, he predicted the Whole Foods-buying, Zoom-using class that we now take for granted, but who at the time were still an odd bird. </p><p>(I'm old enough to remember the mass-market, middle-class post-Eisenhower, pre-Summer-of-Love America, at least as transmitted by my parents who very agilely acclimated to it from the pre-revolutionary, bourgeois Cuba they fled.)</p><p>The relationship is causal: We wouldn't have had the Revolt of the Public in the 2010s without the Revolt of the Elites in the 80s. What do you make of the generational juxtaposition?</p></strong></p></div><p>Well, when my parents brought <em>me</em> to the United States from Cuba, Eisenhower was president.&nbsp; I remember the Summer of Love – hazily.&nbsp; That’s how old I am.&nbsp; So enough of that nonsense, young Antonio.</p><p>I began <em>The Revolt of the Public</em> in media res, at the point in which I and a circle of analysts in CIA became aware that the information landscape was being torn to shreds.&nbsp; I began with the digital tsunami.&nbsp; I hadn’t read the Lasch book at the time, though I have since.&nbsp; I agree with you that it’s a brilliant work of analysis and that it connects directly with my framework.</p><p>The great political conflict of our century, I believe, is that between a networked public and the elites who inhabit the great hierarchical institutions that organize modern life.&nbsp; <em>The Revolt of the Public</em> opens with this tectonic collision already rattling the world.&nbsp; The first edition of the book was published in 2014, and I desperately wanted to make readers aware that behind the rituals of our partisan politics a much more profound struggle was battering and changing the society we had inherited from the 20th century.&nbsp; I used words like “negation” and “nihilism” – it makes me smile to recall how much I agonized whether these terms were too sensational for an analyst to use.&nbsp; Since 2016 and the advent of Donald Trump, of course, everybody wants to talk about nihilism.&nbsp; (Trump’s election gave book sales a big boost, BTW – I sort of place myself in the same category as the <em>New York Times</em>, as a Trump profiteer.)</p><p>But the book left open a number of fundamental questions.&nbsp; For example, the public appears as a leading political actor on center stage already in an angry and rejectionist mood.&nbsp; The public is driven to the streets – and to vote for populists – by a need to repudiate the established order that sometimes tips into nihilism.&nbsp; But why?&nbsp; The usual economic explanations explain nothing, in my opinion.&nbsp; Revolts have happened in poor countries like Somalia and affluent countries like France, Chile, and the US – and the public in revolt, when looked at closely, consists mostly of middle class and college-educated people.&nbsp; That’s true everywhere.</p><p>Similarly, the book shows the elites to be in a state of confusion bordering on panic.&nbsp; They are baffled by anything digital and utterly clueless about where all the nonentities shouting angrily outside their windows come from.&nbsp; But why?&nbsp; In the last century, two generations of elites tackled the Great Depression, World War II, and the Cold War, and came ahead on every count.&nbsp; They built the great dams and nuclear plants that electrified the country, and threw in the interstate highway grid for good measure.&nbsp; What has changed?</p><p>That is where Lasch and <em>Revolt of the Elites</em> make a significant contribution to understanding our present moment.&nbsp; He describes the movement from Jefferson’s “aristocracy of talent” to a “meritocracy” that justifies itself by definition and by opposition.&nbsp; If you are an elite, you must deserve to be one.&nbsp; Why else would you be in your important perch in the hierarchy?&nbsp; After all, you went to the best schools, travelled widely, and speak a few words of French!&nbsp; And of course, every Brahmin class needs a thick wall to keep out the lower castes.&nbsp; Those are the people who went to community college, speak Southern, and on the rare occasion they travel end up (like Mr. Bean) saying “gracias” at the Louvre.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Here is Lasch on this subject:&nbsp; “The new elites are in revolt against ‘Middle America,’ as they imagine it; a nation technologically backward, politically reactionary, repressive in it sexual morality, middlebrow in tastes, smug and complacent, dull and dowdy.”</p><h4><em>The public, which swims comfortably in the digital sea, knows far more than elites trapped in obsolete structures.&nbsp; The public knows when the elites fail to deliver their promised “solutions,” when they tell falsehoods or misspeak, when they are caught in sexual escapades, and when they indulge in astonishing levels of smugness and hypocrisy.&nbsp; The public is disenchanted in the elites and their institutions, much in the way science disenchanted the world of fairies and goblins.&nbsp; The natural reaction is cynicism.&nbsp; The elites aren’t seen as fallible humans doing their best, but as corrupt and arrogant jerks.</em></h4><p>In other words, the elites had abandoned the idea of serving the public before the arrival of the digital tsunami.  What that catastrophe did was to reverse the polarities of power:  it was the public that was now technologically adept, politically restless, and in revolt against the perplexed elites.  The vast gap remained, and the elites have no wish to cross it – to do so would mean breaking that wall that protects the pure soul of the Brahmin.</p><p>We have no way of knowing whether a more talented elite class could have avoided the current anger mobilizing the public or the hair-trigger impulse to revolt.&nbsp; There are no laboratories that run parallel versions of history.&nbsp; I will say this:&nbsp; the struggle today is structural, not personality-dependent.&nbsp; Even an FDR or a Reagan would have difficulty preserving institutions whose authority has collapsed because of a radical reversal in the information environment.</p><p><strong>You write:<p>"Uncertainty is an acid, corrosive to authority. Once the monopoly on information is lost, so too is our trust. Every presidential statement, every CIA assessment, every investigative report by a great newspaper, suddenly acquired an arbitrary aspect, and seemed grounded in moral predilection rather than intellectual rigor. When proof for and against approaches infinity, a cloud of suspicion about cherry-picking data will hang over every authoritative judgment."</p><p>Your assertion, developed eloquently and at length, is that elites are no longer able to mediate reality via mass media, therefore convulsing into feckless inertia as a clamorous public picks apart every institutional shortfall. </p><p>What I couldn't quite discern was whether you thought this was purely a narrative failing, or indeed a competency one? </p><p>In other words, the news has always been fake and the histories at least partly (if not wholly) contrived.&nbsp; Read a French history of Napoleon and compare it to an Anglo one. Or for that matter, read your typical (lefty) English-language take on Cuba, vs. a Spanish language one. But they were self-consistent narratives maintained within meaningful political and linguistic borders. As flawed as these narratives were and are--the map was very definitely not the territory--they were coherent worldviews that helped that society navigate reality. Now those guiding (but also blinding) narratives are gone. Social media has served as a sort of society-wide bodycam: the institutional abuse was always there, now we're simply seeing it.</p><p>Or is your entire argument that institutions are really mired in a period of secular incompetence and decline?</p></strong><em><br></em></p><p>The highest calling of true elites is to translate the flux of reality into a coherent story.&nbsp; To most Americans, who believe reality must be approached “scientifically,” this sounds like spin or propaganda – but it’s much more essential than that.&nbsp; Every society is organized around specific ideals and habits of behavior.&nbsp; The institutions of government, information, commerce, even science, are erected on the basis of those ideals and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.thepullrequest.com/p/the-prophet-of-the-revolt">https://www.thepullrequest.com/p/the-prophet-of-the-revolt</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.thepullrequest.com/p/the-prophet-of-the-revolt</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25001645</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 20:29:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Election Battleground State Changes]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25001438">thread link</a>) | @aarkay
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://alex.github.io/nyt-2020-election-scraper/battleground-state-changes.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alex.github.io/nyt-2020-election-scraper/battleground-state-changes.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T23:15:18.189000">
            <td>2020-11-07 23:15:18 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>37,298</td>
            <td>78,792</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Lancaster:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Lancaster: 100%">    607</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 35.6% /
                64.4% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 25.2%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 73.0%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T21:00:52.182000">
            <td>2020-11-07 21:00:52 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>37,469</td>
            <td>79,399</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Lancaster:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Lancaster: 100%">  2,425</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 52.9% /
                47.1% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 24.3%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 73.0%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T20:23:49.644000">
            <td>2020-11-07 20:23:49 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>37,329</td>
            <td>81,824</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Philadelphia:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Philadelphia: 100%">  1,938</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 88.7% /
                11.3% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 22.3%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 72.2%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T16:42:02.894000">
            <td>2020-11-07 16:42:02 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>34,414</td>
            <td>83,762</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Allegheny:</strong> 76%<br><strong>Armstrong:</strong> 24%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Allegheny: 76%, Armstrong: 24%">  9,480</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 68.8% /
                31.2% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 24.2%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 69.9%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T16:22:41.988000">
            <td>2020-11-07 16:22:41 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>30,908</td>
            <td>93,242</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Philadelphia:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Philadelphia: 100%">  2,850</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 87.2% /
                12.8% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 23.0%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 65.9%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T15:25:34.837000">
            <td>2020-11-07 15:25:34 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>28,833</td>
            <td>96,092</td>
            <td>      0</td>
    <td>N/A</td>
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 26.3%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 64.4%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T14:49:53.923000">
            <td>2020-11-07 14:49:53 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>28,833</td>
            <td>98,167</td>
            <td>      0</td>
    <td>N/A</td>
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 26.3%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 64.0%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T14:41:31.650000">
            <td>2020-11-07 14:41:31 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>28,833</td>
            <td>97,091</td>
            <td>      0</td>
    <td>N/A</td>
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 26.3%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 64.2%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T14:23:36.675000">
            <td>2020-11-07 14:23:36 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>28,833</td>
            <td>99,187</td>
            <td>      0</td>
    <td>N/A</td>
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 26.3%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 63.9%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T03:42:51.218000">
            <td>2020-11-07 03:42:51 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>28,833</td>
            <td>83,589</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Allegheny:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Allegheny: 100%">  3,201</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 76.9% /
                23.1% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 26.3%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 66.6%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T02:41:31.963000">
            <td>2020-11-07 02:41:31 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>27,130</td>
            <td>86,790</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Allegheny:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Allegheny: 100%">  9,256</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 79.6% /
                20.4% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 28.0%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 65.0%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T01:47:07.682000">
            <td>2020-11-07 01:47:07 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>21,705</td>
            <td>96,046</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Chester:</strong> 48%<br><strong>Delaware:</strong> 44%<br><strong>Erie:</strong> 8%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Chester: 48%, Delaware: 44%, Erie: 8%">  5,184</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 77.0% /
                23.0% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 34.2%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 60.7%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T01:05:24.698000">
            <td>2020-11-07 01:05:24 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>19,491</td>
            <td>101,230</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Union:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Union: 100%">    205</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 27.1% /
                72.9% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 35.2%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 59.0%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-07T00:11:30.489000">
            <td>2020-11-07 00:11:30 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>19,584</td>
            <td>101,435</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Allegheny:</strong> 97%<br><strong>Huntingdon:</strong> 3%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Allegheny: 97%, Huntingdon: 3%">  5,497</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 75.8% /
                24.2% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 34.9%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 59.0%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T23:49:59.234000">
            <td>2020-11-06 23:49:59 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>16,784</td>
            <td>106,932</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Bradford:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Bradford: 100%">    437</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 23.5% /
                76.5% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 36.7%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 57.2%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T23:43:16.543000">
            <td>2020-11-06 23:43:16 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>17,012</td>
            <td>107,369</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Philadelphia:</strong> 59%<br><strong>Northampton:</strong> 27%<br><strong>Washington:</strong> 14%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Philadelphia: 59%, Northampton: 27%, Washington: 14%">  3,878</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 77.3% /
                22.7% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 36.0%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 57.3%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T23:26:05.585000">
            <td>2020-11-06 23:26:05 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,923</td>
            <td>111,247</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Mercer:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Mercer: 100%">  1,701</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 61.4% /
                38.6% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 36.6%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 56.1%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T22:35:03.624000">
            <td>2020-11-06 22:35:03 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,541</td>
            <td>112,948</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Pike:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Pike: 100%">     62</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 54.1% /
                45.9% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 36.2%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T22:24:11.877000">
            <td>2020-11-06 22:24:11 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,536</td>
            <td>113,010</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Blair:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Blair: 100%">    363</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 50.0% /
                50.0% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 36.1%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T22:14:55.472000">
            <td>2020-11-06 22:14:55 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,536</td>
            <td>113,373</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Wayne:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Wayne: 100%">     39</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 43.6% /
                56.4% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 35.9%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T22:03:00.523000">
            <td>2020-11-06 22:03:00 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,541</td>
            <td>113,412</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Lebanon:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Lebanon: 100%">     85</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 54.2% /
                45.8% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 35.9%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T21:39:06.880000">
            <td>2020-11-06 21:39:06 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,518</td>
            <td>113,497</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Cambria:</strong> 99%<br><strong>Sullivan:</strong> 1%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Cambria: 99%, Sullivan: 1%">    529</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 29.8% /
                70.2% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 35.7%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T21:30:56.743000">
            <td>2020-11-06 21:30:56 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,731</td>
            <td>114,026</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Centre:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Centre: 100%">      7</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 100.0% /
                 0.0% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 35.1%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T21:22:20.448000">
            <td>2020-11-06 21:22:20 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,724</td>
            <td>114,033</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Lackawanna:</strong> 95%<br><strong>Lycoming:</strong> 5%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Lackawanna: 95%, Lycoming: 5%">    218</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 51.9% /
                48.1% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 35.1%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T21:14:54.182000">
            <td>2020-11-06 21:14:54 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,716</td>
            <td>114,251</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Franklin:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Franklin: 100%">    113</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 42.2% /
                57.8% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 34.9%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T21:06:01.641000">
            <td>2020-11-06 21:06:01 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,733</td>
            <td>114,364</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Greene:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Greene: 100%">  2,070</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 61.0% /
                39.0% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 34.8%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.8%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T20:58:52.037000">
            <td>2020-11-06 20:58:52 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>14,281</td>
            <td>116,434</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Westmoreland:</strong> 90%<br><strong>Bradford:</strong> 10%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Westmoreland: 90%, Bradford: 10%">  2,965</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 61.0% /
                39.0% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 33.4%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.5%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T20:51:21.699000">
            <td>2020-11-06 20:51:21 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>13,641</td>
            <td>119,399</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Carbon:</strong> 61%<br><strong>Dauphin:</strong> 39%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Carbon: 61%, Dauphin: 39%">    479</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 43.0% /
                57.0% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 30.7%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.1%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T20:30:39.158000">
            <td>2020-11-06 20:30:39 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>13,707</td>
            <td>119,878</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Tioga:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Tioga: 100%">      4</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 25.0% /
                75.0% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 30.0%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.1%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T20:17:51.562000">
            <td>2020-11-06 20:17:51 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>13,709</td>
            <td>119,882</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Washington:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Washington: 100%">    255</td>
    
            <td>
                Biden 59.5% /
                40.5% Trump
            </td>
        
            <td>
                Trump is averaging 30.0%
            </td>
        
            <td>Trump needs 55.1%</td>
        </tr>
    

        <tr id="pennsylvania-2020-11-06T19:22:14.276000">
            <td>2020-11-06 19:22:14 UTC</td>
            <td>Biden</td>
            <td>13,662</td>
            <td>120,137</td>
            <td data-toggle="tooltip" data-html="true" data-title="<strong>Estimated county-level breakdown:</strong><br><strong>Erie:</strong> 100%" title="Estimated county-level breakdown: Erie: 100%">    383</td>
    
            <td>
        …</td></tr></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://alex.github.io/nyt-2020-election-scraper/battleground-state-changes.html">https://alex.github.io/nyt-2020-election-scraper/battleground-state-changes.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alex.github.io/nyt-2020-election-scraper/battleground-state-changes.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25001438</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 20:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A guide to live chat tools for startups]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25001001">thread link</a>) | @Fission
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://satchel.com/live-chat/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://satchel.com/live-chat/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main_content"><div><div><p>Last Updated </p><!-- --><p>July 17, 2020</p></div><div><p>Reading Times:</p><p>Summary only: 1 minute</p></div></div><h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2><p>If you've popped your head into Satchel anytime in the past three weeks, you might've seen one of a few (okay fine, one of many) live chat widgets on the bottom-right of the site. If you had the suspicion that we were testing something out, you were right.  We've pretty much done a gigantic A/B test (in this case, more like an A/B/C/D/E/F/G test) to figure out what live chat software you should use if you're an early-stage startup.</p><p>Here's the punchline: use Chatwoot. We think it actually beats out a lot of the big-name, established chat tools out there (and by more than a small margin). It's open-source w/ a hosted option<span></span><span>Read: free or low-cost.</span>, has all of the core functionality you need, was best-liked by visitors when we tested on Satchel (tied with Intercom), and, importantly, passed all of the engineering litmus tests that we've developed over the past few weeks. More on these in a bit.</p><p>We were originally going to split our recommendation between Intercom and Chatwoot, but after talking to a lot of later-stage Intercom customers, we've heard enough stories of price-gouging that we think that there's a big red flag. The full story is a bit more nuanced, but we'll dive into it shortly</p><div><p><a target="_blank" href="https://chatwoot.com/?utm_source=satchel"><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/778fcd4101a8074c6a90332fc23cfc02f3964db7/7bec3/logos/chatwoot.svg"></a></p><div><p>Our Recommendation</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://chatwoot.com/?utm_source=satchel">Chatwoot</a></p><p>Robust, open-source, and preferred by visitors</p><p>Chatwoot was one of the best-liked live chat tools in the eyes of our visitors, and doesn't run into any engineering issues that are many other alternatives have. Plus, it's open source, with a generous hosted option.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://chatwoot.com/?utm_source=satchel">chatwoot.com</a></p></div></div><h2 id="ratings-matrix">Ratings Matrix</h2><h2 id="general-findings">General Findings</h2><h3 id="initial-methodology">Initial Methodology</h3><p>We're focused primarily on the core live chat use case — human-to-human communication. Some chat tools come as part of a larger "customer relationship platform," with things like email marketing capabilities, help desk software, a customer CRM, etc. While some early-stage startups take advantage of this functionality, we find that most of it usually goes unused. Of the 18 founders we surveyed, all but one said that the human-to-human communication was overwhelmingly the most important aspect of their live chat setup<span></span><span>The remaining founder saw the live chat messenger as another communication channel for marketing automation. Marketing automation is a closely related usecase, so we'll talk about that in a bit.</span>. We aren't going to outright dismiss this auxiliary functionality — we'll go more in-depth when we make our rounds discussing each specific product, as these features are product-specific — but much of early-stage startup usage of these live chat products is for, well, live<span></span><span>Or almost live, in the case of continuing a live chat conversation over email.</span> human-to-human communication. Therefore, we'll be focusing our evaluation on the aspects of a product related to human-to-human communication.</p><p>Affordability and ease of use are straightforward and easy to understand, with the latter encompassing both our high-level evaluation of ease of use as well as our assessment of quality-of-life features (e.g. canned responses). Closely related to ease of use is our appraisal of each product's core functionality, which encompass any features that are directly related to live chat. We categorize any functionality that could warrant a standalone article (e.g. marketing automation, help desk, customer CRM, etc.) as adjacent functionality</p><p>After testing for a few weeks, we formulated two new criteria: robustness and end-user preference. We realized that these criteria are substantially more important than we initially gave them credit for, and are the basis of our litmus tests.</p><h3 id="the-litmus-tests">The Litmus Tests</h3><p>Here's where it gets interesting — we did a meta survey of 50 visitors via live chat (doubly meta) to learn more about live chat and live chat products from an end-user perspective. Initially, what we heard didn't surprise us too much — if you've implemented a live chat widget but don't respond, then your users will get frustrated; if you cover up important content with an immovable floating chat button, same deal. These are pretty obvious.</p><p>But we quickly started to see the emergence of an interesting, less obvious trend: that visitors often over-index on the quality of a live chat widget. Specifically, we found that visitors had a worse impression of a live chat widget when it had worse design, and, importantly, that impression translated to the rest of the webpage. </p><p>In other words, using a poorly-designed live chat widget lowered people's impressions of the rest of our website. That said, this observation didn't go in the other direction — that a well-designed live chat tool didn't leave a better impression on visitors than without.</p><p>We initially thought this entire observation was an oddity, but it does make intuitive sense. People are naturally drawn to things that look out-of-place. If you have a well-designed site with well-designed live chat, then your visitors' impressions will be that it's business as usual. But if you have a well-designed site with a poorly-designed widget, then your visitors will start to anchor on that one poorly-designed element. This is compounded by the fact that a live chat widget will likely be the most prominent thing on your website that you won't have styling control over<span></span><span>Plus, whether you like it or not, some live chat providers try to make their widgets as eye-catching as possible.</span>, so it tends to draw lots of attention.</p><p>As we wrapped up testing, we came across another realization: the best products to use (for both us and visitors) were those that had the most attention to detail in the live chat widget. This should make intuitive sense — if a company doesn't address some easy-to-fix (but important) details when engineering the part of the product that people will see and interact with the most, then that's usually an indication that other things are broken behind the scenes. For example, there are plenty of ways for a widget to expand the chatbox when you click on a live chat button: CSS fades, CSS resizes, JS resizes, etc. If a product chooses one of the few approaches that lag and drop frames, especially when there are perfectly performant and usable alternatives, then that's usually a pretty good predictor that the overall quality of the product isn't top notch. The same goes for positioning issues (broken CSS <code>position</code>), formatting problems (inconsistent, out-of-whack <code>li</code> margins), etc.</p><h2 id="our-recommendation-chatwoot">Our Recommendation: Chatwoot</h2><p>We think that Chatwoot has produced a better live chat product than a number of companies that have had a lot more time and manpower. This wasn't a conclusion we expected to make going into our testing process.</p><p>First off, Chatwoot is built well and designed well. The two litmus tests we mentioned earlier? It passes both with flying colors. </p><p>Chatwoot has one of the most well-designed chat widgets both in our eyes and, more importantly, the eyes of our visitors. According to the visitors we talked to, Intercom and Chatwoot were the standouts by far, with Intercom barely edging out the #1 spot. Moreover, Chatwoot, along with Intercom, LiveChat.com, and Olark, was the only chat product that we tested that didn't have a noticeable engineering deficiency on its chat widget. Chatwoot's live chat widget expands from the chat button smoothly without stutters (unlike Freshchat), visitors didn't notice any styling issues (unlike Tawk.to), and the widget loaded in and updated as expected on every website we tested it on (unlike Drift and Crisp). As previously mentioned: while other product's front-end engineering deficiencies might be minor, we found that they're usually a pretty good canary in the coal mine.</p><p>For human-to-human live chat, Chatwoot more or less has all of the core functionality that you should need. It has support for tagging, custom canned responses and shortkeys, chat user details (e.g. browser, OS, etc. that are useful for debugging), email continuation (i.e. to allow users to continue conversations over email), a relatively simple analytics dashboard (not the most advanced one out there, but perfectly serviceable as long as you don't have a full-blown customer service division), and a solid implementation of expected API functionality (e.g. for propagating metadata programmatically to show up when you're chatting with a user, e.g. programmatically setting a user ID so you immediately know what account your user is using). </p><p>The main thing that it lacks is a library of native integrations and support for prequalification and advanced info gathering (through a chatbot or a custom form). Chatwoot has a Slack integration that can ping a Slack channel when new messages come in, but that's it in terms of native integrations. If you want an integration with another product, you'll have to roll it out yourself via their webhook. There's no one-click solution to, say, auto-populate a new account in your CRM when a new visitor starts chatting — if you have a critical integration, you'll have to fiddle around with some webhook connectors like Zapier/Integromat<span></span><span>This is likely a downside but not a dealbreaker if you're an early-stage startup.</span>. Secondly, it doesn't have much support for prequalification or information gathering tasks. Specifically: the widget has a well-designed and well-integrated optional email capture field, but apart from that, it doesn't have any capability to add custom form fields (e.g. for requiring someone's name and company size before they can chat). There's also no chatbot support, although this is ostensibly on their roadmap, so you can't do things like auto-route people to a pricing page if they're interested in pricing. That said, we think that this is a perfectly acceptable tradeoff for an early-stage startup. Chatbots and custom fields are typically used for prequalification at high volume to save time by customer service agents, but usually degrade the chat experience compared to a human on the other end. This shouldn't be something to worry about for an early-stage company.</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://satchel.com/live-chat/">https://satchel.com/live-chat/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://satchel.com/live-chat/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25001001</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 19:13:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Facebook was used as a proxy by web scraping bots]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 259 | Comments 111 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25000514">thread link</a>) | @avastel
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://datadome.co/bot-detection/how-facebook-was-used-as-a-proxy-by-web-scraping-bots/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://datadome.co/bot-detection/how-facebook-was-used-as-a-proxy-by-web-scraping-bots/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://datadome.co/bot-detection/how-facebook-was-used-as-a-proxy-by-web-scraping-bots/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25000514</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 18:15:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Making a Snake Clone with Bevy]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 59 | Comments 9 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24999073">thread link</a>) | @marcusbuffett
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://mbuffett.com/posts/bevy-snake-tutorial/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mbuffett.com/posts/bevy-snake-tutorial/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p><a href="https://bevyengine.org/">Bevy</a> has seen rapid adoption recently, but the
learning resources are still fairly scarce. This is an attempt to provide a next
step after the Bevy book.  The final product looks like this:</p>
<video autoplay="" loop="" muted="" playsinline="">
    <source src="https://mbuffett.com/bevy_snake/new_gifs/game_over.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<p>It’s about 300 lines of Rust, so buckle in; this is a lengthy walkthrough. If
you want to fast-forward to the finished code, the code lives
<a href="https://github.com/marcusbuffett/bevy_snake/tree/tutorial">here</a>. For each
section there’s a diff at the top, which should make it easier to determine
where to place snippets of code, when it’s not clear.</p>
<h2 id="an-empty-bevy-app">An empty bevy app</h2>
<div>
    <p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/diff_icon.svg">
    </p>
    
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/marcusbuffett/bevy_snake/commit/174c226">See the diff</a> for this section
    </p></div>
</div>
<p>We’ll start how the bevy book starts, with an app that does nothing. Run <code>cargo new bevy-snake</code>, then put the following in your <code>main.rs</code>:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>use</span> bevy::prelude::<span>*</span>;

<span>fn</span> <span>main</span>() {
    App::build().run();
}
</code></pre></div><p>We’ll need to add bevy as a dependency in our <code>Cargo.toml</code>, and because I have
the ability to predict the future of this tutorial, let’s go ahead and add
<code>rand</code> in there too so we have it when the time comes.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="toml"><span>//</span> ...

[<span>dependencies</span>]
<span>bevy</span> = <span>"0.3.0"</span>
<span>rand</span> = <span>"0.7.3"</span>
</code></pre></div><h2 id="creating-a-window">Creating a window</h2>
<div>
    <p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/diff_icon.svg">
    </p>
    
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/marcusbuffett/bevy_snake/commit/3f7c30b">See the diff</a> for this section
    </p></div>
</div>
<p>We’re going to be creating a 2D game, which requires a lot of different systems;
one to create a window, one to do a render loop, one to handle input, one to
handle sprites, etc. Luckily Bevy’s default plugins give us all of that:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>main</span>() {
    App::build().add_plugins(DefaultPlugins).run();
}
</code></pre></div><p>Bevy’s default plugins don’t include a camera though, so let’s insert a 2d
camera, which we’ll set up by creating our first system:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>setup</span>(<span>mut</span> commands: <span>Commands</span>) {
    commands.spawn(Camera2dComponents::default());
}
</code></pre></div><p><a href="https://docs.rs/bevy_ecs/0.2.1/bevy_ecs/struct.Commands.html"><code>Commands</code></a> is
used to queue up commands to mutate the world and resources. In this case, we’re
spawning a new entity, with 2D camera components. Prepare for some bevy magic:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust">App::build()
    .add_startup_system(setup.system()) <span>// &lt;--
</span><span></span>    .add_plugins(DefaultPlugins)
    .run();
</code></pre></div><p>All we have to do is call <code>.system()</code> on our function, and Bevy will
auto-magically call it at startup with the <code>commands</code> param. Run the app again,
and you should get an empty window like this:</p>
<p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/bevy_snake/new_pics/empty_window.png"></p><h2 id="the-beginnings-of-a-snake">The beginnings of a snake</h2>
<div>
    <p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/diff_icon.svg">
    </p>
    
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/marcusbuffett/bevy_snake/commit/baaefcc">See the diff</a> for this section
    </p></div>
</div>
<p>Let’s try to get a snake head in there. We’ll define a couple structs:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>struct</span> <span>SnakeHead</span>;
<span>struct</span> <span>Materials</span> {
    head_material: <span>Handle</span><span>&lt;</span>ColorMaterial<span>&gt;</span>,
}
</code></pre></div><p><code>SnakeHead</code> is just an empty struct that we’ll use as a component, it’s sort of
like a tag, we’ll put on an entity, and then we can find that entity later by
querying for entities with the <code>SnakeHead</code> component. Empty structs like these
are a common pattern in Bevy, components often don’t need any state of their
own. <code>Materials</code> is going to be a resource, which stores the material that
we’ll use for the snake head for now, and eventually for the snake segments and
the food.</p>
<p>That <code>head_material</code> handle should be created when the game gets set up, so let’s
do that next, by modifying our <code>setup</code> function:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>setup</span>(<span>mut</span> commands: <span>Commands</span>, <span>mut</span> materials: <span>ResMut</span><span>&lt;</span>Assets<span>&lt;</span>ColorMaterial<span>&gt;&gt;</span>) {
    commands.spawn(Camera2dComponents::default());
    commands.insert_resource(Materials {
        head_material: <span>materials</span>.add(Color::rgb(<span>0.7</span>, <span>0.7</span>, <span>0.7</span>).into()),
    });
}
</code></pre></div><div>
    <p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/warning_icon.svg">
    </p>
    
    <p>Bevy requires a specific ordering to the params when registering
systems. Commands → Resources → Components/Queries. If you get a mysterious
compile-time error after messing with a system, check your order. </p>
</div>
<p><code>materials.add</code> will return a <code>Handle&lt;ColorMaterial&gt;</code>. We create a
<code>Materials</code> struct using this new handle. Later, when we try to access a
resource with the type of <code>Materials</code>, Bevy will find this struct we’ve
created. We’ll now create our snake head entity in a new system, and you can see
what using that resource looks like:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>game_setup</span>(<span>mut</span> commands: <span>Commands</span>, materials: <span>Res</span><span>&lt;</span>Materials<span>&gt;</span>) {
    commands
        .spawn(SpriteComponents {
            material: <span>materials</span>.head_material.clone(),
            sprite: <span>Sprite</span>::new(Vec2::new(<span>10.0</span>, <span>10.0</span>)),
            ..Default::default()
        })
        .with(SnakeHead);
}
</code></pre></div><p>Here we’ve got a new system, which will look for a resource of type
<code>Materials</code>. It will then spawn a new entity, with <code>SpriteComponents</code> and
<code>SnakeHead</code> as components. To create the <code>SpriteComponents</code>, we pass in the
handle to the color material we created earlier, and give the sprite a size
of (10,10). Let’s just add that system into our app builder:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust">.add_startup_system(setup.system())
.add_startup_stage(<span>"game_setup"</span>) <span>// &lt;--
</span><span></span>.add_startup_system_to_stage(<span>"game_setup"</span>, game_setup.system()) <span>// &lt;--
</span></code></pre></div><p>The reason we need a new stage instead of just calling <code>add_startup_system</code>
again, is that we need to use the material that gets inserted in the <code>setup</code>
function. After running this, you should see a snake head in the middle of the
screen:</p>
<p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/bevy_snake/new_pics/snake_pixel.png"></p><p>Okay maybe calling it a snake head is a stretch, you’ll see a 10x10 white sprite.</p>
<h2 id="moving-the-snake">Moving the snake</h2>
<div>
    <p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/diff_icon.svg">
    </p>
    
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/marcusbuffett/bevy_snake/commit/fde99c9">See the diff</a> for this section
    </p></div>
</div>
<p>Snake isn’t much of a game without movement, so let’s get that head moving.
We’ll worry about input later, for now our goal is just to get the head to
move. So let’s create a system that will move all snake heads up:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>snake_movement</span>(<span>mut</span> head_positions: <span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span>(<span>&amp;</span>SnakeHead, <span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> Transform)<span>&gt;</span>) {
    <span>for</span> (_head, <span>mut</span> transform) <span>in</span> head_positions.iter_mut() {
        <span>*</span>transform.translation.y_mut() <span>+=</span> <span>2.</span>;
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>The main new concept here is that <code>Query</code> type. We can use it to iterate through
all entities that have both the <code>SnakeHead</code> component and the <code>Transform</code>
component. We don’t have to worry about actually creating that query, bevy will
take care of creating it and calling our function with it, part of the ECS
magic. So let’s add that system in and see what happens:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust">.add_startup_system_to_stage(<span>"game_setup"</span>, game_setup.system())
.add_system(snake_movement.system()) <span>// &lt;--
</span><span></span>.add_plugins(DefaultPlugins)
</code></pre></div><p>Here’s what we get, a snake head moving off-screen:</p>
<video controls="" loop="" muted="" playsinline="">
    <source src="https://mbuffett.com/bevy_snake/new_gifs/moving_up.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<p>You may be wondering about that Transform component. When we spawned the
<code>SnakeHead</code>, we didn’t give it a <code>Transform</code>, so how come we’re able to find an
entity that has a <code>SnakeHead</code> and a <code>Transform</code> component? What’s going on there
is that <code>SpriteComponents</code> is a
<a href="https://docs.rs/bevy/0.1.2/bevy/prelude/trait.Bundle.html"><code>Bundle</code></a> of
components. For <code>SpriteComponents</code>, that means we get a <code>Transform</code> component,
among a bunch of others (<code>Sprite</code>, <code>Mesh</code>, <code>Draw</code>, <code>Rotation</code>, <code>Scale</code>, etc).</p>
<h2 id="controlling-the-snake">Controlling the snake</h2>
<div>
    <p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/diff_icon.svg">
    </p>
    
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/marcusbuffett/bevy_snake/commit/5e24bf0">See the diff</a> for this section
    </p></div>
</div>
<p>Let’s modify our snake movement system to actually allow us to direct the snake:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>snake_movement</span>(
    keyboard_input: <span>Res</span><span>&lt;</span>Input<span>&lt;</span>KeyCode<span>&gt;&gt;</span>,
    <span>mut</span> head_positions: <span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span>(<span>&amp;</span>SnakeHead, <span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> Transform)<span>&gt;</span>,
) {
    <span>for</span> (_head, <span>mut</span> transform) <span>in</span> head_positions.iter_mut() {
        <span>if</span> keyboard_input.pressed(KeyCode::Left) {
            <span>*</span>transform.translation.x_mut() <span>-=</span> <span>2.</span>;
        }
        <span>if</span> keyboard_input.pressed(KeyCode::Right) {
            <span>*</span>transform.translation.x_mut() <span>+=</span> <span>2.</span>;
        }
        <span>if</span> keyboard_input.pressed(KeyCode::Down) {
            <span>*</span>transform.translation.y_mut() <span>-=</span> <span>2.</span>;
        }
        <span>if</span> keyboard_input.pressed(KeyCode::Up) {
            <span>*</span>transform.translation.y_mut() <span>+=</span> <span>2.</span>;
        }
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>Now we can control the snake, albeit in very un-snake-like fashion:</p>
<video controls="" loop="" muted="" playsinline="">
    <source src="https://mbuffett.com/bevy_snake/new_gifs/moving_not_snake_like.mp4" type="video/mp4">
</video>
<h2 id="slapping-a-grid-on-it">Slapping a grid on it</h2>
<div>
    <p><img src="https://mbuffett.com/diff_icon.svg">
    </p>
    
    <div>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/marcusbuffett/bevy_snake/commit/9ce01c7">See the diff</a> for this section
    </p></div>
</div>
<p>So far we’ve been using window coordinates, and the way that works is that (0,0)
is the middle, and the units are pixels. Snake games generally use grids, so if
we made our snake game 10x10, our window would be <em>really</em> small. Let’s make our
lives a bit easier by using our own positioning and sizing. Then we can use
systems that deal with transforming these to window coordinates.</p>
<p>We’ll make our grid 10x10. We’ll define those as constants up at the top of the
file:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>const</span> ARENA_WIDTH: <span>u32</span> <span>=</span> <span>10</span>;
<span>const</span> ARENA_HEIGHT: <span>u32</span> <span>=</span> <span>10</span>;
</code></pre></div><p>Here are our new structs for positioning/sizing:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>#[derive(Default, Copy, Clone, Eq, PartialEq, Hash)]</span>
<span>struct</span> <span>Position</span> {
    x: <span>i32</span>,
    y: <span>i32</span>,
}

<span>struct</span> <span>Size</span> {
    width: <span>f32</span>,
    height: <span>f32</span>,
}
<span>impl</span> Size {
    <span>pub</span> <span>fn</span> <span>square</span>(x: <span>f32</span>) -&gt; <span>Self</span> {
        Self {
            width: <span>x</span>,
            height: <span>x</span>,
        }
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>Fairly straightforward, with a helper method to get a <code>Size</code> with equal width
and height. Position derives some traits that will be useful later, so we don’t
have to keep going back to it. <code>Size</code> could really just have one float, since
all objects will end up having equal width and height, but it feels wrong so I’m
giving it a width and a height. Let’s add those components to the snake head we
spawn:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust">commands
    .spawn(SpriteComponents {
        material: <span>materials</span>.head_material.clone(),
        sprite: <span>Sprite</span>::new(Vec2::new(<span>10.0</span>, <span>10.0</span>)),
        ..Default::default()
    })
    .with(SnakeHead)
    .with(Position { x: <span>3</span>, y: <span>3</span> }) <span>// &lt;--
</span><span></span>    .with(Size::square(<span>0.8</span>)); <span>// &lt;--
</span></code></pre></div><p>These components aren’t doing anything currently, let’s start with transforming
our sizes into sprite sizes:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>size_scaling</span>(windows: <span>Res</span><span>&lt;</span>Windows<span>&gt;</span>, <span>mut</span> q: <span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span>(<span>&amp;</span>Size, <span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> Sprite)<span>&gt;</span>) {
    <span>for</span> (size, <span>mut</span> sprite) <span>in</span> q.iter_mut() {
        <span>let</span> window <span>=</span> windows.get_primary().unwrap();
        sprite.size <span>=</span> Vec2::new(
            size.width <span>as</span> <span>f32</span> <span>/</span> ARENA_WIDTH <span>as</span> <span>f32</span> <span>*</span> window.width() <span>as</span> <span>f32</span>,
            size.height <span>as</span> <span>f32</span> <span>/</span> ARENA_HEIGHT <span>as</span> <span>f32</span> <span>*</span> window.height() <span>as</span> <span>f32</span>,
        );
    }
}
</code></pre></div><p>The sizing logic goes like so: if something has a width of 1 in a grid of 40,
and the window is 400px across, then it should have a width of 10. Next we can
do the positioning system:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>position_translation</span>(windows: <span>Res</span><span>&lt;</span>Windows<span>&gt;</span>, <span>mut</span> q: <span>Query</span><span>&lt;</span>(<span>&amp;</span>Position, <span>&amp;</span><span>mut</span> Transform)<span>&gt;</span>) {
    <span>fn</span> <span>convert</span>(p: <span>f32</span>, bound_window: <span>f32</span>, bound_game: <span>f32</span>) -&gt; <span>f32</span> {
        p <span>/</span> bound_game <span>*</span> bound_window <span>-</span> (bound_window <span>/</span> <span>2.</span>) <span>+</span> (bound_window <span>/</span> bound_game <span>/</span> <span>2.</span>)
    }
    <span>let</span> window <span>=</span> windows.get_primary().unwrap();
    <span>for</span> (pos, <span>mut</span> transform) <span>in</span> q.iter_mut() {
        transform.translation <span>=</span> Vec3::new(
            convert(pos.x <span>as</span> <span>f32</span>, window.width() <span>as</span> <span>f32</span>, ARENA_WIDTH <span>as</span> <span>f32</span>),
            …</code></pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://mbuffett.com/posts/bevy-snake-tutorial/">https://mbuffett.com/posts/bevy-snake-tutorial/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mbuffett.com/posts/bevy-snake-tutorial/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24999073</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 15:31:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[SVG Path Editor]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 554 | Comments 52 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24998532">thread link</a>) | @blindm
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://yqnn.github.io/svg-path-editor/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yqnn.github.io/svg-path-editor/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yqnn.github.io/svg-path-editor/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24998532</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 14:29:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We are building a CLI first PaaS without a web frontend]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 148 | Comments 98 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24998496">thread link</a>) | @friendly_chap
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://crufter.com/cli-first-paas | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://crufter.com/cli-first-paas">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="page">

        
        <!-- .site-header -->
        

        <div id="content">
    <main id="main">
        <article>
            <!-- .post-header -->
            
            <div>
                <p>At the start of this hectic year I have joined <a href="https://m3o.com/">Micro</a>, an open source microservices platform. The company was born out of a <a href="https://github.com/asim/nitro">Go framework</a>. We took the concepts of the framework - interfaces for service discovery, configuration and other pieces which can run on any implementation (from mdns locally to kubernetes) and provide a live platform version of it. It’s kind of like Netlify, but for the backend.</p>

<p>Once we were happy with the local development flow for the micro server and CLI, we decided to start selling the product as a platform. Building a website seemed like an obvious step to do. It’s 2020 right?</p>

<p>So we got to work. Metrics with nice charts. Tracing. Calling services. Listing endpoints.
It was all shaping up nicely. But slowly and surely we started missing features we got accustomed to on the frontend in the CLI. Being very heavy command line users, whenever we got something available in the CLI, we reached there first.</p>

<p>And then we realised. Who are we building this frontend exactly and why? We prefer the command line. And none of our many thousands of users were asking for a web UI. At most it was considered a “cool” thing to have.</p>

<p>The past three decades have been all about the world wide web (www) and in that we’ve gone through the multiple iterations
of building “web first” experiences which I’d argue really peaked in the Web 2.0 era in the mid 00s with the likes of
Facebook and others. At some point we entered the “Mobile first” era and yet for developers, Web still became a horrible
platform we were stuck with for any platform or tools, AWS is a great example of how to get it really wrong.
If new products and platforms are going Mobile first, maybe we as developers need to go CLI first. So here it is. M3O
is a CLI first experience. No context switches, no ugly dashboards, just a simple straight forward command line utility
that gets out of your way when you need it to.
Our hope at Micro is more learn from this experience and do away with Web UIs entirely. Challenge every assumption you know
about Web for backend development and think, do I really need that, or is it better served as a single CLI experience.</p>

<p>So we doubled down. We entirely sidelined the web UI and decided payment will be the only thing on the website, should supplying card details in the terminal feel sketchy.</p>

<p>What we found after this surprised us. By limiting our choices we unleashed a storm of ideas on how to improve the single medium we can express our thoughts in.</p>

<p>We started to make service call feel just like any command invocation.</p>

<p>What was previously</p>

<div><div><pre><code>micro call servicename endpoint <span>'{"field":"value","otherfield":{"subfield":"value2"}}'</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>became</p>

<div><div><pre><code>micro servicename endpoint <span>--field</span><span>=</span>value <span>--otherfield_subfield</span><span>=</span>value2
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>On the surface it might not seem much, but when you are living and breathing these commands it provides a great satisfaction to remove even little frictions.</p>

<p>New services and their endpoints feel just like builtin Micro commands, which is why our invites simply became</p>

<div><div><pre><code>micro invite user <span>--email</span><span>=</span>someone@domain.com
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Shipping features to end users became as deploying a new service, and users can easily programatically call their endpoints from the terminal.</p>

<p>Bash shines at quick and information dense throwaway scripts, so our <a href="https://github.com/micro/micro/tree/master/test">end to end test framework</a> is built for tests to be written using Micro CLI commands.</p>

<p>We dream of a future where programming is as close to natural languages as possible.
At the moment, the ubiquity of bash provides a great layer for us to quickly interact with microservices. It truly feels like the platform is alive as nouns and verbs are being created by service writers to be composed into sentences.</p>

<p>Why don’t you <a href="https://m3o.com/">give it a go</a>? We have a free tier ;).</p>

<p>Co-Authored with <a href="https://asimaslam.com/">Asim Aslam</a>.</p>

            </div>
            
            <div>
                <p><img src="https://crufter.com/assets/images/logo1.png" alt="János Dobronszki's Picture"></p>
                <div>
                    
                    <p>János Dobronszki is a full stack software engineer with more than 15 years of experience.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            



        </article>
        
        <section>
    <div>
        <h2>Subscribe to Crufter newsletter</h2>
        <p>Get the latest and greatest from Crufter delivered straight to your inbox every week.</p>
        <!-- Begin MailChimp Signup Form -->
        
        <!--End mc_embed_signup-->
    </div><!-- .inner -->
</section><!-- .widget -->
        
        <section>
            <h2>Read Next</h2>
            
            <article>
                
                
                <a href="https://crufter.com/the-future-of-cloud-computing">
                    <img src="https://crufter.com/assets/images/sky640.jpg" alt="Cloud computing needs to be reformed">
                </a>
                
            </article>
            
            
        </section><!-- .read-next -->
    </main><!-- .site-main -->
</div><!-- .site-content -->

        

        

        <!-- .site-footer -->
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://crufter.com/cli-first-paas</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24998496</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 14:27:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[In the Beginning was the Command Line (1999)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 168 | Comments 51 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24998305">thread link</a>) | @BerislavLopac
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | http://cristal.inria.fr/~weis/info/commandline.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://cristal.inria.fr/~weis/info/commandline.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

<p> About twenty years ago Jobs and Wozniak, the founders of Apple, came
up with the very strange idea of selling information processing machines
for use in the home. The business took off, and its founders made a lot of
money and received the credit they deserved for being daring visionaries.
But around the same time, Bill Gates and Paul Allen came up with an idea
even stranger and more fantastical: selling computer operating systems.
This was much weirder than the idea of Jobs and Wozniak. A computer at
least had some sort of physical reality to it. It came in a box, you could
open it up and plug it in and watch lights blink. An operating system had
no tangible incarnation at all. It arrived on a disk, of course, but the
disk was, in effect, nothing more than the box that the OS came in. The
product itself was a very long string of ones and zeroes that, when
properly installed and coddled, gave you the ability to manipulate other
very long strings of ones and zeroes. Even those few who actually
understood what a computer operating system was were apt to think of it as
a fantastically arcane engineering prodigy, like a breeder reactor or a
U-2 spy plane, and not something that could ever be (in the parlance of
high-tech) "productized." 

</p><p> Yet now the company that Gates and Allen founded is selling operating
systems like Gillette sells razor blades. New releases of operating
systems are launched as if they were Hollywood blockbusters, with
celebrity endorsements, talk show appearances, and world tours. The market
for them is vast enough that people worry about whether it has been
monopolized by one company. Even the least technically-minded people in
our society now have at least a hazy idea of what operating systems do;
what is more, they have strong opinions about their relative merits. It is
commonly understood, even by technically unsophisticated computer users,
that if you have a piece of software that works on your Macintosh, and you
move it over onto a Windows machine, it will not run. That this would, in
fact, be a laughable and idiotic mistake, like nailing horseshoes to the
tires of a Buick. 

</p><p> A person who went into a coma before Microsoft was founded, and woke
up now, could pick up this morning's New York Times and understand
everything in it--almost: 

</p><ul>
<li>Item: the richest man in the world made his fortune
     from-what? Railways? Shipping? Oil? No, operating systems.
</li><li>Item: the Department of Justice is tackling Microsoft's
     supposed OS monopoly with legal tools that were invented to
     restrain the power of Nineteenth-Century robber barons.
</li><li>Item: a woman friend of mine recently told me that she'd
     broken off a (hitherto) stimulating exchange of e-mail with
     a young man. At first he had seemed like such an intelligent
     and interesting guy, she said, but then "he started going
     all PC-versus-Mac on me."
</li></ul>

<p> What the hell is going on here? And does the operating system business
have a future, or only a past? Here is my view, which is entirely
subjective; but since I have spent a fair amount of time not only using,
but programming, Macintoshes, Windows machines, Linux boxes and the BeOS,
perhaps it is not so ill-informed as to be completely worthless. This is a
subjective essay, more review than research paper, and so it might seem
unfair or biased compared to the technical reviews you can find in PC
magazines.  But ever since the Mac came out, our operating systems have
been based on metaphors, and anything with metaphors in it is fair game as
far as I'm concerned. 


</p><p>MGBs, TANKS, AND BATMOBILES

</p><p> Around the time that Jobs, Wozniak, Gates, and Allen were dreaming up
these unlikely schemes, I was a teenager living in Ames, Iowa. One of my
friends' dads had an old MGB sports car rusting away in his garage.
Sometimes he would actually manage to get it running and then he would
take us for a spin around the block, with a memorable look of wild
youthful exhiliration on his face; to his worried passengers, he was a
madman, stalling and backfiring around Ames, Iowa and eating the dust of
rusty Gremlins and Pintos, but in his own mind he was Dustin Hoffman
tooling across the Bay Bridge with the wind in his hair. 

</p><p> In retrospect, this was telling me two things about people's
relationship to technology. One was that romance and image go a long way
towards shaping their opinions. If you doubt it (and if you have a lot of
spare time on your hands) just ask anyone who owns a Macintosh and who, on
those grounds, imagines him- or herself to be a member of an oppressed
minority group. 

</p><p> The other, somewhat subtler point, was that interface is very
important. Sure, the MGB was a lousy car in almost every way that counted:
balky, unreliable, underpowered. But it was fun to drive. It was
responsive. Every pebble on the road was felt in the bones, every nuance
in the pavement transmitted instantly to the driver's hands. He could
listen to the engine and tell what was wrong with it. The steering
responded immediately to commands from his hands. To us passengers it was
a pointless exercise in going nowhere--about as interesting as peering
over someone's shoulder while he punches numbers into a spreadsheet. But
to the driver it was an experience. For a short time he was extending his
body and his senses into a larger realm, and doing things that he couldn't
do unassisted. 

</p><p> The analogy between cars and operating systems is not half bad, and so
let me run with it for a moment, as a way of giving an executive summary
of our situation today. 

</p><p> Imagine a crossroads where four competing auto dealerships are
situated. One of them (Microsoft) is much, much bigger than the others. It
started out years ago selling three-speed bicycles (MS-DOS); these were
not perfect, but they worked, and when they broke you could easily fix
them. 

</p><p> There was a competing bicycle dealership next door (Apple) that one
day began selling motorized vehicles--expensive but attractively styled
cars with their innards hermetically sealed, so that how they worked was
something of a mystery. 

</p><p> The big dealership responded by rushing a moped upgrade kit (the
original Windows) onto the market. This was a Rube Goldberg contraption
that, when bolted onto a three-speed bicycle, enabled it to keep up, just
barely, with Apple-cars. The users had to wear goggles and were always
picking bugs out of their teeth while Apple owners sped along in
hermetically sealed comfort, sneering out the windows. But the
Micro-mopeds were cheap, and easy to fix compared with the Apple-cars, and
their market share waxed. 

</p><p> Eventually the big dealership came out with a full-fledged car: a
colossal station wagon (Windows 95). It had all the aesthetic appeal of a
Soviet worker housing block, it leaked oil and blew gaskets, and it was an
enormous success. A little later, they also came out with a hulking
off-road vehicle intended for industrial users (Windows NT) which was no
more beautiful than the station wagon, and only a little more reliable. 

</p><p> Since then there has been a lot of noise and shouting, but little has
changed. The smaller dealership continues to sell sleek Euro-styled sedans
and to spend a lot of money on advertising campaigns. They have had GOING
OUT OF BUSINESS! signs taped up in their windows for so long that they
have gotten all yellow and curly. The big one keeps making bigger and
bigger station wagons and ORVs. 

</p><p> On the other side of the road are two competitors that have come along
more recently. 

</p><p> One of them (Be, Inc.) is selling fully operational Batmobiles (the
BeOS). They are more beautiful and stylish even than the Euro-sedans,
better designed, more technologically advanced, and at least as reliable
as anything else on the market--and yet cheaper than the others. 

</p><p> With one exception, that is: Linux, which is right next door, and
which is not a business at all. It's a bunch of RVs, yurts, tepees, and
geodesic domes set up in a field and organized by consensus. The people
who live there are making tanks. These are not old-fashioned, cast-iron
Soviet tanks; these are more like the M1 tanks of the U.S. Army, made of
space-age materials and jammed with sophisticated technology from one end
to the other.  But they are better than Army tanks. They've been modified
in such a way that they never, ever break down, are light and maneuverable
enough to use on ordinary streets, and use no more fuel than a subcompact
car. These tanks are being cranked out, on the spot, at a terrific pace,
and a vast number of them are lined up along the edge of the road with
keys in the ignition. Anyone who wants can simply climb into one and drive
it away for free. 

</p><p> Customers come to this crossroads in throngs, day and night.  Ninety
percent of them go straight to the biggest dealership and buy station
wagons or off-road vehicles. They do not even look at the other
dealerships. 

</p><p> Of the remaining ten percent, most go and buy a sleek Euro-sedan,
pausing only to turn up their noses at the philistines going to buy the
station wagons and ORVs. If they even notice the people on the opposite
side of the road, selling the cheaper, technically superior vehicles,
these customers deride them cranks and half-wits. 

</p><p> The Batmobile outlet sells a few vehicles to the occasional car nut
who wants a second vehicle to go with his station wagon, but seems to
accept, at least for now, that it's a fringe player. 

</p><p> The group giving away the free tanks only stays alive because it is
staffed by volunteers, who are lined up at the edge of the street with
bullhorns, trying to draw customers' attention to this incredible
situation. A typical conversation goes something like this: 

</p><p> Hacker with bullhorn: "Save your money! Accept one of our free tanks!
It is invulnerable, and can drive across rocks and swamps at ninety miles
an hour while getting a hundred miles to the gallon!" 

</p><p> Prospective station wagon buyer: "I know what you say is
true...but...er...I don't know how to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://cristal.inria.fr/~weis/info/commandline.html">http://cristal.inria.fr/~weis/info/commandline.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://cristal.inria.fr/~weis/info/commandline.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24998305</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 14:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Switching from Vim to Intellij]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 166 | Comments 235 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24998260">thread link</a>) | @cpow85
<br/>
November 5, 2020 | https://browntreelabs.com/from-vim-to-intellij/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://browntreelabs.com/from-vim-to-intellij/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="___gatsby"><div tabindex="-1" id="gatsby-focus-wrapper"><div><nav></nav><section><div><div><div><div><p>📅 <!-- -->November 03, 2020</p><p>👷 Chris Power</p></div></div></div></div><div><div><div><div><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>From Vim</th>
<th>To IntelliJ</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><span>
      <a href="https://browntreelabs.com/static/8805418a02fe96f9f449cb5057c0e95e/1ac29/vimlogo.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="vimlogo" title="vimlogo" src="https://browntreelabs.com/static/8805418a02fe96f9f449cb5057c0e95e/fcda8/vimlogo.png" srcset="https://browntreelabs.com/static/8805418a02fe96f9f449cb5057c0e95e/12f09/vimlogo.png 148w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/8805418a02fe96f9f449cb5057c0e95e/e4a3f/vimlogo.png 295w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/8805418a02fe96f9f449cb5057c0e95e/fcda8/vimlogo.png 590w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/8805418a02fe96f9f449cb5057c0e95e/efc66/vimlogo.png 885w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/8805418a02fe96f9f449cb5057c0e95e/1ac29/vimlogo.png 1022w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></td>
<td><span>
      <a href="https://browntreelabs.com/static/d2f6c44d5d9d14c9e66176feeb648fbf/2bef9/intellijlogo.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="intellijlogo" title="intellijlogo" src="https://browntreelabs.com/static/d2f6c44d5d9d14c9e66176feeb648fbf/fcda8/intellijlogo.png" srcset="https://browntreelabs.com/static/d2f6c44d5d9d14c9e66176feeb648fbf/12f09/intellijlogo.png 148w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/d2f6c44d5d9d14c9e66176feeb648fbf/e4a3f/intellijlogo.png 295w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/d2f6c44d5d9d14c9e66176feeb648fbf/fcda8/intellijlogo.png 590w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/d2f6c44d5d9d14c9e66176feeb648fbf/efc66/intellijlogo.png 885w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/d2f6c44d5d9d14c9e66176feeb648fbf/2bef9/intellijlogo.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>In the beginning, a love affair</h2>
<p>For the last 10 years or so, I have been a die-hard Vim user. I was introduced to Vim on my first programming job. It was almost an instant connection for me. I fell in love with the minimalism of only needing a terminal to do work; and the power of stringing together commands, like words, to edit programs and text.</p>
<p>The love affair I have with Vim stuck with me throughout my career and remains strong to this very day. When I was a junior-level release engineer, working on small scripts, Vim was amazing. Later, working as a Ruby on Rails Engineer, Vim was still an amazing editor. Thoughtbot, Hashrocket, and countless other agencies, companies, and individuals contributed to the community (and cult) of Vim. That community pushed my knowledge, comfort, and understanding further and further.</p>
<p>Eventually, I was running tmux and Vim together in the terminal. With sufficient plugins and dotfiles, I was CRUISING through codebases. I could write tests, run them, refactor code, and run commands with absolute ease.</p>
<hr>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/9b29b/vim-and-tmux.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="vim and tmux" title="vim and tmux" src="https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/fcda8/vim-and-tmux.png" srcset="https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/12f09/vim-and-tmux.png 148w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/e4a3f/vim-and-tmux.png 295w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/fcda8/vim-and-tmux.png 590w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/efc66/vim-and-tmux.png 885w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/c83ae/vim-and-tmux.png 1180w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/c088aa0c91b04d0725177c7b04c624c0/9b29b/vim-and-tmux.png 3840w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<center><i>Vim and tmux... were so amazing</i></center>
<hr>
<h2>Old feelings fade</h2>
<p>Lately, though, I have been feeling a little underwhelmed by Vim. Even with my sophisticated dotfiles, knowledge, and Plugin setup; something felt off. I started a new job working on a large typescript React project. Vim couldn’t handle opening a TSX file larger than 50 lines without crashing.</p>
<p>Within the last few years, I tried my hand at programming mobile applications. Flutter and Dart — although supported by an LSP — was not running very well on my Vim setup. After giving Android Studio a shot with Flutter, it felt like a whole new world.</p>
<h2>Android Studio with Flutter — The tipping point</h2>
<hr>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/0784f/android-studio.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="android studio" title="android studio" src="https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/fcda8/android-studio.png" srcset="https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/12f09/android-studio.png 148w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/e4a3f/android-studio.png 295w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/fcda8/android-studio.png 590w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/efc66/android-studio.png 885w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/c83ae/android-studio.png 1180w,
https://browntreelabs.com/static/2dcc652b86c5e6e9506eaded15001bb0/0784f/android-studio.png 3574w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<center><i>Android Studio was a game changer</i></center>
<hr>
<p>All of a sudden, I had everything at my fingertips. Auto completion, Auto formatting, snippets, and documentation lookup was all set <strong>By Default</strong>. I actually understood the Flutter framework much better because Android Studio made deep framework code easy to debug, inspect, and explore. Not to mention, the Vim integration was <strong>fantastic</strong>. This was the best of both worlds. I had amazing editing, minimal configuration, and Vim keybindings!</p>
<p>When picking up a new language or framework in Vim, I would spend hours configuring plugins, dealing with linting, and looking up documentation. With and IDE like Android Studio, all of this came pre-built without any configuration.</p>
<p>Android Studio was something of a revelation for me. I began thinking to myself, “If this is so great for Flutter, wouldn’t this be great for my other projects?“.</p>
<h2>Vim to VSCode to Webstorm to IntelliJ</h2>
<p>I am now working almost exclusively on IntelliJ IDEA. It is the JetBrains defacto editor that includes plugins for almost anything:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ruby on Rails</li>
<li>Ember</li>
<li>Angular</li>
<li>Typescript</li>
<li>React</li>
<li>The list literally goes on forever</li>
</ul>
<p>Every project I work on — like this Gatsby blog in React, my corporate Typescript React job, or my Ruby on Rails side projects — All work within this one editor.</p>
<p>I had a brief stint with VSCode but, to me, it appeared to have the same flaws I disliked with Vim at the time. It was slow with large files, and it felt sluggish with complicated programs and complicated programming languages (like typescript and tsserver).</p>
<p>I also had a long affair with WebStorm, which was mostly great. I did; however, find it odd to be using an editor <strong>ONLY</strong> made for a few programs. If I wanted to run a Ruby on Rails app in Webstorm, I was SOL. I thought it was a little silly to run RubyMine, Webstorm, and Pycharm on one machine. If I wrote code in all three languages, shouldn’t one editor be able to handle it?</p>
<p>Eventually I wound up running IntelliJ with plugins that handle any programming need I may have. And for now, I am very happy. There are, of course, many cons with IntelliJ. But I truly believe the Pros outweigh the Cons.</p>
<h2>Vim and IntelliJ, a Pros and Cons list:</h2>
<p>I still think Vim is a great editor and I love to break it out every once in a while. But I believe the pros of IntelliJ outweigh the cons of Vim at this point in my career. Here is an overview of my thought process.</p>
<h3>Pros and Cons of Vim</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>When picking up a new language or framework in Vim, I would spend hours configuring plugins, dealing with linting, and looking up documentation.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4><strong><em>Pros:</em></strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Minimalist.</strong> All you need is the terminal, and that is it. You don’t need to open multiple windows, Tmux and Vim together were <strong>awesome</strong> for this.</li>
<li><strong>Gets you into the Flow:</strong> . Vim <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)">gets me into “The Flow”</a> better than anything. I just need to move my fingers a bit, and I’m in/out of windows, buffers, splits, etc… I specifically remember smiling when I was coding with Vim, because it just felt so fun sometimes.</li>
<li><strong>Extensible:</strong> It’s been around forever, Thoughtbot, Hashrocket, and many community members contributed greatly to it.</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong><em>Cons:</em></strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Very steep learning curve:</strong> Vim takes a long time to learn, and you’ll never stop learning it. This is not a problem with more experienced users like myself, but I thought it was worth mentioning.</li>
<li><strong>Inconsistent Plugins:</strong> Quick, tell me the best plugin for auto-completion in Vim. ALE/Omnicomplete? YouCompleteMe? VimCompletesMe? DeoPlete? There is an insane number of plugins for any task you may have. And not all plugins play together. This has become slightly better with the emergence of LSPs; however, I constantly find myself playing with plugins to make things work better, only to dislike the setup and go for another mix of plugins later. Having dot files are nice, but when you switch computers/systems, you have to install pip3/python for some packages, node/npm/yarn for others, and for some, you’ll have to cd into the dir where its installed and run a makefile! (looking at you, YouCompleteMe)</li>
<li><strong>Doesn’t always play nice with everything else:</strong> I have had countless configurations with Vim. Vim standalone, NeoVim, Vim with Tmux, and MacVim/GUIVim. They all have strengths and weaknesses, but there is always one thing in common, it doesn’t play very well with every computer system. Try to set up copy+paste on Vim on a Mac, done? Ok great! Now do it for Linux. There are so many workarounds and hacks to get everything to play well together. When you get it set up, its nice, but sometimes its rough. I find myself reading old blog posts to remember how I set up yank + paste on my system-wide clipboard over and over.</li>
<li><strong>Isn’t very fun with complex codebases in complicated languages (like typescript):</strong> I remember starting a new job that used typescript, and there were a lot of engineers working on some really cool problems. After getting Vim/ ENV vars/ etc… all set up, I go to start woking in Vim and <strong>BAM</strong>, any file over 20 lines freezes and its incredibly slow to work with. Sure enough, my javascript parser/highlighting plugin (see my point above about plugins) was not efficient, and it was bogging down everything. So I had to settle for a lesser parser that performed better. A similar thing happens with prettier, eslint, and tsserver. If you need your code to be auto-fixed with these technologies, its blocks read/write. Even when your IO is blocked for only a short amount of time, it makes for a trudging, slow-as-molasses feeling when writing code.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Pros and Cons of IntelliJ</h3>
<blockquote>
<p>All of a sudden, I had everything at my fingertips. Auto completion, Auto formatting, snippets, and documentation lookup was all set <strong>By Default</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4><strong><em>PROS:</em></strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Everything is pre-configured:</strong> You don’t have to worry about setting up tags, or YouCompleteMe, or NERDTree. I can’t tell you how many times I open a new project, perhaps in a different language, and everything works great out of the box. It’s a total sigh of relief.</li>
<li><strong>File watchers are powerful:</strong> There is a thing in IntelliJ called file watchers. You can set arbitrary tasks to run after you edit/save/type in a file. This can be super powerful when you have more advanced tasks you need to run in your codebase like: sorting imports, running specific eslint rules, or running rubocop after saving a file.</li>
<li><strong>Everything plays nicely with your OS:</strong>  I can’t tell you how many times I set up Vim and tmux on a new OS, like linux. I’ll run all my dot files, configure anything crazy I missed. Compile the plugins that need compilation. Fix any small issues that happen between Vim/tmux/linux (or Mac, whatever). Then I’m programming, and I have to copy+paste something, and BAM, I lose 4 hours configuring copy and paste correctly between Vim/tmux/</li>
<li><strong>Complicated codebases and languages are handled easily:</strong> After using IntelliJ (or Webstorm), all my problems with my large Typescript codebase went away. Everything gets indexed, parsed, highlighted, and rendered correctly. There are very few hangups when working with complicated codebases, and the exceptions are usually much easier to deal with than with Vim.</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong><em>CONS:</em></strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><strong>Complicated Interface:</strong> The interface to IntelliJ is somewhat, complicated. There are a lot of tools, dropdown menus, and configurations. This is definitely a daunting thing at first, but once you get used to it, its not a big problem at all.</li>
<li><strong>Memory Usage:</strong> IntelliJ does eat up a bit of RAM on my machines. I believe this memory usage is worth it though. You’re paying an upfront price to index, tag, and cache programs, so your editing experience is smooth as butter. VSCode and Vim (with plugins) only do this lazily; therefore, your programming experience with complicated projects becomes very awkward and slow over time.</li>
<li><strong>Difficult configuration for some tasks:</strong> Again, this is something you get used to with time. Some configuration options with IntelliJ are less than ideal. For example, when setting up auto-formatting for eslint, you have to go through a couple hoops to set up a file watcher in IntelliJ. Once you understand this concept though, its fairly straightforward and easy to use with other tools.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the end, I have decided that the pros for IntelliJ greatly outweigh the cons. I have …</p></div></div></div></div></section></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://browntreelabs.com/from-vim-to-intellij/">https://browntreelabs.com/from-vim-to-intellij/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://browntreelabs.com/from-vim-to-intellij/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24998260</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 14:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Confusing Grep Mistakes I've Made]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24996089">thread link</a>) | @r4um
<br/>
November 4, 2020 | https://blog.robertelder.org/top-5-grep-mistakes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.robertelder.org/top-5-grep-mistakes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
						<div>


<h5>2020-11-02 - By Robert Elder</h5>





<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_pWO-Z0fO00" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;In this article, I'll discuss 5 very confusing mistakes that have caused me to waste significant amounts of time when using the command-line tool known as 'grep' to search for things. &nbsp;I have chosen to document these mistakes in detail because they are mistakes that beginners are very likely to make at some point, but also to not be able to debug on their own. &nbsp;The root causes of these mistakes are: &nbsp;Not knowing what flavour of regular expression that grep is currently using (and/or not understanding what features that flavour supports); Not considering the escaping rules of your shell; Issues with character encodings.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Here is a file containing a few lines of text that we'll place inside the file 'hello.txt':</p>

<p><code><pre>Hello World.
Hello There World.
Hello Some World.
Hello The World.
HelloWorld.
Goodbye World.
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Let's say that you wanted to use the 'grep' command to find all lines in this file that contain the word 'Hello' followed by the word 'World'. &nbsp;You could use a grep command like this:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>"</span><span>Hello.*World</span><span>"</span> hello.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;and as you expect, this grep command found all of the matches that you expect:</p>

<p><code><pre>Hello World.
Hello There World.
Hello Some World.
Hello The World.
HelloWorld.
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But now you might consider adding the additional requirement that there be at least one character between 'Hello' and 'World' so that the line with 'HelloWorld' is not included in the matches. &nbsp;Since you know that '*' is a regex pattern for 'zero or more' and '+' is a regex pattern for 'oen or more', you decide to try the following:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>"</span><span>Hello.+World</span><span>"</span> hello.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But this doesn't match anything at all! &nbsp;What's going on here? &nbsp;Isn't '+' a regular expression symbol for 'one or more'? &nbsp;The answer is related to the default regular expression mode that grep uses. &nbsp;If you don't specify any flags to grep, it will use 'BRE' or 'Basic Regular Expressions' which are very old and quite primitive. &nbsp;In fact, the official <a href="https://pubs.opengroup.org/onlinepubs/9699919799/basedefs/V1_chap09.html">standard for BRE</a> doesn't even support the '+' quantifier! &nbsp;This can lead to very confusing behaviour since you might just try escaping the '+' and find that it gives you the result you expect:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>"</span><span>Hello.</span><span>\+</span><span>World</span><span>"</span> hello.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;gives the following:</p>

<p><code><pre>Hello World.
Hello There World.
Hello Some World.
Hello The World.
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But since we're still using 'BRE' regular expressions, the official standard says that this is actually undefined behaviour! &nbsp;You can learn more about this in <a href="https://blog.robertelder.org/grep-bre-ere-perl-regular-expressions/">Undefined Behaviour With Grep -E</a>.</p>




<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Let's say we have a file called 'sometext.txt' with the following text in it:</p>

<p><code><pre>Make sure you write out the `date`.

Today's date is Oct 21, 2020.
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;If you wanted to find all lines in this file that contains the word 'date', you could use this grep command:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> date sometext.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;and you'll get the following result which is what you expect:</p>

<p><code><pre>Make sure you write out the `date`.
Today's date is Oct 21, 2020.
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But now, let's assume you wanted to use grep to only find the line that contain the backtick characters around the word 'date'. &nbsp;You might try doing the following:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>`date`</span> sometext.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But this just generates a bunch of error messages in the shell:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span>: Oct: No such file or directory
<span>grep</span>: <span>21</span>: No such file or directory
<span>grep</span>: <span>13</span>:<span>30</span>:<span>57</span>: No such file or directory
<span>grep</span>: EST: No such file or directory
<span>grep</span>: <span>2020</span>: No such file or directory
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;You might be thinking, "Oh, no problem, I'll just use double quotes" and try something like this:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>"</span><span>`date`</span><span>"</span> sometext.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But that <em>still</em> doesn't work (at least not in bash)! &nbsp;It doesn't find any matches at all! &nbsp;The problem in this case is related to the fact that the backtick character has a special meaning in our shell, even when used inside double quotes. &nbsp;To illustrate this point, we can run the following two echo commands:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>date</span><span>"</span>
<span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>`date`</span><span>"</span>
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;and the output of these echo statements is:</p>

<p><code><pre>date
Mon Oct  <span>21</span> <span>13</span>:<span>30</span>:<span>57</span> EST <span>2020</span>
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So from reading the results above example, you can see why the grep command we last used didn't find anything:  We were literally searching for the current date instead of the word 'date' surrounded by backticks! &nbsp;The solution (in bash shell), is to use single-quotes instead:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>'</span><span>`date`</span><span>'</span> sometext.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;which will match correctly as expected:</p>

<p><code><pre>Make sure you write out the `date`.
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This isn't the only issue that you can encounter where your shell could unexpectedly change the meaning of the search string that you pass into grep. &nbsp;You can also encounter an issue with <a href="https://blog.robertelder.org/find-command-wildcard-globbing/">unexpected 'globbing'</a> when you attempt to use a regular expression containing the '*' character without using quotes. &nbsp;For example, consider this simple echo statement that just prints out 'asdf':</p>

<p><code><pre><span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>asdf</span><span>"</span>
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;If you filter this echo statement through a grep search for the character 'a' like this:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>asdf</span><span>"</span><span> </span>| <span>grep</span> a
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the search will pass the line 'asdf' through as expected. &nbsp;And similarly, if you do a regex search with grep for an 'a' followed by any number of other characters like this:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>asdf</span><span>"</span><span> </span>| <span>grep</span> a.*
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;this will also let the 'asdf' through. &nbsp;However, if you create a new file in the current directory called 'a.txt':</p>

<p><code><pre><span>touch</span> a.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the following search won't work anymore! &nbsp;It doesn't find anything:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>asdf</span><span>"</span><span> </span>| <span>grep</span> a.*
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;What!? &nbsp;How can creating a new file change how our grep commands run in the shell??? &nbsp;This problem is explained in detail in <a href="https://blog.robertelder.org/find-command-wildcard-globbing/">this article on shell globbing</a>.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This mistake isn't specific to grep since it's really about regular expressions in general, but it's common enough to include in this article. &nbsp;Consider a case where you're trying to use grep to extract all instances of numbers that include a decimal point. &nbsp;In your search, you're looking for one or more digits, followed by a period, followed by one or more digits. &nbsp;You might try writing a grep command like this:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>234.328</span><span>"</span><span> </span>| <span>grep</span> <span>-Eo</span> <span>"</span><span>[0-9]+.[0-9]+</span><span>"</span>
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;which looks like it works just fine because it does match all of the things you do want. &nbsp;The problem is that is also matches things that you <em>don't</em> want:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>234A328</span><span>"</span><span> </span>| <span>grep</span> <span>-Eo</span> <span>"</span><span>[0-9]+.[0-9]+</span><span>"</span>
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;In the above case, our regular expression will match the pattern '234A328' which isn't a decimal point number. &nbsp;This case becomes obvious when you point it out, since the '.' character usually represents "any character except for newline" in most regular expressions engines. &nbsp;In order to match a 'literal' period character in a regular expression, you need to escape it:</p>

<p><code><pre>
<span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>234A328</span><span>"</span><span> </span>| <span>grep</span> <span>-Eo</span> <span>"</span><span>[0-9]+</span><span>\.</span><span>[0-9]+</span><span>"</span>

<span>echo</span><span> </span><span>"</span><span>234.328</span><span>"</span><span> </span>| <span>grep</span> <span>-Eo</span> <span>"</span><span>[0-9]+</span><span>\.</span><span>[0-9]+</span><span>"</span>
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The lesson is to be careful when using searches that include a '.' character, since it may not always literally mean a period character.</p>




<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Here is some text that we'll place inside a file called 'animals.txt'. &nbsp;Take note that the two 'columns' in this file are separated with tab (\t) characters:</p>

<p><code><pre>Person	Favourite Animal\Pet
Robert	Cat
Alexander	Dog
Sam	Monkey
Michael	Snake
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Let's say that we wanted to write a grep statement to extract the first column from this file. &nbsp;We could do this quickly and crudely by writing a regular expression that will extract anything up and including the tab character. &nbsp;Here's an attempt to do this with the following grep command:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>-o</span> <span>"</span><span>.*</span><span>\t</span><span>"</span> animals.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;But if you run this, you'll get results that are completely wrong:</p>

<p><code><pre>Person  Favourite Animal\Pet
Robert  Cat
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The reason is, again, because of grep's default regular expression mode: BRE or 'Basic Regular Expressions'. &nbsp;However, if we try using the -E flag for 'Extended Regular Expressions', this doesn't fix the problem:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>-Eo</span> <span>"</span><span>.*</span><span>\t</span><span>"</span> animals.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;still gives:</p>

<p><code><pre>Person  Favourite Animal\Pet
Robert  Cat
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;In fact, if you check the <a href="https://pubs.opengroup.org/onlinepubs/9699919799/basedefs/V1_chap09.html">official standard for BRE and ERE</a>, you'll see that it has no support for matching just a 'tab' character! &nbsp;In POSIX BRE or ERE, there are just a handful of characters that you can escape with a backslash, and they don't include tab.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Confusingly, GNU grep <em>does</em> support things like '\s' in ERE even though it's not officially supported by the POSIX standard.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The solution in our case is to use the -P flag for 'Perl-Compatible Regular Expressions':</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> <span>-Po</span> <span>"</span><span>.*</span><span>\t</span><span>"</span> animals.txt
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;which gives us the expected result:</p>

<p><code><pre>Person
Robert
Alexander
Sam
Michael
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Unfortunately, the '-P' flag is not supported by all version of grep, so this solution isn't always available.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This issue is one that you won't encounter every day, but when you do it can be <em>extremely</em> confusing to figure out what's going on. &nbsp;If you ever happen to work with files that are encoded in UTF-16, you'll have to be mindful of the fact that grep isn't aware of character encodings, so whatever you grep for will likely only be found if it's in a character encoding that matches the current encoding of the terminal where you type the grep command.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;For example, imagine that you have two files: the first file encoded in UTF-8 contains this text:</p>

<p><code><pre>Hello World 123!
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;and the second file encoded in UTF-16 contains this text:</p>

<p><code><pre>Hello World 456!
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;On my machine, if I do a grep search over both of these files using this grep command:</p>

<p><code><pre><span>grep</span> World *
</pre></code></p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;this will only match the statement in the first file!</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This fact isn't too surprising when you know what's going on, but the difficult part is noticing that you've got a file that's encoded in a different format in the first place. &nbsp;If you take regular ASCII characters and re-encode them as UTF-16, the file you get will look like regular ASCII encoded text with nulls placed between the characters. &nbsp;Therefore, if you print the file  onto the terminal, the nulls will be ignored and what you see printed will look indistinguishable from regular ASCII text (except for the byte order marker). &nbsp;Programs like vim will automatically recognize the encoding and display the file as normal text, so you likely won't notice the encoding.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;One way to identify the encoding of files is to use …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.robertelder.org/top-5-grep-mistakes/">https://blog.robertelder.org/top-5-grep-mistakes/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.robertelder.org/top-5-grep-mistakes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24996089</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 06:26:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Account Takeover via IDOR in Starbucks Singapore]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 90 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24995657">thread link</a>) | @eshanaswar
<br/>
November 4, 2020 | http://www.kamilonurozkaleli.com/posts/starbucks-singapore-account-takeover/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.kamilonurozkaleli.com/posts/starbucks-singapore-account-takeover/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
			<h3 id="recon"><strong>Recon</strong></h3>
<p>While browsing Starbucks Singapore, I noticed a page loaded with content from a 3rd party site. Let’s call this site <em>example.com</em> in order not to disclose it. When I did some research on this site, I saw the same login page on <em>card.starbucks.com.sg</em> in the directory example.com/starbucks, and at this point I had two possibilities.</p>
<ol>
<li>This application can be an environment where current developments of <em>card.starbucks.com.sg</em> are made and tested.</li>
<li>Or it may have been used as an old test environment and is in an idle state.</li>
</ol>
<p>Both possibilities increased the probability of a bug here, but the main problem is that I did not know whether a bug I will find here would affect the production environment. To understand this, I created a user account at card.starbucks.com.sg and tried to log into example.com/starbucks with this account. BINGO! I was able to successfully login with the account I just created. Both applications seemed to be using the same authentication mechanism.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.kamilonurozkaleli.com/images/starbucks-1.png" alt="Scheme-1, both applications are using same database table."></p>
<h3 id="exploitation"><strong>Exploitation</strong></h3>
<p>From this point I browsed example.com/starbucks and discovered an endpoint which does not exist in the production app. The POST data this endpoint received was as follows.</p>
<p><code>email=hacker@hacker.com</code></p>
<p>When I write the email address of the account I want to takeover in the email parameter here and send a request, I saw the partial information of the account belonging to that email address on my profile page. I could not fully takeover the account yet, and my password change request was not successful due to the invalid CSRF token generated in this application.</p>
<p>To get around this, I copied the PHPSESSID cookie value from example.com/starbucks to card.starbucks.com.sg and BOOM! I was able to see all the information belongs to victim in the production environment, the valid CSRF tokens generated here allowed me to change the password and I was able to completely takeover an account whose e-mail address I know.</p>
<h3 id="impact"><strong>Impact</strong></h3>
<p>Except for seeing all personal information belonging to users and completely taking over the accounts, if there is a loaded credit in the user account, these credits can be spent in Starbucks stores via the mobile application.</p>
<h3 id="multiplying-the-reward"><strong>Multiplying the Reward</strong></h3>
<p>I came across two other test environments on example.com. Let’s call them <em>example.com/starbucks2</em> and <em>example.com/starbucks3</em>. With my account at card.starbucks.com.sg, I was not able to login to either test environment. example.com/starbucks2 did not allow me to create a new account, so I tried my luck at example.com/starbucks3 and successfully created a new account. Things get a little complicated here, I will try to explain it as simply as possible.</p>
<p>I think the applications example.com/starbucks2 and example.com/starbucks3 were using test tables, so users in production could not login in these applications.</p>
<p>With the account I created at example.com/starbucks3, I was able to log in to example.com/starbucks2, but not card.starbucks.com.sg. However, the PHPSESSID I copied from example.com/starbucks2 was valid on card.starbucks.com.sg and I could use that account. Considering all the scenarios, I created a chain here as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>Create a dummy account with the victim’s email address at example.com/starbucks3. (Add to testusers table.)</li>
<li>At example.com/starbucks2, associate the account for that email with your own account via the same endpoint. (Associate the PHPSESSID with the email in the testusers table.)</li>
<li>Copy the PHPSESSID to card.starbucks.com.sg and takeover. (Takeover the real account of the same email address in the production users table.)</li>
</ol>
<p><img src="http://www.kamilonurozkaleli.com/images/starbucks-2.png" alt="Scheme-2, relations between applicaitons and tables."></p>
<p>May 17th - Report Submitted<br>
May 18th - Triaged<br>
May 20th - Rewarded $4000 bounty<br>
Jun 17th - Rewarded $2000 bounty as 1.5x multiplier</p>

		</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.kamilonurozkaleli.com/posts/starbucks-singapore-account-takeover/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24995657</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 04:27:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Linux Commands HandBook]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 129 | Comments 41 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24995352">thread link</a>) | @ekianjo
<br/>
November 4, 2020 | https://openbootcamps.com/the-linux-commands-handbook/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://openbootcamps.com/the-linux-commands-handbook/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                    <!--kg-card-begin: markdown-->
<p>The Linux Commands Handbook follows the 80/20 rule: you’ll learn 80% of a topic in around 20% of the time you spend studying it.</p>
<p>I find that this approach gives you a well-rounded overview.</p>
<p>This handbook does not try to cover everything under the sun related to Linux and its commands. It focuses on the small core commands that you will use the 80% or 90% of the time, and tries to simplify the usage of the more complex ones.</p>
<p>All these commands work on Linux, macOS, WSL, and anywhere you have a UNIX environment.</p>
<p>I hope the contents of this handbook will help you achieve what you want: <strong>getting comfortable with Linux</strong>.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://flaviocopes.com/page/linux-commands-handbook/" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click here to download this handbook in PDF / ePUB / Mobi format</a>.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>

<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>

<h2 id="introductiontolinuxandshells">Introduction to Linux and shells</h2>
<h3 id="whatislinux">What is Linux?</h3>
<p>Linux is an operating system, like macOS or Windows.</p>
<p>It is also the most popular Open Source operating system, and it gives you a lot of freedom.</p>
<p>It powers the vast majority of the servers that compose the Internet. It’s the base upon which everything is built. But not just that. Android is based on (a modified version of) Linux.</p>
<p>The Linux “core” (called a <em>kernel</em>) was born in 1991 in Finland, and it has come a really long way from its humble beginnings. It went on to be the kernel of the GNU Operating System, creating the duo GNU/Linux.</p>
<p>There’s one thing about Linux that corporations like Microsoft, Apple, and Google will never be able to offer: the freedom to do whatever you want with your computer.</p>
<p>They’re actually going in the opposite direction, building walled gardens, especially on the mobile side.</p>
<p>Linux is the ultimate freedom.</p>
<p>It is developed by volunteers, some paid by companies that rely on it, some independently. But there’s no single commercial company that can dictate what goes into Linux, or the project’s priorities.</p>
<p>You can also use Linux as your day to day computer. I use macOS because I really enjoy the applications and design (and I also used to be an iOS and Mac apps developer). But before using macOS I used Linux as my main computer Operating System.</p>
<p>No one can dictate which apps you can run, or “call home” with apps that track you, your position, and more.</p>
<p>Linux is also special because there’s not just “one Linux”, like is the case with Windows or macOS. Instead, we have <strong>distributions</strong>.</p>
<p>A “distro” is made by a company or organization and packages the Linux core with additional programs and tooling.</p>
<p>For example you have Debian, Red Hat, and Ubuntu, probably the most popular distributions.</p>
<p>But many, many more exist. You can create your own distribution, too. But most likely you’ll use a popular one that has lots of users and a community of people around it. This lets you do what you need to do without losing too much time reinventing the wheel and figuring out answers to common problems.</p>
<p>Some desktop computers and laptops ship with Linux preinstalled. Or you can install it on your Windows-based computer, or on a Mac.</p>
<p>But you don’t need to disrupt your existing computer just to get an idea of how Linux works.</p>
<p>I don’t have a Linux computer.</p>
<p>If you use a Mac, you just need to know that under the hood macOS is a UNIX Operating System. It shares a lot of the same ideas and software that a GNU/Linux system uses, because GNU/Linux is a free alternative to UNIX.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix" rel="noopener noreferrer">UNIX</a> is an umbrella term that groups many operating systems used in big corporations and institutions, starting from the 70’s</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The macOS terminal gives you access to the same exact commands I’ll describe in the rest of this handbook.</p>
<p>Microsoft has an official <a target="_blank" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10" rel="noopener noreferrer">Windows Subsystem for Linux</a> which you can (and should!) install on Windows. This will give you the ability to run Linux in a very easy way on your PC.</p>
<p>But the vast majority of the time you will run a Linux computer in the cloud via a VPS (Virtual Private Server) like DigitalOcean.</p>
<h3 id="whatisashell">What is a shell?</h3>
<p>A shell is a command interpreter that exposes an interface to the user to work with the underlying operating system.</p>
<p>It allows you to execute operations using text and commands, and it provides users advanced features like being able to create scripts.</p>
<p>This is important: shells let you perform things in a more optimized way than a GUI (Graphical User Interface) could ever possibly let you do. Command line tools can offer many different configuration options without being too complex to use.</p>
<p>There are many different kind of shells. This post focuses on Unix shells, the ones that you will find commonly on Linux and macOS computers.</p>
<p>Many different kind of shells were created for those systems over time, and a few of them dominate the space: Bash, Csh, Zsh, Fish and many more!</p>
<p>All shells originate from the Bourne Shell, called <code>sh</code>. “Bourne” because its creator was Steve Bourne.</p>
<p>Bash means <em>Bourne-again shell</em>. <code>sh</code> was proprietary and not open source, and Bash was created in 1989 to create a free alternative for the GNU project and the Free Software Foundation. Since projects had to pay to use the Bourne shell, Bash became very popular.</p>
<p>If you use a Mac, try opening your Mac terminal. By default it runs ZSH (or, pre-Catalina, Bash).</p>
<p>You can set up your system to run any kind of shell – for example I use the Fish shell.</p>
<p>Each single shell has its own unique features and advanced usage, but they all share a common functionality: they can let you execute programs, and they can be programmed.</p>
<p>In the rest of this handbook we’ll see in detail the most common commands you will use.</p>

<h2 id="the-man-command">The <code>man</code> command</h2>
<p>The first command I’ll introduce will help you understand all the other commands.</p>
<p>Every time I don’t know how to use a command, I type <code>man &lt;command&gt;</code> to get the manual:</p>
<figure><img src="https://i1.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png?ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png 600w, https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png?ssl=1 1188w" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png 600w, https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png?ssl=1 1188w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-07-04-at-18.42.40.png?ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>
<p>This is a man (from <em>_manual_</em>) page. Man pages are an essential tool to learn as a developer. They contain so much information that sometimes it’s almost too much.<br>The above screenshot is just 1 of 14 screens of explanation for the <code>ls</code> command.</p>
<p>Most of the time when I need to learn a command quickly I use this site called <strong>tldr pages</strong>: <a target="_blank" href="https://tldr.sh/" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://tldr.sh</a>. It’s a command you can install, which you then run like this: <code>tldr &lt;command&gt;</code>. It gives you a very quick overview of a command, with some handy examples of common usage scenarios:</p>
<figure><img src="https://i0.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png?ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png 600w, https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png 1000w, https://i0.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png?ssl=1 1002w" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w600/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png 600w, https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/size/w1000/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png 1000w, https://i0.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png?ssl=1 1002w" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screen-Shot-2020-09-07-at-07.35.41.png?ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></figure>
<p>This is not a substitute for <code>man</code>, but a handy tool to avoid losing yourself in the huge amount of information present in a <code>man</code> page. Then you can use the <code>man</code> page to explore all the different options and parameters you can use on a command.</p>
<h2 id="the-ls-command">The <code>ls</code> command</h2>

<p>Inside a folder you can list all the files that the folder contains using the <code>ls</code> command:</p>
<pre><code>ls
</code></pre>
<p>If you add a folder name or path, it will print that folder’s contents:</p>
<pre><code>ls /bin
</code></pre>
<p><img src="https://i2.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screenshot-2019-02-09-at-18.50.14.png?ssl=1" alt="Screenshot-2019-02-09-at-18.50.14" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i2.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screenshot-2019-02-09-at-18.50.14.png?ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>
<p><code>ls</code> accepts a lot of options. One of my favorite combinations is <code>-al</code>. Try it:</p>
<pre><code>ls -al /bin
</code></pre>
<p><img src="https://i0.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screenshot-2019-02-09-at-18.49.52.png?ssl=1" alt="Screenshot-2019-02-09-at-18.49.52" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-src="https://i0.wp.com/www.freecodecamp.org/news/content/images/2020/10/Screenshot-2019-02-09-at-18.49.52.png?ssl=1&amp;is-pending-load=1" srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"></p>
<p>Compared to the plain <code>ls</code> command, this returns much more information.</p>
<p>You have, from left to right:</p>
<ul>
<li>the file permissions (and if your system supports ACLs, you get an ACL flag as well)</li>
<li>the number of links to that file</li>
<li>the owner of the file</li>
<li>the group of the file</li>
<li>the file size in bytes</li>
<li>the file’s last modified datetime</li>
<li>the file name</li>
</ul>
<p>This set of data is generated by the <code>l</code> option. The <code>a</code> option instead also shows the hidden files.</p>
<p>Hidden files are files that start with a dot (<code>.</code>).</p>

<h2 id="thecdcommand">The <code>cd</code> command</h2>
<p>Once you have a folder, you can move into it using the <code>cd</code> command. <code>cd</code> means <strong>c</strong>hange <strong>d</strong>irectory. You invoke it specifying a folder to move into. You can specify a folder name, or an entire path.</p>
<p>Example:</p>
<pre><code>mkdir fruits
cd fruits
</code></pre>
<p>Now you are in the <code>fruits</code> folder.</p>
<p>You can use the <code>..</code> special path to indicate the parent folder:</p>
<pre><code>cd .. #back to the home folder
</code></pre>
<p>The # character indicates the start of the comment, which lasts for the entire line after it’s found.</p>
<p>You can use it to form a path:</p>
<pre><code>mkdir fruits
mkdir cars
cd fruits
cd ../cars
</code></pre>
<p>There is another special path indicator which is <code>.</code>, and indicates the <strong>current</strong> folder.</p>
<p>You can also use absolute paths, which start from the root folder <code>/</code>:</p>
<pre><code>cd /etc
</code></pre>

<h2 id="the-pwd-command">The <code>pwd</code> command</h2>

<p>Whenever you feel lost in the filesystem, call the <code>pwd</code> command to know where you are:</p>
<pre><code>pwd
</code></pre>
<p>It will print the current folder path.</p>

<h2 id="the-mkdir-command">The <code>mkdir</code> command</h2>

<p>You create folders using the <code>mkdir</code> command:</p>
<pre><code>mkdir fruits
</code></pre>
<p>You can create multiple folders with one command:</p>
<pre><code>mkdir dogs cars
</code></pre>
<p>You can also create multiple nested folders by adding the <code>-p</code> option:</p>
<pre><code>mkdir -p fruits/apples
</code></pre>
<p>Options in UNIX commands commonly take this form. You add them right after the command name, and they change how the command behaves. You can often combine multiple options, too.</p>
<p>You can find which options a command supports by typing <code>man &lt;commandname&gt;</code>. Try now with <code>man mkdir</code> for example (press the <code>q</code> key to esc the man page). Man pages are the amazing built-in help for UNIX.</p>

<h2 id="the-rmdir-command">The <code>rmdir</code> command</h2>

<p>Just as you can create a folder using <code>mkdir</code>, you can delete a folder using <code>rmdir</code>:</p>
<pre><code>mkdir fruits
rmdir fruits
</code></pre>
<p>You can also delete multiple folders at once:</p>
<pre><code>mkdir fruits cars
rmdir fruits cars
</code></pre>
<p>The folder you delete must be empty.</p>
<p>To delete folders with files in them, we’ll use the more generic <code>rm</code> command which deletes files and folders, using the <code>-rf</code> option:</p>
<pre><code>rm -rf fruits cars
</code></pre>
<p>Be careful as this command does not ask for confirmation and it will immediately remove anything you ask it to remove.</p>
<p>There is no <strong>bin</strong> when removing files from the command line, and recovering lost files can be hard.</p>

<h2 id="the-mv-command">The <code>mv</code> command</h2>

<p>Once you have a file, you can move it around using the <code>mv</code> command. You specify the file current path, and its new path:</p>
<pre><code>touch test
mv pear new_pear
</code></pre>
<p>The <code>pear</code> file is now moved to <code>new_pear</code>. This is how you <strong>rename</strong> files and folders.</p>
<p>If the last parameter is a folder, the file located at the first parameter path is going to be moved into that folder. In this case, you can specify a list of files and they will all be moved in the folder path identified by the last parameter:</p>
<pre><code>touch pear
touch apple
mkdir fruits
mv pear apple fruits #pear and apple moved to the fruits folder
</code></pre>

<h2 id="the-cp-command">The <code>cp</code> command</h2>

<p>You can copy a file using the <code>cp</code> command:</p>
<pre><code>touch test
cp apple another_apple
</code></pre>
<p>To copy folders you need to add the <code>-r</code> option to …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://openbootcamps.com/the-linux-commands-handbook/">https://openbootcamps.com/the-linux-commands-handbook/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://openbootcamps.com/the-linux-commands-handbook/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24995352</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 03:19:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[GitHub Source Code Leak]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 970 | Comments 386 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24994746">thread link</a>) | @resynth1943
<br/>
November 4, 2020 | https://resynth1943.net/articles/github-source-code-leak/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://resynth1943.net/articles/github-source-code-leak/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="content">
		
		<p>What do Microsoft <i>really</i> think about open-source?</p>

		<p><strong>Update</strong>: according to multiple online sources, the leaked source code was from GitHub <em>Enterprise</em>, not the version hosted at <a href="http://github.com/">GitHub.com</a>. While a substantial amount of code is shared between the two, they do have some differences.</p>
<p>The entirety of the confidential source code used by GitHub Enterprise has just been leaked to the public.</p>
<p>In a suspicious <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20201104050026if_/https://github.com/github/dmca/tree/565ece486c7c1652754d7b6d2b5ed9cb4097f9d5">commit</a> to the <a href="https://github.com/github/dmca">official GitHub DMCA repository</a>, an unknown individual uploaded the confidential source code, impersonating Nat Friedman using a bug in GitHub's application.</p>
<p>At the heart of open-source, GitHub has long been criticised for keeping its source code private. The platform hosts millions of open-source projects, and critics say GitHub's position is somewhat hypocritical.</p>
<p>However, this raises questions around the security of GitHub's source code, and whether or not GitHub have anything to lose, if they do plan to release the source code in a public setting.</p>
<p>Some worry this will damage the overall security of GitHub, and this may be true. Commonly, closed-source applications perform "security by obscurity". This means the source code is hidden, with the intention of concealing security risks.</p>
<p>Since Microsoft's <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/10/26/17954714/microsoft-github-deal-acquisition-complete">acquisition of GitHub</a> in 2018, Microsoft have repeatedly emphasised their "love" for open-source. We have seen this through repeated commercial advertisements, which aim to place Microsoft at the forefront of open-source development.</p>
<p>Some users, such as Drew DeVault, suggest Microsoft is attempting to <a href="https://drewdevault.com/2020/08/27/Microsoft-plays-their-hand.html">centralise open-source</a>. Through closed-source applications, and proprietary extensions to Git, GitHub is seen as a platform that tries to <em>contain</em> open-source. An example of this is when <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/29/21306674/github-down-errors-outage-june-2020">GitHub went offline for two hours</a>, leaving thousands of open-source projects inaccessible and unusable.</p>
<p>GitHub is, in many ways, the Google of open-source development.</p>
<p>Perhaps GitHub as 12 years late in finally revealing their source code to the public; and maybe this is just what we need. <a href="https://mastodon.tedomum.net/@resynth1943">What do you think?</a></p>


		<!-- Doing a little experiment here. -->
		<p aria-disabled="true">resynth1943.article</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://resynth1943.net/articles/github-source-code-leak/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24994746</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 01:10:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[IPv6 Is a Nightmare]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 137 | Comments 195 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24994587">thread link</a>) | @whereistimbo
<br/>
November 4, 2020 | https://teknikaldomain.me/post/ipv6-is-a-total-nightmare/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://teknikaldomain.me/post/ipv6-is-a-total-nightmare/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>
<div>


<p>So this is just going to be a total rant.
IPv6 is, in theory, a solution to many things, including the dwindling IPv4 address space.
IPv6 was a draft in 1997(!), and became a real <em>Internet Standard</em> in 2017.
And, quite frankly, it’s one of those things that just adds too much hassle for not enough benefit.</p>

<p>Okay, yes, IPv6’s address space is <em><strong>massive.</strong></em>
IPv4 uses 32-bit addresses, allowing for 4,294,967,296 total addresses.
IPv6 uses 128-bit addresses, meaning… 340,282,366,920,938,463,463,374,607,431,768,211,456 addresses.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>
The entire v4 space could fit into the v6 space $7.922816251426434 \times 10^{28}$ times over.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>
The default allocation to people, a <code>/64</code>, meaning the first half of the addresses is fixed and the entire second half is the part unique to the network, means that most people have 18,446,744,073,709,551,616 addresses to play with at home.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>
Compared to v4, where <em>most</em> networks are around <code>/24</code>, meaning the first three groupings are fixed, you get… 254 addresses.
Again, context, a standard <code>/64</code> allocation can, <em>again</em>, fit the entire v4 address space inside itself 4,294,967,296 times. (Yes, that’s the number of addresses <em>in</em> the IPv4 address space. That’s what happens when you divide a power by half of that power.)</p>
<p>IPv4 addresses are, well, sparse, given that most high-level authorities have already run out of addresses, but because CIDR and NAT are a thing, we’ve really started compacting down our usage.
<em>My entire house</em> of easily over 60 IPs takes up… 2, according to the rest of the world.</p>
<h2 id="allocation-issues">Allocation Issues</h2>
<p>One thing that people have criticized IPv4 for is that the allocations are just horrible.
For example, <em>anything</em> starting with <code>127</code> is <code>localhost</code>.
normally this is <code>127.0.0.1</code>, but anything from <code>127.0.0.0</code> to <code>127.255.255.255</code> all mean the <strong>exact same thing.</strong>
That’s 16,777,216 addresses all <em>literally for <code>localhost</code>.</em>
By numbers, 0.39% of the address space, but just keep this in mind.</p>
<p>Similarly, anything starting with a <code>0</code>, is effectively “current network” (only valid as source), again, another 16 million addresses.</p>
<p>There’s also multiple blocks for private networks, <code>10.0.0.0/8</code>, <code>172.16.0.0/12</code>, and <code>192.168.0.0/16</code>.
In total, 17,891,328 addresses.</p>
<p>Compared to IPv6, yes, IPv6 is much better… in theory.
There’s only <em>one</em> loopback address, <code>::1</code>.
At the same time… <code>fc00::/7</code> (26,58,455,991,569,831,745,807,614,120,560,689,152 addresses) is the private address space (more on that later), <code>fe80::/10</code> (332,306,998,946,228,968,225,951,765,070,086,144 addresses) is the <em>local</em> address space, and <code>ff00::/8</code> (1,329,227,995,784,915,872,903,807,060,280,344,576 addresses.) is multicast.
yes, do you see a recurring pattern?
Even though the entire “special” address assignments are exactly 1.271% of the entire IPv6 address space, we’re still allocating <strong>giant</strong> swathes of addresses.
History repeats itself, you can see that <em>right here.</em></p>
<p>And I will admit, that multicast in IPv6 is special since some bits in the address are special flags, and one form of multicast actually includes a response node’s address, so it’s not <em>just</em> an arbitrary number, but… come on, that’s a little uncalled for, having <em>that much</em> space.</p>

<p>We all know what an IPv4 address looks like, right?
Four dotted-decimal grouping in the range from 0–255.
For example, <code>192.168.5.225</code>.
IPv6 uses <em>eight</em> groupings of four <em>hex</em> digits, colon-separated.
For example, <code>2607:f0d0:1002:0051:0000:0000:0000:0004</code>.
That’s… very unweildy, so we have a few shortening rules.
Any zeros that <em>lead</em> the droup can be dropped, giving us this: <code>2607:f0d0:1002:51:0:0:0:4</code>.
And since <em>that</em> is still repetitive, you can replace <em>exactly one</em> sequence of <em>more than one group</em> of all zeros with an empty: <code>2607:f0d0:1002:51::4</code>.
For the record this is why the loopback address is <code>::1</code>.
The full address is <code>0000:0000:0000:0000:0000:0000:0000:0001</code>.
Even with those methods, they’re still <em>much</em> longer, harder to remember, and harder to even say than IPv4 addresses.</p>
<h2 id="urls">URLs</h2>
<p>And remember that this address violates the URL spec, since the <code>:</code> character is specifically to be used to separate the <em>host</em> portion (e.g., <code>google.com</code>) from the <em>port</em> to connect to (assuming nonstandard).
As an example, I can reach my torrent client via <code>http://192.168.5.43:9091</code>.
See that <code>:</code> there?
Because Transmission listens on port 9091, not port 80.
How do we fix this?
Well, by breaking it again, naturally.
To connect to a raw IPv6 address, you wrap it in square brackets.
To connect to <code>2607:f0d0:1002:51::4</code> directly, that’s <code>http://[2607:f0d0:1002:51::4]/</code>
<strong>Why is this a thing?!</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="dns">DNS</h2>
<p>okay, admittedly, IPv6 kinda relies on DNS since… just about everything uses DNS, and of course, actual names are more memorable than 32 hexadecimal digits, but DNS isn’t magic.
Unless you have your own DNS server (actually not that hard) that’s configured, you’re still manually typing addresses.
Of course if you have, say, pfSense managing your network, every static DHCP lease will be registered in DNS, but it has to take a DHCP lease.
And if this device doesn’t… well, I hope you don’t mind typing that out by hand to connect so you can configure it.</p>
<p>Even better, rDNS.
rDNS, or Reverse DNS, is where a DNS query is performed <em>with an IP address</em> that returns the hostname associated, in a <code>PTR</code> record.
For example, the IPv4 that <code>google.com</code> resolves to, <code>216.58.192.142</code>, can be queried as <code>142.192.58.216.in-addr.arpa</code> to get it’s “real” name, a <code>PTR</code> record for <code>ord36s01-in-f142.1e100.net</code>.
With <code>dig</code>, specifying a <code>-x</code> and then the IP will convert it to the correct format.
And if you look close, the query name is the IP, backwards, with <code>in-addr.arpa</code> at the front.
It’s backwards because of the hierarchical nature of DNS, which runs right to left, the opposite of IPs.
Of course, there’s also rDNS for IPv6:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="plaintext">$ dig -x 2607:f0d0:1002:51::4

; &lt;&lt;&gt;&gt; DiG 9.11.3-1ubuntu1.12-Ubuntu &lt;&lt;&gt;&gt; -x 2607:f0d0:1002:51::4
;; global options: +cmd
;; Got answer:
;; -&gt;&gt;HEADER&lt;&lt;- opcode: QUERY, status: NOERROR, id: 22821
;; flags: qr rd ra; QUERY: 1, ANSWER: 1, AUTHORITY: 0, ADDITIONAL: 1

;; OPT PSEUDOSECTION:
; EDNS: version: 0, flags:; udp: 65494
;; QUESTION SECTION:
;4.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.1.5.0.0.2.0.0.1.0.d.0.f.7.0.6.2.ip6.arpa. IN PTR

;; ANSWER SECTION:
4.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.0.1.5.0.0.2.0.0.1.0.d.0.f.7.0.6.2.ip6.arpa. 3600 IN PTR 4000.0000.0000.0000.1500.2001.0d0f.7062.ip6.static.sl-reverse.com.

;; Query time: 731 msec
;; SERVER: 127.0.0.53#53(127.0.0.53)
;; WHEN: Sun Aug 30 00:52:50 EDT 2020
;; MSG SIZE  rcvd: 180
</code></pre></div><p>That is <em><strong>insane.</strong></em>
The IPv6 rDNS <abbr title="Top Level Domain">TLD</abbr>
is just <code>ip6.arpa</code>, and the IP part is…
every single hex digit, reversed.</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="plaintext">2607f0d0100200510000000000000004
4000000000000000150020010d0f7062
</code></pre></div>
<p>One of the core pillars of IPv6 is that most of the processing of traffic should happen at the endpoints — routers don’t do much besides read, and forward, with very little actual data processing.
The IPv6 header while being <em>gargantuan</em> in comparison (because the giant addresses), is also much simpler.
A fixed version code (6), the traffic class (<abbr title="Differentiated Services">DiffServ</abbr>
+ <abbr title="Explicit Congestion Notification">ECN</abbr>
), a <em>flow label</em> which is effectively a random value that’s constant for every packet that’s part of the same logical connection, length, type of next header, and a TTL (then addresses, obviously).
That is <em>it</em>.
The IPv4 header contains 13 fields plus optional sections, and the IPv6 header contains a flat 8.
Of course, you may actually need other details, and that’s where the <em>next header</em> field comes in.
Instead of packing all sorts of options into the standard, global header, IPv6 uses additional header <em>extensions</em> that can get tacked on one after another to provide that information, say for fragmentation or IPsec.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>
The value in the next header field identifies what’s going to come next, and the final header in the line will use this field to indicate the contained protocol, be it TCP, UDP, or something else.</p>
<p>Also note there’s no checksum anymore.
I mean, just about every device uses Ethernet, which has a Frame Check Sequence (FCS), UDP has a checksum option, TCP has a required checksum…
If we want to simply packet processing, drop the sum.
And really, it does make sense, in a way.
Even without that one, that means that most programs have two checksums: the Ethernet FCS as the frame gets transmitted point to point, and the transport layer checksum, making sure the entire packet is still valid.
Also, the IPv4 checksum also included the TTL (max number of hops in the path before the packet is dropped), meaning that at <em>every stop</em> along the way, the checksum had to be recalculated.</p>
<p>As a final point, this also does bring a change to another protocol: UDP.
With IPv4, the UDP checksum field can (and often would) be left blank as all zeros, meaning “no checksum”.
In IPv6, this is now disallowed, and a all zero checksum will still be checked… and then found invalid.
All UDP packets over IPv6 <em>must</em> have a valid checksum calculated.</p>

<p>So every link between devices has an MTU, the Maximum Transmission Unit.
For normal Ethernet links, minus the frame overhead, this is 1500 bytes.
If your equipment supports jumbo frames, that’s closer to 9000 bytes.
Well not all links are equal.
Some devices might have a high-MTU link on one end, and a lower MTU link on the other.
For example, my router might support jumbo frames internally, but the WAN side doesn’t allow that.
To deal with, this, we have <em>fragmentation</em>.</p>
<p>If a router is unable to forward a frame due to MTU differences, it will, if allowed, split the packet into multiple chunks, using the More Fragments flag and the Fragment Offset field of the IPv4 header, and send the packet in multiple frames piece by piece, which the other end can reassemble.
Note that I said “if allowed.”
There is a Don’t Fragment flag in the IPv4 header, and if this is set by the sending device, a router that cannot support a packet of that size will send back an <abbr title="Internet Control Message Protocol">ICMP</abbr>
“packet too big” message which bounces back along the chain.
Any node in the network path can perform this, meaning that for sending data, the only MTU you care about is the MTU of the device you’re directly connected …</p></div></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://teknikaldomain.me/post/ipv6-is-a-total-nightmare/">https://teknikaldomain.me/post/ipv6-is-a-total-nightmare/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://teknikaldomain.me/post/ipv6-is-a-total-nightmare/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24994587</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:37:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Anatomy of a Binary Executable]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24994522">thread link</a>) | @WalterSobchak
<br/>
November 4, 2020 | https://oswalt.dev/2020/11/anatomy-of-a-binary-executable/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://oswalt.dev/2020/11/anatomy-of-a-binary-executable/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

            <div>
                <h3>Anatomy of a Binary Executable</h3>
                
                    <p><em></em>
                        <span>Wed, Nov 4, 2020</span>
                        <em></em>
                        <span>23-minute read</span>
                    </p>
                
            </div>

            <p>Even though I’ve developed software for a number of years now, there’s one question that has always been in the back of my mind and I haven’t had the time or patience to really answer, until now: <strong>What <em>is</em> a binary executable anyways?</strong></p>
<p>For this example, I wrote a brutally simple Rust program that includes a function “<code>sum</code>” to add two integers together, and am invoking it from <code>main()</code>:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>fn</span> <span>main</span>() {
    println<span>!</span>(<span>"{}"</span>, sum(<span>5</span>, <span>8</span>));
}

<span>pub</span> <span>fn</span> <span>sum</span>(a: <span>i32</span>, b: <span>i32</span>) -&gt; <span>i32</span> {
    a <span>+</span> b
}
</code></pre></div><p>My Rust code is always structured the <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/cargo/guide/project-layout.html">“cargo way”</a>, so I can compile my program by running <code>cargo build</code>, and this will produce a binary for me within the <code>target/debug/</code> directory. I have named my crate <code>rbin</code>, so this is the name of the binary that is created at this location:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">~$ cargo build
   Compiling rbin v0.1.0 <span>(</span>/home/mierdin/Code/rbin<span>)</span>
    Finished dev <span>[</span>unoptimized + debuginfo<span>]</span> target<span>(</span>s<span>)</span> in 0.15s

~$ ls -lha target/debug/rbin
-rwxrwxr-x <span>2</span> mierdin mierdin 3.1M Nov  <span>3</span> 22:46 target/debug/rbin
</code></pre></div><p>These days, it’s really easy to take such questions for granted, but if you’re curious, you may be asking:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“But what <strong>is</strong> that file?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I mean we all generally know that it’s an “executable”, in that we run it and our program happens. But what does that mean? What is contained in that file that means our computer automatically just <strong>knows</strong> how to run it? And how is it possible that a program with 7 lines of code can take up over 3 megabytes of disk space?!?</p>
<p>It turns out that in order to create an executable for this ridiculously simple program, the Rust compiler must include quite a bit of additional software to make it possible.</p>

<p>Well, it turns out there is a widely accepted format for these things, called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executable_and_Linkable_Format">“Executable and Linkable Format”</a>, or ELF!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Note that I won’t be comprehensively covering ELF here (there are plenty of other resources, many of which I’ll link to) - rather this is an exploration of what goes into a Rust binary with the simplest, default settings, and some observations about what seems interesting to me.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>ELF is a well-known, popular format, especially in the world of Linux, but there are plenty of others. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_executable_file_formats">Operating systems like Windows and macOS each have their own format</a>, which is a big reason why, when you’re compiling (or simply downloading) software, you have to specify the operating system you want to run it on. This is true despite the fact that the underlying machine code that executes your program may be the same on all of them (e.g. <code>x86_64</code>).</p>
<p>An <strong>exceptional</strong> visual breaking down the ELF format can be found at the link to the ELF wikipedia page above, I have found myself constantly referring back to it while writing this post:</p>
<p><a title="Ange Albertini / CC BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/1.0)" href="https://oswalt.dev/assets/2020/11/elf.png"><img width="512" alt="ELF Executable and Linkable Format diagram by Ange Albertini" src="https://oswalt.dev/assets/2020/11/elf.png"></a>
</p>
<p>Commonly, executable formats like this specify a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File_format#Magic_number">magic number</a> right at the beginning of the file, so that the format can be easily identified. This occupies the first four bytes in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executable_and_Linkable_Format#File_header">file header</a>. This is a very important field, because unless we can first identify an ELF file appropriately, we can’t reasonably expect to do anything “ELF-y” with it. We know where certain bits of information <strong>should</strong> be in an ELF file, but we first must identify using these bytes that this is what we can expect.</p>
<p>The <code>readelf</code> utility is extremely useful for printing all kinds of useful metadata and related tables of information contained within an ELF file. However, this utility expects - naturally - that the file being read is actually an ELF file, and even provides a helpful hint that the expected “magic bytes” for a non-ELF file aren’t set appropriately when used on a non-ELF file, so it doesn’t attempt to read the rest:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">~$ readelf -l .gitignore

readelf: Error: Not an ELF file - it has the wrong magic bytes at the start
</code></pre></div><p>Once identified, the entire rest of the file can be identified using <strong>byte offsets</strong> (that is, the number of bytes from zero).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>For those that are accustomed to looking at network packet captures, this should all sound very familiar to you, as this is exactly how we know where certain fields are located in a packet header. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet_frame">Ethernet frames</a> have a predictable preamble and start-of-frame delimiter. Ethernet also has a field called the “Ethertype”, which provides a clue as to what protocol is contained within the Ethernet frame (which allows computers to then parse those field as well). Just like Ethernet has a standard set of byte offsets that indicate where the various fields should be represented, the ELF format specifies its own offsets for all of the fields providing useful identifying and execution information in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executable_and_Linkable_Format#File_header">file header</a>, which then point to other important locations within the file.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There’s all kinds of useful information in this header, but in particular, the <code>e_entry</code> field  in the file header points to the offset location from where the execution should start. This is the “entry point” for the program. We’ll definitely be following this down the rabbit hole in a little bit.</p>
<p>We can again use <code>readelf</code>, this time on a proper ELF file (our Rust program), and also using the <code>-h</code> flag to show the file header:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">~$ readelf -h target/debug/rbin

ELF Header:
  Magic:   7f <span>45</span> 4c <span>46</span> <span>02</span> <span>01</span> <span>01</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> <span>00</span> 
  Class:                             ELF64
  Data:                              2<span>'</span>s complement, little endian
  Version:                           <span>1</span> <span>(</span>current<span>)</span>
  OS/ABI:                            UNIX - System V
  ABI Version:                       <span>0</span>
  Type:                              DYN <span>(</span>Shared object file<span>)</span>
  Machine:                           Advanced Micro Devices X86-64
  Version:                           0x1
  Entry point address:               0x5070
  Start of program headers:          <span>64</span> <span>(</span>bytes into file<span>)</span>
  Start of section headers:          <span>3195368</span> <span>(</span>bytes into file<span>)</span>
  Flags:                             0x0
  Size of this header:               <span>64</span> <span>(</span>bytes<span>)</span>
  Size of program headers:           <span>56</span> <span>(</span>bytes<span>)</span>
  Number of program headers:         <span>12</span>
  Size of section headers:           <span>64</span> <span>(</span>bytes<span>)</span>
  Number of section headers:         <span>42</span>
  Section header string table index: <span>41</span>
</code></pre></div><p>So, the “magic number” lets us parse at least the rest of the file header, which contains not only information about the file, but byte-offset locations for other important portions of the file. One of these is the “Start of program headers”, which starts after 64 bytes.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executable_and_Linkable_Format#Program_header">program header table</a> contains information that allows the operating system to allocate memory and load the program. This is also referred to as a <a href="http://www.tldp.org/LDP/LG/issue23/flower/psimage.html">process image</a>. You can think of it as a list of “instructions” that tell the system to do various things with chunks of memory in order to prepare to execute this program.</p>
<p>The <code>readelf</code> utility also allows us to read the program headers using the <code>-l</code> flag:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">~$ readelf -l target/debug/rbin

Elf file type is DYN <span>(</span>Shared object file<span>)</span>
Entry point 0x5070
There are <span>12</span> program headers, starting at offset <span>64</span>

Program Headers:
  Type           Offset             VirtAddr           PhysAddr
                 FileSiz            MemSiz              Flags  Align
  PHDR           0x0000000000000040 0x0000000000000040 0x0000000000000040
                 0x00000000000002a0 0x00000000000002a0  R      0x8
  INTERP         0x00000000000002e0 0x00000000000002e0 0x00000000000002e0
                 0x000000000000001c 0x000000000000001c  R      0x1
      <span>[</span>Requesting program interpreter: /lib64/ld-linux-x86-64.so.2<span>]</span>
  LOAD           0x0000000000000000 0x0000000000000000 0x0000000000000000
                 0x0000000000004ed8 0x0000000000004ed8  R      0x1000
  LOAD           0x0000000000005000 0x0000000000005000 0x0000000000005000
                 0x0000000000030571 0x0000000000030571  R E    0x1000
  LOAD           0x0000000000036000 0x0000000000036000 0x0000000000036000
                 0x000000000000be44 0x000000000000be44  R      0x1000
  LOAD           0x0000000000042520 0x0000000000043520 0x0000000000043520
                 0x0000000000002b18 0x0000000000002cf8  RW     0x1000
  DYNAMIC        0x0000000000044740 0x0000000000045740 0x0000000000045740
                 0x0000000000000230 0x0000000000000230  RW     0x8
  NOTE           0x00000000000002fc 0x00000000000002fc 0x00000000000002fc
                 0x0000000000000044 0x0000000000000044  R      0x4
  TLS            0x0000000000042520 0x0000000000043520 0x0000000000043520
                 0x0000000000000000 0x00000000000000d8  R      0x20
  GNU_EH_FRAME   0x000000000003aa8c 0x000000000003aa8c 0x000000000003aa8c
                 0x0000000000000d84 0x0000000000000d84  R      0x4
  GNU_STACK      0x0000000000000000 0x0000000000000000 0x0000000000000000
                 0x0000000000000000 0x0000000000000000  RW     0x10
  GNU_RELRO      0x0000000000042520 0x0000000000043520 0x0000000000043520
                 0x0000000000002ae0 0x0000000000002ae0  R      0x1

 Section to Segment mapping:
  Segment Sections...
   <span>00</span>     
   <span>01</span>     .interp 
   <span>02</span>     .interp .note.gnu.build-id .note.ABI-tag .gnu.hash .dynsym .dynstr .gnu.version .gnu.version_r .rela.dyn .rela.plt 
   <span>03</span>     .init .plt .plt.got .text .fini 
   <span>04</span>     .rodata .debug_gdb_scripts .eh_frame_hdr .eh_frame .gcc_except_table 
   <span>05</span>     .init_array .fini_array .data.rel.ro .dynamic .got .data .bss 
   <span>06</span>     .dynamic 
   <span>07</span>     .note.gnu.build-id .note.ABI-tag 
   <span>08</span>     .tbss 
   <span>09</span>     .eh_frame_hdr 
   <span>10</span>     
   <span>11</span>     .init_array .fini_array .data.rel.ro .dynamic .got 
</code></pre></div><p>Each <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executable_and_Linkable_Format#Program_header">program header type</a> does something different to a chunk of memory (segment). Next to each header can be found two 64-bit (this is a 64 bit ELF after all) hexidecimal values. As indicated at the top of the header output, the top value is the memory offset of the segment that the header refers to (where it is located). The value below that is the size of that particular segment in the …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://oswalt.dev/2020/11/anatomy-of-a-binary-executable/">https://oswalt.dev/2020/11/anatomy-of-a-binary-executable/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://oswalt.dev/2020/11/anatomy-of-a-binary-executable/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24994522</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:26:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
