<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 01:05:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 01:05:03 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I am an 80 column purist]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 6 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25251494">thread link</a>) | @Spiritus
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>I write and prefer code that fits within 80 columns in <a href="https://curl.haxx.se/">curl</a> and other projects – and there are reasons for it. I’m a little bored by the people who respond and say that they have 400 inch monitors already and they can use them.</p>



<p>I too have multiple large high resolution screens – but writing wide code is still a bad idea! So I decided I’ll write down my reasoning once and for all!</p>



<h2>Narrower is easier to read</h2>



<p>There’s a reason newspapers and magazines have used narrow texts for centuries and in fact even books <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line_length">aren’t using long lines</a>. For most humans, it is simply easier on the eyes and brain to read texts that aren’t using really long lines. This has been known for a very long time.</p>



<p>Easy-to-read code is easier to follow and understand which leads to fewer bugs and faster debugging.</p>



<h2>Side-by-side works better</h2>



<p>I <em>never</em> run windows full sized on my screens for anything except watching movies. I frequently have two or more editor windows next to each other, sometimes also with one or two extra terminal/debugger windows next to those. To make this feasible and still have the code readable, it needs to fit “wrapless” in those windows.</p>



<p>Sometimes reading a code diff is easier side-by-side and then too it is important that the two can fit next to each other nicely.</p>



<h2>Better diffs</h2>



<p>Having code grow vertically rather than horizontally is beneficial for diff, git and other tools that work on changes to files. It reduces the risk of merge conflicts and it makes the merge conflicts that still happen easier to deal with.</p>



<h2>It encourages shorter names</h2>



<p>A side effect by strictly not allowing anything beyond column 80 is that it becomes really hard to use those terribly annoying 30+ letters java-style names on functions and identifiers. A function name, and especially local ones, should be short. Having long names make them really hard to read and makes it really hard to spot the difference between the other functions with similarly long names where just a sub-word within is changed.</p>



<p>I know especially Java people object to this as they’re trained in a different culture and say that a method name should rather include a lot of details of the functionality “to help the user”, but to me that’s a weak argument as all non-trivial functions will have more functionality than what can be expressed in the name and thus the user needs to know how the function works <em>anyway.</em></p>



<p>I don’t mean 2-letter names. I mean long enough to make sense but not be ridiculous lengths. Usually within 15 letters or so.</p>



<h2>Just a few spaces per indent level</h2>



<p>To make this work, and yet allow a few indent levels, the code basically have to have small indent-levels, so I prefer to have it set to two spaces per level.</p>



<h2>Many indent levels is wrong anyway</h2>



<p>If you do a lot of indent levels it gets really hard to write code that still fits within the 80 column limit. That’s a subtle way to suggest that you should not write functions that needs or uses that many indent levels. It should then rather be split out into multiple smaller functions, where then each function won’t need that many levels!</p>



<h2>Why exactly 80?</h2>



<p>Once upon the time it was of course because terminals had that limit and these days the exact number 80 is not a must. I just happen to think that the limit has worked fine in the past and I haven’t found any compelling reason to change it since.</p>



<p>It also has to be a hard and fixed limit as if we allow a few places to go beyond the limit we end up on a slippery slope and code slowly grow wider over time – I’ve seen it happen in many projects with “soft enforcement” on code column limits.</p>



<h2>Enforced by a tool</h2>



<p>In <a href="https://curl.se/">curl</a>, we have ‘checksrc’ which will yell errors at any user trying to build code with a too long line present. This is good because then we don’t have to “waste” human efforts to point this out to contributors who offer pull requests. The tool will point out such mistakes with ruthless accuracy.</p>



<h2>Credits</h2>



<p>Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/piotrarssale-15944391/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5016297">piotr kurpaska</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5016297">Pixabay</a></p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2020/11/30/i-am-an-80-column-purist/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25251494</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 07:31:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I Am Not Fat]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 115 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25251082">thread link</a>) | @snow_mac
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content" role="main">
      <p> <em>Published: </em> 11/28/2020</p>

      <p>I’m not fat. There I said it, I should feel better about myself, right? Size is just a number. Right? Come on you know it’s true, size, weight and all that jazz is just a BS figure on the scale. That’s what we tell ourselves to make us feel better.</p>

<p>I’m obese, my medical BMI is 42.0. I’m 335 pounds. As Penn Jillette would say, I’m a “fat fuck”. I’m tired of being a “fat fuck” or as my wife prefers a “big guy”.</p>



<p>I’m an audiobook guy. I’m in love with Audible, she is very wonderful service to have, she reads to me every day, all day. About two weeks ago, I was bored, and she suggested Presto, a book by Penn Jillette about how he lost 100 pounds. I was bored, lazy and waiting for someone so I bought the book. Oh my gosh, the language is obscene, but the author is hilarious and entertaining. I could not put the book down. It made me want to toss the skinny white peppermint mocha and bananas in the trash…</p>

<p>Basically, Penn is a obese guy like me, well he was, he was 330 pounds at his highest. He went to the hospital for heart issues and nearly died. On a fist full of pills to keep his blood pressure less than the voltage of an outlet in Europe he embarked on a crazy, all in diet consisting of potatoes for two weeks. I like his style, he’s an all or nothing guy like me. Either give me the steak, the ice cream and the sides or give me nothing. I want to eat big; I want to live big. Moderation is bullshit as Penn would say, I would agree! I don’t do anything in moderation. If I’m going to do something, it’s all-in baby. When in Vegas last summer, I was the dipshit who went all in with a pair of kings in my hand and straight on the table; that’s me baby, not the smartest guy but hey I like to live it big.</p>

<p>I don’t do keto, I don’t do paleo, but when I do diet, I go really big, I go to Costco and literally buy everything I need to be successful on that plan, I research, I plan. It’s just like thanksgiving this year; I researched, I planned, I went to Costco and planned out each and every ingredient. I was diligent. Every doctor, health coach and fitness instructor has told me that my relationship with food is fucked up. Well, not fucked up, but bad; unhealthy. As Penn would say your life sucks if you’re taking diet advice from a Las Vegas Magician, well, Penn, my life does suck. I can’t breathe outside very well, hell, I get windy walking to the park. I’m an obese guy, I have a CPAP machine, I’m 335 pounds, I can barely do the things I want to do, basic stuff; sleep and wake rested, eat and not feel sick, go for a walk and not get winded. I’m half Penn’s age and his same weight… It’s time for a change.</p>



<p>The plan according to Penn’s buddy, Cray Ray, aka “Ray Cronise” is to do the following:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Eat nothing but potatoes for two weeks. Boiled, baked, steamed, roasted; does not matter, just no salt, oil, or sugar. Plain, nothing added, no salt, no butter, no pepper, no olive oil, just a plain, boring potato. Sweet, red, yellow, gold, purple, do not be a racist pig about potatoes, eat the potato rainbow, but just potatoes. Feel free to pig out on potatoes; just no fries or chips, that’s the beautiful potato ruined by Americans</li>
  <li>Contrast showers: Humans have conquered winter &amp; cold. Therefore, in order to get back to the biologically true lifestyle we’ve grown as a species as, we need to bring back the cold. Turn down the thermostat and cycle 10 seconds hot; 30 seconds cold showers for 5 minutes. It’s brutal but the time goes by shockingly fast</li>
  <li>After two weeks on potatoes, you go to a plant based, vegan lifestyle until you hit your target weight</li>
</ol>



<p>One big thing with CrayRay and Penn is the need for a scale, the smartass of scales. On an impluse I plopped down $100 for the <a href="https://www.withings.com/us/en/body-plus">Withings Body + scale</a>. It’s been 10 days! 10 DAYS!!! I’m 326.4, on day 2 of the plan. In 10 days, 1 of which involving nothing but potatoes, I’ve lost 9 pounds. This is AMAZING.</p>

<p>On day 1, it’s black Friday, or sucker day of the year. Everyone piles in their car after a Thanksgiving Day hang over consisting of pie and turkey, to go buy more stuff to stuff into their garage in six months. It’s all American in style and glory. What am I do? Well, shopping for TVs on Amazon like every other fat guy scared out of his mind of COVID-19. I’m sitting on my couch waiting for the oven, 350 degrees for 45 minutes, to produce 9 potatoes. That’s right 9 potatoes, or about 1000 ish calories. Once done cooking, I scarf down one single sweet potato. It’s sweet (no shit sherlock), delicious and surprisingly moist. I like it, I chase it with 4 tiny petite potatoes and some black coffee. This diet is sure boring.</p>

<p>Lunch time rolls around and I make some food for the kiddo and thanksgiving dinner for lunch for the wife. What do I have? If you guessed potatoes, you’d win the prize! I had 2 potatoes, a red and white. It was bland, boring and good.</p>

<p>A car ride nap, so more black coffee and about 2 liters of water later, we’re sitting down to dinner. I made peanut noodles for the wife, mac and cheese with some TG leftovers for the baby. I have 3 more potatoes, a gold, a red and a sweet potato. 2 potatoes into the meal, I’m stuffed. STUFFED ON TWO POTATOES?!?!??! Yeah, I save the sweet potato for dessert and decide to count my potatoes.</p>

<p>A few days ago, while prepping for thanksgiving, I bought 10 pounds of potatoes. I thought that was a LOT of potatoes, but when I counted it out I had around 20 potatoes left. That’s enough to feed a family a four a potato a night for a week, but for a guy living on potatoes? It’s more like two days if I’m lucky, so I head to Costco.</p>

<p>I love Costco. Everything there is a deal, no matter what the idiots on Life Hacker tell you. I love their steak, their fruit and yes, I love their clothes and bedding. But potatoes, that’s where you really make off like bandits. The potatoes were on sale today too.</p>

<p>I knew to continue the diet I needed to account for 14 days of potatoes, less today and the 1.5 I had in revere; thus, I knew I need about 12 (rounding up) days of potatoes. I’m supposed to be on a calorie restricted diet of 1800 or less per day, which is helping, but to get 1800 calories a day eating just potatoes, I’d need to consume 5 POUNDS of potatoes. That’s right, every day on this thing to hit target calorie intake I’d need 5 POUNDS!?!?!? So, with 12 days needed to be shopped, a total of 60 pounds of potatoes, I headed to Costco.</p>



<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Potato Type</td>
      <td>Per Unit Cost</td>
      <td>Units</td>
      <td>Total Cost</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Creamer Potatoes</td>
      <td>$3.99 / 5 lb</td>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>$16</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Organic Sweet Potatos</td>
      <td>$6.99 / 6.5 lbs</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>$14</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Russet Potatoes</td>
      <td>$7 / 15 lbs</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>$7</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Gold Potatoes</td>
      <td>$6 / 10 lbs</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>$12</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>68 pounds of potatoes for a whopping $49!</p>

<p>Here’s what my shopping chart looked like:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/costco-potatoes.png" alt="Costco cart"></p>

<p>That’s a lot of potatoes! The berries are for my son, Luke, for him to eat with yogurt and breakfast for the next two weeks. Not pictured is the bottles of the sparkling water I got to enhance my diet this week.</p>



<p>If you don’t want to see me shirtless, it’s time to close the page. My starting stats on 11/20/2020 are: 335 LBS, but the offical, diet starting stats are: 333.4 lbs, BMI of 41.7. I’ll be updating this blog with progress, but here’s to my weightloss and success.</p>

<p>I’m off to eat more potatoes!</p>

<p><img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/11272020-front.png" alt="front"> 
<img src="http://www.adambourg.com/assets/img/potato-diet-posts/11272020-side.png" alt="side"></p>



      
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.adambourg.com/fat/lifestyle/health/fitness/potato-diet/2020/11/28/I-am-not-fat.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25251082</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:49:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[And this world’s a fickle measure]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 67 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25250968">thread link</a>) | @jseliger
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-12060">
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>They told me, “You have to watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rhThso-PE_o">this interview where Mike Tyson talks about medieval history</a>,” and so I did, and there he was at the New York Public Library in 2013 being interviewed by curator Paul Holdengräber, whose German accent strikes the American ear as both effortlessly intellectual and lightly amusing, and who would seem to have nothing in common with the face-tattooed boxer.</p>



<p><img data-attachment-id="12067" data-permalink="https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11-57-11-pm-copy/" data-orig-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" data-orig-size="1816,934" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Screen Shot 2020-11-28 at 11.57.11 PM copy" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg?w=863" src="https://quidplurablog.files.wordpress.com/2020/11/screen-shot-2020-11-28-at-11.57.11-pm-copy.jpg" alt=""></p>



<p>The two men do, in fact, find much to talk about. Their discussion is mesmerizing, because to most of us Mike Tyson is nothing but a face and fists, not a man who reflects aloud and at length about his inner life. Holdengräber prompts a reticent Tyson to narrate clips of his greatest moments in the ring, and newcomers to boxing will easily see why Tyson was such a sensation, but Iron Mike grows more animated when other matters arise.</p>



<p>Half an hour into the interview, Holdengräber says that their mutual friend, eccentric German filmmaker Werner Herzog, urged him to ask Tyson why he’s so fascinated by Clovis, the founder of the Merovingian Frankish dynasty, and Pepin the Short, the first Carolingian king of the Franks. Tyson’s answer, however halting, makes him come alive: </p>



<blockquote><p>I don’t know—it all comes from my insecurity from being poor, and not having enough—to be insecure, and being—yeah, that’s what it is: obscure. I never wanted to be obscure. I was born in obscurity and I never wanted to deal with that again, never wanted to be that. And they came from obscurity.</p></blockquote>



<p>Tyson then narrates a capsule history of the Frankish kings. He rambles, he doesn’t get all the details right, and his mispronunciation of names marks him as an autodidact, but it’s a shame to hear the audience laugh when Holdengräber asks, “Mike, how do you know all this shit?” Whether Tyson is mapping his own experiences onto medieval history or hearing echoes of the Franks in his troubled life, the credentialed, status-conscious audience is uncomfortable with his sincere interest in a past they find trivial.</p>



<p>Yet Tyson is the real deal, a book lover not because his peer group yaks about whichever author the <em>New York Times</em> has dubbed fame’s latest love child, but because he’s hungry for ideas, for meaning, for connections across time. He speaks with undisguised emotion about Cus D’Amato, the trainer and manager who turned him into a lethal boxer. Obsessed with Nietzsche and Clausewitz, D’Amato taught Tyson to see boxing as war and war as the key to decoding the world. “That is just what I do,” Tyson explains, an attentive pupil and dutiful son. “I love war. I love the act of war. I love the players in war, the philosophy of war.”</p>



<p>Tyson is searching for more than war on the pages of the past. Having grown up amid crime and chaos and founded his life on violence, he now relies on books to make moral and ethical sense of the world:</p>



<blockquote><p>Yeah—they’re our most priceless possessions, because if you think about it, you know, a room without a book is like a body without a soul. It’s the only way that we can connect the future with the past. Without that, there’s no way that we can know about the future, and know about particularly the past, or the present, you know, that when you think about history, the value of history is not necessarily scientific but moral. By liberating our minds and deepening our sympathies and fortifying our will, we can control—pretty much history allows us to control not society but ourselves, which is a much more important thing to do, you know what I mean? And it would allow us to pretty much meet the future more so than foretell it, and for that reason alone, in order to predict the future we always have to look through the past, because very rarely does time not repeat itself, and it always will repeat itself. </p><p>I’ve heard a quote before in a book that we would be fools to think historically that the past is us in funny clothes, but the past <em><span>is</span></em> us in funny clothes, and that’s truly what it is. That’s from somebody who really said a really profound statement but he misquoted what he was saying, he must have been saying it backwards, because that’s really what the past was, it’s just us in funny clothes, in different times, that’s really what it is.</p></blockquote>



<p>Of course, to hear Tyson cite <a href="http://thecampvs.com/2011/08/03/cicero-on-books-and-the-soul/">a quip inaccurately attributed to Cicero</a>, “a room without books is like a body without a soul,” is to wonder if he’s putting us on. Late in the interview, he jokes that if you quote books, you fool people into thinking you’re smart—but Tyson, for all his malapropisms and mispronunciations and odd mannerisms, <em>is</em> intelligent. He’s going round after round with big questions that  many of the ostensibly educated attendees at his book-talk don’t bother to ask.</p>



<p>When Holdengräber suggests that Tyson’s knowledge of history didn’t improve his behavior, Tyson calmly disagrees. He compares himself to the fictional Ben-Hur, a fellow athlete and celebrity who achieved glory but was doomed to be unfree until he set his priorities in order: “He may not have been famous again,” Tyson points out, “but he got his family, and that was his success.” </p>



<p>After listening to Mike Tyson—childhood criminal, devastating fighter, struggling alcoholic and recovering drug addict, convicted rapist, pop-culture eidolon—speak for an hour and a half, I still don’t quite know who he is. He may be the closest thing 21st-century America has to <a href="https://quidplura.com/2011/11/03/but-the-answers-you-seek-will-never-be-found-at-home/">a Robert E. Howard character</a>, a born barbarian who’s ignorant of social niceties but possesses earned wisdom that the civilization around him disdains. I don’t know whether he’s all in on his bookish pursuits or one slight away from again gnawing off someone’s ear. Whether he’s a good man or a bad man feels foolish to ask about a professional punch-thrower who reads Nietzsche, but Tyson looks like a <em>better</em> man, one who has perhaps searched harder for his humanity than the onlookers snickering from the safety of their library seats. What has their pride gained them? Tyson’s, by contrast, has brought him perspective, and with it the humility to admit that his story is still being written—and has been before.</p>




			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	
	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://quidplura.com/2020/11/29/and-this-worlds-a-fickle-measure/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25250968</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Recruiters and Human Traffickers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 32 | Comments 23 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249818">thread link</a>) | @Danieru
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article>

<p>Japan's <a href="http://www.japaneselawtranslation.go.jp/law/detail_main?id=10&amp;vm=2&amp;re=">Employment Security Act</a> requires a recruitment business to obtain a license. Failure to do so can result in imprisonment of up to a year. While I've met sleazy recruiters, sending them to prison seems a tad excessive to me. Curious about why the industry is so harshly regulated, I started digging. This took me into the seemingly dry but surprisingly interesting topic of the history of recruitment in Japan. As virtually nothing about this is written in English, I'm sharing what I found.</p>

<h2 id="japans-first-employment-agency">Japan’s first employment agency</h2>

<p>The earliest account of an employment agency in Japan comes from the mid-Seventeenth century. <a href="http://shokugyo-kyokai.or.jp/shiryou/gyouseishi/01-1.html">Keian Yamato</a> was a doctor who was sometimes asked by his patients to introduce servants or help arrange marriages. He was compensated for these introductions, and eventually this side business grew so successful that it overtook his medical practice. In 1652, he quit his job as a doctor to focus on his introduction business instead. So much so was his early fame, that early employment agencies were called “Keian” after him.</p>

<p>Keian’s agency and others got started at that point in Japanese history because the economic conditions were right for them. For an employment agency to be a viable business, there needs to be both a large supply of people seeking employment, and employers seeking labor. By mid-Seventeenth century Japan, such a market for labor was flourishing in response to a shift in Japanese society that had started with the dawn of the Edo Period, fifty years earlier.</p>

<h2 id="the-labour-market-in-the-edo-period">The labour market in the Edo Period</h2>

<p>The Edo period started in 1603 when <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tokugawa_Ieyasu">Ieyasu Tokugawa</a> officially assumed control of Japan. Before he came to power, for the last century and a half, Japan had been in a state of near-constant civil war, leading to much of the country struggling to recover from the ongoing conflict.</p>

<p>Ieyasu chose Edo, modern day Tokyo, to be the center of his government and country. Previous to this, the political and cultural center was located in western Japan, and Edo and the surrounding region had been economically underdeveloped. But Ieyasu enacted policies that encouraged the urbanization of Edo, transforming it from a small castle town with only one hundred houses to a bustling metropolis of over 250,000 people by 1650.</p>

<p>Not only did Ieyasu pursue urbanization of Edo, but his policies encouraged it throughout Japan. The government divided all of Japan into specific regions, granting each to a local Daimyo, a powerful feudal lord, who built their own castles surrounded by Samurai residences. This lead to a growth in the number of artisans and merchants, who in turn needed staff, creating new employment opportunities.</p>

<p>Further driving demand for labour was the government policy of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sankin-k%C5%8Dtai">Sankin-kōtai</a>, which required Daimyo to alternate living between their holdings and Edo on a yearly basis, in an attempt to prevent them from gaining too much power. As it was infeasible for Daimyos to relocate their entire household to Edo, this led to a demand for temporary staff.</p>

<p>Simultaneously, Edo saw a large influx of job seekers. Traditionally in Japan, the eldest son inherited everything: the family name, business, and any assets. Other children were seen as a burden, particularly for poor families. Struggling families practiced “Kuchi-berashi”, literally translated as reducing the number of mouths, where they would place their children to work elsewhere. As Edo flourished, many second sons and daughters of poor rural families journeyed there in search of employment.</p>

<p>Not only did children seek employment in Edo, but so did adults. Often these were people from farming villages who were cast out by their family, or samurai who became masterless after their leader fell in battle.</p>

<p>As these job seekers didn’t have local connections, they sought out someone who could make introductions. With the burgeoning employment market, recruiting as a profession was born in Japan.</p>

<h2 id="employment-in-the-edo-period">Employment in the Edo period</h2>

<p>Employment is a relationship where an employer pays an employee for work. While this has been one type of relationship, there are others where people perform work without receiving compensation, such as slavery or indentured servitude. In the Edo Period, the division between compensated and forced labor was ambiguous, with the term <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%A5%89%E5%85%AC">Hōkō</a>, roughly translated as “service” or “apprenticeship”, used to refer to a wide range of employment-like relationships.</p>

<p>The most straightforward kind of Hōkō was temporary labor, where a person tended to be paid daily. Another form was a long term contract of a year or more to work for a samurai house. With this contract, they were usually paid on a monthly or yearly basis, however the salary itself was low as they were also provided room and board while working for the family.</p>

<p>Unpaid apprenticeships also fall under the term Hōkō, whereby a person would work for an artisan or merchant to learn the business. While they usually wouldn’t be directly paid for their work, the expectation was that their previous employer would sponsor their new business.</p>

<p>Children could also be placed out to work under a Hōkō agreement, where they would often learn a craft while being given food, clothes, and a place to live, but not be directly financially compensated. The parents of the children would be given what was effectively an interest free loan: they’d get a lump sum payment when the child started the apprenticeship, which they’d need to pay back when it ended.</p>

<p>While Hōkō tended to refer to agreements of fixed duration, it also encompasses a slavery-like relationship, whereby a whole family was born to serve a wealthy family for their entire life. Near the beginning of the Edo period, this form of permanent Hōkō was banned, and restricted to a fixed period instead (a maximum of 3 years in 1616, but extended it to 10 years in 1625).</p>

<h2 id="recruiter-or-human-trafficker">Recruiter or human trafficker?</h2>

<p>In modern parlance, just like there is a clear divide between employment and forced labour, there is also a clear divide between recruiters who perform employment matchmaking, and human traffickers who provide uncompensated labourers to employers. In the Edo period, the difference between these two professions was murkier than it is today.</p>

<p>For instance, when children ventured into Edo in search of employment and didn’t have any local connections, they would sometimes make use of a local recruiter. These recruiters would sign a contract on behalf of the parents with an employer. While some of these were benevolent, it was easy for them to be exploitative, and force the children to take jobs with poor working conditions.</p>

<p>During this period, the government also established special regions called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Y%C5%ABkaku">Yukaku</a>, which became the only legal area to practice prostitution. The government saw Yukaku as a way of maintaining public order and collecting taxes. To ensure a steady stream of new prostitutes, the government allowed the “apprenticing” of young girls into prostitution. Unlike normal apprenticeships though, where the parents needed to pay back the “loan” that they received, the girl herself became responsible for paying it back. The amount the parents received was so much though, that even if the girl worked her entire life as a prostitute, she could never pay off the debt. The only way out was to have a wealthy man buy out her remaining debt, and become his mistress. Some recruiters took advantage of Yukaku, and effectively bought young girls from poor families in rural areas and sold them to brothels.</p>

<h2 id="first-steps-towards-regulation-of-recruitment">First steps towards regulation of recruitment</h2>

<p>In 1867, the Tokugawa shogunate was finally toppled, ushering in a new era in Japanese history, referred to as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meiji_(era)">the Meiji period</a>. Whereas the previous government had maintained an isolationist stance, the new government embraced western technology and culture, seeking to modernize the country before it was subjugated by western powers.</p>

<p>As part of this modernization, the government abolished the strict class system that divided Japanese into Samurai, peasants, artisans, and merchants, declaring that everyone who had been peasants, artisans, and merchants to be equal. People who were formerly Samurai and Daimyo however were still granted a status as nobles.</p>

<p>With this move modernity, the government sought to regulate the recruiting industry. In 1872, they introduced a requirement that recruiters be licensed and have a guarantor. They also limited the fee a recruiter could receive to be a maximum of 5% of the salary of the introduced employee. This fee was paid by both the employee and employer.</p>

<h2 id="international-attempts-to-ban-private-employment-agencies">International attempts to ban private employment agencies</h2>

<p>As part of the Treaty of Versailles that ended World War I, <a href="https://www.ilo.org/global/about-the-ilo/history/lang--en/index.htm">the International Labour Organization (ILO)</a> was founded to advance social and economic justice through setting international labour standards.</p>

<p>At their very first meeting in 1919, the ILO called on its members to establish free public employment agencies and move towards banning fee charging agencies. As a member of the ILO, Japan created a new law, which required municipal governments to establish public employment agencies and introduced stricter requirements for private employment agencies. While there had been 9,712 private agencies in 1926, the number dwindled to 2,541 by 1934.</p>

<p>The new regulation of the industry also saw stronger controls against unethical recruitment, such as using exaggerated or false claims to recruit people, forcing applications, recruiting women to be prostitutes, blocking applicants’ freedom, and so on.</p>

<p>In April 1938, the public employment agencies that had been operated at a local level were nationalized with a new law. This law also banned private agencies, except for some of the existing agencies, which were allowed to continue while facing even stricter regulations. Many of the private agencies who were banned merged into the national agency. The driving factor for this nationalization was not human rights though, but rather a response to a rapid increase in …</p></article></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/">https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tokyodev.com/2020/10/01/recruiting-in-japan/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249818</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 01:19:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[It’s time to remove news from Facebook and Google]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 46 | Comments 34 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249414">thread link</a>) | @anaxana
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
                <div>
                    <p>Pay up -- or we’re pulling the plug. </p><p>That’s the approach the news industry should take when it comes to Google and Facebook: Pay for our journalism or we’re banning it from your platforms. </p><p>For too long, journalists have given away their stories for free in exchange for distribution by the duopoly. At best, a story may go viral (rare) or hit the SEO lottery and experience a one-off traffic surge (unsustainable). </p><p>And for that, newsrooms have willingly handed over <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/06/09/business/media/google-news-industry-antitrust.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share">billions of dollars</a> in ad revenue to the tech giants that <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2018/02/03/facebooks-siren-call/">threaten</a> their very existence. (Google and Facebook are No. 1 and No. 2 <a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/technology/facebook-ad-revenue-2019-2020">ad platforms</a> in the U.S., respectively).</p><p>The news industry as a whole needs to come together and demand to be fairly compensated for their contributions. Until Facebook and Google agree to pay up, they are simply exploiting journalism under the pretext of democratizing information. </p><p>News drives habit. Habit drives frequency. And frequency drives time spent. In the attention economy (read: ad-driven), news content entices people to come back and stay in platforms’ carefully crafted ecosystems. </p><p>In short, platforms need news. </p><p>Mark Zuckerberg said it himself when Facebook launched its news tab in 2019 (its most recent olive branch to publishers). In a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/25/opinion/sunday/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-news.html">piece for the<em> New York Times</em></a>, the Facebook founder pledged to “support the news industry” and said that journalism today is “more important than ever.” But only <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2019/10/23/facebook-offer-news-tab-users-pay-some-publishers-their-work/">some of the 200+ publishers</a> involved in the news tab were actually paid for their contributions. &nbsp;</p><p>These platforms are simply using their high-minded mission statements (e.g. Facebook: To “give people the power to build community and bring the world closer together” and Google: To “organize the world’s information”) as a thuggish pretext for exploiting journalism. </p><p>Instead, they should pay a licencing fee or provide a sizable cut of ad revenue to newsrooms that are populating the platforms (Murdoch analogized this to a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/jan/22/rupert-murdoch-facebook-should-pay-news-publishers">carriage fee</a>). &nbsp;</p><p>It’s not enough for them to attempt damage control by <a href="https://www.niemanlab.org/2020/06/google-paying-publishers-is-more-about-pr-than-the-needs-of-the-news-industry/">spinning up funds</a> claiming to help journalism or offering some – but not all – publishers fees for their contributions. (If you want to know how Google really feels about paying for news, see <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/google-news/google-to-shut-down-news-site-in-spain-over-copyright-fees-idUSL1N0TV0S520141211">how they treated publishers</a> in Spain).</p><p>That’s why we’re building <a href="https://www.forthapp.com/?utm_source=nillium&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;utm_campaign=frontpage">Forth</a>, a news-first platform that pays journalists for their work and offers the audience concise updates with context -- from the reporters they trust. All revenue generated on Forth is shared with our news partners. </p><p>We only allow trusted and credible journalists (vetted by our editorial team) to publish to the platform. It's a one-stop shop for accurate information about what's happening right now. &nbsp;</p><p>It’s one thing for Facebook and Google to out-innovate a slow-to-adapt industry -- it’s another to profit off of the same industry's work with impunity. </p><p>Newsrooms should be mad as hell -- and they don’t have to take it anymore. </p><p>Let’s Go Forth, </p><p>-- Xana</p><p><br><em>Xana O'Neill is the Co-Founder of Forth, a platform for concise updates with context from the reporters you trust.</em></p>
                </div>
            </section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.nillium.com/its-time-to-remove-news-from-facebook-and-google/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249414</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:14:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Coup-Proofing the Startup]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 21 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249332">thread link</a>) | @harporoeder
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>In the middle of an actual, like, actual workplace coup with secret meetings, purges, puppetmasters, frame-ups, leak investigations, and (rumored) slack DM surveillance, I was listening to the bombshell podcast and heard about this book about coup-proofing, and how it ruins teams.
I picked up a copy, and this year I read it.</p>

<p>The book (Caitlin Talmadge / <a href="https://www.cornellpress.cornell.edu/book/9781501700293/the-dictators-army">The Dictator’s Army</a>) is about how coup fears hamstrung management in two wars:
Saddam Hussein’s 8-year failed invasion of Iran, and South Vietnam’s final defense against the North.
This article is about private sector leadership lessons I took from the book.</p>

<p>Writing about private sector leadership on the eve of a plausible military coup seems like peeing into the ocean, but it’s this or doomscrolling and holding in your pee can kill you.</p>

<p>Most management books are aspirational and map out success.
This one is about repeated failure, despite great funding, first-mover advantage and better equipment, through repeated mistakes, and in the public eye.
Nothing that I would know anything about cough.</p>

<p>Startups sub 30 people have a hard time accessing experienced hires who combine domain skill and the ability to work on a team.
There are real reasons for this, and some boil down to something like Saddam’s coup fears.
But if our society plans to continue airlifting cash into small companies, onboarding good middle managers earlier can make more of these bets pay off.</p>

<p>If you prefer a soundtrack, play this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=thbICk05yPk">masterclass on management</a> (from GI Joe’s Cobra Commander) in the background.
It sometimes gets me through the week.</p>

<ol id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#despots-meddle" id="markdown-toc-despots-meddle">Despots meddle</a></li>
  <li><a href="#managing-up" id="markdown-toc-managing-up">Managing up</a></li>
  <li><a href="#demotions-temporary-and-permanent" id="markdown-toc-demotions-temporary-and-permanent">Demotions, temporary and permanent</a></li>
  <li><a href="#combined-arms" id="markdown-toc-combined-arms">Combined arms</a></li>
  <li><a href="#some-people-out-there-dont-have-maps" id="markdown-toc-some-people-out-there-dont-have-maps">Some people out there don’t <em>have</em> maps</a></li>
  <li><a href="#the-butchers-bill" id="markdown-toc-the-butchers-bill">The butcher’s bill</a></li>
  <li><a href="#professional-silence" id="markdown-toc-professional-silence">Professional silence</a></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="despots-meddle">Despots meddle</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>Despotism is a legitimate mode of government in dealing with barbarians, provided the end be their improvement, and the means justified by actually effecting that end.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>Liberty, as a principle, has no application to any state of things anterior to the time when mankind have become capable of being improved by free and equal discussion.
– JS Mill</p>
</blockquote>

<p>By inference, if you’re not hiring barbarians and / or they don’t need improvement, or your team is capable of discussion, consider a lighter-weight leadership style.</p>

<p>‘Despot’ also means bronze age feudal landowners or the heir apparent of Byzantium, but we haven’t had those for a while.
Adaptive reuse of the term in revolutionary France gave the term its modern meaning:
an absolute ruler who governs without restraint by the law.
See also ‘frondeur’.</p>

<p>When growing teams take on more complex goals but don’t update their management, they encounter pathologies of delegation –
senior leadership who isn’t sure how to solve problems using middle managers, who give them the wrong length leash.
This is the 10 person to 30 person growth spurt.
Good companies outgrow it this <em>if</em> they survive.</p>

<p>Here’s what that looked like in Iraq:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>decision-making at the senior levels of the Iraqi military revolved more around the fear of what Saddam might do than what the Iranians might do.<sup id="fnref:senior-fear" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:senior-fear">1</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>by the middle of the war, Saddam was making a serious effort to inform himself about military matters in order to understand what was happening. However, Saddam was the only decision maker,<sup id="fnref:educate" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:educate">2</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Technocratic middle managers were spending most of their energy undoing their leader’s bad decisions, rather than fighting and winning.
There’s a spectrum between ‘own worst enemy’ and ‘annoying bandwidth bottleneck’, but new managers generally are on it somewhere.</p>

<p>Over-centralization of authority sends a message that people shouldn’t act on their own, which paralyzes your org.
Note that I’m not arguing against hierarchical authority or a clear chain of command, but rather against authority all concentrating at the top, making it impossible for middle managers to do their jobs.
In Vietnam:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>few officers who had come up in the Diem system were willing to do anything “in the absence of detailed orders.”<sup id="fnref:detailed" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:detailed">3</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Centralization also hamstrings the flexibility of a large team to adapt to new information.
Top leaders, often lacking domain skill or up-to-date information, are best at ‘do nothing without asking me’ orders that trap middle managers in bad positions.
In one case:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Because Saddam had decreed that units were not allowed to cede any ground, the Iraqi defense was poorly coordinated and ineffective, eventually inducing panic.<sup id="fnref:panic" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:panic">4</a></sup> …
Iraqi officers in the field lacked the authority to redeploy forward troops or to call on reserves.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>And because the dictators aren’t an expert in any part of the organization, lack the attention to focus on everything at once, and aren’t accountable to anyone, they have zero memory.
In one case in Vietnam, President Thieu’s personal intervention not only disrupted the existing strategy, but he had forgotten by the next day that he’d given the order.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>sudden change in orders from an uninformed Thieu was a disaster, resulting in neither a robust defense of the city nor a clean withdrawal.<sup id="fnref:sudden-change" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:sudden-change">6</a></sup> … Amazingly … Hue’s abandonment apparently came as a surprise to President Thieu<sup id="fnref:abandonment" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:abandonment">7</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Unaccountable, illogical plans from inexpert leaders create hills to die on, in some cases literally.
They also come through unusual channels (because hands-on leaders prioritize fast action).
Unusual channels = coordination and preparation impossible for middle managers.
In one case in South Vietnam, a general:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>personally interceded at all levels, sometimes going so far as to personally issue orders by radio to individual brigade commanders without notifying the division operations center. Both Giai and his division advisers often learned of new orders only as they were being carried out.<sup id="fnref:all-levels" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:all-levels">8</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>By comparison, the North Vietnamese had good delegation and sane command structures in place.
From an internal document, they valued:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“unanimity of thought from the top to the bottom regarding the opportunity we faced and the tactics to be employed” but significant room for commanders to execute their plans<sup id="fnref:unanimity" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:unanimity">9</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>After the American revolution, George III was having a conversation with his American portraitist Benjamin West; he heard Washington was going to resign his commission and ‘return to his farm’.
The King was like ‘ha pull the other one’, recognizing that giving up power is very hard, and said something like ‘<em>if</em> he does it I take back everything I said about the guy.’
The point is that accepting the limits to authority is hard, but also critical for good leaders.</p>

<h2 id="managing-up">Managing up</h2>

<p>One of the lessons of 2020 is probably that sometimes the only person in the room who can stop a bad outcome is a middle manager,
and often they can only do it by managing up, not through direct action.</p>

<p>Middle managers are frequently in situations where their domain skills are better than senior leadership –
either because they’re technocrats with domain skills,
or because they’re dealing with the problem day-to-day and have better information, or both.</p>

<p>We still get shouted down a lot, resulting in waste:
of money, of time, of resources, of opportunities, of morale.
In a war it can be lives.</p>

<p>We speak out a few times but eventually converge to inaction as your <a href="https://danluu.com/wat/">wtfs trail off</a>.
We give up because we’re tired, but that’s not all of it:
We stop arguing because when a leader experiences argument as dissent, their reactions are unpredictable and poison the team.</p>

<p>The way around this way of thinking is to
(1) make very sure that you’re very right when you pick a fight with your boss,
(2) fight for better delegation, not just a correct decision this one time.
And (3) remember that if you succeed, things get permanently better; these are hard fights but companies need them to grow.</p>

<p>Middle managers are the only people who have the authority and connections to fight these fights.
That’s why they leak, that’s why they manage up.
The organization will fail if we don’t.
Employees depend on companies to put food on the table; you do have a moral obligation to help your employer not fail (if you can) (barring circumstances like if <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hn1VxaMEjRU">you’ve looked at these caps recently</a>).</p>

<p>I saw a <a href="https://twitter.com/FutureDocs/status/938173926953443328">JAMA article</a> about ‘professional silence’ by doctors.
Silence is not golden when an important argument is being suppressed.</p>

<p>Senior technocrats have a surprising amount of power when they align their story and band together. For Saddam, years into the war:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Iraqi generals blamed Saddam’s military organizational practices for both sets of losses, raising a serious danger of overthrow from within<sup id="fnref:blame" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:blame">10</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Because his leadership style was in conflict with their technical skills.
He punished losses in ways that deterred ground commanders from requesting backup, creating a losing cycle:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Saddam put great pressure on Iraqi commanders on the ground to avoid losses, which led them not to report failures. Withholding losses from reports and thus not receiving reinforcements or other support left commanders in impossible combat conditions. However, this was better than reporting their failures and suffering execution.<sup id="fnref:pressure" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:pressure">11</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The command-and-control system was incapable of transmitting the true tactical situation. Senior Iraqi officers later noted that they often got more timely information from the media than they did from their own commanders at the front.<sup id="fnref:media" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:media">12</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>In Vietnam, General Phu, a technocrat middle manager who had been brought in to fix the South Vietnamese army’s problems, tried to use his authority to salvage a bad campaign and was talked down.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Phu, who previously had enjoyed an excellent reputation as commander of the 1st Division, expressed grave reservations about the operation to those around him, complaining that he had done it only because of Thieu’s order<sup id="fnref:reservations" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:reservations">13</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<p>President Thieu’s realtime intervention, leading to a bad loss, demoralized him and he was never able to lead again:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Thieu’s absurd order to withdraw immediately from the Central Highlands essentially caused another corps commander, General Phu, …</p></blockquote></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html">https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abe-winter.github.io/book/review/2020/06/04/dictators-army.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249332</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:03:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Keep Data Consistency During Database Migration]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25249208">thread link</a>) | @wb14123
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.binwang.me/2020-11-29-Keep-Data-Consistency-During-Database-Migration.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.binwang.me/2020-11-29-Keep-Data-Consistency-During-Database-Migration.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="article_content">
<article id="post">
  <header>
    
    
      <p>Posted on 29 Nov 2020, tagged <code>database</code><code>distributed system</code><code>consistency</code></p>
    
  </header>

  <p>When a system has been live for a long time, it’s not rare to use newer technologies to improve performance, maintainability, or add new features. One of such changes can be which database to use. This can be the most difficult kind of change. During the migration, there are two data sources, which makes it a distributed system. Make data consistent under a distributed system is very hard and can easily go wrong. In this article, we will explore a way to keep the data consistent during the migration, and maintain a low downtime at the same time.</p>

<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>

<p>There are some requirements in order to use the way described in this article:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The source database support capture data change (CDC) method like MySQL bin log.</li>
  <li>The source database can be dumped with a consistent view and mark the position in data change logs.</li>
  <li>The target database support ACID transactions.</li>
  <li>Both source and target database support read and write permission control.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="steps">Steps</h2>

<p>There are two basic ideas behind the steps:</p>

<ol>
  <li>The clients only write to one of the databases at a given time. So we can avoid distributed transaction which is error prone and slow.</li>
  <li>We make the switch of database by setup the database permissions. It’s faster than switch from client code and easier to make sure to switch all the clients.</li>
</ol>

<p>Here are the detailed steps:</p>

<h3 id="1-dump-the-source-database-to-target-database">1. Dump the source database to target database</h3>

<p>First, we need to dump the source database with a consistent view. And mark the position we’ve dumped. For example, in MySQL, you can use <code>mysqldump</code> with <code>--master-data</code> to dump the database with a bin log position. (<a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/mysqldump.html#option_mysqldump_master-data">Document about the usage</a>). After we get all the data from source database, we can insert them into the target database.</p>

<p>Since this is the first step, it’s very easy to handle failure: just start again from beginning. So it’s very important to capture any error while import the dumped data.</p>

<h3 id="2-capture-changes-from-source-to-target">2. Capture changes from source to target</h3>

<p>The next step is to use the capture data changes from the source database. For example, in MySQL, you can use <a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/8.0/en/binary-log.html">bin log</a> to capture the changes and insert them to the target database. Since we have the start position from last step, we know where to start parse and import the changes.</p>

<p>It’s very important to keep order of the changes while importing. So it’s better to use only one process to parse and import the changes. This part is challenging: the performance matters here. <strong>The time to sync all the changes is the downtime we need for migration</strong>.</p>

<p>We also need to make sure we don’t miss any changes or import any changes multiple times even there are system failures. So it’s very important to record the change log position. It’s convenience to write the position into the target database with the same transaction that imports the data. So the position will be synced with the data we imported.</p>

<h3 id="3-deny-writes-to-the-target-database-from-clients">3. Deny writes to the target database from clients</h3>

<p>The easy way to keep data consistency is to have a single source of truth. Until now, we are using the source database as the source of truth and sync changes to the target database. We don’t want to mess up the target database with other writes. So we need to setup the target database permission to deny all the writes from clients. For example, in MySQL, you can grant only <code>select</code> permission to the table for the clients and deny other operations. We allow the read permission so that we can compare the read results at the next step.</p>

<h3 id="4-modify-the-clients-to-read-and-write-both-databases">4. Modify the clients to read and write both databases</h3>

<p>The next step is to make the clients to read and write both source and target databases.</p>

<p>We want to read/write source database first. Use this result if there is no permission error, use the read/write result from target database otherwise.</p>

<p>The read/write to target database has two purposes:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Before switch to the target database, we can verify the target database works as expected by compare read results and write operations. Note that the target database may have lag to sync up, so the results may not always the same. But we can have an understanding of the correctness based on the percentage of same results.</li>
  <li>After we switch to the target database, the read/write results will be used as the real results.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>If you want to make sure the target database can handle the load, it’s a good idea to allow read/write to the target database for a while .But it’s just as a verification, the data in the target database will not be consistent after that. So after we verify the target database can handle the traffic, we need to cleanup the target database and start from step 1 again.</strong> (We don’t need to modify the client code during the steps).</p>

<p>For the error handling, there are two key points:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Only use target database result if there is permission error from source database. Throw other errors from source database.</li>
  <li>Ignore errors for the target database if the result is not used but make sure to log them, so that it will not affect the current operation while also make sure we don’t have errors before the switch.</li>
</ol>

<p>The client code would be like this:</p>

<div><div>
  <div><pre><span> <a href="#n1" name="n1">1</a></span>db_operation() {
<span> <a href="#n2" name="n2">2</a></span>  try {
<span> <a href="#n3" name="n3">3</a></span>    source_result = source_db_operation()
<span> <a href="#n4" name="n4">4</a></span>  } catch (PermissionException e) {
<span> <a href="#n5" name="n5">5</a></span>    return target_db_operation()
<span> <a href="#n6" name="n6">6</a></span>  }
<span> <a href="#n7" name="n7">7</a></span>  async {
<span> <a href="#n8" name="n8">8</a></span>    // do the following things async so it will not impact the performance
<span> <a href="#n9" name="n9">9</a></span>    try {
<span><strong><a href="#n10" name="n10">10</a></strong></span>      target_result = target_db_operation()
<span><a href="#n11" name="n11">11</a></span>      compare_result(source_result, target_result)
<span><a href="#n12" name="n12">12</a></span>    } catch (Exception e) {
<span><a href="#n13" name="n13">13</a></span>      log_error(e)
<span><a href="#n14" name="n14">14</a></span>    }
<span><a href="#n15" name="n15">15</a></span>  }
<span><a href="#n16" name="n16">16</a></span>  return source_result
<span><a href="#n17" name="n17">17</a></span>}
</pre></div>
</div>
</div>

<h3 id="5-deny-access-to-the-source-database-from-clients-and-wait-for-changes-to-by-synced">5. Deny access to the source database from clients and wait for changes to by synced</h3>

<p>After we are confident with the read and write to the target database, we can make the switch. We switch the database by change the database permissions. First, we deny all the access to the source database from clients. Then we wait for the changes to be full synced to the target database. During this time, the system is down. So how fast the changes are synced from source database to target database determines how much down time it will be.</p>

<h3 id="6-allow-write-to-target-database">6. Allow write to target database</h3>

<p>After the target database is fully synced, we can enable the target database permission for all the clients. After this, the system should be online again and the database is fully switched over.</p>

<h3 id="7-optional-fallback-to-source-database-if-anything-goes-wrong">7. Optional: Fallback to source database if anything goes wrong</h3>

<p>It’s good if everything works well so far. But that may not always the case. Maybe the target database cannot handle the new traffic (that’s why it’s important to test it in step 4). In this case, we need fallback to the source database.</p>

<p>If it’s fine to lost committed data during the migration time, it would be relatively easy to fallback:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Allow access to the source database. After this, the clients should be using the source database again.</li>
  <li>Cleanup the target database and start from the beginning.</li>
</ol>

<p>If it’s critical to save the committed data and make sure they are consistent, then before step 5, we should setup a mechanism to capture changes from target database to source database, and mark the change position after step 6. Then the fallback steps would be:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Deny all the writes to target database.</li>
  <li>Sync from target database to source database (make sure to stop it after fully synced).</li>
  <li>Allow access to the source database.</li>
  <li>Cleanup the target database and start from the beginning again.</li>
</ol>

<p>The sync from target database to source database is very dangerous and hard to test, so it’s really important to test the target database can handle the operations in step 4.</p>

<h3 id="8-cleanup-client-code">8. Cleanup client code</h3>

<p>Once the database is switched to the target database, we can cleanup the code that access the source database. Then the database is fully migrated and you can enjoin it!</p>

</article>







<!-- MathJax -->




</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.binwang.me/2020-11-29-Keep-Data-Consistency-During-Database-Migration.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25249208</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 23:43:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Making Playstation 1 Modchips (2018)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 91 | Comments 36 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248660">thread link</a>) | @cwaffles
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">
    <article>

        

        <section>
            <p>When I was young I owned a PlayStation 1 (PS1). It was one of the first, if not the first, game consoles I owned and it had a profound effect on my future. </p>

<p>I can trace the history of how I got involved in computers back to playing and modding video games. While I wasn't smart enough to mod game consoles when I was young, my dad wasn't bad at it. He modded my PS1 to have a little switch in the back that would allow it to play burnt games. They say the apple doesn't fall far from the tree. </p>

<p>Fast-forward to today and I no longer have my original PS1. I remember some games wouldn't load anymore and I had gotten a PS2. So why keep an old console? Turns out the answer is nostalgia and memories. You miss what you don't have anymore.</p>

<p>Recently a friend gifted me a PS1. And so then the journey begins, how do I mod this thing? </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you are looking for them I am selling <a href="http://rover.ebay.com/rover/1/711-53200-19255-0/1?icep_ff3=2&amp;pub=5575378759&amp;campid=5338273189&amp;customid=&amp;icep_item=223024408143&amp;ipn=psmain&amp;icep_vectorid=229466&amp;kwid=902099&amp;mtid=824&amp;kw=lg&amp;toolid=11111">flashed, prewired modchips</a>. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Very simply, the principles behind PS1 DRM work as follows:</p>

<ol>
<li>Sony baked (not the technical term) strings (i.e. <code>SCEA</code>, <code>SCEI</code>, <code>SCEE</code>, or in rare cases <code>SCEW</code>) into official PS1 games in locations which cannot be replicated by a regular reader. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XUwSOfQ1D3c">This video</a> and <a href="http://www.psxdev.net/forum/viewtopic.php?t=128">this post</a> discuss it reasonably well.  </li>
<li>The CD drive controller looks for those strings to identify a disc as official. Once the controller decides that the disc is/isn't official, the main CPU reads this decision and acts accordingly.  </li>
<li>If the string can't be found or is garbled, the PS1 knows the disc isn't an <strong>authentic</strong> PS1 game. However, because the PS1 needs to account for disc read errors, there's a good amount of leeway in what passes the authenticity check.  </li>
<li>Because region <small>(<strong>A</strong> for America, <strong>I</strong> for Japan, <strong>E</strong> for Europe, and <strong>W</strong> for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Net_Yaroze">Net Yaroze</a>)</small> as well as authenticity are rolled into one string, Sony kills two birds with one stone here and achieves region locking as well as copy protection. </li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you want a real in-depth discussion you can read <a href="http://www.oldcrows.net/mcc2.html">the original posts by The Old Crow</a> or the <a href="https://problemkaputt.de/psx-spx.htm#cdromprotectionmodchips">No$PSX documentation page</a> or this <a href="http://psx-scene.com/forums/f10/psx-modchip-faq-64110/">Modchip FAQ</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>PSX modchips work by electrically stifling the output originally generated by whatever CD is inside the drive and then injecting a new, faked signal into the CD microcontroller. This causes the PS1 to believe that whatever disc is inside is legitimate and proceed to boot up. </p>

<p>Later on Sony added more complicated checks like:</p>

<ul>
<li>Checking for the magic strings during the game instead of at boot </li>
<li>Changing the overall process to make it more difficult to bypass by simply emitting the correct strings.</li>
</ul>

<p>However, modern modchips already deal with this. Modchips that work under these updated circumstances are known as "stealth modchips" because the console shouldn't be able to detect them at all. </p>



<p>The first "open source" modchip was reverse engineered by a guy named "The Old Crow". Surprisingly, The Old Crow specializes in electronic music synthesizers, not hacking video game consoles. It's from his modchip that most other modchips are derived from in some sense. He originally reverse engineered a commercial PS1 modchip that was designed by a western engineer working for a Chinese company. </p>

<p>Today, there are three main modchips which are still used by the community today.</p>

<p>The modchips include:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide/mm3/">Multimode 3 (MM3)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide/mayumi-v4/">Mayumi v4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee">PSNee</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The three have their pros and cons but generally they can be summarized as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>MM3 is the most common PS1 modchip seen/used today. Its only real downside is that it uses an internal oscillator which can become out of sync with the oscillator used by the CD drive. If this happens you simply need to reboot your console to try reading again.  </p></li>
<li><p>Mayumi v4 attempts to use the oscillator used by the CD drive. This reduces the chance of the oscillator sync issue from happening; however, Mayumi v4 is considered a bit difficult to install. </p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee">PSNee</a> is an open source modchip originally written by <a href="https://assemblergames.com/threads/psnee-a-stealth-modchip-for-all-ps1-models.57907/">TheFrietMan</a>. Development on it was <a href="http://www.psxdev.net/forum/viewtopic.php?t=1262">later continued by others</a> and it appears to work rather well on all Playstation 1/PSOne models. Based on the code I believe it attempts to infer where the PS1 is in the boot process to begin injecting fake <code>SCEX</code> strings. Unfortunately PSNee is complicated to install. The provided diagrams are atrocious and nowhere near as simple as the available diagrams for MM3 and Mayumi. I worked out <a href="https://gist.github.com/ColdHeat/be633b7eb6e25758ec80ae0115c1887a">the pinout for the Attiny45</a> but I ended up going with MM3 and Mayumi because it's easier. </p></li>
</ul>



<blockquote>
  <p>If you want them I am selling <a href="http://rover.ebay.com/rover/1/711-53200-19255-0/1?icep_ff3=2&amp;pub=5575378759&amp;campid=5338273189&amp;customid=&amp;icep_item=223024408143&amp;ipn=psmain&amp;icep_vectorid=229466&amp;kwid=902099&amp;mtid=824&amp;kw=lg&amp;toolid=11111">flashed, prewired modchips</a>. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>It's generally pretty easy to make a PS1 modchip provided you have the right tools. In this tutorial we will focus on making MM3 or Mayumi v4 modchips.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>While I do have an Arduino, I prefer to use the MM3 and Mayumi chips over PSNee. If you want to make a PSNee modchip, you can follow the <a href="http://www.instructables.com/id/Program-an-ATtiny-with-Arduino/">instructions here</a> to flash the <a href="https://github.com/kalymos/PsNee/blob/master/PsNee.ino">.ino file</a> to your Attiny. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>You will need:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=PIC12F508+DIP">Microchip PIC12F508</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amzn.to/2tfdeP0">PICkit 3</a>
<ul><li>Also download and install <a href="http://www.microchip.com/mplab/mplab-x-ide">MPLAB IPE</a> from the MPLAB X IDE package. </li></ul></li>
<li>Some kind of <a href="https://amzn.to/2llKUG7">wiring &amp; breadboard</a> to connect the PIC to to the PICkit.</li>
<li>HEX codes for the modchip of your choice (provided below).</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Many tutorials call for the PIC12C508. This is an old model and continuing to use them is unnecessary unless you have them stockpiled. HEX codes that work for the 12C will work for the 12F. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>To begin you should first look your IC and determine which leg is which. The leg nearest the imprinted circle is Pin 1. The leg opposite it is Pin 8. </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/pic12f508-2.JPG" alt="This is a DIP chip. I accidentally got SOIC-8 (i.e. surface mount) and had to solder my chip to a breadboard but generally you can avoid that"></p>

<p>You can plug this into a bread board and then wire it into the Pickit according to the following diagrams. You want to match the following (the rest are unused for now):</p>

<ul>
<li>PICKit 1 ⟷ IC 4 (V<sub>PP</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 2 ⟷ IC 1 (V<sub>DD</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 3 ⟷ IC 8 (V<sub>SS</sub>)</li>
<li>PICKit 4 ⟷ IC 7 (ICSPDAT)</li>
<li>PICKit 5 ⟷ IC 6 (ICSPCLK)</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/pickit-12f508-1.jpg" alt="PICKit 3 on the left, PIC12F508 on the right"></p>

<p>Once you've properly wired up the chip, connect the PICKit to your computer and start MPLAB IPE. Under <code>Device</code> select <code>PIC12F508</code>. </p>

<p>Go into <code>Settings &gt; Advanced Mode</code>. The default password for <code>Advanced Mode</code> is <code>microchip</code>. I don't recommend changing it, not sure why the option is even available. </p>

<p>Go into the <code>Power</code> tab on the left and enable <code>Power Target Circuit from Tool</code>.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-8.39.15-PM.png" alt=""></p>

<p>Go back to the <code>Operate</code> tab and hit <code>Connect</code>.</p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-20-at-8.40.54-PM.png" alt=""></p>

<p>From here download the appropriate HEX code for your chip and console. They are different per console region. </p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3USA.HEX">MM3 for American Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3EUR.HEX">MM3 for European Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mm3/MM3JAP.HEX">MM3 for Japanese Consoles</a></li>
</ul>

<p>You can also use Mayumi v4 on the PIC12F508 if you choose.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-usa4.hex">MayumiV4 for American Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-eu4.hex">MayumiV4 for European Consoles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wiki/ColdHeat/PsNeePy/hexcodes/mayumiv4/mayumi-jap4.hex">MayumiV4 for Japanese Consoles</a></li>
</ul>

<p>In the <code>Source</code> file, select your hex code. </p>

<p>Hit the big <code>Program</code> button. </p>

<p>You should see something similar to the following text:</p>

<pre><code>2018-06-20 20:48:02 -0400 - Loading hex file. Please wait...  
Loading code from /Users/kchung/Repositories/PsNeePy.wiki/hexcodes/mm3/MM3USA.HEX...  
2018-06-20 20:48:03 -0400 - Hex file loaded successfully.

2018-06-20 20:48:20 -0400 - Programming...

Device Erased...

Programming...

The following memory area(s) will be programmed:  
program memory: start address = 0x0, end address = 0x1e7  
configuration memory  
Programming/Verify complete  
2018-06-20 20:48:25 -0400 - Programming complete  
</code></pre>

<p>If you'd like, you can hit the <code>Verify</code> button to make sure that your flash was correct. Your output should look something like the following:</p>

<pre><code>2018-06-20 20:50:10 -0400 - Verifying...

Verifying...

The following memory areas(s) will be verified:  
program memory: start address = 0x0, end address = 0x1ff  
configuration memory  
User Id Memory

Verification successful.  
2018-06-20 20:50:13 -0400 - Verify complete  
</code></pre>

<p>From here you can follow online diagrams for soldering your chip to the PSX that you own. I personally used <a href="https://quade.co/ps1-modchip-guide">William Quade's excellent diagrams</a> and think you should as well.   </p>



<p>While looking at all these modchips, I figured it would be nice to read and write Python code instead of Assembly and C code so I started working on porting PSNee to Python. </p>

<p>By using <a href="https://micropython.org/">MicroPython</a> and an <a href="https://amzn.to/2K4HdTq">ESP8266</a> we can actually create a modchip that we can remotely update and modify through the <a href="https://amzn.to/2K4HdTq">ESP8266</a>'s WiFi.  </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/IMG_1084.jpg" alt="Effectively the very first WiFi enabled PS1!"></p>

<p>In the above photo (SCPH-7501), the ESP8266 is on the top left with the headers face up. The wires connect to the headers and route under the CD drive to a breadboard on the bottom right. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The breadboard has wires that are soldered to the correct MM3 points and then labeled with the corresponding pin number. By using this breadboard I can test modchips that I make much faster than soldering to the board over and over again. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>My modchip (named PsNeePy) is available on Github: <br>
<a href="https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy">https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy</a></p>

<p>While my test console is quite bad at reading discs and the console rarely boots into games, the modchip does work. </p>

<blockquote>
  <p>For the most part (ignoring stealth functionality), modchips are known to be working once you reach the black Playstation logo screen as this indicates that the CPU considers the game authentic. </p>
</blockquote>

<p>However, because the code is based off an older version of PSNee, stealth functionality does not seem to work on some newer PS1 revisions.</p>

<p>I mostly created this as a proof of concept and I'm unlikely to maintain it very much. While I don't recommend using my modchip, I hope that the community adopts it and helps improve it. Despite being a dead console, the PSX community is fairly active. </p>

<p>With <a href="https://github.com/ColdHeat/PsNeePy">PsNeePy</a>, you can remotely update the ESP8266 over WiFi, debug remotely, and also reset the chip easily. Having spent many hours working on the PS1 at this point, a more modern experience is quite refreshing. </p>

<p><img src="https://blog.kchung.co/content/images/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-21-at-2.47.33-AM.png" alt="Remotely controlling the modchip"></p>

<p>Thanks to an anonymous friend for my PS1, Sharan for fixing my PS1, <a href="https://quade.co/">William Quade</a> for the excellent diagrams, AssemblerGames for having good information despite not accepting me into the forum, and PSXDEV for answering some of my questions.</p>
        </section>

        

    </article>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.kchung.co/making-playstation-modchips/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248660</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 22:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Run a Ponzi Scheme for Tech People]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 382 | Comments 187 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248563">thread link</a>) | @nish1500
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article role="article" itemscope="" itemprop="blogPost" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">
<center>
<header>


</header>
</center>
<p>More people are online than ever before. More people are desperate than ever before. Learn how to use that 👇</p>
<h2>Is this the right course for me?</h2>
<p>Good question. My courses are NOT for everyone. You need to be a good fit. This is the prefect course for you if you check any of the following boxes:</p>
<ol><li>You like having a business card that says <strong>I’m CEO bitch</strong></li><li>You dream of petting elephants in a Southeast asian monarchy with a questionable human rights record</li><li>doTerra didn’t work out</li><li>You have $100 to spare</li></ol>
<h2>Basics first. What is a Ponzi scheme?</h2>
<p>Say I managed to save $500 from my day job. I find 5 people who begrudgingly agree to give me $100 because I told them I can turn it into $200 in a month. I give them $200 each at the end of the month.</p>
<p>Now, I am <strong>out of savings</strong> but I have 5 people who doubled their money in a month with no hard work at all.</p>
<p>I use their story as an example to show people that my idea works. Now it’s easier to find people who pay me. I take $100 from 10 more people, wait for a month, and use the proceeds ($1,000) to give $200 each to 5 of those people.</p>
<p>Now I have a <strong>proven business model</strong>, and a good number of people who will vouch for my method. I use the proceeds from each successive group to pay the previous cohort of people.</p>
<h2>But this is a tech community. Not Wall Street.</h2>
<p>A Ponzi scheme can be used in any part of your life. Let’s see how we can use this around us today:</p>
<h3>Example 1: Sell a Course</h3>
<p>Create a twitter account and manage to get 100 followers through a combination of spamming famous people, dad jokes, and paid followers. Write this blog post and share it:</p>
<blockquote><p>How I got 100 followers in my first week with no hard work at all.</p></blockquote>
<p>Over the next week 50 people will read your tweet / post and start following you. These people are curious, and it costs them nothing to follow you. 50 followers isn’t much but you get to write another exciting post:</p>
<blockquote><p>How I increased my twitter following by 50% in less than 3 days.</p></blockquote>
<p>Now people are intrigued, and you have 500 more followers. Write another post.</p>
<blockquote><p>How I got 500 followers overnight</p></blockquote>
<p>Does it remind you of something – like a <strong>for</strong> loop? When iteration = 5, <strong>sell a course</strong> on Gumroad.</p>
<h3>Example 2: Become a Digital Nomad</h3>
<p>Quit your job in Colorado and move to Thailand because a long-haired guy and his hot girlfriend shared a beach selfie telling you how they are living the digital nomad life, and how you can do it too. Best $100 you ever spent.</p>
<p>Except, it didn’t work out (teaching English in Thailand only pays so much), and now you’re stuck in Koh Samui running out of money and ideas. Go to the nearest beach, take a picture of your laptop with sunset in the background and write this blog post:</p>
<blockquote><p>How quitting my 9-5 job and moving to Thailand was the best thing I ever did.</p></blockquote>
<p>Congrats, now people are listening. Create a course, somehow manage to make $1,000. Now use that $1,000 to buy some food, rent a moped, and share more selfies about your perfect life. It’s a massive market – these regular folks working boring jobs in rich white countries who believe in the good intentions of strangers on the internet. Exploit them.</p>
<h3>Example 3: No Code, Only Money</h3>
<p>Aren’t you sick of all these I’m-so-smart programmers with their statically-typed-languages-are-fast on HackerNews? When you came across this priceless <strong>No Code</strong> directory of tools you realized it was the next big thing. You spend $100 on the site, and use the knowledge to create a form (using a form builder) and a Zapier hook that emails people on new responses. Genius idea. You try to sell it for $500. No buyers. It’s all your fault.</p>
<p>Time to pivot. You create a <strong>No Code</strong> website to teach people how to make money using No Code tools (like you did, haha) such as <strong>Airtable</strong> and <strong>Zapier</strong>.</p>
<p><em>Note: the lesson here is NOT that you can make money by creating a valuable tool like Airtable using code. No.</em></p>
<p>Between your <strong>No Code website</strong> and <strong>No Code podcast</strong> you manage to make $500. You take a screenshot of your Stripe dashboard and share it with the world. Now you are hot shit. Going from 0 to $500 was the hard bit; going from $500 to $5,000 is easier.</p>
<h2>FAQ</h2>
<h4>Are places like Indiehacker and Gumroad and just enablers of Ponzi schemes?</h4>
<p>Of course not. There are some amazing people there working on cool new ideas. They write comments here and there, and make a post once in a while, but mostly it’s busy work building something. Most such communities are started by a group of well-intentioned people, who slowly become the minority.</p>
<p>Not all courses are scams. I bought one on Gumroad yesterday. Except it wasn’t teaching me how to grow my twitter following; it was teaching me a cool programming language that I’ve been meaning to learn for a while.</p>
<h4>Will I be sharing fake milestones and fake Stripe dashboards?</h4>
<p>You didn’t read anything, did you? No, you will actually get 500 new followers, and actually make $5,000. The ones who won’t are the suckers who buy your course.</p>
<h4>Won’t people call me out when they buy my course and fail to become rich?</h4>
<p>That is the best part – they will blame <strong>themselves</strong>. You made money. The people who gave you Twitter testimonials apparently made money. If people fail they will think it’s them. In fact, sell them your <strong>Advanced Course</strong>.</p>
<h4>How do I convince people I am legit?</h4>
<p>Tell people you are open to <strong>speaking engagements</strong>. Talk about the number of <strong>trees you planted</strong> this month. Tell them someone else forced you to post on IH or HN because of how great your content is. Talk about <strong>failure</strong> so you seem relatable. Act <strong>quirky</strong> on Twitter.</p>
<h4>Wait, are you writing this just to make me a part of your Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<p>Do you really think I am going to spend half a Sunday writing and formatting this long-ass post (instead of using my magic formula to make money for myself) for any reason other than the goodness of my heart?</p>
<p>Of course not. I swear. I just want to share my success with the world, help the little guy, Build in Public™, like every other ‘How I Made $5,000’ post. Pinky promise.</p>
<h4>I am sold. So, how DO I run a Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<p>You see, my goal in sharing my success here is to see <strong>YOU grow</strong>. Just like the guy who sold me into his Ponzi scheme – I am only paying it forward 🙏🏼.</p>
<p>I do like to charge <strong>$100</strong> JUST to ensure that only serious people become a part of my Ponzi-family. We call it an investment.</p>
<p>Enough talk. Signup here:</p>
<p><a href="https://nish.formcrafts.com/ponzi-scheme" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://nish.formcrafts.com/ponzi-scheme</a></p>
<h4>How do I NOT run a Ponzi scheme?</h4>
<ol><li>Look around you for problems people would pay to resolve.</li><li>Create something of value.</li><li>Have fun while you do it.</li></ol>
<p>Discuss on <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25248563" target="_blank">HN</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/nish_crafts" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">@nish_crafts</a></p>

</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://callmenish.com/how-to-run-a-tech-ponzi-scheme/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25248563</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 22:10:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Vancouver's empty home tax is increasing to 3% next year]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 85 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247904">thread link</a>) | @synack
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>VANCOUVER -- 
	The empty homes tax in Vancouver will more than double next year, the city announced Wednesday.</p>
<p>
	Council voted in favour of increasing the tax from 1.25 per cent to three per cent for 2021. The current rate still applies for 2020 declarations, which are due by Feb. 2.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	"I'm so glad that council backed my plan to stand up for renters and raise the empty homes tax to three per cent," said Mayor Kennedy Stewart in a news release.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	"This groundbreaking tool has helped move thousands of homes back onto the rental market to help house our neighbours, but there are still too many homes that remain empty."</p>
<p>
	When the tax was first introduced in 2017, it started at one per cent. Then council voted to increase it for the first time in 2019, to 1.25 per cent.</p>
<p>
	"By tripling the tax from one to three per cent since the tax launched, we're sending an even stronger message that homes are for people, not speculation," Stewart said.</p>
<p>
	According to the city, $61.3 million in net revenues from the tax has been used to support affordable housing initiatives. Vacant property has decreased by 25 per cent since the tax was introduced in 2017, the city says.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
                                              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://bc.ctvnews.ca/vancouver-s-empty-home-tax-is-increasing-to-3-next-year-1.5204533</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247904</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 20:43:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Software and Hardware for General Robots]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 36 | Comments 22 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247499">thread link</a>) | @ericjang
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="post-body-6885150399029037702" itemprop="description articleBody">
<p><i>Disclaimer, these are just my opinions and not necessarily those of my employer or robotics colleagues.</i></p><p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247499">Hacker News Discussion</a></p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moravec%27s_paradox">Moravec's Paradox</a> describes the observation that our AI systems can solve "adult-level cognitive" tasks like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MuZero">chess-playing</a> or passing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GPT-3">text-based intelligence tests</a> fairly easily, while accomplishing basic sensorimotor skills like crawling around or grasping objects - things one-year old children can do - are very difficult.</p><p>Anyone who has tried to build a robot to do anything<span>&nbsp;</span>will realize that Moravec's Paradox is not a paradox at all, but rather a direct corollary of our physical reality being so&nbsp;<i>irredeemably complex&nbsp;</i>and <i>constantly demanding</i><i>. </i>Modern humans traverse <i>millions </i>of square kilometers in their lifetime, a labyrinth full of dangers and opportunities. If&nbsp;we had to consciously process and deliberate all the survival-critical sensory inputs and motor decisions like we do moves in a game of chess, we would have probably been selected out of the gene pool by Darwinian evolution. Evolution has optimized our biology to perform sensorimotor skills in a&nbsp;split second and make it feel easy.&nbsp;</p><p>Another way to appreciate this complexity is to adjust your daily life&nbsp;to a major motor disability, like losing fingers or trying to get around San Francisco without legs.</p><p><b>Software for General Robots</b></p><p>The difficulty of&nbsp;sensorimotor&nbsp;problems is especially apparent to people who work in robotics and get their hands dirty with the messiness of "the real world". What are the consequences of an irredeemably complex reality on how we build software abstractions for controlling robots?&nbsp;</p><p>One of my pet peeves is when people who do not have sufficient respect for Moravec's Paradox propose a programming model where high-level robotic tasks ("make me dinner") can be divided into sequential or parallel computations with clearly defined logical boundaries: wash rice, de-frost meat, get the plates, set the table, etc. These sub-tasks can be in turn broken down further. When a task cannot be decomposed further because there are too many edge cases for conventional software to handle ("does the image contain a cat?"), we can attempt to invoke a Machine Learning model as "magic software" for that capability.</p><p>This way of thinking - symbolic logic that calls upon ML code - arises from engineers who are used to clinging to the tidiness of <a href="https://medium.com/@karpathy/software-2-0-a64152b37c35">Software 1.0 abstractions</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/programming-guide/concepts/async/">programming tutorials</a>&nbsp;that use cooking analogies.&nbsp;</p><p>Do you have any idea how much intelligence goes into a task like "fetching me a snack", at the very lowest levels of motor skill? Allow me to illustrate. I recorded a short video of me opening a package of dates and annotated it with all the motor sub-tasks I performed in the process.</p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="416" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/b1lysnGFpqI" width="501" youtube-src-id="b1lysnGFpqI"></iframe></p><p>In the span of 36 seconds, I counted about 14 motor and cognitive skills. They happened so quickly that I didn't consciously notice them until I went back and analyzed the video, frame by frame.&nbsp;</p><p>Here are some of the things I did:</p><div><ul><li>Leverage past experience opening this sort of package to understand material properties and how much force to apply.</li><li>Constantly adapt my strategy in response to unforeseen circumstances (Ziploc not giving)</li><li>Adjusting grasp when slippage occurs</li><li>Devising an ad-hoc Weitlaner Retractor with thumb knuckles to increase force on the Ziploc.</li></ul></div><p>As a roboticist, it's humbling to watch&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/ericjang11/status/1315537835630358530?s=20">videos of animals</a>&nbsp;making decisions so quickly and then watch our own robots struggle to do the simplest things. We even have to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QzlI_ny4l8s">speed up the robot video 4x-8x&nbsp;</a>to prevent the human watcher from getting bored!&nbsp;</p><div><div><p>With this video in mind, let's consider where we currently are in the state of robotic manipulation. In the last decade or so, multiple research labs have used deep learning to develop robotic systems that can perform any-object robotic grasping from vision. Grasping is an important problem because in order to manipulate objects, one must usually first grasp them. It took the Google Robotics and X teams&nbsp;<a href="https://www.blogger.com/blog/post/edit/842965756326639856/6885150399029037702#">2-3 years</a>&nbsp;to develop our own system, QT-Opt. This was a huge research achievement because it was a general method that worked on pretty much any object and, in principle, could be used to learn other tasks.&nbsp;</p></div><p>Some people think that this capability to pick up objects can be wrapped in a simple programmatic API and then used to bootstrap us to human-level manipulation. After all, hard problems are just composed of simpler problems, right?&nbsp;</p></div><p>I don't think it's quite so simple. The high-level API call&nbsp;"<span>pick_up_object()</span>" implies a clear semantic boundary between when the robot grasping begins and when it ends. If you re-watch the above video above, how many times do I perform a grasp? It's not clear to me at all where you would slot those function calls. Here is&nbsp;<a href="https://forms.gle/1GLHrf4PcBdHKXNS6">a survey</a>&nbsp;if you are interested in participating in a poll of "how many grasps do you see in this video", whose results I will update in this blog post.&nbsp;</p><p>If we need to solve 13 additional manipulation skills just to open a package of dates, and each one of these capabilities take 2-3 years to build, then we are a long, long way from making robots that match the capabilities of humans. Never mind that there isn't a clear strategy for how to integrate all these behaviors together into a single algorithmic routine. Believe me, I wish reality was simple enough that complex robotic manipulation could be done mostly&nbsp;in Software 1.0. However, as we move beyond pick-and-place towards dexterous and complex tasks, I think we will need to completely rethink how we integrate different capabilities in robotics.</p><p>As you might note from the video, the meaning of a "grasp" is somewhat blurry. Biological intelligence was not specifically evolved for grasping - rather, hands and their behaviors emerged from a few core drives:&nbsp; regulate internal and external conditions, find snacks, replicate.</p><div><div><p>None of this is to say that our current robot platforms and the Software 1.0 programming models are useless for robotics research or applications. A general purpose function&nbsp;<span>pick_up_object()&nbsp;</span>can still be combined with "Software 1.0 code" into a reliable system worth billions of dollars in value to Amazon warehouses and other logistics fulfillment centers. General pick-and-place for any object in any unstructured environment remains an unsolved, valuable, and&nbsp;<i>hard</i>&nbsp;research problem.</p></div><p><b>Hardware for General Robots</b></p><p>What robotic hardware do we require in order to "open a package of dates"?</p><p>Willow Garage was one of the pioneers in home robots, showing that a teleoperated PR2 robot could be used to tidy up a room (note that two arms are needed here for more precise placement of pillows). These are made up of many pick-and-place operations.</p><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="374" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o7JH3UWO6I0" width="450" youtube-src-id="o7JH3UWO6I0"></iframe></p><p>This video was made in 2008. That was 12 years ago! It's sobering to think of how much time has passed and how little the needle has seemingly moved. Reality is hard.&nbsp;</p><p>The <a href="https://hello-robot.com/product">Stretch</a>&nbsp;is&nbsp;a simple telescoping arm attached to a vertical gantry. It can do things like pick up objects, wipe planar surfaces, and open drawers.</p><div><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="373" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2msVU0ygrqM" width="449" youtube-src-id="2msVU0ygrqM"></iframe></p><p>However, futurist beware! A common source of hype for people who don't think enough about physical reality is to watch demos of robots doing useful things in one home, and then conclude that the same robots are ready to do those tasks in <i>any home</i>.</p><div><p>The Stretch video shows the&nbsp;<a href="https://youtu.be/2msVU0ygrqM?t=41">robot pulling open a dryer door</a>&nbsp;(left-swinging) and retrieving clothes from it. The video is a bit deceptive - I think the camera&nbsp; physically cannot see the interior of the dryer, so even though a human can teleoperate the robot to do the task, it would run into serious difficulty when ensuring that the dryer has been completely emptied.</p><p>Here is a picture of my own dryer, which features a dryer with a <i>right-swinging</i>&nbsp;door close to a wall. I'm not sure if the Stretch actually can fit in this tight space, but the PR2 definitely would not be able to open this door without the base getting in the way.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-n8U9MC3ww-Q/X8MEUSH03jI/AAAAAAAAepg/JkqUn4xiirU2wiJ76aEC4av5ukvVqNtkACNcBGAsYHQ/s2048/128546115_197081455371161_5776583945816761781_n.jpg"><img data-original-height="2048" data-original-width="1536" height="320" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-n8U9MC3ww-Q/X8MEUSH03jI/AAAAAAAAepg/JkqUn4xiirU2wiJ76aEC4av5ukvVqNtkACNcBGAsYHQ/s320/128546115_197081455371161_5776583945816761781_n.jpg"></a><a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Wxb4M30Yk3A/X8MEhN4mcvI/AAAAAAAAepo/Pv7jQZ_NXPU19mjwdHnZGQKf2FHcbrAmQCNcBGAsYHQ/s1920/128903470_992029601279712_5029308404263396832_n.png"><img data-original-height="1920" data-original-width="1080" height="400" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Wxb4M30Yk3A/X8MEhN4mcvI/AAAAAAAAepo/Pv7jQZ_NXPU19mjwdHnZGQKf2FHcbrAmQCNcBGAsYHQ/w225-h400/128903470_992029601279712_5029308404263396832_n.png" width="225"></a></p></div><div><p>Reality's edge cases are often swept under the rug when making robot demo videos, which usually show the robot operating in an optimal environment that the robot is well-suited for. But the full range of tasks humans do in the home is&nbsp;<i>vast</i>.&nbsp; Neither the PR2 nor the Stretch can crouch under a table to pick up lint off the floor, change a lightbulb while standing on a chair, fix caulking in a bathroom, open mail with a letter opener, move dishes from the dishwasher to the high cabinets, break down cardboard boxes for the recycle bin, go outside and retrieve the mail.&nbsp;</p><div><p>And of course, they can't even open a Ziploc package of dates. If you think <i>that </i>was&nbsp;complex, here is a first-person video of me chopping strawberries, washing utensils, and decorating a cheesecake. This was recorded with a GoPro strapped to my head. Watch each time my fingers twitch - each one is a separate manipulation task!</p></div><p><iframe allowfullscreen="" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Hd7JkOo0B8" width="482" youtube-src-id="_Hd7JkOo0B8"></iframe></p><br></div><p>We often talk about a future where robots do our cooking for us, but I don't think it's possible with any hardware on the market today. The only viable hardware for a robot meant to do <i>any task</i> in human spaces is an adult-sized humanoid, with two-arms, two-legs, and five fingers on each hand.&nbsp;</p><p>Just like I discussed about Software 1.0 in robotics, there is still an enormous space of robot morphologies that can still provide value to research and commercial applications. That doesn't change the fact that any alternative hardware can't do all the things a humanoid can in a human-centric space. Agility Robotics is one of the companies <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BKjRVlzKEMI">that gets it</a>&nbsp;on the hardware design front. People who build physical robots use their hands a lot -&nbsp;could you imagine the robot you are building assembling a copy of itself?&nbsp;</p><p><b>Why Don't We Just Design Environments to be More Robot-Friendly?</b></p><p>A compromise is to co-design the environment with the robot to avoid infeasible tasks like above. This can simplify both the hardware and software problems. Common examples I hear <i>incessantly </i>go like this:</p><div><ol><li>Washing machines are better than a bimanual robot washing dishes in the sink, and a dryer is a more efficient machine than a human hanging out clothes to air-dry.</li><li>Airplanes are better at …</li></ol></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html">https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.evjang.com/2020/11/moravec-bots.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247499</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:47:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Simple Password Management with GPG]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 84 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247211">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <!--**This is a post about a password management system where you GPG encrypt markdown files on Linux and Syncthing them to Android.**-->

<!--Want to use GPG encrypted files to manage your passwords?-->

<!-- use the word `markdown files` instead of `plain-text files` is because people who care enough to read on are tech savvy people that knows markdown anyway, but then 会make it too 复杂吗, 再看吧, 感觉 say plain-text might 也比较好的 -->

<!--I'm not too fond of using password management tools like `Dashlane` or `1Password`, I've never really tried them, because there's no guarantee that they will live forever, nor that their security perfect.-->

<!--Even though some of them are open-source, they are still at the mercy of their developers unless I'm willing to modify it myself,-->
<!--so it is harder to modify it to fit my needs better.-->

<!--I just want a password management system that is simple, extensible and will live forever, this is my setup:-->
<p>If you want a password management system that is plain-text based, let me introduce to you my setup which utilizes GPG encrypted files to do that.</p>

<p>It uses GPG to encrypt markdown files containing my login credentials, and Syncthing to synchronize them to my Android phone to realize cross-device availability.</p>


<!--To be more exact, I create markdown files and store my login credentials plain-text, then-->

<ul>
  <li>On my computer, I use
    <ul>
      <li><code>gpg</code> to encrypt the markdown files</li>
      <li><a href="https://vimawesome.com/plugin/gnupg-vim">jamessan/vim-gnupg</a> Vim plugin to easily decrypt and edit the files</li>
      <li><code>Git</code> to version control the folder so I have full history of my login credentials</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>To access them from my phone, I use
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://syncthing.net/">Syncthing</a> to synchronize the folder to my phone</li>
      <li><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.sufficientlysecure.keychain&amp;hl=en">OpenKeychain</a> app to decrypt and read the encrypted files</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I could just Syncthing the markdown files <em>without encryption</em> to my phone, but on the off chance that my phone is stolen / lost / hacked, I don’t want my passwords to go down with it, so it is safer to have it gpg encrypted.</p>

<p><del>I’m aware of <a href="https://www.passwordstore.org/">pass</a> and tried it before I came to this setup, but I want to put more info than just a password string in my files, so that’s why <code>pass</code> doesn’t fit my need.</del>
As many have pointed out in this <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25247211">HackerNews thread</a>, pass allows multi-line edit, so this paragraph is incorrect.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-replicate-this-setup">How to replicate this setup</h3>

<p><strong>1. Generate a PGP keypair with GPG</strong></p>

<p>you can skip this if you already have a keypair.</p>

<p>$ <code>gpg --full-gen-key</code></p>

<p><strong>2. Install the Vim plugin and put in corresponding config</strong></p>

<p>Assuming you’re using VimPlug ( a vim plugin manager ),
put this into your ~/.vimrc and run <code>:PlugInstall</code> in Vim.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Plug 'jamessan/vim-gnupg'
" Armor files
let g:GPGPreferArmor=1
" Set the default option
let g:GPGDefaultRecipients=["youremail@provider.com"]"
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>NOTE: remember to modify the <code>youremail@provider.com</code> to the email associated with your PGP key</p>

<!--This plugin will auto decrypt encrypted files when you open them with Vim, making the only difference with opening a normal unencrypted file a slight delay of opening the file due to the decryption process.-->
<!--有点啰嗦 this ^ line, comment it out first-->

<p><strong>3. Create a markdown file</strong></p>

<p>$ <code>touch mygmail.md</code></p>

<p><strong>4. Encrypt the markdown file</strong></p>

<!--$ `gpg --recipient youremail@provider.com --armor --output %f.asc --encrypt %f`-->
<p>$ <code>gpg -e -r youremail@provider.com path/to/file</code></p>

<p>if you use <a href="https://github.com/ranger/ranger">Ranger</a>, you can put this mapping into your rc.conf to encrypt it easily by pressing <code>te</code> when the selection is hovering on the file:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>map te shell gpg --recipient youremail@provider.com --armor --output %f.asc --encrypt %f &amp;&amp; rm %f
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Open the file with Vim to make sure it can auto decrypt and open up the file.</p>


<p><strong>5. Setup Syncthing</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://syncthing.net/downloads/">Install Syncthing</a> on Linux and Android, then set it up to sync your password folder to your phone.</p>

<p><strong>6. Setup OpenKeychain</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Install <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.sufficientlysecure.keychain&amp;hl=en">OpenKeychain</a> Android app on your phone</p>
  </li>
  <li>export your PGP private key from Linux
    <div><div><pre><code>  $ gpg --export-secret-keys --armor youremail@provider.com &gt; privkey.asc
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>Transfer the file to your Android phone (for example through wire)</li>
  <li>Import the key file into <code>OpenKeychain</code> app</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>7. Try decrypting your files on Android</strong></p>

<p>To decrypt and view your password file:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Open the <code>OpenKeychain</code> app</li>
  <li>
    <p>Press the hamburger menu icon on the top left</p>
  </li>
  <li>Press <code>Encrypt/Decrypt</code></li>
</ol>

<p><img src="https://tylerlmz1.github.io/assets/decrypt.png" width="200px"></p>

<ol>
  <li>Press <code>Select input file</code> and browse to the encrypted password file</li>
  <li>Enter your PGP key passphrase</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>8. Done</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://tylerlmz1.github.io/assets/view_decrypted_pw_file.png" width="200px"></p>

  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://tylerlmz1.github.io/tools/2020/05/15/Password-management.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25247211</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 19:13:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Only distributed fact-checking can keep up with democratized distribution]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 120 | Comments 164 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25246733">thread link</a>) | @awinter-py
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p><img src="https://abe-winter.github.io/assets/swift-ftl.png" alt="tweet: the problem with being faster than light is that you always live in darkness"></p>

<p>Has social media democratized reporting as promised?
We’ve democratized <em>writing and publishing</em> but this year has made the point that there’s more to journalism than hitting send.
The rest of the stuff that happens in the newsroom has stayed in the newsroom:
cultivating sources, editing for quality, and most importantly, fact-checking.</p>

<p>Lacking checks, social media is amplifying or at least fertilizing false beliefs,
and then people cross state lines to shoot up pizza joints.
If the newsroom’s adversarial functions can’t make the jump to social media,
life will continue to be this weird.</p>

<p>We’re starting to address fact-checking, and will do more.
<a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2019/11/why-cant-internet-companies-stop-awful-content/">Failing to curb antisocial behavior kills companies</a>, as well as communities.</p>

<p>Facebook has the technology to filter out the worst-quality content that their users think is ‘P(bad for the world)’ – <a href="https://twitter.com/kevinroose/status/1331257332538359810">but only at the cost of lower engagement</a>.
Given these incentives, nobody benefits if we leave this to platforms to solve.
Users should bring their own moderation to the web.</p>

<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles" id="markdown-toc-private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles">Private groups will decamp if they don’t like the fact bubbles</a></li>
  <li><a href="#conspiracies-are-topics-too" id="markdown-toc-conspiracies-are-topics-too">Conspiracies are topics too</a></li>
  <li><a href="#cranky-boomers-r-us" id="markdown-toc-cranky-boomers-r-us">Cranky boomers R us</a></li>
  <li><a href="#byo-vs-centralized-moderation" id="markdown-toc-byo-vs-centralized-moderation">BYO vs centralized moderation</a></li>
  <li><a href="#information-also-has-professional-customers" id="markdown-toc-information-also-has-professional-customers">Information also has professional customers</a></li>
  <li><a href="#conclusions" id="markdown-toc-conclusions">Conclusions</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="private-groups-will-decamp-if-they-dont-like-the-fact-bubbles">Private groups will decamp if they don’t like the fact bubbles</h2>

<p>Filter bubbles don’t have to put up with fact bubbles.
By filter bubbles, I mean clique groups that see mostly content that supports their priors.
By fact bubbles, I mean those blue exclamation marks that say ‘official sources have called the election differently’.</p>

<p>Private groups have the power to resist centralized moderation if they don’t like it.
Private groups are sticky which is why facebook <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/30/18524188/facebook-f8-keynote-mark-zuckerberg-privacy-future-2019">bet their future on them</a>,
but this stickiness makes them hard to control.
Yes, their internal cohesion leads to engagement on FB, but it also allows them to move off the platform if they’re unhappy.
They own their slice of the network; their moat has a drawbridge.</p>

<p>A heavy hand will drive private groups to dark corners of the web –
not <em>un</em>-moderated exactly, because trust me, nobody wants that.
But ‘differently moderated’.
Reality is a participation sport and groups which don’t want to participate, won’t.</p>

<p>That said, deplatforming isn’t zero-cost for groups:
they recruit in public spaces, and are helped by ‘suggested groups’ features (which FB <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/ryanmac/facebook-suspended-group-recommendations-election">partially disabled</a> for the election).
Standalone forums can’t grow like that.
The fickle graces of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/5/20754943/8chan-epik-offline-voxility-service-cutoff-hate-speech-ban">hosts</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/8/4/20754310/cloudflare-8chan-fredrick-brennan-ddos-attack">DDOS-protection companies</a> also make it hard to go solo.</p>

<p>But it’s not like IRL networks will stop feeding online groups.
The counterargument to ‘social media gives bad politicians a voice’ is that once someone has been elected, they’ll probably <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f7131IkiSCg">have a voice anyway</a>.
FB’s design gives eyeballs to demagogues but <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triumph_des_Willens">so did Leni Riefenstahl</a>.</p>

<p>As I drafted this in early november, twitter was fact-bubbling multiple tweets in a row from the president,
the ‘uncensored’ social media app parler <a href="https://twitter.com/yashar/status/1325229370126991363">trended to #1</a> in apple’s store,
and local hero <a href="https://twitter.com/WilliamShatner/status/1326223481646665728">Bill Shatner took up the cause of moderation</a> to oppose them.
The ‘moderation drives exodus’ hypothesis is plausible.</p>

<p>But parler can’t really want to be unmoderated.
Their debut came with a quick correction that despite the sales pitch, <a href="https://twitter.com/viaCristiano/status/1277941967402553345">your username can’t be cumdumpster</a>.
(<a href="https://twitter.com/cumdumpster">Twitter has allowed this</a> since at least 2013).</p>

<p>My point: nobody wants to live in a trash can.
Every community has some kind of semi-official management.
I think even 8kun revoked someone’s access to the Q account after they had a falling out (admittedly, not over content I think, and also I don’t really understand this world).
But the <em>forms</em> of moderation we invent have to be trusted or at least tolerated, or people will ditch.</p>

<p>Fact-checking, if it’s trustworthy and useful, will be embraced IMO. But it can’t be imposed.</p>

<h2 id="conspiracies-are-topics-too">Conspiracies are topics too</h2>

<p>A swedish friend, trying to explain why their <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweden_Democrats">far-right party</a> gained power in the Riksdag,
said something like ‘It’s not that we’re all nazis, but nobody else would even talk about immigration, and it’s a real problem’.</p>

<p>I like the ‘marketplace of ideas’ as a concept.<sup id="fnref:marketplace" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:marketplace">1</a></sup>
Markets are an interesting model for public discourse.
Like goods on markets, there are a limited number of explanations or ideologies available (assuming most people can’t coin our own – for various reasons, I believe we can’t).
Also, like a real market, it’s two-sided, in that in addition to the ideas on offer, there are buyers:
people looking for an action, belief, or political party that suits them.</p>

<p>The marketplace model explains why political parties get to lie out loud, be revealed for hypocrisy, and admit their strategy is disingenuous.
They’re <em>still</em> the only rallying point for ‘critical idea X’ that their buyers need.
It may not matter to the fighting faithful if the center is hollow.
They’re willing to ignore the cognitive dissonance.</p>

<p>I wonder if there’s a similar effect in the antivax movement –
autism seems to really be on the rise (0.7 to 1.5% in this century),
and if your family is affected by this, and there’s no other explanation, you ‘buy’ the idea that comes with a clear cause and a solution.</p>

<h2 id="cranky-boomers-r-us">Cranky boomers R us</h2>

<p>People are seeking answers that are plausible to them,
but may not be able or willing to dig deeply, and may not be ready to hear the truth if it means abandoning their hope, identity, or <a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-11-beliefs-world-filter.html">existing opinions</a>.
I suspect if someone is at the bottom of a rabbit hole and sees a fact bubble saying ‘this is stupid’, that’s the same as saying ‘you’re stupid’, and they won’t listen.
The challenge here is matching them with a well-meaning authority whom they’ll trust and find useful.</p>

<p>There was a measles outbreak in Minnesota enabled by high vaccine refusal rate in a single immigrant community.
Parents noticed a lot of their kids in special autism education<sup id="fnref:stat-antivax" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:stat-antivax">2</a></sup>, then fell prey to antivax lecturers or something.
But the parents had access to doctors.
And presumably they had access to other experts at the autism schools.
They ignored the fact bubble.
They chose who to trust.</p>

<p>On the flip side, community-owned moderation sometimes works rather well.
I’m thinking about subreddits, who tend to have very specific rules about what to post, and their users accept that these communities are actively moderated for the benefit of the community.
(Given that the community is a result of moderation, this is a little circular and feedback loop-y, but that may not be a bad thing).</p>

<p>I asked a friend who mods a small subbredit what it’s like:
“In six years, no one has ever said anything mean on my subreddit. I’ve never had to ban anyone and submitters and subscribers are respectful.”</p>

<p>Cranky boomers got us into this mess by believing everything they read on facebook.
Maybe Cranky-Boomers-R-Us™️ is the right branding for a community fact check to filter out some fast-spreading egregious claims.</p>

<p>We train people to consider the source, but mainstream mastheads like NYT feel ideologically hostile to readers who aren’t centrists over 55.
Their news coverage can be accurate without being neutral – factual claims in articles are fact-checked, but that’s mixed with interpretive conclusions.
The op-eds are <a href="https://www.cjr.org/the_media_today/james_bennet_tom_cotton_objectivity.php">far stranger</a>.</p>

<p>I don’t blame people for switching to ideologically comfortable news.
I just wish they had a fact-check that was ideologically comfortable, but also competent and reputation-bound, to go along with it.</p>

<p>Repentant neocon Francis Fukuyama writes about social trust now and is <a href="https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-emergence-of-a-post-fact-world-by-francis-fukuyama-2017-01">worried about post-fact world</a> where
“all authoritative information sources are challenged by contrary facts of dubious quality and provenance”.
Readers have reasons for straying from reality.
Let’s give people an ideologically comfortable way to come back.</p>

<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harm_reduction">Gentler public health messaging</a> that accepts people’s lifestyles can have higher efficacy;
I suspect the same is true of fact-checks.
Our goal isn’t to change minds; it’s to improve outcomes.</p>

<h2 id="byo-vs-centralized-moderation">BYO vs centralized moderation</h2>

<p>We need a market ecosystem of moderation vendors who provide different kinds of value to different kinds of users.
A moderation marketplace is good for platforms because they don’t want to be the arbiter of truth, they just want users to have a good experience.
(Platforms will still have some policing to do on their own).</p>

<p>It’s good for users because they’re not forced into anything; they can pick which web they want to dwell on.
This may sound like a filter bubble, where ‘everyone has their own truth’,
but moderation vendors will still need to maintain their reputation for being right –
whatever their ideological alignment.
Moderation vendors, unlike cable news channels, don’t produce content;
they just react to it and grade it.
BYO moderation isn’t BYO newspaper, it’s BYO snopes / politifact.</p>

<p>Centralized moderation has problems:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The costs are asymmetric, meaning it’s too expensive to do widely, well, and fast (see lego point below). Jimmy Wales of wikipedia describes the economics here leading to a <a href="https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/jimmy-wales-tyler-cowen-wikipedia-610b6e931d20">sweatshop model</a>.</li>
  <li>It’s susceptible to abuse by platforms and institutions and therefore will be less trusted by users, especially the more conspiracy-minded ones whom we want to deradicalize. Note I’m not saying ‘prone to abuse’ or ‘untrustworthy’. Just less trust-<em>ed</em>, and less able to balance minority viewpoints in a way that feels authentic to minorities.</li>
  <li>Private groups will turn off mod systems if not effective / ergonomic / trustable, or else deplatform.</li>
  <li>For messy issues, cookie-cutter moderation can <a href="https://www.eff.org/wp/caught-net-impact-extremist-speech-regulations-human-rights-content">support violence by hiding its proof</a>. Or like <a href="https://twitter.com/KatMurti/status/1276183164109697028">where’s the parler for breastfeeding</a>?</li>
</ul>

<p>Every community needs moderation.
Some get away without it because they moderate membership rather than content –
small workplaces, for example, have relatively informal content moderation processes, but can fire you.</p>

<p>This isn’t just a facebook / twitter issue anymore – it’s a problem for anyone with a supply of eyeballs and UGC or DM features, like <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/11/07/pinterest-linkedin-election-disinfo/">pinterest and linkedin</a>.
The older and funnier version of this is the <a href="https://www.managingcommunities.com/2015/06/04/lego-universes-penis-problem-and-why-moderation-efforts-arent-hopeless/">lego MMO’s penis problem</a> –
they …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html">https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://abe-winter.github.io/only/fans/2020/11/29/everything-in-moderation.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25246733</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:01:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Study links mindfulness and meditation to narcissism and “spiritual superiority”]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 54 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245512">thread link</a>) | @Bologo
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.psychnewsdaily.com/study-links-mindfulness-meditation-to-narcissism-and-spiritual-superiority/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245512</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 15:09:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA['Leave shaming' employees needs to stop]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 29 | Comments 7 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245244">thread link</a>) | @rustoo
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://m.dailyhunt.in/news/india/english/money+control+english-epaper-mconten/leave+shaming+employees+needs+to+stop+in+india-newsid-n232431602 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://m.dailyhunt.in/news/india/english/money+control+english-epaper-mconten/leave+shaming+employees+needs+to+stop+in+india-newsid-n232431602">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://m.dailyhunt.in/news/india/english/money+control+english-epaper-mconten/leave+shaming+employees+needs+to+stop+in+india-newsid-n232431602</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245244</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:22:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Little Things That Made Amiga Great]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 213 | Comments 172 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245206">thread link</a>) | @eitland
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245206</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:14:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Pijul – The Mathematically Sound Version Control System Written in Rust]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 88 | Comments 58 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25245129">thread link</a>) | @initialcommit
<br/>
November 29, 2020 | https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://initialcommit.com/blog/pijul-version-control-system</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25245129</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 14:01:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A better Kubernetes from the ground up]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 249 | Comments 147 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25243159">thread link</a>) | @mr-karan
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<div>
		<p><span>Written by</span>
        David Anderson
        <br>
        <span>on&nbsp;</span><time datetime="2020-11-28 00:00:00 +0000 UTC">November 28, 2020</time>
</p>
		


		

		<p>Recently I had a chat with the excellent <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery Lancey</a>, about Kubernetes. Specifically, what we would do differently if we built something new, from the ground up, with no regard for compatibility with Kubernetes. I found that conversation so stimulating that I feel the need to write things down, so here we are.</p>

<p>Before we get started, I want to stress a few things.</p>

<ul>
<li>This is not a fully formed design. Some of these things may not work at all, or require significant redesign. Each section is one random piece of the entire puzzle.</li>
<li>These are not solely my ideas. Some I <em>think</em> are original, but like many things in the Kubernetes community it’s the product of collective thinking. I know at least <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/maisem_ali">Maisem Ali</a> have influenced my thinking at one time or another, and I’m forgetting many more. If you like an idea, it was a group effort. If you hate it, it’s entirely mine.</li>
<li>Some of these things are polarizing. I’m designing something that makes <em>me</em> happy.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="guiding-principles">Guiding principles</h2>

<p>My experience of Kubernetes comes from two very different places: authoring <a href="https://www.metallb.org/">MetalLB</a> for bare metal clusters, and operating a large fleet of clusters-as-a-service in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine">GKE SRE</a>. Both of these taught me that Kubernetes is extremely complex, and that most people who are trying to use it are not prepared for the sheer amount of work that lies between the marketing brochure and the system those brochures promise.</p>

<p>MetalLB taught me that it’s not possible to build robust software that integrates with Kubernetes. I think MetalLB makes a damn good go of it, but Kubernetes still makes it far too easy to construct broken configurations, and far too hard to debug them. GKE SRE taught me that even the foremost Kubernetes experts cannot safely operate Kubernetes at scale. (Although GKE SRE does a spectacular job with the tools they’re given.)</p>

<p>Kubernetes is the C++ of orchestration software. Immensely powerful, includes all the features, looks deceptively simple, and <em>will</em> hurt you repeatedly until you join its priesthood and devote your life to its mysteries. And even then, the matrix of possible ways to configure and deploy it is so large that you’re never on firm footing.</p>

<p>Continuing that analogy, my guide star is Go. If Kubernetes is C++, what would the Go of orchestration systems look like? Aggressively simple, opinionated, grown slowly and warily, and you can learn it in under a week and get on with what you were actually trying to accomplish.</p>

<p>With that, let’s get going. Starting with Kubernetes, and with a license to completely and utterly break compatibility, what would I do?</p>

<h2 id="mutable-pods">Mutable pods</h2>

<p>In Kubernetes, pods are mostly (but not entirely) immutable after creation. If you want to change a pod, you don’t. Make a new one and delete the old one. This is unlike most other things in Kubernetes, which are mostly mutable and gracefully reconcile towards the new spec.</p>

<p>So, I’m going to make pods be not special. Make them entirely read-write, and reconcile them like you would any other object.</p>

<p>The immediately useful thing I get from that is in-place restarts. If scheduling constraints and resource allocations haven’t changed, guess what? SIGTERM runc, restart runc with different parameters, and you’re done. Now pods look like regular old systemd services, that can move between machines <em>if necessary</em>.</p>

<p>Note that this doesn’t require doing mutability at the runtime layer. If you change a pod definition, it’s still mostly fine to terminate the container and restart it with a new configuration. The pod is still holding onto the resource reservation that got it scheduled onto this machine, so conceptually it’s equivalent to <code>systemctl restart blah.service</code>. You could try to be fancy and make some operations actually update in place at the runtime level as well, but don’t have to. The main benefit is decoupling scheduling, pod lifetime, and lifetime at the runtime layer.</p>

<h2 id="version-control-all-the-things">Version control all the things</h2>

<p>Sticking at the pod layer for a bit longer: now that they’re mutable, the next obvious thing I want is rollbacks. For that, let’s keep old versions of pod definitions around, and make it trivial to “go back to version N”.</p>

<p>Now, a pod update looks like: write an updated definition of the pod, and it updates to match. Update broken? Write back version N-1, and you’re done.</p>

<p>Bonus things you get from this: a diffable history of what happened to your cluster, without needing GitOps nonsense. By all means keep the GitOps nonsense if you want, it has benefits, but you can answer a basic “what changed?” question using only data in the cluster.</p>

<p>This needs a bit more design. In particular, I want to separate out external changes (human submits a new pod) from mechanical changes (some internals of k8s alter a pod definition). I haven’t thought through how to encode both those histories and make both accessible to operators and automation. Maybe it could also be completely generic, wherein a “changer” identifies itself when submitting a new version, and you can then query for changes by or excluding particular changers (think similar to how label queries work at the minute). Again, more design needed there, I just know that I want versioned objects with an accessible history.</p>

<p>We’ll need garbage collection eventually. That said, changes to single pods should delta-compress really well, so my default would be to just keep everything until it becomes a truly dumb amount of data, and figure something out at that point. Keeping everything also acts as a useful mild pressure to avoid “death by a thousand changes” in the rest of the system. Prefer to have fewer, more meaningful changes over a flurry of control loops each changing one field in pursuit of convergence.</p>

<p>Once we have this history, we can do some neat minor things too. For example, the node software could keep container images for the last N versions pinned to the machine, so that rollbacks are as fast as they can possibly be. With an accessible history, you can do this more precisely than “GC older than 30 days and hope”. Generalizing, all the orchestration software can use older versions as GC roots for various resources, to make rollbacks faster. Rollbacks being the primary way of ending outages, this is a very valuable thing to have.</p>

<h2 id="replace-deployment-with-pinneddeployment">Replace Deployment with PinnedDeployment</h2>

<p>This is a short section to basically say that <a href="https://timewitch.net/">Vallery</a> knocked it out of the park with her <a href="https://timewitch.net/post/2019-12-30-pinneddeployments/">PinnedDeployment</a> resource, which lets operators explicitly control a rollout by tracking 2 versions of the deployment state. It’s a deployment object designed by an SRE, with a crisp understanding of what SREs want in a deployment. I love it.</p>

<p>This combines super well with the versioned, in-place pod updates above, and I really don’t have anything to add. It’s clearly how multi-pod things should work. There’s probably some tweaking required to adapt from the Kubernetes-constrained world to this new wonderful unconstrained universe, but the general design is perfect.</p>

<h2 id="explicit-orchestration-workflows">Explicit orchestration workflows</h2>

<p>The biggest issue I have with the “API machinery” bits of Kubernetes is the idea of orchestration as a loose choreography of independent control loops. On the surface, this seems like a nice idea: you have dozens of little control loops, each focused on doing one small thing. When combined in a cluster, they indirectly cooperate with each other to push the state forward and converge on the desired end state. So, what’s the problem?</p>

<p>The problem is that it’s entirely impossible to debug when it goes wrong. A typical failure mode in Kubernetes is that you submit a change to the cluster, then repeatedly refresh waiting for stuff to converge. When it doesn’t… Well, you’re screwed. Kubernetes doesn’t know the difference between “the system has converged successfully” and “a control loop is wedged and is blocking everything else.” You can hope that the offending control loop posted some events to the object to help you, but by and large they don’t.</p>

<p>At which point your only option is to cat the logs of every control loop that might be involved, looking for the one that was wedged. You can make this a bit faster if you have intimate knowledge of all the control loops and what each one does, because that lets you infer from the object’s current state which loop might be trying to run right now.</p>

<p>The key thing to notice here is that the complexity has been shifted from the designer of the control loop to the cluster operator. It’s easy (though not trivial) to make a control loop that does a dinky little thing in isolation. But to operate a cluster with dozens of these control loops requires the operator to assimilate the behavior of all of them, their interactions with each other, and try to reason about an extremely loosely coupled system. This is a problem because you have to write and test the control loop once, but work with it and its bugs many more times. And yet, the bias is to simplify the thing you only do once.</p>

<p>To fix this, I would look to systemd. It solves for a similar lifecycle problem: given a current state and a target, how do you get from A to B? The difference is that in systemd, the steps and their dependencies are made explicit. You <em>tell</em> systemd that your unit is a required part of <code>multi-user.target</code> (aka “normally-booted happy system”), that it must run after filesystems have been mounted, but before networking it brought up, and so forth. You can also depend on other concrete parts of the system, for example to say that your thing needs to run whenever sshd is running (sounds like a sidecar, right?).</p>

<p>The net result of this is that systemd can tell you precisely what piece of the system malfunctioned, or is still working on its thing, or failed a precondition. It can also print you a graph of the system’s boot process, and analyze it for things like “what’s the long pole of bootup?”</p>

<p>I want to steal all this wholesale, and plop it into my cluster orchestration …</p></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/">https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.dave.tf/post/new-kubernetes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25243159</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 05:35:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Undeleting a file overwritten with mv]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 262 | Comments 81 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25242444">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="main">

    <article>

        

<!--         <header class="post-header">
            <a id="blog-logo" href="https://behind.pretix.eu">
                
                    <span class="blog-title">pretix – behind the scenes</span>
                
            </a>
        </header> -->

        <!-- <span class="post-meta">
            <time datetime="2020-11-28">28 Nov 2020</time>
            
                on Technology, Forensics, and Linux
            
        </span> -->

        <!-- <h1 class="post-title">Undeleting a file overwritten with mv</h1> -->

        <section>
            <p>It’s been a while since we shared the story of an incident with you, and that’s probably a good thing –
most operational incidents we had in the past year were “boring” enough in nature to fix them easily.
This time, we’ve got a story of a data loss, caused by pure and simple human error – and the story of
how we recovered the data.</p>

<p>Even though it is quite embarrassing how the data loss happened, we think it’s worth sharing the story
of its recovery, as it might allow you to learn a few useful things in case you ever end up in a
similar situation.</p>

<p>As you might have seen, over the last 7 months we’ve extended our offerings beyond ticketing to allow
our customers to transform their events into the digital space as long as the global pandemic makes
traditional event formats impossible. The result of our effort is a joint venture called 
<a href="https://venueless.org/">Venueless</a> that you should absolutely check out if you haven’t yet.</p>

<p>One component of the virtual events we run on venueless is <strong>live video streaming</strong>. In this process,
our customers use a tool like <a href="https://obsproject.com/">OBS</a> or <a href="https://streamyard.com/">StreamYard</a>
to create a live video stream. The stream is then sent to an <strong>encoding server</strong> of ours via RTMP.
On the encoding server, we re-encode the stream into different quality levels and then distribute
it to our very own tiny streaming CDN.</p>

<p>Venueless currently does <strong>not yet</strong> include a video-on-demand component and usually, our customers record
their content at the source, e.g. with OBS or StreamYard, and process or publish them on their own.
However, just to be safe, we keep a recording of the incoming stream as well. This isn’t currently
part of our promoted service offering, we rather see it as a free backup service to our clients in case they
lose their recording. Given that we already consider it to just be a backup, we currently don’t make any
further backups of this data.</p>

<h4 id="data-loss">Data loss</h4>

<p>Usually, we delete these recordings after a while, but in some cases, our customers ask us to get them, e.g.
because their own recording failed, or because StreamYard only records the first 8 hours of every
stream. Since this doesn’t happen a lot, it’s not yet an automated process in our system. Whenever a customer
requests a recording we SSH into the respective encoding server and move the recording file to a
directory that’s accessible through HTTP, like this:</p>

<pre><code>/var/recordings $ mv recording-12345.flv public/
</code></pre>

<p>That’s it, we share the link with the customer, and the process is done. One of the simplest steps possible
in all this. Yesterday, a customer asked us for the recordings of the two last streams of their event. Just
before finishing up for the week, I wanted to supply them with the required file, SSH’d into the server,
looked for the correct files and typed…</p>

<pre><code>/var/recordings $ mv recording-16678.flv recording-16679.flv
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Oops.</strong> I hit return before typing out <code>public/</code>, and therefore replaced the last stream with the
second-last, losing one of the videos.</p>

<h4 id="damage-control">Damage control</h4>

<p>Having a very naive understanding of how file systems work, I knew that the <code>mv</code> command has only
changed the directory listing of the file system, but hasn’t actually wiped the file from the disk,
so I knew there is likely still a chance to recover the file, if it’s not overwritten by something
else in the meantime.</p>

<p>Since I didn’t manage to re-mount the root partition as read-only to avoid further damage softly,
I used the <a href="https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/sysrq.html">big hammer</a> to remount
everything read-only immediately:</p>

<pre><code># echo u &gt; /proc/sysrq-trigger
</code></pre>

<p>Uhm, okay, this worked, but how do I install any data recovery tools now? After some experiments,
I decided it would be easiest to reboot into the recovery system provided by our server provider
<a href="https://www.hetzner.com/">Hetzner</a>. So I configured the boot loader to boot their recovery system
from the network and forcefully rebooted the server.</p>

<p>To be able to perform disk dumps and have some operational flexibility without downloading a 2 TB
disk image to my local machine (which would take rougly a week), I also quickly purchased
a <a href="https://www.hetzner.com/storage/storage-box">Hetzner Storage Box</a> with 5 TB space.</p>

<h4 id="failed-attempts">Failed attempts</h4>

<p>Just before I executed my fatal <code>mv</code> command, I executed <code>ls -lisah</code> to get a directory listing
of the files:</p>

<pre><code>3146449 1.1G -rw-r--r-- 1 www-data www-data 1.1G Nov XX XX:XX recording-16678.flv
3146113 1.6G -rw-r--r-- 1 www-data www-data 1.6G Nov XX XX:XX recording-16679.flv
</code></pre>

<p>This meant I <strong>knew</strong> the inode number of the deleted file! As I mentioned before, my understanding
of file systems was (and is) rather naive, and I was pretty optimistic to be able to recover the
file using that information. Isn’t that sort of what a journaling file system is for?</p>

<p>Recovering the file this way hover appeared to be impossible. <a href="http://ext4magic.sourceforge.net/howto_en.html">ext4magic</a>
and <a href="http://extundelete.sourceforge.net/">extundelete</a> are powerful tools that did find some 
deleted files on my disk – but not the one I was looking for, even after trying different options
for over two hours.</p>

<p>I did not spend the time to really understand how ext4 works, but from what I gathered from various
blogs, I was pretty much out of luck since the inode did no longer contain the relevant information
and ext4magic also wasn’t able to <a href="http://ext4magic.sourceforge.net/howto_en.html#Recovery_process_5">recover the neccessary information from the journal</a>
either.</p>

<pre><code>debugfs:  inode_dump &lt;3146113&gt;
0000  a081 0000 8503 0000 e83a c15f e83a c15f  .........:._.:._
0020  e83a c15f 0000 0000 7200 0100 0800 0000  .:._....r.......
0040  0000 0800 0100 0000 0af3 0100 0400 0000  ................
0060  0000 0000 0000 0000 0100 0000 e6eb c000  ................
0100  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000  ................
*
0140  0000 0000 92d0 2cf5 0000 0000 0000 0000  ......,.........
0160  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 6fb2 0000  ............o...
0200  2000 e3fb 208a 515b 7c65 5d5a 7c65 5d5a   ... .Q[|e]Z|e]Z
0220  e83a c15f 7c65 5d5a 0000 0000 0000 0000  .:._|e]Z........
0240  0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000 0000  ................
*
</code></pre>

<p>However, if you’re in a similar situation – the ext4magic how-tos are really helpful and worth a try.</p>

<h4 id="successful-recovery">Successful recovery</h4>

<p>There is this one other approach to file recovery that is often recommended on the internet, usually
for “small text files”: Just <code>grep</code> your whole disk for known parts of its contents! So why wouldn’t
this work on larger non-text files as well?</p>

<p>The first problem is obviously what to grep for. The only thing I know about the missing file, apart
from its rough size, is that it’s a FLV video file. Luckily, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_Video#Flash_Video_Structure">all FLV files</a>
that contain video start with the byte sequence <code>FLV\x01\x05</code>. So let’s search our 2 TB disk for
that byte sequence and print out the byte offset of all occurences!</p>

<pre><code>cat /dev/md2 \
	| pv -s 1888127576000 \
	| grep -P --byte-offset --text 'FLV\x01\x05' \
	| tee -a /mnt/storagebox/grep-log.txt
</code></pre>

<p>This took roughly 7 hours. The <code>pv</code> command with the (rough) total size of the disk is optional, but gives you
a nice progress bar. Overall, this took a little over 6 hours on our server.</p>

<p><code>grep</code> works line-based, which in a binary file menas “any byte sequence between two ASCII line breaks”. The
log file therefore contained lots of lines like this:</p>

<pre><code>184473878409:&lt;some binary data&gt;FLV&lt;some binary data&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>In total, the search found 126 FLV file headers on our disk. This was pretty reassuring, since we had 122 FLV files
still known to the file system – so there are at least four FLV byte sequences without a filename!</p>

<pre><code># find /mnt/disk/var/recordings/ -name '*.flv' -not -empty -ls | wc -l
122
</code></pre>

<p>Now, I needed to find out which of the 126 byte sequences did not have a filename. Since I really didn’t want
to spend all weekend with a deep-dive into the ext4 disk layout, I went for an easier solution: For every file
still known in the file system, I computed a hash of the first 500 kilobytes of the file:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>#!/usr/bin/python3
</span><span>import</span> <span>glob</span>
<span>import</span> <span>hashlib</span>
<span>import</span> <span>os</span>

<span>hashsize</span> <span>=</span> <span>500</span> <span>*</span> <span>1024</span>
<span>known_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>not_deleted_files</span> <span>=</span> <span>sorted</span><span>(</span>
    <span>glob</span><span>.</span><span>glob</span><span>(</span><span>'/mnt/disk/var/recordings/*.flv'</span><span>)</span> <span>+</span> 
    <span>glob</span><span>.</span><span>glob</span><span>(</span><span>'/mnt/disk/var/recordings/public/*.flv'</span><span>)</span>
<span>)</span>
<span># Ignore files shorter than our hash size
</span><span>not_deleted_files</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>f</span> <span>for</span> <span>f</span> <span>in</span> <span>not_deleted_files</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>os</span><span>.</span><span>stat</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>).</span><span>st_size</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>hashsize</span>
<span>]</span>

<span>for</span> <span>fname</span> <span>in</span> <span>not_deleted_files</span><span>:</span>
    <span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>fname</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
        <span>h</span> <span>=</span> <span>hashlib</span><span>.</span><span>md5</span><span>(</span><span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>hashsize</span><span>)).</span><span>hexdigest</span><span>()</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"duplicate hash found:"</span><span>)</span>
        <span>known_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>fname</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>fname</span><span>)</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span>
    <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>not_deleted_files</span><span>),</span> <span>"files with"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>len</span><span>(</span><span>known_hashes</span><span>),</span> <span>"hashes"</span>
<span>)</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Interestingly, two files from the completely different customers shared the same hash of the first 500 kilobytes.
I haven’t tested it yet, but my theory is that those were streams that just did not contain any audio or video
in their first minutes, but only empty frames. However, since I knew this isn’t the case for my missing file,
I felt confident in proceeding with this approach.</p>

<p>Next, I computed the same hash for every byte offest found by grep and compared it to the hashes found in the
previous step:</p>

<figure><pre><code data-lang="python"><span>grep_log</span> <span>=</span> <span>'/mnt/storagebox/grep-log.txt'</span>
<span>disk</span> <span>=</span> <span>'/dev/md2'</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Parsing grep log…"</span><span>)</span>
<span>positions</span> <span>=</span> <span>[]</span>
<span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>grep_log</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>line</span> <span>in</span> <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>().</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>b'</span><span>\n</span><span>'</span><span>):</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>line</span><span>:</span>  <span># ignore empty line e.g. at end of file
</span>            <span>continue</span>
        <span>pos</span><span>,</span> <span>data</span> <span>=</span> <span>line</span><span>.</span><span>split</span><span>(</span><span>b':'</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span><span>)</span>
        <span>pos</span> <span>=</span> <span>int</span><span>(</span><span>pos</span><span>.</span><span>decode</span><span>())</span>
        <span># add offset of FLV within line
</span>        <span>binoffset</span> <span>=</span> <span>data</span><span>.</span><span>index</span><span>(</span><span>b"FLV</span><span>\x01</span><span>"</span><span>)</span>
        <span>pos</span> <span>+=</span> <span>binoffset</span> 
        <span>positions</span><span>.</span><span>append</span><span>(</span><span>pos</span><span>)</span>

<span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Computing hashes of files on disk…"</span><span>)</span>
<span>found_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{}</span>
<span>with</span> <span>open</span><span>(</span><span>disk</span><span>,</span> <span>'rb'</span><span>)</span> <span>as</span> <span>f</span><span>:</span>
    <span>for</span> <span>p</span> <span>in</span> <span>positions</span><span>:</span>
        <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>seek</span><span>(</span><span>p</span><span>)</span>
        <span>d</span> <span>=</span> <span>f</span><span>.</span><span>read</span><span>(</span><span>hashsize</span><span>)</span>
        <span>h</span> <span>=</span> <span>hashlib</span><span>.</span><span>md5</span><span>(</span><span>d</span><span>).</span><span>hexdigest</span><span>()</span>
        <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"At offset"</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span><span>,</span> <span>"found known hash"</span><span>,</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span>
                  <span>"corresponding to"</span><span>,</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>])</span>
        <span>else</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"At offset"</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span><span>,</span> <span>"found unknown hash"</span><span>,</span> <span>h</span><span>)</span>
        <span>found_hashes</span><span>[</span><span>h</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>p</span>

<span>unknown_hashes</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>h</span><span>:</span> <span>p</span> <span>for</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>p</span> <span>in</span> <span>found_hashes</span><span>.</span><span>items</span><span>()</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>h</span> <span>not</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span>
<span>}</span>
<span>files_not_found</span> <span>=</span> <span>[</span>
    <span>fname</span> <span>for</span> <span>h</span><span>,</span> <span>fname</span> <span>in</span> <span>known_hashes</span><span>.</span><span>items</span><span>()</span>
   …</code></pre></figure></section></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/">https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://behind.pretix.eu/2020/11/28/undelete-flv-file/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25242444</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 02:21:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Isetta: Writing a Game Engine from Scratch]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 136 | Comments 8 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25241361">thread link</a>) | @da_big_ghey
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        <div data-md-component="container">
          
            
              
            
            
              
            
          
          <div>
            <article>
              
                
                
                
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction<a href="#introduction" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h2>
<p>The Isetta Engine is a student-driven project about demystifying game engine development and providing a roadmap and relevant knowledge for novice developers. To do so, <a href="https://isetta.io/team/">our team</a> will make a game engine by ourselves starting from a collection of base frameworks, and document the process, pitfalls, and advice for our audience with periodic blogs. Besides that, we will conduct interviews with experienced professionals to augment our novice perspective. We believe the novice perspective from our blogs and expert perspective from the interviews will nicely come together and form a complete document to help people get started. </p>
<p>The reason we think more work needs to be done in this field is that too many game engine developers wait until the completion of the engine, typically years, to talk about their development. For studios, this is because they consider the final product to be the game, not the engine. For others, it may be because the engine is what they see as valuable, not the writing. As a result, these talks typically lose the minutiae of the actual daily struggles that took place in the development process. There are others who document their development which has been going on for years, which makes it a daunting task for newcomers to start following along. </p>
<p>Although the project is aimed at helping novice developers, this is not to be used as a sole source of learning engine development. Being new engine developers ourselves, we can't guarantee the way we develop the engine will be correct, which is why interviews will help the project remain grounded. This means others who are learning can use what we've done as a guide and not necessarily the ground truth. The blogs won't be a walkthrough/tutorial/step-by-step instructions on how to develop an engine. We are learning as we go and think our journey is what can be valuable to you. </p>
<h3 id="about-the-project">About the Project<a href="#about-the-project" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>This project is being done as a student-pitched project at the <a href="https://www.etc.cmu.edu/">Entertainment Technology Center</a> (ETC). The ETC is an interdisciplinary Master's degree program at Carnegie Mellon University where students' main focus is working on small teams on a project each semester during a 3-month time period. Throughout the semester, a team's work will be presented to faculty and peers with feedback and critique being presented to help aid in the project development. Our particular project idea has gone through multiple iterations to do the following:</p>
<ol>
<li>Simplify the engine to be feasible within 3 months and</li>
<li>Deliver content that would be useful, and hopefully enjoyable, to consume.</li>
</ol>
<p>As of writing this, we've learned that creating content that will satisfy both is difficult and time-consuming, so we will be focusing on writing these milestone-type blogs as well as posting various types of content to test which is the best form of presenting our work. The short project duration also forces us to think clearly about our scope and be lean on the features we include before starting. </p>
<h3 id="schedule">Schedule<a href="#schedule" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>During the course of this project <strong>(08/26 - 12/16, 2018</strong>), a blog post will be published every week to share our thoughts and process, and an interview will be published every 1-2 weeks. The interview schedule depends on our progress on the engine itself, as each interview's topic will be themed around our current work.</p>
<p>For latest schedule, see our <a href="https://isetta.io/schedule/">schedule</a> page.</p>
<h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites<a href="#prerequisites" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>Although we will cover some basic features of engine development, it will profoundly help if you have experience in C++ programming and developing software, especially games, as our project won't provide step-by-step instructions on how to do everything. For a list of resources on how to gain related knowledge, please go to the <a href="#Readings">Readings</a> section. Additional resources will be posted on our <a href="https://isetta.io/resources/">resource page</a>.</p>
<p>Another prerequisite is passion for learning game engine development. As you are still reading this, we assume you are as excited about this as we are. This will be a bumpy ride, but you will have us on your side.</p>
<h2 id="research">Research<a href="#research" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h2>
<p>Being a student-pitched ETC project means that the project needed to pass through a pitch process of consulting and convincing faculty in the program. This allowed us to receive feedback about what could be considered a reasonable/manageable scope and where we might hit challenges for a general project. For this project to be a valid ETC project as well as accomplish our mission statement, there needs to be a fine balance between documentation and development. </p>
<p>Before confronting the big monster of engine development and documentation, we thought it would be a good idea to gear up by getting input from people who have actually done this. During our pitch process, we reached out and got the chance to talk to numerous industry professionals and got extremely helpful advice from them. All of these suggestions helped us shape our project into what it is now and provided invaluable knowledge on how to start a game engine. Thus we encourage you, too, to approach professionals and get advice if possible. We've compiled our notes from our conversations with them into a write-up, which will be published soon.</p>
<h3 id="why-another-engine">Why another engine?<a href="#why-another-engine" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>Using an existing game engine like <a href="https://unity3d.com/">Unity</a>, <a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/what-is-unreal-engine-4">Unreal</a> or <a href="https://www.panda3d.org/">Panda3D</a> is always a handy option to make a game. These well-established engines have a strong collection of tools and APIs so that developers can focus on making the game, not the wheels. However, there is the limitation of not having full control over all systems in the engine as well as not knowing how the engine is processing the game logic and assets. These can obstruct the complex systems of an engine, so although you may have an understanding of how a physics or graphics engine works, each engine operates differently and optimizes for different constraints. </p>
<p>In terms of learning about game engines and how to develop one, these established engines aren't a good source. Panda3D, originally developed by Disney and expanded by past ETC projects, has an older codebase in 2018 with limited community involvement. It is also not using the current industry standard language (C++). Unity and Unreal are both too massive and too cutting-edge to be suitable engine learning material for novices. In addition, Unity's source code isn't publicly available so you technically can't learn from it. The huge codebase sets a high threshold for any beginner to get started.</p>
<h2 id="roadmap">Roadmap<a href="#roadmap" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h2>
<p>The Isetta Engine will support the most primitive form of networked multiplayer twin-stick shooter game. Networked multiplayer was selected to be a part of the engine because it offers significant design and development challenge on every level of the project, and will help differentiate this engine from others being developed. We decided to create the engine in 3D for two reasons: Most AAA engines are 3D, and 3D requires more math and problem solving for us as developers to learn and grow from.</p>
<p>While planning, and before we knew too much about game engines, we had a basic idea of what a game engine would consist of. The image below displays the second/third iteration of what the Isetta engine would look like. We were initially naive thinking we may be able to do both networking as well as physics, however quickly came to grips that would balloon the scope too much. The audio and graphics were and are still planned to be imported from external libraries, and more of the discussion of what is imported and why will be included in a future blog. This diagram of the engine will soon be replaced with more in-depth explanations.</p>
<p><img alt="alt_text" src="https://isetta.io/images/blogs/week-0/pitch_architecture.png" title="Engine Architecture During Pitch"></p>
<h3 id="genre">Genre<a href="#genre" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>As for our choice of the twin-stick shooter genre, we came to the decision after lengthy consideration of the components required to build other game types as well as how that genre would utilize multiplayer. Twin-stick shooters can effectively have little to no physics, which is different from collisions (this will be explained in <a href="https://isetta.io/blogs/week-1/">week 1 blog</a>). Likewise, the information passed between networked sessions is relatively minimal and not too strict on latency. What's more, a twin-stick shooter specializes in simplistic gameplay that doesn't need a world editor or too much design. </p>
<p>In a Skype meeting, <a href="https://waltdestler.com/">Walt Destler</a> explained to us that each game -and more particularly, each genre- requires vastly different netcode solutions. This is also one of the reasons why we prefer netcode over physics, as it can greatly narrow down the genre options. For example, multiplayer shooters, specifically PvP shooters, require small amounts of information to be passed (i.e. bullet and player locations) from server to client with relatively low latency. PvP shooters can also feature client-side prediction <sup id="fnref:0"><a href="#fn:0" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> as well as the additional requirement of lobby/matchmaking with usually more than 2 players. On the other hand, genres like turn-based strategy require large amounts of information to be passed (all units, decisions, resources, etc.) to all users without too much concern for latency or prediction.</p>
<h3 id="building-with-an-example-game">Building with an Example Game<a href="#building-with-an-example-game" title="Permanent link">¶</a></h3>
<p>The other piece of advice we frequently heard from professionals and our faculty alike was the benefit of developing a game in conjunction with the engine. Doing so, they explained, allows you to prove and demonstrate your engine works as expected. The game can also test features to show immediate edge cases of the engine. </p>
<p>Another nicety of developing an engine is that feature creep can be prevented when you keep expanding certain features that won't be utilized in the final product. What the game built from this engine <em>won't</em> be is something original or necessarily fun. However, that's not to say a fun, original game couldn't be created from this engine. The idea of our sample game is to intentionally be derivative so features of a basic twin-stick shooter will be already included in the engine, rather than only specific …</p></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/">https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://isetta.io/blogs/week-0/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25241361</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 23:09:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Growl in Retirement]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 440 | Comments 228 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25241030">thread link</a>) | @flyingyeti
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | http://336699.org/GrowlRetirement | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://336699.org/GrowlRetirement">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section id="container">
  <article id="8GugXoUrk4po3a8J7EZnDS">
	<time datetime="2020-11-28">November 28, 2020</time>
  
	<p>Growl is being retired after surviving for 17 years. With the announcement of Apple’s new hardware platform, a general shift of developers to Apple’s notification system, and a lack of obvious ways to improve Growl beyond what it is and has been, we’re announcing the retirement of Growl as of today.</p>

<p>It’s been a long time coming. Growl is the project I worked on for the longest period of my open source career. However at WWDC in 2012 everyone on the team saw the writing on the wall. This was my only WWDC. This is the WWDC where Notification Center was announced. Ironically Growl was called Global Notifications Center, before I renamed it to Growl because I thought the name was too geeky. There’s even a sourceforge project for Global Notifications Center still out there if you want to go find it.</p>

<p>We’ve had a lot of support over the years; from our hosting providers at <a href="http://www.networkredux.com/">Network Redux</a>, <a href="http://www.cachefly.com/">CacheFly</a> and others, to all of the apps using our framework, bindings, or any other integration. Special thanks go to <a href="https://adium.im/">Adium</a> and <a href="https://colloquy.app/">Colloquy</a>. Without these two projects having developers who wanted different types notifications, Growl wouldn’t have existed. Without Growl I do not know that we would have any sort of decent notification system in OS X, iOS, Android or who knows what else. </p>

<p>Special thanks goes to <a href="https://www.transifex.com/">Transifex</a> who made localizing into 24 languages a lot easier than anything else we tried. It’s a fantastic product, if you make software please try it. Our localizers were fantastic people and should all be commended for their work. </p>

<p>For developers we recommend transitioning away from Growl at this point. The apps themselves are gone from the app store, however the code itself still lives. Everything from our rake build system to our code is available for use on our <a href="https://github.com/growl/growl/">GitHub page</a></p>

  <figure id="kudo_8GugXoUrk4po3a8J7EZnDS">
    <a href="#kudo">
      
    </a>
    <p>1,805</p>
    <p>Kudos</p>
  </figure>
  <figure id="kudo_side_8GugXoUrk4po3a8J7EZnDS">
    <a href="#kudo">
      
    </a>
    <p>1,805</p>
    <p>Kudos</p>
  </figure>
</article>

</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://336699.org/GrowlRetirement</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25241030</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 22:19:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Blogging vs. Blog Setups]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 258 | Comments 105 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25240939">thread link</a>) | @Kye
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Hi, I'm Rakhim. I teach, program, make podcasts, comics and videos on computer science at <a href="https://codexpanse.com/">Codexpanse.com</a>. You can learn more about <a href="https://rakhim.org/about">my work</a> and even <a href="https://www.patreon.com/rakhim">support me</a> via Patreon.</p><p><form action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/rakhim" method="post" target="popupwindow" onsubmit="window.open('https://buttondown.email/rakhim','popupwindow')"><label for="bd-email">Oh, and I have a monthly non-spammy personal newsletter:</label><br>

</form></p><nav><p><a href="https://rakhim.org/">Home</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://blog.rakhim.org/">Blog</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/about">About</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://codexpanse.com/">Courses</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/talks">Talks</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined">Comics</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/bookshelf">Bookshelf</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/codexpanse">YT</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://twitter.com/freetonik">TW</a>
<span>|</span>
<a href="https://rakhim.org/index.xml">RSS</a></p></nav><p>© Rakhim Davletkaliyev, 2020<br>Powered by <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a>, <a href="https://www.netlify.com/">Netlify and the Everett interpretation of QM.</a></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25240939</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 22:03:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Second Swiss firm allegedly sold encrypted spying devices]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 247 | Comments 171 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25240179">thread link</a>) | @secfirstmd
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/second-swiss-firm-allegedly-sold-encrypted-spying-devices/46186432 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/second-swiss-firm-allegedly-sold-encrypted-spying-devices/46186432">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<section>
<div>
<div>
<figure>
<picture>
<source srcset="https://www.swissinfo.ch/resource/image/46186430/landscape_ratio3x2/880/587/a683e845a8c9bdb270a5b635dfc947ed/gO/omnisec.jpg" media="(min-width: 900px)">
<source srcset="https://www.swissinfo.ch/resource/image/46186430/landscape_ratio3x2/580/387/a683e845a8c9bdb270a5b635dfc947ed/Gx/omnisec.jpg" media="(min-width: 321px)">

</picture>
<figcaption>
Omnisec is the second Swiss company that allegedly sold manipulated encryption devices to US intelligence services. <span>Keystone / Walter Bieri</span>
</figcaption> </figure>
</div>
</div><p>Swiss public television, SRF, has found a second company besides Crypto AG&nbsp;was involved in manufacturing manipulated devices allegedly used for spying by foreign intelligence.</p>
<span>This content was published on November 26, 2020 - 11:34</span>
<time datetime="2020-11-26T11:34:28+01:00">

</time><p>According to <a rel="noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.srf.ch/news/schweiz/verschluesselungsgeraete-geheimdienstaffaere-weitere-schweizer-firma-rueckt-in-den-fokus">SRF sources</a>, the Swiss company Omnisec AG had ties to US intelligence services. This follows revelations in February by SRF, German television ZDF and <em>The Washington Post</em> that Zug-based firm Crypto AG was at the heart of a huge international spying operation led by the CIA, and to a lesser extent by the German BND spy agency.&nbsp;Omnisec was one of the largest competitors of Crypto AG.</p><p>Swiss cryptologist and professor Ueli Maurer was a consultant for Omnisec for years and told SRF that in 1989 US intelligence services (National Security Agency) contacted Omnisec through him.</p><p>Of concern are the OC-500 series devices. Devices were sold to several Swiss federal agencies. However, Swiss&nbsp;authorities only noticed the devices weren't secure&nbsp;in the mid-2000s.</p><p>Several Swiss companies also received manipulated devices from Omnisec, including Switzerland’s largest bank, UBS. It is unclear whether the authorities informed UBS about the weak devices in the mid-2000s. UBS told SRF that it does not comment on security matters but that it had no indications that sensitive data were exposed at the time.</p>
<p>Omnisec, founded in 1987, manufactured voice, fax and data encryption equipment. It was dissolved a few years ago. The most recent head of the company, Clemens Kammer, told SRF that Omnisec customers “have and will continue to place great value on security, confidentiality, discretion and reliability in business relationships”.</p><p>Some politicians have called for further investigations into these latest allegations that may reveal who, if anyone, in the federal government knew of Omnisec’s business affairs with foreign intelligence.</p><h2>Crypto affair</h2><p>Earlier this month, a nine-month&nbsp;<a rel="noopener" target="_blank" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20201110183555/https:/www.parlament.ch/press-releases/Pages/mm-gpdel-2020-11-10.aspx">investigation</a>&nbsp;by the Swiss parliamentary audit committee (GPDel), found that the Swiss intelligence service knew that the US Central Intelligence Agency was behind the Swiss-based Crypto AG as far back as 1993. The report says that Swiss intelligence later collaborated with them to gather information from foreign sources.&nbsp;</p><p>More than 100 countries bought encryption devices from the Zug-based company, which did business under the guise of Swiss neutrality. In reality, the firm belonged to the CIA and Germany intelligence service, which could freely read what it encrypted. Information intercepted with the help of Crypto’s devices changed the course of events, including the Iran hostage crisis of 1979.</p> </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/second-swiss-firm-allegedly-sold-encrypted-spying-devices/46186432</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25240179</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 20:18:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[30 years later, QBasic is still the best]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 312 | Comments 131 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25239424">thread link</a>) | @ohjeez
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | http://www.nicolasbize.com/blog/30-years-later-qbasic-is-still-the-best/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.nicolasbize.com/blog/30-years-later-qbasic-is-still-the-best/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p><span><em>(5 minutes read)</em></span></p>
<p><span>My oldest son Noah turned 7 three months ago. If he could trade his family for a 2 hour session of playing minecraft, he would do it in a heartbeat. The other love of his life is Super Mario Maker, and&nbsp;it’s been a thrill to see him play the same game and levels that I played when I was his age. About 5 months ago, I left my family for my yearly pilgrimage of <a href="http://ludumdare.com/compo/">ludum dare</a>: a game dev competition during which I lock myself away with friends, return to a&nbsp;state of primitive caveman, not sleep for 48h, and create&nbsp;a full game from scratch (play it at the end of this post!) As I proudly showed my revolutionary AAA title to my wife, Noah was naturally intrigued and I introduced him to the world of code, showing him how simple&nbsp;words&nbsp;(he had just learned how to read) produced an actual game. Since&nbsp;that very day, Noah&nbsp;has been asking me repeatedly to teach him how to make&nbsp;his own video games. And for the past 5 months, I have been looking for the holy grail of language/IDE for kids in the hope of turning that spark of interest into a memorable experience…</span></p>
<p><span>My quest has led me to&nbsp;endless forums, through which I have tried countless suggestions: SmallBasic, Pico-8, Smalltalk, Scratch, etc. I have even inquired of the Great&nbsp;Oracles of StackOverflow,&nbsp;to&nbsp;no avail. After 5 months,&nbsp;I&nbsp;ended up with a disappointing conclusion: nothing is even close to what I had back in another era. 30 years later, QBasic is still the best when it comes to&nbsp;discovering programming.&nbsp;</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span>“OMG please don’t teach him GOTOs!!”</span></p>
</blockquote>
<pre><code>10 PRINT “OH NO, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!!!”
20 GOTO 10</code></pre>
<p><span>Yes, QBasic is a terrible procedural language. It introduces one to concepts widely considered harmful, uses awkward syntax for implicit declarations, is not case sensitive, is non-zero-based, etc. the list goes on… When developing a skill, it is much better to acquire the right reflexes from the start rather than have to correct years of bad practice. Following this advice, I should have probably started off with&nbsp;the basics of the ruby language which I love. Yet, while most of those QBasic concepts are today generally considered&nbsp;as red flags by our peers, they each served a very specific&nbsp;purpose at the time: to keep the language simple and accessible, a notion that every other language has left behind in favor of flexibility, complexity and logic.</span></p>
<p><span>I installed QBasic on my son’s 11” HP Stream today, having to hack a DOSBox manual installation. He double clicked the icon on his desktop and in a split second, we were in the IDE, greeted with the introduction screen which brought back so many memories to my mind:</span></p>
<p><img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/01/QBasic_Opening_Screen.png" alt="" width="640" height="400"></p>
<p><span>I then told Noah that there was a very sacred ritual, mandatory&nbsp;for anyone who enters the secret&nbsp;inner&nbsp;circle of programmers, to start off with a program that greets every other programmer out there. As I dictated the formula, he slowly&nbsp;searched for each&nbsp;key, carefully&nbsp;typing with his right finger&nbsp;the magic words: <code>PRINT “hello world”</code></span></p>
<p><span>He pressed F5 and looked amazed as he saw his code being compiled into text rendered on his black screen. He smiled, gave me a high-five, and then scribbled down the code in his little notebook so that he could remember later.</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_1.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p>We went on to a couple more commands: CLS, COLOR, PLAY, INPUT, and IF. There was nothing to explain: no complexity, no awkward operator, no abstract concepts, no documentation that needed to be read, no notion of objects/class/methods, no framework to install, no overwhelming menu/buttons in the IDE, no special keyword or parenthesis. It was code in its purest simplicity and form.</p>
<p><span>After less than an hour, he wrote his first program on his own – an interactive and incredibly subtle application which lets you know the computer’s feelings towards&nbsp;you as an individual and sensible human being:</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_3.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p><span>…which he ran with utmost pride for his cousin and best friend Christian:</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_4.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p><span>…after which he proceeded to easily explain him&nbsp;</span><span><b>how</b></span><span>&nbsp;it worked and what the code was doing!</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_5.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="600"></p>
<p><span>And so it was that in a single hour, my 7 year old was able to not only write his first text game, but also to experience the fun and thrill that comes from creating, compiling and executing his own little program. Bonus points, it all fit on a single notebook page:</span></p>
<p><img src="http://nicolasbize.com/blog/images/noah_2.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="800"></p>
<p><span>I was so glad that he was able to understand why I keep saying that I have the best job in the world.&nbsp;</span><span>My only regret today was to realize that in more than 30 years, we have not been able to come up with something&nbsp;better for our kids: Qbasic has a limited set of simple keywords (the entire help fits on a single F1 screen and is packed with simple examples!), does not distract the coder with any visual artifacts, has a very confined and cosy dev environment, shows errors as early as possible, compiles and executes the code in a heartbeat with a single key, and is extremely straightforward. &nbsp;We have built more robust and more complex languages/frameworks/IDEs (which are of course necessary for any real-life application), but we have never really made a simpler or more direct access to the thrill of programming than QBasic. Even running QBasic today has become dreadful&nbsp;to the novice that uses&nbsp;a modern Mac/PC/Linux machine, whereas it used to simply require inserting a 3,5” floppy in the A:\ disk drive…</span></p>
<p><span>Enough rant, today is all about the celebration of yet another person who discovered the excitement and beauty of programming!</span></p>
<p><span>Cheers!</span></p>
<p><span>(as promised, <a href="http://nicolasbize.com/ld34/">my AAA title</a> for which I await&nbsp;EA’s call to purchase copyrights)</span></p>
			</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.nicolasbize.com/blog/30-years-later-qbasic-is-still-the-best/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25239424</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 18:32:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Machine Learning for Art with Google’s Emil Wallner]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 25 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25239217">thread link</a>) | @andreyk
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://www.letstalkai.show/e/mlart-interview/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.letstalkai.show/e/mlart-interview/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	<div>


		
			<div id="post-15958234">
				<p><a href="https://www.letstalkai.show/">
										<img src="https://pbcdn1.podbean.com/imglogo/image-logo/7703921/Lets_Talk_Logo.jpg"></a></p><div>
				<div>
					
					<p>Nov 27th, 2020 by <a title="Posts by Skynet Today">Skynet Today</a> </p>
				</div>

				<div>
					 <div>
<p>An interview with <span>Emil Wallner, the creator of mlart.co . Emil is an internet-educated, independent machine learning researcher, and resident at the Google Arts &amp; Culture Lab. As a resident at Google he is using machine learning to explore art and culture. Part-time, he applies machine learning to logical tasks such as programming and mathematics.</span></p>
<p>Subscribe: <a href="https://feed.podbean.com/aitalk/feed.xml">RSS</a> | <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/lets-talk-ai/id1502782720">iTunes</a> | <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/17HiNdxcoKJLLNibIAyUch">Spotify</a> | <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCKARTq-t5SPMzwtft8FWwnA">YouTube</a></p>
<div>
<p>Check out coverage of similar topics at <a href="http://www.skynettoday.com/">www.skynettoday.com</a></p>
<p>Theme: Deliberate Thought Kevin MacLeod (incompetech.com)</p>
</div>
</div>
									</div>

				

   <p><span id="postbar_15958234"> <span> | </span><a href="https://www.podbean.com/site/EpisodeDownload/PBF380DAKYNN9" target="_blank">Download</a> </span></p>			</div>

		


	</div>
</div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.letstalkai.show/e/mlart-interview/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25239217</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 18:08:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Apple Silicon M1: A Developer's Perspective]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 393 | Comments 485 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25238608">thread link</a>) | @steipete
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://steipete.com/posts/apple-silicon-m1-a-developer-perspective/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://steipete.com/posts/apple-silicon-m1-a-developer-perspective/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div> <p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/7dbf04694dfeeec9985b2ebb27cc1faff153111b/75e93/assets/img/2020/m1/m1.jpg"></p><p>The excitement around Apple’s new M1 chip is <a href="https://www.singhkays.com/blog/apple-silicon-m1-black-magic/">everywhere</a>. I bought a MacBook Air 16GB M1 to see how viable it is as main development machine - here’s an early report after a week of testing.</p><h2 id="xcode">Xcode</h2><p>Xcode runs FAST on the M1. Compiling the <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/">PSPDFKit PDF SDK</a> (debug, arm64) can almost compete with the fastest Intel-based MacBook Pro Apple offers to date, with <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332052251712614405?s=21">8:49 min vs 7:31 min</a>. For comparison, my Hackintosh builds the same in less than 5 minutes.</p><p>One can’t overstate how impressive this is for a fan-less machine. Apple’s last experiment with fan-less MacBooks was the 12-inch version from 2017, which builds the same project in 41 minutes.</p><p>Our tests mostly ran just fine, although I found <a href="https://github.com/Aloshi/dukglue/pull/27">a bug specific to arm64</a> that we missed before, as we don’t run our tests on actual hardware on CI. Moving the Simulator to the same architecture as shipping devices will be beneficial and will help find more bugs.</p><p>Testing iOS below 14 is problematic. It seems <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332654247809257473?s=21">WebKit is crashing in a memory allocator</a>, throwing EXC_BAD_INSTRUCTION (code=EXC_I386_INVOP, subcode=0x0) (Apple folks: FB8920323). Performance also seems really bad, with Xcode periodically <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332348616145563653?s=21">freezing</a> and the whole system becoming so <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1332648748158246922?s=21">slow</a> that the mouse cursor gets choppy. Some Simulators even make problems on iOS 14, <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1331628274783543297?s=21">such as the iPad Air (4th gen) which still emulates Intel</a>, so try to avoid that one.</p><p>We were extremely excited to be moving our CI to Mac Mini’s with M1 chip and are <a href="https://www.macstadium.com/m1-mini">waiting on MacStadium to release devices</a>, however it seems we will have to restrict tests to iOS 14 for that to work. With our current schedule, we plan to drop iOS 12 in Q3 2021 and iOS 13 in Q3 2022, so it will be a while until we can fully move to Apple Silicon.</p><p>There is a chance that Apple fixes these issues, however it’s not something to count on - given that this only affects older versions of iOS, the problem will at some point just “go away”.</p><p><strong>Update:</strong> We’re working around the WebKit crashes for now via detecting Rosetta2 translation at runtime and simply skipping the tests where WebKit is used. This isn’t great, but luckily we’re not using WebKit a lot in our current project. <a href="https://gist.github.com/steipete/e15b1fabffc7da7d49c92e3fbd06971a">See my Gist for details</a>. Performance seems acceptable if you restrict parallel testing to at most two instances - else the system simply runs out of RAM and swapping is just really slow.</p><h2 id="docker">Docker</h2><p>We use Docker to automate our Website and load environments for our <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/pdf-sdk/web/">Web and Server PDF SDKs</a>. Docker posted a <a href="https://www.docker.com/blog/apple-silicon-m1-chips-and-docker/">status update blog post</a> about the current state of things, admitting that it currently won’t work but that they’re <a href="https://github.com/docker/roadmap/issues/142">working on it</a>. There are more <a href="https://finestructure.co/blog/2020/11/27/running-docker-on-apple-silicon-m1-follow-up">hacky ways to use Apple’s Hypervisor to run Docker container manually</a>, however this needs arm-based containers.</p><p>I expect a solution in Q1 2021 that runs arm-based containers. We’ll have to do some work to add arm-support (something already on the roadmap) so this is only a transitional issue.</p><h2 id="virtualization-and-windows">Virtualization and Windows</h2><p>To test our <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/pdf-sdk/windows/">Windows PDF SDK</a>, most folks are using a VMware virtual machine with Windows 10 and Visual Studio. Currently none of the Mac virtualisation solutions support Apple Silicon, however both <a href="https://appleinsider.com/articles/20/11/11/parallels-confirms-apple-m1-support-amid-silence-from-other-virtualization-companies">VMware and Parallels</a> are working on it. I do not expect Virtualbox to be updated <a href="https://forums.virtualbox.org/viewtopic.php?f=8&amp;t=98742">anytime soon</a>.</p><p>I expect that eventually we’ll be able to run ARM-based Windows with commercial tooling. Various <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2020/11/27/arm-windows-virtualization-m1-mac/">proof-of-concepts</a> already exist, and performance seems <a href="https://twitter.com/imbushuo/status/1332772957609922561?s=21">extremely promising</a>. Microsoft currently doesn’t sell ARM-based Windows, so getting a license will be interesting.</p><p>ARM-Windows can emulate x86 applications, and Microsoft is working on <a href="https://www.neowin.net/news/it039s-official-x64-emulation-is-coming-to-windows-on-arm">x64 emulation</a>, which is already rolling out in Insider builds. In a few months, it should be possible to develop and test our Windows SDK with Visual Studio on M1 in reasonable performance.</p><p>Running older versions of macOS might be more problematic. We currently support macOS 10.14 with our <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/blog/2017/pspdfkit-for-macos/">AppKit PDF SDK</a> and macOS 10.15 with the <a href="https://pspdfkit.com/blog/2019/pspdfkit-for-mac-catalyst/">Catalyst PDF SDK</a>, both OS releases that require testing. It remains to be seen if VMWare or Parallels include a complete x64 emulation layer. This would likely be really slow, so I wouldn’t count on it.</p><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/bbf100981357e4bc26c49722d31253daf76d293d/5b456/assets/img/2020/m1/memory.png" alt=""></p><p>Lastly, 16 GB RAM just isn’t a lot. When running parallel tests, the machine starts to heavily swap and performance really goes down the drain. This will be even more problematic with virtual machines running. Future machines will offer 32 GB options to alleviate this issue.</p><p><strong>Update:</strong> <a href="https://gist.github.com/niw/e4313b9c14e968764a52375da41b4278#file-readme-md">How to run Windows 10 on ARM in Qemu with Hypervisor.framework patches on Apple Silicon Mac</a></p><h2 id="android-studio">Android Studio</h2><p>IntelliJ is working on porting the <a href="https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/JBR-2526">JetBrains Runtime</a> to Apple Silicon. The apps currently work through Rosetta 2, however building via Gradle is <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/androiddev/comments/jx4ntt/apple_macbook_air_m1_is_very_slow_in_gradle_builds/">extremely slow</a>. Gradle creates code at runtime, which seems a particular bad combination with the Rosetta 2 ahead-of-time translation logic.</p><p>I expect that most issues will be solved by Q1 2021, however it will likely be some more time until all Java versions run great on ARM. A lot of effort has been put into <a href="https://bell-sw.com/java/arm/performance/2019/01/15/the-status-of-java-on-arm/">loop unrolling and vectorisation</a>, not everything there is available on ARM just yet.</p><p><strong>Update:</strong> <a href="https://www.azul.com/press_release/azul-announces-support-of-java-builds-of-openjdk-for-apple-silicon/">Azul offers macOS JDKs for arm64</a>, including for <a href="https://www.azul.com/downloads/zulu-community/?os=macos&amp;architecture=arm-64-bit&amp;package=jdk">Java 8</a>.</p><h2 id="homebrew">Homebrew</h2><p><a href="https://brew.sh/">Homebrew</a> currently works via Rosetta 2. Just prefix everything with <code>arch -x86_64</code> and it’ll just work. It is possible to install an additional (arm-based) version of Homebrew <a href="https://soffes.blog/homebrew-on-apple-silicon">under <code>/opt/homebrew</code></a> and mix setup, as <a href="https://github.com/Homebrew/brew/issues/7857">more and more software</a> is adding support for arm.</p><p>This is not a problem currently (performance is good) and will eventually just work natively.</p><h2 id="applications">Applications</h2><p>Most applications just work, Rosetta is barely noticeable. Larger apps to take a longer initial performance hit (e.g. Microsoft Word takes <a href="https://www.zdnet.com/article/microsoft-office-will-be-about-20-second-slower-initially-on-apple-silicon-rosetta-2/">around 20 seconds</a> until everything is translated), but then these binaries are cached and subsequent runs are fast.</p><p>There’s the occasional app that can’t be translated and fails on startup (e.g. <a href="https://beamer-app.com/download">Beamer</a> or the <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en_gh/drive/download/">Google Drive “Backup and Sync” client</a>), but this is rare. Some apps are confused about their place on disk and ask to be moved to the Applications directory, when really it’s just the translated binary that runs somewhere else. Most of these dialogs can be ignored. Some apps (e.g. Visual Studio Code) <a href="https://twitter.com/steipete/status/1331884524934995968?s=21">block auto-updating</a> as the translated app location is readonly. However, in case of VS Code, the Insider build is already updated to ARM and just works.</p><p>Electron-based apps are slow if they run on Rosetta. It seems the highly optimized V8 JavaScript compiler blocks ahead-of-time translation. The latest stable version of Electron (Version 11) already <a href="https://www.electronjs.org/blog/apple-silicon">fully supports Apple Silicon</a>, and companies like Slack already updated their beta version to run natively.</p><p>Google just shipped <a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/3597749/google-releases-chrome-87-with-support-for-apple-silicon-macs.html">Chrome that runs on ARM</a>, however there’s still quite a performance gap between it and Apple Safari, which just <em>flies</em> on Apple Silicon.</p><h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2><p>The new M1 MacBooks are fast, beautiful and silent and the hype is absolutely justified. There’s still a lot to do on the software-front to catch up, and the bugs around older iOS Simulators are especially problematic.</p><p>All of that can be fixed in software and the whole industry is currently working on making the experience better, so by next year, when Apple updates the 16-inch MacBook Pro and releases the next generation of their M chip line, it should be absolutely possible to use a M1 Mac as main dev machine.</p><p>For the time being, the M1 will be my <del>travel</del> secondary laptop, and I’ll keep working on the 2,4 GHz 16-inch MacBook Pro with 32 GB RAM, which just is the faster machine. I’ll be much harder to accept the loud, always-on fans though, now that I know what soon will be possible.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://steipete.com/posts/apple-silicon-m1-a-developer-perspective/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25238608</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 16:47:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[No Config for Old Men]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 358 | Comments 285 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25238523">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://datagubbe.se/noconf/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://datagubbe.se/noconf/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>


<p><b>...or anyone else, for that matter.</b></p>

<p><i>Autumn 2020</i></p>

<p>Ask anyone who's really into cooking and they'll tell you how important it is to have a kitchen that's arranged just right. To someone who rarely cooks, a kitchen is probably just a place to store a few pots and a toaster, and the placement of such stuff doesn't matter much: canned soup and microwave dinners are designed for ease of preparation.</p>


<p>For the enthusiastic home cook, however, a lot of things can go wrong. Often there's only a second's notice to fix something that might ruin a perfect meal or set you back hours of hard toil. Hollandaise starting to split? Better bring out that ice cold water post haste! Garlic burning? Better chop some more right this instant, or the pasta will be overcooked and there goes the Aglio e Oglio.</p>


<p>To achieve speed, you have to know where your knives, pots, pans, spoons, whisks and other utensils are and you want to be able to arrange them so that they're easy to reach. Seasonings, spices, herbs and condiments should be within reach from the stove. Then there's the mise en place before the actual cooking begins: chopping all the vegetables, cubing the meat, slicing the bacon and so on.</p>


<p>All of this is, thankfully, easy to achieve. Even the most cramped kitchen will, after having been battle tested through a few meals, be as optimal as possible according to the cook's personal preference. The same goes for painters, carpenters, car mechanics and even office dwellers. Hammer missing from the hammer hook? For shame! Stapler not to the immediate right of the stack of post-its? Well it should be!</p>


<h3>The regulated kitchen</h3>


<p>Now imagine if you couldn't organize your kitchen to your heart's content. Not because you're lacking the funds or skills, but because some federally appointed clerk is constantly coming to inspect it.</p>


<p>"Nah," he says, adjusting his clip-on tie, "you can't put your spices there. Against regulations. All spices must be kept more than two yards from the stove at all times." He then goes on to explain that you'll have to call him every time you want to use the stove, just to make sure the pots you're using are compliance tested. Plus, they have to be stored in the government approved pot storage cabinet below the sink, otherwise they're not fit for kitchen use.</p>


<p>Want to change the color of the counter top? Sorry, no can do. Want to switch from glass bowls to stainless? Alas, you used to be able a few years ago, but nobody wants stainless anymore anyway, right? The salt <i>can</i> be put next to the stove, but it's not recommended and might change in the near future. Knives are now to be honed every Tuesday afternoon by a designated craftsman. Sure, you can postpone a few times, but eventually, you just have to live with that. Plus, there's going to be some dudes coming to inventory your pantry on a regular basis, most likely when you're in the middle of cooking something really complicated. There's no use in protesting - this is all for your own good.</p>

<p>And yes.


</p><p>Of course this is a metaphor for computers.</p>


<h3>The curious disappearance of configuration</h3>


<p>For the casual user, some of this can <i>maybe</i> be convenient - or at least not annoying. If someone who rarely uses the kitchen has decided to whip up a home cooked feast, it doesn't matter that the spices are kept strangely far from the stove: they're just happy they found them. And <i>maybe</i> there is, for the casual user, some "security" in lock-in efforts such as MacOS calling home<sup><a href="#footnote1">[1]</a></sup> to check if a program is allowed to run and that web browsers automatically block certain URLs.</p>


<p>Likewise, maybe a handful of confused beginners are helped by the fact that certain system settings are extremely hard to find, or that you're supposed to put all your photos in a specific directory, or that you can't decide what partition you want to install a program on, or that some indexing service starts running when you least expect it, or that not a single application gives a crap about the few color settings you're allowed to make.</p>


<p>For the power user, such things range from nuisances to something that seriously hampers productivity and creativity.</p>


<p>It used to be that whenever I got a new computer, I spent a day or two setting it up. I selected the fonts I wanted to use, I picked the colors I liked for window decorations and GUI elements, I installed my preferred tools and utilities and I organized the desktop icons and program launchers to my liking. It took a bit of time, but it was a labor of love. In times of trouble I was, if nothing else, at least the boss of my own desktop environment.</p>


<p>I don't know of any proprietary OS where I can do that anymore. Linux is, considering what's going on with the major distributions, desktop environments and UI toolkits, seemingly heading the same way. Sure, pick your own window manager, see if we care - we've got client side decorations! Want to theme your GUI? Yeah, but not in our Snap packages you won't! Want to turn off cursor blinking? Mmmmyyeeaahhh, not too sure about that. Oh, you started a GUI file manager? Hey, enjoy the ten new folders we've littered your home directory with! They all start with capital letters: designed for typing convenience in a case sensitive file system.</p>


<p>Of course I still spend a fair amount of time setting up a Windows machine, but these days it's not the joyful experience of configuring the best fonts and nicest colors and arranging the icons on the start menu in the correct order for my muscle memory. Instead it's usually a week of swearing over removed settings and working hard to find the ones that actually remain, or trying various registry hacks to circumvent seemingly unchangeable defaults. I'm working against the system instead of with it, and someone else is trying to boss me around.</p>


<h3>A better example</h3>


<p>All of this could be different. It used to be. On my <a href="https://datagubbe.se/ltmag/">Amiga</a>, I could configure <i>everything</i>. Apart from things like fonts and colors I could draw my own mouse pointer, tiling desktop backgrounds and icons. (Yes, the system really shipped with separate little paint programs just for pointers, desktop tiles and icons.) I could customize double click speed and key repeat rates on millisecond levels. I could even control the exact position of individual icons and the size and position of every individual directory window opened.</p>


<p>Most casual users didn't care about all that, but they didn't have to. The system came with a reasonable set of defaults and when or if they grew more proficient and wanted to change something about their daily working environment, they had the option to do so.</p>


<p>This was a great approach to users. Instead of being treated like an incompetent moron and placed in a walled garden, you were entrusted and empowered. Something as simple as drawing my own mouse pointer on the Amiga was a profound and formative experience for me. As corny as it sounds, it was as if the guys who built this amazing machine put it in my hands and said, "Hey kid, you're in charge. This computer is yours. Learn how to use it and you can make it do anything." It was a call for exploration and creativity.</p>


<p>Today, I can't even change the system font in Windows. I can select an "accent color", but most applications completely ignore it. Every program defaults to downloading into a Downloads folder and I've lost count of how many times I've changed its folder view from grouped to not grouped, only to discover it's been magically changed back the next time I browse it. Lots of settings have been removed completely while others are buried deep in strange places where a user clearly isn't really supposed to venture.</p>


<p>The problem is that there's no toggle for enabling "advanced mode". I'm just supposed to accept that I can no longer change simple things I've been able to configure for the past thirty years. Someone, somewhere just decided that all users have the same basic skill level and that the defaults are always acceptable.</p>


<h3>General purpose Instagram cameras</h3>


<p>I suppose the lack of configurability is a metaphor for personal computing in general: we're not buying our machines, we're renting them by way of bizarrely complex EULA:s for everything from the firmware to the OS and we're not supposed to be curious or creative, we're supposed to sit back and passively consume advertisements. The base level of creative computer use is no longer exploring programming or graphics or music, but photographing a meal someone else has prepared and then applying a predefined sepia filter to said photo. The base level of configuring a system is no longer picking some personal favorites among fonts and colors, but - maybe - selecting between dark and light mode.</p>


<p>
On the flip side, more and more people also need to use computers 
for actually producing stuff - not least programming all those ad 
delivery platforms and the curiously unconfigurable operating systems 
they run on. But there are also armies of innocents; office workers,
administrators, hotel clerks, librarians, teachers - those people now often 
have no choice but to strain their eyes staring at black text on bright 
white backgrounds, unable to select a font they find easier to read.
</p>

<p>Too bad they can no longer store their spices close to the stove, but hey, who cares? Let them take one for the team. We're all swimming in ad revenue and if people learn to configure things, maybe they'll suddenly realize that the presence of those ads should be configurable as well.</p>

<br>

<hr>



<p id="footnote1">
<sup>1</sup> In case my sarcasm isn't coming through here: No, it's not secure. The privacy and security problems this entails are huge.
</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://datagubbe.se/noconf/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25238523</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 16:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Parsing All of Wikipedia to an Offline Encyclopedia]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 24 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25238316">thread link</a>) | @kxrm
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://daveshap.github.io/DavidShapiroBlog/automation/2020/11/15/parsing-all-wikipedia.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://daveshap.github.io/DavidShapiroBlog/automation/2020/11/15/parsing-all-wikipedia.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://daveshap.github.io/DavidShapiroBlog/automation/2020/11/15/parsing-all-wikipedia.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25238316</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 16:01:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Is Probability Real?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 215 | Comments 191 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25237356">thread link</a>) | @EbTech
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Today, I want to address an issue with statements involving chance. To demonstrate, let’s first consider a statement that doesn’t involve chance:</p>

<p>“<em>A cubic die tossed onto a flat surface will come to rest on one of its six sides.</em>”</p>

<p>This claim can be empirically tested, with various dice and surfaces. If any one of our experiments results in the die spinning endlessly on a corner, we will have disproven the claim. We may have to refine the claim’s conditions; for instance, by requiring the presence of gravity. Nonetheless, it’s fairly clear what it means for the statement to be true or false. Now let’s try to make a claim involving probability:</p>

<p>“<em>If a pair of standard dice are thrown, the probability of their face-up sides summing to nine will be one in nine (about 0.11 or 11%).</em>”</p>

<p>What does it mean for this statement to be true? Unlike the first statement, this one doesn’t specify which result we’ll actually see. How can we possibly hope to test it, or to make use of its information?</p>



<p>Within the realm of abstract mathematics, we’re free to model probability in a way that fits our intuitions. Imagine a multiverse containing an infinity of possible worlds, whose total <em>measure</em> is 100%. Define the probability of an <em>event</em>, such as that of rolling a nine, to be the measure assigned to the subset of worlds in which the event actually occurs.</p>

<p>In the abstract formalism, we’re allowed to assign the measure however we like, subject to Kolmogorov’s axioms: the measure must be non-negative, countably additive, and total to 100%. By respecting the symmetry of an idealized die,<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup> we might argue that only one such assignment makes sense; from it, we can calculate the probability of any event involving dice rolls.</p>

<p>There are two shortcomings to this approach. Firstly, we won’t always deal with nicely symmetrical objects for which direct a priori arguments are possible. Thus, we still need a means of testing probabilistic claims using real-life observations. Secondly, such arguments can never be airtight: after all, how can we hope to infer the measure on a hypothetical multiverse, when we only ever experience <em>one</em> world? Indeed, a realist might question if it makes any sense to discuss the chances of an event happening: either it happens or it doesn’t!</p>



<p>You might be more trusting of someone who puts their money where their mouth is. To back up a definite claim, not involving chance, I can simply agree to pay a penalty if it turns out I’m wrong.</p>

<p>This idea can be extended to probabilistic claims in the following manner: consider a lottery that pays a $90 jackpot if the next roll of a pair of dice yields a nine. If the maximum that I’m willing to pay to play is $10, this indicates that I believe a not-nine roll is eight times more likely than a nine roll. This approach is appealing because, after all, the <em>raison d’être</em> of probability theory is to explain the decision-making of individuals facing uncertainty.</p>

<p>If another gambler’s view conflicts with mine, you may aggregate our beliefs by creating a market on which we buy and sell predictions. Consider a contract that pays $100 (plus interest) when a specified event occurs. Its price on the market can be interpreted as the percentage probability of that event. Thus, to say an event is twice as “likely” as another, simply means its market price is double.</p>

<p>Unlike your typical gambler, a frictionless market offers transparent near-identical buy and sell prices. As a result, any violations of Kolmogorov’s axioms become money-making arbitrage opportunities. Arbitrage activity acts as an enforcer of the axioms, creating what economists call the <em>risk-neutral probability measure</em>.</p>

<p>In real markets, however, this probability measure exhibits several inconsistenties. Firstly, it depends on which currency is used: as an extreme example, we wouldn’t buy a dollar-denominated wager that only pays out if the dollar collapses, no matter how likely we imagine the collapse to be. Secondly, this measure is sensitive to (non-diversifiable) risk: if a widely-believed prophecy held that rolling a nine would induce a catastrophic famine, the market would value this outcome a lot more, because everyone wants to buy insurance against such a catastrophe. Thirdly, markets can be misinformed: indeed, one motivation for participating in a market is to try to beat it! And finally, liquid markets are hard to set up.</p>

<p>For these reasons, we abandon this approach. We’ll seek to define probability in terms of actual outcomes instead of human bets. Nonetheless, human bets are what inspired the creation of probability theory: it’s hard to think of any other practical application! Therefore, we should remember to revisit the matter once we’ve found an appealing probability concept. Ultimately, we must be able to explain <em>how</em> individuals and markets behave with respect to our concept, and answer <em>why</em> they should care about it at all.</p>

<p>These questions are incredibly subtle: the theory of evolution by natural selection tells us that individuals are wired to use strategies that enabled their ancestors’ survival; however, the nature of probabilistic beliefs is that a wide range of outcomes are plausible. Indeed, while a coin will always land heads or tails, it’s considered unwise to bet your life savings on either heads or tails. Intuitively speaking, the rationale is that you’re almost certain to lose <em>eventually</em>, if you keep playing this way. This idea of repeated trials inspires our next interpretation, which happens to be the most popular among scientists.</p>



<p>According to the frequentist school of thought, a probabilistic statement is not to be taken literally. Although it refers to a single event, the statement should be taken as shorthand for a claim involving a very large collection of similar events. Imagine rolling the dice over and over. The probabilistic claim that we started with is converted into the following:</p>

<p>“<em>If a pair of standard dice are thrown repeatedly, then in the limit as the number of throws goes to infinity, the proportion of nines converges to one in nine (about 0.11 or 11%).</em>”</p>

<p>The short-run probability is replaced by a long-run proportion. Given an infinite sequence of rolls, this statement unambiguously reveals itself to be true or false. In light of the frequentist interpretation, we can even make more sense of our earlier interpretations. While we only experience one world, repeating an experiment under similar conditions is like observing the experiment in a parallel universe: whether we count trials or worlds, the math is virtually identical. In the limit of infinitely many bets, we can make some unambiguous conclusions about the quality of a gambler’s strategy, too: this is how casinos ensure that the house always wins!</p>

<p>Testing our claim is a simple matter: we roll the dice, over and over, and over and over… infinity times. Oops. Of course, there is no such thing as an experiment with infinity trials. Our arms will get tired, the dice will wear out, the Sun will explode, and all the free energy in the universe will be consumed. At best, we can do a very large number of trials. Let’s say we roll dice 9,000 times; one in nine of these would be 1,000. Perhaps we won’t roll exactly 1,000 nines, so let’s interpret our claim with a suitable margin of error, called a <em>confidence interval</em>:</p>

<p>“<em>If a pair of standard dice are thrown 9,000 times, then the face-up sides will sum to nine for between 920 and 1,080 of the throws.</em>”</p>

<p>The probability of obtaining between 920 and 1,080 nines can be calculated to be 99.3%.<sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup> Thus, we’ve turned a probabilitic statement into a much more certain but still probabilistic statement. If we observe 1,100 nines, we should be able to dismiss the probabilistic claim as false. And yet, if every household on Earth were to independently perform this 9,000-throw experiment, we should expect that a great many of their results would fall outside the confidence interval. They would disagree on the truth of our statement!</p>

<p>There’s no getting around it: despite its intuitive appeal, the frequentist definition of probability is circular, reducing probability claims to probability claims.<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup> To end the cycle, the frequentist chooses a threshold (say, 99%) beyond which to treat events as objective truths. This grants the claim an empirically observable meaning. And yet, the frequentist must take care not to consider too many such events, for otherwise the probability of <em>at least one</em> of the events failing may ALSO exceed the threshold of certainty: a logical contradiction.</p>

<p>Things only work out nicely in the limit of infinite sample size. Statisticians mainly deal with experiments which can be repeated so many times that, for most practical purposes, their conclusions can be treated as definite. Non-philosophers are usually happy to ignore a sub-1% chance of error; and if that’s not good enough, make it 0.0001%! Confidence can be increased by gathering more data, i.e., increasing the sample size.</p>

<p>This approach turns out to be very powerful. By designing more complex hypotheses in which probabilities vary as a function of context variables, even some phenomena that aren’t easily repeatable can be statistically analyzed. For example, weather forecasts are based on well-tested models that use measurements of variables such as temperature, pressure, humidity, and wind.</p>

<p>On the other hand, statistical models of sports games, democratic elections, or company stocks tend to be less testable: the interactions are very complex and there are too few outcomes from which to extrapolate. Similarly, when you try to predict which colleges will admit you or which of your friends will start a business, you don’t make your case using repeatable tests. Clearly, the frequentist interpretation cannot apply. One may argue that no conclusions in these cases would hold up to a scientific standard; nonetheless, if we seek a theory of decision-making under uncertainty, there’s no …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability">https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.arameb.com/blog/2020/11/22/probability</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25237356</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 13:23:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Always leave the code better than you found it]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 70 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25237341">thread link</a>) | @hans1729
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://letterstoanewdeveloper.com/2020/11/23/always-leave-the-code-better-than-you-found-it/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://letterstoanewdeveloper.com/2020/11/23/always-leave-the-code-better-than-you-found-it/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Dear new developer,</p>



<p>I’ve spent a lot of my time maintaining working code. I think that is more typical of software developers than working in greenfield development. Yes, there are definitely jobs where you are writing more new code than maintaining, upgrading, bug fixing and improving old code (startups without product market fit being one, consulting being another) but in general code is expensive and folks want to run it for a long time. </p>



<p>Often you’ll jump into code to fix a bug, investigate an issue or answer a question.</p>



<p>When you do so, improve it. This doesn’t mean you rewrite it, or upgrade all the libraries it depends on, or rename all the variables. </p>



<p>You don’t need to transform it. </p>



<p>But you should make it better. Just clean it up a bit. Doing so makes everyone’s lives just a bit better, helps the codebase in a sustainable way, and assists the business by making its supporting infrastructure more flexible.</p>



<p>What are some ways to improve the code when you are in it?</p>



<p><strong>Document</strong></p>



<p>Whether that is a comment that explains something tricky, a larger piece of documentation external to the code which explains how to interact with it, or fixing a typo, trustworthy documentation is key to interacting with code. This is a good way to start improving a codebase because it has minimal impact on the actual code. Therefore it is low risk. But if you’ve ever had a great comment explain a confusing bit of code, you’ll appreciate the time this effort can save.</p>



<p>You can also help documentation by removing old, crufty docs. If you see a comment that doesn’t apply, remove it. If there’s cut and paste documentation which doesn’t apply, get rid of it. That cleans up the code for the next person to come along (who might be you).</p>



<p><strong>Write a test or improve a test</strong> </p>



<p>Tests help you write maintainable, extensible code that others can change fearlessly. If you run across code that isn’t tested and you have time and the supporting framework to write one, do so. </p>



<p>Even if it tests simple functionality such as “can I instantiate this object” or “how does this function react when I pass it two null values”, an additional test will help the robustness of the code. </p>



<p><strong>Refactor it</strong></p>



<p>This is one of the most flexible improvements. Refactoring code can range from renaming a variable to be more true to its nature to an overhaul of an entire module. Start small and don’t get wrapped up in perfection. Make the code clearer in intent. </p>



<p>It’s easy with refactoring to get wound around an axle and make too many changes and end up with broken things. Timeboxing is one technique I use to avoid, or at least minimize, my tendencies toward this when refactoring. If all I have is 30 minutes, I’ll make my changes smaller in scope.</p>



<p>A warning about refactoring. Don’t refactor what you don’t understand. Don’t drive by refactor. Discuss your plan with someone more familiar with the code; <code>git blame</code> is your friend. Especially if the code is not well tested, you want to make sure you don’t do more harm than good.</p>



<p><strong>Upgrade a dependency</strong></p>



<p>It’s sometimes a winding path, but upgrading your dependencies regularly is a good way to maintain the code. I remember working in a fork of struts. It was an important application for the company, but we didn’t spend the time upgrading the dependencies, because it was too painful. Eventually, parts of the code became harder to update. The entire application couldn’t benefit from newer technologies and paradigms because of the older dependencies holding it back. </p>



<p>It never feels good to spend time updating a dependency; to me this always feels like running in place. But if you don’t do so, eventually dependencies will end of life and you’ll be forced to update. That’ll be even less pleasant. </p>



<p><strong>How to do it</strong></p>



<p><em>Based on feedback (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/k2cbtb/always_leave_the_code_better_than_you_found_it/gdv0kg9/?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3">this comment</a>, among others), I added this section on Nov 28.</em></p>



<p>When you are making these changes to improve the code, you’ll help out code reviewers and your future self by making changes that are improving the code separate from changes that add functionality. Whether you do this in separate pull requests, tickets, or commits depends on your team culture. Ask about that. But such separation will make it easier for people who aren’t familiar with the changes to understand them and give feedback on them, whether that is a code review this week or someone reviewing this component two years from now.</p>



<p><strong>Why do it</strong></p>



<p>All of these actions not only help others because they improve the quality of the code, they also provide examples to other developers on how to do so. For example, it is far easier to write the second test in a suite than the first. You can cut and paste a lot of the setup code and tweak only what is different. The first bit of documentation will inspire more.</p>



<p>Code isn’t everything, but it is an important work output. Whenever you touch it, you should strive to leave it in a better place that it was before you did so.</p>



<p>Sincerely,</p>



<p>Dan</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://letterstoanewdeveloper.com/2020/11/23/always-leave-the-code-better-than-you-found-it/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25237341</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 13:19:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[What were these Roman objects used for?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 52 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25237271">thread link</a>) | @jd115
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">
<p><strong>DECODING THE DRUIDIC DODECAHEDRON </strong></p>

<p><img src="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/OrgImages/Dodecahedron/Dodecahedron%20Types.jpg" width="900" height="438"></p>
<p><strong>These bronze artefacts are so-called <em>Roman</em> dodecahedra (plural of dodecahedron)  of which about 120 have been found in the Celtic countries of Europe. Strangely, none of these have been found in Italy, home turf of the Romans.</strong> <strong>To the left is seen a dodecahedron from the Römermuseum Schwarzenacker, Homburg, Germany collection. To the right is seen another pristine example from the Hunt Museum in Limerick Ireland </strong></p>

<p><img src="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/OrgImages/Dodecahedron/Dodecahedron%20Types3.jpg" width="935" height="438"></p>
<p><strong>To the left is a dodecahedron from Archaeological  Service Canton Aargau, Brugg, Switzerland (Vindonissa Museum). To the right is a dodecahedron from the Gallo-Roman Museum, Tongeren, Belgium. </strong></p>
<p>The basic design of these artefacts remains relatively constant (12 pentagonal faces with knop-shaped legs), however, there can be a range of different  incised designs in the layout of the faces<strong>. </strong></p>
<p>The actual function of these artefacts cannot be explained by our historians or archaeologists, although many theories abound,  none of which seem particularly convincing. Also, there is no  mention of these items in old historical records of the Romans or those of anyone else for that matter. They are such an enigma that academics have pretty-much come to the defeatist conclusion that <em><strong>"we will never know what these dodecahedrons were used for". </strong></em></p>
<p>In reviewing the academic literature, one begins to see why the mystery will probably never be solved within that community. Here are some of the impediments and pitfalls our experts create for themselves:</p>
<p>All archaeological measurements are given in metric increments (centimetres or millimetres), which is a modern system that was created as much as 2000-years after some of these dodecahedra were cast in bronze. Earlier exemplars in stone or wood could predate the latter, more refined ones, by yet another thousand years or more. This  metric measurement preoccupation renders the  encoded numbers invisible or unrecognisable. Our academics know a large swathe of the ancient measurements that were in use two thousand years ago or before, so why not apply them to this study? </p>
<p>Most assuredly, the various sized holes in the 12-faces, the concentric circles that circumnavigate them, as well as the additional incised lines or dotted circles, etc, infer that there is something vividly measurable going on and it's evident that each hole or ring  has been very purposely fabricated to represent a known, precise and sought-after measurement.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/OrgImages/Dodecahedron/Calibrated.jpg" width="900" height="476"> </p>
<p><strong>A number of dodecahedra have calibration marks along their edges or around the holes in their faces. To the left is seen a calibrated dodecahedron from Hereford Museum, Kenchester and to the right is seen another from Goodrich Castle. Yet another one found in Wales shows etched calibration marks. </strong></p>
<p>In their reports,  archaeologists will often round out measurements of the holes in the dodecahedron faces to the nearest millimetre only, which is grossly insufficient. It's much appreciated by researchers when measurements can be supplied to 1/10th  of a millimetre, but  it is nigh on impossible  to acquire more refined measurements undertaken with electronic vernier callipers. Precise measurements and scaling must precede any serious analysis of these artefacts, but our experts don't seem to think there would be anything significant to find anyway, so don't subject the dodecahedra to rigorous measurement analysis.</p>
<p>Despite the fact that 25.4 millimetres (1 British Standard Inch) or fraction expressions of the same will recur repeatedly in the faces of dodecahedra, no-one seems to have arrived at the conclusion that the enigmatic<em><strong> "inch"</strong></em> recurrence is worthy of serious investigation. </p>
<p>Almost anything considered high-art, technically advanced or an engineering feat within ancient European civilisations seems to be automatically attributed to the Romans, which is certainly the case for these dodecahedra artefacts. This  is a hangover of biased, classicist-isolationist historical  interpretations of  European history where, first came the  Roman conquerors, who finally retreated after centuries of domination, only to be replaced by Rome's State church. With the pedigree of the church being Greco-Roman it was in their interests to push the concept that the Roman armies had found everything in the regions they invaded to be backwards, rudimentary or crude until Rome delivered the great-unwashed masses out of their depravity and into  enlightenment and high-civilisation. </p>
<p>This general process of misattribution further hobbles or seriously limits proper investigation into the purpose and function of dodecahedra artefacts, inasmuch as focus is  directed, almost exclusively, to what Roman armies might have used them for as range-finders or other battle related paraphernalia, including club-heads. The druids or others don't get  any serious consideration, despite the fact that they are historically recorded as having been  advanced mathematicians and astronomers.</p>
<p>Within controlled academia the ability to do open-ended, ground-breaking research can be severely curtailed by the requirements of <em><strong>"peer review"</strong></em> by colleagues.  This is largely a racket that ensures one doesn't move too far from the protected consensus opinion upon which academic reputations are built and anyone venturing too far out into left field is considered a maverick who threatens the insulated central body.</p>
<p>By the same token academia, these days, is lumbered with deep-set social responsibilities and crippling political agendas. When it comes to European history, especially, the requirement is to be self-effacing, while lauding and applauding the (often meager) accomplishments of other ethnicities. Under  guises of political correctness and racial sensitivity, the door is opened for antagonistic non-European, prejudiced individuals, to write and interpret  our history for us, while pushing their own  cultural-Marxist or similar wheel-barrows.  All one has to do is sit through lectures in our western universities to see just how far out of kilter the abysmal problem of  European history-misrepresentation has become.</p>
<p>But, with regards to the dodecahedra artefacts,what one person can build, another can generally duplicate or back-engineer, sufficient to make sense of what's going on. </p>
<p>So, let's cut to the chase, bypass all the  confusion of modern-day naysayers and source testimony directly from an observer who lived contemporary to the druids, before they fell under Roman domination </p>
<p>Julius Caesar, who was a very thorough historian, writes the       following regarding the late era druids of his time (circa 55 BC) and        practices within their many universities in Britain, where students from Gaul       and elsewhere, including Rome, went for training:</p>
<p><strong>'They hold aloof from war and do not pay war taxes; they       are excused from military service and exempt from all liabilities. Tempted       by these great advantages, many young men assemble of their own motion to       receive their training, many are sent by parents and relatives. Report says       that in the schools of the Druids they learn by heart a great number of verses,       and therefore some persons remain twenty years under training'. </strong></p>
<p><strong>'They do not think it proper to commit these utterances to       writing, although in all other matters and in their public and private accounts       they make use of Greek characters. I believe that they have adopted the practice       for two reasons- that they do not wish the rule to become common property,       nor those who learn the rule to rely on writing and so neglect the cultivation       of memory; and, in fact, it does usually happen that the assistance of writing       tends to relax the diligence of the student and the action of memory...They       also lecture on the stars in their motion, the magnitude       of the Earth and its divisions, on natural history, on the power and       government of God; and instruct the youth in these subjects' <em>(see De Ballo       Gallico, VII, 15, 16.).</em></strong></p>
<p>Historian, Isabel Hill Elder  writes, <strong>'The students at these       colleges numbered at times sixty thousand of the youth and young nobility       of Britain and Gaul. Caesar comments on the fact that the Gauls sent their       youth to Britain to be educated...It required twenty years to master the complete       circle of Druidic knowledge. Natural philosophy, astronomy,       mathematics, geometry, medicine, jurisprudence, poetry and oratory       were all proposed and taught-natural philosophy and       astronomy with severe exactitude' (Elder refers to <em>Strabo I IV,       page 197. Caesars Comm. Lib V. Sueotonius, V Calegula. E. Campion, Accounts       of Ireland, pg. 18.).</em></strong></p>
<p>Isabel Hill Elder further writes,<strong> 'The education system       adopted by the Druids is traced to about 1800 BC when Hu Gardarn Hysicion       (Isaacson), or Hu the Mighty, led the first colony of Cymri into Britain from       Defrobane, where Constantinople now stands'.</strong> </p>
<p>Further commenting on Hu       Gardarn Hysicion, Isabel Hill Elder writes that he, <strong>'is commemorated in       Welsh archaeology as having made poetry the vehicle of memory'.</strong> Elsewhere       she writes, he <strong>'is said to have mnemonically systematized the wisdom of       the ancients...'.</strong> She goes on to say,<strong> 'The published compositions of       the Druids and Bards form but a very small portion of the extant remains of       their works. The Myvyrian MSS. alone, now in the British Museum, amount to       47 volumes of poetry, in 1600 pages, besides about 2000 epigrammatic stanzas.       Also in the same collection are 53 volumes of prose, in about 15,300 pages,       containing many curious documents on various subjects...' <em>(see Celt, Druid       and Culdee, pages 54 &amp; 55).</em></strong></p>
<p>With the testimony of Julius Caesar ringing in our ears, lets see how the druids would have used the dodecahedron artefacts as <em><strong>"memory"</strong></em>devices for mathematically encoding astronomical cycles,<em><strong> ("the stars in their motion")</strong></em>, navigation systems <em><strong>("the …</strong></em></p></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html">http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://www.celticnz.co.nz/Dodecahedron/Decoding%20the%20Druidic%20Dodecahedron1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25237271</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 13:03:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Interpretable Machine Learning]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25236675">thread link</a>) | @e2e4
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://christophm.github.io/interpretable-ml-book/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://christophm.github.io/interpretable-ml-book/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        

        <div tabindex="-1" role="main">
          <div>

            <section id="section-">

<div id="summary">

<p><img src="https://christophm.github.io/interpretable-ml-book/images/title_page.jpg" width="500"></p>
<p>Machine learning has great potential for improving products, processes and research. But <strong>computers usually do not explain their predictions</strong> which is a barrier to the adoption of machine learning. This book is about making machine learning models and their decisions interpretable.</p>
<p>After exploring the concepts of interpretability, you will learn about simple, <strong>interpretable models</strong> such as decision trees, decision rules and linear regression. Later chapters focus on general model-agnostic methods for <strong>interpreting black box models</strong> like feature importance and accumulated local effects and explaining individual predictions with Shapley values and LIME.</p>
<p>All interpretation methods are explained in depth and discussed critically. How do they work under the hood? What are their strengths and weaknesses? How can their outputs be interpreted? This book will enable you to select and correctly apply the interpretation method that is most suitable for your machine learning project.</p>
<p>The book focuses on machine learning models for tabular data (also called relational or structured data) and less on computer vision and natural language processing tasks. Reading the book is recommended for machine learning practitioners, data scientists, statisticians, and anyone else interested in making machine learning models interpretable.</p>
<p>You can buy the PDF and e-book version (epub, mobi) <a href="https://leanpub.com/interpretable-machine-learning">on leanpub.com</a>.</p>
<p>You can buy the print version <a href="http://www.lulu.com/shop/christoph-molnar/interpretable-machine-learning/paperback/product-24036234.html">on lulu.com</a>.</p>
<p><strong>About me:</strong> My name is Christoph Molnar, I'm a statistician and a machine learner. My goal is to make machine learning interpretable.</p>
<p>Mail: <a href="mailto:christoph.molnar.ai@gmail.com">christoph.molnar.ai@gmail.com</a></p>
<p>Website: <a href="https://christophm.github.io/">https://christophm.github.io/</a></p>
<p>Follow me on Twitter! <a href="https://twitter.com/ChristophMolnar">@ChristophMolnar</a></p>
<p>Cover by <a href="https://twitter.com/YvonneDoinel">@YvonneDoinel</a></p>
<div>
<p><img src="https://christophm.github.io/interpretable-ml-book/images/by-nc-sa.png" alt="Creative Commons License"></p><p>Creative Commons License</p>
</div>
<p>This book is licensed under the <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License</a>.</p>
</div>
            </section>

          </div>
        </div>
      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://christophm.github.io/interpretable-ml-book/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25236675</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 10:08:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Generalized f-Mean]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 60 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25236328">thread link</a>) | @goldenkey
<br/>
November 28, 2020 | https://churchofthought.org/blog/2017/03/26/the-generalized-mean-an-algorithmic-approach/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://churchofthought.org/blog/2017/03/26/the-generalized-mean-an-algorithmic-approach/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<div>

			<p>In school, we are first taught the arithmetic mean, then later the geometric mean, and maybe one or two others like the harmonic/contraharmonic mean.</p>
<p>But most teachers do not teach the logic or derivation behind these means. They merely provide the formulas and perhaps provide some scenarios where each mean would be more useful than the others.</p>
<p>I’d like to illustrate the definition of a mean, in the most abstract sense, from a programmer’s perspective, an algorithmic point of view.</p>
<h2>A Balancing Act</h2>
<hr>
<p>Suppose we have a list of N numbers, and a binary operation $f(a,b)$</p>
<p>If we apply that binary operation to one number from the list, we must&nbsp;apply its inverse operation to another number from the list.</p>
<p>We can continue applying $f$ to one element then $f^{-1}$ to another element as many times as we need to, until every number in the list is equal. That number that all elements are equal to…is the mean!</p>
<p>Means are just balancing acts!</p>
<p>** I am aware we haven’t specified the most&nbsp;optimized way to perform this algorithm to ensure it halts.</p>

<h2>Example</h2>
<hr>
<p>let our list be $(2,4,6)$ and our $f(a,b)=a+b$</p>
<p>then we apply the operation and its inverse to two elements respectively:</p>
<p>$(f(2,2), 4 ,f^{-1}(6,2)) = (2+2, 4 ,6-2) =&nbsp;(4,4,4)$</p>
<p>So our mean is 4.&nbsp;We just performed the&nbsp;<em>arithmetic mean</em>!</p>

<h2>What is it good for?</h2>
<hr>
<p>Well, given ANY invertible&nbsp;symmetric binary function, we can define a mean and derive its “shortcut” formula!</p>
<p>Here are the functions that define the means we usually come across:</p>
<p>arithmetic mean: $f(a,b) = a+b$<br>
geometric mean: $f(a,b) = ab$<br>
geometric mean (alternative definition): $f(a,b) = ln(a) + ln(b)$<br>
harmonic mean: $f(a,b) = 1/(1/a + 1/b)$</p>

<h2>Favoring Large or Small Numbers</h2>
<hr>
<p>Now, most of us learn that geometric mean tends to favor smaller&nbsp;numbers.</p>
<p>For example, the arithmetic mean of 1&nbsp;and 100 is $50\frac{1}{2}$. But the geometric mean of 1 and 100 is 10.</p>
<p>Knowing what we do now, can we create a mean that favors smaller numbers&nbsp;even more?</p>
<p>I don’t know if these already exist in the formal mathematics universe, ie. books or published papers. So let me know if you find a previous name for them!</p>
<p>Franken-mean: $f(a,b) = a^b b^a$</p>
<p>Franken-mean v2: $f(a,b) = a^b + b^a$</p>
<p>You might ask if we can skew our mean toward smaller numbers&nbsp;even more than our above exponential mean. We sure can. Using something called Tetration, simply put – it is iterated exponentiation. There are even operations that encompass iterated tetration and so on…these kind of operations are called&nbsp;hyperoperations. So we can make a mean skewed toward lows or highs as much as we want, and it’s beautiful isn’t it? Before different means are taught, the theory of what defines a mean should really be taught.</p>
<p>But before I forget,&nbsp;you must be saying: “Where’s my shortcut formulas?!!”</p>
<p>Okay okay.</p>

<h2>Deriving the Closed Formulas</h2>
<hr>
<p>Let’s derive the arithmetic mean first. Assume we have a list of 4 elements, ${x,y,z,t}$</p>
<p>Given the binary symmetric&nbsp;function that defines the arithmetic mean $f(a,b)=a+b$,</p>
<p>we let $g(a) = f(a,f(a,f(a,a))) = a + a + a + a = 4a$</p>
<p>Our formula for the mean of the 4 numbers in our list will be:</p>
<p>$g^{-1}(f(x,f(y,f(z,t))))$</p>
<p>We know $g(a) = 4a$, so $g^{-1}(a) = a/4$</p>
<p>That means our mean is $(x+y+z+t)/4$, which is what we expected from the arithmetic mean</p>
<p>Above was just a demonstration for a fixed size list of 4 elements. The concept is the same for any sized list. We can use induction to extrapolate what the formula will be for a list of n&nbsp;elements, $(x+y+z+t…….+w)/n$</p>

<h2>Mathematica code for the generalized mean</h2>
<hr>
<pre id=""><code>GeneralizedMean[l_List, f_Function] := (
InverseFunction[
(Fold[f, ConstantArray[#, Length[l]]]) &amp;
] [Fold[f, l]]
);
</code></pre>
<ul>
<li>Arithmetic Mean
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x,y,z,t},(#+#2)&amp;]
Out= 1/4 (t+x+y+z)</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Geometric Mean
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x, y, z, t}, (#*#2) &amp;]
Out= (t x y z)^(1/4)
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Harmonic Mean
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x, y, z, t}, (1/(1/# + 1/#2)) &amp;]
Out= 4/(1/t + 1/x + 1/y + 1/z)
</code></pre>
</li>
<li>Franken Mean v1
<pre id=""><code>In:= GeneralizedMean[{x, y}, (#^#2 * #2^#) &amp;]
Out= Log[x^y y^x]/(2 ProductLog[1/2 Log[x^y y^x]])
</code></pre>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I had to use 2 variables for the above, because Mathematica’s symbolic inverses aren’t strong enough.<br>
Franken Mean v2 does not even compute with symbolics or even numbers.<br>
I will eventually work on this to hopefully get at least numerics to work nomatter what.</p>
<h2>Alternative Implementation</h2>
<hr>
<p>This is an alternative implementation which seems to yield better results in some cases:</p>
<pre id=""><code>GeneralizedMean[l_List, f_Function] := (
Module[{x},
Solve[Fold[f, l] == Fold[f, ConstantArray[x, Length[l]]], x][[-1,
1, 2]]
]);
</code></pre>

<h2>Create your own means!</h2>
<hr>
<p>Enjoy creating your own means! Number theoretic means on lists of primes and that sort of stuff should be very interesting to explore, cheers!</p>
<h3><strong>Continued in:</strong></h3>

<h3><a href="https://churchofthought.org/means-of-infinite-sets-and-more/"><strong>Part Two: Means of Infinite Sets</strong></a></h3>
<p><em>P.S.</em></p>
<p>Kolmogorov actually did something similar and came up with what’s called the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quasi-arithmetic_mean">Generalized f-mean</a></p>
<p>But he restricted his construct to only functions of the form $f(a,b) = g(a) + g(b)$, where g is the function that determines the mean and is to be specified.</p>


		</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://churchofthought.org/blog/2017/03/26/the-generalized-mean-an-algorithmic-approach/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25236328</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 08:51:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Bill Gates is wrong about education]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 31 | Comments 64 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25235672">thread link</a>) | @rajlego
<br/>
November 27, 2020 | https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Bill_Gates_is_wrong_about_education | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Bill_Gates_is_wrong_about_education">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="mw-content-text" lang="en" dir="ltr"><p><small>This text is part of: "<i><a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Problem_of_Schooling" title="Problem of Schooling">I would never send my kids to school</a></i>" by <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Piotr_Wozniak" title="Piotr Wozniak">Piotr Wozniak</a> (2017)</small>
</p>


<h2><span id="Bill_Gates_is_my_hero">Bill Gates is my hero</span></h2>
<p>Bill Gates was an early guiding light and <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo_World" title="SuperMemo World">our</a> inspiration. When <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Krzysztof_Biedalak" title="Krzysztof Biedalak">Krzysztof Biedalak</a> and I made our first $3 investment in a corporate rubber stamp, which was a post-communist obligation for all companies in Poland in 1991, Microsoft was a multibillion-dollar company. How could we not have been blinded by inspiration? We wanted to write a universally useful piece of software and the world would be ours - we thought. Bill Gates's software philosophy, based on respect for backward compatibility, sheltered <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo" title="SuperMemo">SuperMemo</a> on its path to its painfully slow adoption. Software and database compatibility have been preserved for 30 years now. My first pieces of knowledge in medical sciences, typed in on Dec 13, 1987, are still there in my collection, well-memorized and useful. Without Gates and his stance on compatibility, I would have lost all that knowledge to some upgrade hiccup long ago. When Gates moved to philanthropy, he has secured his place on my list of the greatest people who ever walked this planet. Perhaps as many as <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Bill_Gates_saved_over_100_million_children" title="Bill Gates saved over 100 million children">30-120 million kids have been saved by Bill's foundation</a>. This begs a vital question: Why is Gates so awfully wrong about education? Why does he fall for the same old myth that <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Myth:_You_can_improve_education_by_throwing_more_money_in_it" title="Myth: You can improve education by throwing more money in it">investing in education will produce better outcomes</a>? The education system is wrong and it must be redesigned. <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Compulsory_schooling_must_end" title="Compulsory schooling must end">Compulsory schooling must end</a>. See: <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Grand_Education_Reform" title="Grand Education Reform">Grand Education Reform</a>
</p>
<h2><span id="Could_Bill.27s_great_mind_be_wrong.3F">Could Bill's great mind be wrong?</span></h2>
<p>Everyone who disagrees with a great mind needs to pause and re-examine. Gates got sensational credentials. He sports a genius mind. He has seen more places that I could possibly ever manage to visit in Google Maps. He has spoken to more great people than I have had a chance to read about. He has visited more schools that I have seen on pictures. He started his forays into education in 1999. In contrast, I started thinking about "the system" only in 2016 when getting ready to write this <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Problem_of_Schooling" title="Problem of Schooling">book</a>. This makes me into a fledgling with an immature point of view. Gates himself is a great example of a brisk student who has turned his skills and talents into a monumental achievement. His credentials are so much better than mine!
</p>
<h2><span id="Bill_Gates.27s_perspective">Bill Gates's perspective</span></h2>
<p>Could this just be that Gates's perspective is so much different than mine?
</p><p>He looks at the education system like at the operating system. Measure the performance, look for bottlenecks in the system, fix the parameter here and there, videotape a great teacher, and make others copy the method, and manufacture greatness.
</p><p>He looks at education like a philanthropic job. Like he treats health problems with mass vaccinations, he looks for a simple formula which could improve the education of the masses with some industrial move? He seems less focused on letting the brightest thrive, and more focused on preventing the weakest from dropping out. He wants to bring up the average using some <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Testing" title="Testing">standardized testing</a> approach.
</p><p>He looks at education like a big company that needs to be managed effectively with departments, and sub-departments. With a clear division of responsibility. <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Modern_schooling_is_like_Soviet_economy#Schooling_is_like_Soviet_Economy" title="Modern schooling is like Soviet economy">With an industrial goal in mind?</a>
</p><p>Could this be that this great capitalist shows more socialist thinking than a little well-indoctrinated ex-communist like myself?
</p><p>There is a different perspective of an employer and an employee, esp. in a creative position. Gates looks at the number of college graduates. I look for specific skills and creative powers. Actual degrees do not matter much if you take time to get into a particular brain.
</p><p>He looks at students like productive workers. The heretic idea of a longer school day must have come from the factory model thinking. Longer days, more production, more manufacturing.
</p><p>He looks at education from a societal point of view, while I look at the brain of an individual. He wants to move the masses to high achievement, while I want to produce more little Bill Gateses.
</p><p>Unlike myself, Bill Gates does not focus on having more Bill Gateses. He focuses on helping the poor, in boosting qualifications of the middle class, and adds "<i>you can't run a society on top 5%</i>". He is right, however, that top 5% can forge a path in education that would inspire all the rest. They cannot be run through a compulsory system set on pushing through the remaining 95%.
</p><p>Gates's approach would be great for some poorer countries (e.g. in Africa). Where there are no schools, industrial approach and good management could quickly improve health, eliminate poverty, and provide basic education.
</p><p>My approach is probably more suited to well-developed nations where the industrial approach makes people sick of schooling. With social awareness and education on the rise, we look for more little future Noble Prize winners and future Bill Gateses.
</p><p>His own kids get the best kind of learning. During his trips around the world, they get to visit places like the Large Hadron Collider at CERN. This could spark a life-long passion that could turn them into future particle physicists or another incarnation of <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Tim_Berners-Lee" title="Tim Berners-Lee">Tim Berners-Lee</a>.  
</p><p>Where Gates optimizes for improving the average, I am looking for the optimum of peak intellectual performance.
</p><p>Last but not least, could Gates's approach be an afterglow of his dropping out from Harvard. I see that over and over again, dropouts seem to suffer from this life-long hangover about what could have been? They tend to over-appreciate the power of schooling or the power of college. In the same way, I might be under-appreciating my own degrees. Gates is <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Thiel_on_competition_for_degrees" title="Thiel on competition for degrees">the opposite of Peter Thiel</a> who studiously climbed the educational ladder until he stumbled to see the light. Thiel is now one of the staunchest critics of college.
</p>
<h2><span id="Bill_Gates.27s_formula_for_success">Bill Gates's formula for success</span></h2>
<p>I see Gates's own life as a simple formula for success in science, engineering, or life in general:
</p>
<ul><li> healthy childhood of few concerns (preferably without the relegation to <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Daycare_misery" title="Daycare misery">daycare</a>)</li>
<li> healthy approach to schooling with pranks, rebellions, disobedience, and freedom </li>
<li> minor trajectory nudges within the <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Push_zone" title="Push zone">push zone</a> by inspirational tutors. If tutors are not parents, this might be the most expensive part of the formula</li>
<li> breakthrough passion, e.g. for tinkering with computers or software</li>
<li> healthy education, possibly interrupted by some breakthrough decision (e.g. <i>Let me drop out from Harvard to set up the greatest software company in the world</i>)</li>
<li> relentless lifelong pursuit of goals born from that <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Passion_and_memory" title="Passion and memory">youthful passion</a></li>
<li> voracious reading (see: <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Bill_Gates_and_his_non-incremental_reading" title="Bill Gates and his non-incremental reading">Bill Gates and his non-incremental reading</a>)</li></ul>
<p>Only Bill Gates truly knows it, but my understanding of his life story is that his future was determined by just one major factor: getting his hands on a computer. He was good at math and programming. So are dozens of kids in my neighborhood. My thinking comes from the fact that I was also strongly affected by my first contact with computers.
</p>

<p>When <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/First_steps_of_SuperMemo" title="First steps of SuperMemo">I got my first computer in 1986</a>, ZX Spectrum, I was 24 and experienced wild elation with computer's obedience in executing my commands. I told the computer what to do, and it did it perfectly without asking questions. That was wonderful. I started writing my <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Plan" title="Plan">program for planning my day</a> on paper long before I got the computer on my desk. I was eager to see it work! As ZX Spectrum would load programs from a cassette tape, I could not easily dream of having <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo" title="SuperMemo">SuperMemo</a>. It needed access to some disk drive. I got my first PC with a 360 KB <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Floppy_disk">floppy disk</a> drive only <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo_1.0_for_DOS_(1987)" title="SuperMemo 1.0 for DOS (1987)">in 1987</a></p>
<p>The above hypothetical formula for educational success is simple and effective. Only a few might ever dream to replicate the scope of Bill's success. If that formula does not bring serial Nobel Prize winners, it should at least bring up a great deal of happy and fulfilled individuals. Freedom to explore the world is essential and it is denied to a great deal of kids in the modern world. When Peter Thiel pays kids to drop out from college, he looks for this type of free thinking experience that can change one life and then can change the world.
</p>
<h2><span id="My_attempt_at_employing_Gates.27s_formula">My attempt at employing Gates's formula</span></h2>

<p>I am happy with <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Exponential_adoption_of_spaced_repetition" title="Exponential adoption of spaced repetition">my achievements in life</a>. I have followed the formula employed by Gates. However, there were some exceptions. Perhaps I could use them as an excuse for not being as wildly successful as Bill? I was sent to <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Daycare_misery" title="Daycare misery">daycare</a>, and I am sure this slowed down my development. The time I spent with my brother was more intellectual and inspirational by two orders of magnitude. However, he was a student and could not babysit the little me for ever. In later years, I was forced into a degree of conformity by an ever-present threat of being enlisted by the army in service of the Warsaw Pact. In 1986, I was finally free of the army service, and could finally drop out, however, I was not ready. There was no market economics culture in Poland of the 1980s. I read about entrepreneurial science in Science in 1989 (Oct 31, 1989). This was the first time when it occurred to me that my research into memory might actually be a seed of a business. Initially, though, my passions led me in the direction of a PhD. Schooling told me that science done by entrepreneurs is inferior to science done in academia. I thought of <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo" title="SuperMemo">SuperMemo</a> as an opportunity to earn money for a trip to America. It seems that while Gates was fast to mature as a little entrepreneur, I needed 28 long years to even start thinking of my <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/SuperMemo_World" title="SuperMemo World">own business</a>.</p>
<h2><span id="Reconciling_Gates_and_Woz">Reconciling Gates and Woz</span></h2>
<p>Gates wants better teachers, better education, verification, <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Testing" title="Testing">testing</a>, measuring, carrot-and-stick for teachers, etc. In contrast, I stand with Steve Jobs. Jobs told the kids to <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Fundamental_law_of_learning" title="Fundamental law of learning">rebel</a>!
</p><p>Gates believes that the key to the <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Reform" title="Reform">great future education system</a> is the teacher. He is almost right. If we could populate present schools with great teachers, I wouldn't ever need to write <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Problem_of_Schooling" title="Problem of Schooling">this book</a>. The problem is that <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Progressive_education" title="Progressive education">a great teacher is simply a truly great man</a>. Great teaching requires a degree of genius. We need millions of those great people. How can we possibly hope to produce hundreds of thousands …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Bill_Gates_is_wrong_about_education">https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Bill_Gates_is_wrong_about_education</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://supermemo.guru/wiki/Bill_Gates_is_wrong_about_education</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25235672</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 06:12:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Considerations Before Graduating as an Engineer]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 45 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=25235665">thread link</a>) | @Ninroot
<br/>
November 27, 2020 | https://reflexio.debec.eu/considerations-before-graduating-engineer | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://reflexio.debec.eu/considerations-before-graduating-engineer">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

        
        <figure>
            <img alt="cover" src="https://reflexio.debec.eu/assets/piano.svg">
            <figcaption><a href="https://www.pinterest.de/pin/521995413033512913/" target="_blank">credit</a></figcaption>
            
        </figure>
        
        <p>In 2018, I graduated from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%C3%89cole_pour_l%27informatique_et_les_techniques_avanc%C3%A9es">EPITA</a>, a french engineering “Grande École” specialized in computer science. The subjects I had treated there were very technical: from the implementation of an ISO file reader to a <a href="https://www.lrde.epita.fr/~tiger/tiger.html">Tiger compiler</a>.</p>

<p>The technical focus, taught in technical programs such as my engineering school, has led me to some small surprises during my first steps in the business world. The following list outlines what I would have liked to have learned before graduation. The article is obviously influenced by computer science, which is the specialty of my school. Nevertheless, I hope that the students will find some teaching in it, whatever the technical field they are targeting.</p>



<h2 id="human-is-the-new-challenge">Human is the New Challenge</h2>

<p>Coming from a school whose implicit motto was “the more technical, the better”, I had to quickly get used to the idea that the new technicality coming out of school was primarily human. Don’t make me wrong: having technical knowledge is as necessary as expected by the business world. But if many of us have been trained to take up technical challenges, we have been much less prepared for the strangeness of human behavior.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Technical skills should no longer be your challenge, your challenge should now be human.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Schopenhauer said in The Art of Being Right “<em>A man may be objectively in the right, and nevertheless in the eyes of bystanders, and sometimes in his own, he may come off worst</em>” which in our case could be perfectly translated as “<em>You may be technically right and yet not be supported by others.</em>”. Sometimes engaging technical decisions are taken on the basis of very non-technical arguments, for example:</p>
<ul>
  <li>you were sick on the day of an important meeting;</li>
  <li>your level in English is not good enough to argue well enough;</li>
  <li>your manager used to work at XYZ, therefore XYZ technology is chosen for the project;</li>
  <li>your ambition to change a design frightens the rest of the team, despite the little amount effort it actually requires;</li>
  <li>your colleague X doesn’t like you, therefore it doesn’t like your design;</li>
  <li>etc.</li>
</ul>

<p>The list is endless. Just keep in mind that if you want technical decisions to be accepted, you will have to arm yourself with skills that go well beyond technique, starting with <em>negotiation</em> for example.</p>



<p>The school doesn’t just train engineers in languages or tools, it establishes a culture and a discipline that becomes stronger or weaker by joining a firm. Depending on the business sector, company, project or team, not everyone gives the same attention to software engineering. It is very unlikely that this discipline is the core business of your company, nor even the academic background of your colleagues. The good practices, taken for granted, can then be violently disrupted: no code review, no unit tests, sometimes even no version-control tool.</p>

<p>The intuitive reflex of a young engineer is to bring a purely technical solution: no version-control tool? let’s install git! No code review? Let’s protect the master branch! No unit tests? Install the right testing library! Etc. But here we are, the problem is <em>not</em> technical, the problem is primarily human, more particularly cultural. Changing the corporate culture, or more modestly, <em>the culture of a team is far more difficult to change than any tool</em>.</p>

<p>I will always remember the long struggle to get GitLab for an old project. This was the kind of indispensable work tool for a software engineer. The battle was long, not because the tool did not exist (it just had to be downloaded and installed) but because the required culture was not ready.</p>

<p>It takes time and effort to change a culture, but it is well worth the effort. A tool can always be dropped, a <code>git push</code> can always be forced, but a disciplined team is hardly swindled. So when choosing between a very well equipped team and a very disciplined team, <em>choose discipline without hesitation</em>!</p>

<h2 id="professional--genius">Professional &gt; Genius</h2>

<p>In university, a lot of credit was given to geniuses who, alone, could compile a few thousand lines of complicated code in a single night’s work. When I entered the business world, my vision changed a lot from that kind of profile, capable of doing a lot of work in record time. Their confidence (or arrogance) leads to an extra commitment, which makes it difficult to meet delivery deadlines. And because geniuses understand complex things, they <a href="https://reflexio.debec.eu/principles-for-better-design#keep-it-simple-stupid">design complex systems</a> that no one understands. Their loneliness makes them unique masters of their subjects, thereby nurturing their self-esteem. Knowledge remains in their heads and their presence becomes necessary for every decision.</p>

<p><a href="https://armament.solutions/tactics/single-points-of-failure.html"><img src="https://reflexio.debec.eu/assets/single_point_of_failure.svg" alt="Single point of failure"></a></p>

<p>But geniuses also have 24-hour days and quickly turn out to be the <em>bottleneck</em> of everything, slowing down everyone else. You don’t need to be a software architecture expert to agree that it is not desirable to over-commit and underestimate a single resource: apart from the inability to scale, the resource is the single point of failure. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_point_of_failure">The design of a single point of failure is unforgivable</a>. Once the engineer gets sick, goes on vacation, or leaves the company, the entire team will have to pay back months or even years of unprofessionalism.</p>

<p>It is a black and exaggerated portrait that I paint here. I can nevertheless bet that you will encounter this kind of profile in your career which, in addition to having a negative impact on entire projects (and on people’s health), will sometimes be claimed as a hero by the organization. <em>Real geniuses are the geniuses also capable of <a href="https://reflexio.debec.eu/principles-for-better-design#keep-it-simple-stupid">designing simplicity</a>, taking people on board while humble towards humanity and their workload</em>. These are called great professionals. They spread knowledge and responsibility in order to become not the single point of failure or the bottle neck.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Geniuses build scalable services, professionals are scalable geniuses. - <a href="https://twitter.com/arnaud_debec/status/1327584444849524736">Twitter</a></p>
</blockquote>

<!--
## Read Through What Is Ask From You

If you asked your manager if you had to do unit tests, he would tell you not to waste time with it.

> If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses. - [Henry Ford](https://hbr.org/2011/08/henry-ford-never-said-the-fast)

 -->

<h2 id="side-note">Side note</h2>

<p>Do you think there’s a principle missing? Send me your comments! This list will certainly be extended and refined, subscribe to the <a data-formkit-toggle="78a863d4eb" href="https://reflexio-debec.ck.page/78a863d4eb">newsletter</a> if you wish to be notified about it.</p>

    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://reflexio.debec.eu/considerations-before-graduating-engineer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-25235665</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 06:09:49 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
