<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 20]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 20. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 04:23:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-20.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 04:23:52 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I No Longer Tell My Friends about Anki/SuperMemo]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 57 | Comments 74 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24957617">thread link</a>) | @kioleanu
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/2020-10-31-why-i-no-longer-tell-my-friends-about-anki-supermemo/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/2020-10-31-why-i-no-longer-tell-my-friends-about-anki-supermemo/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p>This article <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/6NvbSwuSAooQxxf7f/beware-of-other-optimizing">Beware of Other-Optimizing</a> by Eliezer Yudkowsky is highly illuminating. I recommend you read it through the lens of “recommending Anki to a friend.” This article is about the problems of giving advice on how to learn.</p>
<h2>Spreading the “gospel” to the world</h2>
<p>If you deeply believe something, along the lines of “if everyone did it, the world would be much better off.” and have tried convincing other people to do that thing, then you will realize it’s almost impossible to change others’ opinions or behaviors.</p>
<p>Maybe you’re not that ambitious to convince everyone, so you start small: you share it with your friends, but then discovered nobody actually cares or realizes its significance. A mild version is like <a href="https://www.deathbulge.com/comics/206">showing your favorite TV show and they don’t care</a>:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/26c8c80614f9b9a1a0a8f6e2ff1e17c2/acb04/deathbulge.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="deathbulge" title="deathbulge" src="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/26c8c80614f9b9a1a0a8f6e2ff1e17c2/1c72d/deathbulge.jpg" srcset="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/26c8c80614f9b9a1a0a8f6e2ff1e17c2/a80bd/deathbulge.jpg 148w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/26c8c80614f9b9a1a0a8f6e2ff1e17c2/1c91a/deathbulge.jpg 295w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/26c8c80614f9b9a1a0a8f6e2ff1e17c2/1c72d/deathbulge.jpg 590w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/26c8c80614f9b9a1a0a8f6e2ff1e17c2/acb04/deathbulge.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>My faith in evidence-based learning strategies is informed by my personal experience and <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/2020-02-25-how-to-learn-about-meta-learning-my-resource-list">my meta-learning list</a>. I wholeheartedly believe Spaced Repetition Software (SRS) like SuperMemo and Anki is the key to effective and efficient learning. If you believe education is the future, then the knowledge about evidence-based learning strategies is one big key to unlocking that future, both individually and collectively.</p>
<h2>“Doing this every day seems very tiring.”</h2>
<p>Two years ago I was doing my Anki reps. One friend glanced over and was interested in what I was doing.</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/443ff24d4c08fb6e97f3db4438a49b2e/ee745/myTime.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="My time has come" title="My time has come" src="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/443ff24d4c08fb6e97f3db4438a49b2e/1c72d/myTime.jpg" srcset="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/443ff24d4c08fb6e97f3db4438a49b2e/a80bd/myTime.jpg 148w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/443ff24d4c08fb6e97f3db4438a49b2e/1c91a/myTime.jpg 295w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/443ff24d4c08fb6e97f3db4438a49b2e/1c72d/myTime.jpg 590w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/443ff24d4c08fb6e97f3db4438a49b2e/ee745/myTime.jpg 660w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>We ate lunch together while I was giving her a little presentation. I talked <em>very enthusiastically</em> about spaced repetition, basic memory science and Anki operations. Of course I had to show her the infamous forgetting curve:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/2abe95310027f94ad36981994f56c65d/8aab1/forgetting-curve-wired-wozniak.webp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="forgetting-curve" title="forgetting-curve" src="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/2abe95310027f94ad36981994f56c65d/5ca24/forgetting-curve-wired-wozniak.webp" srcset="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/2abe95310027f94ad36981994f56c65d/cbe2e/forgetting-curve-wired-wozniak.webp 148w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/2abe95310027f94ad36981994f56c65d/3084c/forgetting-curve-wired-wozniak.webp 295w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/2abe95310027f94ad36981994f56c65d/5ca24/forgetting-curve-wired-wozniak.webp 590w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/2abe95310027f94ad36981994f56c65d/8aab1/forgetting-curve-wired-wozniak.webp 630w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>She sounded excited about the possibility of finally mastering a second language. But at one point she was confused:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If I hadn’t learned it how could I recall it from memory?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So I explained that assessment <strong>for</strong> learning (testing as a means of learning) is different from assessment <strong>of</strong> learning (finding out what you’ve learned). The act of “recalling from memory” is itself a learning process. Then I was aware that her confusion was probably due to a common misconception about memory: human memory works like computer memory:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The functional architecture of how humans forget, remember, and learn is <strong>unlike</strong> the corresponding processes in man-made devices […] We think of ourselves as working like computers, we become prone to assuming that exposing ourselves to information and procedures will lead to storage (i.e., recording) of such information or procedures in our memories—that the information will write itself in one’s memory.</p>
<p>If we think of human memory equals to memory in a computer, we are unlikely to appreciate that retrieving information from our memory increases the subsequent accessibility of that information, while retrieving information from computer memory leaves the status of that information unperturbed. <a href="https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/e/9780203842539/chapters/10.4324%2F9780203842539-6">On the Symbiosis of Remembering, Forgetting, and Learning</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Side note: this story might give you the impression that I liked to show off what I know. No not really. I like to be convinced with evidence, and I thought others were the same. I was wrong. Also, I included the above quotes for the sake of convincing you, the reader. I didn’t obfuscate the subject matter further with phrases like assessment <strong>for</strong> learning and assessment <strong>of</strong> learning.</p>
<p>She looked… befuddled. Sort of like this:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e459a547d1aa99ea034a06ea3f4f1f13/c08c5/AwkwardSmile.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="awkwardSmile" title="awkwardSmile" src="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e459a547d1aa99ea034a06ea3f4f1f13/1c72d/AwkwardSmile.jpg" srcset="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e459a547d1aa99ea034a06ea3f4f1f13/a80bd/AwkwardSmile.jpg 148w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e459a547d1aa99ea034a06ea3f4f1f13/1c91a/AwkwardSmile.jpg 295w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e459a547d1aa99ea034a06ea3f4f1f13/1c72d/AwkwardSmile.jpg 590w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e459a547d1aa99ea034a06ea3f4f1f13/c08c5/AwkwardSmile.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>I remember I was so excited and nervous at the same time that I was fumbling for words, trying to simplify it as much as I could. In retrospect, I was making things worse.</p>
<p>She’d listen to me quite intently, signaling that she was thinking and trying to figure it out, but I could tell she was still confused. And the more I explained, the deeper the rabbit hole went (like keep clicking hyperlinks in Wikipedia), and the more confused she became, so I stopped talking to stop making the whole situation uncomfortable. The following monologue is how I imagine what she was thinking at the time:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“He’s so passionate about this stuff and so sure of himself that I guess he’s right.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>“I’m not really sure what he means. I do want to learn Japanese but the stuff he’s talking about is so confusing…”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>“I was indeed interested in the beginning, but I don’t really care at this point. I’m just going to pretend I understand and end this whole conversation asap.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I will never forget what she said at one point,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Doing this every day seems very tiring.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I was like “Yeah…” I never followed up on her progress. I figured if she was truly interested, when she bumped into problem she would ask for my help. As expected, we never talked about it and I never mentioned Anki again.</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/7a936abffcd1a452478dca75a9f1ec62/0b533/sadFrog.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="sadFrog" title="sadFrog" src="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/7a936abffcd1a452478dca75a9f1ec62/0b533/sadFrog.png" srcset="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/7a936abffcd1a452478dca75a9f1ec62/12f09/sadFrog.png 148w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/7a936abffcd1a452478dca75a9f1ec62/e4a3f/sadFrog.png 295w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/7a936abffcd1a452478dca75a9f1ec62/0b533/sadFrog.png 500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>These has happened countless times. I usually look nonchalant on the outside but dying on the inside. People looked interested (probably due to my enthusiasm and it’s impolite to look otherwise) and then never actually bothered to use Anki. Some would actually try, make a few cards, do the reps for a few days and then say, “I tried and Anki doesn’t work.”</p>
<p>I’m probably over my head, but sometimes it feels like I’m personally attacked, that what I’m saying is not valuable. I understand it’s not true, but it took me years to study the learning science and to gain the experience with Anki/SuperMemo. The fact that they’re dismissing the software feels like they’re dismissing my knowledge and experience.</p>
<h2>The problems of giving advice on how to learn</h2>
<h3>#1. Nobody cares <em>that</em> much, alright?</h3>
<p>When I first discovered Anki I was like, “How come no one around me knows this?! I need to share this to everyone!” So I would tell my friends about Anki but nobody was interested. I’ve introduced Anki to people and every time it’s a very frustrating experience. (Surprise surprise, not SuperMemo. The learning curve of Anki is much lower. What chance do I have if I preached SuperMemo when they even think Anki is too hard to use?)</p>
<p>Update: I was never a missionary and randomly went out my way to tell people about Anki all the time like this:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e160326dcc1a72ba87b79f26f888d457/737f1/thejenkinscomicVim.webp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="vim" title="vim" src="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e160326dcc1a72ba87b79f26f888d457/737f1/thejenkinscomicVim.webp" srcset="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e160326dcc1a72ba87b79f26f888d457/cbe2e/thejenkinscomicVim.webp 148w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e160326dcc1a72ba87b79f26f888d457/3084c/thejenkinscomicVim.webp 295w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/e160326dcc1a72ba87b79f26f888d457/737f1/thejenkinscomicVim.webp 585w" sizes="(max-width: 585px) 100vw, 585px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p><a href="https://thejenkinscomic.wordpress.com/">Source</a></p>
<p>Very early on I did give unsolicited advice once to my best friend by intentionally bringing up Anki. Then I did bring up Anki on multiple occasions, but only when the opportunity presented itself, like the story above.</p>
<p>People may be interested in how you’ve developed a skill or become fluent in a foreign language, but just not <strong>that</strong> interested. And they certainly don’t expect to be suddenly lectured on how learning and memory work.</p>
<p>I never liked following up to people with questions like “So how’s Anki? Have you used it?” It feels like pushing an agenda to them. Also, since most would not even bother buying and downloading the app, their response is usually, “I forgot about it. I’ll do it later.” and the conversation would end in an awkward tone.</p>
<h3>#2. I’m not sure if I actually want it, alright?</h3>
<p>Sometimes people keep lamenting “I want to learn X or I want to get better grades.” How many times do you hear people say they want to learn a second language? This is like that friend who keeps saying “I want to lose weight”. Probably after all, they’re just lamenting and not yet ready to put in the effort to change.</p>
<p>Trying to convince others to use Anki/SuperMemo is like trying to convince your friends to go to the gym regularly. You can talk about the benefits of exercising/weight-lifting, how good you’ll feel afterwards, how much more productive you’ll be and so on. But nothing will work if they don’t try it in the first place, and it doesn’t help that spaced repetition doesn’t work in the short-term since using Spaced Repetition Software is a life-long pursuit (just as learning is):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This long term focus may explain why explicit spaced repetition is an uncommon studying technique: the pay-off is distant &amp; counterintuitive, the cost of self-control near &amp; vivid. <a href="https://www.gwern.net/Spaced-repetition">Gwern’s Spaced Repetition for Efficient Learning</a></p>
</blockquote>
<h3>#3. Why are you so hyped about it?</h3>
<p>It’s rare if people could understand and realize the significance and application of Spaced Repetition Software in a casual 10-min chat. It’s not about the complexity (it’s not rocket science after all), but rather it’s about awareness: problems with current learning approaches and how Anki/SuperMemo could solve the problems. In other words, if I don’t see the problems, why bother changing?</p>
<p>I have a friend who was learning German. She copied German vocabulary on one side and the equivalent English on the other in a notebook. I showed her my Korean Anki cards: “Take a look at these beautiful images! Gifs! Sentence cards! Audio clips! Mass Immersion Approach! (Former: All Japanese All The Time (AJATT)), Stephen Krashen’s Input Hypothesis!” Then I had another friend who was studying to become a nurse. I told him about Anki: “Image occlusion for anatomy!” It felt wrong of me to be hiding Anki (<a href="https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1374772155">Image Occlusion</a> to be specific) from him. Deep down I want to shove their faces to this table:</p>
<p><span>
      <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/91608/UtilityAssessment.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="UtilityAssessment" title="UtilityAssessment" src="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/fcda8/UtilityAssessment.png" srcset="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/12f09/UtilityAssessment.png 148w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/e4a3f/UtilityAssessment.png 295w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/fcda8/UtilityAssessment.png 590w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/efc66/UtilityAssessment.png 885w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/c83ae/UtilityAssessment.png 1180w,
https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/static/50f60f43bbd89353f63423035d211043/91608/UtilityAssessment.png 1251w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p>
<p>(Image source: <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/stoken/rbtfl/Z10jaVH/60XQM/full">Improving Students’ Learning With Effective Learning Techniques</a>)</p>
<p>I was exaggerating but you get the point: it’s not possible to convey the significance and application of it all in a casual 10-min chat. With the benefit of hindsight, all my attempts could’ve been a lot better:</p>
<ul>
<li>Maybe I was so convinced and have so much faith in Spaced Repetition Software that I came off as condescending, giving off the impression like “you don’t know how to study; let me teach you.”</li>
<li>Maybe it’s the bold claims: “You’ll get 2x results with half the study time.” (How many are really true whenever you hear such claim?)</li>
<li>Maybe it’s the situation: all he or she wants is someone to listen about the difficulty of studying, not some real advice or suggestions.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s the guy from <a href="http://brianjx.altervista.org/">How I Passed the Demanding […] Italian Language Exam Without Going to Italy – Here’s a Hint: the 326,538 Flashcard Reviews Helped a Lot.</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Like many language teachers, V. had never heard of Anki (but she did know Reverso Context). I showed her how I studied Italian …</p></blockquote></section></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/2020-10-31-why-i-no-longer-tell-my-friends-about-anki-supermemo/">https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/2020-10-31-why-i-no-longer-tell-my-friends-about-anki-supermemo/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.masterhowtolearn.com/2020-10-31-why-i-no-longer-tell-my-friends-about-anki-supermemo/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24957617</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 06:33:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Visualizing Git Concepts with D3]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 47 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24957280">thread link</a>) | @gilad
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://onlywei.github.io/explain-git-with-d3/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://onlywei.github.io/explain-git-with-d3/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    <div id="ExplainGitCommit-Container">
      <p>
        We are going to skip instructing you on how to add your files for commit in this explanation.
        Let's assume you already know how to do that. If you don't, go read some other tutorials.
      </p>
      <p>
        Pretend that you already have your files staged for commit and enter <span>git commit</span>
        as many times as you like in the terminal box.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitTag-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git tag name</span> will create a new tag named "name".
        Creating tags just creates a new tag pointing to the currently checked out commit.
      </p>
      <p>
        Tags can be deleted using the command <span>git tag -d name</span> (coming soon).
      </p>
      <p>
        Type <span>git commit</span> and <span>git tag</span> commands
        to your hearts desire until you understand this concept.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitBranch-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git branch name</span> will create a new branch named "name".
        Creating branches just creates a new tag pointing to the currently checked out commit.
      </p>
      <p>
        Branches can be deleted using the command <span>git branch -d name</span>.
      </p>
      <p>
        Type <span>git commit</span> and <span>git branch</span> commands
        to your hearts desire until you understand this concept.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitCheckout-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git checkout</span> has many uses,
        but the main one is to switch between branches.<br>
        For example, to switch from master branch to dev branch,
        I would type <span>git checkout dev</span>.
        After that, if I do a git commit, notice where it goes. Try it.
      </p>
      <p>
        In addition to checking out branches, you can also checkout individual commits. Try it.<br>
        Make a new commit and then type <span>git checkout bb92e0e</span>
        and see what happens.
      </p>
      <p>
        Type <span>git commit</span>, <span>git branch</span>,
        and <span>git checkout</span> commands to your hearts desire
        until you understand this concept.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitCheckout-b-Container">
      <p>
        You can combine <span>git branch</span> and <span>git checkout</span>
        into a single command by typing <span>git checkout -b branchname</span>.
        This will create the branch if it does not already exist and immediately check it out.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitReset-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git reset</span> will move HEAD and the current branch back to wherever
        you specify, abandoning any commits that may be left behind. This is useful to undo a commit
        that you no longer need.
      </p>
      <p>
        This command is normally used with one of three flags: "--soft", "--mixed", and "--hard".
        The soft and mixed flags deal with what to do with the work that was inside the commit after
        you reset, and you can read about it <a href="http://git-scm.com/2011/07/11/reset.html">here</a>.
        Since this visualization cannot graphically display that work, only the "--hard" flag will work
        on this site.
      </p>
      <p>
        The ref "HEAD^" is usually used together with this command. "HEAD^" means "the commit right
        before HEAD. "HEAD^^" means "two commits before HEAD", and so on.
      </p>
      <p>
        Note that you must <b>never</b> use <span>git reset</span> to abandon commits
        that have already been pushed and merged into the origin. This can cause your local repository
        to become out of sync with the origin. Don't do it unless you really know what you're doing.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitRevert-Container">
      <p>
        To undo commits that have already been pushed and shared with the team, we cannot use the
        <span>git reset</span> command. Instead, we have to use <span>git revert</span>.
      </p>
      <p>
        <span>git revert</span> will create a new commit that will undo all of the work that
        was done in the commit you want to revert.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitMerge-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git merge</span> will create a new commit with two parents. The resulting
        commit snapshot will have the all of the work that has been done in both branches.
      </p>
      <p>
        If there was no divergence between the two commits, git will do a "fast-forward" method merge.<br>
        To see this happen, checkout the 'ff' branch and then type <span>git merge dev</span>.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitRebase-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git rebase</span> will take the commits on this branch and "move" them so that their
        new "base" is at the point you specify.
      </p>
      <p>
        You should pay close attention to the commit IDs of the circles as they move when you do this exercise.
      </p>
      <p>
        The reason I put "move" in quotations because this process actually generates brand new commits with
        completely different IDs than the old commits, and leaves the old commits where they were. For this reason,
        you never want to rebase commits that have already been shared with the team you are working with.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitFetch-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git fetch</span> will update all of the "remote tracking branches" in your local repository.
        Remote tracking branches are tagged in grey.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitPull-Container">
      <p>
        A <span>git pull</span> is a two step process that first does a <span>git fetch</span>,
        and then does a <span>git merge</span> of the remote tracking branch associated with your current branch.
        If you have no current branch, the process will stop after fetching.
      </p>
      <p>
        If the argument "--rebase" was given by typing <span>git pull --rebase</span>, the second step of
        pull process will be a rebase instead of a merge. This can be set to the default behavior by configuration by typing:
        <span>git config branch.BRANCHNAME.rebase true</span>.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitPush-Container">
      <p>
        A <span>git push</span> will find the commits you have on your local branch that the corresponding branch
        on the origin server does not have, and send them to the remote repository.
      </p>
      <p>
        By default, all pushes must cause a fast-forward merge on the remote repository. If there is any divergence between
        your local branch and the remote branch, your push will be rejected. In this scenario, you need to pull first and then
        you will be able to push again.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitClean-Container">
      <p>
        One simple example of the use of <span>git reset</span> is to completely restore your local repository
        state to that of the origin.<br>
        You can do so by typing <span>git reset origin/master</span>.
      </p>
      <p>
        Note that this won't delete untracked files, you will have to delete those separately with
        the command <span>git clean -df</span>.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitFetchRebase-Container">
      <p>
        Below is a situation in which you are working in a local branch that is all your own. You want to receive the latest code
        from the origin server's master branch. To update your local branch, you can do it without having to switch branches!
      </p>
      <p>
        First do a <span>git fetch</span>, then type <span>git rebase origin/master</span>!
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitDeleteBranches-Container">
      <p>
        <span>git branch -d</span> is used to delete branches.
        I have pre-created a bunch of branches for you to delete in the playground below.
        Have at it.
      </p>
      
    </div>
    <div id="ExplainGitFree-Container">
      <p>
        Do whatever you want in this free playground.
      </p>
      
    </div>
  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://onlywei.github.io/explain-git-with-d3/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24957280</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 04:43:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Toronto-area lawyer had to flee Canada after taking on the tow truck industry]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 200 | Comments 87 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24957200">thread link</a>) | @walterbell
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://www.ctvnews.ca/w5/this-toronto-area-lawyer-had-to-flee-the-country-after-taking-on-the-tow-truck-industry-1.5167869 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ctvnews.ca/w5/this-toronto-area-lawyer-had-to-flee-the-country-after-taking-on-the-tow-truck-industry-1.5167869">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>TORONTO -- 
	Lisa Carr never thought her work would lead to armed threats, a firebombing, a shooting and a conspiracy to kill her.</p>
<p>
	The Carr Law office is in a nondescript strip mall in Vaughan, Ont., north of Toronto. It’s closed now, after the litigation lawyer says police told her they could no longer protect her.</p>
<p>
	She was shuttled to another country where she spent five long months in hiding. Carr has never before told her story, but agreed to meet for an interview as part of a W5 investigation into the shady underbelly of an industry that forced her to give up her business and almost cost her, her life: The tow truck industry.</p>
<p>
	Over the last number of years, criminal elements have been battling for lucrative control of the major highways around the Toronto area. It has resulted in more than 50 arsons, multiple shootings and at least four murders.</p>
<p>
	So why is there so much violence over a couple of hundred-dollar tows at the side of the road? Because that one tow can net tens of thousands of dollars.</p>
<p>
	Here’s how it works: The tow truck driver gets a kickback from an unscrupulous auto body shop, which then submits wildly inflated repair fees to an insurance company.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="york police" src="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.4954903!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_960/image.jpg"></p>
<p>
	The insurance industry estimates that fake repair bills tally up to $2 billion a year in Canada. And that’s why Carr was in the crosshairs. She was hired by an insurance company to challenge bogus claims.</p>
<p>
	Over the course of a number of months, Carr’s law firm was the target of increasingly violent attacks. First a firebombing and then her office was set on fire.</p>
<p>
	Months later, in broad daylight, a colleague leaving work had a gun put to her head and was told, “Stop suing our friends.” Shortly after that, again in broad daylight, someone opened fire through the front door of the busy office.</p>
<p>
	Carr says it is incredible no one was struck by the flurry of bullets.</p>
<p>
	“I looked down the hall and I saw my receptionist on her hands and knees surrounded by glass. And one of the other girls came running at me saying, ‘Shots fired, shots fired. Call 911.’”</p>
<p>
	While the violence surrounding the tow truck industry has made headlines in the Greater Toronto Area, the story that has never been told is that York Regional Police (YRP) uncovered a plot to kill Carr.</p>
<p>
	It was such a credible threat that they gave her an hour to pack up her belongings and leave her home. Carr and her husband were then whisked out of the country and spent five months in hiding.</p>
<p>
	Three separate police services – YRP, Toronto Police Service and Ontario Provincial Police – joined forces to launch Project Platinum to investigate the violence associated with the tow truck industry.</p>
<p>
	They carried out a series of raids this past spring, which netted dozens of high-powered weapons and led to the arrests of 35 people who face almost 500 charges, including the attempted murder of Carr.</p>
<p>
	<img alt="weapon" src="https://www.ctvnews.ca/polopoly_fs/1.4954983!/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_960/image.jpg"></p>
<p>
	Now back in Canada, Carr says police have told her she is likely no longer in danger, but with one caveat.</p>
<p>
	“The police said we believe the risk is low. As long as you don't go back to work, as long as you don't restart the firm,” she says.</p>
<p>
	“So they have effectively ended my career. We lost everything. They won.”</p>
                                              </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/w5/this-toronto-area-lawyer-had-to-flee-the-country-after-taking-on-the-tow-truck-industry-1.5167869</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24957200</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 04:20:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Simple Image Vectorization]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 44 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24957120">thread link</a>) | @thesephist
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://wordsandbuttons.online/simple_image_vectorization.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wordsandbuttons.online/simple_image_vectorization.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
    <p>
Vectorization is when you take some minecraft-style raster image and make a crisp vector picture out of it.
    </p>
    <img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/6b/Bitmap_VS_SVG.svg">
    
    <p>
It's especially useful when you want to turn a satellite photo into a map. Or if you want to scan some blueprint and turn it into a CAD model. Or if you want to reissue an old game and you don't want to redraw all the artwork from scratch.
    </p>
    <p>
The algorithm I'm going to show you has nothing to do with all these things. It's a basic vectorization technique which, in its original form, has little to none applications in the industry.
    </p>
    <p>
On the plus side, it illustrates the approach rather well. It shows how things like bilinear interpolation, gradient descent, and parametric splines work together to solve a real-world problem. At the very least, it makes learning about all these things a little more compelling.
    </p>

    <h2>
An input image
    </h2>
    <p>
A raster image is essentially a rectangular table of things. If it's a full-color RGB, then it's a table of color pixels. Color pixels are the triplets of 8-bit integer values where each value represents an amount of red, green, and blue color.
    </p>
    <p>
Medical images, such as obtained from computed tomography, are usually the tables of 12-bit or 16-bit integers. It's not a color really since the values come from invisible X-ray radiation, but they are called gray values nevertheless.
    </p>
    <p>
Satellite images may have a lot of channels. Apart from the colors of the visible specter they may contain ultra-violet and infra-red luminosity. Channels may be represented by integers or floating point values.
    </p>
    <p>
Our image will be a simple gray-scale bitmap.
    </p>
    <canvas id="greyscale_canvas" width="640" height="640"></canvas>
    <p>
Technically, we can already turn it into vectors rather easily. Let's just agree on some threshold, and mark the contour of all the pixels that have the values exceeding this threshold.
    </p>
    <canvas id="greyscale_canvas_contour" width="640" height="640"></canvas>
    <p>
Well, it's simple, but it's not what we wanted. We want curves, not corners. And for that, we have to make our image less cornery.
    </p>
    <h2>
<span id="index_image_interpolation">Image interpolation</span>
    </h2>
    <p>
Let's say our image is not a table of values. Let's say we only know the values in the centers of the pixels, and we have to guess the values between them somehow.
    </p>
    <p>
This is called interpolation. The simplest case would be the nearest neighbor interpolation, where for every point on an image, the value is the value from the nearest pixel's center. But this simply turns it back into a table.
    </p>
    <p>
A little more advanced is the <span id="index_bilinear_interpolation">bilinear interpolation</span>. The value is the linear sum of the four neighboring values. It looks like this.
    </p>
    <div>
    <pre id="code_1">// pixel value with out of bounds checks
function pixel_in(pixels, i, j) {
    if(i &gt;= pixels.length)
        return pixel_in(pixels, pixels.length-1, j);
    if(i &lt; 0)
        return pixel_in(pixels, 0, j);
    if(j &gt;= pixels[0].length)
        return pixel_in(pixels, i, pixels[0].length-1);
    if(j &lt; 0)
        return pixel_in(pixels, i, 0);
    return pixels[i][j];
}

// linear interpolation
function value_in(pixels, x, y) {
    var j = Math.floor(x - 0.5);
    var tj = x - 0.5 - j;
    var i = Math.floor(y - 0.5);
    var ti = y - 0.5 - i;
    return pixel_in(pixels, i, j) * (1 - ti) * (1 - tj)
         + pixel_in(pixels, i, j+1) * (1 - ti) * (tj)
         + pixel_in(pixels, i+1, j+1) * (ti) * (tj)
         + pixel_in(pixels, i+1, j) * (ti) * (1 - tj);
}
    </pre>
    </div>
    <p>
If we darken the pixels where the interpolated value meets the threshold, we'll get some kind of a contour.
    </p>
    <canvas id="interpolation_canvas" width="640" height="640"></canvas>
    
    <p>
There are other methods. Plenty of them. But linear interpolation solves the cornery border problem just fine. Although, the border we see is just the borderline of some threshold. It's not a vector representation yet.
    </p>

    <h2>
Turning an interpolated image into a contour
    </h2>
    <p>
We can borrow an idea from the <a href="https://wordsandbuttons.online/the_simplest_possible_smooth_contouring_algorithm.html">simplest possible smooth contouring</a> algorithm. We'll build an initial border from the source pixels, and then we'll use our linearly interpolated image to find the best place to put each contour point so the image value will meet the threshold value.
    </p>
    <p>
When you have a <span id="index_distance_field">distance field</span>, it's easy. A distance field is when for any point in space you can tell how far it lies from the surface you want. It's basically a function from point in space to distance.
    </p>
    <p>
You take its gradient, take the difference between the value you have and the threshold value. Since it's the distance field, the value difference is exactly the distance you should move your point for. And the gradient is the exact opposite direction. You just inverse, multiply, add — and you're there.
    </p>
    <p>
Unfortunately, we don't have a distance field. We have a continuous image which only resembles one.
    </p>
    <p>
But the principle still works. If you traverse against the gradient, you will get closer to the threshold value. And the more the difference, the further you have to go. It's just you wouldn't always get there in one try.
    </p>
    <p>
So let's try several times then. Let's make an <a href="https://wordsandbuttons.online/interactive_introduction_to_iterative_algorithms.html">iterative algorithm</a> out of it.
    </p>
    <div>
    <pre id="code_2">// gradient
function gradient(pixels, x, y) {
    const eps = 1e-5;
    return [(value_in(pixels, x + eps, y) - value_in(pixels, x, y)) / eps,
            (value_in(pixels, x, y + eps) - value_in(pixels, x, y)) / eps];
}

// how far should you shift the point to meet the isoline
// if value_in were a distance function
function gradient_shift(pixels, threshold, x, y) {
    var g = gradient(pixels, x, y);
    var g_norm = Math.sqrt(g[0]*g[0] + g[1]*g[1]);
    var d = threshold - value_in(pixels, x, y);
    return [g[0] * d / g_norm / g_norm, g[1] * d / g_norm / g_norm];
}

// brings a point closer to the threshold isoline
function fit_point_better(pixels, threshold, point) {
    const ok_error = 1/255;
    if(Math.abs(value_in(pixels, point[0], point[1]) - threshold) &lt; ok_error)
        return point;
    gs = gradient_shift(pixels, threshold, point[0], point[1])
    var new_point = [point[0] + gs[0], point[1] + gs[1]];
    return fit_point_better(pixels, threshold, new_point);
}
    </pre>
    </div>
    <p>
We'll move our contour points against the gradient until we're close enough to the threshold
    </p>
    <canvas id="fitting_canvas" width="640" height="640"></canvas>
        
    <p>
That's good but we can do better. Let's make the contour smooth.
    </p>

    <h2>
Cubic splines
    </h2>
    <p>
All we have to do to make the contour smooth is to turn each line segment into a parametric cubic curve.
    </p>
    <p>
It's probably sounds more complicated than it is. A parametric cubic curve is just a pair of polynomials. If you have the points and partial derivatives in this points, you can get the coefficients for them from this pair of <a href="https://wordsandbuttons.online/programmers_introduction_to_linear_equations.html">linear systems</a>:
    </p>
    <div><p>
Px(t<sub>1</sub>)' = 3a<sub>x</sub>t<sub>1</sub><sup>2</sup> + 2b<sub>x</sub>t<sub>1</sub> + c = dx<sub>1</sub>/dt
<br>
Px(t<sub>1</sub>) = a<sub>x</sub>t<sub>1</sub><sup>3</sup> + b<sub>x</sub>t<sub>1</sub><sup>2</sup> + c<sub>x</sub>t<sub>1</sub> + d = x<sub>1</sub>
<br>
Px(t<sub>2</sub>) = a<sub>x</sub>t<sub>2</sub><sup>3</sup> + b<sub>x</sub>t<sub>2</sub><sup>2</sup> + c<sub>x</sub>t<sub>2</sub> + d = x<sub>2</sub>
<br>
Px(t<sub>2</sub>)' = 3a<sub>x</sub>t<sub>2</sub><sup>2</sup> + 2b<sub>x</sub>t<sub>2</sub> + c = dx<sub>2</sub>/dt
    </p><p>
    
Py(t<sub>1</sub>)' = 3a<sub>y</sub>t<sub>1</sub><sup>2</sup> + 2b<sub>y</sub>t<sub>1</sub> + c = dy<sub>1</sub>/dt
<br>
Py(t<sub>1</sub>) = a<sub>y</sub>t<sub>1</sub><sup>3</sup> + b<sub>y</sub>t<sub>1</sub><sup>2</sup> + c<sub>y</sub>t<sub>1</sub> + d = y<sub>1</sub>
<br>
Py(t<sub>2</sub>) = a<sub>y</sub>t<sub>2</sub><sup>3</sup> + b<sub>y</sub>t<sub>2</sub><sup>2</sup> + c<sub>y</sub>t<sub>2</sub> + d = y<sub>2</sub>
<br>
Py(t<sub>2</sub>)' = 3a<sub>y</sub>t<sub>2</sub><sup>2</sup> + 2b<sub>y</sub>t<sub>2</sub> + c = dy<sub>2</sub>/dt
    </p></div>
    <p>
The curve itself will then look like this.
    </p>
    <canvas id="cubic_canvas" width="640" height="640"></canvas>
    <p>
Even more, since we get to choose the parameter range, we can make it [0..1]. This greatly simplifies our system and makes it really easy to solve.
    </p>
    <p>
Here is the function that makes one array of polynomial coefficients from two pairs of point and tangent values.
    </p>
    <div>
    <pre id="code_3">// solver specific to [0..1] parametrized splines
function spline_for(p1, p1d, p2, p2d) {
//     A = [
//         [1, 0, 0, 0],
//         [0, 1, 0, 0],
//         [1, 1, 1, 1],
//         [0, 1, 2, 3]];
//     B = [p1, p1d, p2, p2d]
    return [
        p1,
        p1d,
        3*p2 - p2d - 3*p1 - 2*p1d,
        p2d + p1d - 2*p2 + 2*p1
    ];
}
    </pre>
    </div>
    <p>
The polynomial is then computed in every <i>t</i> with this function.
    </p>
    <div>
    <pre id="code_4">// polynomial
function polynomial_in_t(A, t){
    var pt = 0.0;
    for(var i = 0; i &lt; A.length; ++i){
        pt += A[i] * Math.pow(x, i);
    }
    return pt;
}
    </pre>
    </div>
    <p>
So for every line segment with tangents, we can make a parametric polynomial. There is one problem though. We don't have tangents.
    </p>
    <p>
We have the gradient, which is orthogonal to the tangent, but there are two possible tangents in every point. The tangent can be oriented left or right from the gradient.
    </p>
    <p>
But this is solvable. Let's just pick the direction we like and keep it consistent.
    </p>
    <p>
Let the curves that originally come from horizontally oriented segments always have both tangents that way that <i>dx &gt; 0</i>. And the ones that come from vertically oriented segments, will have <i>dy &gt; 0</i>.
    </p>
    <p>
It looks like we have enough parts to assemble an algorithm.
    </p>
    <h2>
Creating splines from the pixels
    </h2>
    <p>
Let's split our vectorization into two parts. First, we'll get points and tangents for every line segment from the pixels. Then we'll turn it all into polynomial splines.
    </p>
    <p>
The function that does the first part looks like this.
    </p>
    <div>
    <pre id="code_5">function turn_pixels_into_points_and_tangents(pixels, threshold) {
    var points = [];
    var tangents = [];

    // "horizontal" pieces
    for(var i = 0; i &lt;= pixels.length; i += 1) {
        var old_point = [];
        var old_tangent = [];
        for(var j = 0; j &lt;= pixels[0].length; j += 1) {
            // if right, left, top, and bottom pixels have a sign change,
            // there should be a spline there
            var sign_change_on_the_right  =
                (pixel_in(pixels, i-1, j+0) - threshold) *
                (pixel_in(pixels, i+0, j+0) - threshold) &lt; 0;
            var sign_change_on_the_left   =
                (pixel_in(pixels, i-1, j-1) - threshold) *
                (pixel_in(pixels, i+0, j-1) - threshold) &lt; 0;
            var sign_change_on_the_bottom =
                (pixel_in(pixels, i+0, j-1) - threshold) *
                (pixel_in(pixels, i+0, j+0) - threshold) &lt; 0;
            var sign_change_on_the_top    =
                (pixel_in(pixels, i-1, j-1) - threshold) *
                …</pre></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://wordsandbuttons.online/simple_image_vectorization.html">https://wordsandbuttons.online/simple_image_vectorization.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wordsandbuttons.online/simple_image_vectorization.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24957120</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 03:57:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Yet another alternative to floating-point numbers]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24956184">thread link</a>) | @okaleniuk
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://wordsandbuttons.online/yet_another_alternative_to_floating_point_numbers.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://wordsandbuttons.online/yet_another_alternative_to_floating_point_numbers.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
	
	<p>
Floating-point numbers are fine. They are decently designed and well standardized, they provide a good compromise between performance and precision. They work great most of the time. Until the day when they suddenly don't and nobody knows why.
	</p>
	<p>
For me, that day came when I encountered a bug in the Taubin estimator. <a href="https://graphics.stanford.edu/courses/cs468-01-fall/Papers/taubin-smoothing.pdf">Taubin smoothing</a> takes a triangle mesh, a pair of magic numbers called λ and μ, a little time to think, and it makes the input mesh smooth. It also makes sure that the mesh isn't reduced to a perfectly smooth but rather uninteresting sphere or a point.
	</p>
	<p>
The first magic number λ is something between 0 and 1. When it's 0 — nothing happens at all, and when it's 1 — nothing good happens either. It should be somewhere in between. Nobody really knows how to pick this number but an experienced engineer can at least make an educated guess. 
	</p>
	<p>
The second magic number governs shrinkage compensation. It's a negative number slightly greater than λ in its absolute value. Nobody knows how to pick it either but this time even an educated guess is a challenge.
	</p>
	<p>
That's why you need an estimator. Something that picks the μ for you. And we have one. And it was bugged. And I was the one to fix it.
	</p>
	<p>
The first day of the investigation showed that the estimator is in fact entirely correct. The second day of the investigation  showed that the tests covering the bug are correct just as well. The third day of the investigation brought a promising hypothesis that the whole story is just a bad dream and all it takes to solve the mystery is to wake up. The fourth morning killed that hypothesis and left me completely clueless.
	</p>
	<p>
Luckily I have a friend who is smarter than me and he advised to fuzz the input a little and see what happens then. I did. And something happened. The bug didn't go away but the μ changed a lot. Way unproportionally to the small changes in the input. Fascinating!
	</p>
	<p>
We can expect a computation to work with some error. It's fine, we get input data from sensors and they embed some error, to begin with. We print out our finished models, and the printers have some limited precision as well so a small error doesn't upset anyone. It's all good while the error is small. But what if it isn't?
	</p>
	<p>
As it turns out, in my case, a completely correct algorithm had a computational error of about 1. Not 1e-16 or 1e-5 but 1. Just 1. So if you expect your μ to be somewhat close to -0.7, and the estimator says it's 0.3, it is in fact correct. It is still a correct estimation within its error range.
	</p>
	<p>
Correct but entirely useless.
	</p>
	<h2>
Challenge your intuition with a “Guess the Error” game
	</h2>
	<p>
Ok, so it's not the computational error per se that causes trouble but only the unexpected and unpredictable error. Can we predict it though?
	</p>
	<p>
Well, of course, we can. There is a whole field of numerical error analysis for that but let's be honest, most of the time we use our intuition instead. So how good is our intuition exactly?
	</p>
	<p>
I propose a game to find out. Let's take a cubic equation solver. It's a relatively complex computation with a very simple way to validate its precision. We will pick some roots first and then we will generate the cubic equation for these roots. Then we'll make the cubic solver find our roots back through the computation. The difference between the original and the computed value for each root will be our measurable error. This error divided by the original value will be our relative error.
	</p>
	<p>
Here is the exact code for the experiment. It's also <a href="https://github.com/akalenuk/wordsandbuttons/blob/master/exp/rational_bounds/rationale/cubic_solver_example.cpp">available on GitHub</a>.
	</p>
	
	
	
	<p>
Now if we pick our roots as 1, 2, and 3, the equation produced will be:
	</p>
	<p>
(x - 1) (x - 2) (x - 3) = 0
	</p>
	<p>
Expanding the brackets we get this:
	</p>
	<p>
x<sup>3</sup> - 6x<sup>2</sup> + 11x - 6 = 0
	</p>
	<p>
And when we run our solver we get:
	</p>
	<p>
x = 1, x = 2, x = 3
	</p>
	<p>
Well, yes. On the equation this simple there is no error whatsoever. The computation works flawlessly. So let's start making it worse.
	</p>
	<h2>Round 1</h2>
	<p>
The slider below lets you pick an interval in the logarithmic scale. The interval may start at 10<sup>-12</sup> and end at 10<sup>12</sup>. It's impossible to predict the exact error up to a single number so you should just pick an appropriate interval that covers the error<span id="shown_note_1"><u onclick="show('note_1')">*</u>.</span>
	</p>
	<p>
Let's say we have the roots of 0.001, 2, 3 000. So to which interval, in your opinion, the maximum relative error for a cubic solver belongs?
	</p>
	<canvas id="interval_1" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	
	

	<h2>Round 2</h2>
	<p>
Now let's make our roots even more diverse in magnitude. How about 1e-6, 2, and 3e6?
	</p>
	<p>
Where do you think the error might be?
	</p>
	<canvas id="interval_2" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	
	

	<h2>Round 3</h2>
	<p>
And what about 1e-9, 2, and 3e9?
	</p>
	<canvas id="interval_3" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	
	
	<h2>Meet the <span id="index_rational_bounds">rational bounds</span></h2>
	<p>
It's not the error per se that is bad. Error is omnipresent. Every measuring device has its error, every 3D printer and every milling machine has its maximal precision. The error is fine.
	</p>
	<p>
It's only the unpredictability that makes it unpleasant.
	</p>
	<p>
People address errors in multiple ways. In metrology, a measured value is supplemented with its absolute error. You don't say that the temperature outside is 10°, you say it's 10° ± 0.5°. This might seem redundant since this is a small error for the weather outside, but in some other context, this very error might become significant. If you're measuring body temperature, a 1-degree difference is enough to tell a sick person from a perfectly healthy one. You can not afford a whole 1-degree error in this scenario.
	</p>
	<p>
If you have this input error written down, you can pull it through your computation to see if the resulting error is still tolerable. To do that, you need to exchange your measured numbers for intervals. A number with error becomes an interval: 10° ± 0.5° becomes [9.5, 10.5]°.
	</p>
	<p>
You can sum these intervals just as you add numbers:
	</p>
<canvas id="interval_4" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	<p>
+
	</p>
<canvas id="interval_5" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	<p>
=
	</p>
<canvas id="interval_6" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	<p>
You can multiply them as well.
	</p>
<canvas id="interval_7" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	<p>
×
	</p>
<canvas id="interval_8" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	<p>
=
	</p>
<canvas id="interval_9" width="608" height="84"></canvas>
	<p>
So with intervals, you can accommodate the input error. You can drag it through the computation and see how it plays with other values with their own error. In the end, you will have your computed value within some interval and the size of this interval will indicate the output error. But what about the error of the computation itself?
	</p>
	<p>
A computational error occurs when we can't store the operation result in the same types we keep our operands in and we're forced to throw some data away. Let's say we have Python-style “unlimited” length integers. This means that if our computation only consists of addition, subtraction, and multiplication, we would never face any computational error.
	</p>
	<p>
Of course, with division, things get a little bit different. E. g. we can't store <nobr>16 ¾</nobr> in integers so we have to truncate it into 16. In this case, the whole fractional part becomes our error.
	</p>
	<p>
We can use pairs of integers to represent rational numbers. This will solve the division issue. However, this type of rational number, while does not accumulate errors, accumulates digits. The more digits it has, the slower the computation goes. At some point, it may simply become impractically slow. Just like with the uncontrollable error, uncontrollable size becomes an issue.
	</p>
	<p>
We want a compromise. Some entity that grows error controllably yet still operates in constant speed. And we can get it, for example, by merging two ideas: intervals and rational numbers together.
	</p>
	<p>
Let's say, we want to write a number as an interval of its tenths. We can do that most intuitively by throwing away all the digits after the first one.
	</p>
	<table><tbody><tr>
	<td></td>
	<td>≤</td>
	<td></td>
	<td>≤</td>
	<td></td>
	</tr></tbody></table>
	<p>
Just like we can do this with decimal fraction, we can do this with any rational number. We can put it between a pair of rational numbers made by finite integers. In this case, every integer is in the range [0, 1, ..., 99].
	</p>
	<table><tbody><tr>
	<td></td>
	<td rowspan="2">≤</td>
	<td></td>
	<td rowspan="2">≤</td>
	<td></td>
	</tr><tr>
	<td></td>
	<td></td>
	<td></td>
	</tr></tbody></table>
	<p>
Ok, this is not entirely true. If the number is greater than 99, then we can't really store it in our tiny rationals but we can say that it's larger than 99 by assigning the 0 divisor to its upper bound. Of course, it's just a dirty hack but let's leave it like that.
	</p>
	<p>
Now if we want to accommodate both input error and computational error, all we have to do is to represent an input interval in its finite rational numbers. A finite rational lower bound of this interval and a finite rational upper bound of the same interval.
	</p>
	<table><tbody><tr>
	<td></td>
	<td rowspan="2">≤</td>
	<td></td>
	<td rowspan="2">≤</td>
	<td></td>
	<td rowspan="2">≤</td>
	<td></td>
	</tr><tr>
	<td></td>
	<td></td>
	<td></td>
	<td></td>
	</tr></tbody></table>
	<p>
This entity — a pair of finite rational bounds, represents a real number along with both its input error and representational error. It also grows computational error explicitly while the size of the entity remains constant.
	</p>
	<p>
The implementation example is <a href="https://github.com/akalenuk/wordsandbuttons/tree/master/exp/rational_bounds/sketch_in_cpp">available on GitHub</a>. Please note that it's just a proof of concept and not the best possible solution in terms of neither error minimization nor speed.
	</p>

	<h2>Conclusion</h2>
	<p>
The computational error may become a problem at the least appropriate moment. Both rational numbers and intervals are well-known alternatives for floating-point numbers when the error becomes an issue.
	</p>
	<p>
Rational bounds, being a chimeric product of both ideas, let you manage both measurement error and computational error in a coherent way without compromising performance all that much.
	</p>


	

	
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://wordsandbuttons.online/yet_another_alternative_to_floating_point_numbers.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24956184</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 23:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[NAT Slipstreaming]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 360 | Comments 99 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24955891">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://samy.pl/slipstream/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://samy.pl/slipstream/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p><a href="https://samy.pl/slipstream/">NAT Slipstreaming</a> allows an attacker to remotely access any TCP/UDP service bound to a victim machine, bypassing the victim's NAT/firewall (arbitrary firewall pinhole control), just by the victim visiting a website.</p><p><em>animation generated with my <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/samyk/drawio">fork</a> of <a target="_blank" href="https://draw.io/">draw.io</a>, allowing exportable edge context flow &amp; control in animations</em></p><p>NAT Slipstreaming exploits the user's browser in conjunction with the Application Level Gateway (ALG) connection tracking mechanism built into NATs, routers, and firewalls by chaining internal IP extraction via timing attack or WebRTC, automated remote MTU and IP fragmentation discovery, TCP packet size massaging, TURN authentication misuse, precise packet boundary control, and protocol confusion through browser abuse. As it's the NAT or firewall that opens the destination port, this bypasses any browser-based port restrictions.</p><p>This attack takes advantage of arbitrary control of the data portion of some TCP and UDP packets <i>without</i> including HTTP or other headers; the attack performs this new packet injection technique across all major modern (and older) browsers, and is a modernized version to my original <a target="_blank" href="https://samy.pl/natpin/">NAT Pinning technique from 2010</a> (presented at DEFCON 18 + Black Hat 2010). Additionally, new techniques for local IP address discovery are included.</p><p>This attack requires the NAT/firewall to support ALG (Application Level Gateways), which are mandatory for protocols that can use multiple ports (control channel + data channel) such as SIP and H323 (VoIP protocols), FTP, IRC DCC, etc.</p><div>
  <li>victim visits malicious site (or site with malicious advertisement)<!-- eg <a target=_blank href="https://samy.pl/slipstream/server">https://samy.pl/slipstream/server</a>--></li>
<li>internal IP of victim first must be extracted by browser and sent to server

<ul>
<li>internal IP attempted to be extracted via <a target="_blank" href="https://www.w3.org/TR/webrtc/">WebRTC</a> data channel over https</li>
<ul>
<li>some browsers (Chrome) only divulge the local IP via WebRTC over HTTPS but some of our attacks require HTTP so we first redirect to the HTTPS version of the attack software to extract the local IP</li>
<li>we then redirect to the HTTP version with the local IP included in the URL if we were able to obtain it to bypass other cross-origin protection mechanisms (the <code>.local</code> mDNS/Bonjour address presented will not be useful for the attack)</li>
</ul>
<li>if internal IP not divulged by WebRTC (Safari) or no WebRTC (&lt;= IE11), <strong>web-based TCP timing attack performed</strong>

<ul>
<li>hidden <code>img</code> tags to all common gateways (eg <code>192.168.0.1</code>) are loaded in background</li>
<li><code>onerror/onsuccess</code> events attached to <code>img</code> tags</li>
<li>if any TCP RST (oneror) returned by gateway, or SYN + HTTP response (onsuccess), within a few seconds (before TCP timeout triggers onerror), we've detected valid subnet</li>
<li>re-perform timing attack across all IPs on detected subnets (/24), measuring time to onerror/onsuccess firing</li>
<li>fastest response is likely internal IP, though all responses are considered victim internal IP candidates and attacked</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>large TCP beacon sent via hidden form and automatic HTTP POST to attacker "HTTP server" bound to a non-standard port to force TCP segmentation and maximum MTU size discovery of the victim's IP stack
<ul>
<li>attacker TCP server sends <a target="_blank" href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc793#section-3.1">Maximum Segment Size</a> TCP Option to massage victim outbound packet sizes (<a target="_blank" href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc793#section-3.1">RFC 793 x3.1</a>), allowing control of how large browser TCP packets will be</li>
</ul></li>
<li>large UDP beacon sent from browser via WebRTC TURN authentication mechanism to non-standard port to attacker's server to force IP fragmentation with TURN <code>username</code> field stuffed
<ul>
<li>we perform a similar attack as our TCP segmentation, but over UDP as IP fragmentation will occur and provide different values than TCP segmentation</li>
<li>victim MTU size, IP header size, IP packet size, TCP header size, TCP segment sizes detected by server and sent back to victim's browser, used later for packet stuffing</li>
</ul></li>
<li>"SIP packet" in new hidden form generated, containing internal IP to trigger Application Level Gateway connection tracking
<ul>
<li>"HTTP POST" to server on TCP port 5060 (SIP port) initiated, avoiding <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/samyk/chromium/blob/2d57e5b8afc6d01b344a8d95d3470d46b35845c5/net/base/port_util.cc#L20-L90">restricted browser ports</a></li>
<li>POST data is "stuffed" to exact TCP segment size / packet boundary, then “SIP packet” appended and posted via web form</li>
<li><b>victim IP stack breaks the POST into multiple TCP packets, leaving the "SIP packet" (as part of POST data) in its own TCP packet without any accompanying HTTP headers</b></li>
<li>if browser alters size of multipart/form boundary (Firefox) or packet size changes for any other reason, size change is communicated back to client and client auto-resends with new size</li>
<li>when opening UDP port, SIP packet is sent over TURN protocol inside specially crafted <code>username</code> field forcing IP fragmentation and precise boundary control</li>
</ul></li>
<li>victim NAT sees proper SIP REGISTER packet on SIP port (with no HTTP data), triggering ALG to open any TCP/UDP port defined in packet back to victim
<ul>
<li>victim NAT rewrites SIP packet, replacing internal IP with public IP, hinting to attacker exploit was successful</li>
<li>even if victim NAT normally rewrites source ports, the ALG will still be forced to port forward to the attacker's port of choice as it believes victim machine opened that port and attacker sees new source port in arriving SIP packet </li>
<li><b>attacker can now bypass victim NAT and connect directly back to any port on victim's machine, exposing previously protected/hidden services</b></li>
</ul></li>
<li><i>to investigate...perhaps by you?</i>
<ul>
  <li>non-malicious usage: this technique essentially gives browsers full TCP and UDP socket capability to communicate to any protocol locally on the system; the connection can be abstracted through a cloud server that connects back but the browser just talks to the cloud server as if it's the socket and makes browsers much more powerful to communicate on non-web-friendly protocols</li>
  <li>if testing in a virtual machine (VM) using shared networking (used to protect a host from attacks by routing it through the host, not letting it directly onto the network), if the packets make it out, the parent host machine is where the ports end up getting opened, not the VM ;)</li>
  <li>IP fragmentation allows full control of all data in the IP data section, meaning full control of the <b>UDP header</b>, including source/dest ports in the overflowed packet...what else could this abuse?</li>
</ul></li>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/samyk/slipstream/main/img/pinpkt2.png"><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/samyk/slipstream/main/img/pinpkt2.png" alt="successful packet broken into valid SIP packet"></a></p>



<h2 id="network-address-translation-nat">Network Address Translation (NAT)</h2>

<p>We use NATs (Network Address Translation) for several reasons. The most useful feature of NAT is that it allows a single public IP address to be shared among multiple systems. It does this by creating a local network, providing local IP addresses to all machines that connect, and when one of those systems reaches out to the Internet, it rewrites packets going out to use the public IP so responses come back to the NAT, and vice versa, rewriting desination IP to specific client's IP. </p>

<p>It's the responsibility of the NAT to differentiate connections to the same addresses/ports (google.com:443) from internal hosts as ultimately their outbound port, destination ip and source ip will all be the same. If two different internal peers attempt to connect from the same source port, modern NATs will alter one of the source ports (some networks do this to all TCP/UDP source ports).</p>

<p><img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/samyk/slipstream/main/img/lan.png" alt="NAT"></p>

<h3 id="connection-tracking">Connection Tracking</h3>

<p>From <a target="_blank" href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Netfilter">Wikipedia ala Wikiwand</a>:</p>

<div><pre><code>One of the important features built on top of the Netfilter 
framework is connection tracking. Connection tracking 
allows the kernel to keep track of all logical network 
connections or sessions, and thereby relate all of the packets
which may make up that connection. NAT relies on this 
information to translate all related packets in the same way, 
and iptables can use this information to act as a stateful 
firewall.</code></pre></div>

<p>If a machine behind your NAT sends a packet out and your router expects the remote host may respond, it keeps track of information, specifically the source and destination ports, source and destination IP addresses, and your internal IP, then returns any packets matching it back to your internal IP.</p>

<p>If another host on your LAN attempts to make the same connection with the same source and destination ports + IPs, your NAT wouldn't be able to discriminate it (the source IPs are different on your LAN but are rewritten to the same public IP on the WAN side), so it alters the source port, but rewrites it when sending back to you.</p>

<h3 id="application-level-gateway">Application Level Gateway</h3>

<p>ALGs allow NAT to track a multi-port protocol like FTP to go out from your system to an FTP server, then track when you request a file to be sent to your internal IP on a specific port, the ALG can rewrite the packet to include your public IP, then forward the FTP's server connection back to you. Had it not rewritten your IP, the FTP server would try to connect back to you on your internal IP (or not try at all if it expects the source IP to be the same as the signaling connection).</p>

<p>From <a target="_blank" href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Application-level_gateway">Wikipedia</a>:</p>

<div><pre><code>In the context of computer networking, an application-level 
gateway consists of a security component that augments a 
firewall or NAT employed in a computer network. It allows 
customized NAT traversal filters to be plugged into the 
gateway to support address and port translation for certain 
application layer "control/data" protocols such as FTP, 
BitTorrent, SIP, RTSP, file transfer in IM applications, etc. 
In order for these protocols to work through NAT or a 
firewall, either the application has to know about an address/
port number combination that allows incoming packets, or the 
NAT has to monitor the control traffic and open up port 
mappings (firewall pinhole) dynamically as required. 
Legitimate application data can thus be passed through the 
security checks of the firewall or NAT that would have 
otherwise restricted the traffic for not meeting its limited 
filter criteria.</code></pre></div>

<h2 id="router-investigation--firmware-dumping">Router Investigation / Firmware Dumping</h2>

<p>I'd first like to see how common gateways actually treat packets and multi-port protocols like FTP, SIP, etc. To do this, we’ll want to reverse engineer the firmware from common routers. We could dump the flash from physical routers, however if we can get unencrypted firmware from the manufacturers, we’ll be able to investigate more router models and much faster.</p>

<p>We'll start with a common router, the Netgear Nighthawk R7000. A <a target="_blank" href="http://bfy.tw/NjZh">quick search</a> helps us …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://samy.pl/slipstream/">https://samy.pl/slipstream/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://samy.pl/slipstream/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24955891</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 22:57:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Homicide victim found in burnt-out SUV ID'd as man behind spam-email empire]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 150 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24955454">thread link</a>) | @goodcanadian
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/davis-wolfgang-hawke-missing-dead-1.5782107 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/davis-wolfgang-hawke-missing-dead-1.5782107">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>More than three years after his death, a man who was shot dead and found in a burnt-out SUV near Squamish, B.C., has been identified as a U.S. citizen known for spreading racist, neo-Nazi ideologies&nbsp;and for a massive spam email campaign that led to a $12.8-million US lawsuit.</p><div><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="" sizes="" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782212.1604017727!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpeg_gen/derivatives/16x9_780/davis-wolfgang-hawke.jpeg"></p></div><figcaption>Davis Wolfgang Hawke was found dead in a burnt-out SUV in Squamish, B.C., on June 14, 2017. Police said his death was a homicide.<!-- --> <!-- -->(IHIT)</figcaption></figure><p><span><p>More than three years after his death, a man who was shot dead and found in a burnt-out SUV near Squamish, B.C., has been identified as a U.S. citizen known for spreading racist, neo-Nazi ideologies&nbsp;and for a massive spam email campaign that led to a $12.8-million US lawsuit.</p>  <p>Police found Davis Wolfgang Hawke dead on the Cheekye Forest Road, off the Sea to Sky Highway east of&nbsp;Paradise Valley, around 9:30 a.m. on June 14, 2017. Officers had been called about a burnt,&nbsp;red&nbsp;2000&nbsp;GMC&nbsp;Yukon XL on the side of the road.</p>  <p>An autopsy later confirmed the man had been shot dead,&nbsp;but&nbsp;for years&nbsp;the RCMP could not confirm his real name.</p>  <p>The Integrated Homicide Investigation Team (IHIT) only knew he&nbsp;went by the alias&nbsp;Jesse James, and that he was well known as an&nbsp;avid climber&nbsp;in Squamish, which is around 50 kilometres north of Vancouver.</p>  <p>But with IHIT's confirmation of his identity on Thursday, details about Hawke's past —&nbsp;including his fascist sympathies and a lucrative&nbsp;spam empire he built hawking loans, pornography, jewelry and prescription drugs — have come to light thanks to the work of an investigative journalist.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782321.1604000520!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/britt-greenbaum.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782321.1604000520!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/britt-greenbaum.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782321.1604000520!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/britt-greenbaum.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782321.1604000520!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/britt-greenbaum.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782321.1604000520!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/britt-greenbaum.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782321.1604000520!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/britt-greenbaum.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Andrew Britt Greenbaum (aka Davis Hawke) at his grandparents' home in the U.S. in this undated picture. In posts online, his late mother said her son had been missing for years and that this was a cherished photo of her lost boy.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Facebook)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Brian McWilliams, author of the book <em>Spam Kings</em>, spent years tracking the young man, who&nbsp;he says lived a nomadic, risk-taking existence. He often travelled with half-wolf dogs, which were the only thing he appeared to be loyal to, according to McWilliams.</p>  <p>"It doesn't surprise me that this guy died in an inglorious and maybe a violent way. He was always living on the edge," McWilliams said.</p>    <p>McWilliams said Hawke,&nbsp;born Andrew Britt Greenbaum, changed his name many times and was&nbsp;evasive when the journalist was chasing him for a story on his junk-email&nbsp;empire.</p>  <p>He said Hawke and his associates bragged about making up to $300,000 in a year in the spam business, after dropping out of college.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782537.1604017307!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/andrew-britt-greenbaum.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782537.1604017307!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/andrew-britt-greenbaum.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782537.1604017307!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/andrew-britt-greenbaum.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782537.1604017307!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/andrew-britt-greenbaum.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782537.1604017307!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/andrew-britt-greenbaum.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782537.1604017307!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/andrew-britt-greenbaum.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>Greenbaum, who would later change his name to Hawke, grew up in a suburb of Boston and excelled at chess, before he branched into online spamming and vanished.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Facebook)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>While IHIT&nbsp;said they had little information on Hawke, other than he was 38 when he died and was originally from the U.S.,&nbsp;McWilliams&nbsp;has gathered a lot of information about the "puzzling" young man who grew up in an affluent Boston suburb and was a chess prodigy.</p>  <p>McWilliams, who interviewed Hawke and his family, learned how he was bullied as a child&nbsp;for being small and Jewish —&nbsp;before he rejected&nbsp;his Jewish background,&nbsp;changed&nbsp;his name to Hawke&nbsp;and soon after became known to anti-racism groups as a neo-Nazi.</p>  <p>"At some point, he just became infatuated with this white supremacy notion," said McWilliams.</p>  <p>"He brought that mentality of everybody being inferior to him into the rest of his life," he said.</p>  <p>He organized a failed anti-government march in Washington, D.C., in 1999, and was written about in the New York Times and Rolling Stone magazine.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782374.1604017399!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/davis-wolfgang-hawke-forest-road.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782374.1604017399!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/davis-wolfgang-hawke-forest-road.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782374.1604017399!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/davis-wolfgang-hawke-forest-road.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782374.1604017399!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/davis-wolfgang-hawke-forest-road.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782374.1604017399!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/davis-wolfgang-hawke-forest-road.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782374.1604017399!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/davis-wolfgang-hawke-forest-road.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>The entrance to the Cheekye Forest Road as seen from the Sea to Sky Highway in Squamish, B.C. Hawke was found dead inside a burnt-out SUV along the road on June 14, 2017.<!-- --> <!-- -->(Google Street View)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>Later he used his writing talents to trick people into sending him cash, and his spam email venture took off,&nbsp;according to court documents.</p>  <p>"He was a con man. He felt that he could convince anybody to buy herbal Viagra, just writing some clever email text. This guy was super intelligent and thought there was a sucker born every minute — and he was real good at finding them," said McWilliams.</p>    <p>In 2005, internet company AOL won a $12.8-million US judgment in federal court in Virginia against Hawke, who was accused of breaking federal law by sending massive amounts of unwanted spam emails to its customers. Hawke never showed for the trial.</p>  <p>Investigators believed he and his partners earned more than $600,000 on the spam sales pitches.</p>  <p>AOL also won a court order to dig up two properties owned by Hawke's relatives&nbsp;in Massachusetts to recoup costs, because&nbsp;Hawke had&nbsp;once bragged he buried gold and platinum in the yards, according to U.S. district court documents.</p>  <p>The company&nbsp;ultimately decided&nbsp;not to search the properties, which belonged to Hawke's grandmother and parents.</p>  <p>The family said no money was ever there.</p>    <p>A warrant for Hawke's arrest remained active.</p>  <p>Lawyers who worked on the case for AOL told CBC&nbsp;News on Thursday they hunted Hawke for years, and learned he'd escaped the&nbsp;U.S. by sneaking on board fishing trawlers, spending time in Belize.</p>  <p>After warrants for his arrest expired, the search wound down.&nbsp;But Hawke kept living like a fugitive and never returned home, according to his family.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.4172626.1498106495!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/ihit-truck-stock.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.4172626.1498106495!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/ihit-truck-stock.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.4172626.1498106495!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/ihit-truck-stock.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.4172626.1498106495!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ihit-truck-stock.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.4172626.1498106495!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/ihit-truck-stock.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.4172626.1498106495!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/ihit-truck-stock.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>A stock photo of a 2000 red GMC Yukon XL, the same type of vehicle where the body of Hawke was found.<!-- --> <!-- -->(IHIT)</figcaption></figure></span></p>  <p>McWilliams said he always wondered if Hawke would settle down one day and "sell insurance," but said, "It sounds like he stayed kind of a wild man."</p>  <p>Hawke's uncle Raleigh Davis said his nephew's death was communicated to the family last week. He said nobody had seen Hawke in 20 years, and confirmation of his death at least offered some closure.</p>  <p>"He was really smart and really&nbsp;clever and really confident in a lot of ways.&nbsp;I think he had a really insecure side, though," said Davis.</p>  <p>"It's just sad."</p>  <p>Anyone with more information about Hawke's death is asked to phone IHIT&nbsp;at 1-877-551-4448&nbsp;or email ihitinfo@rcmp-grc.gc.ca&nbsp;or call Crime Stoppers at 1-800-222-8477&nbsp;if they want to remain anonymous.</p>  <p><span><figure><div><p><img loading="lazy" alt="" srcset="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782109.1604017467!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_300/davis-wolfgang-hawke.jpg 300w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782109.1604017467!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_460/davis-wolfgang-hawke.jpg 460w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782109.1604017467!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_620/davis-wolfgang-hawke.jpg 620w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782109.1604017467!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/davis-wolfgang-hawke.jpg 780w,https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782109.1604017467!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_1180/davis-wolfgang-hawke.jpg 1180w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 300px,(max-width: 460px) 460px,(max-width: 620px) 620px,(max-width: 780px) 780px,(max-width: 1180px) 1180px" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5782109.1604017467!/fileImage/httpImage/image.jpg_gen/derivatives/original_780/davis-wolfgang-hawke.jpg"></p></div><figcaption>IHIT Sgt. Frank Jang holds a photo of Hawke.<!-- --> <!-- -->(CBC)</figcaption></figure></span></p></span></p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/davis-wolfgang-hawke-missing-dead-1.5782107</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24955454</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 21:47:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why Dark Mode Matters]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 27 | Comments 57 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24951606">thread link</a>) | @desoga
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://thecodeangle.com/5-reasons-why-dark-mode-matters/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thecodeangle.com/5-reasons-why-dark-mode-matters/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-1527" itemtype="https://schema.org/CreativeWork" itemscope="itemscope">

	
	
<div>

	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	
	<div itemprop="text">

		
		<blockquote><p><em>When it is dark enough, you can see the stars.</em><br>
<em>―&nbsp;</em></p></blockquote>
<h2>Table of Contents</h2>
<ul>
<li><em><strong><a href="#introduction">Introduction</a></strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong><a href="#reasons-for-dark-mode">Reasons for Dark Mode</a></strong></em>
<ul>
<li><em><strong><a href="#visual-attraction">Visual Attraction</a></strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong><a href="#user-experience">User Experience</a></strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong><a href="#eye-strain">Eye Strain &amp;&nbsp;</a></strong></em><em><strong>Blue Light Removal</strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong><a href="#reduction-of-photophobia">Reduction of Photophobia</a></strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong><a href="#battery-saver">Battery Saver</a></strong></em></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><em><strong><a href="#factors-to-consider">Factors to Consider When Selecting Dark Mode</a></strong></em></li>
<li><em><strong><a href="#conclusion">Conclusion</a></strong></em></li>
</ul>

<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>According to an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Screen_time#Statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">American survey,</a> children&nbsp;between the ages of 8-12 and 13-18 spend a daily average of 4 hours, 44 minutes and 7 hours, 22 minutes respectively, staring at screens.</p>
<p>The data for these numbers were collected in 2019. For adults, this figure is higher and according to an article on the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/03/24/screen-time-iphone-coronavirus-quarantine-covid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Washington Post </a>earlier this year, the amount of screen time increased considerably during the quarantine period due to <strong>COVID-19</strong></p>
<p>Today, mobile devices take a large percentage of the amount of time people spend staring at screens, this is why there is a need for applications to have a <strong>Dark Mode</strong> option for its users.</p>
<p><strong>Dark Mode</strong> according to <strong>Wikipedia,</strong><em> is a color scheme that uses light-coloured text, icons, and graphical user interface elements on a dark background and is often discussed in terms of computer user interface design and web design.</em></p>
<p>Now, let us look at the 5 reasons why <strong>Dark Mode</strong> really matters for the end-users of an application!<br>
<a name="reasons-for-dark-mode"></a></p>
<h2>Reasons For Dark Mode</h2>
<p><img src="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/visual_apeal-300x200.jpg" alt="visual appeal" width="1055" height="703" srcset="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/visual_apeal-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/visual_apeal-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/visual_apeal-768x512.jpg 768w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/visual_apeal-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/visual_apeal.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1055px) 100vw, 1055px"><br>
<a name="visual-attraction"></a></p>
<h3>1). Visual Attraction</h3>
<p><strong>Dark Mode</strong> when applied in the right manner always looks really appealing to the eye. It provides the opportunity to present a unique user interface to the end-users of an application.</p>
<p>Also, in terms of data presentation for graphical contents like dashboards that contain graphs and charts, <strong>Dark Mode</strong> brings out the elegance in the design as shown below.</p>
<p><img src="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/darkmode-300x156.png" alt="Dark Mode" width="1106" height="575" srcset="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/darkmode-300x156.png 300w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/darkmode-1024x531.png 1024w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/darkmode-768x398.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1106px) 100vw, 1106px"></p>
<p>Unlike the drab white look that most applications have, the above image shows how <strong>Dark Mode</strong> can bring a significantly deeper and more attractive visual perception to an application.<br>
<a name="user-experience"></a></p>
<h3>2). User Experience</h3>
<p>Providing the users of a product with the option of a <strong>Dark Mode</strong> is a good business decision, especially if the application requires users to spend lots of time on the application. A streaming site, for example, implementing a dark mode feature is a good business decision.</p>
<p>Streaming a video in <strong>light-mode</strong> under a dark environment or at night may not be a good experience for the eyes. Hence, applications that require people spending lots of screen time should provide an option for <strong>Dark Mode</strong> for a better user experience.</p>
<p>Above all, it is worthy to note that context is a key factor in making decisions on whether to implement the option of a <strong>Dark Mode</strong>.<br>
<a name="eye-strain"></a></p>
<h3>3). Eye Strain &amp; Blue Light Removal</h3>
<p>By default, <strong>Dark Mode</strong> helps to reduce overall screen brightness. Although no study has outrightly confirmed that <strong>Dark Mode</strong> reduces eye strain, it can, however, be effective in low-light conditions.</p>
<p>Also, <strong>Dark Mode</strong> helps to reduce exposure to <strong>Blue Light.</strong>&nbsp;Blue light is a high-frequency colour in the “visible light spectrum” that can be seen by the human eye.</p>
<p><img src="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blue-light-300x200.jpg" alt="blue-light" width="990" height="660" srcset="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blue-light-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blue-light-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blue-light-768x512.jpg 768w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blue-light-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blue-light.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 990px) 100vw, 990px"></p>
<p><strong>Blue Light&nbsp;</strong>can be found almost everywhere, from smartphones to computers and other digital devices. Another source of Blue Light is the sun, so by stepping out of your house, you are exposed to a certain degree of blue light.</p>
<p>Too many exposures to Blue Light can lead to digital eye strain.</p>
<p>Since not everyone can see well with <strong>Dark Mode</strong>, some mobile devices provide the option for Blue Light filters. This can be found in the display settings area and can be easily adjusted to the level of blue light exposure you want.<br>
<a name="reduction-of-photophobia"></a></p>
<h3>4). Reduction of Photophobia</h3>
<p>Photophobia is a symptom of abnormal intolerance to the visual perception of light. The source of this light could be any form of light source including sunlight.</p>
<p>There are so many things that can cause photophobia, some of which includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Excessive light entering the eyes</li>
<li>Eye infection</li>
<li>Medications</li>
<li>Meningitis</li>
<li>Lack of eye pigment (Albinism)</li>
<li>Wearing contact lenses for an extended period of time, or wearing it wrongly.</li>
<li>Post Eye Surgery</li>
</ul>
<p>Photophobia usually disappears once the underlying cause is treated. A good way to deal with photophobia is making use of the <strong>Dark Mode </strong>of a mobile device or an application. This helps to reduce the amount of bright light that goes directly into the eyes.</p>
<p>An extension you may consider installing on your desktop browser is &nbsp;<a href="https://nighteye.app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Night Eye</a>. It is supported by almost all major web browsers. It helps you enable <strong>Dark Mode </strong>and other features across almost all the websites you view, to help cope with the light sensitivity.</p>
<p>However, if light sensitivity persists, you may want to see your doctor!<br>
<a name="battery-saver"></a></p>
<h3>5). Battery Saver</h3>
<p>Another positive impact of <strong>Dark Mode</strong> is the impact it has on the battery life of mobile devices. <strong>Dark Mode </strong>can significantly help reduce the battery drain on devices which use OLED(Organic Light-Emitting Diode) screens.</p>
<p><img src="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/battery-saver-205x300.jpg" alt="battery-saver" width="952" height="1393" srcset="https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/battery-saver-205x300.jpg 205w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/battery-saver-699x1024.jpg 699w, https://thecodeangle.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/battery-saver-768x1125.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 952px) 100vw, 952px"></p>
<p>Numerous studies have confirmed the fact that <strong>Dark Mode</strong> saves battery life. In an<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UljafaxRcEE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Android Dev Summit</a> in November of 2018, Google also confirmed that themes on android devices have a significant impact on the battery life of a mobile device.</p>
<p>If you are using an Android device, you should consider using <strong>Dark Mode</strong>, especially at night. Not only is it easy on the eyes, but it also helps save your battery life.<br>
<a name="factors-to-consider"></a></p>
<h3>Factors To Consider When Selecting Dark Mode</h3>
<p>In as much as <strong>Dark Mode</strong> seems trendy, it is necessary to consider some factors before deciding to implement it in an application. Some of these factors are discussed below:</p>
<p><strong>Readability and Visibility:&nbsp;</strong>Readability simply means the ease at which a reader can easily understand or perceive a written text. Applications that contain lots of text in their interface will have to be careful about how <strong>Dark Mode</strong> is implemented.</p>
<p>If the <strong>Dark Mode</strong> is not well implemented, this will lead to a poor user experience with the users struggling to read the texts. This defeats one of the purposes for which <strong>Dark Mode</strong> is created and could lead to eye strain.</p>
<p>Lots of research must go into how the backgrounds, text colour and font will work together.</p>
<p><strong>Test Before Implementation:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>Testing helps to discover the strength and weakness of the Color scheme used in an application. <strong>Dark Mode</strong> does not work well for all applications. A website that contains lots of elements(text, images, tables) may make it difficult for <strong>Dark Mode</strong> to be implemented.</p>
<p>Other factors to consider include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Determination of the target audience</li>
<li>Providing an option to switch between Light Mode and Dark Mode</li>
<li>The Environment</li>
<li>Accessibility</li>
</ul>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>The decision to always use <strong>Dark Mode </strong>should always be a relative one. For users of an application, knowing when to use light mode and <strong>Dark Mode </strong>at different times of the day is very essential for the eye.</p>

		
		
			</div><!-- .entry-content .clear -->
</div>

	
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thecodeangle.com/5-reasons-why-dark-mode-matters/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24951606</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 14:10:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[FreeCAD BIM development news]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24951311">thread link</a>) | @buovjaga
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://yorik.uncreated.net/blog/2020-011-freecad-september | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://yorik.uncreated.net/blog/2020-011-freecad-september">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="wrapper">

        
    

    <div id="main">

         
        

        <div>
            
            
            <p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-01.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Hi all,</p>
<p>After a very, very long delay, here comes finally another development report about the <a href="https://github.com/yorikvanhavre/BIM_Workbench">BIM tools</a> for <a href="https://www.freecadweb.org/">FreeCAD</a>. Awfully sorry about the black-out during these last months, lots of things <a href="https://www.rtbf.be/info/regions/liege/detail_circuit-de-spa-francorchamps-80-millions-d-investissements-et-le-retour-de-la-moto?id=10604892">happened</a> (all the 3D&amp;BIM done with FreeCAD and Blender) and  of course the pandemic didn't ease things either. Anyway, that doesn't mean nothing happened on the FreeCAD front, on the contrary, bugs still get addressed, things get fin-tuned, ideas get discussed, and FreeCAD gets everyday better.</p>
<p>This last month we also had a hectic turnover, because Autodesk changed the terms of the free version of  their <a href="https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/overview">Fusion360</a>. There is a full load of new limitations that restrain much the use for personal/hobby users. For example, the g-code you export from Fusion360 to CNC machines (that cut objects out of a block of material), is now making the machine running slower (and therefore raising the production costs), for no apparent reason other than nagging the users into buying a subscription. As a result, we saw a massive migration of users to FreeCAD, and it's really thrilling to see people discovering FreeCAD and learning it and liking it.</p>
<p>Thanks once more to everybody who contributes to my <a href="https://www.patreon.com/yorikvanhavre">Patreon</a> or <a href="https://liberapay.com/yorik/">Liberapay</a> campaigns, I'm really grateful you guys didn't just drop me away when I fail to write for 3 months.</p>
<p>Also, for who didn't notice, FreeCAD now has a proper <a href="https://liberapay.com/FreeCAD/">Liberapay teams account</a> where all money received is divided equally between the FreeCAD developers registered there (currently 7). This account has seen a huge raise of donations these last weeks (it receives around 1000 USD/month at the moment), thanks to the flow of new ex-Fusion360 users, and the impressive job Kunda1 is doing on <a href="https://twitter.com/FreeCADNews">the official FreeCAD twitter account</a> (subscribe to it if you are a twitter user, that account used to be just a mirror of the FreeCAD Facebook page, but is now very, very well maintained) and the campaigning of other people (special thanks to my <a href="https://www.twitter.com/beatnikqueen">girlfriend</a>, the most awesome person in the world).</p>
<p>So, no more loitering, to the news! Here is what we got this month:</p>
<h3>Customizable section color</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-02.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p><a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Arch_SetMaterial">Materials</a> now have a new <strong>Section Color</strong> property, which allows to give a different color when the material is viewed and when it is cut through. So for example you can now have your walls appear white when viewed, but black when cut and seen on a TechDraw page.</p>
<p>This is a small improvement so far, but it laid the structure to have more advanced things, such as supporting hatch patterns. The main problem for this, is that, although the SVG format has an excellent support for hatch patterns (anything can become a hatch pattern, even bitmap images), the Qt implementation of the SVG format lacks support for it (it has its own <a href="https://doc.qt.io/Qt-5/qbrush.html#details">system</a> but it's not very practical to make that compatible with SVG). Therefore at the moment we have no clear idea of how to go further.</p>
<p><a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/TechDraw_Module">TechDraw</a>'s implementation of hatch patterns internally recreates OpenCasCade geometry, which works very well but might be heavy for large BIM models. In any case, that's a track I'm <a href="https://github.com/yorikvanhavre/FreeCAD/tree/td-makedrawgeomhatch">exploring</a> too.</p>
<h3>Default windows are now openable</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-03.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Another very small fix, but the default door and windows created with the <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Arch_Window">Door and windows tools</a> now have a hinge edge defined, so their <strong>Opening</strong> property now works out-of-the-box. It might not open in the direction you want, though, so you might still need to tweak this. But next items on my list are adding a couple of controls to easily switch opening directions.</p>
<h3>Default pattern size option</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-04.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>The Draft patterns system is now working again (hatch patterns can be added to all closed Draft objects such as rectangles, polylines, circles, etc). I also added a preferences option under <em>Edit -&gt; Preferences -&gt; Draft -&gt; Visual settings</em> to set a default hatch pattern scale, which is useful when you always work with objects of a similar size range, for example building plans. I still have to experiment a bit (0.0025 seems like a very good default setting for BIM), but will add that to the BIM setup screen once I found a couple of good settings.</p>
<h3>Section plane label</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-05.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p><a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Arch_SectionPlane">Section planes</a> now have a <strong>Show Label</strong> property, which, when turned on, show the section plane label on the plane in the 3D view. This is useful to easily identify these section planes when there are many in your document. The text size currently depends on the arrow size, but I'll make all this better customizable later on.</p>
<p>We have further plans too for the section planes, such as be able to double-click or activate them somehow, and find yourself in a separate 2D view with all needed geometry cut or turned off, where you can still work on the model in a 2D environment. This would be a bit like an intermediary step between the full 3D model and a TechDraw view. You can see a first draft of that coded by Carlo Pavan on the experimental tools palette in the BIM workbench.</p>
<h3>TechDraw tools in BIM workbench</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-06.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Among the annotation tools on the BIM workbench, you'll now find two TechDraw tools, <strong>Create page</strong> and <strong>Create view</strong>. The first one is the same of the <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/TechDraw_PageTemplate">Create page from template</a> TechDraw tool, except that it remembers the last template you used and gets you right there when you use the tool again, so it gives a little bit faster workflow. The second tool is currently the same as the <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/TechDraw_ArchView">TechDraw ArchView tool</a> but I plan to make it a bit more flexible in the future so it would become a mix of TechDraw's ArchView and DraftView tools, depending on the selected objects.</p>
<h3>TSV export</h3>
<p>The <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Arch_Schedule">Schedule</a> tool has been extended to now allow to export results to the .tsv (Tab-Separated Values) format, which is basically the same as the .csv (Comma-Separated Values) format, but using tab characters to separate columns, instead of commas. The big problem of csv, of course, is if there are commas in the columns texts. Usually spreadsheet apps are pretty tolerant with .csv files, they will usually ask you what character to consider as column separator on import, but others (for example GitHub) doesn't display them correctly if they don't use a comma as separator. So from now on there is a correct way to please everybody <i></i></p>
<h3>Blender exporter upgrade</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-07.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>The <a href="https://gist.github.com/yorikvanhavre/029f6fcce9f4d0e62fb6163804b7f80d">FreeCAD exporter for Blender</a> has seen several small fixes, it now automatically adds the .FCStd extension to the generated file if you haven't added it yourself, it now correctly handles object rotation and scaling, and it applies modifiers before exporting. It now also supports faceless objects (wireframe objects).</p>
<p>This coupled with the <a href="https://blenderbim.org/">BlenderBIM</a> improvements, it now becomes increasingly easy to work on BIM models in Blender, or parts of BIM models, and when needed, integrate everything seamlessly in FreeCAD. There are many more joint FreeCAD/Blender developments going on, such as the new <a href="https://forum.freecadweb.org/viewtopic.php?style=4&amp;t=51069&amp;p=438881">Sverchok nodes</a> that use FreeCAD internally, literally creating a kind of new interface for FreeCAD withing Blender.</p>
<h3>Detect and suggest development version</h3>
<p>The BIM workbench will now detect your FreeCAD version on the setup screen, and suggest you to install a development version if you are not using one. This will help people to be aware of the existence of development versions, and become more used to them and how to install and mange them.</p>
<h3>Grid extension setting in Working Plane panel</h3>
<p>The overall size of the grid is now settable directly from the <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Draft_SelectPlane">Working Plane</a> task panel.</p>
<h3>Multiple custom folders on start page</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-08.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>The <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Start_Workbench">start page</a> can now show multiple custom folders. To achieve that, go to the start page preferences under menu <em>Edit -&gt; Preferences -&gt; Start</em> and instead of choosing one custom folder, type manually several folder paths, separated by ;;</p>
<p>For example: <code>/home/yorik;;/home/yorik/Examples;;/home/yorik/FreeCAD/Examples</code></p>
<h3>Image Plane scaling</h3>
<p><img src="https://yorik.uncreated.net/images/2020/freecad-09-09.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>The <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Draft_Scale">Draft Scale</a> tool now support image planes created with the <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Image_Module">Image workbench</a>. So it is now easy to import reference images such as scanned floor plans, position them on a common reference point, and scale them to the desired size.</p>
<h3>Unit and Show Unit in Draft dimension preferences</h3>
<p>You can now set default value for these two settings under <em>Edit -&gt; Preferences -&gt; Draft -&gt; Dimensions and Texts</em>, that will affect all newly created dimensions.</p>
<h3>Manual upgrade</h3>
<p>And last but not least, I started upgrading the <a href="https://wiki.freecadweb.org/Manual">manual</a> to FreeCAD 0.19, and this time I intend well to produce a printed book with it. To be continued!</p>
<p>That's it for this month I guess, I promise to do everything I can to resume posting once per month!</p>
<p>Cheers</p>
<p>Yorik</p>
            
        </div>

                
            </div>


        
    
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://yorik.uncreated.net/blog/2020-011-freecad-september</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24951311</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 13:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Spectre Is Haunting Unicode]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 262 | Comments 113 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24951130">thread link</a>) | @polm23
<br/>
October 31, 2020 | https://www.dampfkraft.com/ghost-characters.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.dampfkraft.com/ghost-characters.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>In 1978 Japan's <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%B5%8C%E6%B8%88%E7%94%A3%E6%A5%AD%E7%9C%81">Ministry of Economy, Trade and
Industry</a>
established the encoding that would later be known as JIS X 0208, which still
serves as an important reference for all Japanese encodings. However, after the
JIS standard was released people noticed something strange - several of the
added characters had no obvious sources, and nobody could tell what they meant
or how they should be pronounced. Nobody was sure where they came from. These
are what came to be known as the ghost characters
(<a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%B9%BD%E9%9C%8A%E6%96%87%E5%AD%97">幽霊文字</a>).</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/a824aa10/ghostcanvas.jpg"><img src="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/a824aa10/img/ghostcanvas.jpg.l.jpg"></a><figcaption>Be careful what you write. <a href="http://dl.ndl.go.jp/info:ndljp/pid/1312837">via the NDL</a>
</figcaption></figure>
<p>For a long time the ghost characters remained an unexplained and mostly
forgotten curiosity, but in 1997 an investigation was launched to discover
where they had come from.  While all characters in the JIS standard were
supposed to have a record of their sources, even when it existed it
wasn't very specific, typically just listing the document it was sourced from.</p>
<p>You'd think that listing the source would make tracking down the origins of the
characters easy, but it's important to clarify what counts as a "source" - one
of the more common sources for the ghost characters was the "Overview of
National Administrative Districts" (国土行政区画総覧), a comprehensive list of
place names in Japan. You might, as I initially did, imagine this to be a kind
of atlas, an oversize book with at most a few hundred pages. It turns out the
<a href="http://kokudo.or.jp/books/index.html">latest edition</a> is a seven volume set
with each volume having roughly nine hundred pages. Imagine tracking down a
single character without a page reference.</p>
<p>Despite the difficulty, the investigation into the ghost characters was
successful in discovering their origins - mostly. By interviewing the
catalogers involved in the creation of the standard, the investigators
established that some characters were inadvertently invented as mistakes in the
cataloging process. For example, 妛 was an error introduced while trying to
record "山 over 女". "山 over 女" occurs in the name of a particular place and
was thus suitable for inclusion in the JIS standard, but because they couldn't
print it as one character yet, 山 and 女 were printed separately, cut out, and
pasted onto a sheet of paper, and then copied. When reading the copy, the line
where the two little pieces of paper met looked like a stroke and was added to
the character by mistake. The original character
(<a href="https://ja.wiktionary.org/wiki/%F0%A1%9A%B4">𡚴</a>) was not added to JIS or
Unicode until much later and doesn't display on most sites for me.</p>
<figure><a href="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/a824aa10/yuureimoji.png"><img src="https://www.dampfkraft.com/by-id/a824aa10/img/yuureimoji.png.l.png"></a><figcaption>The core ghost characters: 妛挧暃椦槞蟐袮閠駲墸壥彁
</figcaption></figure>
<p>In the end only one character had neither a clear source nor any historical
precedent: 彁. The most likely explanation is that it was created as a
misreading of the 彊 character, but no specific incident was uncovered.</p>
<p>Following the general adoption of the JIS standards these characters all made
their way into Unicode, which has its own <a href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/CJK%E7%B5%B1%E5%90%88%E6%BC%A2%E5%AD%97#%E5%B9%BD%E9%9C%8A%E6%BC%A2%E5%AD%97">separate set of ghost
characters</a>
introduced during CJK unification.</p>
<p>To sum up - in 1978 a series of small mistakes created some characters out of
nothing. The errors went undiscovered just long enough to be set in stone, and
now these ghosts are, at least in potential, a part of every computer on the
planet, lurking in the dark corners of character tables.</p>
<p>At this rate they'll presumably be with humanity forever. Ψ</p>
<p>References / related links:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.wdic.org/w/WDIC/%E5%B9%BD%E9%9C%8A%E6%96%87%E5%AD%97">幽霊文字 ‐ 通信用語の基礎知識</a> - the most thorough online source, with citations from the 1997 investigation.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.asahi.com/special/kotoba/archive2015/moji/2011082400019.html">大正十二年の幽霊文字 - ことばマガジン：朝日新聞デジタル</a> - an example of 彁 mistakenly used in a digitized Taisho newspaper due to a faded printing of 彊.</li>
<li><a href="http://dic.nicovideo.jp/a/%E5%B9%BD%E9%9C%8A%E6%96%87%E5%AD%97">Nico Nico Douga's Wiki</a> treats each of them as the name of a youkai.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.xubing.com/cn/work/details/206?year=1991&amp;type=year#206">天书</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Book_from_the_Sky">A Book from the Sky</a>, a hand-printed book by Xu Bing using only made-up Chinese characters.</li>
</ul>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.dampfkraft.com/ghost-characters.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24951130</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 13:07:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[LIL: Little Interpreted Language]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 54 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24949515">thread link</a>) | @marttt
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page">



<p><b>LIL</b> (stands for <b>L</b>ittle <b>I</b>nterpreted <b>L</b>anguage)
is a small highly dynamic scripting language inspired by Tcl and
unix shells. LIL has two implementations, one written in <b>C</b>,
which consists of a pair of <tt>.c</tt> and <tt>.h</tt> files
and one in <b><a href="http://freepascal.org/">Free Pascal</a></b>,
which consists of a single <tt>pas</tt> file (a unit). Also a
<a href="http://lazarus-ide.org/">Lazarus</a> package for the
latter is provided.</p>

<h2>Contents</h2>

<menu>
  <li><a href="#downloads">Downloads</a>
  <menu>
    <li><a href="#latestversion">Latest version</a>
    </li><li><a href="#olderversions">Older versions</a>
    </li><li><a href="#winlil">WinLIL</a>
    </li><li><a href="#lilgui">LILGUI</a>
  </li></menu>
  </li><li><a href="#stability">API stability and compatibility</a>
  </li><li><a href="#documentation">Documentation</a>
  </li><li><a href="#status">Status</a>
  </li><li><a href="#license">License</a>
</li></menu>

<h2><a name="downloads"></a>Downloads</h2>

<p>LIL is currently available as source code snapshots of both
the C and the Free Pascal version combined in a single ZIP file.
These snapshots are versioned using their release date. Note that
the interpreter's reflect version command will report <i>0.1</i>
regardless of date versioning. Both of these will change at some
point in the future to provide proper versioned releases.</p>

<h3><a name="latestversion"></a>Latest version</h3>

<p>The latest version of LIL is <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20190821.zip">lil20190821.zip</a>
(159KB). This is an extract from my private Fossil repository
(the files are mostly the same as the older archives, but this
also includes a full changelog from the repository going back
to 2010 and the LIL logo as an XCF image which can be opened with
GIMP).</p>

<p>Please note that <b>20190821</b> contains slightly altered
behavior for line breaking during list parsing that <i>could</i>
affect some scripts, especially with lists that contain code inside
square brackets, however the previous behavior was completely
broken (e.g. having multiple commands inside brackets in a list
would merge all commands into a single one and if a semicolon
was used for the multiple commands, the entire command wouldn't
be parsed properly). Because of that i expect any reliance on
the previous behavior to be accidental (and in practice i do not
really expect any such script to even exist). Also in the same
version a Bash script is introduced to check the differences between
different executables by running the same scripts under both and
comparing the results, which show that FPLIL contains a few incompatibilities
with C LIL. At this moment FPLIL doesn't implement the changes
mentioned so far - all these incompatibilities and changes will
be fixed in a later release.</p>

<h3><a name="olderversions"></a>Older versions</h3>

<p>Some older versions are also available in case you need them.
LIL should be mostly backwards compatible (see below), but right
now there is no promise for strict API or ABI compatibility.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20190819.zip">lil20190819.zip</a> (155KB)<a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20190818.zip"></a>
  </li><li><a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20190818.zip">lil20190818.zip</a> (154KB)
  </li><li><a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20190114.zip">lil20190114.zip</a> (91KB)
  </li><li><a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20161129.zip">lil20161129.zip</a> (88KB)
  </li><li><a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20160812.zip">lil20160812.zip</a> (88KB)
  </li><li><a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lil20160603.zip">lil20160603.zip</a> (88KB)
</li></ul>

<h3><a name="winlil"></a>WinLIL</h3>

<p>If you are using Windows you can also download <b>WinLIL</b>,
a small Windows-based environment with editor, console and extra
graphics functions that can be used to experiment with LIL. It
is self-contained in a single executable, including the LIL documentation.</p>

<p>The latest version is <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/winlil14.zip">WinLIL 1.4</a>
(204KB) based on <i>C LIL 20190821</i>. <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/winlil.png">Here
is a screenshot</a> of it in action. Also a small doodle program
can be <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/doodle.lil">downloaded here</a> and a <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/doodle.gif">screenshot
seen here</a>. <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/winlil20190821231511.zip">This archive</a>
(45KB) contains the source code, but note that it uses the original
Borland C++ Builder and to compile with a newer version (such
as the free Community Edition) you'll need to recreate the project
file and make a few modifications to the code.</p>

<p>Older versions of WinLIL can be found in these files: <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/winlil13.zip">winlil13.zip</a>
(1.3 binary), <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/winlil20190524200539.zip">winlil20190524200539.zip</a>
(1.3 source), <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/winlil20170425.zip">winlil20170424.zip</a>
(binary), <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/winlilsrc20161220.7z">winlilsrc20161220.7z</a>
(source).</p>

<h3><a name="lilgui"></a>LILGUI</h3>

<p><b>LILGUI</b> is an experimental API specification for GUI
applications that provide scripting functionality through LIL
to expose a simple GUI API. It is mainly intended for creating
embeddable GUIs (e.g. a panel in a sidebar) although it can also
be used for popup windows and dialogs. Currently the only implementation
for LILGUI is <b>LazLILGUI</b>, which is a component for Lazarus
that uses LCL to provide the actual GUI functionality.</p>

<p>The latest version of LILGUI files (which include the API spec,
LazLILGUI and a couple of examples) can be <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/lilgui20190708215135.zip">downloaded
here</a> (85KB). A 64bit windows binary for <b>LazLILGUI Notepad</b>,
a text editor that provides a sidebar to try out LILGUI code,
can be <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/llgnotepad20190708.zip">downloaded here</a> (1.3MB).
Also you can see the screenshots of program in action under <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/llgnotepadwin.png">Windows</a>, <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/llgnotepadlin.png">Linux</a>
and <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/llgnotepadosx.png">Mac OS X</a> and also the <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/llgcce.png">Custom Control Example</a> under Windows.</p>

<h2><a name="stability"></a>API stability and compatibility</h2>

<p>Generally speaking, both the C and Free Pascal implementation
APIs are stable <i>for the most part</i>. The <b>C API</b> was
broken only once in middle 2010 when <code>lil_command_t</code>
was renamed to <code>lil_func_t</code> and the <b>C ABI</b> for
the Windows DLL is also backwards compatible since late 2010.
The <b>Free Pascal</b> implementation has a less stable API but
as Free Pascal itself does not support ABI stability, this is
less of a concern.</p>

<p>In the foreseeable future the C API should be stable, but i'd
recommend <i>against</i> building a system-wide shared version
of the library before a proper versioned release is made. Once
a versioned release is made, both the API and ABI will remain
stable for as long as it is technically possible.</p>

<p>Script code should be backwards compatible even as new commands
are introduced since scripts and host applications will redefine
any conflicting functions anyway. The only time script code was
broken was in 2012 when the multiline comments were introduced
so any script that used a comment line like <code>#####</code>
was broken. This was addressed in a fix in 2014 that added a special
check for such cases so that multiline comments can only start
and end with two <code>#</code>s but not three or more (while
this could have broken any script that used three or more <code>#</code>s
to start and end multiline comments, the chances for such a script
are very slim).</p>

<p>Like with the C API, the script backwards compatibility currently
is mostly stable, but minor changes (like the multiline comment
changes mentioned above) might be made until a versioned release
is made or fixes to the script behavior to be closer to what is
described in the documentation or simply fix broken behavior.
At that point no changes will be made that may affect backwards
compatibility.</p>

<p>LILGUI and LazLILGUI are more experimental and may see backwards
incompatible changes in the future.</p>

<h2><a name="documentation"></a>Documentation</h2>

<p>Currently the only documentation is the (lengthy) <tt>readme.txt</tt>
file that <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/readme.txt">you can read here</a> or as part
of the archive containing the source code. At some point i'll
write better formatted documentation. Free Pascal has its own
API documentation <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/pasreadme.txt">readable here</a> and
also as a part of the archive containing the source code.</p>

<p>The LILGUI API can be <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/api.txt">found here</a> and
the documentation for LazLILGUI can be <a href="http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/llgreadme.txt">found
here</a>. Both are also part of the LILGUI archive.</p>

<p>Also <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/badsectoracula/lil-presentation">an
old LIL presentation can be found on SlideShare</a>. Please note
that the URLs in the presentation are not valid anymore.</p>

<h2><a name="status"></a>Status</h2>

<p>LIL is practically <i>feature-complete</i> and i do very little
development of it. I do not plan on making it a big and bloated
library that tries to provide everything - if anything, in the
future i might add some conditionals to remove bits of the library
for users who do not need, e.g, the string or list functions.</p>

<p>Further work is mostly "around" LIL and not on the
language itself: improving the documentation, writing a test suite
(currently there are several examples which i run after making
changes and almost half of them come from bug fixes, but i'd like
somethnig more automated), fixing some issues with the Free Pascal
implementation, adding more functions on the C API to access LIL's
state, etc.</p>

<h2><a name="license"></a>License</h2>

<p>Both the C and Free Pascal implementations as well as WinLIL
are licensed under the zlib license below:</p>

<blockquote>
  <pre>LIL - Little Interpreted Language
Copyright (C) 2010-2019 Kostas Michalopoulos

This software is provided 'as-is', without any express or implied
warranty.  In no event will the authors be held liable for any damages
arising from the use of this software.

Permission is granted to anyone to use this software for any purpose,
including commercial applications, and to alter it and redistribute it
freely, subject to the following restrictions:

1. The origin of this software must not be misrepresented; you must not
   claim that you wrote the original software. If you use this software
   in a product, an acknowledgment in the product documentation would be
   appreciated but is not required.
2. Altered source versions must be plainly marked as such, and must not be
   misrepresented as being the original software.
3. This notice may not be removed or altered from any source distribution.</pre>
</blockquote>



</div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://runtimeterror.com/tech/lil/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24949515</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 06:20:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Everything you need to know about windsocks]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 51 | Comments 14 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24949514">thread link</a>) | @oftenwrong
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://www.hollandaviation.nl/en/windsock-everything-you-need-to-know-about-windsocks/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hollandaviation.nl/en/windsock-everything-you-need-to-know-about-windsocks/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hollandaviation.nl/en/windsock-everything-you-need-to-know-about-windsocks/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24949514</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 06:19:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Better Mousetrap – Converting WebPages to Web APIs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24948779">thread link</a>) | @shanselman
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://turnerj.com/blog/a-better-mousetrap | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://turnerj.com/blog/a-better-mousetrap">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div role="article">
<p>Today is a big day for me as after many months (or years depending how you look at it), I've <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/brandvantage">finally launched the first product for my business, BrandVantage</a>.
This post is the story of how I started with one idea and ended up launching with a different one.</p>
<h2>The Original Idea: Let's build a digital brand expert!</h2>
<p>I worked as a web developer for a local web development agency for a number of years and in that time, I learnt a lot about how a variety of different businesses operated online.</p>
<p>There were a few key "problems" I found in common across many of those businesses:</p>
<ul>
<li>Under-utilising analytics</li>
<li>Misunderstanding analytics</li>
<li>Not keeping on top of industry information</li>
<li>Lack of competitor analysis/understanding</li>
<li>Difficulty with Search Engine Optimization (SEO)</li>
</ul>
<p>In moderate-to-large companies where you have marketing departments, most of this stuff can be covered by one or more staff dedicated to these things.
In smaller companies, the business owner is normally the one where these tasks fall on to, but they are already wearing many different hats.
It felt like something was here - if I could automate some of these tasks in different ways, I could both help business owners and earn myself some money along the way.</p>
<p>Automation of tasks, especially ones in analytics or SEO spaces, isn't a new idea.
In fact, I've seen many businesses in a similar space launch on Product Hunt over the years since starting, but that didn't deter me.
I was building <a href="https://idioms.thefreedictionary.com/a+better+mousetrap"><em>a better mousetrap</em></a> and wanting to launch it at a lower price, not something truly innovative so it was going to be an uphill battle.
This area though, helping small businesses online be as efficient in tasks as some bigger businesses can, is something I felt passionately about so I proceeded anyway.</p>
<h3>Attempt One: Very Hacky (in PHP)</h3>
<p>Way back in 2015/16/17, while still at my full-time job, I spent nights and weekends building and tinkering on solutions to the problems business owners face.
It was a hacky PHP solution pulling real-time information from sources like Twitter, Google Analytics and Facebook.
A hacky approach seemed like a good idea as that seemed to be the way people launched things, do the quickest and hackiest thing you can to get it out the door.</p>
<p>While working on it, I had a few interested parties though what I built could barely be considered a prototype.
The thing was a mess.
I could do some basic queries, but it wasn't what I considered sellable and definitely not user-friendly, something I considered key to the product.
I was also running into technical problems with scale - any sufficiently complex query was performed real-time, which was getting more complicated.
Real-time processing had to be out.
I needed to pre-compute and store it in a database.</p>
<p>I wanted to take this more seriously and I didn't feel like a "quick and hacky" approach to building a product was right for me.
With this in mind, it seemed like a good opportunity to change the tech stack to something that would be better long term.</p>
<h3>Attempt Two: Slightly Less Hacky (in .NET)</h3>
<p>Moving to .NET felt like the smart move for me as at my job I had spent a lot more time working in .NET than PHP, plus I vastly prefered the tooling in .NET vs PHP.
That said, the .NET code I had worked on to-date would definitely be considered "legacy code".</p>
<p>My first version in .NET (specifically .NET Framework), predating my use of version control, was trying to keep costs low by using MySQL through Entity Framework.
After a lot of pain and suffering with that, I had a short stint of MSSQL before I settled upon MongoDB.</p>
<p>MongoDB might seem like a weird choice - there are some people that have very strong opinions about which type of database you should use.
Honestly it came down to a gut feel after messing around with it - it seemed more compatible to the way I was approaching problems than a relational database would.
I liked the code-first approach to Entity Framework so much though that I recreated the "feel" of Entity Framework for MongoDB with some custom code.
This later became an open source project of mine called <a href="https://www.mongoframework.com/">MongoFramework</a>.</p>
<p>I'm not going to lie, progress was... slow.
While I was putting quite a lot of time into working on it, it was still an extremely ambitious project.
I have strong feelings about building "MVPs" where some people focus too much on the "minimum" without enough focus on the "viable".
At the end of the day people buy products that meet their needs, and cutting too much out would meet no-ones needs.
If someone was going to use this, in a market with many competitors of varying quality, it had to do its job well.
There didn't seem much I could reasonably cut to make it any more minimal if I wanted people to buy it.</p>
<p>I kept working at it every night, building pieces to extract and store data from a variety of sources.
I was pulling in data from Google Analytics, Google Webmaster Tools (now called Google Search Console), Twitter, Facebook, IP Geolocation, DNS information and also from news articles.
What I thought I could do is once I had the different data sources together, I would write custom rules that could infer insights from individual or combined data sets.
These insights would form the basis of the "digital brand expert".
After all, that was the goal of the idea, something that could help out small business owners.</p>
<p>After 2 years of working on this in my spare time, it felt the right time to leave my job and go into this full time.
I felt like I was <em>so close</em> to launching and I just needed something more than the same day-to-day work.
So I did it - <a href="https://turnerj.com/blog/i-left-my-job-today-after-seven-years">I left my job after 7 years</a>.</p>
<h3>Going Full-time into the Idea</h3>
<p>Right out of the gate, I had moved from .NET Framework to .NET Core, was working on UI/UX improvements for the application and launched the website for it.
I worked with an accountant and a lawyer to setup the business, bought a trade mark for the product name, and I felt good like I was only a few months away from launching.
This feeling didn't last though...</p>
<p>Over time, it felt like I was taking two steps forward then one step back - some technical, some business related.
Sure, that is still progress, but having new issues crop up every day or so can really crush your motivation.</p>
<p>My best/happiest/most productive days were days I ignored or avoided different issues I had.
If I had a problem with the login system, I would focus on how the UX of the menus worked.
If I had a problem with data gathering, I would add more tests to the codebase.
While I didn't entirely ignore the problem, I would wait a week or two before I looked at it again, somewhat hoping it would solve itself - unfortunately that isn't how things work.</p>
<p>In time though, I got to a stage where it felt like I could launch and was hyping myself up until reality struck: I didn't actually build what I set out to build.</p>
<p>The UI/UX was good, I had strategies for deployment and plans for next steps, but it wasn't a "digital brand expert".
It was instead a glorified data store for information that people could better access through existing tools.
That's kinda a big problem!</p>
<p><img src="https://turnerj.com/blog/2020/images/a-better-mousetrap-ive-made-a-huge-mistake.gif" alt="Gob Bluth saying &quot;I've made a huge mistake.&quot; from the TV Show &quot;Arrested Development&quot;"></p>
<p>When realising this I poured time into fixing that huge lapse in judgement, but I couldn't do it.
No matter how I tried, I just couldn't figure out how to build this rules engine.
It was like my entire thought process was just clouded.
I couldn't see the solution to the problem like I can for most other things.</p>
<p>This was depressing and I ended up having a month or so hiatus from working on it.
When I have had stints of not feeling like or not being able to do programming in the past, I try and spur it on again by watching some show or movie which has some strong relation to technology (fictional or not).
My go-to is usually something like <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0371746/">Iron Man</a>, but this time I was rewatching <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2543312/">Halt and Catch Fire</a> where I found some inspiration.</p>
<h2>The Pivot: An API to the Internet</h2>
<p>Later in the series a lot of the focus is around the Web, and it was in these episodes where my thoughts about the Internet and the data on it have changed.
There is a quote from one of the main characters at the end of Season 3 that resonates with me:</p>
<div>
<blockquote>
<p>"The moment we decide what the Web is, we've lost. The moment we try to tell people what to do with it, we've lost.
All we have to do is build a door and let them inside."</p>
<p>- Joe MacMillan (Season 3, Episode 10)</p>
</blockquote>
</div>
<p>The Internet is a treasure trove of information, it is searchable but generally unstructured.
People have managed to create all sorts of different pages in HTML, but in the process of making a website everything is designed for a human user.
It is this way for obvious reasons, <em>we</em> are the consumers of web pages after all... aren't we?</p>
<p>Behind these user-friendly web pages are usually other specific bits of markup, providing some level of structured data for specific situations.
Sometimes it is a description metatag for search engines, other times it might be <a href="https://ogp.me/">Open Graph</a> metatags for social media links.
We build these things to help aid computers processing our web pages.</p>
<p>In 2011, <a href="https://schema.org/">Schema.org</a> was created.
This was a collaborative effort between Google, Bing and Yahoo (later that year, Yandex as well) with the mission to "create, maintain, and promote schemas for structured data on the Internet, on web pages, in email messages, and beyond".
Through 3 different encodings (<a href="https://turnerj.com/blog/what-is-microdata-and-why-should-i-care">Microdata</a>, <a href="http://rdfa.info/">RDFa</a> and <a href="https://json-ld.org/">JSON-LD</a>), websites could express detailed structured data.</p>
<p>There is another quote from Halt and Catch Fire which I like:</p>
<div>
<blockquote>
<p>"Computers aren't the thing. They're the thing that gets us to the thing."</p>
<p>- Joe MacMillan (Season 1, Episode 1)</p>
</blockquote>
</div>
<p>As much as I like computers and programming, they are used to help us achieve other goals.
From my attempts of trying to build a "digital brand expert", I knew that data is fundamental to help build more advanced systems and give new insights.
Having easier access to other forms of data from web pages around the world may allow new and different tools to be built.</p>
<p>So I decided rather than try and solve a problem that I was clouded by, I …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://turnerj.com/blog/a-better-mousetrap">https://turnerj.com/blog/a-better-mousetrap</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://turnerj.com/blog/a-better-mousetrap</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24948779</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 02:49:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Complexity in Operating Systems]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 23 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24945856">thread link</a>) | @fcambus
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://x86.lol/generic/2020/10/30/complexity-in-operating-systems.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://x86.lol/generic/2020/10/30/complexity-in-operating-systems.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Over the last years I’ve been working on very different operating
systems. Operating systems are usually incredibly complex beasts. I
think there are mainly three drivers of this complexity. Surprisingly
enough, neither of these is having to deal with hardware.</p>

<p>The first one is resource <strong>discovery</strong>, i.e. figuring out how the
computer the OS is running on actually looks like. On x86, this
involves parsing countless bitfields, tables, executing byte code
provided by the firmware, probing individual features, etc. The most
painful example of this I’ve seen so far is figuring out which
interrupt a particular PCI interrupt line is routed to. It’s worth a
set of posts, but until then, feel free to checkout <a href="https://habr.com/en/post/501912/">this
description</a>. (If it’s down, it’s
also cached by
<a href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:CXZUV61m7hwJ:https://habr.com/en/post/501912/+&amp;cd=1&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk">Google</a>.)</p>

<p>The second issue is <strong>resource management</strong>. Essentially, how do you
hand out and eventually reclaim all the resources you discovered. For
some workloads performance matters here, so this code is usually
written with speed in mind.</p>

<p>The third reason is that at compile time the <strong>workload</strong> is
unclear. So the kernel has to assume the worst. It must be ready to
start a couple of hundred VMs or create a thousand TCP sockets in a
blink of an eye, because there is no way to know what’s going to
happen or what the actual requirements are.</p>

<p>A fun exercise is to checkout the <a href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v5.9.1/source/virt/kvm/kvm_main.c#L739">KVM code for creating
VMs</a>. Try
to follow
<a href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v5.9.1/source/arch/x86/kvm/x86.c#L9904">the</a>
<a href="https://elixir.bootlin.com/linux/v5.9.1/source/arch/x86/kvm/vmx/vmx.c#L7059">code</a>
to where the actual VM is created in hardware. <em>Spoiler:</em> There is
none. It’s all figuring out what the platform can do and then setting
up a bunch of spinlock, mutexes, lists, arrays, structs, …</p>

<p>I don’t want to pick on KVM in particular. I think it’s pretty ok as
far as Linux kernel code goes. Operating System kernel code is mostly
like this: A lot of really mind numbing platform discovery and
resource management code written for speed assuming the worst case
requirements in a language that doesn’t do parsing, resource
management or concurrency well (among other things).</p>

<p>People take this all for granted. But when I look around, I see many
systems that don’t need this complexity and where it is only a safety
and security burden. Consider most appliance-type products, e.g. a
Wi-Fi router. Or a system that runs one service on a cloud VM. You
know everything in advance!</p>

<p>If you read until this point, you are probably asking yourself, where
I am going with this. If you think <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Separation_kernel">separation
kernel</a>, you are
right. My rough plan to write a couple of more posts to flesh out the
idea of doing all the complicated OS parts at compile time and how
this results in an incredibly simple, secure, and efficient system at
runtime. There will be <a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V</a>,
<a href="https://www.haskell.org/">Haskell</a>, <a href="https://dhall-lang.org/">Dhall</a>,
and <a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust</a> content.</p>

<p>Stay tuned.</p>

  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://x86.lol/generic/2020/10/30/complexity-in-operating-systems.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24945856</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 19:20:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Scientists Take Over: George Orwell Reviews “That Hideous Strength” (1945)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 89 | Comments 55 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24945608">thread link</a>) | @benbreen
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | http://lewisiana.nl/orwell/index.htm | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://lewisiana.nl/orwell/index.htm">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>







<p><b><span lang="EN-US">George
Orwell’s review of C. S. Lewis, <i>That
Hideous Strength</i> (1945)<o:p></o:p></span></b></p>



<p><span lang="EN-US">THE SCIENTISTS TAKE OVER<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><b><i><span lang="EN-US">Manchester Evening News</span></i></b><b><span lang="EN-US">, 16 August 1945. </span></b><span lang="EN-US">Reprinted in <i>The Complete Works of George Orwell</i>, ed. Peter Davison,
Vol. XVII (1998), No. 2720 (first half), pp. 250–251<o:p></o:p></span></p>











<p><span lang="EN-GB">On</span><span lang="EN-US"> the whole, novels are better when there are no
miracles in them. Still, it is possible to think of a fairly large number of worth-while
books in which ghosts, magic, second-sight, angels, mermaids, and what-not play
a part.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">Mr. C. S. Lewis’s “That Hideous Strength” can be included in their number –
though, curiously enough, it would probably have been a better book if the
magical element had been left out. For in essence it is a crime story, and the
miraculous happenings, though they grow more frequent towards the end, are not
integral to it.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">In general outline, and to some extent in atmosphere, it rather resembles
G. K. Chesterton’s “The Man Who Was Thursday.”<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">Mr. Lewis probably owes something to Chesterton as a writer, and certainly
shares his horror of modern machine <span>civilisation</span> (the
title of the book, by the way, is taken from a poem about the Tower of Babel)
and his reliance on the “eternal verities” of the Christian Church, as against
scientific materialism or nihilism.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">His book describes the struggle of a little group of sane people against a
nightmare that nearly conquers the world. A company of mad scientists – or,
perhaps, they are not mad, but have merely destroyed in themselves all human
feeling, all notion of good and evil – are plotting to conquer Britain, then
the whole planet, and then other planets, until they have brought the universe
under their control.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">All superfluous life is to be wiped out, all natural forces tamed, the
common people are to be used as slaves and vivisection subjects by the ruling
caste of scientists, who even see their way to conferring immortal life upon
themselves. Man, in short, is to storm the heavens and overthrow the gods, or
even to become a god himself.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">There is nothing outrageously improbable in such a conspiracy. Indeed, at a
moment when a single atomic bomb – of a type already pronounced “obsolete” –
has just blown probably three hundred thousand people to fragments, it sounds
all too topical. Plenty of people in our age do entertain the monstrous dreams
of power that Mr. Lewis attributes to his characters, and we are within sight
of the time when such dreams will be <span>realisable</span>.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">His description of the N.I.C.E. (National Institute of Co-ordinated
Experiments), with its world-wide ramifications, its private army, its secret
torture chambers, and its inner ring of adepts ruled over by a mysterious
personage known as The Head, is as exciting as any detective story.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">It would be a very hardened reader who would not experience a thrill on
learning that The Head is actually – however, that would be giving the game
away.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">One could recommend this book unreservedly if Mr. Lewis had succeeded in keeping
it all on a single level. Unfortunately, the supernatural keeps breaking in,
and it does so in rather confusing, undisciplined ways. The scientists are <span>endeavouring</span>, among other things, to get hold of the body
of the ancient Celtic magician Merlin, who has been buried – not dead, but in a
trance – for the last 1,500 years, in hopes of learning from him the secrets of
pre-Christian magic.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">They are frustrated by a character who is only doubtfully a human being,
having spent part of his time on another planet where he has been gifted with
eternal youth. Then there is a woman with second sight, one or two ghosts, and
various superhuman visitors from outer space, some of them with rather tiresome
names which derive from earlier books of Mr. Lewis’s. The book ends in a way
that is so preposterous that it does not even succeed in being horrible in
spite of much bloodshed.<o:p></o:p></span></p>

<p><span lang="EN-US">Much is made of the fact that the scientists are actually in touch with
evil spirits, although this fact is known only to the inmost circle. Mr. Lewis
appears to believe in the existence of such spirits, and of benevolent ones as
well. He is entitled to his beliefs, but they weaken his story, not only
because they offend the average reader’s sense of probability but because in
effect they decide the issue in advance. When one is told that God and the
Devil are in conflict one always knows which side is going to win. The whole
drama of the struggle against evil lies in the fact that one does not have
supernatural aid. However, by the standard of the novels appearing nowadays
this is a book worth reading.<o:p></o:p></span></p>







</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://lewisiana.nl/orwell/index.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24945608</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 18:55:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[A Neighbourly Solution to the 'X Is Deprecated? ' Conundrum]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 58 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24945538">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/10/29/improving-x/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/10/29/improving-x/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      <div>
        <article lang="en">
          
          <p>Recent posts about the state of Xorg and its future has been stirring the
internets as of late and, as almost always, it is best to stay clear of the
comments sections. The more insightful post is <a href="https://ajaxnwnk.blogspot.com/2020/10/on-abandoning-x-server.html">On Abandoning the X Server</a>.</p>

<p>There are a few details in it that should be emphasised before we move on.</p>

<div><div><pre><blockquote>Though the code happens to implement an unfortunate
specification, the code itself is quite well structured, easy to hack on, and
not far off from being easily embeddable.</blockquote></pre></div></div>

<p>From my own experiences with Xorg internals, I agree completely. A whole lot
of the code there is noticably better than corresponding paths in certain
Wayland compositors. There is more thought; domain expertise; engineering and
pure elbow grease behind it than you might have been led to believe -- if you
have only listened in to the collective moans in various discussion groups.</p>

<div><div><pre><blockquote>So is Xorg abandoned? To the extent that means using it to actually
control the display, and not just keep X apps running, I'd say yes. But xserver
is more than xfree86. Xwayland, Xwin, Xephyr, Xvnc, Xvfb: these are projects
with real value that we should not give up. A better way to say it is that we
can finally abandon xfree86.</blockquote></pre></div></div>

<p>There are some nuances here that many will miss as it requires you to know
something about the architecture of the X server. The main thing is to not
conflate ‘xfree86’ with rest of what you think of as X, hence why the blog post
separates out XFree86-the-project from 'xfree86 the hardware driver'. It is
unfortunate that the predecessor to Xorg was also called XFree86. Naming
things is hard and all that.</p>

<p>If you look at the xorg code, recommended reading for many who can
understand the language, you will see that the device-dependent code used to
drive displays (hw/ in the source tree) has a few backends, mentioned above.
Venture into the hw/xfree86 part and you will hopefully see why Adam Jackson
and others deserve the software engineering equivalent of a Purple Heart for
their service to your desktop, possibly alongside anyone that ever had to work
on ASN.1.</p>

<p>
<i>Rightfully throw Xorg-xfree86 into the fires of Mt. Doom. If you
still need Xorg-xfree86 to be your graphics card driver, you have bigger things
to worry about, such as plain old bitrot.</i></p>

<p>Is there something else? Yes. I’m not going to say <a href="https://arcan-fe.com/">Arcan</a> – it is <i>very</i> likely that there
is only a small percentage of the stakeholders we would ever get along with.
That is fine. The goals and agenda reach much further than many will ever care
to travel -- unless you really want to push the boundaries of computing, or you
are actively targeted by nefarious individuals; our funding is not based on
popularity or mass adoption, but rather sticking to the shadows.</p>

<h2>The Compromise</h2>
<p>So what can we do instead? The current Wayland maintainer has
<a href="https://github.com/emersion/libliftoff">libliftoff</a> for smoothing
over the rather ‘unergonomic’ APIs that are used to get the open, modern,
graphics stack up and running. <em>Write a DDX backend that uses it.
hw/liftoff!</em></p>

<p>This will get liftoff the lift-off and mileage it needs to become good
enough for Wayland compositors to use as their default, and as a slightly more
polite migration path in order for NVIDIA to be less contemptible in the
unlikely event that they are one day struck by some capitalist version of
religious insight. Thus, it improves parts of the Wayland compositor situation
that is, politely put, chaotic.</p>

<p>Those that don’t care about what Wayland tries to achieve can stay with X and
not worry about their graphics breaking after a kernel update, or well, more
than usual -- Linux gotta Linux. NVIDIA blob users can continue down that path
and stop bothering Wayland developers, yet still run their Steam games without
submitting to open source ideals.</p>

<p>Next steps. This is for the window managers. Take libarcan-shmif-server and
embed as a module in Xorg, fork it off even. If you are unaware, this is the
IPC system part of Arcan. Both the server and the client sides of it are fairly
trivial to use and are written with developers, not toolkits, in mind.</p>

<p>It is beyond feature parity with the rest of X, but has a comparable view on
capabilities and division of responsibility. You will only get a fraction of
the benefits of Arcan as a display server, but without other dependencies or
friction - many of the problems that X clients are plagued with can be worked
around while leaving the X11 protocol and its family of extensions to rest.
Hacks relying on facilities like uinput can be put down.</p>

<p>The security around these clients will be much tighter and they can be
gradually tuned to the specification of the developer. It lets XFCE, AwesomeWM,
WindowMaker and the tens to hundreds of others WM projects to continue to
improve their respective ecosystems, specialized widgets and other tools,
rather than to burn resources they don't have to rewrite themselves with bugs
that won't be discovered or fixed in time to matter.</p>

<p>It also gives the conservative side of BSDs a portable way of improving
their use of the graphics stack without reworking fundamentals they care little
about. The OpenBSD fork 'Xenocara' can be dropped.</p>

<p>This way, the heritage is preserved and kept alive, with a band aid to live
out another decade or three. It will still work for the marginalized that have
little interest- or option- in going elsewhere. It will be less painful to
maintain and work with.</p>

<h2>The Reality</h2>
<p>Wayland only is not an option that will ever work across the board. It is
not a replacement, it is a fundamental change of principles. Stop trying to
market it as some kind of inevitable transition. There are strong differences
that will not get smoothed over regardless of how many 'protocols' you define;
<i>Wayland is Policy over Mechanism, X11 is Mechanism over Policy</i>. This is
the real barrier. Not unsubstantiated claims of 'security'. It is a tectonic
shift and no matter your feelings about that, we won't all be in the same
country or continent anymore.</p>

<p>Heralding a 'Screenshot Protocol' and similar exercises as the fix that will
bridge this gap will only serve to distract from the fact that the power of all
these little tools and hacks from the crowd of X11 users comes from the
'screenshot' being just one case of <i>'give me the contents of a specific
window and all of its children'</i> or <i>'composite these windows to an
offscreen buffer and send me the results'</i> as the building blocks
available to be creative with.

</p><p>The mechanism approach provides a huge set of possibilities and opens up for
experimentation and 'works for me' kind of hacks. The downside is that it
surrenders control on the server side and are much harder to make robust.</p>

<p>The policy aproach will only do what both sides agree to, and <i>that
	agreement has the final say</i>. If you violate this contract, you are to be
blamed. However, that contract has to be bikeshedded to near state-space
exhaustion and carefully screened for conflicts as more contracts are added to
the pile.</p>

<p>The current trajectory is Gnomelanders and Swaylanders and Kwinners and so
on continuing to lock down singular uses cases and with political gunplay try
to push that as the one solution that will convince a few more bread crumbs.
The hand that controls the toolkit will eventually just decide. <i> This will
erode the strength of the policy contract</i>.</p>

<p>This has already led to a substantial amount of dissonance -- it turns out
that the 'opting-server-side decoration protocol' in the mix had implications
for how to interpret the 'subsurface protocol' and the 'redshift gamma
protocol' will clash with whatever 'color management protocol' that materialize
and so on. To get a feel for how involved such policies become, just <a href="https://github.com/wayland-project/wayland-protocols/blob/3a74660e94d85fde24f504cc9d4375d42192e84a/stable/xdg-shell/xdg-shell.xml#L402">
read the specification</a> and you will see why no implementation arrives at
the same calculation.</p>

<p>Take the perspective of a client developer chasing after the tumbleweed of
'protocols' drifting around and try to answer 'what am I supposed to implement
and use'? To me it looked like like a Picasso painting of ill-fitting- and
internally conflicted ideas. Let this continue a few cycles more and X11 will
look clean and balanced by comparison. Someone should propose a desktop icon
protocol for the sake of it, then again, someone probably already has.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>
<p>This approach will force Wayland to demonstrate its worth through the
virtues of its properties alone or by inventing actually compelling features
rather than by throwing shade on the elderly; or reimplementing the past
through rebranded and traced outlines from shadows cast by grander window
managers of yore.</p>

<p>The proposal leaves us with three well-defined paths.</p>

<ul>
<li>Wayland lets your own solipsist thiefdoms expand towards the horizon,
while trying to save embedded from the Android expanse.</li>
<li>People that have invested their hearts and souls into the X ecosystem can
continue to use their computers without fear of a kernel upgrade leaving them
with broken graphics, or a switch of display server paradigm leaving them with
an incompatible mental model of how system graphics work, and perhaps, one day,
stop whining about Wayland ruining their day and leave the devs alone.</li>
<li>Arcan lets you play with crazy ideas at a low initial cost. The ones
that might revolutionise your world or fail miserably. It will continue to
pushing things towards whatever is beyond the Twilight Zone in order to answer
profound questions such as 'what happens to productivity if your heartbeat
aligns with the blink rate of the cursor' (well that's actually be done since
forever and the RESULTS WOULD SHOCK YOU! - but it still illustrates the
point).</li>
</ul>

<p>It might even turn out so well that one of these paths will have a
fighting chance against the open desktop being further marginalised as a thin
client in the Azure clouded future; nothing more than a silhouette behind
unwashed Windows, a virtualized ghost of its former self.</p>

        </article>
	     </div>
     </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/10/29/improving-x/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24945538</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 18:45:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[KDE.org migrated to Hugo]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 187 | Comments 78 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24944537">thread link</a>) | @ognarb
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://carlschwan.eu/2020/10/30/kde-org-hugo.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://carlschwan.eu/2020/10/30/kde-org-hugo.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section><p><img src="https://carlschwan.eu/assets/img/heading_hugo.png" alt="Screenshot KDE.org"></p>

<p><a href="https://kde.org/">KDE.org</a> now uses <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a>. Hugo is a fast and modern static site
generator written in Go. It provides a few improvements over the old system that was
using plain PHP. A large part of the work was done by Anuj during GSoC 2020. This
was a massive work, converting the repository storing more than 20 years of KDE
history.</p>

<p>The website is now generated once and no longer uses PHP to generate itself at runtime.
This improves the loading speed of the website, but the speed boost is not significant,
since the PHP code used before was quite small and KDE’s servers are powerful.</p>

<p>But the biggest improvement is in terms of features. We are now working with markdown
files instead of raw HTML files, this makes the life of the promo team much easier.</p>

<p>The internationalization of the website now creates a unique URL per language, this
should allow Google to link to the version of the website using the correct language.
A <a href="https://kde.org/fr/">French</a>, <a href="https://kde.org/uk/">Ukrainian</a>,
<a href="https://kde.org/ca/">Catalan</a>, <a href="https://kde.org/nl/">Dutch</a>, and a few more languages
are already available. There is also a proper language selector! We also don’t need
to manually tag each string for translations.</p>

<p>There is also now an <a href="https://kde.org/announcements/index.xml">RSS feed</a> with all the
latest announcements. Another big improvement is that the announcements list is
autogenerated and no longer modified by hand and with the help of the release scripts.</p>

<p>Another nice change for website developers is that now the SCSS code for the individual
pages is located in the kde-org repository itself instead of another repository.
Overall the developer experience is much better, there is no need to set up an apache
server and to the PHP configs to include the <a href="https://invent.kde.org/websites/capacity">capacity framework</a>, just to get the
website running locally. Now you only need to download the Hugo binary from their
release page and run it on the repo.</p>

<h2 id="hugo-and-gettext">Hugo and Gettext</h2>

<p>The internationalization of KDE.org was quite a challenge. When working on a multilingual
website with Hugo, Hugo expects a markdown document per language for each translated
page.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>plasma-desktop.md
plasma-desktop.es.md
plasma-desktop.fr.md
plasma-desktop.uk.md
...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The problem is that traditional translations workflow rely on a string-based approach,
where a document is split in paragraphs and translated individually. So I couldn’t
just put each file markdown file as big blobs in the po files. To solve this problem,
I created a python script splitting the markdown files in paragraphs, simplifying
the markdown syntax (removing leading <code>#</code> and <code>+</code> for heading and list item). This
script also handles Hugo shortcodes transforming:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>
{{&lt; img caption="My figure caption" alt="My accessible description" src="..." &gt;}}

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>in two strings:</p>

<ul>
  <li>My figure caption</li>
  <li>My accessible description</li>
</ul>

<p>The script can obliviously put the individual strings back in place. The scripts also
handle the menu translation, and the translations of the strings in the footers.
For now, the script is just a file in the kde-org repository, but I would like to
transform it to a standalone library so that other gettext and Hugo users can
translate their website.</p>

<p>Using Hugo API, the language selector was trivial to write:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>
&lt;ul class="navbar-nav ml-auto"&gt;
  {{ if .IsTranslated }}
    &lt;li class="nav-item dropdown" aria-describedby="language-picker-description"&gt;
      &lt;p class="sr-only" id="language-picker-description"&gt;{{ i18n "Select-your-language" }}&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a class="nav-link dropdown-toggle" href="#" data-toggle="dropdown" role="button" aria-haspopup="true" aria-expanded="false"&gt;
        &lt;img src="/Language-Icons/icon20x24px-exported-transparent.png" alt="" /&gt;
        &lt;span&gt;{{ i18n "translations" }}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;div class="dropdown-menu dropdonw-trans" role="listbox"&gt;
        &lt;a class="dropdown-item" aria-selected="true" hreflang="{{ .Site.Language.Lang }}" role="option" lang="{{ .Site.Language.Lang }}" href="{{ .Permalink }}"&gt;{{ .Site.Language.LanguageName }}&lt;/a&gt;
        {{ range .Translations }}
          &lt;a class="dropdown-item" hreflang="{{ .Language.Lang }}" role="option" lang="{{ .Language.Lang }}" href="{{ .Permalink }}"&gt;{{ .Language.LanguageName }}&lt;/a&gt;
        {{ end }}
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  {{ end }}
&lt;/ul&gt;

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is a bit verbose because this selector is also fully accessible for screen readers.</p>

<p>There are a few more tricks employed in kde.org to improve the internationalization, for
example when a page doesn’t exist in a language, there is an Apache rule redirecting it
to the English version. Another nice trick is that there is a special Hugo shortcode
called <code>i18n_var</code> and used to parametrize the strings. For example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>
{{&lt; i18n_var "Today KDE releases a bugfix update to KDE Plasma 5, versioned %[1]s" "5.20.2" &gt;}}

</code></pre></div></div>

<p>And the extractor is clever and only extract the part that needs to be translated.</p>

<p><a href="https://invent.kde.org/websites/kde-org/-/blob/master/translations.py">The script</a></p>

<p>You can comment this post on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kde/comments/jl1pim/kdeorg_migrated_to_hugo/?">r/kde</a>
and <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24944537">HN</a>.</p>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://carlschwan.eu/2020/10/30/kde-org-hugo.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24944537</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 17:19:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Mendoza: Use stack machines to compute efficient JSON diffs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 114 | Comments 33 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24943775">thread link</a>) | @evenw
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://www.sanity.io/blog/mendoza | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.sanity.io/blog/mendoza">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>When we started work on the recently released feature <a href="https://www.sanity.io/blog/review-changes">Review Changes</a>, we needed a way to keep a significant part of the edit history of a document in the browser memory to be able to respond quickly to different user interface states. As the user picked various document versions to compare we wanted to be able to quickly reconstruct a specific section of the history of a document. </p><figure><div role="button"><div data-has-aspect="false"></div></div><figcaption>Review Changes for Sanity Studio. Powered by Mendoza.</figcaption></figure><p>For text diffs, we use the <a href="https://github.com/google/diff-match-patch">diff-match-patch format</a>, and we just assumed someone would have implemented a similarly efficient and compact diff format for JSON documents, but no such luck. If we wanted a general JSON diff format that was super compact and fast to apply, we would have to invent it ourselves. And thus, Mendoza, the totally non-human readable diff format for structured JSON documents, was born.</p><p>Mendoza is:</p><ul><li>Lightweight JSON format</li><li>A flexible format that can accommodate more advanced encodings in the future</li><li>As a Go library for encoding and decoding</li><li>A JavaScript library for decoding</li><li>Efficient handling of the renaming of fields</li><li>Efficient handling of reordering of arrays</li><li>Not designed to be human-readable</li></ul><p>Mendoza differs (hah!) from normal diffs as they are:</p><ul><li>Made for humans to read and understand and based on simple operations (like keep, insert, and delete text)</li><li>Possible to apply even if the source has changed a bit by including some of the contexts around every part that has changed</li><li>Designed for text, and not structured documents</li></ul><p>Now, this is great when you are collaborating with humans on code development and use something like git to track your changes. What it isnâ€™t great for, however, is expressing differences between structured documents (such as JSON) in a compact manner that can be efficiently transferred over the network and parsed in JavaScript inside of browsers.</p><div data-block-key="27e85758c59a"><h2><a id="most-diffs-arent-meant-for-machines-27e85758c59a"></a><a href="#most-diffs-arent-meant-for-machines-27e85758c59a"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="20" height="20" viewBox="0 0 20 24"><path d="M0 0h24v24H0z" fill="none"></path><path fill="currentColor" d="M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76 0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71 0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71 0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z"></path></svg></a>Most diffs aren't meant for machines</h2></div><p>Most diff formats are made to be human-readable. Take these two documents, where a key and the array have some changes between them:</p><p>If these where two commits, the Git diff between them would be expressed like this:</p><p>This makes it somewhat practical for humans to understand what is going on when the latter change is applied. But as you can see, in terms of pure data, there is a lot of repetition going on. and expressing all changes with only plusses and minuses isn't very efficient.</p><p>The same diff with Mendoza is expressed like this:</p><p>Mendoza constructs a minimal recipe for transforming a document into another. All it really does is to compare two JSON documents and figure out the most minimal way to express their difference as strings and integers in an array. You can use this difference to reconstruct the first document to the other.</p><div data-block-key="308db67aa205"><h2><a id="how-to-read-a-mendoza-patch-even-though-you-shouldnt-308db67aa205"></a><a href="#how-to-read-a-mendoza-patch-even-though-you-shouldnt-308db67aa205"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="20" height="20" viewBox="0 0 20 24"><path d="M0 0h24v24H0z" fill="none"></path><path fill="currentColor" d="M3.9 12c0-1.71 1.39-3.1 3.1-3.1h4V7H7c-2.76 0-5 2.24-5 5s2.24 5 5 5h4v-1.9H7c-1.71 0-3.1-1.39-3.1-3.1zM8 13h8v-2H8v2zm9-6h-4v1.9h4c1.71 0 3.1 1.39 3.1 3.1s-1.39 3.1-3.1 3.1h-4V17h4c2.76 0 5-2.24 5-5s-2.24-5-5-5z"></path></svg></a>How to read a Mendoza patch (even though you shouldn't)</h2></div><p>A Mendoza patch consists of an array of integers and strings. The integers are <em>opcodes</em> (short for â€œoperation codesâ€�), 8-bit numbers that correspond to an operation. Opcodes take parameters as strings, positive numbers, or JSON values (that is: the actual data that is changing). The list of available opcodes is as follows, notice that 10-18 are composites of the preceding ones:</p><ul><li>0 <code>Value<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>1 <code>Copy<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>2 <code>Blank<!-- -->â€‹</code></li><li>3 <code>ReturnIntoArray<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>4 <code>ReturnIntoObject<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>5 <code>ReturnIntoObjectSameKey<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>6 <code>PushField<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>7 <code>PushElement<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>8 <code>PushParent<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>9 <code>Pop<!-- -->â€‹ </code></li><li>10 <code>PushFieldCopy</code></li><li>11 <code>PushFieldBlank</code></li><li>12 <code>PushElementCopy</code></li><li>13 <code>PushFieldBlank</code></li><li>14 <code>ReturnIntoObjectPop</code></li><li>15 <code>ReturnIntoObjectSameKeyPop</code></li><li>16 <code>ReturnIntoArrayPop</code></li><li>17 <code>ObjectSetFieldValue</code></li><li>18 <code>ObjectCopyField</code></li><li>19 <code>ObjectDeleteField</code>â€‹ </li><li>20 <code>ArrayAppendValue</code>â€‹ </li><li>21 <code>ArrayAppendSlice<!-- -->â€‹</code></li><li>22 <code>StringAppendString<!-- -->â€‹</code></li></ul><p>Mendoza reads these opcodes from the patch and produces the resulting document from them. Depending on the patch, Mendoza might choose not to strictly follow the opcodes but take a simpler path. If every field and value has changed, for example, itâ€™s more efficient just to replace the whole document with the new data without going through all the operations. Or if you have a list of objects where one has moved to another position and changed a key-value, Mendoza will manage to go back to the original and represent the change in a cheap way.</p><p>Mendoza is implemented in Go and can be found in this <a href="https://github.com/sanity-io/mendoza">GitHub repository</a>. We have also made <a href="https://github.com/sanity-io/mendoza-js">a parser for Mendoza patches in JavaScript</a>, that you can use in your own application. </p><p>Of course, you can dive into <a href="https://github.com/sanity-io/sanity/blob/a3f7158016d63728a9b435e6ab444ff2b90fd424/packages/%40sanity/desk-tool/src/panes/documentPane/documentHistory/history/timeline.ts#L421">the source code for the Sanity Studio</a> and explore how Mendoza is used there. If you want a slightly simpler use-case, you can also <a href="https://github.com/sanity-io/groq-store/blob/main/src/patch.ts">check out how weâ€™re using Mendoza to simulate a part of Sanityâ€™s real-time datastore</a> in the browser to power the <a href="https://github.com/sanity-io/next-sanity">real-time preview for Next.js</a>. </p><p>Naming a project is always difficult. Since this project is focused on representing changes between <em>JSON</em> documents I naturally started thinking about names like "JSON differ, JSON changes, JSON patch, â€¦". However, most of these names have already been used by existing projects. While I was muttering "JSON, JSON, JSON" it suddenly turned into "JSON, JSON, Jason, Jason Mendoza".</p><p>Jason Mendoza is a character from the show The Good Place, and while this project has little in common with the stupidest DJ from Florida, at least it's short and catchy.</p><p>Since a Mendoza patch is just describing the effect of a change it is also limited to work for the documents it was based on. It doesnâ€™t come with guarantees for consistency if the document you apply it on has changed from the original in meanwhile. This is one of the tradeoffs that we needed to do to make it really compressed. </p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.sanity.io/blog/mendoza</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24943775</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:15:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Goodbye IFTTT]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 347 | Comments 152 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24943685">thread link</a>) | @todsacerdoti
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <p>I was a power user of <a href="https://ifttt.com/">IFTTT</a> for many years, so I had mixed
feelings recently about <a href="https://archive.is/zpx2r">their decision</a> to change
their pricing model. Under IFTTT's new pricing, you can only have 3 “custom”
actions created/enabled at any time – which is quite a downgrade from the
current unlimited free plan. On the one hand, I'm glad to see IFTTT take
necessary steps to ensure it has long-term financial stability, but on the other
hand, I don't personally get enough value from their service anymore to justify
a recurring cost. (The plan will likely be
$4/month<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>, but if you sign up before a deadline, you
can lock in a price as low as $2/month)</p>
<p>IFTTT was an awesome and uniquely easy-to-use service when it first came out,
but now there are better options for personal automation for people like me, who
like to tinker with this sort of thing. Systems like
<a href="https://nodered.org/">node-red</a> and iOS shortcuts can be self hosted or run on
device, and they provide more sophisticated logic for workflows than IFTTT.</p>
<p>I stayed on IFTTT this long mostly due to inertia, and it's fantastically long
list of supported services. If I needed to throw together a quick
spreadsheet-recording automation, or cron-like trigger, IFTTT was a great
starting place. However, it does have limitations. Until now (though it seems
like this might change with their premium offering), IFTTT basically only did
what its name implied: “if this, then that”. No “if X then Y else Z”, no “if X
and Z then Y”, etc. Often times, you don't need any complicated logic or
filtering, but it was frustrating that there wasn't the option for more advanced
automation. Ultimately, IFTTT had a great “on-ramp”, but once you were on board
with their system, you realize how shallow it is. Excellent breadth, mediocre
depth.</p>
<p>Similarly, in the past couple years IFTTT's UI has leaned heavily into the
“applet” metaphor, with these big goofy toggle switches to enable/disable
automations. The site also transitioned towards a focus on community- (or, more
often corporate-) created automations, at the expense of the experience for
creating your own applets. Like seriously, why is 30% of the UI for an applet
<em>details page</em> (!) taken up by the connection status toggle?</p>
<figure>
    
    <a href="https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/ifttt.png">
        
            
                
                
            
        
        <img src="https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/ifttt_hu1a43e8a517283105e03bcbb0c4894a01_37903_0x300_resize_lanczos_2.png" loading="lazy"> 
        </a>
</figure>

<p>The settings page, too, is woefully information sparse. As a user, this makes me
feel that desktop-usability was not high on IFTTT's design priorities. You have
to scroll the page to begin to start to see what the automation is doing:</p>
<figure>
    
    <a href="https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/ifttt-settings.png">
        
            
                
                
            
        
        <img src="https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/ifttt-settings_hub4acc09d90c5c0c4cbf3054a07fa3040_91989_0x400_resize_lanczos_2.png" loading="lazy"> 
        </a>
</figure>

<p>Eventually, the UI got to the point where it felt like using
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lego_Duplo">Duplos</a> or something. It didn't have
to be this way! There are great low-to-no-code tools that have much more usable
interfaces, like
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scratch_(programming_language)">Scratch</a>.</p>
<figure>
    
    <a href="https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/scratch.png">
        
            
        
        <img src="https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/scratch.png" loading="lazy"> 
        </a>
</figure>

<p>So, I decided to migrate away, since the move to premium was already going to
substantially limit what I could do with IFTTT. In going through my catalog of
IFTTT “applets”, I identified 3 main patterns of automations that I used IFTTT
for: (1) triggering an action to happen at a specific time, (2) triggering an
action to happen in response to a location change (i.e. geofencing), or (3)
triggering an action to happen in response to an event in a web service.</p>
<p>Of these 3 buckets, iOS shortcuts readily handles the first 2: as of iOS 14,
Shortcuts can be triggered in the background at a specific time of day, or in
response to entering/leaving a geofence. Shortcuts also has a much more
sophisticated integration with iOS than any of IFTTT's apps, so more exciting
mobile automation becomes possible – for example, setting my phone to Low Power
Mode once the battery drops below a certain threshold. Of course, you are
restricted to apps/services that support Shortcuts, and the number of supported
services is considerably smaller than IFTTT.</p>
<p>Node-red handles buckets 1 and 3: it has good support for time-based actions,
and can receive webhooks to respond to events from external services. It also
has a great plugin ecosystem, so it's support begins to rival IFTTT's impressive
selection of supported services. Additionally, node-red has many “escape
hatches” that IFTTT does not: you can use it to make raw HTTP requests and write
your own plugins/logic in Javascript, allowing for much more complex automation.</p>
<p>Neither node-red nor iOS shortcuts are as easy to use as IFTTT for putting
together a simple automation, which is a shame. However, between them (and other
alternative automation frameworks that I've trialed, like <a href="https://n8n.io/">n8n</a>
and <a href="https://github.com/huginn/huginn">huginn</a>), I've more than covered my
personal automation needs.</p>
<p>And so, goodbye IFTTT! ðŸ‘‹ I'm not put off by them charging for their service; I
think charging for software is a good thing! It's just that this was the nudge I
needed to move my automations to infrastructure that I have more control over,
which has other benefits outside the scope of this article. I'm thankful that a
service like IFTTT continues to exist; I still think it's a fantastic tool to
“on-ramp” less technical folks into automation and no-code tools.</p>
<p><em>Cover art:
<a href="https://artvee.com/dl/the-village-of-murnau/">The Village Of Murnau (1908)</a></em></p>
<section role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>A previous version of this article stated that the price for IFTTT Pro was
$10/month. While the original press release, as covered <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/9/10/21430265/ifttt-pro-subscriptions-free-controversy">here</a> indicated a $10/month
price, and the current suggested price for IFTTT Pro on their signup form is
$10/month, it seems like going forward the Pro price will be $4/month. I
apologize for the inaccuracy. <a href="#fnref:1" role="doc-backlink">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>

        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://benjamincongdon.me/blog/2020/10/30/Goodbye-IFTTT/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24943685</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:07:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[MCS-48: The quest for 16-bit division on the 8-bit CPU which can’t divide]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 39 | Comments 29 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24941189">thread link</a>) | @noexani
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | http://tech.mattmillman.com/mcs-48-the-quest-for-16-bit-division-on-the-8-bit-cpu-which-cant-divide-anything/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://tech.mattmillman.com/mcs-48-the-quest-for-16-bit-division-on-the-8-bit-cpu-which-cant-divide-anything/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-4862">
	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

		<div>
		
<p>Recently while working on my <a href="http://tech.mattmillman.com/projects/an-intel-mcs-48-based-dual-temperature-sensor/">MCS-48 temperature sensor</a> project I had to confront one of the largest challenges, which is to implement an option where changing a jumper displayed Fahrenheit instead of Celsius. The output from the DS18B10 temperature sensors is Celsius only, as it should be, so a conversion would need to be performed.</p>



<figure><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/CodeCogsEqn.gif" alt=""><figcaption>A quick reminder of the conversion needed to be performed</figcaption></figure>



<p>In my case it’s +320 as I’m using fixed point arithmetic i.e. 15.3° = 153. This is a tough conversion to perform on an MCS-48 as a slew of different operations are required:</p>



<ul><li>16-bit negate (more about that below)</li><li>16-bit unsigned multiply</li><li>16-bit unsigned divide</li><li>16-bit add with wrap-around</li></ul>



<p>A tall order for a CPU which has just <em>one </em>math instruction: 8-bit add. To perform all of this, one must sling a long sequence of primitive instructions together. Since this is an assembly language only architecture, I couldn’t cheat by compiling it in C and pinching the resulting instructions as I have done for PIC16 in the past.</p>



<p><em>Edit: Since publishing this a cornucopia of different approaches to this problem have been proposed to me. I’m happy with implementation as it currently stands. It works, it makes very efficient use of program memory, the improved performance is not required, and the above math routines are re-used for other tasks in the project.</em></p>



<p>The best place to find such examples is in the MCS-48 assembly language manual:</p>



<figure><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual.jpg"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual-800x638.jpg" alt="" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual-800x638.jpg 800w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual-300x239.jpg 300w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual-150x120.jpg 150w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual-768x612.jpg 768w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual-1536x1224.jpg 1536w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/manual-2048x1633.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px"></a></figure>



<p>(A scan of it can be viewed <a href="http://www.nj7p.org/Manuals/PDFs/Intel/9800255D.pdf">here</a>). Everything I needed was in there, except how to divide. There is no mention whatsoever in that manual of how to perform any kind of division operation, <em>but</em>, tacked in the back of the 1980 edition MCS-48 handbook, I found this:</p>



<figure><a href="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv.png"><img src="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv-623x800.png" alt="" srcset="http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv-623x800.png 623w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv-233x300.png 233w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv-117x150.png 117w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv-768x987.png 768w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv-1195x1536.png 1195w, http://techmattmillman.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/isisdiv.png 1263w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px"></a><figcaption>Woohoo! A working divide routine for MCS-48. It wouldn’t OCR, so I typed it up.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Unfortunately that routine only has an 8-bit quotient, which isn’t much use for my application because it would overflow in most cases.</p>



<p>I was easily able to work around that with the following implementation (pseudo code):</p>



<pre><code>if (celsius &lt; 0)
{   // If negative, note it, and make it positive
    // so we can work with simpler unsigned routines below
    celsius = -celsius;
    is_negative = 1;
}

fahrenheit = multiply_16x8r16(celsius, 9);

// Divide by 50 so the result of divide_16x8r8 doesn't overflow
fahrenheit = divide_16x8r8(fahrenheit, 50, &amp;remainder);

// Multiply it back up
fahrenheit = multiply_16x8r16(fahrenheit, 10);

// Factor remainder
remainder = multiply_16x8r16(remainder, 10);

// Divide and add remainder
fahrenheit += divide_16x8r8(remainder, 50, NULL);

if (is_negative)
{   // Make it negative again, if it was previously
    is_negative = 1;
}

// Add 32. Requires a 16-bit add with wrap around to
// correctly handle negative temperatures
fahrenheit += 320</code></pre>



<p>While that does the job, it’s poo poo. What I really want is that complicated looking divide routine to have a 16-bit quotient, so I can do the division in a single operation. To help me understand it, I translated it to C code:</p>



<pre><code>uint8_t mcs48_divide(uint16_t dividend, uint8_t divisor, uint8_t *remainder)
{
    if ((dividend &gt;&gt; 8) &gt;= divisor)
        goto mcs48_div_exit; // Impossible. Result would
                             // overflow. Bail.

    for (int i = 0; i &lt; 8; i++) // One pass for each bit of result
    {
        uint8_t msb;
        uint8_t bit15_was_set = 0;

        if (dividend &amp; 0x8000)
            bit15_was_set = 1; // Note if this was set,

        dividend &lt;&lt;= 1; // Next bit

        msb = (dividend &gt;&gt; 8);
        if (msb &gt;= divisor || bit15_was_set)
        {
            // Subtract remainder from MSB,
            // preserve and increment quotient
            dividend = (((msb - divisor) &lt;&lt; 8) | (dividend &amp; 0xFF)) + 1;
        }
    }

mcs48_div_exit:
    *remainder = (dividend &gt;&gt; 8);
    return (dividend &amp; 0xFF);
}</code></pre>



<p>It’s immediately clear that it’s a <a href="https://www.wikihow.com/Divide-Binary-Numbers">binary division</a> implementation. What wasn’t immediately clear is how to make the change I wanted. I put the question to <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/64544654/can-anyone-figure-out-how-to-extend-this-software-divide-routine-to-have-a-16-bi/64549557#64549557">stack overflow</a>, and on the face of it, it looked like a dumb question, i.e. just double the integer type sizes, <em>stupid</em>. predictably I got punished with a bunch of down-votes.</p>



<p>Yes we can do that, but it’s not what I want to do to the assembly routine that I’m trying to modify, so perhaps I didn’t quite ask the question as well as I could have done. The answer provided sent me in the right direction, in that the working accumulator needs to be larger, 24-bits in my case, and the 16-bit shift needs to be a 24-bit.</p>



<pre><code>uint16_t mcs48_div16(uint16_t dividend, uint8_t divisor, uint8_t *remainder)
{
    uint32_t accumulator = dividend;

    for (int i = 0; i &lt; 16; i++) // One pass for each bit of result
    {
        uint8_t msb;
        uint8_t bit24_was_set = 0;

        if (accumulator &amp; 0x800000)
            bit24_was_set = 1; // Note if this was set,
                               // can't check if after shift.

        accumulator &lt;&lt;= 1; // Next bit
        accumulator &amp;= 0xFFFFFF; // Simulate 24 bit type

        msb = (accumulator &gt;&gt; 16);
        if (msb &gt;= divisor || bit24_was_set)
        {
            // Subtract remainder from MSB,
            // preserve and increment quotient
            accumulator = (((msb - divisor) &lt;&lt; 16) | (accumulator &amp; 0xFFFF)) + 1;
        }
    }

mcs48_div_ext_exit:
    *remainder = (accumulator &gt;&gt; 16);
    return (accumulator &amp; 0xFFFF);
}</code></pre>



<p>Above is the pseudo code of my routine after the changes. In the final implementation registers A, R1 and R2 hold the 24-bit accumulator, so this doesn’t translate too well to C because there isn’t a 24-bit integer type.</p>



<p>The final changes to the routine can be viewed <a href="https://github.com/inaxeon/mcs48temp/compare/e006467..a531d32">here</a>.</p>



<p>Ah, that’s better.</p>
	</div><!-- .entry-content -->
	
	</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://tech.mattmillman.com/mcs-48-the-quest-for-16-bit-division-on-the-8-bit-cpu-which-cant-divide-anything/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24941189</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 11:39:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Awk: `Begin { ` Part 1]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 215 | Comments 101 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24940661">thread link</a>) | @quyleanh
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://jemma.dev/blog/awk-part-1 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://jemma.dev/blog/awk-part-1">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>The other day, I was watching Bryan Cantrill’s 2018 talk, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2wZ1pCpJUIM">Rust, and Other Interesting Things</a>, and he made an offhanded comment while discussing values of different programming languages and communities. He said, “If you get the <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/gawk/manual/gawk.html">awk programming language manual</a>…you’ll read it in about two hours and then you’re done. That’s it. You know all of awk.”</p>

<p>Only two hours to learn an entire language?! …. Challenge accepted!</p>

<p>I had previously used snippets of awk here and there. Most of them were given to me by Stack Overflow answers when googling for niche data file manipulations. But, I did not know enough to successfully write an awk program from scratch. I definitely did not have a real grasp on the language nor its power. And, a couple of hours sounded like a relatively small time investment to learn what Bryan Cantrill said was a language he used three times a day.</p>

<p>It turns out it takes more than two hours to learn awk, and I am by no means an expert… yet (growth mindset!). But, I now know enough to write a little about the essentials. Here goes!</p>

<h3 id="what-is-awk-useful-for">What is awk useful for?</h3>

<p>Awk is useful for data file manipulation. Already, having used it for a few days only, I wish I had invested time in learning it earlier. My usual workflow when encountering a data file is to import it into Google Sheets and use their builtin functions. If those weren’t enough, I would write little code snippets to somewhat awk..wardly get the information I want. Awk is way more powerful than what I was doing before. Let’s take a look:</p>

<h3 id="running-awk-programs">Running awk programs</h3>

<p>If we’re going to learn awk, we need to know how to run an awk program. The syntax to run an awk program in a shell is:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>'awk_program_contents'</span> data-file-1 data-file-2
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>We can also write a longer awk program to run instead of writing the awk code inline. We could write a file with awk codeand then pass inline to awk with <code>-f &lt;awk-program-filename&gt;</code></p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>-f</span> awk-program.awk data-file-1 data-file-2
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="awk-program-contents">awk program contents</h3>

<p>Well, what is an awk program? We know it is best used for simple data reformatting or manipulation. The way it does this is by performing different actions on different patterns within a data file. The basic syntax of an awk program depends on these pattern and actions.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>pattern <span>{</span> action <span>}</span>
pattern <span>{</span> action <span>}</span>
...
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We can give as many <code>pattern { action }</code> pairs as we want. Each pair will be executed independently of the others. This means if a line matches more than one pattern, it will have more than one corresponding action. In the example above we use newlines to separate distinct pairs. Similar to bash, we can also use <code>;</code> to separate commands and put everything on one line: <code>pattern { action }; pattern { action }</code></p>

<h3 id="awk-with-data-files">awk with data files</h3>

<p>But, it turns out awk is much more useful (and fun!) with a data file. The UN has a few <a href="https://data.un.org/">publicly available datasets</a>. I picked <a href="https://data.un.org/_Docs/SYB/CSV/SYB62_309_201906_Education.csv">this one</a> on education at the primary, secondary and tertiary levels to delve into first.</p>

<p>Let’s start by using awk to get a sense of what the data looks like.  <code>NR</code> is a predefined variable which records the number of rows read in a file so far. We can use it to look at the first few lines of a program. In this case, our pattern will be <code>NR &lt;= 5</code>, and by not including an action, the implied action will be <code>print</code>:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>'NR &lt;= 5'</span> education.csv
T07,<span>"Enrolment in primary, secondary and tertiary education levels"</span>,,,,,
Region/Country/Area,,Year,Series,Value,Footnotes,Source
1,<span>"Total, all countries or areas"</span>,2005,Students enrolled <span>in </span>primary education <span>(</span>thousands<span>)</span>,<span>"678,991.6070"</span>,,<span>"United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), Montreal, the UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) statistics database, last accessed March 2019."</span>
1,<span>"Total, all countries or areas"</span>,2005,Gross enrollement ratio - Primary <span>(</span>male<span>)</span>,104.9360,,<span>"United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), Montreal, the UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) statistics database, last accessed March 2019."</span>
1,<span>"Total, all countries or areas"</span>,2005,Gross enrollment ratio - Primary <span>(</span>female<span>)</span>,99.9214,,<span>"United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), Montreal, the UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) statistics database, last accessed March 2019."</span>
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Okay, so looks like this is giving us a bit of information about our file. Notably:</p>
<ol>
  <li>There are two header rows: a title row, and a row telling us what the fields are</li>
  <li>The file is comma separated</li>
  <li>… except there are sometimes commas within double quoted strings: <code>"Total, all countries or areas"</code></li>
</ol>

<p>Let’s address these one by one!</p>



<p>We can ignore the first two header rows by using our nifty <code>NR</code> moving forward. We can pattern match that <code>NR &gt; 2</code>. Note: awk is 1-indexed.</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>'NR &gt; 2'</span> education.csv
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="field-separators">Field Separators</h3>

<p>awk’s <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/gawk/manual/gawk.html#Default-Field-Splitting">default field separator</a> is a space. We can actually see this by printing the first field. To access the value of a field, we use <code>$&lt;field_index&gt;</code>. So <code>$1</code> is the first field, <code>$2</code> the second, and so on. <code>$0</code> refers to the entire row.</p>

<p>If we try this:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>'NR &lt;= 5 { print $1 }'</span> education.csv
T07,<span>"Enrolment
Region/Country/Area,,Year,Series,Value,Footnotes,Source
1,"</span>Total,
1,<span>"Total,
1,"</span>Total,
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>we can confirm that we’re splitting on spaces. awk has the option to specify a different field separator with the <code>-F 'separator'</code> flag:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>-F</span> <span>','</span> <span>'NR &lt;= 5 { print $1 }'</span> education.csv
T07
Region/Country/Area
1
1
1
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Great! But…. we had commas embedded within strings with double quotes. Sure enough, if we print the second field (<code>$2</code>), we see:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>-F</span> <span>','</span> <span>'NR &lt;= 5 { print $2 }'</span> education.csv
<span>"Enrolment in primary

"</span>Total
<span>"Total
"</span>Total
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Hmmm. What we want here is to split fields by <em>content</em>. Which awk does not have, but gawk (GNU awk) does: <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/gawk/manual/gawk.html#Splitting-By-Content">FPAT</a>! From the gawk manual: “All properly written awk programs should work with gawk. So most of the time, we don’t distinguish between gawk and other awk implementations.”</p>

<p>Sounds like we can use gawk here instead then. Let’s try pattern matching. I’m not going to go into regex here, but the pattern we want, defined by <code>"[^,]*|\"[^\"]+\""</code> is anything that either starts with a non-comma character, or starts with a double quote, contains only non-quote characters, and ends with a double quote:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span>gawk <span>'BEGIN { FPAT = "[^,]*|\"[^\"]+\"" } NR &lt;= 5 { print $2 }'</span> education.csv
<span>"Enrolment in primary, secondary and tertiary education levels"</span>

<span>"Total, all countries or areas"</span>
<span>"Total, all countries or areas"</span>
<span>"Total, all countries or areas"</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I snuck a <code>BEGIN</code> in there without explaining it. Let’s go on a brief tangent…</p>

<h3 id="begin--tangent-">BEGIN { tangent }</h3>

<p>Beyond the pattern and actions, awk also has a concept of <code>BEGIN</code> and <code>END</code> blocks. The <code>BEGIN</code> is executed before any of the data is processed. It can be useful for declaring variables or printing text to appear at the beginning. Analogously, the <code>END</code> is executed after the data is processed. It can be useful for performing manipulations on aggregates of the data, like averaging a sum.</p>

<p>This means if we wanted to write a little “Hello, awk!” program, we could do it without even needing a data file.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>'BEGIN { print "Hello, awk!" }'</span>
Hello, <span>awk</span><span>!</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="end--tangent-">END { tangent }</h3>

<p>…back to our example. In our case, we used a <code>BEGIN</code> block to declare the <code>FPAT</code> <em>before</em> reading our data file.</p>

<p>But, we’ve only looked at the first 5 lines. For all we know, the rest of the file could look completely different. Let’s use <code>NR</code> again to see some more of the file. First, let’s figure out how long the file is. We can use the <code>END</code> block here. After we’ve parsed the whole file, we can see what the value of <code>NR</code> is, and that’ll tell us how many lines it is:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>'END { print NR }'</span> education.csv
8630
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Okay, so maybe if we print every 500 lines, we’ll get a sense of what data we’re looking at. We can set our pattern to be only if <code>NR</code> is a multiple of <code>500</code>:</p>
<div><div><pre><code><span>$ </span><span>awk</span> <span>'NR % 500 == 0'</span> education.csv
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>… and I’m going to leave this blog post on a real cliff hanger. Mostly because it already feels too long! There’s <a href="https://jemma.dev/blog/awk-part-2">a second post</a> about awk actually looking at the data and manipulating it to figure out which countries have stark differences in number of males and females that they educate.</p>

<h3 id="tldr-or-tlskimmed-far-enough-to-get-here-please-give-me-the-shorter-version">TL;DR or TL;Skimmed far enough to get here, please give me the shorter version:</h3>
<p>To rehash what we’ve learned about awk:</p>
<ul>
  <li>awk is run using <code>awk 'awk_program' data-file</code></li>
  <li>awk programs have the form <code>pattern { action }; pattern { action };</code></li>
  <li><code>BEGIN</code> blocks are executed before reading data files</li>
  <li><code>END</code> blocks are executed after reading data files</li>
  <li><code>NR</code> is a variable that tells us the number of rows read</li>
  <li><code>-F '&lt;separator&gt;'</code> is how we can define a field separator for a file</li>
  <li>Space is the default field separator</li>
  <li><code>FPAT="..."</code> is a way to use regex to define a pattern for each field</li>
  <li><code>FPAT</code> is only defined in gawk</li>
</ul>


  </div>
</article>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://jemma.dev/blog/awk-part-1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24940661</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 09:51:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: Backtest Trading Strategies: A Quantopian Alternative]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 30 | Comments 11 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24940644">thread link</a>) | @hydershykh
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://www.tradytics.com/backtester | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.tradytics.com/backtester">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

        <div>
          <p>
            <h4>Trading Strategies Backtester</h4>
            <h5>Backtest your favorite technical analysis based strategies with our backtester.</h5>
          </p>
          
        </div>

        <div>
          

          <div>
            <div>
              <p>
                <h5>Buy Strategy</h5>
              </p>
              <div>
                <div>
                  
                  <div aria-labelledby="dropdownMenuButtonBuy">
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta('RSI')">RSI</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta('CCI')">CCI</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta('MFI')">MFI</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta('MACD')">MACD</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta('ATR')">ATR</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta('ADX')">ADX</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta('STOCHS')">STOCHS</p>
                  </div>
                </div>
                
                
                </div>
              <div>
                <h6>Pre-made</h6>
                <div>
                  <div aria-labelledby="dropdownMenuButtonPremade">
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA9 > EMA20')">9EMA &gt; 20EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA20 > EMA50')">20EMA &gt; 50EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA9 < EMA20')">9EMA &lt; 20EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA20 < EMA50')">20EMA &lt; 50EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA20 > Price')">20EMA &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA50 > Price')">50EMA &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA20 < Price')">20EMA &lt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('EMA50 < Price')">50EMA &lt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('obv_slope > 0')">Pos OBV Slope</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('obv_slope < 0')">Neg OBV Slope</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('VWAP > Price')">VWAP &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('VWAP < Price')">VWAP &lt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('SIGNAL > MACD')">Signal &gt; MACD</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('SIGNAL < MACD')">Signal &lt; MACD</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('hband > Price')">UpperBollinger &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy('lband < Price')">LowerBollinger &lt; Price</p>
                    <!--<p class="dropdown-item" onclick="make_current_strategy('At Support')">At Support</p>
                    <p class="dropdown-item" onclick="make_current_strategy('At Resistance')">At Resistance</p>-->
                  </div>
                </div>
                </div>
            </div>
          </div>



          <div>
            <div>
              <p>
                <h5>Sell Strategy</h5>
              </p>
              <div>
                <div>
                  
                  <div aria-labelledby="dropdownMenuButtonSell">
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta_sell('RSI')">RSI</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta_sell('CCI')">CCI</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta_sell('MFI')">MFI</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta_sell('MACD')">MACD</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta_sell('ATR')">ATR</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta_sell('ADX')">ADX</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_ta_sell('STOCHS')">STOCHS</p>
                  </div>
                </div>
                
                
                </div>
              <div>
                <h6>Pre-made</h6>
                <div>
                  <div aria-labelledby="dropdownMenuButtonPremadeSell">
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA9 > EMA20')">9EMA &gt; 20EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA20 > EMA50')">20EMA &gt; 50EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA9 < EMA20')">9EMA &lt; 20EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA20 < EMA50')">20EMA &lt; 50EMA</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA20 > Price')">20EMA &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA50 > Price')">50EMA &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA20 < Price')">20EMA &lt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('EMA50 < Price')">50EMA &lt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('obv_slope > 0')">Pos OBV Slope</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('obv_slope < 0')">Neg OBV Slope</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('VWAP > Price')">VWAP &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('VWAP < Price')">VWAP &lt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('SIGNAL > MACD')">Signal &gt; MACD</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('SIGNAL < MACD')">Signal &lt; MACD</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('hband > Price')">UpperBollinger &gt; Price</p>
                    <p onclick="make_current_strategy_sell('lband < Price')">LowerBollinger &lt; Price</p>
                  </div>
                </div>
                </div>
            </div>
          </div>
          
          
        </div> <!-- row -->


         <!-- row -->

         <!-- row -->

         <!-- row -->

        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div>
                <p>
                  <h6><i data-feather="activity"></i> Win Rate</h6>
                </p>
                <p>Win rate of this strategy.</p>
                
                
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div>
                <p>
                  <h6><i data-feather="corner-right-down"></i> Biggest Drawdown</h6>
                </p>
                <p>Highest loss incurred in a trade.</p>
                
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div>
                <p>
                  <h6><i data-feather="navigation-2"></i> Biggest Win</h6>
                </p>
                <p>Highest profit gained in a trade.</p>
                
              </div>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div> <!-- row -->


        <div>
          <div>
            <div>
              <div>
                <p>
                  <h6><i data-feather="arrow-up"></i> Long Only</h6>
                </p>
                <p>Profits and losses from long positions.</p>
                
              </div> 
            </div>
          </div>

          <div>
            <div>
              <div>
                <p>
                  <h6><i data-feather="arrow-down"></i> Short Only</h6>
                </p>
                <p>Profits and losses from short positions.</p>
                
              </div> 
            </div>
          </div>
        </div> <!-- row -->

        
        

      </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.tradytics.com/backtester</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24940644</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 09:48:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Java Concurrency – Understanding the Basics of Threads]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 134 | Comments 69 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24940545">thread link</a>) | @turkogluc
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://turkogluc.com/java-concurrency-basics-of-threads/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://turkogluc.com/java-concurrency-basics-of-threads/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                
                <p>Java <code>Thread</code> objects allow us to run our code in separate threads. When an application starts JVM creates the initial thread named <code>main</code>. The main method is run on the main thread. Inside the application we can create new threads to execute other tasks in parallel with the main thread.</p><p>Java uses native operating system threads. So one java thread is mapped by one OS thread.</p><h3 id="creating-threads">Creating Threads</h3><p>The constructor of the <code>Thread</code> class takes a <code>Runnable</code> object. Runnable interface has an abstract <code>run</code> method which is called by <code>Thread#start()</code> method. It object can be instantiated by a lambda, anonymous class or a class which implements Runnable method. </p><figure><img src="https://turkogluc.com/content/images/2020/10/Screenshot-2020-10-29-at-20.03.52.png"></figure><p>Using lambdas are generally easier and more compact:</p><pre><code>Thread thread = new Thread(() -&gt; {
    // content of run command
});
thread.start();</code></pre><p>Thread lives as long as the its run hook method has not returned. The scheduler can suspend and run the Thread many times. For a thread to execute forever, it needs an infinite loop that prevents it from returning. </p><p><code>Join</code> method allows one thread to wait for the completion of another. This is a simple form of barrier synchronisation.</p><figure><img src="https://turkogluc.com/content/images/2020/10/Screenshot-2020-10-29-at-20.19.19.png"></figure><h3 id="java-thread-types-user-and-daemon-threads">Java Thread Types: User and Daemon Threads</h3><p>When JVM start it contains a single User thread, named Main thread. The main difference between User and Daemon threads are what happens when they exit.</p><ul><li>A user thread continues its lifecycle even if the main thread exits.</li><li>However all Daemon threads terminates when all the user threads exits.</li><li>JVM itself exits when all the user threads has exited.</li></ul><p>Thread class contains boolean <code>daemon</code> field to specify whether the thread is daemon. It can be set at the time of creation by the constructor or by setter method.</p><pre><code>Thread thread = new Thread(getRunnable());
thread.setDaemon(true);
thread.start();</code></pre><p>By default daemon field is false, so most of the Threads that we generate is a User Thread. Threads copy the <code>isDaemon</code> status of the parent threat if it is not specified. Java uses Daemon thread in some places such as <code>ForkJoinPool</code> and <code>Timer</code>. To illustrate we can use the following example:</p><pre><code>public class Main {

    public static void main(String[] args) throws InterruptedException, ExecutionException {
//        runDeamonThread();
        runUserThread();
        System.out.println(getCurrentThreadName() + " exits");
    }

    private static void runDeamonThread() throws ExecutionException, InterruptedException {
        ExecutorService executorService = Executors.newWorkStealingPool(10);
        executorService.execute(getRunnable());
    }

    private static void runUserThread() {
        Thread thread = new Thread(getRunnable());
        thread.start();
    }

    private static Runnable getRunnable() {
        return () -&gt; {
            for (int i = 0; i &lt;= 200; i++) {
                System.out.print(".");
                Thread.yield();
            }
            System.out.println(getCurrentThreadName() + " exits. isDeamon: " + isDaemon());
        };
    }

    private static boolean isDaemon() {
        return Thread.currentThread().isDaemon();
    }

    private static String getCurrentThreadName() {
        return Thread.currentThread().getName();
    }
}</code></pre><ul><li>When we invoke <code>runUserThread</code> method it show the following example output:</li></ul><pre><code>................................................
main exits
........................................................................................
Thread-0 exits. isDeamon: false</code></pre><ul><li>The second case is invoking the <code>runDeamonThread</code> which uses <code>ForkJoinPool</code> as an example of Daemon Threads. I could simply use <code>setDaemon(true)</code> method, but wanted to give an example usage. Output:</li></ul><pre><code>main exits</code></pre><p>So when the main method exits, all the user threads are terminated and JVM exits and kills all daemon threads, so that we did not even have a chance to see output from daemon threads.</p><h3 id="stopping-threads">Stopping Threads</h3><p>Compared to creating, stopping a thread is quite hard thing. Once thread starts running it diverges from the caller and it has it is own lifecycle anymore. It can either complete the task and exits or if it does a long running operation it can work forever. Java does not provides us a method (non-deprecated) to stop the thread voluntarily. </p><ol><li>A naive approach could be using a stop flag:</li></ol><pre><code>volatile boolean isStopped = false;

public void test() {
    new Thread(() -&gt; {
        while (!isStopped) {
            System.out.print(".");
        }
        System.out.println("Child Exits");
    }).start();

    try {
        Thread.sleep(100);
    } catch (InterruptedException e) {
        e.printStackTrace();
    }
    isStopped = true;
    System.out.println("Main exits");
}</code></pre><p>Note that the flag is <code>volatile</code> in order to make its up-to-date value visible for both threads. However this approach fails if the thread is doing blocking operations such as <code>sleep</code>, <code>wait</code>, <code>join</code> or blocking I/O operations.</p><p>2. Another way to stop the tread is to use <code>interrupt()</code> method of the thread. </p><blockquote>An interrupt request to a thread is an indication that it should stop what it is doing and do something else. It is up to the programmer to decide exactly how a thread responds to an interrupt but it is very common for the tread to terminate.</blockquote><p>For the interrupt mechanism to work correctly, the interrupted thread must support its own interruption mechanism. There are 2 cases we can examine for interruption:</p><ul><li>Non Blocking and Long Running Tasks</li></ul><p>In this case calling the <code>thread.interrupt()</code> method will set the interrupt flag of the that thread but if the task itself does not check the status of the interrupted flag it will not have any impact. For example:</p><pre><code>public void test() throws InterruptedException {
    Thread thread = new Thread(() -&gt; {
        System.out.println("Child Starts");
        while (true) {
            System.out.print(".");
        }
    });

    thread.start();
    thread.interrupt();
    
    thread.join();
    System.out.println("Main exits");
}</code></pre><p>In order for the thread to catch the interrupt, it should iteratively check the status of the interrupt flag so that it can understand if there are any pending interruption request and handle the request accordingly. </p><p>So we can check the flag in our while loop in if it is true we can return or break the loop. In the lambda expression it is not possible to throw an exception but in appropriate places we can throw <code>InterruptedException</code> as well.</p><pre><code>public void test() throws InterruptedException {
    Thread thread = new Thread(() -&gt; {
        System.out.println("Child Starts");
        while (true) {
            if (Thread.interrupted()) {
                break;
            }
            System.out.print(".");
        }
        System.out.println("Child exits");
    });

    thread.start();
    thread.interrupt();

    thread.join();
    System.out.println("Main exits");
}</code></pre><p>Note the <code>Thread.interrupted()</code> method returns the value of the flag and clears it if it has been true. So if we want to keep the state of the Thread as interrupted for the upper level of stack, we can set it back with <code>Thread.currentThread().interrupt();</code> </p><ul><li>Blocking Tasks</li></ul><p>If a thread frequently calls the blocking methods such as <code>wait</code>, <code>join</code>, <code>sleep</code>, <code>blocking I/O</code> which are all run interruptively, these methods internally check if they have been interrupted and if so they automatically throw <code>InterruptedException</code>. This exception should be caught and handled in the appropriate context. The following example uses the interruption to break the loop in a blocking <code>sleep</code> operation:</p><pre><code>public void test() throws InterruptedException {
    Thread thread = new Thread(() -&gt; {
        System.out.println("Child Starts");
        try {
            while (true) {
                Thread.sleep(10000);
            }
        } catch (InterruptedException e) {
            System.out.println("Thread interrupted: " + e.getMessage());
        }
        System.out.println("Child Exits");
    });

    thread.start();
    thread.interrupt();

    thread.join();
    System.out.println("Main exits");
}</code></pre><p>There are patterns for dealing with Java <code>InterruptedException</code>:</p><ul><li>One approach is propagating the exception to the callers, so higher layer would be responsible.</li><li>Before re-throwing, we can do task specific clean up.</li><li>If it is not possible to re-throw, we can set the interrupted status to true again with <code>Thread.currentThread().interrupt()</code> to preserve the evidence if the higher layers want to check it.</li></ul><p>So as a conclusion if we want to implement cancellable tasks we need to periodically check the status of the interrupt status and handle the interruption in a way that thread will exit.</p><h3 id="thread-groups">Thread Groups</h3><p>In order to simplify thread management, multiple threads &nbsp;can be organised with <code>java.lang.ThreadGroup</code> objects that group related threads. Each Thread Group needs to have a parent group. In the hierarchy, there is the <code>Main</code> group which is the parent of the other groups or threads we create in the program. We can create <code>ThreadGroup</code> by calling its constructor with a parent group and/or name. To add the Threads in a group we need to specify the group in the Thread's constructor.</p><pre><code>public void test() {
    ThreadGroup tg1 = new ThreadGroup("Thread-group-1");
    ThreadGroup tg2 = new ThreadGroup(tg1, "Thread-group-2");

    Thread thread1 = new Thread(tg1,"thread-1");
    Thread thread2 = new Thread(tg2,"thread-2");
    Thread thread3 = new Thread(tg2,"thread-3");

    thread1.start();
    thread2.start();
    thread3.start();
    
    Thread[] threads = new Thread[tg2.activeCount()];
    tg2.enumerate(threads);

    Arrays.asList(threads).forEach(t -&gt; System.out.println(t.getName()));
    tg1.list();
}</code></pre><p>We can iterate over the threads by calling the <code>enumerate</code> method, which fills the given array with the thread references of the group.</p><p>We can implement a Thread Pool by making use of Thread Groups:</p><pre><code>public class ThreadPool {
    // Create a thread group field
    private final ThreadGroup group = new ThreadGroup("ThreadPoolGroup");
    // Create a LinkedList field containing Runnable
    private final List&lt;Runnable&gt; tasks = new LinkedList&lt;&gt;();

    public ThreadPool(int poolSize) {
   …</code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://turkogluc.com/java-concurrency-basics-of-threads/">https://turkogluc.com/java-concurrency-basics-of-threads/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://turkogluc.com/java-concurrency-basics-of-threads/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24940545</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 09:32:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[For Complex Applications, Rust Is as Productive as Kotlin]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 79 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24939875">thread link</a>) | @quyleanh
<br/>
October 30, 2020 | https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/rust-as-productive-as-kotlin/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/rust-as-productive-as-kotlin/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div id="preamble">
<div>
<p>In this article, we will compare one apple (IntelliJ Rust) to one orange (rust-analyzer) to reach general and sweeping conclusions.
Specifically, I want to present a case study supporting the following claim:</p>
<p>For complex applications, Rust is as productive as Kotlin.</p>
<p>For me, this is an unusual claim to argue: I always thought exactly the opposite, but I am not so sure now.
I came to Rust from C++.
I was of the opinion that this is a brilliant low-level language and always felt puzzled at people writing higher-level things in Rust.
Clearly, choosing Rust means taking a productivity hit, and using Kotlin, C# or Go just makes much more sense if you can afford GC.
My <a href="https://matklad.github.io/2020/09/20/why-not-rust.html">list of Rust criticisms</a> starts with this objection.</p>
<p>What moved my position in the other direction was my experience as the lead developer of rust-analyzer and IntelliJ Rust.
Let me introduce the two projects.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/intellij-rust/intellij-rust"><strong>IntelliJ Rust</strong></a> is the plugin for IntelliJ Platform, providing Rust support.
In effect, it is a Rust compiler front-end, written in Kotlin and making use of language-support features of the platform.
These features include lossless syntax trees, a parser generator, persistence and indexing infrastructure, among others.
Nonetheless, as programming languages differ lot, the bulk of logic for analyzing Rust is implemented in the plugin itself.
Presentational features like completion list come from the platform, but most of the language semantics is hand-written.
IntelliJ Rust also includes a bit of a Swing GUI.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/rust-analyzer/rust-analyzer"><strong>rust-analyzer</strong></a> is an implementation of
<a href="https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/">Language Server Protocol</a> for Rust.
It is a Rust compiler front-end written from scratch with an eye towards IDE support.
It makes heavy use of <a href="https://github.com/salsa-rs/salsa">salsa</a> library for incremental computations.
Beyond the compiler itself, rust-analyzer includes code for managing long-lived multithreaded process of the language server itself.</p>
<p>The projects are essentially equivalent in scope — rust compiler front-ends suitable for IDEs.
The two biggest differences are:</p>
<div>
<ul>
<li>
<p>IntelliJ Rust is a plugin, so it can re-use code and design patterns of the surrounding platform.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>rust-analyzer is the second system, so it leverages experience of IntelliJ Rust for a from-scratch design.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>The internal architecture of the two projects also differs a lot.
In terms of <a href="https://rust-analyzer.github.io/blog/2020/07/20/three-architectures-for-responsive-ide.html">Three Architectures</a>, IntelliJ Rust is map-reduce, and rust-analyzer is query-based.</p>
<p>Writing an IDE-ready compiler is a high-level task.
You don’t need to talk to the operating system directly.
There are some fancy data structures and concurrency here and there, but they are also high-level.
It’s not about implementing crazy lock-free schemes, it’s about maintaining application state and sanity in the multithreaded world.
The bulk of the compiler is symbolic manipulation, arguably best suited for lisp.
Picking a VM-based language for such task (for example, OCaml), doesn’t have any intrinsic downsides.</p>
<p>At the same time, the task is pretty complex and unique.
The ratio of “your code” vs “framework code” when implementing features is much higher than in a typical CRUD backend.</p>
<p>Now that the projects are introduced, lets take two roughly equivalent slices of history.</p>

<p>Both are about 2 years old, with 1-1.5 developers working full time and vibrant and thriving community of open-source contributors.
There are 52k lines of Kotlin and 66k lines of Rust.</p>
<p>Both delivered roughly equivalent feature sets at that time.
To be honest, I still don’t really believe this :)
rust-analyzer started from zero, it didn’t have a decade worth of Java classes to bootstrap from, and the productivity drop between Kotlin and Rust is supposed to be huge.
But it’s hard to argue with reality.
Instead, let me try to reflect on my experience building both, and to try to explain Rust’s surprising productivity.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h2 id="_learning_curve">Learning Curve</h2>
<div>
<p>It’s easy to characterize Kotlin’s learning curve — it is nearly zero.
I’ve started IntelliJ Rust without Kotlin experience and never felt that I need to specifically learn Kotlin.</p>
<p>When I switched to rust-analyzer, I was pretty experienced with Rust.
I would say that one definitely needs to deliberately learn Rust, it’s hard to pick it up on the go.
Ownership and aliasing control are novel concepts (even if you come from C++), and taking holistic approach to learning them pays off.
After the initial learning step the ride is generally smooth.</p>
<p>By the way, this is the perfect place to plug our Rust courses and tailor-made <a href="https://ferrous-systems.com/training/">trainings</a> :-)
The next <a href="https://ferrous-systems.com/training/#package-intro-training">introduction to Rust</a> is happening this December!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h2 id="_modularity">Modularity</h2>
<div>
<p>This I think is the biggest factor.
Both projects are moderately large in terms of scope as well as in terms of amount of source code.
I believe that the only way to ship big things is to split them in independent-ish chunks and implement the chunks separately.</p>
<p>I also find most of the languages I am familiar with to be pretty horrible with respect to modularity.
More generally, I am amused with FP vs OO debate, as it seems that “why no one does modules right?” is a more salient issue.</p>
<p>Rust is one of the few languages which has first-class concept of libraries.
Rust code is organized on two levels:</p>
<div>
<ul>
<li>
<p>as a tree of inter-dependent modules inside a crate</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>and as a directed acyclic graph of crates</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p>Cyclic dependencies are allowed between the modules, but not between the crates.
Crates are units of reuse and privacy: only crate’s public API matters, and it is crystal clear what crate’s public API is.
Moreover, crates are anonymous, so you don’t get name conflicts and dependency hell when mixing several versions of the same crate in a single crate graph.</p>
<p>This makes it very easy to make two pieces of code <strong>not</strong> depend on each other (non-dependencies are the essence of modularity): just put them in separate crates.
During code review, only changes to Cargo.tomls need to be monitored carefully.</p>
<p>At the time of comparison, rust-analyzer is split into 23 internal crates, with a handful general-purposed ones released on crates.io.
In contrast, IntelliJ Rust is a single Kotlin module, where everything can depend on everything else.
Although internal organization of IntelliJ Rust is pretty clean, it’s not reflected in the file system layout and build system, and needs constant maintenance.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h2 id="_build_system">Build System</h2>
<div>
<p>Managing project’s build takes significant amount of times, and has multiplicative effect on everything else.</p>
<p>Rust’s build system, <a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/cargo/index.html">Cargo</a>, is very good.
It’s not perfect, but it is a breath of fresh air after Java’s <a href="https://gradle.org/">Gradle</a>.</p>
<p>Cargo’s trick is that it doesn’t try to be a general purpose build system.
It can only build Rust projects, and it has rigid expectation about the project structure.
It’s impossible to opt out of the core assumptions.
Configuration is a static non-extensible TOML file.</p>
<p>In contrast, Gradle allows free-form project structure, and is configured via a Turing complete language.
I feel like I’ve spend more time learning Gradle than learning Rust!
Running <code>wc -w</code> gives 182_817 words for Rust book, and 280_506 for Gradle’s user guide.</p>
<p>Additionally, Cargo is just faster than Gradle in most cases.</p>
<p>Of course, the biggest downside is that custom build logic is not expressible in Cargo.
Both projects needs substantial amount of logic beyond mere compilation to deliver the final result to the user.
For rust-analyzer, this is handled by hand-written Rust script, which works perfectly at this scale.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h2 id="_ecosystem">Ecosystem</h2>
<div>
<p>Language-level support for libraries and top-notch build system/package manager allow for a thriving ecosystem.
rust-analyzer relies on third-party libraries much more than IntelliJ Rust.
Some parts of rust-analyzer are also published to crates.io for other projects to reuse.</p>
<p>Additionally, low-level nature of the Rust programming language often allows for “perfect” library interfaces.
Interfaces which exactly reflect the underlying problem, without imposing intermediate language-level abstractions.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<h2 id="_basic_conveniences">Basic Conveniences</h2>
<div>
<p>I feel that Rust is significantly more productive when it comes to basic language nuts and bolts — structs, enums, functions, etc.
This is not specific to Rust — any ML-family language has them.
However, Rust is the first industrial language which wraps these features in a nice package, not constrained by backwards compatibility.
I want to list specific features which I think allow producing maintainable code faster in Rust</p>
<p><em>Emphasis on data over behavior</em>.
Aka, Rust is not an OOP language.
The core idea of OOP is that of dynamic dispatch — which code is invoked by a function call is decided at runtime (late binding).
This is a powerful pattern which allows for flexible and extensible system.
The problem is, extensibility is costly!
It’s better only to apply it in certain designated areas.
Designing for extensibility by default is not cost effective.
Rust puts static dispatch front and center: it is mostly clear whats going on by just reading the code, as it is independent of runtime types of the objects.</p>
<p>One small syntactic thing I enjoy about Rust is how it puts fields and methods into different blocks syntactically:</p>
<div>
<div>
<pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>struct</span> <span>Person</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>first_name</span><span>:</span> <span>String</span><span>,</span>
  <span>last_name</span><span>:</span> <span>String</span><span>,</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>impl</span> <span>Person</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>fn</span> <span>full_name</span><span>(</span><span>&amp;</span><span>self</span><span>)</span> <span>-&gt;</span> <span>String</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>...</span>
    <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<p>Being able to see at a glance all the fields makes understanding the code much simpler.
Fields convey much more information than methods.</p>
<p><em>Sum types</em>.
Rust’s humbly named enums are full algebraic data types.
This means that you can express the idea of disjoint union:</p>
<div>
<div>
<pre><code data-lang="rust"><span>enum</span> <span>Either</span><span>&lt;</span><span>A</span><span>,</span> <span>B</span><span>&gt;</span> <span>{</span> <span>A</span><span>(</span><span>A</span><span>),</span> <span>B</span><span>(</span><span>B</span><span>)</span> <span>}</span></code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<p>This is hugely useful in day-to-day programming in the small, and some times during programming in the large as well.
To give one example, one of the core concepts for an IDE are references and definitions.
A definition a like <code>let foo = 92;</code> assigns a name to an entity which can be used down a line.
A reference like <code>foo + 90</code> <em>refers</em> to some definition.
When you ctrl-click on reference, you go to the definition.</p>
<p>Natural way to model that in Kotlin is by adding <code>interface Definition</code> and <code>interface Reference</code>.
The problem is, some things are …</p></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/rust-as-productive-as-kotlin/">https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/rust-as-productive-as-kotlin/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ferrous-systems.com/blog/rust-as-productive-as-kotlin/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24939875</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 07:10:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Getting Audio Visualizations Working with Web Audio API]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 50 | Comments 15 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24938292">thread link</a>) | @arcatech
<br/>
October 29, 2020 | https://dwayne.xyz/post/audio-visualizations-web-audio-api | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dwayne.xyz/post/audio-visualizations-web-audio-api">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
            <h2>Web Audio API</h2>
<p>I’ve been working on getting WebRTC video chat working here on the website for a few weeks now. I finally got to the point where both text, video chat, and screen sharing all work really well, but somewhere in the back of my mind I kept thinking about complaints about “<a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/brain-waves/202007/why-zoom-fatigue-is-real-and-what-you-can-do-about-it">Zoom fatigue</a>” during the pandemic:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Zoom fatigue, Hall argues now, is real. “Zoom is exhausting and lonely because you have to be so much more attentive and so much more aware of what’s going on than you do on phone calls.” If you haven’t turned off your own camera, you are also watching yourself speak, which can be arousing and disconcerting. The blips, delays and cut off sentences also create confusion. Much more exploration needs to be done, but he says, “maybe this isn’t the solution to our problems that we thought it might have been.” Phone calls, by comparison, are less demanding. “You can be in your own space. You can take a walk, make dinner,” Hall says.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>It’s kind of an interesting thing to have on your mind while spending weeks writing/debugging/testing video chat code.</p>
<p>So I decided to add an audio-only mode. And if I was gonna do that, I had to show something cool in place of the video. So I figured I would try to add audio visualizations when one or both of the users didn’t have video on. Using the relatively recent<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Audio_API">Web Audio API</a> seemed like the right way to go.</p>
<p>Here’s what I came up with:</p>
<div><video controls="" muted="" autoplay="" playsinline="" loop=""><source src="https://media.dwayne.xyz/blog/audio-visualization.mp4" type="video/mp4"></video><p>Screen recording of the local audio visualization. I cycle through bar graph in light mode, bar graph in dark mode, sine wave in dark mode, then sine wave in light mode.</p></div>
<h2>Creating and hooking up an AnalyserNode</h2>
<p>To create audio visualizations, the first thing you’ll need is an <code>AnalyserNode</code>, which you can get from the <code>createAnalyser</code> method of a <code>BaseAudioContext</code>. You can get both of these things pretty easily<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> like this:</p>
<pre><span>1</span><span>const</span> audioContext <span>=</span> <span>new</span> <span>window</span>.AudioContext();
<span>2</span><span>const</span> analyser <span>=</span> audioContext.createAnalyser();
</pre><p>Next, create a <code>MediaStreamAudioSourceNode</code> from an existing data stream (I use either the local or remote data streams from either <code>getUserMedia</code> or from the ‘track’ event of <code>RTCPeerConnection</code> respectively) using <code>AudioContext.createMediaStreamSource</code>. Then you can connect that audio source to the analyser object like this:</p>
<pre><span>1</span><span>const</span> audioSource <span>=</span> <span>this</span>.audioContext.createMediaStreamSource(stream);
<span>2</span>audioSource.connect(analyser);
</pre>
<h2>Using requestAnimationFrame</h2>
<p><code>window.requestAnimationFrame</code> is nice. Call it, passing in your drawing function, and then inside that function call <code>requestAnimationFrame</code> again. Get yourself a nice little recursive loop going that’s automatically timed properly by the browser.</p>
<p>In my situation, there will either be 0, 1, or 2 visualizations running, since either side can choose either video chat, audio-only (…except during screen sharing), or just text chat. So I have one loop that draws both. It looks like this:</p>
<pre><span>1</span><span>const</span> drawAudioVisualizations <span>=</span> () =&gt; {
<span>2</span>    audioCancel <span>=</span> <span>window</span>.requestAnimationFrame(drawAudioVisualizations);
<span>3</span>    localAudioVisualization.draw();
<span>4</span>    remoteAudioVisualization.draw();
<span>5</span>};
</pre><p>I created the class for those visualization objects, and they handle whether or not to draw. They each contain the analyser, source, and context objects for their visualization.</p>
<p>Then when I detect that loop doesn’t have to run anymore, I can cancel it using that <code>audioCancel</code> value:</p>
<pre><span>1</span><span>window</span>.cancelAnimationFrame(audioCancel);
<span>2</span>audioCancel <span>=</span> <span>0</span>;
</pre>
<h2>Configuring the Analyser</h2>
<p>Like in the <a href="https://github.com/mdn/voice-change-o-matic/blob/gh-pages/scripts/app.js">example you’ll see a lot</a> if you look at the MDN documentation for this stuff, I provide options for two audio visualizations: frequency bars and a sine wave. Here’s how I configure the analyser for each type:</p>
<pre><span> 1</span><span>switch</span> (<span>this</span>.type) {
<span> 2</span>    <span>case</span> <span>'frequencybars'</span><span>:</span>
<span> 3</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.minDecibels <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>90</span>;
<span> 4</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.maxDecibels <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>10</span>;
<span> 5</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.smoothingTimeConstant <span>=</span> <span>0.85</span>;
<span> 6</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.fftSize <span>=</span> <span>256</span>;
<span> 7</span>        <span>this</span>.bufferLength <span>=</span> <span>this</span>.analyser.frequencyBinCount;
<span> 8</span>        <span>this</span>.dataArray <span>=</span> <span>new</span> Uint8Array(<span>this</span>.bufferLength);
<span> 9</span>        <span>break</span>;
<span>10</span>    <span>default</span><span>:</span>
<span>11</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.minDecibels <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>90</span>;
<span>12</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.maxDecibels <span>=</span> <span>-</span><span>10</span>;
<span>13</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.smoothingTimeConstant <span>=</span> <span>0.9</span>;
<span>14</span>        <span>this</span>.analyser.fftSize <span>=</span> <span>1024</span>;
<span>15</span>        <span>this</span>.bufferLength <span>=</span> <span>this</span>.analyser.fftSize;
<span>16</span>        <span>this</span>.dataArray <span>=</span> <span>new</span> Uint8Array(<span>this</span>.bufferLength);
<span>17</span>        <span>break</span>;
<span>18</span>}
</pre><div><p>I’ve adjusted these numbers a lot, and I’m gonna keep doing it. A note about <code>fftSize</code> and <code>frequencyBinCount</code>: <code>frequencyBinCount</code> is set right after you set <code>fftSize</code> and it’s usually just half the <code>fftSize</code> value. These values are about the amount of data you want to receive from the main analyser functions I’m about to talk about next. As you can see, they directly control the size of the data array that you’ll use to store the audio data on each draw call.
</p></div>
<h2>Using the Analyser</h2>
<p>On each draw call, depending on the type of visualization, call either <code>getByteFrequencyData</code> or <code>getByteTimeDomainData</code> with the array that was created above, and it’ll be filled with data. Then you run a simple loop over each element and start drawing. Here’s my sine wave code:</p>
<pre><span> 1</span><span>this</span>.analyser.getByteTimeDomainData(<span>this</span>.dataArray);
<span> 2</span><span>this</span>.ctx.lineWidth <span>=</span> <span>2</span>;
<span> 3</span><span>this</span>.ctx.strokeStyle <span>=</span> audioSecondaryStroke;
<span> 4</span>
<span> 5</span><span>this</span>.ctx.beginPath();
<span> 6</span>
<span> 7</span><span>let</span> v, y;
<span> 8</span><span>for</span> (<span>let</span> i <span>=</span> <span>0</span>; i <span>&lt;</span> <span>this</span>.bufferLength; i<span>++</span>) {
<span> 9</span>    v <span>=</span> <span>this</span>.dataArray[i] <span>/</span> <span>128.0</span>;
<span>10</span>    y <span>=</span> v <span>*</span> height <span>/</span> <span>2</span>;
<span>11</span>
<span>12</span>    <span>if</span> (i <span>===</span> <span>0</span>) {
<span>13</span>        <span>this</span>.ctx.moveTo(x, y);
<span>14</span>    } <span>else</span> {
<span>15</span>        <span>this</span>.ctx.lineTo(x, y);
<span>16</span>    }
<span>17</span>
<span>18</span>    x <span>+=</span> width <span>*</span> <span>1.0</span> <span>/</span> <span>this</span>.bufferLength;
<span>19</span>}
<span>20</span>
<span>21</span><span>this</span>.ctx.lineTo(width, height <span>/</span> <span>2</span>);
<span>22</span><span>this</span>.ctx.stroke();
</pre><div><p>The fill and stroke colors are dynamic based on the website color scheme.
</p></div>
<h2>Good ol' Safari</h2>
<p>So I did all of this stuff I just talked about, but for <strong>days</strong> I could <em>not</em> get this to work in Safari. Not because of errors or anything, but because both <code>getByteFrequencyData</code> and <code>getByteTimeDomainData</code> just filled the array with 0s every time. No matter what I did. I was able to get the audio data in Firefox just fine.</p>
<p>So at first, I figured it just didn’t work at all in Safari and I would just have to wait until Apple fixed it. But then I came across <a href="https://mdn.github.io/voice-change-o-matic/">this sample audio project</a> and noticed it worked just fine in Safari.</p>
<div><p>So I studied the code for an hour trying to understand what was different about my code and theirs. I made a lot of changes to my code to make it more like what they were doing. One of the big differences is that they’re connecting the audio source to different audio distortion nodes to actually change the audio. I just want to create a visualization so I wasn’t using any of those objects.
</p></div>
<h3>Audio Distortion Effects</h3>
<p>The <code>BaseAudioContext</code> has a few methods you can use to create audio distortion objects.</p>
<ul>
<li><code>WaveShaperNode</code>: Use <code>BaseAudioContext.createWaveShaper</code> to create a non-linear distortion. You can use a custom function to change the audio data.</li>
<li><code>GainNode</code>: Use <code>BaseAudioContext.createGain</code> to control the overall gain (volume) of the audio.</li>
<li><code>BiquadFilterNode</code>: Use <code>BaseAudioContext.createBiquadFilter</code> to apply some common audio effects.</li>
<li><code>ConvolverNode</code>: Use <code>BaseAudioContext.createConvolver</code> to apply reverb effects to audio.</li>
</ul>
<p>Each one of these objects has a <code>connect</code> function where you pass another context, output, or filter. Each one has a certain number of inputs and outputs. Here’s an example from that sample project of connecting all of them:</p>
<pre><span>1</span>source <span>=</span> audioCtx.createMediaStreamSource(stream);
<span>2</span>source.connect(distortion);
<span>3</span>distortion.connect(biquadFilter);
<span>4</span>biquadFilter.connect(gainNode);
<span>5</span>convolver.connect(gainNode);
<span>6</span>gainNode.connect(analyser);
<span>7</span>analyser.connect(audioCtx.destination);
</pre><p><strong>Note</strong>: Don’t connect to your audio context <code>destination</code> if you’re just trying to create a visualization for a call. The user will hear themselves talking.</p>
<div><p>Anyway, I tried adding these things to my code to see if that would get it working in Safari, but I had no luck.
</p></div>
<h2>Figuring out the Safari issue</h2>
<p>I was starting to get <em>real</em> frustrated trying to figure this out. I was gonna let it go when I thought Safari was just broken (because it usually is), but since I knew it <em>could</em> work in Safari, I couldn’t leave it alone.</p>
<p>Eventually I downloaded the actual HTML and Javascript files from that sample and started removing shit from their code, running it locally and seeing if it worked. Which it did. So now I’m editing my own code, and <em>their code</em>, to get them to be pretty much the same. Which I did. And <strong>still</strong> theirs worked and mine didn’t.</p>
<p>Next I just started desperately logging every single object at different points in my code to figure out what the fuck was going on. Then I noticed something.</p>
<div><p><img src="https://media.dwayne.xyz/blog/audio-context-suspended.png" alt="Dev console showing the output of logging this.audioContext. The state attribute is shown as suspended"></p><p>Output of logging the audio context object.</p></div>
<p>The <code>state</code> is “suspended”? Why? I don’t know. I did the same log in the sample code (that I had downloaded and was running on my machine) and it was “running”.</p>
<p>This is the code that fixes it:</p>
<pre><span>1</span><span>this</span>.audioSource <span>=</span> <span>this</span>.audioContext.createMediaStreamSource(<span>this</span>.stream);
<span>2</span><span>this</span>.audioSource.connect(<span>this</span>.analyser);
<span>3</span><span>this</span>.audioContext.resume(); <span>// Why??????
</span></pre><div><p>Calling <code>resume</code> changes the state and then everything works. To this day I still don’t know why the sample code didn’t need that line.
</p></div>
<h2>Drawing the image and supporting light/dark modes</h2>
<p>Like everything else on my site, all of this must support different color schemes (and screen sizes, and mobile devices). That was surprisingly difficult when trying to draw an SVG on the canvas.</p>
<p>I’m using <a href="https://fontawesome.com/">FontAwesome</a> for all my icons on the site. I wanted to use one of them for these visualizations. The FontAwesome files are all SVGs (which is great), but I didn’t know how to draw the image in different colors in Javascript. The way I decided to do this was to load the SVG file into a Javascript <code>Image</code> object, then draw that onto the canvas each draw call.</p>
<p>That worked, but it only drew it black even after changing the fill and stroke colors. So after some web searching I read about someone deciding to draw out an image on an offscreen canvas, reading all the image data, and …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://dwayne.xyz/post/audio-visualizations-web-audio-api">https://dwayne.xyz/post/audio-visualizations-web-audio-api</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dwayne.xyz/post/audio-visualizations-web-audio-api</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24938292</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 01:55:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Vega-Lite: A Grammar of Interactive Graphics]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 227 | Comments 50 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24937954">thread link</a>) | @tosh
<br/>
October 29, 2020 | https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <section>
    <p>
  <strong>Vega-Lite</strong> is a high-level grammar of interactive graphics. It provides a concise, declarative JSON syntax to create an expressive range of visualizations for data analysis and presentation.
</p>

<p><span>
  <span>
    Vega-Lite specifications describe visualizations as encoding mappings from data to <strong>properties of graphical marks</strong> (e.g., points or bars).
    The Vega-Lite compiler <strong>automatically produces visualization components</strong> including axes, legends, and scales.
    It determines default properties of these components based on a set of <strong>carefully designed rules</strong>.
    This approach allows Vega-Lite specifications to be concise for quick visualization authoring, while giving user control to override defaults and customize various parts of a visualization.
    As we also designed Vega-Lite to support data analysis, Vega-Lite supports both <strong>data transformations</strong> (e.g., aggregation, binning, filtering, sorting) and <strong>visual transformations</strong> (e.g., stacking and faceting).
    Moreover, Vega-Lite specifications can be <strong>composed</strong> into layered and multi-view displays, and made <strong>interactive with selections</strong>.
  </span>
  <span>
  <a href="https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/tutorials/getting_started.html">Get started<br><small>Latest Version: 4.17.0</small></a>
  <a href="https://vega.github.io/editor/#/custom/vega-lite">Try online</a>
  </span>
</span></p>

<p>Compared to <a href="https://vega.github.io/vega">Vega</a>, Vega-Lite provides a more concise and convenient form to author common visualizations. As Vega-Lite can compile its specifications to Vega specifications, users may use Vega-Lite as the <em>primary</em> visualization tool and, if needed, transition to use the lower-level Vega for advanced use cases.</p>

<p>For more information, read our <a href="https://medium.com/@uwdata/de6661c12d58">introduction article to Vega-Lite v2 on Medium</a>, watch our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9uaHRWj04D4">OpenVis Conf talk about the new features in Vega-Lite v2</a>, see the <a href="https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/docs/">documentation</a> and take a look at our <a href="https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/examples/">example gallery</a>. Follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/vega_vis">Twitter at @vega_vis</a> to stay informed about updates.</p>

<h2 id="example">Example</h2>



<h2 id="additional-links">Additional Links</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Award winning <a href="https://idl.cs.washington.edu/papers/vega-lite">research paper</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9uaHRWj04D4">video of our OpenVis Conf talk</a> on the design of Vega-Lite</li>
  <li>Listen to a Data Stories episode about <a href="http://datastori.es/121-declarative-visualization-with-vega-lite-and-altair-with-dominik-moritz-jacob-vanderplas-kanit-ham-wongsuphasawat/">Declarative Visualization with Vega-Lite and Altair</a>
</li>
  <li>
<a href="http://json-schema.org/">JSON schema</a> specification for <a href="https://github.com/vega/schema">Vega-Lite</a> (<a href="https://vega.github.io/schema/vega-lite/v4.json">latest</a>)</li>
  <li>Ask questions about Vega-Lite on <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/tags/vega-lite">Stack Overflow</a> or <a href="https://bit.ly/join-vega-slack-2020">Slack</a>
</li>
  <li>Fork our <a href="https://bl.ocks.org/domoritz/455e1c7872c4b38a58b90df0c3d7b1b9">Vega-Lite Block</a>, or <a href="https://beta.observablehq.com/@domoritz/vega-lite-demo">Observable Notebook</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="users">Users</h2>

<p>Vega-Lite is used by thousands of data enthusiasts, developers, journalists, data scientists, teachers, and researchers across many organizations. Here are some of them. Learn about integrations on our <a href="https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/ecosystem.html">ecosystem page</a>.</p>



<h2 id="team">Team</h2>

<p>The development of Vega-Lite is led by the alumni and members of the <a href="https://idl.cs.washington.edu/">University of Washington Interactive Data Lab</a> (UW IDL), including <a href="https://twitter.com/kanitw">Kanit “Ham” Wongsuphasawat</a> (now at Apple), <a href="https://twitter.com/domoritz">Dominik Moritz</a> (now at CMU / Apple), <a href="https://twitter.com/arvindsatya1">Arvind Satyanarayan</a> (now at MIT), and <a href="https://twitter.com/jeffrey_heer">Jeffrey Heer</a> (UW IDL).</p>

<p>Vega-Lite gets significant contributions from its community–in particular <a href="https://willium.com/">Will Strimling</a>, <a href="https://github.com/YuhanLu">Yuhan (Zoe) Lu</a>, <a href="https://github.com/invokesus">Souvik Sen</a>, <a href="https://github.com/chanwutk">Chanwut Kittivorawong</a>, <a href="https://github.com/mattwchun">Matthew Chun</a>, <a href="https://github.com/AkshatSh">Akshat Shrivastava</a>, <a href="https://github.com/Saba9">Saba Noorassa</a>, <a href="https://github.com/sirahd">Sira Horradarn</a>, <a href="https://github.com/donghaoren">Donghao Ren</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/haldenl">Halden Lin</a>. Please see the <a href="https://github.com/vega/vega-lite/graphs/contributors">contributors page</a> for the full list of contributors.</p>

  </section>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vega.github.io/vega-lite/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24937954</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:52:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
