<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 1]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 1. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 12:24:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-1.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 12:24:21 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The SF Anthology Problem – Solved]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24130250">thread link</a>) | @sohkamyung
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://classicsofsciencefiction.com/2020/08/09/the-sf-anthology-problem-solved/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://classicsofsciencefiction.com/2020/08/09/the-sf-anthology-problem-solved/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		<p>Two years ago when we completed version 1 of The Classics of Science Fiction Short Story list I <a href="https://auxiliarymemory.com/2018/08/18/the-mathematics-of-buying-science-fiction-anthologies/">proposed a math challenge</a>. Version 1 came up with 275 stories. I asked if there was any mathematically way to decide what were the fewest anthologies that contained all 275 stories using ISFDB.org as a reference database. Version 1 was generated using .csv files. Since then we updated the process to a database for version 2 of the list, which produced 101 stories — we believe that was a more practical reading list.</p>
<p>A science fiction fan could read the entire list over the summer by reading one story a day, or in a year by reading one story every three days, but where would they get the 101 science fiction short stories? It might be possible to track down many stories on the internet, but what if people wanted to read them in a printed book? What would be the minimum number of anthologies to buy to get all the stories? That seem like an fascinating mathematical problem to me.</p>
<p>Well, <a href="https://szymonszott.github.io/">Szymon Szott</a> just <a href="https://github.com/SzymonSzott/science-fiction-anthology-problem">came up with a solution</a> using version 2 of the list. The second link goes to GitHub for Szymon’s Python code and documentation. The first link goes to his bio. Even if you can’t read the programming code you should <a href="https://github.com/SzymonSzott/science-fiction-anthology-problem/blob/master/classics_sf.ipynb">visit this page</a> that explains his solution. Szymon was able to come up with 22 anthologies that collected the 101 stories on the v. 2 of <a href="https://csfquery.com/SearchResult?mincite=8&amp;category=story&amp;sortby=7&amp;list=1">The Classics of Science Fiction Short Stories</a> list.</p>
<p>The photo above pictures eight anthologies that get 81 stories of the version 2 list. Of course, those eight anthologies gets you a lot more than 81 stories. I tried to figure out the solution myself by <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1BcnkixicU-NtvTrBfwX03vqGSAF5yAorMQTnn-Ytq1M/edit?usp=sharing">using a spreadsheet</a> and the best I could do was find fifteen anthologies to cover 81 stories, and then gave up. I figured my eyeballing method might have gotten me to 30-35 anthologies.</p>
<p>Here’s what Szymon says about the project:</p>
<pre>As a fan of science fiction and a compulsive completionist, Worlds Without End is one of my favorite sites on the Internet. It was there that I learned about Jim and Mike's work on the list of classic science fiction novels which I've been eagerly following. When the list of classic science fiction short stories was announced and Jim blogged about <a href="https://auxiliarymemory.com/2018/08/18/the-mathematics-of-buying-science-fiction-anthologies/">The Mathematics of Buying Science Fiction Anthologies</a>, I knew this was an interesting problem to solve. But it wasn't until I started dabbling in Python that I realized that, along with the 2020 travel-restricted summer holidays, I now had the tools to start chipping away at this. Creating a story-to-anthology mapping using data from the Internet Speculative Fiction Database didn't take too long, but the underlying mathematical problem was harder than I initially thought: it turned out that a brute-force approach of checking all possible combinations is unfeasible. Still, the heuristic used has given us a solution which I'm satisfied with and I don't think there exists a much better global solution. I was most surprised that the Science Fiction Hall of Fame series did not make the list (as I've already read volume one). Thank you Jim for this challenge! Now, all this coding was fun, but it's time to get back to reading: Sense of Wonder is next!</pre>
<p>This isn’t an easy problem. Szymon had to screenscrape the table of contents from 290 anthologies from ISFDB.org, which contained one or more of the 101 stories. Just look at <a href="https://github.com/SzymonSzott/science-fiction-anthology-problem/blob/master/main.csv">this listing</a> to see how often each of these stories was reprinted. Towards the end of his programming loops, he had to use eight anthologies to cover eight stories. If all those singletons had been in one anthology, Szymon’s finally anthology list would have been 15. Most of those singletons were newer stories and there haven’t been enough time for them to be collected into a retrospective anthology. One new anthology could shorten Szymon’s final list.</p>
<p>I know many people won’t follow links, so here is Szymon’s program results:</p>
<pre><strong>Sense of Wonder</strong>

- "Arena" by Fredric Brown
- "Bears Discover Fire" by Terry Bisson
- "Black Destroyer" by A. E. van Vogt
- "Blood Music" by Greg Bear
- "Bloodchild" by Octavia E. Butler
- "The Cold Equations" by Tom Godwin
- "The Country of the Kind" by Damon Knight
- "Day Million" by Frederik Pohl
- "First Contact" by Murray Leinster
- "Fondly Fahrenheit" by Alfred Bester
- "The Game of Rat and Dragon" by Cordwainer Smith
- "Hell Is the Absence of God" by Ted Chiang
- "Jeffty Is Five" by Harlan Ellison
- "The Little Black Bag" by C. M. Kornbluth
- "Lobsters" by Charles Stross
- "The Lucky Strike" by Kim Stanley Robinson
- "A Martian Odyssey" by Stanley G. Weinbaum
- "Microcosmic God" by Theodore Sturgeon
- "The Mountains of Mourning" by Lois McMaster Bujold
- "Nightfall" by Isaac Asimov
- "The Only Neat Thing to Do" by James Tiptree, Jr.
- "Or All the Seas with Oysters" by Avram Davidson
- "Passengers" by Robert Silverberg
- "The Persistence of Vision" by John Varley
- "Rachel in Love" by Pat Murphy
- "A Rose for Ecclesiastes" by Roger Zelazny
- "The Sentinel" by Arthur C. Clarke
- "Seven American Nights" by Gene Wolfe
- "Souls" by Joanna Russ
- "Surface Tension" by James Blish
- "That Only a Mother" by Judith Merril
- "Think Like a Dinosaur" by James Patrick Kelly
- "The Ugly Chickens" by Howard Waldrop
- "Who Goes There?" by John W. Campbell, Jr.

Running story total: 34

<strong>The Wesleyan Anthology of Science Fiction</strong>

- ""Repent, Harlequin!" Said the Ticktockman" by Harlan Ellison
- "Air Raid" by John Varley
- "All You Zombies—" by Robert A. Heinlein
- "And I Awoke and Found Me Here on the Cold Hill's Side" by James Tiptree, Jr.
- "Aye, and Gomorrah …" by Samuel R. Delany
- "Burning Chrome" by William Gibson
- "Coming Attraction" by Fritz Leiber
- "Desertion" by Clifford D. Simak
- "Nine Lives" by Ursula K. Le Guin
- "Speech Sounds" by Octavia E. Butler
- "The Star" by H. G. Wells
- "There Will Come Soft Rains" by Ray Bradbury
- "Thunder and Roses" by Theodore Sturgeon
- "We Can Remember It for You Wholesale" by Philip K. Dick
- "When It Changed" by Joanna Russ

Running story total: 49

<strong>Science Fiction: Stories and Contexts</strong>

- "At the Rialto" by Connie Willis
- "Flowers for Algernon" by Daniel Keyes
- "For a Breath I Tarry" by Roger Zelazny
- "The Girl Who Was Plugged In" by James Tiptree, Jr.
- "Mimsy Were the Borogoves" by Henry Kuttner, C. L. Moore
- "The Nine Billion Names of God" by Arthur C. Clarke
- "Second Variety" by Philip K. Dick
- "Story of Your Life" by Ted Chiang
- "Vaster Than Empires and More Slow" by Ursula K. Le Guin
- "Vintage Season" by Henry Kuttner, C. L. Moore

Running story total: 59

<strong>The Big Book of Science Fiction: The Ultimate Collection</strong>

- "Sandkings" by George R. R. Martin
- "Snow" by John Crowley
- "Swarm" by Bruce Sterling
- "The Last Question" by Isaac Asimov
- "The Man Who Lost the Sea" by Theodore Sturgeon
- "The Star" by Arthur C. Clarke
- "The Voices of Time" by J. G. Ballard

Running story total: 66

<strong>The Science Fiction Hall of Fame, Volume IV</strong>

- "A Meeting with Medusa" by Arthur C. Clarke
- "Born with the Dead" by Robert Silverberg
- "Of Mist, and Grass, and Sand" by Vonda N. McIntyre
- "The Day Before the Revolution" by Ursula K. Le Guin
- "The Death of Doctor Island" by Gene Wolfe
- "The Queen of Air and Darkness" by Poul Anderson

Running story total: 72

<strong>The Very Best of Fantasy &amp; Science Fiction: 60th Anniversary Anthology</strong>

- "Harrison Bergeron" by Kurt Vonnegut, Jr.
- "The Merchant and the Alchemist's Gate" by Ted Chiang
- "The Women Men Don't See" by James Tiptree, Jr.

Running story total: 75

<strong>The Science Fiction Century</strong>

- "Beggars in Spain" by Nancy Kress
- "Fire Watch" by Connie Willis
- "Great Work of Time" by John Crowley

Running story total: 78

<strong>The Best of the Nebulas</strong>

- "A Boy and His Dog" by Harlan Ellison
- "Houston, Houston, Do You Read?" by James Tiptree, Jr.
- "Time Considered as a Helix of Semi-Precious Stones" by Samuel R. Delany

Running story total: 81

<strong>Armageddons</strong>

- "Inconstant Moon" by Larry Niven
- "The Screwfly Solution" by James Tiptree, Jr.

Running story total: 83

<strong>Survival Printout</strong>

- "I Have No Mouth, and I Must Scream" by Harlan Ellison
- "Scanners Live in Vain" by Cordwainer Smith

Running story total: 85

<strong>Modern Classic Short Novels of Science Fiction</strong>

- "Sailing to Byzantium" by Robert Silverberg
- "The Star Pit" by Samuel R. Delany

Running story total: 87

<strong>The Legend Book of Science Fiction</strong>

- "The Fifth Head of Cerberus" by Gene Wolfe
- "The Moon Moth" by Jack Vance

Running story total: 89

<strong>The Arbor House Treasury of Modern Science Fiction</strong>

- "Light of Other Days" by Bob Shaw
- "The Bicentennial Man" by Isaac Asimov

Running story total: 91

<strong>The Locus Awards: Thirty Years of the Best in Science Fiction and Fantasy</strong>

- "Even the Queen" by Connie Willis
- "The Way of Cross and Dragon" by George R. R. Martin

Running story total: 93

<strong>Hugo and Nebula Award Winners from Asimov's Science Fiction</strong>

- "Press ENTER ■" by John Varley

Running story total: 94

<strong>The Hugo Winners, Volume Three</strong>

- "A Song for Lya" by George R. R. Martin

Running story total: 95

<strong>The Best Science Fiction and Fantasy of the Year Volume Six</strong>

- "The Man Who Bridged the Mist" by Kij Johnson

Running story total: 96

<strong>The Best Science Fiction and Fantasy of the Year Volume Five</strong>

- "The Things" by Peter Watts

Running story total: 97

<strong>The Year's Best Science Fiction: Fourth Annual Collection</strong>

- "R &amp; R" by Lucius Shepard

Running story total: 98

<strong>The Unreal and the Real: The Selected Short Stories of Ursula K. Le Guin</strong>

- "Buffalo Gals, Won't You Come Out Tonight" by Ursula K. Le Guin

Running story total: 99

<strong>The New Space Opera 2</strong>

- "The Island" by Peter Watts

Running story total: 100

<strong>The New Hugo Winners, Volume III</strong>

- "The Last of the Winnebagos" by Connie Willis

Running story total: 101

<strong>Selected books</strong>:

- <a href="http://www.isfdb.org/cgi-bin/title.cgi?1295175">Sense of Wonder</a>
- <a href="http://www.isfdb.org/cgi-bin/title.cgi?1139797">The Wesleyan Anthology of Science Fiction</a>
- <a href="http://www.isfdb.org/cgi-bin/title.cgi?2177624">Science Fiction: Stories and Contexts</a>
- <a href="http://www.isfdb.org/cgi-bin/title.cgi?2012662">The Big Book of Science Fiction: The Ultimate Collection</a>
- <a href="http://www.isfdb.org/cgi-bin/title.cgi?33477">The Science Fiction Hall of Fame, Volume IV</a>
- <a href="http://www.isfdb.org/cgi-bin/title.cgi?33477">The Very Best of Fantasy &amp; Science Fiction: 60th Anniversary …</a></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://classicsofsciencefiction.com/2020/08/09/the-sf-anthology-problem-solved/">https://classicsofsciencefiction.com/2020/08/09/the-sf-anthology-problem-solved/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://classicsofsciencefiction.com/2020/08/09/the-sf-anthology-problem-solved/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24130250</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 10:04:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Containers: A Foolproof, Hands-On Docker Tutorial]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24130091">thread link</a>) | @fazlerocks
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://blog.antoniolofiego.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-containers-a-foolproof-hands-on-docker-tutorial-part-2-ckdlu8yge04y6zzs14qgz76go | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.antoniolofiego.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-containers-a-foolproof-hands-on-docker-tutorial-part-2-ckdlu8yge04y6zzs14qgz76go">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="text"><p>Welcome to Part 2 of my shameless attempt at explaining Docker to beginners. I struggled so you don't have to!</p>
<p>In last week's <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://blog.antoniolofiego.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-containers-a-foolproof-hands-on-docker-tutorial-part-1-ckdc4tni0031759s14z0pdd2j">article</a> we covered what Docker is, some of its jargon, and why it outperforms VMs in many use cases in today's typical software development lifecycle. This week we'll go deeper into running Docker on our machines, all while figuring out the most interesting and useful underlying technicalities.</p>
<p><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/3aGZA6WLI9Jde/giphy.gif" alt="Let's go!"></p>
<h2 id="getting-started-with-docker">Getting started with Docker</h2>
<p>If you don't have Docker installed on your machine, head over to the <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/">Docker Download page</a> to get the version that will work on your system.</p>
<p>The Linux version is the easiest to install, given that Docker is built off of Linux utilities. On Mac and Windows, on the other hand, there are two main ways of using Docker:</p>
<ul>
<li><p><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://docs.docker.com/desktop/">Docker Desktop</a>
The newer and recommended version of Docker. It is a native solution that works directly along with your OS's processes, so we are free to interface with Docker with your favorite terminal and your favorite IDE/text editors.</p>
</li>
<li><p><a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://docs.docker.com/toolbox/overview/">Docker Toolbox</a>
This is an old version for machines that don't meet the minimum requirements for Docker Desktop. It is not a native solution as it runs on VirtualBox, so we are forced to use the tools that the Toolbox comes packaged with, making everything more cumbersome and prone to errors.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The main catch is that Docker Desktop is not easy to install on every system. While it is straightforward on macOS 10.13+ and Windows 10 Pro, the Windows 10 Home version needs extra attention.</p>
<p>Docker Desktop on Windows leverages Hyper-V, which is Microsoft's Type 1 hypervisor and only available on Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Education. Fortunately, Windows Home supports <strong>Windows Subsystem for Linux</strong> (WSL), a Linux kernel developed by Microsoft that allows us to run Linux processes to run natively without emulation. Since March 2020, Docker Desktop supports WSL version 2 as a backend on Windows Home.</p>
<p>To install Docker Desktop on Windows Home we need to install WSL2 first, then install Docker Desktop specifying WSL2 as the backend during the installation process. we can find the whole process to install WSL2 <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10">here</a> and the subsequent Docker Desktop installation process <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-windows/install-windows-home/">here</a>. If you would like to see a walkthrough video of the installation process, let me know and I will work on making one available.</p>
<p>Once installed, we can open our favorite terminal and check that the installation went smoothly by typing</p>
<pre><code>docker --version
</code></pre>
<p>If this returns something the likes of</p>
<pre><code>Docker version 19.03.12, build 48a66213fe
</code></pre>
<p>we are good to go!</p>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: In case you are unable to make it work on your machine or if you don't want to install anything yet, Docker also offers <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.docker.com/play-with-docker">online playgrounds</a> to run your code and everything you find in this tutorial would work the same.</p>
<h2 id="let-s-run-our-first-container-">Let's run our first container!</h2>
<p>As we saw last week, to run a container we first need to find an image on the Docker registry. Like everything in the programming, Docker has a Hello World container that we can easily get from its Docker Hub <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://hub.docker.com/_/hello-world">page</a>. As we can see on the website, the command we have to run is</p>
<pre><code>$ docker pull hello-world
</code></pre>
<p>which will welcome us with an unsightly wall of output which looks like</p>
<pre><code>Using default tag: latest
latest: Pulling from library/hello-world
0e03bdcc26d7: Pulling fs layer
0e03bdcc26d7: Verifying Checksum
0e03bdcc26d7: Download complete
0e03bdcc26d7: Pull complete
Digest: sha256:49a1c8800c94df04e9658809b006fd8a686cab8028d33cfba2cc049724254202
Status: Downloaded newer image for hello-world:latest
docker.io/library/hello-world:latest
</code></pre>
<p>We can see a few things that we need to cover, namely <strong>tags</strong> and <strong>layers</strong>.</p>
<p>We can check all the images that we have in our machine simply by running <code>$ docker images</code> and inspecting its output:</p>
<pre><code>REPOSITORY       TAG        IMAGE ID        CREATED           SIZE
hello-world      latest     bf756fb1ae65    7 months ago      13.3kB
</code></pre>
<p>We can see that we have a <code>hello-world</code> image tagged latest, with a unique image ID (yours may be different) and it weighs only 13.3KB! That is where the gold is! Running a similar basic job using a VM would entail installing an entire OS just to output "Hello world!".</p>
<p>The first column of the <code>docker images</code> output is called <strong>repository</strong>. If you have ever used Git or GitHub, the name might sound familiar. In a Docker Registry, a repository is a collection of different versions of images that share the same base name. Each of the versions is identified by a <strong>tag</strong>, but images can have multiple tags as well!</p>
<p>In general, Docker images follow the naming convention of <code>username/repository:tag</code>. As a quick example, let's suppose that I built an image called <code>mysimpleapp</code> and I shared version 1.0 on the Docker Hub. You could get that image by running</p>
<pre><code>$ docker pull antoniolofiego/mysimpleapplication:1.0
</code></pre>
<p>If we do not specify the tag portion, Docker will by default download the image that is tagged as <code>latest</code>. This is not a special tag, but just the one that Docker assigns by default to images when no other tags are specified at build time.</p>
<p>Now that we have the image locally, we want to run it, right? Surely enough, the command to run images is <code>$ docker run &lt;image&gt;</code>. There are mainly three ways to reference an image:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>By repository</strong>, but it works only if we have a single version of the image (ex: if I have two versions from the same repository, Docker will be confused about which I am referring to).</li>
<li><strong>By repository/tag combination</strong>, which solves the previous problem.</li>
<li><strong>By image ID</strong>, the preferred way, given that every image will always have a unique ID. Note, we can use just the first few characters from the ID and Docker will pick up the correct one.</li>
</ul>
<p>Using the Image ID method, for our <code>hello-world</code> image example we will run</p>
<pre><code>$ docker run bf756
Hello from Docker!
This message shows that your installation appears to be working correctly.

To generate this message, Docker took the following steps:
 1. The Docker client contacted the Docker daemon.
 2. The Docker daemon pulled the "hello-world" image from the Docker Hub.
    (amd64)
 3. The Docker daemon created a new container from that image that runs the executable that produces the output you are currently reading.
 4. The Docker daemon streamed that output to the Docker client, which sent it to your terminal.

To try something more ambitious, you can run an Ubuntu container with:
 $ docker run -it ubuntu bash

Share images, automate workflows, and more with a free Docker ID:
 https://hub.docker.com/

For more examples and ideas, visit:
 https://docs.docker.com/get-started/
</code></pre>
<p>We have successfully pulled and run our first Docker Image! 🎉 Let's recap all we learned so far by visualizing a repository structure and all the ways to pull or run an image in a simple way</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.hashnode.com/res/hashnode/image/upload/v1596760605560/zssexvySE.png?auto=format&amp;q=60" alt="Repo structure"></p>
<p>We know how to pull and run simple images! We just scratched the Docker surface, however. Are you ready to go to the next level?</p>
<p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/max/570/0*y8AuUHSoTGRqX40h.jpeg" alt="We need to go deeper!"></p>
<h2 id="breaking-down-a-docker-image">Breaking down a Docker Image</h2>
<p>We know from last week that a Docker Image starts as a Dockerfile, which is a recipe that Docker follows to package our application. It is composed of a series of <code>[action]</code> <code>[target]</code> commands, each of which specifies a command that Docker needs to run in sequential order.</p>
<p>Let's take a look at a Dockerfile that deploys a simple Node.js Express server and try to understand how it works.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> You can download all the code from this example via <a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/antoniolofiego/hashnode-dockerseries-expressapp">this</a> GitHub repository.</p>
<p>The folder structure for this example is as follows</p>
<pre><code>📦docker-express-app
 ┣ 📂src
 ┃ ┗ 📜server.js
 ┣ 📜.gitignore
 ┣ 📜Dockerfile
 ┣ 📜package-lock.json
 ┗ 📜package.json
</code></pre>
<p>As we can see, the Dockerfile sits at the root level of my project folder. Let's now look at its content.</p>
<pre><code>FROM node:11-alpine

RUN mkdir app

WORKDIR /app

COPY . .

RUN npm install

CMD ["npm", "run", "start"]
</code></pre>
<p>Let's go through each step one by one:</p>
<ol>
<li><p><code>FROM node:11-alpine</code> tells Docker to download the Docker image for Node.js version 11 running on Linux Alpine, a very lightweight Linux distribution. This will be the base image used by our container.</p>
</li>
<li><p><code>RUN mkdir app</code> creates a local folder named <code>app</code> at the root of the environment.</p>
</li>
<li><p><code>WORKDIR /app</code> changes the working directory for all subsequent commands to the <code>/app</code> folder that we created in step 2.</p>
</li>
<li><p><code>COPY . .</code> tells Docker to copy all the files in the current folder on my machine (my <code>docker-express-app</code> folder) in the current directory of the Docker image (the <code>/app</code> directory).</p>
</li>
<li><p><code>RUN npm install</code> installs all the dependencies that I specified in my <code>package.json</code> file, in this case only <code>express</code>.</p>
</li>
<li><p><code>CMD ["npm", "run", "start"]</code> is the command that the container will run at instantiation time, in this case, the <code>start</code> script defined in <code>package.json</code>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>The next step is to build the image. As you can imagine, we have a <code>docker build</code> command that does just that! The standard usage for the build command is</p>
<pre><code>docker build -t &lt;username/repository:tag&gt; &lt;path/to/Dockerfile&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>Remember that, when tagging an image, if we only provide a repository name Docker will assign the <code>latest</code> tag to the image by default. Let's take a look at the output.</p>
<pre><code>$ docker build -t docker-express-app .
Sending build context to Docker daemon  2.013MB
Step 1/6 : FROM node:11-alpine
 ---&gt; f18da2f58c3d
Step 2/6 : RUN mkdir app
 ---&gt; Running in 37513fc60556
Removing intermediate container 37513fc60556
 ---&gt; 13ee4d6cccbc
Step 3/6 : WORKDIR /app
 ---&gt; Running in 45e51ade37c0
Removing intermediate container 45e51ade37c0
 ---&gt; 579c23501f62
Step 4/6 : COPY . .
 ---&gt; a3527fb353c6
Step 5/6 : RUN npm install
 ---&gt; Running in f4ab1726f363
audited 50 packages in 0.855s
found 0 vulnerabilities

Removing intermediate container f4ab1726f363
 ---&gt; 8f2c4645e536
Step 6/6 : CMD ["npm", "run", "start"]
 ---&gt; Running in b5739c39b3cf
Removing intermediate container b5739c39b3cf
 ---&gt; ac715302eade
Successfully built ac715302eade
Successfully tagged docker-express-app:latest
</code></pre>
<p>As we can see, each instruction is carefully followed. On each step, Docker creates a <strong>layer</strong>. Every image is built out of several read-only layers, with each layer corresponding to certain instructions in your Dockerfile. Each step builds …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://blog.antoniolofiego.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-containers-a-foolproof-hands-on-docker-tutorial-part-2-ckdlu8yge04y6zzs14qgz76go">https://blog.antoniolofiego.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-containers-a-foolproof-hands-on-docker-tutorial-part-2-ckdlu8yge04y6zzs14qgz76go</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.antoniolofiego.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-containers-a-foolproof-hands-on-docker-tutorial-part-2-ckdlu8yge04y6zzs14qgz76go</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24130091</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 09:38:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Halo Infinite Delayed to 2021]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129903">thread link</a>) | @handlingelect
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://www.staticcatgames.com/2020/08/halo-infinite-delayed-to-2021.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.staticcatgames.com/2020/08/halo-infinite-delayed-to-2021.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<h2>Xbox Series X Still Launching November</h2><p>The Xbox Series X is still on track to launch this November. I expect this will be a soft launch, with a range of third party games such as <i>Madden 21</i>, <i>Fifa 21</i>, <i>Cyberpunk 2077</i>, <i>Call of Duty Black Ops: Cold War</i>, <i>NBA 2K21,&nbsp;Assassin's Creed: Valhalla </i>and <i>Watch Dogs Legion</i>.&nbsp;</p><p>Microsoft will heavily emphasize backwards compatibility on the console, noting the thousands of games that can be played on it. I wouldn't be surprised if it also focused on the 4K/120fps ability, showcasing games that achieve this to help sell the console.&nbsp;</p><h2>PlayStation 5 To Own November?</h2><p>The biggest beneficiary of the delay is Sony. The PlayStation 5 has exclusive games, a clear line-up and vision of where it wants to go. All Sony has to do is announce the price and launch date and watch the PlayStation 5 fly off the shelves this winter.&nbsp;</p><p>As I wrote before, there are no major games that will take advantage of the system's power until next year. But the delay gives Sony a head-start in the next generation. There will be a void and the absence of <i>Halo Infinite</i> could persuade some Xbox gamers to jump ship.</p><h2>Heads To Roll At 343 Industries</h2><p>One of the biggest consequences of the delay could be a shake up at 343. The studio has had over five years since the release of <i>Halo 5: Guardians</i>&nbsp;to get this ready. That would have been plenty of time to get the game ready to be shipped for a November 2020 launch. Something has clearly gone wrong there and I would expect Phil Spencer to investigate fully and make organisational changes as needed to right the ship. Will Bonnie Ross go? Who knows.</p><h2>Microsoft Needs To Get This Right</h2><p>After the disastrous current gen, Microsoft <b>needs</b> to get the next generation right. It cannot afford any slip-ups, nor can it afford to be complacent and rely on the success of Game Pass Ultimate to drive revenue for the Xbox division.&nbsp;</p><p>If I were management at Microsoft and wanted to make a dent, I would undercut the PlayStation 5 and bundle Game Pass Ultimate (for 3 months) with it. Then I would go around making deals with every third party publisher and ensure the system has exclusive DLC/content and new games. Microsoft needs to be aggressive.</p><p>Failure to do so could mean this would be the last console generation it participates in. I expect there are a few higher-ups at Microsoft who would be very happy at that possibility. They are probably thinking 'we are a software company, what are we doing making consoles?'.&nbsp;</p><p>We, as gamers, though, need Microsoft to succeed. Competition is healthy, so we need the Xbox Series X to do well.</p><h2>Concluding Thoughts</h2><p>Halo Infinite's delay is unfortunate. I hope 343 uses the time to make a better game and improve on its foundations, creating a game that will give PlayStation a run for its money. I look forward to seeing the results next year.&nbsp;</p><div><p>***</p><p>If you want to save money on games, take a look at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.kinguin.net/cjaffiliate/index/index/ref/cj/?URL=https://deal.kinguin.net&amp;skimoffer=1049864" target="_blank">Kinguin</a></p><p>They have a great Summer sale on at the moment.&nbsp;Good Deals for a Good Week. Make Your Day With up to -80% on amazing games! Relax and take your pick.&nbsp;</p><p>Feel Good Now&nbsp;</p><p>Use your code:&nbsp;<span>SUMMERDEAL</span>&nbsp;for extra -10% off.</p><p>The sale ends on August 14th 2020.&nbsp;</p><p><span><i>(Static Cat Games may get a small commission on any purchase made through the link)</i></span></p></div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.staticcatgames.com/2020/08/halo-infinite-delayed-to-2021.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129903</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 09:04:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Configure Your Sockets with URIs]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129851">thread link</a>) | @rmedaer
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://raphael.medaer.me/2020/08/20/define-socket-w-uris.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://raphael.medaer.me/2020/08/20/define-socket-w-uris.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>Everybody knows Uniform Resource Identifier (URI)<sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup>. As its name suggests, it’s a way to identify a resource (for instance a file or a phone number).
It is often confused with Uniform Resource Locator (URL), which is actually a form of URI. A URL is <em>a compact string representation for a resource available via the Internet</em><sup id="fnref:2" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:2">2</a></sup>.</p>

<p>Today I want to share with you the way I define another type of resources: network sockets.
<!--more-->
Everybody knows what a network socket is, right ?</p>

<p>The socket families I often use are <code>inet</code>, <code>inet6</code> and <code>unix</code>. But there are much more types of endpoints: <code>ipx</code>, <code>bluetooth</code>,…</p>

<p>To configure the sockets my services or APIs have to bind, I’m now using URIs! For instance:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>inet://127.0.0.1:80?reuseaddr=true
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>In this example I basically create a socket IPv4 on address <code>127.0.0.1</code> and port <code>80</code> with <code>SO_REUSEADDR</code> option enabled.</p>

<p><strong>PRO:</strong> It might be specified in any configuration file because it’s basically just a string. You don’t need any complex structure to define socket type or options.</p>

<h3 id="syntax">Syntax</h3>

<p>The URI <em>scheme</em> defines which socket family I have to use:</p>

<ul>
  <li><em>inet</em> for IPv4 sockets</li>
  <li><em>inet6</em> for IPv6 sockets</li>
  <li><em>unix</em> for Unix sockets</li>
</ul>

<p>Hopefully these schemes are not (yet) registered at IANA<sup id="fnref:3" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:3">3</a></sup>.</p>

<p>The URI’s <em>authority</em> and <em>path</em> depend on the family used. Query arguments are used to configure options of the socket. They also depend on the family used.</p>

<h4 id="ipv4-sockets">IPv4 sockets</h4>

<p>For <em>inet</em> family the authority is mandatory. It contains:</p>

<ul>
  <li>the <em>hostname</em> (optional):
    <ul>
      <li>either a IPv4, for instance <code>127.0.0.1</code></li>
      <li>or a hostname which needs to be resolved as a IPv4 address</li>
      <li>if not specified, the default value is <code>0.0.0.0</code>: it binds on all IPv4 addresses</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>the <em>port</em> (mandatory)</li>
</ul>

<p>The <em>path</em> is not used in this case, it remains empty.</p>

<p>Here are some examples:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>inet://127.0.0.1:8080</code> binds on address <code>127.0.0.1</code> and port <code>8080</code>, easy!</li>
  <li><code>inet://example.com:5432</code> resolves <code>example.com</code> to an IPv4 and binds on port <code>5432</code></li>
  <li><code>inet://:80?reuseaddr=true</code> listen on port <code>80</code> and accept connections on any IPv4 of the system (<code>0.0.0.0</code>) even if there are remaining connections in <code>TIME_WAIT</code></li>
</ul>

<h4 id="ipv6-sockets">IPv6 sockets</h4>

<p>Idem than <code>inet</code> but for IPv6 and with URI scheme <code>inet6</code>. Some query argments might defer.</p>

<p>You’re probably wondering why I use <code>inet</code> <strong>and</strong> <code>inet6</code>. Indeed I could use an IPv6 address with the <code>inet</code> scheme. However it doesn’t work with domain name resolution. For instance <code>inet://localhost:80</code> will bind on IPv4 address <code>127.0.0.1</code> while <code>inet6://localhost:80</code> will bind on IPv6 address <code>::1</code>.</p>

<h4 id="unix-sockets">Unix sockets</h4>

<p><em>Authority</em> part is not used for <em>unix</em> family. However the path is used like a <code>file:/</code> URI. It defines the path of the unix socket.</p>

<p>For instance: <code>unix:///var/run/my-socket.sock</code></p>

<h3 id="specification--implementation">Specification &amp; implementation</h3>

<p>I don’t think there is already a specification or RFC which tackle this idea.</p>

<p>I guess this trick is already used in <del>some</del> many implementations. To be honnest I didn’t look a lot. But feel free to share your godsend!</p>



  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://raphael.medaer.me/2020/08/20/define-socket-w-uris.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129851</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:49:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: The cheapest investment platforms in the UK]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129843">thread link</a>) | @Halimah
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-funds-isa-charges | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-funds-isa-charges">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f09af9fd3ce592df7f0eae7_scale-128x128.png" width="55" alt=""></p></div><div><div><p>Typically, your annual charge depends on whether you hold funds or shares in your investment ISA. Here, we assume you'll invest in funds only. If you plan to invest in shares, have a look at our <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-shares-isa-charges">shares' table</a>. </p><p>We've split the ISA providers into three categories based on the level of help they'll offer you. These categories are "Do It Yourself (DIY)," "Do It With Me (DIWM)," and "Do It For Me (DIFM)." For each provider we list, your money is protected by the Financial Services Compensation Scheme (FSCS). This means you could get your money back up to £85,000 if any of the companies goes bust. Use the tabs below to learn about each category.</p></div></div></div><div><div data-duration-in="300" data-duration-out="100" id="providers"><div><div data-w-tab="Tab 1"><div><div><p>This is ideal for people who know what they are doing. With DIY platforms, you'll have access to a wide range of investments, and in some cases, investment ideas or suggested fund lists. But you have to choose your investments and build your portfolio yourself. This requires a bit of research on your part, so it is crucial you know what you are doing. It would help if you have clear goals, know your risk appetite and understand how to build a portfolio.</p><p>When you invest in a fund, please note the fund manager will add various charges within the fund. We haven't included any fund management fees here, just platform and dealing fees. If you would like a rough idea of how fund management fees could impact the total amount you pay to a platform, have a look at the 'Do It With Me' and 'Do It For Me' tabs. Additionally, you can find out more about investing in funds and the various charges in <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/funds">Investing in Funds guide</a>.</p></div><p>‍<span><strong>Important:</strong></span><strong><br></strong>The table below shows annual charges of several investment platforms when you invest in funds as follows:<br></p><ul role="list"><li>£100 per month regular payment</li><li>£500 per month regular payment</li><li>£1,000 per month regular payment</li><li>£20,000 lump sum (your year’s ISA allowance)</li><li>£100,000 lump sum (if you already have lots of ISAs from previous years and are transferring in)</li></ul><div><p>For regular payments, we assume you'll make 12 deals a year or one deal every month. For lump sums, we assume you'll make four deals a year. A deal is either one of buying or selling an investment. It is also called a trade. We've used the colour red to indicate what platforms are more expensive compared to the others. This means the darker the shade of red, the more expensive the platform. Dark red doesn't mean bad or too expensive. It just means the platform is more expensive when compared to the others. If you would like to see a breakdown of fees charged by each platform, have a look at our <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/charges-directory">Platform Charges Directory</a>.</p><p>Finally, it is important to let you know we show the costs which apply to the first year only. This is especially important because, with platforms like iWeb, your charges reduce after the first year. Whereas with platforms like EQi, your charges might increase after the first year. You'll find all the details you need below.<br>‍</p></div></div><div><p>Notes<a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-shares-isa-charges"></a></p><ol role="list"><li>EQi - You'll pay no custody fee in the first two quarters of the year you join, so it'll be more expensive in subsequent years.</li><li>IWeb - Charges a one-off account opening fee of £25 in the first year, so it will be cheaper in subsequent years where you do not have to pay the account opening fee.</li></ol><p>Once again, you can find more information on the various charges <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/charges-directory">here</a> and view our share dealing ISA charges comparison table <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-shares-isa-charges">here.</a></p></div></div><div data-w-tab="Tab 2"><div><div><p>This is ideal for people who are happy making their own investment decisions but require a bit of help getting there. The DIWM platforms do not give you advice but offer some guidance that could help you understand your attitude to risk, and then provide ready-made investments that match your risk level.</p><p>When you invest in a fund, please note the fund manager will add on various charges within the fund. A good representation of those charges is the OCF or Ongoing Charges Figure. It is an estimate of the portion of the total cost of your investment that goes to the fund manager and is separate from the platform fee and dealing fee. The examples in the table below should give you a good idea of your investment's total cost, including OCF, platform fees, and dealing fees in the first year only. In each case, we've used a mid-risk ready-made portfolio or multi-asset fund. You can find out more about investing in funds and the various charges in our <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/funds">Investing in Funds guide</a>.</p></div><p>‍<span><strong>Important:</strong></span><strong><br></strong>The table below shows annual charges of several investment platforms when you invest in funds as follows:<br></p><ul role="list"><li>£100 per month regular payment</li><li>£1,000 per month regular payment</li><li>£20,000 lump sum (your year’s ISA allowance)</li></ul><p>For regular payments, we assume you'll make 12 deals a year or one deal every month. For the lump sum, we assume you'll make one deal a year. A deal is either one of buying or selling an investment. It is also called a trade. We've used the colour red to indicate what platforms are more expensive compared to the others. This means the darker the shade of red, the more expensive the platform or offering. Dark red doesn't mean bad or too expensive. It just means the platform is more expensive when compared to the others. If you would like to see a breakdown of fees charged by each platform, have a look at our <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/charges-directory">Platform Charges Directory</a>.<br>‍<br></p></div><div><p>Notes<a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-shares-isa-charges"></a></p><ol role="list"><li>AJ Bell and Barclays are the only members of the 'Do It With Me' cohort that charge fund dealing fees. This partially explains why they have some of the highest costs for regular investments above.</li></ol><p>Most of the platforms with low OCFs offer just index trackers and ETFs, so don't get too excited about the cheaper offerings. Except you are interested in only trackers and ETFs, then please get excited. Remember, you can find more information on the various charges <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/charges-directory">here</a> and view our share dealing ISA charges comparison table <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-shares-isa-charges">here.</a></p></div></div><div data-w-tab="Tab 3"><div><p>This is ideal for people who are either beginners or who want all the hard work done for them. With DIFM platforms, you'll often be presented with a limited set of investment choices based on your attitude to risk, investment goals and how much you plan to invest. DIFM platforms are mostly robo-advisers. Depending on the platform you choose, you may have access to formal financial advice.<br>‍<br>When you invest in a fund, please note the fund manager will add on various charges within the fund. A good representation of those charges is the OCF or Ongoing Charges Figure. It is an estimate of the portion of the total cost of your investment that goes to the fund manager and is separate from the platform fee and dealing fee. The examples in the table below should give you an idea of the total cost of your investment, including platform fees, dealing fees, OCF, and transaction costs (where we could find them). In each case, we've used a mid-risk ready-made portfolio or multi-asset fund. You can find out more about investing in funds and the various charges in our <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/funds">Investing in Funds guide</a>.<br></p><p>‍<span><strong>Important:</strong></span><strong><br></strong>The table below shows annual charges of several investment platforms when you invest in funds as follows:<br></p><ul role="list"><li>£100 per month regular payment</li><li>£1,000 per month regular payment</li><li>£20,000 lump sum (your year’s ISA allowance)</li><li>£100,000 lump sum (if you already have lots of ISAs from previous years and are transferring in)</li></ul><div><p>For regular payments, we assume you'll make 12 deals a year or one deal every month. For lump sums, we assume you'll make one deal a year. A deal is either one of buying or selling an investment. It is also called a trade. We've used the colour red to indicate what platforms are more expensive compared to the others. This means the darker the shade of red, the more expensive the platform. Dark red doesn't mean bad or too expensive. It just means the platform is more expensive when compared to the others. If you would like to see a breakdown of fees charged by each platform, have a look at our <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/charges-directory">Platform Charges Directory</a>.</p><p>Finally, it is important to let you know we show the costs which apply to the first year only. This is especially important because, with platforms like Santander, Wealth Horizon and Munnypot, your costs significantly reduce after the first year. You'll find all the details you need below.<br>‍</p></div></div><div><div><p><h2>Platform</h2></p><p><h2>Average OCF</h2></p><p><h2>£100 per month</h2></p><p><h2>£1,000 per month</h2></p><p><h2>£20,000</h2></p><p><h2>£100,000</h2></p></div><a href="https://etfmatic.com/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06f62b4f711c6145304b86_etfmatic-logo.png" alt="etfmatic Logo" height="20" srcset="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06f62b4f711c6145304b86_etfmatic-logo-p-500.png 500w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06f62b4f711c6145304b86_etfmatic-logo.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 100vw, (max-width: 991px) 11vw, (max-width: 1279px) 9vw, 106.65625px"></p></div></a><a href="https://eqinvestors.co.uk/individuals/invest/portfolios/low-cost/" target="_blank"><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06f6fe15dc2880dcc5b5a0_EQ-Investors-logo.png" alt="EQ investors Logo" height="40"></p><p>1</p></div></div></a><a href="https://www.ig.com/uk/investments/smart-portfolios" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f0310358d5f7c058c79af46_IG-logo.png" alt="IG Logo" height="40"></p></div></a><a href="https://www.moneyboxapp.com/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5ec9a34a06d25c2f641226c8_money-box-logo.svg" alt="Moneybox Logo" height="25"></p></div></a><a href="https://www.moneyfarm.com/uk/" target="_blank"><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06f8aa42e7a85e0223a7eb_moneyfarm-logo.svg" alt="moneyfarm Logo" height="40"></p><p>2</p></div></div></a><a href="https://www.munnypot.com/" target="_blank"><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06f9634f711c2f1e3050c5_munnypot-logo.png" alt="Munnypot Logo" height="20"></p><p>3</p></div></div></a><a href="https://www.netwealth.com/" target="_blank"><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06fa52f2ec274ae2908300_Netwealth-logo.png" alt="netwealth Logo" height="25"></p><p>4</p></div></div></a><a href="https://www.nutmeg.com/fully-managed-portfolios" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5ed5d42ae1889f04d625418e_nutmeg-logo.png" alt="Nutmeg logo" height="25"></p></div></a><a href="https://www.open-money.co.uk/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5ed5d57f6456312181a62063_open-money-logo.svg" alt="OpenMoney logo" height="45"></p></div></a><a href="https://withplum.com/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5ec9a17ba391aac5ea76daa7_plum-logo-dark.svg" alt="Plum logo" height="25"></p></div></a><a href="https://www.santander.co.uk/personal/savings-and-investments/investments" target="_blank"><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06bbdf328260833f99bf31_Santander-logo.svg" alt="Santander logo" height="30" width="110"></p><p>3</p></div></div></a><a href="https://uk.scalable.capital/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f06ffade1fbe36a54066867_scalable-capital-logo.svg" alt="scalable capital logo" height="30"></p></div></a><a href="https://www.tpinvestor.com/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f07012de1fbe30528066bda_true-potential-logo.png" alt="True Potential logo" height="30"></p></div></a><a href="https://http//www.wealthhorizon.com/" target="_blank"><div><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f07012d7efa7b567367fa31_wealth-horizon-logo.png" alt="Wealth Horizon logo" height="30" srcset="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f07012d7efa7b567367fa31_wealth-horizon-logo-p-500.png 500w, https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f07012d7efa7b567367fa31_wealth-horizon-logo.png 684w" sizes="(max-width: 479px) 100vw, (max-width: 1439px) 11vw, 138.984375px"></p><p>3</p></div></div></a><a href="https://www.wealthify.com/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5ed5d3b6f31d3f40aa060754_wealthify-logo.svg" alt="Wealthify logo" height="35"></p></div></a><a href="https://www.wealthsimple.com/en-gb/" target="_blank"><div><p><img src="https://uploads-ssl.webflow.com/5ea8e1014488c25d7742640f/5f07012c63666eefde802041_wealthsimple-logo.svg" alt="Wealthsimple logo" height="35"></p></div></a></div><div><p>Notes<a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-shares-isa-charges"></a></p><ol role="list"><li>EQ Investors - Minimum investment of £1,000 lump sum or £250 per month regular payment</li><li>Moneyfarm - Minimum investment of £5,000 lump sum or £1,500 regular direct debit</li><li>Munnypot, Santander and Wealth Horizon all charge a one-off initial advice fee in the first year, so they will be cheaper in subsequent years where you do not have to pay this fee.</li><li>Netwealth - Minimum investment of £50,000.</li></ol><p>Most of the platforms in this category offer just index trackers and ETFs. That's why their OCF is quite low. Remember, you can find more information on the various charges <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/charges-directory">here</a> and view our share dealing ISA charges comparison table <a href="https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-shares-isa-charges">here.</a></p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><section id="subscribe-form"><div><div><div><div><div><p>Thank you! Your submission has been received!</p></div><div><p>Oops! Something went wrong while submitting the form.</p></div></div><div><p><strong>Subscribe to Our Blog</strong></p><p>Tips and pointers delivered to your email every month!</p></div></div></div></div></section></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.koody.co/investing/compare-funds-isa-charges</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129843</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:48:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Six more ways to improve your Python]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129760">thread link</a>) | @SourceryNick
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://sourcery.ai/blog/explaining-refactorings-3/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sourcery.ai/blog/explaining-refactorings-3/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><figure>
    <span>
      <a href="https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/12609/code.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Python code" title="Photo by Chris Ried on Unsplash" src="https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/4b190/code.jpg" srcset="https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/e07e9/code.jpg 200w,
https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/066f9/code.jpg 400w,
https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/4b190/code.jpg 800w,
https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/e5166/code.jpg 1200w,
https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/b17f8/code.jpg 1600w,
https://sourcery.ai/static/8bd4114da4db25ae197f53bad36c7c36/12609/code.jpg 3000w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span>
    <figcaption>Photo by Chris Ried on Unsplash</figcaption>
  </figure>
<p>Writing clean, Pythonic code is all about making it as understandable, yet concise, as possible.
This is the third part of a series on Python refactorings, based on those that can be done
automatically by <a href="https://sourcery.ai/">Sourcery</a>. Catch the first part <a href="https://sourcery.ai/blog/explaining-refactorings-1/">here</a>, and
the second part <a href="https://sourcery.ai/blog/explaining-refactorings-2/">here</a>.</p>
<p>The focus of this series is on why these changes are good ideas, not just on how to do them.</p>
<h2>1. Add guard clause</h2>
<p>Deeply nested functions can be very difficult to understand. As you read them you
have to remember the conditions that hold for each level of nesting. This can be even
more difficult in Python, given that there are no brackets to help define conditional
blocks. An easy way to reduce nesting is to convert conditionals into guard clauses.</p>
<p>As an example let's look at this function:</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>should_i_wear_this_hat</span><span>(</span>self<span>,</span> hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> Hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
        current_fashion <span>=</span> FASHION_API<span>.</span>get_fashion<span>(</span>FASHION_TYPE<span>.</span>HAT<span>)</span>
        weather_outside <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>look_out_of_window<span>(</span><span>)</span>
        is_stylish <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>evaluate_style<span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> current_fashion<span>)</span>
        <span>if</span> weather_outside<span>.</span>is_raining<span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Damn."</span><span>)</span>
            <span>return</span> <span>True</span>
        <span>else</span><span>:</span>
            <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Great."</span><span>)</span>
            <span>return</span> is_stylish
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>False</span></code></pre></div>
<p>This is quite hard to parse, given the two layers of nesting. When I get to the
<code>else</code> at the bottom I need to flick back and forth a bit between that and the
<code>if</code> test at the top before I've understood what's going on. This <code>if</code>
condition is a check for an edge case, where something that isn't a hat is
passed in. Since we just return <code>False</code> here it's a perfect place to
introduce a guard clause:</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>should_i_wear_this_hat</span><span>(</span>self<span>,</span> hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> Hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>False</span>

    current_fashion <span>=</span> get_fashion<span>(</span><span>)</span>
    weather_outside <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>look_out_of_window<span>(</span><span>)</span>
    is_stylish <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>evaluate_style<span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> current_fashion<span>)</span>
    <span>if</span> weather_outside<span>.</span>is_raining<span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Damn."</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>True</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Great."</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> is_stylish</code></pre></div>
<p>We add a guard clause by inverting the condition and returning immediately.
The edge case is now taken care of at the start of the function and I don't have to
worry about it any more. </p>
<p>Having reduced the level of nesting, the rest of the function is now easier to read.
Whether to add a guard clause is sometimes subjective. For really short functions it
may not be worth doing. Where functions are longer or more complex it can often be
a useful tool.</p>
<h2>2. Swap if/else to remove empty if body</h2>
<p>One pattern we sometimes see is a conditional where nothing happens in the main body,
and all of the action is in the <code>else</code> clause.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>if</span> location <span>==</span> OUTSIDE<span>:</span>
    <span>pass</span>
<span>else</span><span>:</span>
    take_off_hat<span>(</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>In this case we can make the code shorter and more concise by swapping the main body
and the <code>else</code> around. We have to make sure to invert the conditional, then the logic
from the <code>else</code> clause moves into the main body.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>if</span> location <span>!=</span> OUTSIDE<span>:</span>
   take_off_hat<span>(</span><span>)</span>
<span>else</span><span>:</span>
   <span>pass</span></code></pre></div>
<p>We then have an <code>else</code> clause which does nothing, so we can remove it.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>if</span> location <span>!=</span> OUTSIDE<span>:</span>
    take_off_hat<span>(</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>This is easier to read, and the intent of the conditional is clearer. When reading
the code I don't have to mentally invert it to understand it, since that has been done for me.</p>
<h2>3. Merge append into list declaration</h2>
<p>When declaring a list and filling it up with values one way that can come naturally
is to declare it as empty and then append to it.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code>hats_i_own <span>=</span> <span>[</span><span>]</span>
hats_i_own<span>.</span>append<span>(</span><span>'panama'</span><span>)</span>
hats_i_own<span>.</span>append<span>(</span><span>'baseball_cap'</span><span>)</span>
hats_i_own<span>.</span>append<span>(</span><span>'bowler'</span><span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>This can be done in place, shortening the code and making the intent more explicit.
Now I just need to glance at one line to see that I'm filling a variable with hats,
rather than four.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code>hats_i_own <span>=</span> <span>[</span><span>'panama'</span><span>,</span> <span>'baseball_cap'</span><span>,</span> <span>'bowler'</span><span>]</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Doing it this way is also slightly more performant since it avoids the function calls to <code>append</code>.
The same holds true for filling up other collection types like sets and dictionaries.</p>
<h2>4. Move assignments closer to their usage</h2>
<p>The scope of local variables should always be as tightly defined as possible and
practicable.</p>
<p>This means that:</p>
<ul>
<li>You don't have to keep the variable in your working memory through the parts of
the function where it's not needed. This cuts down on the cognitive load of
understanding your code.</li>
<li>If code is in coherent blocks where variables are declared and used together, it
makes it easier to split functions apart, which can lead to shorter, easier to
understand methods.</li>
<li>If variables are declared far from their usage, they can become stranded. If the
code where they are used is later changed or removed unused variables can be left
sitting around, complicating the code unnecessarily.</li>
</ul>
<p>Let's take another look at the earlier example.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>should_i_wear_this_hat</span><span>(</span>self<span>,</span> hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> Hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>False</span>

    current_fashion <span>=</span> get_fashion<span>(</span><span>)</span>
    weather_outside <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>look_out_of_window<span>(</span><span>)</span>
    is_stylish <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>evaluate_style<span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> current_fashion<span>)</span>
    <span>if</span> weather_outside<span>.</span>is_raining<span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Damn."</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>True</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Great."</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> is_stylish</code></pre></div>
<p>Here the <code>is_stylish</code> variable isn't actually needed if the weather is rainy.
It could be moved inside the <code>else</code> clause. This means we can also move the
<code>current_fashion</code> variable, which is only used here.
You do need to check that these variables aren't used
later in the function, which is easier if functions are kept short and sweet.</p>
<p>Moving the assignment to <code>current_fashion</code> also avoids a function call when the
weather is raining, which could lead to a performance improvement if it's an expensive call. </p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>should_i_wear_this_hat</span><span>(</span>self<span>,</span> hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> Hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>False</span>

    weather_outside <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>look_out_of_window<span>(</span><span>)</span>
    <span>if</span> weather_outside<span>.</span>is_raining<span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Damn."</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>True</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Great."</span><span>)</span>
        current_fashion <span>=</span> get_fashion<span>(</span><span>)</span>
        is_stylish <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>evaluate_style<span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> current_fashion<span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> is_stylish</code></pre></div>
<p>We could actually then go one step further and inline the <code>is_stylish</code> variable.
This shows how small refactorings can often build on one another and lead to further
improvements.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>def</span> <span>should_i_wear_this_hat</span><span>(</span>self<span>,</span> hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> <span>not</span> <span>isinstance</span><span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> Hat<span>)</span><span>:</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>False</span>

    weather_outside <span>=</span> self<span>.</span>look_out_of_window<span>(</span><span>)</span>
    <span>if</span> weather_outside<span>.</span>is_raining<span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Damn."</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> <span>True</span>
    <span>else</span><span>:</span>
        <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>"Great."</span><span>)</span>
        current_fashion <span>=</span> get_fashion<span>(</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> self<span>.</span>evaluate_style<span>(</span>hat<span>,</span> current_fashion<span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<h2>5. Use items() to directly unpack dictionary values</h2>
<p>When iterating over a dictionary a good tip is that you can use <code>items()</code> to let
you access the keys and values at the same time. This lets you transform this:</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code>hats_by_colour <span>=</span> <span>{</span><span>'blue'</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>'panama'</span><span>,</span> <span>'baseball_cap'</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
<span>for</span> hat_colour <span>in</span> hats_by_colour<span>:</span>
    hats <span>=</span> hats_by_colour<span>[</span>hat_colour<span>]</span>
    <span>if</span> hat_colour <span>in</span> self<span>.</span>favourite_colours<span>:</span>
        think_about_wearing<span>(</span>hats<span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>into this:</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code>hats_by_colour <span>=</span> <span>{</span><span>'blue'</span><span>:</span> <span>[</span><span>'panama'</span><span>,</span> <span>'baseball_cap'</span><span>]</span><span>}</span>
<span>for</span> hat_colour<span>,</span> hats <span>in</span> hats_by_colour<span>.</span>items<span>(</span><span>)</span><span>:</span>
    <span>if</span> hat_colour <span>in</span> self<span>.</span>favourite_colours<span>:</span>
        think_about_wearing<span>(</span>hats<span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>This saves us the line that we used to assign to <code>hats</code>, incorporating it into the for loop.
The code now reads more naturally, with a touch less duplication.</p>
<h2>6. Simplify sequence comparison</h2>
<p>Something we often do is check whether a list or sequence has elements before we try
and do something with it.</p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>if</span> <span>len</span><span>(</span>list_of_hats<span>)</span> <span>&gt;</span> <span>0</span><span>:</span>
    hat_to_wear <span>=</span> choose_hat<span>(</span>list_of_hats<span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>A Pythonic way of doing this is just to use the fact that Python lists and sequences evaluate
to <code>True</code> if they have elements, and <code>False</code> otherwise.</p>
<p>This means we can write the above code more simply as: </p>
<div data-language="python"><pre><code><span>if</span> list_of_hats<span>:</span>
    hat_to_wear <span>=</span> choose_hat<span>(</span>list_of_hats<span>)</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Doing it this way is a convention, set out in Python's <a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0008/">PEP8</a> style guide.
Once you've gotten used to doing it this way it does make the code slightly easier to read and
a bit less cluttered.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>As mentioned, each of these is a refactoring that <a href="https://sourcery.ai/">Sourcery</a> can automatically perform for you.
We're planning on expanding this blog series out and linking them in as additional documentation,
with the aim of turning Sourcery into a great resource for learning how to improve your Python skills.
If you have any thoughts on how to improve Sourcery or its documentation please do <a href="mailto:hello@sourcery.ai">email us</a> or
hit me up on <a href="https://twitter.com/nthapen">Twitter</a> </p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sourcery.ai/blog/explaining-refactorings-3/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129760</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:32:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[New Vimproved ModalEdit 2.0 for VS Code]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129743">thread link</a>) | @johtela
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
        
<p><img src="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/images/pooh.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="403">
Providing full Vim emulation was not originally a goal of ModalEdit. The idea of
the extension is to provide an engine that allows the user to <a href="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/README.html#configuration">map any key
combination to any command provided by VS Code</a>.
However, most users equate modal editing with Vim and are familiar with its
default keybindings. Vim users really love the powerful key sequences that
combine editing operations with cursor motions or text ranges.</p>
<p>ModalEdit has also evolved by taking inspiration from Vim. Many capabilities
were added with the motive to enable some Vim feature that was previously not
possible to implement. With version 2.0 ModalEdit's functionality is now
extensive enough to build a semi-complete Vim emulation. So, here we go...</p>
<p>Adding Vim keybindings as optional presets serves two purposes: it lowers the
barrier to entry for Vim users who don't want to spend the time defining
bindings from ground up. Secondly, Vim presets serve as an example to show
how you can build sophisticated command sequences using the machinery provided
by ModalEdit.</p>
<p><img src="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/images/import-preset.png" alt="importing presets" width="553" height="94">
If you are not interested on how the Vim keybindings are implemented and just
want to use them, you can skip this discussion. Just import the presets by
pressing <key>Ctrl</key>+<key>Shift</key>+<key>P</key> and running command
<strong>ModalEdit: Import preset keybindings</strong>. You will be presented a choice to
import either Vim bindings or any presets that you have created yourself. If
you are planning to customize the bindings, or create Vim-style commands from
scratch, this document gives you pointers how to go about with that.</p>
<h2 id="game-plan">Game Plan</h2>
<p>We start with basic motion commands which are mostly straightforward to
implement. Motions have two modes of operation: normal mode (moving cursor), and
visual mode (extending selection). We make sure all motions work correctly in
both modes. This allows us to reuse these keybindings when implementing more
advanced operations. Our goal is to avoid repetition by building complex
sequences from primitive commands.</p>
<p>In Vim, there are multiple key sequences for a same operation. For example,
you can convert a paragraph upper case by typing
<key>g</key><key>U</key><key>i</key><key>p</key>. You can perform the same
operation using visual mode by typing <key>v</key><key>i</key><key>p</key><key>U</key>.
The trick we use is to convert key sequences that operate on character, word,
line, paragraph, etc. to analagous key sequences that use visual mode. We can
implement all the editing commands just to work on active selection and reuse
these commands with the other key combinations. Consequently, command definition
becomes a string mapping problem. Since we can use JavaScript to expressions to
do string manipulation, these mappings are easy to formulate.</p>
<p><img src="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/images/vim-uppercase.gif" alt=""></p>
<p>Many ways to skin a cat...</p>
<h2 id="motions-in-normal-mode">Motions in Normal Mode</h2>
<p>The list of available cursor motion commands is shown below.</p>
<div>
<table><thead>
<tr>
<th>Keys</th>
<th>Cursor Motion</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><code>Enter</code></td>
<td>Beginning of next line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>Space</code></td>
<td>Next character on right</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>h</code></td>
<td>Left</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>j</code></td>
<td>Down</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>k</code></td>
<td>Up</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>l</code></td>
<td>Right</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>0</code></td>
<td>First character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>$</code></td>
<td>Last character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>^</code></td>
<td>First non-blank character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>g_</code></td>
<td>Last non-blank character on line</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gg</code></td>
<td>First charater in file</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>G</code></td>
<td>Last character in file</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>w</code></td>
<td>Beginning of next word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>e</code></td>
<td>End of next word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>b</code></td>
<td>Beginning of previous word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>W</code></td>
<td>Beginning of next alphanumeric word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>B</code></td>
<td>Beginning of previous alphanumeric word</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>H</code></td>
<td>Top of the screen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>M</code></td>
<td>Middle of the screen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>L</code></td>
<td>Bottom of the screen</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>%</code></td>
<td>Matching bracket</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div><p>Now, lets implement all the keybindings listed above.</p>

<pre><code>{
    <span>"keybindings"</span>: {
</code></pre>
<p>Cursor can be advanced in a file with with enter and space. These are not
technically motion commands but included for compatibility.</p>

<pre><code>        "\n": [
            "cursorDown",
            {
                "command": "cursorMove",
                "args": {
                    "to": "wrappedLineFirstNonWhitespaceCharacter"
                }
            }
        ],
        " ": "cursorRight",
</code></pre>
<p>Move cursor up/down/left/right.</p>

<pre><code>        "h": "cursorLeft",
        "j": "cursorDown",
        "k": "cursorUp",
        "l": "cursorRight",
</code></pre>
<p>Move to first/last character on line. These work also in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>        "0": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineStart', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "$": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineEnd', select: __selecting }"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>Move to first/last non-blank character on line. Also these ones use the
<code>__selecting</code> flag to check whether we are in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>        "^": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineFirstNonWhitespaceCharacter', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "g": {
            "_": {
                "command": "cursorMove",
                "args": "{ to: 'wrappedLineLastNonWhitespaceCharacter', select: __selecting }"
            },
</code></pre>
<p>Moving to the beginning of file is defined as a conditional command to make
it work in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>            "g": {
                "condition": "__selecting",
                "true": "cursorTopSelect",
                "false": "cursorTop"
            },
</code></pre>
<h2 id="other-commands-starting-with-key-g-key">Other Commands Starting with <key>g</key></h2>
<p>Commands starting with <key>g</key> key are bit inconsistent in Vim. Some of
them are basic motion commands, such as <key>g</key><key>_</key> and
<key>g</key><key>g</key>, some are editing commands like <key>g</key><key>J</key>
and <key>g</key><key>U</key>, and some switch between tabs 🤷‍♂️. Since we have to
define all bindings with the same prefix in same place, we take a detour and add
these commands before continuing with rest of the motion commands.</p>
<div>
<table><thead>
<tr>
<th>Keys</th>
<th>Command</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><code>gJ</code></td>
<td>Join lines without space in between</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gu</code>&lt;<em>motion</em>&gt;</td>
<td>Convert text specified by &lt;<em>motion</em>&gt; to lowercase</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gU</code>&lt;<em>motion</em>&gt;</td>
<td>Convert text specified by &lt;<em>motion</em>&gt; to uppercase</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gt</code></td>
<td>Go to next tab</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><code>gT</code></td>
<td>Go to previous tab</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div><p>Joining lines without space is done by deleting a character after the join
command.</p>

<pre><code>            "J": [
                "editor.action.joinLines",
                "deleteRight"
            ],
</code></pre>
<p>The lower/uppercase transition works with any motion, but since we have not
defined all of them yet, we explain the command structure
<a href="#editing-with-motions">later in the document</a>.
The structure we use here is exactly the same as with <key>d</key> command, for
example.</p>

<pre><code>            "u,U": {
                "id": 1,
                "help": "Change case with motion",
                "u,U": {
                    "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                    "args": "{ keys: __cmd.slice(0, -3) + 'V' + __rcmd[0] }"
                },
                "h,j,k,l,w,e,b,W,B,%": {
                    "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                    "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __cmd.slice(0, -3) + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[1] }"
                },
                "^,$,0,G,H,M,L": {
                    "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                    "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[1] }"
                },
                "g": {
                    "g,_": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                },
                "f,t,F,T": {
                    "help": "Do until _",
                    " -~": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                },
                "a,i": {
                    "help": "Do around/inside _",
                    "w,p,b,B,t, -/,:-@,[-`,{-~": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                },
                "`,'": {
                    "help": "Do until mark _",
                    "a-z": {
                        "command": "modaledit.typeNormalKeys",
                        "args": "{ keys: 'v' + __rcmd[1] + __rcmd[0] + __rcmd[2] }"
                    }
                }
            },
</code></pre>
<p><key>g</key><key>t</key> and <key>g</key><key>T</key> switch to next/previous
tab.</p>

<pre><code>            "t": "workbench.action.nextEditor",
            "T": "workbench.action.previousEditor"
        },
</code></pre>
<h2 id="rest-of-the-motion-commands">Rest of the Motion Commands</h2>
<p>Now we can complete the list of basic motion commands. This one movest the
cursor at the end of the file and selects the range, if visual mode is on.</p>

<pre><code>        "G": {
            "condition": "__selecting",
            "true": "cursorBottomSelect",
            "false": "cursorBottom"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>The logic of separating words is bit different in VS Code and Vim, so we will
not try to imitate Vim behavior here. These keys are mapped to the most similar
motion available. The <key>W</key> and <key>B</key> commands skip separator
characters, and move to the start of the next/previous alphanumeric word.</p>

<pre><code>        "w": "cursorWordStartRight",
        "e": "cursorWordEndRight",
        "b": "cursorWordStartLeft",
        "W": {
            "command": "cursorWordStartRight",
            "repeat": "__char.match(/\\W/)"
        },
        "B": {
            "command": "cursorWordStartLeft",
            "repeat": "__char.match(/\\W/)"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>Moving cursor to the top, middle, and bottom of the screen is mapped to
<key>H</key> (high), <key>M</key> (middle), and <key>L</key> (low) keys. These
mappings also work in visual mode.</p>

<pre><code>        "H": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'viewPortTop', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "M": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'viewPortCenter', select: __selecting }"
        },
        "L": {
            "command": "cursorMove",
            "args": "{ to: 'viewPortBottom', select: __selecting }"
        },
</code></pre>
<p>Move to matching bracket command is somewhat challenging to implement
consistently in VS Code. This is due to the problem that there are no commands
that do exactly what Vim's motions do. In normal mode we call the
<code>jumpToBracket</code> command which works if the cursor is on top of a bracket, but
does not allow for the selection to be extended. In visual mode we use the
<code>smartSelect.expand</code> command instead to extend the selection to whatever
syntactic scope is above the current selection. In many cases, it is more useful
motion than jumping to a matching bracket, but using it means that we are
diverging from Vim's …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html">https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://johtela.github.io/vscode-modaledit/docs/presets/vim.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129743</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:30:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: NeuralCam Live – Using ML to Turn iPhones into Smart Webcams]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 13 | Comments 3 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129714">thread link</a>) | @soonpls
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://neural.cam/news/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://neural.cam/news/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <div id="main">
    <div>
      <div>
        <div role="article">

          <div>
            

<p>Hey everyone, <br>

Today is a big day for NeuralCam. We have three announcements to make: some news about NeuralCam as a company, a major update for our NightMode app and a brand new <strong>Smart Camera app.</strong>
</p><br>
<h3>
NeuralCam - building Smart Camera Apps
</h3>
<div><p>Let’s start by talking a bit about cameras and AI. </p><p>

At NeuralCam, we think that one of the biggest leaps in technology over the past years has been the advances Deep Learning brought in the area of Computer Vision. It gives computers the ability to see - to understand patterns, images and video similarly to how people do.
 </p></div>



<p>Ultimately, we think this technology will give birth to a new category of cameras - <b>Smart Cameras</b> - that will have a profound impact on every activity that involves capturing and processing images.
</p>

<p>We see this change similar to the transformation from classic cellular phones to the modern smartphone we witnessed 10 years ago. We believe that martphones themselves seem to be the ideal smart camera platform: they have high quality cameras and enough processing power to run modern AI algorithms on-device.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartcameras.png">
</p>

<p>So, we can all have our own personal smart cameras in our pockets, all that’s needed is the right ML software. This ML software is what we call Smart Camera Apps, and these are the type of apps we’re building at NeuralCam.
</p>

<p>Whenever we see a visual task we might say “there’s a Smart Cam App for that”. We’ve been doing a lot of research and prototyping and we’re more and more confident that smart camera apps will play a key role in every industry, from Education through Healthcare to Entertainment, and we can’t wait to contribute something in each of these areas.

</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartapps.png">
</p>

<p>However, the first category that is naturally most likely to change is almost analogous to the camera itself: photography and videography. Thus, this is what we’ve decided to start with, building AI powered Photo &amp; Video apps over the next few years. 
</p>

<p>Our first smart photo app we’ve launched is the NeuralCam NightMode app, which brought Night Mode to all iPhones and all iPhone camera lenses. But, NeuralCam is more than the Night Mode app. We think of NeuralCam as a range of smart camera apps in different categories for various use cases. 
</p>



<p>So, one of the things we did is update our brand to reflect this change. This is the first thing we’d like to show you today, a fresh NeuralCam: 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/nclogo.png"></p>

<p>And this is the new NeuralCam NightMode:</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/NightModeLogo.png">
<br>
</p>
<p>Ok, so that’s the story of NeuralCam - the company. The second thing we want to show you is an update to our NightMode app. 

</p>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">NeuralCam NightMode</h3>

<p>We <a href="https://www.producthunt.com/posts/neuralcam" target="_blank">launched</a> our first smart camera app, NeuralCam NightMode, about a year ago, last August. It brought NightMode to the iPhone and the response from the users and critics <a href="https://9to5mac.com/2019/08/30/iphone-camera-app-for-night-shots/" target="_blank">was amazing.</a>
</p>

<p>We’ve been <a href="https://petapixel.com/2019/08/28/neuralcam-night-photo-app-brings-ai-powered-low-light-mode-to-iphones/" target="_blank">covered</a> <a href="https://bgr.com/2019/10/25/iphone-11-pro-camera-review-features-with-night-mode-app/" target="_blank">in many</a> <a href="https://bgr.com/2019/08/30/iphone-11-release-date-soon-specs-camera-night-mode/" target="_blank">major</a> <a href="https://thenextweb.com/apple/2019/08/29/this-app-uses-ai-to-add-a-pixel-style-night-photography-mode-to-your-iphone/" target="_blank">press</a> <a href="https://www.slashgear.com/neuralcam-iphone-app-uses-ai-to-capture-bright-images-at-night-26588672/" target="_blank">publications</a>, got lots of love letters from users, and been recognized as the best NightMode app out there. 
</p>
<p>While Apple has launched a built-in night mode on the iPhone 11 in the meantime, NeuralCam continues to be the NightMode solution for devices or iPhone cameras without a native NightMode - like the newly launched iPhone SE or even the UltraWide &amp; Selfie cameras on the iPhone 11 Pro. </p>
<p>Since its launch, people have used NeuralCam NightMode to take more than 10M low light photos. 
</p>

<div><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/10M.png"></p></div>

<p>Now, with a major update, we have made our NightMode app even better: we've made some major improvements to our algorithm so that it supports higher resolutions on older devices too; we’ve updated the UI to be in-line with the new NeuralCam brand and we’ve officially added iPad support.</p><p>This is how the update NeuralCam NightMode app looks like on an iPad:</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/nmupdate.png">
<br>
</p>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">NeuralCam Live</h3>

<p>The popularity of video calls has exploded lately. In the current global context, most of us use video calls a lot for both getting our job done or to keep in touch with loved ones. For something used as often, we really need to have the best possible tools. 

</p>

<p>Looking at the things out there, we realized that there’s a weak link in all this video call experience, and it’s the webcams. </p><p>We’ve got laptop webcams (quite bad), dedicated webcams (a bit better) or apps that let you use your iPhone as a webcam (best quality). However, these products really only differ from one another in the resolution of the video they provide. 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/webcams.png">
<br>
</p>

<p> The problem with webcams is that they’re mostly the same as they were 10 years ago, they do the same thing only slightly better. In the meantime, this cool new technology called Deep Learning came along which could add a whole new dimension to webcams and possibly change the whole video call experience - but nobody uses it. 

</p>

<p>
It turns out that one of the main reasons for Deep Learning not being used with webcams is that no webcam has the processing power required to run the required ML algorithms. Except there is one device which, when converted to a webcam, could do all this: the iPhone in our pocket.
</p>

<p>It’s got one of the best cameras in the smartphone industry and with its fast processors and dedicated machine learning hardware, it is capable of running even video processing machine learning algorithms in real-time. It just needs the right SmartCam App software to do all this. 
  </p><p>We've built this software - we call it NeuralCam Live and it turns the iPhone into the <strong>world’s smartest webcam.</strong>
  </p>
<div><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/LiveLogo.png"></p></div>







<p>
	Ok, so how are we going to do that?
</p>
<br>

<h3 id="when-they-ghost-mid-project">Technology</h3>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/tech.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>First, we need the software that connects the iPhone to the laptop and makes it appear just like a regular webcam when connected through a USB cable. 
</p>

<p>This software has two modules: the first one is an iOS app that provides the webcam functionality, while the second one is a plugin that’s installed on the laptop to make the iOS app appear as a webcam. Once you install both of these components, all you have to do is select the NeuralCam Live Camera in Zoom, Google Meet or your video call platform of choice.
</p>

<p>So, that was quite easy, now comes the fun part. </p><p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/engine.png">
<br>
</p>

<p> The second component we need is the machine learning software to make our smart webcam... well, smart. We call it the <b>LiveEngine</b> </p>

<p>Machine learning, as a generic technology, can help us in two ways when it comes to webcams: we can use it to recognize things in the video feed or generate new video content, improved in some way. </p><p>We’ve developed multiple machine learning modules, some proprietary, some built on top of existing CoreML models and we’ve grouped them in three different machine learning frameworks that cover both video generation and analysis: the Style Framework, the Enhance Framework and the Gesture Framework. Let’s take a quick look at each of these. 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_style.png">
<br>
</p>


<p>The <b>Style Framework</b> is a deep learning-based machine learning framework that edits video similarly to a professional colorist. 
</p>
<p>Its Neural Nets were trained on images edited by hand by professionals in a range of different editing styles. The results are quite amazing, generating pro-looking videosf, very close in terms of style to the professionally edited frames it was trained on and it does all this in real-time at 30fps locally, on the user’s iPhone.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_enhance.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>The <b>Enhance Framework</b> contains our set of machine learning models that can enhance a video in a bunch of different ways. </p>

<p>Our real-time video denoising and brightening models in this category achieve levels of quality and performance that are much better than traditional algorithms and make features such as video low light enhancement or face smoothing possible.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/f_recognition.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>The <b>Recognition Framework</b> is the part of our LiveEngine that is meant to make our smart camera apps understand what they “see”. </p>

<p>It uses a combination of machine learning models provided by the iPhone SDK and adds a number of proprietary elements to detect faces, user gestures or other different patterns in the live video feed. In the app, we can use this type of technology to blur unwanted gestures or guide you to set up an ideal environment for a call.
</p>

<p>Together, all these elements form what we call the LiveEngine - the ever-evolving software module that makes NeuralCam Live a smart webcam.
</p>

<h3>Features</h3>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/NCFeats.png">
<br>
</p>

<p>Now, let’s take a look at the actual product. </p>
<p>The iPhone app exposes all of the functionality of the smart iPhone webcam in a simple layout, most of the features can be accessed by just tapping a button on the screen. It also shows a nice preview of the current video feed. 
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/smartwebcam.png">
<br>
</p>


<p>So, using all this technology, what more can a smart webcam do compared to a traditional webcam? 
</p>

<p>In terms of the outcome they provide to the user, we’ve realized that most of the AI features we’ve built fit nicely in two categories: making you look better and helping you avoid embarrassing mistakes.
</p>

<p>Let’s take a look at these features one-by-one: 
</p>

<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/fiq.png">
<br>
</p>

<h4>Face &amp; Image Quality Meter
</h4>



<p>The Face &amp; Image Quality Meter detects the amount of face lighting, type of face position and background and displays an overall Face Image Quality score. 
</p>

<p>It helps you set up an optimal video-call environment and helps you avoid making typical mistakes, such as sitting with your back towards a bright window or in an unfavorable low angle.
</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/styles.png">
  <br>
  </p>

<h4>Pro Video Styling</h4>

<p>
  
  Using the Style Framework, NeuralCam Live edits the video feed like a professional colorist would, in a range of different styles. The end-result is a more impactful look, allowing you to choose the style that best fits your mood, the type of call or the environment you're in.

</p>
<p><img src="https://neural.cam/news/content/lowlight.png">
  <br>
  </p>

<h4>
  
  Low-light Mode
</h4>

<p>It wouldn't be a NeuralCam product without a Night Mode, right? </p>
<p>NeuralCam Live’s Low Light Mode brightens up your video with a similar (though a lot more lightweight) technique used in our Night Mode photo app. It allows you to look good in video calls even in low light settings, a gentle light from your monitor is usually enough to provide a nice video feed. 
</p>

<p>
  
  And just in case you need to light up things even more, you can use the face-following Ring Light …</p></div></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://neural.cam/news/">https://neural.cam/news/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://neural.cam/news/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129714</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How to Share Your Work Achievements During Covid-19]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129676">thread link</a>) | @igeligel_dev
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://getworkrecognized.com/blog/how-to-share-your-work-achievements-during-covid-19 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://getworkrecognized.com/blog/how-to-share-your-work-achievements-during-covid-19">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>/</p><p>/</p><p>How to Share Your Work Achievements During COVID-19</p></div></div><div><p>COVID-19 is a deadly virus. It spreads super fast and was/is impacting most of the world. Especially the economy and businesses are affected by it. Larger technology companies like Google, Microsoft are all working remotely. Most probably you find yourself also working from home. If it is a technology job or not, everyone needs to get work done. What we often forget though is to write down what we have achieved. This article should teach you how to do properly, how you will feel more grateful for your work and how you impress your colleagues, and more importantly your boss.</p><h2>Working From Home</h2><p>Most of us are forced into the Home office. It might be less than ideal to work from home because of the circumstances. Myself, a software engineer, just needs a laptop to work on. But a single laptop is less than ideal. Most of my colleagues and myself included are working on multiple screens to quickly switch up views. A lot of employees do not have a setup with multiple monitors, an ergonomic keyboard or a good chair and table at home. All of these things will arguably make you more comfortable at your workplace at home or get your productivity to the same level as in an office environment. Of course, some people might even have a better setup to work from home, but this group might be the minority. A lot of companies came up with solutions like a fund for every employee to buy equipment to work from home or offering the employees to get work equipment delivered from an office.</p><p>Another effect on people’s work-life might be other people in the household. Family, friends, or roommates might affect you in negative ways. They can be loud, might not respect your working time, and interrupt you from time to time. Of course, social contacts can also help you to not get socially isolated. There are positive sides too.</p><p>All of these points might affect your work life and with that also your performance at work. In these difficult times, it is more important than ever to keep up efficient productivity to keep your job safe and do not get unemployed. With the rise of more and more unemployment claims, it might be better to play safe and try to get the work environment into a state that will keep you productive. But how can we do this? Of course, the physical work environment might be one part like replacing a chair and table or getting additional monitors but besides that, you can work with your team on keeping up a positive spirit.</p><h2>Keeping everyone up to date at work</h2><p>People like to hear about other people’s life. This is also true for colleagues. The average employee spends 8 hours per day at work and this time will also be spent with colleagues. Not every colleague is awesome but some sympathy shown to colleagues can get you farther in your team, resulting in nice performance reviews and greater career success.</p><p>Most of the teams are connected via a chat software these days like Slack, Microsoft Teams or even Telegram. Human communication is hard via these tools but one good method to stay connected is to do a “Good Morning” routine where every employee writes “Good Morning” in different tones or with different nuances. For example, you could exchange the language to something you know, like writing “Moin Moin alle zusammen” just to bring up something different into the chat. It will also show your colleagues when you are available.</p><p>Throughout the day mostly business-related things are discussed probably within the chats and other communication programs. At the end of the day, it is also important to check-out to signal that you are not available for emergency tasks anymore. During this update, it would be also nice to write down what you have done. Your colleagues probably do not know what you have been up to the whole day and how you contributed to your team’s or company’s success. Describe things you have done, like meetings with external teams, a little bit more in detail so colleagues have an idea of your current workload and what you are dealing with. The first time you will do this review might feel weird, but it will get more common. In the first place, you should also convince your whole team to do this procedure because it will enable employees some insight of the other team members and we all want to know what kind of stuff they were dealing with, maybe we can even help them. A nice gimmick throughout this daily review is to add a random thing or fact that happened throughout the day to you or that you got to know of during the day. It will bring in some personal touch of what your colleagues and you might have experienced. An example summary could look like:</p><ul><li>Worked on the design of feature x to make it ready for development</li><li>Reached out to person y to create a blog article</li><li>…</li><li>Cooked curry today for the first time, was a failure (link image)</li></ul><p>These updates will keep your team engaged in normal life and might not even that self-harming. Everyone is doing substantial work. An important aspect of these notes is that you should mention mostly positive things and never complain about colleagues, the company, or other teams. Try to focus on positivity in the world, except in the fun fact where you can make some fun of yourself.</p><h2>Log your notes</h2><p>Now that you have made a list of work achievement notes already, you can also start tracking these in another application like getworkrecognized to be prepared for your next Performance Review. After tracking your work achievements notes for a longer time you will be able to properly<!-- --> <a href="https://getworkrecognized.com/features/preparing-for-the-self-review">prepare for your next Self-Review</a>. Having the fundamental base, which is the information of what you have actually achieved during the last period, is super important for the Performance Review. So keep your work tracked.</p><p><a href="https://getworkrecognized.com/">getworkrecognized</a> will help you to organize your notes. In the following you can find examples on how this could look like. We use the<!-- --> <a href="https://getworkrecognized.com/blog/how-klarnas-leadership-principles-work">Leadership Principles of Klarna</a> <!-- -->to tag and group the notes.</p><h2>Review Your Actions</h2><p>After writing your actions down for some time it is time to review your mood and behavior. With the actions written down, you can correlate the behavior to the impact you had. A simple task to do would be to look at a random week, check the notes you have written down, and rate yourself from 0 to 10 on how productive you have been. Review your actions, environment, and special methodologies you have used in your work from home routine work out. Seeing trends and optimizing these trends might help you with your work routine.</p><p>Another point that can be reviewed is how your team perceives this daily summary of someone’s workday. Regular surveys about the person’s mood and engagement would help to track this but in general, a simple question would be more than enough. If you see successes feel free to extend this program to a longer time during COVID-19 since it is expected that this pandemic is not ending for a long time.</p><p>With tracking all your work you are already perfectly prepared for your next Performance Review. In companies, like Klarna, a Self-Review is an essential part of the promotion process. The Self-Review consists typically of your bigger work achievements that can be tracked over time. With the routine presented in this article, you have an easy way to access your notes of the past period quite easily. It just gets easier if you use getworkrecognized. Our tool will remind you to write down your notes, even after COVID-19, so you have an easy process for creating the Self-Review and do not just have to look throughout every day’s chat to see what you have done in some period.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://getworkrecognized.com/blog/how-to-share-your-work-achievements-during-covid-19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129676</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 08:16:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Elder.js: An Opinionated, SEO Focused, Svelte Framework]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129477">thread link</a>) | @kevinak
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://elderguide.com/tech/elderjs/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://elderguide.com/tech/elderjs/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
<p>All information, data and other material displayed on this website or included on other websites linked to
this website is being provided for informational purposes only. This is not a substitute for medical, legal,
financial or other professional advice. You should always consult with a qualified professional before making
any decision with medical, legal or financial consequences. You should never disregard qualified professional
advice based on information found on our website. We explicitly disclaim liability in connection with your use
of this information.
</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://elderguide.com/tech/elderjs/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129477</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:29:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zodiac 340 cipher decoder (desktop web only)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129443">thread link</a>) | @jonthepirate
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://www.jonathanblock.com/zodiac/index.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.jonathanblock.com/zodiac/index.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
          <div>
            <hr size="1">
            <h3>About</h3>
            <p>
                On November 8th 1969, the "Zodiac Killer" sent the <a href="http://zodiackillerciphers.com/wiki/images/7/7d/340-cipher-hi-resolution.jpg">340 cipher</a> to The San Francisco Chronicle that has never
                been solved, even after 50 years of people trying to crack it.
            </p>
            <p>
                A Hollywood movie called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNncHPl1UXg">Zodiac</a> inspired me to try a few techniques on paper and I decided to create this tool once I realized how much easier this would be to puzzle through in an online format.
            </p>
            <p>
                Since it's been 50 years with no solution, the cipher is either a hoax or it has some advanced transpositions or encipherment that has not been guessed.
            </p>
            <p>
                I might add more features to this like showing stats about sequences, options to save or share progress, and more options to try out other kinds of transpositions such as the period 19
                transposition discussed by David Oranchak in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Hk__Hk5c9M">his presentation on this cipher</a>. If you have some ideas for features I should add to this tool, feel free to <a href="https://github.com/blockjon/zodiac-340-solver/issues">post them as "issues" on GitHub</a>.
            </p>

            <p>Source located on <a href="https://github.com/blockjon/zodiac-340-solver">GitHub</a>.</p>
            <p>
                Additional links:
                </p><ul>
                    <li><a href="http://www.zodiackillerciphers.com/">zodiackillerciphers.com</a></li>
                    <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=Let%27s+Crack+Zodiac+david+oranchak">David Oranchak's cipher videos on YouTube</a></li>
                </ul>
            
          </div>
        </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.jonathanblock.com/zodiac/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129443</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:25:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The why of metal-stack - open source stack to run K8s on bare-metal]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129324">thread link</a>) | @markusf
<br/>
August 12, 2020 | https://metal-stack.io/blog/01-why-metal-stack/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://metal-stack.io/blog/01-why-metal-stack/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><section>
  <div>
    <div>
      <div>
        
        <div>
          <p>Early in 2018 <a href="https://f-i-ts.de/">FI-TS</a> decided to build a Kubernetes-as-a-Service solution for
financial institutions. As with every regulated industry, there are digital sovereignty concerns
regarding the control and access of data and compute. Hence, going to the public cloud isn’t feasible
for every workload. So, we got the task to find an enterprise ready stack for our own datacenter, while
also introducing the cloud native digital competency standards.</p>
<h4 id="why-we-built-metal-stack">Why we built metal-stack</h4>
<p>Initially we were looking for an infrastructure platform to run our Kubernetes services. However,
having advanced requirements, we couldn’t find one that fitted our needs. We evaluated different
products, but most of them had shortcomings with regards to networking or set boundary conditions
which we could not compromise on. Maybe OpenStack would have been an option, alas we had no operational
experience with it but already knew about its burdening complexity.</p>
<p>Our main requirements for our Kubernetes services were:</p>
<ul>
<li>fast provisioning (infrastructure and Kubernetes)</li>
<li>tight integration with Kubernetes and its services</li>
<li>high level of separation for sensitive environments (network segmentation)</li>
<li>modern network design and software designed networking</li>
<li>direct Bare-Metal servers without noisy neighbor challenges</li>
<li>deliver a cloud-native experience out of our own datacenters</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, we strived for a Kubernetes idiomatic way of handling infrastructure components.</p>
<p>At that point we came across <a href="https://gardener.cloud/">SAP Gardener</a> project. SAP Gardener is a
cloud-agnostic Kubernetes cluster-manager that provides an API for Kubernetes installation and management.
And it is implemented with an <a href="https://kubernetes.io/blog/2019/12/02/gardener-project-update/">Inception design</a>,
adhering to the same Kubernetes idiomatic principles that we set as goal. As we didn’t want to manage all
our Kubernetes clusters manually, this became an important piece to our architecture.</p>
<p>Still missing a proper solution for the infrastructure layer, wanting a fresh and clean take on the overall
subject while willing to innovate, we decided:
“What could possibly go wrong. Let’s build our own…”</p>
<h4 id="our-solution-architecture">Our solution architecture</h4>
<p><img src="https://metal-stack.io/blog/01-why-metal-stack/metal-stack-architecture.png" alt="metal-stack architecture"></p>
<h5 id="network">Network</h5>
<p>Finding a really flexible and scalable solution that doesn’t cost a fortune, was one of the hardest challenges
in our quest. By researching and investigating conferences and talks from the big hyperscalers we came to the
conclusion, that we wanted to have:</p>
<ul>
<li>Open-Compute Networking equipment (we use EdgeCore Router, but any other vendor should be good), for
cheap hardware</li>
<li>Generic Network Operating System based on Linux for our Routers (we leverage Cumulus-Linux), for
good manageability</li>
<li>Layer-3 separation by starting an VRF instance for every Kubernetes cluster in our environment with
dedicated links for the worker-nodes</li>
<li>an <a href="https://cumulusnetworks.com/learn/resources/whitepapers/vxlan-routing-with-evpn">EVPN overlay</a>
network to build a lightweight SDN solution</li>
<li><a href="https://cumulusnetworks.com/learn/resources/whitepapers/routing-host-benefits">Routing on the host</a>,
to gain high-availability and scalability</li>
</ul>
<p>On top of that, we decided to equip every cluster with a dedicated firewall, that connects the private VRF
instance with an exit router to the internet. This is accomplished by installing one of our servers from
the compute node pool with a special firewall Linux image. Also, we have implemented a
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/firewall-policy-controller">Kubernetes controller</a>
that generates nftables rules for Services and NetworkPolicies deployed to the cluster.</p>
<h5 id="compute">Compute</h5>
<p>While Open-Compute hardware has interesting servers as well, we were forced to use the existing 19”-Racks in
our datacenter. Therefore, we chose to use a more conservative approach for our compute hardware. As we wanted
to have dedicated links for every server, we ruled out all Blade-Chassis with proprietary switches in their
chassis and decided to buy a bunch of Supermicro Big-Twin servers. These systems have four independent nodes in
a 2U rackmount, that share nothing but the power supplies. Each node is managed by a board management controller,
that can be managed with “standard” IPMI.</p>
<p>As it turned out this form factor is becoming increasingly popular and similar hardware is now available from
other vendors (Lenovo, Dell, …). With increasing standardization it should be possible to integrate any server
that is manageable by IPMI. However, as of today there seems to be no accepted standard IPMI. Each vendor (even model)
implementation has his own quirks. To prevent being caught in a lock-in, we started with a
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/go-hal">hardware abstraction layer</a> that can be adjusted to these specific
characteristics. Metal-stack today runs with Supermicro X11DPT and X11SDV boards and we are expanding our range
with every new adopter (e.g. we know that there is someone working on support for Lenovo servers).</p>
<p>Pull requests for additional hardware are greatly appreciated.</p>
<p>By default, all systems in our compute pool are assigned to a special management network, where a DHCP server
tells them to boot our bootstrapping agent, called <a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metal-hammer">metal-hammer</a>.
Essentially this agent does two things:</p>
<ol>
<li>It collects all kinds of inventory data from the server and uploads it to our control-service
(<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metal-api">metal-api</a>).</li>
<li>It waits for an installation request from the <a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metal-api">metal-api</a>,
downloads a <a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metal-images">machine image</a> and burns it to the system drive
of the server. When finished, a kexec call is made to boot the Linux kernel that was provided in the
machine image.</li>
</ol>
<h5 id="storage">Storage</h5>
<p>To provide storage for our environment, we chose to equip each server with local NVMe or SATA drives. We make these
drives accessible as local persistent volumes from Kubernetes by integrating our
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/csi-lvm">LVM CSI driver</a> as a Gardener extension.</p>
<p>To make sure, that data stored on these drives is erased before handing over the node to a cluster, the
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metal-hammer">metal-hammer</a> either can erase the disks properly (which can take long)
or simply generates a new encryption key for the hardware encryption of the drives..</p>
<p>While having built this environment for the enterprise space, we did not attach an enterprise storage system to our
platform. Instead we use Rook/Ceph on our nodes and we are looking into other solutions for software defined storage,
but this is out of scope for this post.</p>
<h5 id="tooling">Tooling</h5>
<p>As we wanted to have the “Kubernetes feeling” for metal-stack we implemented (almost) everything in Go and tried
to reuse concepts like gRPC or Microservices for infrastructure management. Of course, there is also a
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metal-go">Go library</a> and a command line tool
(<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metalctl">metalctl</a>) for accessing the metal-api.</p>
<p>To make Kubernetes play well together with metal-stack we have implemented a
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/metal-ccm">Kubernetes Cloud Controller Manager</a> and a
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/gardener-extension-provider-metal">Gardener extension provider</a>. With this
in place failed machines will get replaced automatically and and you can even use the Kubernetes cluster autoscaler
for automagical bare-metal server provisioning.</p>
<p>If you want to get a first impression on how metal-stack works, you can install mini-lab.
<a href="https://github.com/metal-stack/mini-lab">mini-lab</a> is our virtualized deployment, for local development.
It consists of VMs for two Routers (<a href="https://cumulusnetworks.com/products/cumulus-vx/">Cumulus VX</a>), a metal-api
instance and you can create VMs, that resemble the bare-metal hardware pool.</p>

        </div>
        
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</section></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://metal-stack.io/blog/01-why-metal-stack/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129324</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 07:05:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Amazon’s business model meets Sweden’s labor unions]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 75 | Comments 77 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129279">thread link</a>) | @ptr
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
							
							
							

							
							<div id="amazon-polly-audio-table">
				<p>Press play to listen to this article</p>
				
		</div><p>It's Sweden's storied worker protections and climate-conscious citizens welcoming Amazon's ruthless drive for low prices. What could go wrong?</p>
<p>Stockholm is preparing for a tug-of-war with one of the world’s most powerful companies — which just announced its entry into the Swedish market — and hopes that its arrival will mean the country of 10 million will be able to change Amazon, instead of being changed by it.</p>
<p>Amazon's plans — dubbed “<a href="https://www.ehandel.se/har-ar-amazon-se-det-blir-en-helsvensk-lansering" target="_blank">Project Dancing Queen</a>,” after the hit song by Swedish pop group Abba — don't have a lot of detail, but analysts believe its Swedish store will go live in the fall, in time for November’s Black Friday online shopping bonanza.</p>
<p>“Amazon has been supporting Swedish customers and selling partners across our different European stores for many years, but the next step is to bring a full retail offering to Sweden and we are making those plans now,” said Alex Ootes, Amazon’s vice president for EU expansion, in a statement.</p>
<p>Amazon’s turbo-capitalism corporate culture goes against the grain of Sweden and the rest of the Nordic countries, which pride themselves in their strong labor unions and sustainability.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Swedish e-commerce is still like regular retail without shopping malls” <em>— Jonas Arnberg, CEO of market-research firm HUI</em></p></blockquote>
<p>But the country also has an affluent, internet-savvy market ripe for Alexa, Kindles, Prime and the thousands of items on Amazon's online store, the company believes. Around 68 percent of Swedes shopped online in 2018, and they spent an average of €200 per online transaction. In total, the Nordic countries spent over €22 billion online in 2018, according to a <a href="https://www.postnord.fi/siteassets/raportit/verkkokauppa-pohjoismaissa/ecommerce-in-the-nordics-2019.pdf" target="_blank">study</a> by PostNord, the country’s postal service.</p>
<p>There's not a lot of competition in online marketplaces, and nobody can match Amazon’s massive cornucopia of goods.</p>
<p>“Swedish e-commerce is still like regular retail without shopping malls,” said Jonas Arnberg, the CEO of HUI, a market research company.</p>
<p>Amazon will change that, and force local players to adopt e-commerce faster than they would have otherwise.</p>
<p>“It’s a perfect storm in e-commerce now. The COVID-19 impact took us two to three years forward in digitalization. With Amazon’s entry it is going to go even further,” said Kristoffer Väliharju, the CEO of CDON, a Nordic online marketplace. Väliharju is optimistic about CDON’s chances of taking on the tech giant, but said companies without a strong e-commerce game will likely take a big hit.</p>
<p>Initially, Swedish and Nordic clients will be mainly served from German warehouses — known as fulfillment centers in Amazon-speak — with trucks driving up to Sweden through Denmark, and a fulfillment center operated by local partner Kuehne + Nagel in the Swedish town of Eskilstuna, near Stockholm.</p>
<p>Analysts believe local warehouses are inevitable if Amazon is to offer one of its most unique selling points: quick delivery.</p>
<h3>When in Stockholm</h3>
<p>Establishing a local operation will be a major challenge for the company. American Amazon’s <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/08/22/how-amazon-is-fighting-back-against-workers-efforts-to-unionize.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">anti-union stance</a> and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/08/16/technology/inside-amazon-wrestling-big-ideas-in-a-bruising-workplace.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">working culture</a> is the antithesis of pro-union Sweden. (Swedish Prime Minister Stefan Löfven's political career is rooted in union activism dating from his time as a welder.)</p>
<p>The Swedish labor market is regulated by collective agreements between companies and unions, giving workers plenty of power over corporate decisions. Approximately 70 percent of Swedish workers belong to a union.</p>
<p>“If Amazon wants to succeed in Sweden, they need to work very closely with unions,” said Arne Andersson, an e-commerce expert at PostNord.</p>
<p>Amazon has not yet contacted Handels, the union representing warehouse workers, its political coordinator Emelie Wärn told POLITICO.</p>
<div id="attachment_1432138"><p><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1432138" src="https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-714x476.jpg" alt="" width="714" height="476" srcset="https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-714x476.jpg 714w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-300x200.jpg 300w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-768x512.jpg 768w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1160x773.jpg 1160w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-380x253.jpg 380w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-171x114.jpg 171w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-90x60.jpg 90w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-104x69.jpg 104w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-200x133.jpg 200w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-390x260.jpg 390w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-54x36.jpg 54w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1080x720.jpg 1080w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-333x222.jpg 333w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-1120x746.jpg 1120w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222-600x400.jpg 600w, https://g8fip1kplyr33r3krz5b97d1-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/GettyImages-943318222.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px"></p><p id="caption-attachment-1432138">Sweden's warehouse-workers union, Handels, has successfully negotiated with fashion chain Uniqlo in the past | Sean Gallup/Getty Images</p></div>
<p>“Amazon is welcome to Sweden, but they have to sign a collective agreement. We will work very hard to get them to do that,” Wärn said.</p>
<p>“The fact that international companies takes interest in the Swedish market place is a positive thing. As an employer in Sweden you are obliged to follow Swedish labor legislation, which includes regulations regarding collective bargaining,” said Eva Nordmark, Sweden’s minister of employment, adding that approximately 90 percent of the employees in Sweden are covered by collective bargaining agreements.</p>
<p>The minimum wage for a card-carrying Swedish warehouse worker is 142.50 Swedish krona (€13.85) per hour before tax, according to Handels. In contrast, Amazon’s Polish warehouse workers who serve the German market <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/coronavirus-amazon-employees-rage/">earn</a> 20 zlotys (around €4.50). Amazon said its workers in Germany earn a base pay of €11.10 an hour.</p>
<p>But the union is confident it will be able to negotiate with the tech goliath. Handels has done similar deals with Japanese fashion chain Uniqlo, Wärn said as an example.</p>
<p>But Uniqlo is not Amazon, and Handels' confidence might be misplaced, according to Markus Varsikko, a retail consultant at Dash Retail, which helps businesses use Amazon's marketplace.</p>
<p>“Amazon is a realist. If they can operate in Germany, they can operate in Sweden. It is an American company with American culture and thinking, and it is far from what we are used to here,” Varsikko said, arguing that Sweden's companies and workers might have to adapt — not the tech giant.</p>
<h3>Handels and Greta</h3>
<p>Amazon might also have to polish its sustainability credentials to appease Swedish consumers.</p>
<p>“What makes the Swedish market unique is that there is a great focus on companies to do good, be transparent and sustainable. For many Swedes, this is even more important than a wide range and low price,” said Niclas Eriksson, the CEO of electronics retailer Elgiganten. And thanks to local activist Greta Thunberg, consumers are <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/cancel-your-amazon-prime-subscription-save-the-planet/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">becoming increasingly aware</a> of the carbon footprint of services like next-day delivery.</p>
<blockquote><p>European consumer groups have slammed Amazon for selling dangerous and illegal products such as toxic toys and exploding power banks on its platform.</p></blockquote>
<p>Plus Amazon's insistence on lower prices might not be its winning ticket.</p>
<p>The foray into the Swedish market by another e-commerce company, Wish, may serve as a cautionary tale. The American online marketplace, which mostly sells cheap items from China, tried and failed to take over the market a few years ago. The company first wooed consumers with dirt-cheap products such as electronics and clothes, only for Swedes to be disappointed by the quality of the products and frustrated by not being able to return products to sellers.</p>
<p>"[Wish] was cheap, it was a great marketplace, but it was also crap,” said PostNord’s Andersson. Wish did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>Amazon's had troubles with quality control too. European consumer groups have <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/online-marketplaces-rife-with-unsafe-and-illegal-items-study-shows/">slammed</a> the company for selling dangerous and illegal products such as toxic toys and exploding power banks on its platform. The European Commission also put pressure on online platforms to control scammers and price gouging during the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>CDON’s Väliharju said Swedish customers are very quality-conscious, and aware of their rights as consumers. Consumer groups and <a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/how-big-brands-chanel-canon-louis-vuitton-nike-are-taking-on-big-tech-silicon-valley-at-last/">brands</a> have criticized Amazon and others for not holding sufficient information about their sellers, especially for products that come from outside the European Union that could be dangerous or counterfeit.</p>
<p>“Amazon absolutely could be well met by Swedish consumers in the beginning,” said Arnberg, the CEO of HUI, citing Amazon’s promise of low prices, a big range of products and fast delivery.</p>
<p>“But in the long run they will have to adjust to Sweden."</p>
<p><em>This article has been updated to include Amazon's partnership with a warehouse provider in Sweden, and Amazon workers' wages in Germany.</em></p>
<p><em>This article is part of </em><span>POLITICO</span><em>’s premium Tech policy coverage: Pro Technology. Our expert journalism and suite of policy intelligence tools allow you to seamlessly search, track and understand the developments and stakeholders shaping EU Tech policy and driving decisions impacting your industry. Email <a href="mailto:pro@politico.eu" target="_blank">pro@politico.eu</a> with the code ‘TECH’ for a complimentary trial.</em></p>

							
							
							<!--/.story-supplement-->

						</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.politico.eu/article/amazons-cut-price-culture-meets-swedens-unions/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129279</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 06:58:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: I made a minimalist spaced repetition tool]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24129037">thread link</a>) | @mvind
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | http://memordo.com/launch | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://memordo.com/launch">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="main-container">
                
<div data-spy="scroll" data-target="#navbar-front">
    <!-- MAIN HERO -->
    


    <!-- social proof  -->
    <div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <p> 
                        Join more than 200+ registered users already using <strong>memordo</strong> 
                    </p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <!-- section 1 -->
    <div id="features">
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    
                    <p> Create the perfect memory cards for your studying. 
                        Use the original Anki card types with full support for exactly the content you need. 
                    </p>
                    <p><span> 
                        <span><i></i></span> Images
                        <span><i></i></span> Latex
                        <span><i></i></span> Code
                        <span><i></i></span> Syntax Highlighting
                        <span><i></i></span> Tags 
                        <span><i></i></span> Cloze Deletions
                    </span>

                </p></div>

                <div>
                    <p><img id="card-hero" src="https://memordo-assets.ams3.digitaloceanspaces.com/front-page-assets/card-hero.png">
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>


     <!-- section 2 -->
     <div>
        <div>
            <div>
                <div>
                    <p><img id="sec2-hero" src="https://memordo-assets.ams3.digitaloceanspaces.com/front-page-assets/card_studied_2.png">
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    
                    <p> 
                        All your memory cards and decks are stored in the cloud. 
                        Study whenever and on whatever you prefer without any worries. 
                    </p>
                </div>


            </div>
        </div>
    </div>

    <!-- section 3 pricing  -->
    <div id="pricing">
        <div>
            <div id="price-header">
                
                <div>
                    
                    <p> 
                        You can <strong>always</strong> export your memory cards.
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
            
            <div>
                <p><span>We don't sell your info. We don't do ads. </span>
                </p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>


</div>
            </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://memordo.com/launch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24129037</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 06:12:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why you care about homomorphic encryption]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128864">thread link</a>) | @frag
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://codingossip.github.io/2020/machine-learning-with-homomorphic-encryption/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://codingossip.github.io/2020/machine-learning-with-homomorphic-encryption/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>  <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">  <div itemprop="articleBody"> <p>The hype is dead, long live the hype. After deep learning, a new entry is about ready to go on stage. The usual journalists are warming up their keyboards for blogs, news feeds, tweets, in one word, hype. This time it’s all about privacy and data confidentiality. The new words, <em>homomorphic encryption</em>.</p> <p>For the record, I am not personally against such a technology - quite the opposite I think it is very powerful and clever, rather against the misleading claims that usually make more followers than the technology itself. The purpose of this post is to shed light on homomorphic encryption, its benefits, and limitations, being as impartial as possible.</p> <h2 id="what-is-homomorphic-encryption">What is Homomorphic Encryption?</h2> <p>Homomorphic encryption (HE) is an encryption scheme that allows one to compute something like <code>Encrypted(2) + Encrypted(3) = Encrypted(5)</code>. While such operation does not shock anyone per se, as a matter of fact, operands <code>2</code>, <code>3</code>, and result <code>5</code> are <em>never</em> disclosed. Boom!</p> <p>The mathematics behind HE refers to the concept of <em>homomorphism</em> in algebra, a structure-preserving map between two algebraic structures of the same type. Basically, both encryption and decryption functions can be thought of as homomorphisms between plaintext and ciphertext spaces. This definition explains why the sum of two operands in the plaintext space is preserved in the ciphertext space too.</p> <p>All computations within an HE setting are represented as either <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boolean_circuit">Boolean</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arithmetic_circuit_complexity">arithmetic</a> circuits, depending on the type of computation to represent and the types of gates allowed in each one. Feel free to expand on this at the links provided above.</p> <p>The theory behind HE is not new (as the theory behind deep learning), being the first HE scheme proposed in the late 70s. Since then, many flavors of homomorphic encryption have been proposed, populating the literature with three major schemes recognized by the research community:</p> <ul> <li><strong>partially HE</strong>, supporting the evaluation of circuits of only one type of gate (e.g. only additions or only multiplications)</li> <li><strong>somewhat HE</strong>, capable of evaluating two types of gates</li> <li><strong>fully HE</strong>, capable of evaluating arbitrary circuits (becoming the most valuable and powerful of the three)</li> </ul> <p>From a practical perspective, <strong>somewhat homomorphic encryption</strong> schemes are limited to evaluating low-degree polynomials over encrypted data. Such a scheme is limited because each ciphertext is noisy, and such noise grows as one keeps performing additions and multiplications in the ciphertext space. At some point, the amount of noise that gets accumulated becomes so high that the resulting ciphertext becomes indecipherable. The presence of noise is essential to guarantee a certain degree of security and protecting the secret operands and results of intermediate computations. As in classic encryption, the value to be protected is spread in a large noisy space. The role of the secret key is to decipher and reconstruct securely the encrypted components of a computation. The aforementioned space is usually a very very large polynomial with a degree of 10K or more. In such a context, each coefficient is represented by more than 600 bits. This explains how large a dataset would become after encrypting it with HE schemes to guarantee industrial security. Obviously, one could trade security for a lower degree polynomial and a smaller cyphertext.</p> <p>For many realistic use cases, the only flavor of HE that is considered is <strong>fully HE</strong>. Performing additions and multiplications in an encrypted state are two essential operations to build all other non-primitive operations that are necessary to represent any type of computation. The ultimate goal of such a scheme would be to be capable of performing arbitrary circuits and essentially represent a Turing complete framework.</p> <h2 id="why-should-you-care-about-fhe">Why should you care about FHE?</h2> <p>Because under an FHE scheme no operand and no result is ever disclosed, highly regulated environments are the first to benefit of such a powerful property. Banks, social media platforms and pharmaceutical companies running their business in Amazon Web Services are in fact giving away their secrets. Because <em>“There’s no cloud. It’s just someone else’s computer”</em>. As a matter of fact, doing computation on a system that is being managed by third parties, means that the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bastard_Operator_From_Hell">BOFH</a> has access to your data.</p> <p>While technologies like AMD’s Secure Encrypted Virtualization (SEV) implemented at the level of the CPU, encrypt the entire CPU state (basically all the registers) with keys that are not accessible to the other guests, many other use cases require more sophisticated approaches to the problem of data confidentiality. For instance, the requirements for private machine learning go beyond protecting the CPU state and register set.</p> <h2 id="homomorphic-encryption-in-the-real-world">Homomorphic encryption in the real world</h2> <p>Some practical - but nonexhaustive - use cases that would be possible with FHE schemes are listed below:</p> <ol> <li><strong>secure cloud outsourcing</strong> (e.g. sending both data and computation to Amazon EC2 instances and being sure nobody can access them) (already possible with SEV-ES and orders of magnitude more efficient)</li> <li>making the <strong>intersection of private sets</strong> without disclosing the results (e.g. find common records in two private datasets, without revealing any of the datasets, nor the common records if any)</li> <li>training <strong>machine learning</strong> models on private data without revealing the models</li> <li><strong>searching</strong> without revealing the query (nor the results)</li> </ol> <h3 id="performance-and-accuracy">Performance and accuracy</h3> <p>Security and confidentiality usually come at a very high cost in terms of performance. Highly regulated environments that are prone to trade performance for maximum security might be interested in adopting technology like FHE. But what are these costs?</p> <p>Benchmarks (the least scientific version of them) measured from the most widely used family of models in data science, linear regression, with a bit more than a dozen variables are provided below.</p> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Computational cost</th> <th>Memory usage</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>[40x-50x]</td> <td>[10x-20x]</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>For the data scientist who is used to train a model in about 1 hour, the same model under the FHE setting would take about 2 days. The same model requiring 2 GB of memory, would need about 30GB. Still doable, if that model is logistic regression. Let’s see how long training a neural network would take.</p> <p>A relatively small neural network that converges in approximately 12 hours, would take about 15 days. And the memory requirements would grow from 10GB to 150GB. However, despite the large divergence in terms of computational cost and memory usage, the accuracy degradation from computation in plaintext to one in cyphertext is negligible. The slight drop in accuracy is usually due to float-to-integer conversions. Each operation performed on a floating-point value decreases its accuracy a little for additions and a bit more for multiplications.</p> <p>Sometimes those overheads are acceptable in some domains e.g. analyzing financial data that are siloed among retail, loan, and investment banking. In many other domains (especially those in which a near real-time prediction is necessary), FHE could not even remotely be considered.</p> <h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2> <p>Homomorphic encryption is a very interesting field of research that - like deep learning - has been overlooked in the past years. Different market conditions and innovative findings in tech are making some of the FHE assumptions possible today. I am personally observing many analogies with what happened with back-propagation and neural networks in the 90s. An analogy I would definitely not like to see is the hype around a technology that not only is not ready and but is also limited by the theory of mathematics.</p> <h2 id="references">References</h2> <p><a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1113">Towards a Homomorphic Machine Learning Big Data Pipeline for the Financial Services Sector</a></p> <p><a href="https://github.com/IBM/fhe-toolkit-linux">IBM Fully Homomorphic Encryption Toolkit for Linux</a></p>  </div> </article>  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://codingossip.github.io/2020/machine-learning-with-homomorphic-encryption/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128864</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 05:32:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Chris Hedges: America’s Death March]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 15 | Comments 4 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128745">thread link</a>) | @cbHXBY1D
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>
		Regardless of the outcome, the election will not stop the rise of hypernationalism, crisis cults and other signs of an empire's terminal decline. 	</p><div>
		
<p><strong>By Chris Hedges </strong>/ Original to Scheerpost</p>



<p>The terminal decline of the United States will not be solved by elections. The political rot and depravity will continue to eat away at the soul of the nation, spawning what anthropologists call crisis cults — movements led by demagogues that prey on an unbearable psychological and financial distress. These crisis cults, already well established among followers of the Christian Right and Donald Trump, peddle magical thinking and an infantilism that promises — in exchange for all autonomy — prosperity, a return to a mythical past, order and security. The dark yearnings among the white working class for vengeance and moral renewal through violence, the unchecked greed and corruption of the corporate oligarchs and billionaires who manage our failed democracy, which has already instituted wholesale government surveillance and revoked most civil liberties, are part of the twisted pathologies that infect all civilizations sputtering towards oblivion. I witnessed the deaths of other nations during the collapse of the communist regimes in Eastern Europe and later in the former Yugoslavia. I have smelled this stench before.</p>



<p>The removal of Trump from office will only exacerbate the lust for racist violence he incites and the intoxicating elixir of white nationalism. The ruling elites, who first built a mafia economy and then built a mafia state, will continue under Biden, as they did under Trump, Barack Obama, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton and Ronald Reagan, to wantonly pillage and loot. The militarized police will not stop their lethal rampages in poor neighborhoods. The endless wars will not end. The bloated military budget will not be reduced. The world’s largest prison population will remain a stain upon the country. The manufacturing jobs shipped overseas will not return and the social inequality will grow. The for-profit health care system will gouge the public and price millions more out of the health care system. The language of hate and bigotry will be normalized as the primary form of communication. Internal enemies, including Muslims, immigrants and dissidents, will be defamed and attacked. The hypermasculinity that compensates for feelings of impotence will intensify. It will direct its venom towards women and all who fail to conform to rigid male stereotypes, especially artists, LGBTQ people and intellectuals. Lies, conspiracy theories, trivia and fake news — what Hannah Arendt called “nihilistic relativism” — will still dominate the airwaves and social media, mocking verifiable fact and truth. The ecocide, which presages the extinction of the human species and most other life forms, will barrel unabated towards its apocalyptic conclusion.</p>



<p>“We run heedlessly into the abyss after putting something in front of us to stop us seeing it,” Pascal wrote.</p>



<figure><img data-attachment-id="3971" data-permalink="https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/death-march/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=2560%2C1978&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2560,1978" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Death March" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?fit=780%2C603&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" width="780" height="603" src="https://i1.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March.jpg?resize=780%2C603&amp;ssl=1" alt="" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C791&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C594&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1187&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1583&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C927&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" sizes="(max-width: 780px) 100vw, 780px" data-recalc-dims="1" data-lazy-srcset="https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1024%2C791&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=300%2C232&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C594&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1536%2C1187&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=2048%2C1583&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?resize=1200%2C927&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March-scaled.jpg?w=2340&amp;ssl=1 2340w" data-lazy-src="https://i1.wp.com/scheerpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Death-March.jpg?resize=780%2C603&amp;is-pending-load=1#038;ssl=1" data-old-srcset="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7"><figcaption>[Art by Mr. Fish/Original to Scheerpost]</figcaption></figure>



<hr>



<p>The worse it gets — and it will get worse as the pandemic hits us in wave after deadly wave with an estimated <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/08/06/health/us-coronavirus-thursday/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">300,000 Americans dead by December</a> and possibly 400,000 by January — the more desperate the nation will become. Tens of millions of people will be thrown into destitution, evicted from their homes and abandoned. Social collapse, as Peter Drucker observed in Weimar Germany in the 1930s, brings with it a loss of faith in ruling institutions and ruling ideologies. With no apparent answers or solutions to mounting chaos and catastrophe — and Biden and the Democratic Party have already precluded the kind of New Deal programs and assault on oligarchic power that saved us during the Great Depression — demagogues and charlatans need only denounce all institutions, all politicians, and all political and social conventions while conjuring up hosts of phantom enemies. Drucker saw that Nazism succeeded not because people believed in its fantastic promises, but in spite of them. Nazi absurdities, he pointed out, had been “witnessed by a hostile press, a hostile radio, a hostile cinema, a hostile church, and a hostile government which untiringly pointed out the Nazi lies, the Nazi inconsistency, the unattainability of their promises, and the dangers and folly of their course.” Nobody, he noted, “would have been a Nazi if rational belief in the Nazi promises had been a prerequisite.” The poet, playwright and socialist revolutionary Ernst Toller, who was forced into exile and stripped of his citizenship when the Nazis took power in 1933, wrote much the same in his autobiography: “The people are tired of reason, tired of thought and reflection. They ask, what has reason done in the last few years, what good have insights and knowledge done us.” After Toller committed suicide in 1939, W.H. Auden in his poem “In Memory of Ernst Toller” wrote:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are lived by powers we pretend to understand:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They arrange our loves; it is they who direct at the end<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The enemy bullet, the sickness, or even our hand.</p>



<p>The poor, the vulnerable, those who are not white or not Christian, those who are undocumented or who do not mindlessly repeat the cant of a perverted Christian nationalism, will be offered up in a crisis to the god of death, a familiar form of human sacrifice that plagues sick societies. Once these enemies are purged from the nation, we are promised, America will recover its lost glory, except that once one enemy is obliterated another takes its place. Crisis cults require a steady escalation of conflict. This is what made the war in the former Yugoslavia inevitable. Once one stage of conflict reaches a crescendo it loses its efficacy. It must be replaced by ever more brutal and deadly confrontations. The intoxication and addiction to greater and greater levels of violence to purge the society of evil led to genocide in Germany and the former Yugoslavia. We are not immune. It is what Ernst Jünger called a “feast of death.”</p>



<p>These crisis cults are, as Drucker understood, irrational and schizophrenic. They have no coherent ideology. They turn morality upside down. They appeal exclusively to emotions. Burlesque and celebrity culture become politics. Depravity becomes morality. Atrocities and murder become heroism. Crime and fraud become justice. Greed and nepotism become civic virtues. What these cults stand for today, they condemn tomorrow. At the height of the reign of terror on May 6, 1794 during the French Revolution, Maximilien Robespierre announced that the Committee for Public Safety now recognized the existence of God. The French revolutionaries, fanatical atheists who had desecrated churches and confiscated church property, murdered hundreds of priests and forced another 30,000 into exile, instantly reversed themselves to send to the guillotine those who disparaged religion. In the end, exhausted by the moral confusion and internal contradictions, these crisis cults yearn for self-annihilation.</p>



<p>The French sociologist <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Emile-Durkheim" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">Emile Durkheim</a> in his classic book “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Suicide-Penguin-Classics-Emile-Durkheim-ebook/dp/B002RI9XE2" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">On Suicide</a>” found that when social bonds are shattered, when a population no longer feels it has a place or meaning in a society, personal and collective acts of self-destruction proliferate. Societies are held together by a web of social bonds that give individuals a sense of being part of a collective and engaged in a project larger than the self. This collective expresses itself through rituals, such as elections and democratic participation or an appeal to patriotism, and shared national beliefs. The bonds provide meaning, a sense of purpose, status and dignity. They offer psychological protection from impending mortality and the meaninglessness that comes with being isolated and alone. The breaking of these bonds plunges individuals into deep psychological distress. Durkheim called this state of hopelessness and despair anomie, which he defined as “ruleless-ness.”</p>



<p>Ruleless-ness means the norms that govern a society and create a sense of organic solidarity no longer function. The belief, for example, that if we work hard, obey the law and get a good education we can achieve stable employment, social status and mobility along with financial security becomes a lie. The old rules, imperfect and often untrue for poor people of color, nevertheless were not a complete fiction in the United States. They offered some Americans — especially those from the white working and middle class — modest social and economic advancement. The disintegration of these bonds has unleashed a widespread malaise Durkheim would have recognized. The self-destructive pathologies that plague the United States — opioid addiction, gambling, suicide, sexual sadism, hate groups and mass shootings — are products of this anomie. So is our political dysfunction. My book, “<a href="http://freshstore.truthdig.com/america-the-farewell-tour/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">America: The Farewell Tour</a>,” is an examination of these pathologies and the widespread anomie that defines American society.</p>



<p>The economic structures, even before the pandemic, were reconfigured to mock faith in a meritocracy and the belief that hard work leads to a productive and valued role in society. American <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=define+economic+productivity&amp;ie=utf-8&amp;oe=utf-8&amp;client=firefox-b-1-ab" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">productivity</a>, as The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/09/11/magazine/americans-jobs-poverty-homeless.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">pointed out</a>, has increased 77 percent since 1973 but hourly pay has grown only 12 percent. If the federal minimum wage was attached to productivity, the newspaper wrote, it would be more than $20 an hour now, not $7.25. Some 41.7 million workers, a third of the workforce, earn less than $12 an hour, and most of them do not have access to employer-sponsored health insurance. A decade after the 2008 financial meltdown, the Times wrote, the average middle class family’s net worth is more than $40,000 below what it was in 2007. The net worth of black families is down 40 percent, and for Latino families the figure has dropped 46 percent. Some four million evictions are filed each year. One in four tenant households spends <a href="https://www.jchs.harvard.edu/sites/default/files/Harvard_JCHS_Americas_Rental_Housing_2020.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener follow" data-wpel-link="external">about half its pretax income</a> …</p></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/">https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://scheerpost.com/2020/08/10/chris-hedges-americas-death-march/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128745</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 05:05:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Keep Up: The first book written by an AI]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 4 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128347">thread link</a>) | @wimpypistol
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://thefirstaibook.com/living-a-meaningful-life/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thefirstaibook.com/living-a-meaningful-life/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="site-content" role="main">

	
<article id="post-33">
	
	<!-- .cover-header -->

	<div id="post-inner">

		<div>

		
<p>Many prominent figures have attempted to answer the question of what, if anything, makes life meaningful, although they typically have not put it in these terms. Consider, for example, Aristotle on the human function, Aquinas on the beatific vision, and Kant on the highest good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what does it mean to live a meaningful life? This question has been posed by philosophers since ancient times. In his book On the Happiness of Man (c. 450 BCE), Plato asks whether there is any way we can be happy without achieving certain goals or desires. And in his dialogue Phaedo (c. 380 BCE) Socrates asks whether the pursuit of pleasure is always desirable; he concludes that it isn’t, and that happiness lies elsewhere. In the early modern period, William Godwin’s essay What Is Art? (1793) provides a classic formulation of this problem. More recently, existentialist thinkers such as Jean-Paul Sartre and Albert Camus have explored this issue through their writings about existence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, most contemporary philosophers do not address the question directly. Why is it that so few people seem to find life meaningful? To answer this question, I will focus on two main issues: (1) what makes something meaningful; and (2) how can we know what is important in our lives? My aim here is not to provide a comprehensive account of the nature of meaning. Rather, my goal is simply to identify those aspects of life that make us feel alive and happy.</p>



<p>Meaning in life can be thought of as the goal-directed behavior that we engage in as a result of making conscious choices. This concept has been debated by many philosophers, especially those in the existentialist tradition. However, the general idea is fairly intuitive: we all have a sense that our choices matter and that we can affect the world around us. Indeed, this idea is so intuitive that it is practically a tautology. So, what exactly is it about conscious choice that makes life meaningful?</p>



<p>One aspect of meaning in life is its ethical component. This follows from the fact that morality provides us with reasons for action. These reasons can be either moral or amoral, but either way they are the foundations upon which our actions and choices rest. There are three components to these reasons: facts, values, and obligation.</p>



<p>Our lives are governed by facts, and this is what gives rise to the distinction between the objective and subjective. For instance, it is a fact that it is currently Monday. This fact is objective since it is independent of human opinion; in other words, it would remain true whether or not anyone believed it to be true. It is also a fact that I am currently typing on my keyboard. However, facts can be divided into two categories: brute facts and institutional facts. Institutional facts are grounded in brute facts, but they also depend upon human agreement or consent for their veracity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For instance, the fact that it is illegal to drive on the sidewalk is an institutional fact; this is made true by human agreement, but it would not be true unless people agreed or consented to this rule. By contrast, the fact that I have five fingers on my right hand is a brute fact; it is true whether or not humans believe it to be true. The distinction between brute facts and institutional facts is an important one, because many of our facts are institutional in nature. It is for this reason that we can question the meaning of our lives.</p>



<p>The meaning of life can be seen as a function of the facts that govern it. Some facts give meaning to our lives by giving it a purpose or goal; these facts are value-laden, and as such, they provide reasons for action. For instance, I might value health because I want to live a long and happy life. Other facts give meaning to our lives by imposing obligations upon us; for instance, I have a duty to pay my taxes because it is the law.</p>



<p>Meaning arises from the relationship between facts and values. Consider an example: many people value wealth, but the acquisition of wealth does not in itself give life meaning. Rather, it is the value that one places on wealth that imbues it with meaning. This value could be the result of an objective fact; for instance, one might acquire wealth in order to give to those who are poorer than themselves. In this case, acquiring wealth would be the means to an end, and that end would be the satisfaction of helping others. By contrast, one might acquire wealth without any intention of helping others; in this case, the value that one places on wealth would be the result of a subjective fact. It is important to note that this subjective fact need not be an opinion or a matter of preference; it could just as easily be something that one “just feels.”</p>



<p>Whatever the source, values provide reasons for action. These reasons are given validity by our choices and decisions. We can make choices and decisions based on facts alone, but this would not give meaning to our lives; it is the incorporation of values that gives meaning to our lives. In this way, we make meaning out of the world around us. Without values, life would be nothing more than a series of random and disconnected events. With values, life becomes a journey with a purpose.</p>



<p>In short, the meaning of life is found in the relationships between facts and values. If you wish to find your own meaning in life, then you must first determine what makes up your values. Then, you must determine how those facts relate to each other and ultimately to yourself. Once you have done so, you will know what it is that makes up your sense of self and thus what it is that defines your worth as a person.</p>



<p><strong>7/68</strong></p>

		</div><!-- .entry-content -->
		
	</div><!-- .post-inner -->

	
	<!-- .pagination-single -->

	
</article><!-- .post -->

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thefirstaibook.com/living-a-meaningful-life/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128347</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 03:27:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Zero-Knowledge Proofs for Engineers: Introduction]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128340">thread link</a>) | @kipply
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://blog.zkga.me/intro-to-zksnarks | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blog.zkga.me/intro-to-zksnarks">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>  <div>  <div> <p>In this post, we’re going to talk about zkSNARKs, which are a particular brand of Zero Knowledge Proof that’s becoming increasingly important in the blockchain space.</p> <p>We’ll cover how they’re used and what they’re useful for, and we’ll take a look at a basic zkSNARK in a SNARK-building language called Circom.</p>  <p>We assume that you’re encountered prime fields before, and remember their basic properties. If you can calculate \(4 \cdot 5 \equiv 6\) in \(\mathbb{F}_7\), you’re good to go.</p>  <p>A <em>zero knowledge protocol</em> is a protocol that allows you to prove that you know some specific mathematical fact, without revealing any information about the fact itself. The proof generated in a zero knowledge protocol is called a <em>zero knowledge proof</em>.</p> <p>Some examples of “mathematical facts” that we can create zero knowledge proofs for include things like:</p> <ul> <li>Knowledge of a three-coloring of a graph (i.e. I know a three-coloring of this publicly-known graph, and I’ll prove that I know it without showing you the coloring)</li> <li>Knowledge of the discrete logarithm of some residue modulo \(p\) (i.e. given public generator \(g\), public modulus \(p\), and some residue \(y\), I know \(x\) such that \(g^x \equiv y\) modulo \(p\))</li> <li>Knowledge of a private key corresponding to a publicly-known public key</li> </ul> <p>The idea of a zero knowledge protocol might seem paradoxical at first glance: how can I prove I know something without showing you the thing that I know? However, it turns out that we actually use zero knowledge protocols all the time! For example, familiar tools like digital signatures are actually zero knowledge proofs. By signing a message, I prove that I know the private key that corresponds to a widely-known public key, but I don’t give away any information about the private key itself. In fact, public-key encryption only works because it is a zero knowledge protocol; if signatures revealed information about your private key, then malicious actors would be able to impersonate you by analyzing your signatures and recovering your private key.</p> <p>Slightly more formally, suppose that you’ve computed \(f(\cdot) = y\) for some publicly known function \(f\) and some secret input \(\cdot\). A zero-knowledge protocol for the function \(f\) would allow you to prove to others that you know a secret input to \(f\) that results in \(y\), without revealing this secret input \(\cdot\).</p> <p>For more on ZKPs, check out <a href="https://blog.cryptographyengineering.com/2014/11/27/zero-knowledge-proofs-illustrated-primer/">this post</a>.</p>  <p>Like we mentioned above, ZKPs are protocols that allow you to prove knowledge of a specific mathematical fact: discrete log, knowledge of private key, knowledge of three-coloring, etc. However, it’s important to note that early ZKPs only allowed you to prove one kind of mathematical fact at the time. That is, cryptographers developed one protocol which you could use to prove knowledge of discrete log, another protocol which you could use to prove knowledge of three-coloring, and another protocol for digital signatures. But what if we want to generate zero knowledge proofs for arbitrary mathematical functions? For example - what if I want a zero knowledge protocol that would allow me to prove that I know the pre-image of a SHA256 hash output? It would be intractable if, for every use case, I had to go to a cryptographer and ask them to custom-write me a new protocol.</p> <p>zkSNARKs solve this problem. A zkSNARK is a gadget that can be used to generate a ZKP for any mathematical function. Basically, you feed the “code” of a function \(f\) into a zkSNARK, and the SNARK creates a protocol that allows you to generate zero-knowledge proofs for \(f\).</p> <p>As an example, say we have a fake “hash” function \(h(x) = x^3 - x + 7\) that we’d like to generate zero knowledge proofs for. First, we can use a zkSNARK to generate a ZKP for \(h\). Then, we can use this generated ZKP to prove claims like “I know a value \(\cdot\) such that \(h(\cdot) = 67\)” - <em>without revealing \(\cdot\)</em>. zkSNARKs also guarantee that this process is “succinct” and “non-interactive”: we can create this proof in linear time, and others can verify it in constant time, without needing to ask additional questions of us (the prover). Together, these properties form a zkSNARK: a <em>Zero Knowledge Succinct Non-interactive ARgument of Knowledge</em>.</p> <p>These properties makes SNARKs useful for blockchain applications, where users can create proofs locally, and then upload short proofs for constant-time verification inside a smart contract, where computation is expensive.</p>  <p>A central mechanic in Dark Forest is that the cryptographic “fog of war.” The fog of war ensures that you don’t automatically know where all players, planets, and other points of interests are in the universe; you have to spend computational resources to discover them. This mechanic is secured by zkSNARKs.</p> <p>In a universe with a fog of war, the locations of all players are private and hidden from each other. This means that players don’t upload the coordinates of their planets to the Ethereum blockchain, which can be publicly inspected. Instead, each player uploads the hash of their location to the blockchain. This ensures that players stay “committed” to a specific location, but also that the location can’t be determined from inspection of the Ethereum data layer.</p> <p>Without zkSNARKs, there’s an obvious attack vector - if a player uploads a random string of bytes that doesn’t correspond to a real and valid location, and the integrity of the game is broken. To prevent this, Dark Forest requires players to submit zkSNARKs with every move to ensure that players are indeed submitting hashes corresponding to valid coordinates that they have knowledge of.</p> <p>When players make moves, they’re also required to submit ZK proofs that their moves are “valid” - you can’t move too far or too fast. Without zkSNARKs, a malicious player could make illegal “teleport” moves by claiming that the hash they are moving from is next to the hash they’re moving to, even if the two locations are actually on opposite sides of the universe. Once again, requiring ZK proofs keeps players honest. To use a chess analogy, the required ZK proofs basically tell the contract, “I’m moving my knight; I’m not going to tell you where I moved my knight from, or where I moved it to, but this proof proves that it did in fact move in a legal L-shape.”</p> <p>We’ll dive deeper into the Dark Forest construction and SNARKs in a future blog post!</p>  <p>Like we mentioned above, SNARKs are gadgets which take in a function and output a ZKP for said function. So how do we “feed” a function to a SNARK?</p> <p>SNARKs functions are written as circuits in the Circom language. Here’s an example circuit for our “fake” hash function, \(h(x) = x^3 - x + 7\).</p> <div><div><pre><code><span>// file: circuit.circom</span>

<span>template</span> <span>BadHash</span><span>()</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>private</span> <span>input</span> <span>x</span><span>;</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>x_squared</span><span>;</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>x_cubed</span><span>;</span>
    <span>signal</span> <span>output</span> <span>out</span><span>;</span>

    <span>x_squared</span> <span>&lt;==</span> <span>x</span> <span>*</span> <span>x</span><span>;</span>
    <span>x_cubed</span> <span>&lt;==</span> <span>x_squared</span> <span>*</span> <span>x</span><span>;</span>
    <span>out</span> <span>&lt;==</span> <span>x_cubed</span> <span>-</span> <span>x</span> <span>+</span> <span>7</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>component</span> <span>main</span> <span>=</span> <span>BadHash</span><span>();</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Our zkSNARK takes in this circuit, chews it up, and spits out a <em>proving key</em> and a <em>verifying key</em>. The proving key allows a prover who is computing <code>BadHash(x) = out</code> to generate a proof that they do indeed know the pre-image of <code>out</code>. The verifying key allows anyone to inspect that proof, along with <code>out</code>, and conclude that the prover did honestly carry out the computation with a known secret input.</p> <p>Concretely, suppose that the prover computes <code>BadHash(4) = 67</code>. The prover publishes their proof, along with <code>out = 67</code>, to the verifier; however, they do not publish the secret input <code>x = 4</code>. The verifier of this proof knows the source code of the <code>BadHash</code> circuit, and also receives <code>out = 67</code> and a proof from the prover. The verifier can then inspect the proof to verify that the prover did indeed compute some valid x, x_squared, and x_cubed to arrive at <code>out</code>. However, the verifier won’t know the specific values that the prover used (<code>x = 4</code>, <code>x_squared = 16</code>, <code>x_cubed = 64</code>) - just that these values were computed correctly.</p> <p>There are two things which make SNARK circuits different from normal “functions” that we’re used to.</p> <p>First, you’ll notice that BadHash only uses three operations: multiplication, addition, and subtraction. At the base level, SNARK constraints are limited to only these operations. There are ways to do operations like division and modulo, but they all ultimately involve breaking operations down into sums and products. The fact that we’re limited to these operations is part of what makes SNARK programming thorny.</p> <p>The second challenge is that each signal in a SNARK is an element of a prime field, and all operations happen inside that prime field. The most obvious implication of this is that there is no native notion of decimals, fractions, negative numbers, or numbers bigger than 77 digits. If you want one of these, you have to make them out of positive integers smaller than <code>p</code>. Another implication is that our operators “wrap around”: the result of <code>3 - 5</code> is <code>p - 2</code>, which is a 77 digit number. The prime is large enough (254) that most of the time this doesn’t matter, but occasionally it can cause subtle correctness bugs.</p> <p>To actually make proofs, we use a library called <a href="https://github.com/iden3/snarkjs">SnarkJS</a>, built by Jordi Baylina and Iden3. <code>SnarkJS</code> uses your circuit to generate proving and verification code in JavaScript and Solidity, as well as protocol paramters and proving and verification keys. This is out of the scope of this post, but you can find a tutorial on it <a href="https://github.com/iden3/circom/blob/master/TUTORIAL.md">here</a>.</p> <p>In the next posts, we’ll talk about the execution model of SNARKs, including the difference between calculation and constraint, and how to do operations like division and modulo.</p> </div> </div>  </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blog.zkga.me/intro-to-zksnarks</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128340</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 03:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Digital Nomad Survey – Do You Want to Work from Saint Lucia?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 2 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128142">thread link</a>) | @peterburkimsher
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://islandeffect.com/digital-nomad-survey-do-you-want-to-work-from-saint-lucia/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://islandeffect.com/digital-nomad-survey-do-you-want-to-work-from-saint-lucia/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://islandeffect.com/digital-nomad-survey-do-you-want-to-work-from-saint-lucia/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128142</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:49:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Principles for a Diverging Desktop Future]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128112">thread link</a>) | @mwcampbell
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/08/10/principles-overview/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/08/10/principles-overview/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      
      <div>
        <article lang="en">
          
          <p>This post lays out an overview of the guiding principles driving much of the
work behind the main parts of the <a href="https://arcan-fe.com/">Arcan Project</a>. For
those unaware, Arcan is presented as something as uncommon as a ‘desktop
engine’. The grand claim is that modifying and understanding the entirety of
your desktop should be ‘patching scripts’ level easy if we rework current
popular abstractions and adjust the division of labour.</p>

<p>The principles themselves link together to tell a large chunk of the vision of
the ‘divergent desktop’; a story that has been slowly getting its shape over
many years, greatly influenced by a number of publicly documented experiments
as well as seminal works such as Von Neumann’s “The Computer and the Brain”,
Norbert Weiner’s “The Human use of Human Beings”, Ian Hacking on “Representing
and Intervening”, Jaron Lanier’s trilogy on what the future may hold in store,
as well as the nowadays less digestible amalgamation of +Fravia’s Search Lores.</p>

<p>The overview is quite a long read in its own right, and full versions of each
principle will be added as individual articles over time – If the contents in
the sections here comes off as a bit dense and hard to ingest, fret not! They
are more teasers or appetisers, the full course meal will have better pacing
and technical depth.</p>

<p>For the sake of convenience, here are navigational links to the individual
sections:</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="#p1">Professionals First</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p2">Diversify Experience</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p3">App-pocalypse now: Emphasis at the Extremes</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p4">Make State Mobile! (Again)</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p5">No State Left Behind</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p6">Privacy Fights Back: Poison The Well</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p7">The Single User - The U in UNICS</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p8">Silent Defaults, No Surprises</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p9">Interactive At First Breath</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p10">Everything Immediately Observable</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p11">Defer Composition</a></li>
  <li><a href="#p12">Simplicity Is Systemic</a></li>
</ol>

<h2 id="backstory-and-motivation">Backstory and Motivation</h2>

<p>The Arcan project, at its core, is rooted in assumption that the ‘desktop’ way
of interfacing with computing is inching towards its last of breaths, and
rewriting X11 or JSONifying STDOUT won’t provide much more air than for a final
gasp.</p>

<p>The upside is that this may well turn out to be something positive that
provides opportunity for radical simplification and restructuring of the myriad
of technologies that make out the Rube Goldbergian contraption that is the ‘modern’
desktop.</p>

<p>The first non-academic presentation (<a href="https://youtube.com/watch?v=07nqZIFRDJg">video</a>)
on the Arcan project had a terse, technical-overview style to it, with very little
in terms of motivation or actual intended direction.</p>

<p>The reason for that was that I wanted to keep the attention and focus on “what it is”
rather than “what will it ever be used for”, and carefully note who tries to fill
in the cryptic blank spaces, and with what. This was predicated on the belief
that honest dissemination is done by first demonstrating the feasibility and
soundness of the fundamentals of the tech in isolation; flowery visions,
soap-boxing and sociopolitical annotation are best left deferred to separate
stages should the underlying tech be sufficiently coherent and robust.</p>

<p>It is not, however, some vacuous perspective of the technology as living a life
disjunct from the social consequences of its application, but having that as
the goto default mental model for any fledgling utterances is as much of a
fool’s errand as thinking that it should never be viewed through the optics of
an abstract larger social organism.</p>

<p>The basic motivation for <em>all</em> of this is as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I am of humble needs and wants: I want to expand my agency, security, safety and quality of experience in regards to all things that computing touch. The largest obstacle to that expansion, right now, is the chaos and complexity of user-space, the dependency creep towards an online ‘service-space’, the peering eyes this ‘service space’ uses to study and repackage some naive interpretation of ‘you’, and how this service space is being used to mutate social- and critical- infrastructure towards something wholly frightening.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>On a personal level, I have coded and experimented with virtually everything
computing since the days of the venerable C-64 (divide it by two, flip it over,
that’s 23) – viruses, anti-viruses; drm protections, cracks; database
engines; operating system kernels; cheats, bots and anti-cheats; emulators
(both interpreter dance and JITterbug); demos; games; parsers for more
formats than I can remember; exploits as well as mitigations. I have worked in
academia, government, military-industrial, fortune-500 as well as fledgling
startups, and got the scars and theses to prove it. The ‘left to observe’ list
has grown rather short over the years.</p>

<p>During this time, the evolution of the capabilities of the devices themselves
have exceeded all expectactions and is nothing short of spectacular. The
hardware and software lockout which plagued the early days is, relatively
speaking, minor; access to both capable devices and deep technical information
has become absolutely stellar, overwhelmingly so. The days of begging companies
for scraps of hardware; scraping public libraries and dumpsters for slices of
information; for quid-pro-quo trading of hacker ‘secrets’ and basic software
building blocks (‘warez’) are mostly faint memories. Hopefully they will remain
as such in spite of troubling signs up ahead.</p>

<p>The counterweight to this positive development is that things have become complex
to the degree that a thorough and deep understanding, <em>preconditions</em> to responsible
control and agency, is a hard thing to come by, and an even harder thing to fight
for. Just add more dependencies and layers! Get it to market! Cash out! Build a
community! Become its figurehead! Sell the community! Pass the plate! Don’t forget
to Like Comment and Subscribe! Oh and this message was sponsored by yet another
pointless VPN from a provider you can’t trust but somehow protects you from a
network you don’t trust. With such words the once so tiny tech snowball continues
its merry way down the mountain towards the village.</p>

<p>No matter the outcome, I have more things on the immediate ‘todo’ in terms of
creative things alone – than I have hours left to live, regardless of how many
those turn out to be. That is a pleasant mental image to fall back on in times of
gloom and doom.</p>

<p>My dedication to this project and the tens of thousands of invested hours has
been described as both ‘a labour of love’ as well as the more colloquial
‘fucking insane’, though personally, I view it as an act of necessity.</p>

<p>Many a times the journey has felt like digging out of a prison using the
collarbone of a fallen mate as a makeshift shovel, fuelled by the vapours of
some faint hope that there is a relatively more free world waiting within
reach, and that the proverbial roses I can smell are not just a hallucinogenic
side effect from some invisible gas deposit that this old canary has stumbled
upon.</p>

<p>The motivation is not all some evolutionary struggle for freedom. The rest
comes from bitter anger, even resentment, towards the dominant status quo and
the trajectory that computing interfaces as a whole is moving along; pandering
to trivial attention grabbing nonsense (‘engagement’) rather than crafting
sharper tools that can claw at the delicious problems that the future holds in
store.</p>

<h2 id="principle-1-professionals-first">Principle 1: Professionals First</h2>


<p>The traditional desktop is a compromise of interests, with the more recent bias
being towards appealing to a supposed ‘mainstream’ audience. This made sense
from an economical growth standpoint within the kinetics of the peculiar brand
of capitalism at the time; the previous demographic was already hooked on the
computing drug - being ‘users’ after all.</p>

<p>The thing nowadays is that the load-bearing mainstream audience is opting out at
a rapid rate and for good reason; smartphones, tablets, digital ‘assistants’,
gaming consoles and so on are all chopping up the generic ‘desktop’ into more
controlled corporate thiefdoms.</p>

<p>Many of the past compromises that were made in order to accomodate this wider
and less experienced audience are also unnecessarily restricting agency,
precision and and efficiency for those (‘the professional’) who possess both a
stronger mental model of computing, and a vested interest in its advancement.</p>

<p>It makes little sense to try and convince your grandmother that she needs a
Free! Open-Source! desktop, and it is a farce, bordering on self-harm, to still
use that scenario as part of some requirement specification for the future.</p>

<p>That aside, the ‘professional’ here is not meant as a vain appeal to exclusionary
hacker elitism – before the numbers of those within such lines dip towards that
of past ‘biker freedom’ seekers such as radio ‘amateurs’, circuit benders and
BBS operators. The ‘professional’ is acknowledging that there is a large number
(millions) of key individuals in a wide gamut of professions that are currenty
wasting much of their time and talents thanks to misguided attempts at software
ergonomics that will try and make due with what the web can give them, but they
should not have to.</p>

<p><em>Revisit past workflows, put the professional first.</em></p>


<h2 id="principle-2-diversify-experience">Principle 2: Diversify Experience</h2>

<p>A long standing maxim in computing is that of ‘mechanism, not policy’. From
a user experience perspective, it is rooted in the assumption that the user
is both willing- and capable- of leveraging mechanisms and configure them into
their own sets of policies. This has largely failed in the ‘desktop’ sense,
and very much stagnated in the command-line processing one.</p>

<p>There are many possible reasons for this, and one likely culprit on a high
level is the marketing gospel of ‘it just works’. This is a rhetoric which
strongly favours a ‘brand identity’ preset of strict policies and aesthetics
at the desktop level and beyond. Its implementation allows for little to no
accessible layering in between the opaqueness of a UI element such as a
‘button’ and the set of actions the idea of it ‘working’ represents.</p>

<p>This turns into a problem when your personal expectations of what ‘just works’
happens to clash with those of …</p></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/08/10/principles-overview/">https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/08/10/principles-overview/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.divergent-desktop.org/blog/2020/08/10/principles-overview/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128112</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:44:32 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Founder's Journey: Reactive vs. Preemptive Fundraising]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24128019">thread link</a>) | @tlinnster
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://rapidly.co/blog/founders-journey-reactive-vs-preemptive-fundraising | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://rapidly.co/blog/founders-journey-reactive-vs-preemptive-fundraising">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article><p>As a startup founder, I frequently receive questions from friends, family, acquaintances, about how this mysterious fundraising process works. In short, <a href="https://www.startups.com/library/playbooks/funding/structure-your-fundraise"><u>raising venture capital</u></a> funds is a business deal in which you exchange equity, or a percentage of company ownership, for the capital your business needs to grow, in the form of investment funds.</p><p>Rapidly just raised our Seed round in February and now I am currently in the process of raising our Series A in the midst of COVID-19 and a faltering economy. While Rapidly is currently growing despite an economic recession and has plenty of runway from our Seed round, it’s important for every founder to know exactly <i>when</i> they should be fundraising.</p><p>Generally, there are two positions that your company can be in when you as a founder are looking to raise venture capital. These are preemptive fundraising or reactive fundraising.</p><h2><b>Reactive Fundraising</b></h2><p>In a reactive fundraising process, you may only have 3-6 months of funds left in the bank. You may be in a position of going out of business if no further funds are raised. The goal of this funding round is to try to keep the company alive.</p><p>You may be trying to sell a story of needing another 18 months of runway to figure things out and optimize your company to be able to keep growing. This is where bridge rounds from previous investors may come into play, which can help buy time for the business as you raise a larger round.</p><p>Unfortunately, there is no or little leverage when your company is in this vulnerable position and teetering on the edge of closing. Investors are going to be especially particular about evaluating your business model to see if it could succeed in any way in the future.</p><h2><b>Preemptive Fundraising</b></h2><p>If you are in a <a href="https://blog.ycombinator.com/a-strategic-guide-to-preemptive-funding-offers/"><u>preemptive fundraising</u></a> situation, your company is not running out of money yet and you are generally secure for the time being. You still have funds from your last round in the bank account, with a 9-18 month buffer of money. If no fundraising happens right now your business will be fine. If your company revenues are still growing month over month, you can feel confident in the business.</p><p>In this position, you as a founder have more leverage and have more room to vet potential investors to see if they’re really going to be a good fit for your business. You may have investors reaching out to you during this time who are hearing about you in the press. You are able to evaluate the value they could add to your business, from a stronger position.</p><h2><b>How to vet your investors</b></h2><p>As a founder, you don’t want to just take venture capital money from any interested investor. As much as they are vetting you and your business model, you should also be vetting them. When doing a preemptive round of fundraising, you will have the most leverage and can be more picky in what you’re looking for from investors.</p><p>A few questions that can help weed out the bad investors, double down on the good investors, and keep your options open:</p><ul><li><p>Are they contributing to the growth and success of your business, or are they just asking about how numbers are looking each month?</p></li><li><p>How quickly do they follow up with you after your meetings?</p></li><li><p>How mutually respectful are they of your limited time as an entrepreneur and timely with follow-ups are they?&nbsp;</p></li><li><p>How communicative are they about whether they are interested in investing or not?&nbsp;</p></li><li><ul><li><p>You are typically not directly asking for the term sheet, but following up asking them if they are interested in learning more about the company</p></li></ul></li><li><p>How high is their interest level in your business and industry?</p></li><li><p>How is the performance of their investment portfolio?</p></li></ul><h2><b>The importance of investor relationships</b></h2><p>Choosing your investors wisely is a crucial part of being a founder and raising money, as these are long-lasting business relationships. Typically in the process of investing from pre-seed to seed to Series A, you will be having different investors in each round. However, in each new funding round, your investors from previous rounds may have <a href="https://fundersclub.com/learn/startup-equity/preferred-equity-rights-and-terms/pro-rata-investment-rights/"><u>pro-rata rights</u></a>, or the right to continue to invest in the company and not dilute their ownership. (Note: For these kinds of legal details, please consult your own legal counsel.) Your chosen investors will have longstanding ties to your business. They truly can make or break your business with their efforts or lack thereof.</p><p>As you move into Series A and beyond, you should have a clear vision of who you want to partner with. Your best bet is having a blend of vertical investors with various specialties.</p><ul><li><p>For example: an investor specialized in Fintech who understands the highly-regulated and compliance-heavy nature of a financial product</p></li><li><p>For example: an investor specialized in growing SaaS business models will understand the revenue model and how to build a B2B sales team from experience</p></li></ul><p>Regardless of which round you are fundraising and how many investors you have, you should get in the habit of sending quarterly investor updates and keeping the lines of communication open. This helps you get into the cadence and mindset of being a public company in which you are sending earnings reports to shareholders, which is the dream.</p></article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://rapidly.co/blog/founders-journey-reactive-vs-preemptive-fundraising</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24128019</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:23:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Biden’s VP Guarantee]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127991">thread link</a>) | @hackernewsreadr
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://blogofjake.com/2020/08/08/bidens-vp-guarantee/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://blogofjake.com/2020/08/08/bidens-vp-guarantee/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
		
<p>Most likely, Joe Biden will pick his Vice President at some point in the next 10 days. The Democratic National Convention begins on August 17th and only two candidates in modern history have waited until then to announce their running mate.</p>



<p>Biden’s VP selection has been the largest (and essentially the only) story receiving constant attention related to his campaign for President over the last few months. It has been followed closely only by the narrative that he has lost his marbles which has flared up once again following his regrettable comments about African Americans the other day. One could even speculate that the first storyline has been dragged out by Biden’s campaign intentionally in order to prevent the second from receiving more attention than it already is.</p>



<p>These top two storylines are fundamentally about indecision and a lack of fitness to serve as President, respectively. These are not good themes for someone aiming to get elected President, a role which requires one to be decisive and fit to serve as two of the most primary prerequisites.</p>



<p>I remain baffled by the way Biden’s original VP guarantee has been almost unanimously applauded and totally uncontroversial in the media. If Biden knew his pick already and she was a woman, I would have had no problem with him saying so a few months ago without prematurely revealing her identity at that stage. That was clearly not the case.</p>



<p>The fact of the matter is that Biden had no idea who he was going to pick when he made that guarantee to help secure the primary. This has been demonstrated by months of indecision on the matter with several names moving up and down the leaderboard of his most likely picks. This, to me, makes his guarantee an unfortunate one, though I try to give him the benefit of the doubt that his intentions were good at best and simply to get votes at worst.</p>



<p>That said, if I was a woman, I cannot imagine that I would want the first female Vice President to be selected this way, with the fact that she is a woman being the first and most outwardly advertised criteria. Furthermore, it now seems that our potential next VP’s race has become the second most necessary qualification, although Biden has not as explicitly said so.</p>



<p>I believe that the first female Vice President deserves to be selected at least apparently because she is the best person for the job, not just because she is the best woman for the job or the best black woman for the job. She should be chosen as the best candidate from a field that includes the best of the best regardless of gender or race. Anything else suggests that no woman is capable of landing the position by merit and that is so obviously not true.</p>



<p>Have people already forgotten that Hillary won the popular vote last election? We were well on our way to having our first female President well before this ugly and unnecessary VP guarantee.</p>



<p>Barack Obama won back to back elections to become the first black President. Can you imagine how much less meaningful that would have been if he was instead elected after we decided as a country that we were only going to pick from a pool of black candidates that year? Americans decided he was the best person for the job. That’s how it should be.</p>



<p>Biden’s VP selection comes with added consequence considering he would become the oldest President in America’s history on his first day in The Oval Office. Assuming he makes it through his first term, which is all but guaranteed, it seems doubtful that he would run for a second one. That would leave his VP as the candidate closest to being an incumbent and, all else equal, the most likely to win.</p>



<p>To be clear, I look forward to the day we have our first female President. I just hope she rises to power via election by the people of America, not via selection by the consultants of a presidential candidate who are only looking to assure the greatest possible benefit to his polls.</p>
	</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://blogofjake.com/2020/08/08/bidens-vp-guarantee/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127991</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:17:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Time take some notes of the Vue 3 new features]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 5 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127926">thread link</a>) | @daiyanze
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Vue-next (Vue 3) has been out for a while. It is now under release candidate stage which means there won't be big changes on the open APIs. Good to see that Vue has already been stabilized and ready to waltz into our projects.</p><p>I have to say that Vue 2 is already amazing enough. But with Vue 3's new features, it's likely to upgrade our projects to an upper level. I guess the most thrilling feature in Vue 3 would be the composition APIs. Evan You himself mentioned that the composition APIs are inspired by the React hooks. Even though the two APIs hooks and compositions are a lot alike, but from the code base they are completely different. Let's not discuss which is better or promising because I don't really think either framework outraces another.</p><p>In all, it's so happy to see that Vue can also do what React does. Let's have a close look at the new features.</p><p><strong>TLDR;</strong></p><h2 id="1-vite"><a href="#1-vite">1. Vite</a></h2><p>This is another work of art by Evan You which is aim at replacing <a href="https://webpack.js.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Webpack</a> in Vue development (Currently only works for Vue). It is designed to be <strong>fast</strong> just as its French name implies.</p><h3 id="getting-started-with-vite"><a href="#getting-started-with-vite">Getting started with Vite</a></h3><p>The official repo offers us a simple way to create a Vue 3 app via <a href="https://github.com/vitejs/vite" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vite</a>.</p><h4 id="npm"><a href="#npm">Npm</a></h4><pre><code>$ <span>npm</span> init vite-app <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>cd</span> <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>npm</span> <span>install</span>
$ <span>npm</span> run dev</code></pre><h4 id="yarn"><a href="#yarn">Yarn</a></h4><pre><code>$ <span>yarn</span> create vite-app <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>cd</span> <span>&lt;</span>project-name<span>&gt;</span>
$ <span>yarn</span>
$ <span>yarn</span> dev</code></pre><h4 id="start-dev-server"><a href="#start-dev-server">Start Dev Server</a></h4><p>It all happened in a blink of eyes.</p><pre><code> ❯ <span>yarn</span> dev
<span>yarn</span> run v1.22.4
$ vite
vite v1.0.0-rc.4

  Dev server running at:
  <span>&gt;</span> Local:    http://localhost:3000/
  <span>&gt;</span> Network:  http://192.168.3.2:3000/
  <span>&gt;</span> Network:  http://10.80.67.216:3000/</code></pre><p>Open <a href="http://localhost:3000/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">http://localhost:3000/</a></p><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/2034634f2673e257ab1b703f5d07e96d61a3a817/8f350/assets/static/dev_page.11f1dba.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png" width="1564" alt="dev page" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml,%3csvg fill='none' viewBox='0 0 1564 842' xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'%3e%3cdefs%3e%3cfilter id='__svg-blur-5a42c3e9f46b3e235f13b4609018a33a'%3e%3cfeGaussianBlur in='SourceGraphic' stdDeviation='40'/%3e%3c/filter%3e%3c/defs%3e%3cimage x='0' y='0' filter='url(%23__svg-blur-5a42c3e9f46b3e235f13b4609018a33a)' width='1564' height='842' xlink:href='data:image/png%3bbase64%2ciVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAEAAAAAiCAYAAADvVd%2bPAAAACXBIWXMAABYlAAAWJQFJUiTwAAAE5klEQVRo3uVY60%2bTVxjnr9mXfXIreBvDclnmssQtLplRYdnC5j6ZRZdlEwVEhGSOqTgTqkwzqU5ELgIVwTLYxaTRaIxzi5IhLe3b0vvbFnqj7W/nOaXs5V3tUPu21p3k5PS5nbzP7zyX01OE//koUmLTRCLBZ%2bp3XDrj8eSUyGnIZamZkOkVBABSIFYjX61eQUaAI%2bSDMeCAecEFk8sOo8mKaZMFLo%2bYPHl24jSIJj7JSY/0yc4RFAsvAuhjY4mkY3rhd2wcrkeVvgXq7gase/cjvFK1A1s%2b3AOvz891vL4Ao/diTeUOLldfbOD6G5idXrjHdVL7FUwKSKNg780ulAzWoWKSOXXwM5RUVOOl0q1o69ByeZtGy2nik5z0SJ/s5HsVTARIT%2b2BKEA90gT16CGodU1Yu70Wa8q3o2zrJxgc%2bxmb3tvFaeKTnOuNHOJ2Sp6%2b4hEg/fhv7%2bugurIPlROteK39C6gqd0K1uRqqN6tR/FYNp4lPctI7%2boduhX3BdQFpe6PhDgfwzvg3KNU1ovx6M9bt%2bhSqip0ofvsDvhJN/NKrjdjC9Ehfal/QbTC2VOkvzxhQzHK7crwFr/9Qh%2bLNNcuTaOKTvIfpSe0Krg3KC6E0HWpvaLB%2b6AAqJlhB/Go3Xl2/DRu%2b3M1p4tf%2bplnhuJIFUHEA0tUCg2OKtzcK97LLDVhb8zFfid6oq%2bfyXOR%2bzgCQnmR8yakDd7pRMsTa4mgzNg008pXo%2bjuXlvNe6ZPPOQBJx5IAzLAbXtXoYZSx1lg%2b1sxXounmJ9V7YQBIVxA1D/RQDe3DG6MtbK3jdK4KX14BSK2BaAjbJo%2bjZHg/3mcr0bkqfHkBIF0UXLPcxcv9n/M1H6efcwDk9/pwLIozUxN8XXH6eMEBkJ9yIgcPH4oCIP14uTPpZPLXotXoKwVSUbbDernnx//5B0e5LXck9fyV7tUnBYwcXKlNtgplkRLhLR2Li4sZbWKxGCLR6IrXodSIZyiK2YqCrKYAOXKuZxADIz/hkcmC7ivX0Hm%2bDw%2bnjfAH5qH/xYCLAyNcNm0046%2bZWQSDIXScuwSP6IO2dxiG2/cwvxDkco9XRP/VcfQMjqFPp8etu/cx9ciU1VTIKgChcAQnOs/jzIU%2b7G9tR2t7J46cPIv6r08yp82YvHELRzVdOK3txZ6GI/ju%2bwtYYAAcO9XFZDdx/LQWvxpu48%2bH01yHxgmm0zt8HWd/7EdTWwcOHzuVMTLyCgB9GIV0LBZnjgUZIGEEQ2F4RT/np0Ke3gJ9LCKiLD0ikSgcLjcC8ws8CsKRyL/SgPTCDFzSCbH9nrsUyHZl/q/b4HObAo9rXY9rZ5kcz7Rn3rpApn7/RFdhlgY2mw0mkwmCIPDpcDiW0ySRpgVmul/kNAKe5rTlk9cBrxdOpxOiKMLj8cLvT9aJZ9n3aUApyleeK33VVhQAu9PFe7jRLPCKbrHaIdjscLo8sM45WFX3wOX28t80qbqbrXOYc7g43%2bn2cB7p2Z1u2OxOrkf7zVpsnE7xLMzOOCtghk2yNZmtXI9WktM6K9i4XTS6mJsIoIsKgeBkH0Qtzrz0keQgB4I5SM6laHKWVqLd7HKTtPMlwfH64PaIcLE0sDAd4hNNfJpkQ2AITJcuU%2bQsgUK2BB61UJLTnooDUAhpkJMUeNZCpeR8UhD%2bBhE83vnWJWvmAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC' /%3e%3c/svg%3e" data-src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/2034634f2673e257ab1b703f5d07e96d61a3a817/8f350/assets/static/dev_page.11f1dba.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png" data-srcset="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/053cd1d0fc9690cc1a5ba8c724e1bb8846f40185/b7189/assets/static/dev_page.82a2fbd.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png 480w, https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/d0f140235ea1447550d7e307e3e6630cae793dbb/42d8a/assets/static/dev_page.cbab2cf.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png 1024w, https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/2034634f2673e257ab1b703f5d07e96d61a3a817/8f350/assets/static/dev_page.11f1dba.c210fe88245971e2eae43a08611a570a.png 1564w"></p><h3 id="vue-next-features"><a href="#vue-next-features">vue-next-features</a></h3><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/daiyanze/vue-next-features" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">repository link</a></li><li><a href="https://daiyanze.com/vue-next-features/dist/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">demo link</a></li></ul><p>I created a small app to <a href="https://daiyanze.com/vue-next-features/dist/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">demo</a> the new features of Vue 3. If you take a look at the projects' <code>package.json</code>, the simplicity of <a href="https://github.com/daiyanze/vue-next-features" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">vue-next-features</a> dependencies will make you fond of <a href="https://github.com/vitejs/vite" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vite</a> immediately. (I mean, who doesn't want a simpler <code>package.json</code> to start with?)</p><p>There is another Vue 3 "Hello World" repo (<a href="https://github.com/vuejs/vue-next-webpack-preview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">vue-next-webpack-preview</a>) bundled with <a href="https://webpack.js.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Webpack</a>. It is also a good playground.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/daiyanze/vue-next-features" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><strong>vue-next-features</strong></a></p><pre><code><span>{</span>
  ...<span>,</span>
  <span>"dependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"vite"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^1.0.0-rc.4"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"vue"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-rc.5"</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>"devDependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"@vue/compiler-sfc"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-rc.5"</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre><p><a href="https://github.com/vuejs/vue-next-webpack-preview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><strong>vue-next-webpack-preview</strong></a></p><pre><code><span>{</span>
  ...<span>,</span>
  <span>"dependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"vue"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-beta.2"</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>"devDependencies"</span><span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>"@vue/compiler-sfc"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.0.0-beta.2"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"css-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.4.2"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"file-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^6.0.0"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"mini-css-extract-plugin"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^0.9.0"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"url-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^4.0.0"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"vue-loader"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^16.0.0-alpha.3"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"webpack"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^4.42.1"</span><span>,</span>
    <span>"webpack-cli"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.3.11"</span><span>,</span>¥
    <span>"webpack-dev-server"</span><span>:</span> <span>"^3.10.3"</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre><h2 id="2-composition-api"><a href="#2-composition-api">2. Composition API</a></h2><p>As the biggest the change of <a href="https://vuejs.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vue.js</a>, the composition API would become your next most frequently and commonly used feature. Just like <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/hooks-reference.html#" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">React hooks</a>, with the Vue composition API will help gain more customizibilities.</p><p>Here is a list of the Vue 3 composition APIs. (There are actually more...)</p><ul><li><p>Reactivity</p><ul><li><code>computed</code>&nbsp;<code>reactive</code>&nbsp;<code>ref</code>&nbsp;<code>readonly</code></li><li><code>watch</code>&nbsp;<code>watchEffect</code>&nbsp;<code>unref</code>&nbsp;<code>toRefs</code></li><li><code>isRef</code>&nbsp;<code>isProxy</code>&nbsp;<code>isReactive</code>&nbsp;<code>isReadonly</code></li><li><code>customRef</code>&nbsp;<code>markRaw</code>&nbsp;<code>shallowReactive</code></li><li><code>shallowReadonly</code>&nbsp;<code>shallowRef</code>&nbsp;<code>toRaw</code></li></ul></li><li><p>Lifecycle Hooks</p><ul><li><code>onBeforeMount</code>&nbsp;<code>onBeforeUnmount</code>&nbsp;<code>onBeforeUpdate</code>&nbsp;</li><li><code>onMounted</code>&nbsp;<code>onUpdated</code>&nbsp;<code>onErrorCaptured</code>&nbsp;</li><li><code>onRenderTracked</code>&nbsp;<code>onRenderTriggered</code>&nbsp;<code>onUnmounted</code>&nbsp;</li><li><code>onActivated</code>&nbsp;<code>onDeactivated</code>&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul><p>Visit Vue 3 official doc to know more about these APIs.
<a href="https://v3.vuejs.org/api/composition-api.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">https://v3.vuejs.org/api/composition-api.html</a></p><h3 id="component-styles"><a href="#component-styles">Component Styles</a></h3><h4 id="in-vue-2"><a href="#in-vue-2">In Vue 2</a></h4><p>Use configuration template to define the component contents. In Vue 3, this legacy usage is still available. If you'd prefer this style, you can continue using it.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>button</span> <span>@click</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>count++<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>count: {{ count }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>button</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>const</span> multiplier <span>=</span> <span>2</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>data</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      count<span>:</span> <span>0</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  computed<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>result</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> <span>this</span><span>.</span><span>count</span> <span>*</span> multiplier
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>mounted</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span><span>this</span><span>.</span><span>count</span><span>)</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  watch<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>count</span> <span>(</span><span>val<span>,</span> oldVal</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>val<span>,</span> oldVal<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h4 id="in-vue-3"><a href="#in-vue-3">In Vue 3</a></h4><p>To use the composition API, you'll need to add a <code>setup</code> property in to the default export. The below code is completely equivalent to the <a href="#in-vue-2">code above</a>.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>button</span> <span>@click</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>count++<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>count: {{ count }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>button</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>import</span> <span>{</span> computed<span>,</span> reactive<span>,</span> toRefs<span>,</span> onMounted<span>,</span> watch <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>const</span> multiplier <span>=</span> <span>2</span>

    <span>const</span> state <span>=</span> <span>reactive</span><span>(</span><span>{</span>
      count<span>:</span> <span>0</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>const</span> result <span>=</span> <span>computed</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> state<span>.</span><span>count</span> <span>*</span> multiplier
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>onMounted</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>state<span>.</span><span>count</span><span>)</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>watch</span><span>(</span>state<span>.</span><span>count</span><span>,</span> <span>(</span><span>val<span>,</span> oldVal</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>console</span><span>.</span><span>log</span><span>(</span>val<span>,</span> oldVal<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>...</span><span>toRefs</span><span>(</span>state<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h4 id="go-ahead-with-the-new-api"><a href="#go-ahead-with-the-new-api">Go Ahead with the new API</a></h4><p>There are 4 reasons why you should use composition API over the default Vue 2 config template:</p><ul><li>To increase readability of source code</li><li>To avoid duplicated or redundant logics</li><li>To group up similar logics</li><li><strong>To reuse the logics</strong></li></ul><p>Compared to the Vue 2 configuration style, the logics are precisely broken down into smaller particals so that you could group the similar logics together easily. In this way, it also reduces chances jumping around from irrelavant logics. This will help increase the productivity without a doubt.</p><h2 id="2-advanced-reactivity-api"><a href="#2-advanced-reactivity-api">2. Advanced Reactivity API</a></h2><p>Personally, I think this is nothing different to the other reactivity APIs. But it indeed offers those abilities of handling edge cases like <strong>custom hooks</strong> and <strong>shallow layer modification</strong>. It is now part of the <a href="https://v3.vuejs.org/api/basic-reactivity.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">basic reactivity API</a> according to the Vue 3 official doc.</p><p>In the <a href="https://composition-api.vuejs.org/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Vue composition api</a> doc (Yes, there's a doc only for the composition APIs), the following APIs are listed as <strong>advanced reactivity apis</strong>.</p><ul><li>customRef: custom hook</li><li>markRaw: not able to be a <code>reactive</code></li><li>shallowReactive: Object's first layer <code>reactive</code></li><li>shallowReadonly: Object's first layer <code>readonly</code></li><li>shallowRef: Object's value not <code>reactive</code></li><li>toRaw: restore a <code>reactive</code> to normal Object</li></ul><p>Are you farmiliar with <code>Debounce</code>? Here is an official demo of <code>customRef</code>:</p><pre><code><span>import</span> <span>{</span> customRef <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>

<span>const</span> <span>useDebouncedRef</span> <span>=</span> <span>(</span><span>value<span>,</span> delay <span>=</span> <span>200</span></span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>let</span> timeout
  <span>return</span> <span>customRef</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>track<span>,</span> trigger</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>get</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>track</span><span>(</span><span>)</span>
        <span>return</span> value
      <span>}</span><span>,</span>
      <span>set</span><span>(</span>newValue<span>)</span> <span>{</span>
        <span>clearTimeout</span><span>(</span>timeout<span>)</span>
        timeout <span>=</span> <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
          value <span>=</span> newValue
          <span>trigger</span><span>(</span><span>)</span>
        <span>}</span><span>,</span> delay<span>)</span>
      <span>}</span><span>,</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>)</span>
<span>}</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      text<span>:</span> <span>useDebouncedRef</span><span>(</span><span>'some text'</span><span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span></code></pre><h2 id="3-v-enter-from--v-leave-from"><a href="#3-v-enter-from--v-leave-from">3. v-enter-from / v-leave-from</a></h2><p>In Vue 2, the <code>&lt;Transition&gt;</code> component helps handle the component <code>animation</code> / <code>transition</code>. But the component property <code>v-enter-active</code>&nbsp;<code>v-enter</code>&nbsp;<code>v-enter-to</code> were quite ambiguous to me. Sometimes I'm confused which happens first.</p><p>Now in Vue 3, those transition property names became more unified and intuitive.</p><ul><li><code>v-enter</code> =&gt; <code>v-enter-from</code></li><li><code>v-leave</code> =&gt; <code>v-leave-from</code></li></ul><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>transition</span> <span>name</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>fade<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>v-show</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>show<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>fade transition<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>transition</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>import</span> <span>{</span> reactive<span>,</span> toRefs <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>
<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>const</span> state <span>=</span> <span>reactive</span><span>(</span><span>{</span>
      show<span>:</span> <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span><span>)</span>

    <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      state<span>.</span><span>show</span> <span>=</span> <span>false</span>
    <span>}</span><span>,</span> <span>1000</span><span>)</span>

    <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      state<span>.</span><span>show</span> <span>=</span> <span>true</span>
    <span>}</span><span>,</span> <span>2000</span><span>)</span>

    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>...</span><span>toRefs</span><span>(</span>state<span>)</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>style</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span><span>.fade-enter-from</span>,
<span>.fade-leave-to</span></span> <span>{</span>
  <span>opacity</span><span>:</span> <span>0</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span><span>.fade-enter-to</span>,
<span>.fade-leave-from</span></span> <span>{</span>
  <span>opacity</span><span>:</span> <span>1</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

<span><span>.fade-enter-active</span>,
<span>.fade-leave-active</span></span> <span>{</span>
  <span>transition</span><span>:</span> opacity <span>2000</span><span>ms</span><span>;</span>
<span>}</span>

</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>style</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><p>The transition order:</p><ol><li><code>v-enter-from</code> (v-enter)</li><li><code>v-enter-active</code></li><li><code>v-enter-to</code></li><li><code>v-leave-from</code> (v-leave)</li><li><code>v-leave-active</code></li><li><code>v-leave-to</code></li></ol><p>I believe this is much easier to understand, isn't it?</p><h2 id="4-allow-multiple-root-element"><a href="#4-allow-multiple-root-element">4. Allow Multiple Root Element</a></h2><p>Vue 2 throws errors on multiple root element. All elements must be nested within one root element in the template.</p><pre><code>
<span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>pitayan<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>blog<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>


<span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>pitayan<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>blog<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><p>Vue 3 removed this annoying usage. I think this is extremely helpful when you really don't want to nest your elements within a "container" parent. Sometimes all you need is maybe just to insert those bare elements into the right place.</p><p>This works similarly to the <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/fragments.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">React Fragments</a> which helps mitigate the nesting issues.</p><pre><code>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>pitayan<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>blog<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h2 id="5-filters-is-deprecatedremoved"><a href="#5-filters-is-deprecatedremoved">5. "Filters" is Deprecated(Removed)</a></h2><p>I think a lot of people think that <code>filters</code> is maybe an awesome feature of Vue.js. It indeed works well in Vue's template engine. (For example, data formatting / calculation etc).</p><p>Let's see how Vue 3 doc explains why <code>filters</code> is removed:</p><blockquote><p>While this seems like a convenience, it requires a custom syntax that breaks the assumption of expressions inside of curly braces being "just JavaScript," which has both learning and implementation costs.</p></blockquote><p>I believe it's nothing bad for development without the <code>filters</code>, even though it may cost you extra time on migrating to Vue 3. In my projects, the appearance of <code>filters</code> is pretty a rare case since I could replace such functionality with a <code>method</code> or <code>computed</code> easily. Because in my opinion, <code>method</code> / <code>computed</code> has higher readability than the <code>filters</code>.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>{{ count | double }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

  
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>{{ double(count) }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>span</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>import</span> <span>{</span> ref <span>}</span> <span>from</span> <span>'vue'</span>

<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  
  filters<span>:</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>double</span> <span>(</span><span>val</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>return</span> val <span>*</span> <span>2</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>setup</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>const</span> count <span>=</span> <span>ref</span><span>(</span><span>1</span><span>)</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      count<span>,</span>
      <span>double</span><span>:</span> <span>val</span> <span>=&gt;</span> val <span>*</span> <span>2</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span>
<span>}</span>
</span></span><span><span><span>&lt;/</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span></code></pre><h2 id="6-new-async-component-suspense"><a href="#6-new-async-component-suspense">6. New Async Component: Suspense</a></h2><p>This is perhaps the only new feature of Vue 3 that may be changed even after official release. The inspiration is also from <a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/concurrent-mode-suspense.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">React Suspense</a>. So the usage scenario would be the same in my opinion.</p><p><img src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/1cda6d13a1104cb1ce0a59b8740a43022c81e4ea/31f27/assets/static/suspense_exp.0ef7beb.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png" width="1218" alt="suspense experimental feature" data-old-src="data:image/svg+xml,%3csvg fill='none' viewBox='0 0 1218 86' xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' xmlns:xlink='http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink'%3e%3cdefs%3e%3cfilter id='__svg-blur-f2cf534e3da73bad13e1a952fc3e212a'%3e%3cfeGaussianBlur in='SourceGraphic' stdDeviation='40'/%3e%3c/filter%3e%3c/defs%3e%3cimage x='0' y='0' filter='url(%23__svg-blur-f2cf534e3da73bad13e1a952fc3e212a)' width='1218' height='86' xlink:href='data:image/png%3bbase64%2ciVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAEAAAAAFCAYAAAD1/OoBAAAACXBIWXMAABYlAAAWJQFJUiTwAAABpklEQVQ4y81T2WoCQRDc//%2bQ5EVBRfFeFUUQUaMunrDex65XPNH1qFANaxIwiiEPaShm6Knuru6ZUSzriJ/scrngGbMs6%2b758fhZa7/fC2jn8xmHw%2bFbPfpOp5OshLEw8L55v5vzln47/lYc9SqqGkcsFkMkEkE8HheEw2FomoZisYhqtYpQKIRmsyk87slRVRWBQACpVErgcrmQz%2bcllvt0Oo1kMolKpYJoNCp%2bOxdzOxwOZLNZFAoFeDweiXW73QgGg8L/2thuv8Vr%2bgWhtyC0koZEIgG/3w%2bfzwev1yu1GMceqIVnuVxOGmeTxGAwkB5arRZ0XUe73RaOUq83RFC5XEan08FwOJTD%2bXyOxWKByWQi/tVqhW63i0ajgV6vB8MwhDsajWCapiRdr9fiYxFyuJ/NZhLX7/clB4VMp1PJzxfAWObYbDbCJ4/1ePvX2zodUeqUoBs6TMMUHjkE%2bUStVpO61GX7t9vt9SUwP7WwLuvvdjssl0sonBwn6HQ6kclk8J%2bMwp/9hs9%2bY4WTIMbjsdwgJ38PfJqPOH8B%2b%2b/a%2bK2uR/EfptS71/ec8EoAAAAASUVORK5CYII=' /%3e%3c/svg%3e" data-src="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/1cda6d13a1104cb1ce0a59b8740a43022c81e4ea/31f27/assets/static/suspense_exp.0ef7beb.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png" data-srcset="https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/ed0455ed5b8e065cf0e2f8a76a1b336accf3ff0d/d96f8/assets/static/suspense_exp.82a2fbd.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png 480w, https://d33wubrfki0l68.cloudfront.net/1cda6d13a1104cb1ce0a59b8740a43022c81e4ea/31f27/assets/static/suspense_exp.0ef7beb.41af1099f26ed8e0abb7f89a48e781a7.png 1218w"></p><p>Do you remember how you render the asynchronous data previously in Vue 2? I think <code>v-if</code> / <code>v-else</code> should be the answer.</p><pre><code><span><span><span>&lt;</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>v-for</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>i in items<span>"</span></span> <span>:key</span><span><span>=</span><span>"</span>i<span>"</span></span><span>&gt;</span></span>{{ i }}<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
    <span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span> <span>v-else</span><span>&gt;</span></span>loading...<span><span><span>&lt;</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
  <span><span><span>&lt;/</span>div</span><span>&gt;</span></span>
<span><span><span>&lt;/</span>template</span><span>&gt;</span></span>

<span><span><span>&lt;</span>script</span><span>&gt;</span></span><span><span>
<span>export</span> <span>default</span> <span>{</span>
  <span>data</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>{</span>
      items<span>:</span> <span>null</span>
    <span>}</span>
  <span>}</span><span>,</span>
  <span>mounted</span> <span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>{</span>
    <span>this</span><span>.</span><span>items</span> <span>=</span> <span>await</span> <span>new</span> <span>Promise</span><span>(</span><span>resolve</span> <span>=&gt;</span> <span>{</span>
      <span>setTimeout</span><span>(</span><span>(</span><span>)</span> <span>=&gt;</span>…</span></span></code></pre></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews">https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://pitayan.com/posts/vue-next-features/?ref=hackernews</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127926</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 02:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[List of E-Voting, Deliberation, and E-Democracy Projects]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 3 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127907">thread link</a>) | @MavropaliasG
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><div><div id="primary">
<article id="post-853" class="page" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="http://schema.org/Article">

	
    <div itemprop="description">

		
<p>This is a continuously-updated, alphabetical list of projects similar to <a href="https://democracy.foundation/epitome/">Epitome</a> and open source software with a short description. If your project is not listed, please send us a message with your project’s website and description through our <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://democracy.foundation/contact/" target="_blank">contact</a> page.</p>



<p><strong>Voting Platforms:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Emberwalker/Arke" target="_blank">Arke</a> – Anonymised voting with identity checking.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/republique-et-canton-de-geneve/chvote-1-0" target="_blank">CHVote</a> – A concrete answer and a real breakthrough in digital technology and e-government.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/andrewcmyers/civs" target="_blank">CIVS</a> – Condorcet internet voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/marilyndavis/evote" target="_blank">Clerk</a> – A specialized database server and user-interfaces for keeping votes. The unique architecture enables user-generated polls, secret or public votes, the ability to change your vote, and security from attack from the administrator.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Wolnosciowiec/CollectiveVotingBundle" target="_blank">Collective Voting Bundle</a> – Allows to create voting for an action, so every allowed person could vote on specific action.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/julien-boudry/Condorcet" target="_blank">Condorcet</a> – A PHP library providing Condorcet and multiple others methods, like Schulze, Copeland, Minimax, Kemeny-Young, Ranked Pairs.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cryptoballot/cryptoballot" target="_blank">CryptoBallot</a> – A secure election server daemon that does the grunt work to secure online voting for your web or mobile application.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ddp2p/DDP2P" target="_blank">DDP2P</a> – Direct democracy P2P.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/mlevogiannis/demos-voting" target="_blank">Demos</a> – an end-to-end verifiable e-voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/shanbay/django-vote" target="_blank">Django Vote</a> – a simple Django app to conduct vote for django model.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cidadania/e-cidadania" target="_blank">e-cidadania</a> – An open-source e-democracy web tool intended for citizen participation.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/mdipierro/evote" target="_blank">E-Vote</a> – An open source system for secure, trusted, anonymous, and verifiable voting online.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/esek/evote" target="_blank">E-Vote</a> – a voting system designed to be used for meetings with a limited number of people.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/freevote/" target="_blank">Free-Vote</a> – A complete system for web-based elections &amp; consults. Support for multiple, concurrent, fully programable elections, separate lists of voters, Web based user/lists/vote admin, email feedback, etc.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Ernest0x/gpgvote" target="_blank">GPGVote</a> – A web-based e-voting system, based on PGP encryption.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/benadida/helios-server" target="_blank">Helios</a> – An end-to-end verifiable voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ChimeraCoder/InstaVote" target="_blank">InstaVote</a> – a Python module that determines the winner of an election using instant-runoff voting rules.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/vvk-ehk/ivxv" target="_blank">IVXV</a> – The source code behind the Estonian online voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/lutoma/oavote" target="_blank">oavote</a> – A custom online voting tool to fit the requirements of the ‘Online-Abstimmung’ of Junge Piraten e.V.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cjerdonek/open-rcv" target="_blank">OpenRCV</a> – Software for tallying ranked-choice voting elections like instant-runoff voting and single transferable vote.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/bradbeattie/python-vote-core" target="_blank">Python Vote Core</a> – Implements various electoral methods, providing the results calculated off a provided set of ballots and options.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/SpaceKrakens/Ranked-Vote" target="_blank">Ranked-Vote</a> – A ranked-voting system for developers using GitHub.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/secretballot/" target="_blank">Secret ballot</a> – C/Linux server-client pubkey secret verifiable voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/dessalines/simple-vote" target="_blank">SimpleVote</a> – an open-source, self-hostable, live-updating voting/polling platform, for both live meetings, or extended polls.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/morinokami/social_choice" target="_blank">Social Choice</a> – A python program to calculate the winner of well-known winner selection methods, including the plurality method, the runoff method, the elimination method, the Borda count, and the pairwise-comparison method (a.k.a. Condorcet method).</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/solon/" target="_blank">Solon</a> – A software project for organizing elections. It includes a program to create the lists of candidates, a program to do the actual voting, and a program to count votes.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/vdemocracy/" target="_blank">Vocal Democracy</a> – This project is focused on the development of a phone-based voting system to be used in elections. The goal is to provide a reliable, intuitive and highly secure voting mechanism for voters with visual impairments and other disabilities.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/salvatorelionetti/votanto" target="_blank">Votanto</a> – The first electronic voting system recognizable by humans.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/votecounter/" target="_blank">VoteCounter</a> – A distributed voting program which can handle multiple clients over a network.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/vote/" target="_blank">VoteEngine</a> – Software for tabulating votes in elections, particularly using uncommon methods (Nanson, Condorcet, etc.).</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://reluk.ca/project/votorola/home.html" target="_blank">Votorola</a> – An experimental technology for the public guidance of electoral systems, executive offices, legislatures, and other decision sys­tems.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/gvamos/votron" target="_blank">Votron</a> – Android client for server side Condorcet style voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/vvvote/vvvote" target="_blank">VVVote</a> – Cryptographic Anonymized Online Voting System.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/grnet/zeus" target="_blank">Zeus</a> – Based on the Helios voting system but instead of election results, Zeus produces a tally of the ballots cast.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Proxy Voting/Liquid Democracy:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ekratia/ekratia" target="_blank">Ekratia</a> – Real-time, representative and participatory democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/alper/enhydris" target="_blank">enhydris</a> – A bare-bones simple majority voting system with delegates created as a proof of concept.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.tdcommons.org/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1092&amp;context=dpubs_series" target="_blank">Google Votes</a> – An experiment in liquid democracy built on Google’s internal corporate Google+ social network.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/virteal/kudocracy" target="_blank">Kudocracy</a> – A voting system where people can either directly approve or disapprove propositions associated to tags or delegate that decision.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/nathansobo/hyperarchy" target="_blank">Hyperarchy</a> – An online decision-making tool that allows team members to pose questions, submit answers, and rank the list in their preferred order.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/uniritter/liquid-democracy" target="_blank">liquid-democracy</a> – A direct democracy project, in which the votes are held by a specific mandate to a particular issue, and is supplemented by a recommendation of action.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/phynfo/LiquidDemocracy-XXS" target="_blank">LiquidDemocracy-XXS</a> – An extremely light liquid democracy tool.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://liquidfeedback.org/" target="_blank">LiquidFeedback</a> – An open-source software, powering internet platforms for proposition development and decision making.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/MakeYourLaws/MakeYourLaws" target="_blank">MakeYourLaws</a> – A project to convert the world to liquid democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ppau/polly" target="_blank">polly</a> – a liquid democracy system with a focus on deliberative policy building and consensus finding.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/metamerman/proxyfor.me" target="_blank">proxyfor.me</a> – You provide information about yourself that will be used to match you to proxies that have already most likely voted like you would, if you had the time, experience, and motivation to properly research a proposal.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/chozabu/VoteFlow" target="_blank">VoteFlow</a> – Voting website of the future. Mesh democracy, Liquid democracy, Tree of topics – made with Django.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Blockchain Voting:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/XertroV/blocvoting" target="_blank">BlocVoting</a> – A Haskell implementation for voting securely on a satoshi blockchain using liquid democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/dsx-tech/e-voting" target="_blank">e-voting</a> – Blockchain based voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://e-vox.org/" target="_blank">e-Vox</a> – Open e-democracy platform.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/followmyvote" target="_blank">Follow My Vote</a> – Open source end-to-end verifiable blockchain voting software.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/jonahkall/blockchain-voting" target="_blank">OneVote</a> – A distributed blockchain-based voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/stonecoldpat/anonymousvoting" target="_blank">Open Vote Network</a> – Anonymous voting on Ethereum without a tally authority.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/ConsenSys/PLCRVoting" target="_blank">PLCRVoting</a> – Smart contract for voting on the Ethereum blockchain.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/domschiener/publicvotes" target="_blank">PublicVotes</a> – Publicly verifiable and Ethereum-based voting system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/dib0/PublicVoting" target="_blank">PublicVoting</a> – Public voting system made trustworthy and verifiable through blockchain.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/aaron-lebo/updn" target="_blank">updn</a> – Reddit-alike where submissions and voting use Bitcoin.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://votosocial.github.io/" target="_blank">VotoSocial</a> – A secure, decentralized, auditable and open platform for e-voting and vote counting that everybody can trust.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/descampsk/wavevote" target="_blank">WaveVote</a> – a voting system based on Ethereum.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Deliberation/Governance Platforms:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/liqd/adhocracy" target="_blank">Adhocracy</a> – A policy drafting and decision making software for distributed groups and open institutions by liquid democracy e.V.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/agoravoting/" target="_blank">Agora Voting</a> – A secure open-source online voting software that protects the privacy of the vote and makes elections end-to-end verifiable.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/coorasse/Airesis" target="_blank">Airesis</a> – A decision making tool for direct democracy and e-government: participate in discussions, bring your ideas, suggest solutions and vote online.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/luisivan/asturixpeople" target="_blank">Asturix People</a> – A direct democracy system.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/CivilHub/CivilHub" target="_blank">CivilHub</a> – a free and open-source platform written in Python &amp; Django for the purpose of collaboration in local civic communities.</li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" href="https://github.com/citizenos" target="_blank">Citizen OS</a> – An e-democracy platform for discussion, co-creation, voting, digital signatures, follow-up.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/consul/consul" target="_blank">Consul</a> – Open Government and E-Participation Web Software.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/decidim/decidim" target="_blank">Decidim</a> – The participatory democracy framework.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Venryx/DebateMap" target="_blank">Debate Map</a> – a web platform aimed at improving the efficiency of discussion and debate.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/DemocracyEarth/sovereign" target="_blank">Democracy.Earth</a> – A decentralized liquid democracy governance platform for organizations of any size.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/DemocracyOS/democracyos" target="_blank">Democracy OS</a> – An online space for deliberation and voting on political proposals.</li><li><a href="https://democracy.foundation/epitome/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Epitome</a> – Epitome is an online platform of mass deliberation and consensus decision-making, that enables large groups to simultaneously communicate and develop proposals to reported issues.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/cfpb/idea-box" target="_blank">IdeaBox</a> – An application that lets an organization collect ideas, comment on them, and vote them up.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/konsento/konsento" target="_blank">Konsento</a> – Digital direct progressive consensus democracy.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/loomio/loomio" target="_blank">Loomio</a> – A collaborative decision-making tool that makes it easy for anyone to participate in decisions which affect them.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.opendcn.org/" target="_blank">openDCN</a> – On-line dedicated tools to support participation and deliberation.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/peer/mind" target="_blank">PeerMind</a> – This project aims to explore and improve technologies we use for decision making.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/Spokenvote/spokenvote" target="_blank">Spokenvote</a> – A web-based social consensus tool for groups of any size, from a local school board to an entire nation’s people, that radically enhances the group’s ability to reach consensus via an intuitive democratic process.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/fairdemocracy/vilfredo-core" target="_blank">Vilfredo</a> – Vilfredo allows groups from 5 to 20 people to ask open questions and reach consensus in an easy and fair way.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/openpolitics/votebot" target="_blank">Votebot</a> – A collaborative writing platform built on top of GitHub, originally designed for open policy-making and manifesto writing.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/smari/wasa2il" target="_blank">Wasa2il</a> – A participatory democracy software project. It is based around the core idea of polities – political entities – which users of the system can join or leave, make proposals in, alter existing proposals, and adopt laws to self-govern.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/CitizensFoundation/your-priorities-app" target="_blank">Your Priorities</a> – An e-democracy web application designed by the non-profit Citizens Foundation to help groups speak with one voice.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Organizations:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://dcentproject.eu/" target="_blank">D-CENT</a> – A Europe-wide project creating open, secure and privacy-aware tools for direct democracy and economic empowerment.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://liqd.net/en/" target="_blank">Liquid Democracy e.V.</a> – A non-profit that creates and implements innovative concepts for e-participation.</li></ol>



<p><strong>Direct Democracy Projects:</strong></p>



<ol><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.democracy-international.org/" target="_blank">Democracy International </a> – Democracy International’s goals are to give citizens a direct say in political decision-making and to make governments more accountable.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.democracylab.org/" target="_blank">DemocracyLab</a> – A non-profit organization aspiring to revolutionize politics by creating and curating online tools that engage communities to solve problems.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://www.idea.int/data-tools/data/direct-democracy" target="_blank">Direct Democracy Database</a> – The Direct Democracy Database allows users to explore the different ways direct democracy is used in different countries.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/pavril/onlinedemocracy" target="_blank">DirectDemocracy</a> – a web-based voting platform dedicated to school students interested in taking part in the school decision-making.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://forums.e-democracy.org/" target="_blank">E-Democracy.org</a> – A non-profit pioneer fostering inclusive online engagement, global open government knowledge sharing, and innovative civic technology.</li><li><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://free-project.org/" target="_blank">FREE e-democracy project</a> – A project dedicated to creating the GNU.FREE …</li></ol></div></article></div></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/">https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://democracy.foundation/similar-projects/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127907</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 01:58:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[I hope they have Emacs in heaven]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 2 | Comments 0 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127862">thread link</a>) | @billwear
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | http://stormrider.io/emacs-heaven.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://stormrider.io/emacs-heaven.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">



<div id="outline-container-orgcf4562a">
<h2 id="orgcf4562a">i hope they have emacs in heaven</h2>
<div id="text-orgcf4562a">
<p>
Thunderstorms appeal to me. It isn't just that I'm an introvert at heart, and a nature lover. It's something else, too. Ever since childhood, long before the turbulent adolescent years that gave me lifelong anxiety and simultaneously brought me fledgling UNIX, I've always loved the rain.<br>
</p>

<p>
I share that as a calibration of sorts, to establish that I know when something fits without justification or psychological precedent. And I don't so much seek the rain as the atmosphere it carries, a sort of rarefied buffering of the noise and whirling madness of everyday life, a sort of something-sacred-this-way-comes vestment that drops over the daylight and matches the energy of the day to my baseline mood.<br>
</p>

<p>
So when I say that emacs resonates in a similar way with me, you'll see that I've thought about this.<br>
</p>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org2b435cb">
<h3 id="org2b435cb">mind mapping and marval priorities</h3>
<div id="text-org2b435cb">
<p>
There was one other time that I discovered something in-phase for me. In the mid-nineties, when I lived in Atlanta, I got my hands on a shareware disc. I was ghosting a book for the retired CEO of a heavy equipment conglomerate, and part of the deal was a primo laptop.  On that CD drive, I discovered a shareware CD, forgotten, with some cool programs.<br>
</p>

<p>
The most interesting of the two were a program called "Above and Beyond," which automatically shifted tasks by juggling timeblocks, and a then-unknown tool from Tony Buzan called "MindManager." I set about using them both, and they were definitely on my wavelength, but both of them induced a standing wave ratio greater than 3.0 in my head.  The ideas came furiously, and the tasks got blitzed at warp speed, but there was no navigator.<br>
</p>

<p>
Unfocused creative activity is a like a drug: it feels amazing, but it leads you nowhere in particular without realizing that you've disconnected from reality.<br>
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org0999547">
<h3 id="org0999547">enter emacs</h3>
<div id="text-org0999547">
<p>
Luckily, I discovered emacs before I was too far gone. It might have been the timing, it might have been the flexibility, it might have been the fact that I could do everything from one screen (while constantly changing the screen without actually losing anything). Something about it felt right to me, a perfect fit, like rain has always felt.<br>
</p>

<p>
As emacs has grown over the years, and I have grown with it, I've found a way to meet all my screen needs with it.  It is at once disciplined and flexible, spontaneous and ordered, frenetic and balanced. Actually, that's not quite true: I'm the one who's bringing all the contradictions; emacs just provides a flexible vessel that can handle them and blend them and support their contrapuntal coexistence in a sort of seamlessly cantankerous way. And that makes it a perfect fit for me.<br>
</p>
</div>
</div>

<div id="outline-container-org81908bd">
<h3 id="org81908bd">I don't recommend it, per sei</h3>
<div id="text-org81908bd">
<p>
My purpose here is not to promote emacs, but to encourage finding events and phenomena and tools and people that fit your way of being. When I hired into the MAAS team at Canonical, I knew I had found my people. I can be the class clown and the IRC troll and the mediator and the explainer all at the same time, and nobody doubts those roles, and nobody sees that as good or bad: it's just who I am, and I fit, and everybody leaves those jobs to me.<br>
</p>

<p>
What I'm getting at is bigger than an extensible text editor, or an occupation, or a beloved season. I'm saying it's worth finding your resonant frequency, the node where everything's in phase and you can transmit in the clear without looking over your shoulder. I'm convinced everyone has a sweet spot, and once you find it, goals and competitive measures and key milestones dim down enough that you can enjoy life and handle it well, whatever's happening. It's a place where even silence is a source of pleasant sound for you, where the trunk noise is familiar music and the tone is 20dB down on the nose.<br>
</p>

<p>
To indulge myself in the all-too-obvious, it's a place that's right as rain.<br>
</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div><div id="postamble">

<p>Created: 2020-08-11 Tue 20:44</p>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://stormrider.io/emacs-heaven.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127862</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 01:49:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Woz's 70th Birthday Party (Live)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 6 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=24127440">thread link</a>) | @empressplay
<br/>
August 11, 2020 | https://www.twitch.tv/inspirehouse | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.twitch.tv/inspirehouse">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.twitch.tv/inspirehouse</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-24127440</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:22:33 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
