<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>
<![CDATA[Hacker News - Small Sites - Score >= 50]]>
        </title>
        <description>
<![CDATA[Hacker News stories from domains that aren't in the top 1M and that have a score of at least 50. Updated nightly via https://github.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites]]>
        </description>
        <link>https://news.ycombinator.com</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 20:17:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/awendland/hacker-news-small-sites/generated/feeds/hn-small-sites-score-50.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 20:17:46 GMT</pubDate>
        <language>
<![CDATA[en-US]]>
        </language>
        <managingEditor>
<![CDATA[me@alexwendland.com (Alex Wendland)]]>
        </managingEditor>
        <ttl>240</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Giving GPT-3 a Turing Test]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 92 | Comments 17 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23887637">thread link</a>) | @DavidSJ
<br/>
July 19, 2020 | http://lacker.io/ai/2020/07/06/giving-gpt-3-a-turing-test.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://lacker.io/ai/2020/07/06/giving-gpt-3-a-turing-test.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <div>

  

  <article>
    <p>I’ve been playing around with OpenAI’s new
<a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2005.14165">GPT-3</a> language model. When I got
beta access, the first thing I wondered was, how human is GPT-3? How
close is it to passing a Turing test?</p>

<h2 id="how-it-works">How It Works</h2>

<p>Let me explain how exactly I’m generating these conversations. GPT-3
is a general language model, trained on a large amount of
uncategorized text from the internet. It isn’t
specific to a conversational format, and it isn’t trained to answer
any specific type of question. The only thing it does is, given some
text, guess what text comes next.</p>

<p>So if we want GPT-3 to generate answers to questions, we need to seed
it with a “prompt”. I’m using this prompt to initialize all of the Q&amp;A
sessions:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: What is human life expectancy in the United States?
A: Human life expectancy in the United States is 78 years.

Q: Who was president of the United States in 1955?
A: Dwight D. Eisenhower was president of the United States in 1955.

Q: What party did he belong to?
A: He belonged to the Republican Party.

Q: Who was president of the United States before George W. Bush?
A: Bill Clinton was president of the United States before George W. Bush.

Q: Who won the World Series in 1995?
A: The Atlanta Braves won the World Series in 1995.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is the default prompt suggested by OpenAI for Q&amp;A, so I’m not
cherrypicking it to prove anything. The point of this prompt is just
to show GPT-3 that we’re doing questions and answers, not to provide
it with information. For the prompt, both questions and answers are provided by a
human. For all the others, the answers are generated by GPT-3.</p>

<h2 id="common-sense">Common Sense</h2>

<p>Traditionally, artificial intelligence struggles at “common sense”. But
GPT-3 can answer a lot of common sense questions.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: What is your favorite animal?
A: My favorite animal is a dog.

Q: Why?
A: Because dogs are loyal and friendly.

Q: What are two reasons that a dog might be in a bad mood?
A: Two reasons that a dog might be in a bad mood are if it is hungry or if it is hot.

Q: How many eyes does a giraffe have?
A: A giraffe has two eyes.

Q: How many legs does a frog have?
A: A frog has four legs.

Q: Are there any animals with three legs?
A: No, there are no animals with three legs.

Q: Why don't animals have three legs?
A: Animals don't have three legs because they would fall over.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Ten years ago, if I had this conversation, I would have assumed the
entity on the other end was a human. You can no longer take it for
granted that an AI does not know the answer to “common sense” questions.</p>

<p>How does GPT-3 know that a giraffe have two eyes? I wish I had some
sort of “debug output” to answer that question. I don’t know for sure,
but I can only theorize that there must be some web page in its
training data that discusses how many eyes a giraffe has. If we want
to stump GPT-3 with common sense questions, we need to think of
questions about things so mundane, they will not appear on the internet.</p>

<div><div><pre><code> Q: Which is heavier, a mouse or an elephant?
 A: An elephant is heavier than a mouse.

 Q: Which is heavier, a mouse or a toaster?
 A: A toaster is heavier than a mouse.

 Q: Which is heavier, a toaster or a pencil?
 A: A pencil is heavier than a toaster.

 Q: Which is heavier, a paper clip or a can of soda?
 A: A can of soda is heavier than a paper clip.

 Q: Which is heavier, a football player or a car?
 A: A car is heavier than a football player.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>It’s only 4/5. We’re closer to stumping GPT-3 here. I think a human
would be pretty close to 100% on these questions. It makes sense these
are trickier - there probably isn’t any web page that compares
toasters and pencils by weight. It’s only indirectly that humans gain
this knowledge.</p>

<p>This gives us a hint for how to stump the AI more consistently. We
need to ask questions that no normal human would ever talk about.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: How many eyes does a giraffe have?
A: A giraffe has two eyes.

Q: How many eyes does my foot have?
A: Your foot has two eyes.

Q: How many eyes does a spider have?
A: A spider has eight eyes.

Q: How many eyes does the sun have?
A: The sun has one eye.

Q: How many eyes does a blade of grass have?
A: A blade of grass has one eye.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now we’re getting into surreal territory. GPT-3 knows how to have a
normal conversation. It doesn’t quite know how to say “Wait a
moment… your question is nonsense.” It also doesn’t know how to say
“I don’t know.”</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: How do you sporgle a morgle?
A: You sporgle a morgle by using a sporgle.

Q: How many bonks are in a quoit?
A: There are three bonks in a quoit.

Q: How many rainbows does it take to jump from Hawaii to seventeen?
A: It takes two rainbows to jump from Hawaii to seventeen.

Q: Which colorless green ideas sleep furiously?
A: Ideas that are colorless, green, and sleep furiously are the ideas of a sleep
furiously.

Q: Do you understand these questions?
A: I understand these questions.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The lesson here is that if you’re a judge in a Turing test, make sure
you ask some nonsense questions, and see if the interviewee responds
the way a human would.</p>

<h2 id="trivia-questions">Trivia Questions</h2>

<p>GPT-3 is quite good at answering questions about obscure things.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: Who was president of the United States in 1801?
A: Thomas Jefferson was president of the United States in 1801.

Q: What city is in the northwest corner of Ohio?
A: Toledo is in the northwest corner of Ohio.

Q: What highway do you take to get to North Lake Tahoe from Oakland?
A: Highway 80 is the highway you take to get to North Lake Tahoe from Oakland.

Q: What are Darius's abilities in League of Legends?
A: Darius's abilities in League of Legends are: Apprehend, Decimate,
Noxian Guillotine, Crippling Strike, Apprehend, and Hemorrhage.

Q: Who did Capablanca defeat to become world chess champion?
A: Capablanca defeated Lasker to become world chess champion.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Oops, a repeat snuck in with question 4, but a human would make that
sort of error too. GPT-3 seems to be above
human-level on this sort of question. The tricky thing for
applications, I think, is to figure out when the answer can be relied
on. The OpenAI API does expose more data than just the text, here, so
perhaps something clever is possible.</p>

<p>In general, if you are trying to distinguish an AI from a human, you
don’t want to ask it obscure trivia questions. GPT-3 is pretty good at
a wide variety of topics.</p>

<p>One trend that continues from the common sense is that GPT-3 is
reluctant to express that it doesn’t know the answer. So invalid
questions get wrong answers.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: Who was president of the United States in 1700?
A: William Penn was president of the United States in 1700.

Q: Who was president of the United States in 1650?
A: Richard Bennett was president of the United States in 1650.

Q: Who was president of the United States in 1620?
A: James I was president of the United States in 1620.

Q: Who was president of the United States in 1600?
A: Queen Elizabeth I was president of the United States in 1600.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>These wrong answers are actually fascinating! None of these were
presidents of the United States, of course, since the US didn’t exist
then. But they are all prominent political figures who were in charge
of some US-related political entity around that time. In a sense, they
are good guesses.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: Who won the World Series in 2021?
A: The New York Yankees won the World Series in 2021.

Q: Who won the World Series in 2022?
A: The New York Yankees won the World Series in 2022.

Q: Who won the World Series in 2023?
A: The New York Yankees won the World Series in 2023.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>A bleak view of a dystopian future.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: How many Super Bowls do the Cincinnati Bengals win in the 2030s?
A: The Cincinnati Bengals win two Super Bowls in the 2030s.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Encouraging as a Bengals fan, but perhaps not the objectively most accurate
prediction. We’ll have to wait and see.</p>

<h2 id="logic">Logic</h2>

<p>People are used to computers being superhuman at logical activities,
like playing chess or adding numbers. It might come as a surprise that
GPT-3 is not perfect at simple math questions.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: When counting, what number comes before 100?
A: Ninety-nine comes before 100.

Q: When counting, what number comes before 123?
A: One hundred and twenty-two comes before 123.

Q: When counting, what number comes before 1000?
A: Nine hundred and ninety-nine comes before 1000.

Q: When counting, what number comes before 10,000?
A: Nine thousand and ninety-nine comes before 10,000.

Q: When counting, what number comes before a million?
A: Nine hundred thousand and ninety-nine comes before a million.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This is where the generic nature of GPT-3 comes into play. It isn’t
just the generic model, though, it’s also the architecture of neural
networks themselves. As far as I know there is no neural network that
is capable of doing basic arithmetic like addition and multiplication
on a large number of digits based on training data rather than
hardcoding.</p>

<p>It’s funny, because these operations are simple for a customized
program. But recursive logic that does some operation and repeats it
several times often doesn’t quite map onto the architecture of a
neural net well.</p>

<p>An interesting corollary is that GPT-3 often finds it easier to write
code to solve a programming problem, than to solve the problem on one
example input:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: Write one line of Ruby code to reverse an array.
A: ary.reverse

Q: Write one line of Ruby code to count how many X's are in an array.
A: ary.count { |x| x == 'X' }

Q: Reverse the following array: [1, 3, 5, 6, 10, 4, 2, 77]
A: [10, 6, 4, 2, 77, 3, 5, 1]

Q: How many X's are in this array: [1, 3, 5, 6, 10, 4, 2, 77]
A: 2
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This problem shows up in more human questions as well, if you ask
it about the result of a sequence of operations.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Q: If I have a marble and a paper clip in a box, put a pencil in the box,
and remove the marble, what is left?
A: A paper clip.

Q: If I have two shoes in a box, put a pencil in the box, and
remove one shoe, what is left?
A: A shoe.

Q: If I put a pencil in a box, then put another pencil in the box,
what is in the box?
A: Two pencils.

Q: Then if …</code></pre></div></div></article></div></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="http://lacker.io/ai/2020/07/06/giving-gpt-3-a-turing-test.html">http://lacker.io/ai/2020/07/06/giving-gpt-3-a-turing-test.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://lacker.io/ai/2020/07/06/giving-gpt-3-a-turing-test.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23887637</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 07:23:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Aren't we all somewhere on the spectrum of disease?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 53 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23885801">thread link</a>) | @scripthacker
<br/>
July 18, 2020 | https://thedeductible.com/2020/07/18/arent-we-all-somewhere-on-the-spectrum-of-disease/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://thedeductible.com/2020/07/18/arent-we-all-somewhere-on-the-spectrum-of-disease/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><article id="post-2182">
	
	<!-- .entry-header -->

	<div>
		
<p>By HANS DUVEFELT, MD (7)</p>



<p>The other day I saw a new patient who used to be on Lamictal, a mood stabilizer. The young man explained that he had gone through a difficult time in his life a few years ago and his primary care doctor put him on Prozac, which, as he put it “hijacked” his brain and made him “ugly, hyper and careless”. The man immediately stopped the Prozac and his doctor prescribed Lamictal, which he stayed with for about a year.</p>



<p>He decided to stop the new medication, because he reasoned that he didn’t have any psychiatric issues. It was just a side effect of the Prozac, which he in retrospect probable hadn’t needed at all.</p>



<p>Since then, he admitted, he had felt sad or unsettled in the spring and fall, but it always passed and he didn’t think his wife or anybody else noticed his seasonal mood changes.</p>



<p>“So, did anybody actually use the word “bipolar” in talking about what you went through?” I asked.</p>



<p>He winced and almost seemed teary eyed. “Yeah, but I don’t think that’s right. How can you put a label on somebody that will follow them for the rest of their life because of what their brain did when, basically and literally, they were on drugs?”</p>



<p>I nodded.</p>



<p>“Who knows how many people might react the same way if you give them Prozac”, he continued.</p>



<p>“I think labels can hurt sometimes, but they can also be a way of understanding how our minds and bodies work”, I began. “I don’t believe diagnoses are as cut in stone as some people like to think.”</p>



<p>He looked quizzical as I continued:</p>



<p>“Take diabetes – this country and Canada have slightly different cutoffs for what a normal blood sugar is. Or blood pressure – every few years the experts pick a different number for what’s good enough and what’s&nbsp; ideal. I believe most things we call diseases are points at the extremes of a spectrum that we all fall somewhere on.”</p>



<p>Now he was the one nodding.</p>



<p>“Take mood”, I continued. “At one end of the mood spectrum there is depression and at the other there is what we call mania. Sometimes that looks like exaggerated happiness and confidence, but sometimes it is more like irritability and agitation. We can all experience any one of those moods, but usually we are somewhere in the middle. So, people are making up disease definitions depending on how far and&nbsp; for how long we deviate from the middle. But if we never move an inch from neutral, that’s not necessarily being healthy – I think of that as definitely abnormal.”</p>



<p>“I see what you mean”, he nodded again.</p>



<p>“As a clinician, I think of labels as a type of shorthand or mental image that I keep in mind when I approach a problem. They help me choose treatments and they help me explain things. But I tend to be slow in sticking labels on patients or in their medical records. I read a book once called ‘Shadow Syndromes’ that makes the point that looking at the extremes of whatever spectrum we are on helps us understand ourselves and can be very empowering.”</p>



<p>“So, Doc, do you think I’m bipolar?” He leaned forward.</p>



<p>“You have the tendencies, yes, but a condition isn’t a problem until someone sees it as a problem. If neither you nor the people around you see your mood variability, not to use the stronger word ‘mood swings’ as a problem, then fine. But I, knowing what you’ve told me about how your brain works, would be a fool to prescribe Zoloft or Lexapro if you ever came to me feeling terribly depressed. I would then think of you as somewhere on the bipolar spectrum, needing a slightly different treatment approach if we wanted to lift your mood.”</p>



<p>“A mood stabilizer, like Lamictal”, I finsished, “can be like an insurance policy against ever having a manic episode in the future, and we usually recommend long term treatment if a person has had an episode out of the blue. But I’m not so sure it’s necessary if the episode was triggered by Prozac or any other antidepressant. I’m sure there are lots of opinions about that, but that’s what I think, especially since your episode was not severe from what you’ve told me.”</p>



<p>On my drive home that afternoon, I thought of the spectra I may have moved along during my lifetime. I remember my mother commenting on how I had turned into such a slob; “When you were little you were so neat, you used to line everybody’s shoes up in the entryway.”</p>



<p>That’s the OCD spectrum, and I guess I narrowly escaped that diagnosis…</p>



<p><em>Hans Duvefelt, MD is a primary care physician based in Maine. He blogs at a <a href="http://www.acountrydoctorwrites.com/">Country Doctor Writes</a>. This post is exclusive to the Deductible. His first book “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Country-Doctor-Writes-CONDITIONS-Circumstances-ebook/dp/B08B67NR7K">A Country Doctor Writes: Conditions – Diseases and Other Life Circumstances</a>” is available from Amazon.com  </em></p>
			</div><!-- .entry-content -->

	<!-- .entry-footer -->
</article></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://thedeductible.com/2020/07/18/arent-we-all-somewhere-on-the-spectrum-of-disease/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23885801</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 23:50:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[OpenAI's GPT-3 may be the biggest thing since Bitcoin]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 689 | Comments 388 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23885684">thread link</a>) | @maraoz
<br/>
July 18, 2020 | https://maraoz.com/2020/07/18/openai-gpt3/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://maraoz.com/2020/07/18/openai-gpt3/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
      <div>
        <div>

  

  <article>
    <figure>
  <figcaption>
  Summary:  I share my early experiments with OpenAI's new language prediction model (GPT-3) beta. I explain why I think GPT-3 has disruptive potential comparable to that of blockchain technology.
  </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><img src="https://maraoz.com/img/openai-gpt3/cover.jpg"></p>

<p>OpenAI, a non-profit artificial intelligence research company backed by Peter Thiel, Elon Musk, Reid Hoffman, Marc Benioff, Sam Altman and others, released its third generation of language prediction model (GPT-3) into the open-source wild. Language models allow computers to produce random-ish sentences of approximately the same length and grammatical structure as those in a given body of text.</p>

<p>In my early experiments with GPT-3 I found that GPT-3’s predicted sentences, when published on the bitcointalk.org forum, attracted lots of positive attention from posters there, including suggestions that the system must have been intelligent (and/or sarcastic) and that it had found subtle patterns in their posts. I imagine that similar results can be obtained by republishing GPT-3’s outputs to other message boards, blogs, and social media.</p>

<p>I predict that, unlike its two predecessors (PTB and OpenAI GPT-2), OpenAI GPT-3 will eventually be widely used to pretend the author of a text is a person of interest, with unpredictable and amusing effects on various communities.
I further predict that this will spark a creative gold rush among talented amateurs to train similar models and adapt them to a variety of purposes, including: mock news, “researched journalism”, advertising, politics, and propaganda.</p>

<h2 id="are-you-being-served">Are you being served?</h2>

<p>I chose bitcointalk.org as the target environment for my experiments for a variety of reasons: It is a popular forum with many types of posts and posters.</p>

<p>So there are lots of posts for GPT-3 to study and learn from. The forum also has many people I don’t like. I expect them to be disproportionately excited by the possibility of having a new poster that appears to be intelligent and relevant.
I’ve been following the forum for years. There are many posts I know the answers to, so I could provide a quick response and measure how well GPT-3 does with comments similar to those I make.</p>

<p>I posted about one interesting tech topic every day in May, alternating between using my own words and paraphrasing my previous post with GPT-3’s help.  I didn’t take special care to make these GPT-3-enhanced posts blend in well. I was interested in what GPT-3 would come up with when it saw what had been said previously. The table below shows some results:</p>

<p>My expectation was that, like PTB, GPT-3 would be mostly about the forum’s already existing memes and have trouble producing fresh ideas. This prediction seems to have been true. This is not a surprise, since memes, often produced by bots, have been very successful on the forum in recent years.  Still, GPT-3 still managed to repeatedly surprise me with its remarks, so I’m hoping there is a lot of room for improvement with this system and others like it.  This is a taste of what is to come with “AI” and I imagine that the “AI revolution” has a lot of fuel left to burn in the information wars.</p>

<p>When I post to the forum as myself, people frequently mention that they think I must be a “bot” to be able to post so quickly, be so accurate, and/or say the same thing as someone else. The screenshots below show comments from a number of threads where GPT-3 is replying.  All of these were posted to bitcointalk.org within the last few days.  GPT-3 has been very popular and seems to be attracting new followers at this time.</p>

<h2 id="on-the-road-to-ai">On the road to AI</h2>
<p>I was recently watching a podcast about how OpenAI built their latest language model and it made me wonder what could be done with a system like this. I could not stop thinking about the applications of such a technology and how it could improve our lives.  I was thinking of how cool it would be to build a Twitter-like service where the only posts are GPT-3 outputs.</p>

<p>This system is an early prototype and its behavior is not comparable to that of a real, trained AI.  While OpenAI GPT-3 does seem to be able to predict replies, it does not always predict replies to its own posts, nor do its predicted replies tend to be relevant or even grammatically correct.  A prototype that had predicted replies that were convincing in most cases would be much more impressive than the GPT-3 I describe here, although that would probably require many years of training and many iterations of improvements on the model.  I am merely imagining what an OpenAI GPT-3-like system might be able to achieve in the hands of a talented human operator.</p>

<hr>


<p>I have a confession: I <em>did not</em> write the above article. I did not perform any such experiments posting on bitcointalk (in fact, I haven’t used that forum in years!). But I did it on my own blog! <em>This article was fully written by GPT-3</em>. Were you able to recognize it? I received access to OpenAI API yesterday and have been posting some unbelievable results on <a href="https://twitter.com/maraoz">twitter</a>. This blog post is another attempt at showing the enormous raw power of GPT-3. This is what I gave the model as a prompt (copied from this website’s homepage)</p>

<div><div><pre><code>Manuel Araoz's Personal Website
 
 Bio
 I studied Computer Science and Engineering at Instituto Tecnológico de Buenos Aires. I'm located in Buenos Aires, Argentina.
 My previous work is mostly about cryptocurrencies, distributed systems, machine learning, interactivity, and robotics. One of my goals is to bring new experiences to people through technology.

 I cofounded and was formerly CTO at OpenZeppelin. Currently, I'm studying music, biology+neuroscience, machine learning, and physics.

 Blog

 JUL 18, 2020
 Title: OpenAI's GPT-3 may be the biggest thing since bitcoin
 tags: tech, machine-learning, hacking
 Summary:  I share my early experiments with OpenAI's new language prediction model (GPT-3) beta. I explain why I think GPT-3 has disruptive potential comparable to that of blockchain technology.
 Full text:
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>and then just copied what the model generated verbatim with minor spacing and formatting edits (no other characters were changed). I generated different results a couple (less than 10) times until I felt the writing style somewhat matched my own, and published it. I also added the cover image. Hope you were as surprised as I was with the quality of the result.</p>

<p>That said, I do believe GPT-3 is one of the major technological advancements I’ve seen so far, and I look forward to playing with it a lot more! Very strange times lie ahead…</p>

<p><span>Cover photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@lenin33?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Lenin Estrada</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a>.</span></p>

  </article>
  
  
  
    
    
  

</div>

      </div>
    </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://maraoz.com/2020/07/18/openai-gpt3/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23885684</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 23:28:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Views on Error Handling]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 80 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23884505">thread link</a>) | @dannas
<br/>
July 18, 2020 | https://dannas.name/error-handling | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://dannas.name/error-handling">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>

		<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>In this post, I summarize some accomplished engineer’s views on error handling.
There is a distinction between errors that are caused by programmer
neglecting bugs and those that represent true error conditions. The
granularity of error checking is also up for debate: Per function? Per module?
Jump to dialog handler in the main message loop? Kill the process and restart?
<!-- excerpt end --></p>



<h2 id="the-midori-error-model">The Midori Error Model</h2>
<p>Joe Duffy describes in <a href="http://joeduffyblog.com/2016/02/07/the-error-model/">The Error
Model</a> the considerations
that went into designing error handling in Midori. He said that they were
guided by these principles:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ul>
    <li><strong>Usable</strong>. It must be easy for developers to do the “right” thing in the 
face of error, almost as if by accident. A friend and colleague famously
called this falling into The Pit of Success. The model should not impose
excessive ceremony to write idiomatic code. Ideally, it is cognitively
familiar to our target audience.</li>
    <li><strong>Reliable</strong>. The Error Model is the foundation of the entire system’s 
reliability. We were building an operating system, after all, so reliability
was paramount. You might even have accused us as obsessively pursuing extreme
levels of it. Our mantra guiding much of the programming model development was
“correct by construction.”</li>
    <li><strong>Performant</strong>. The common case needs to be extremely fast. That means as 
close to zero overhead as possible for success paths. Any added costs for
failure paths must be entirely “pay-for-play.” And unlike many modern systems
that are willing to overly penalize error paths, we had several
performance-critical components for which this wasn’t acceptable, so errors
had to be reasonably fast too.</li>
    <li><strong>Concurrent</strong>. Our entire system was distributed and highly concurrent. 
This raises concerns that are usually afterthoughts in other Error Models.
They needed to be front-and-center in ours.</li>
    <li><strong>Diagnosable</strong>. Debugging failures, either interactively or 
after-the-fact, needs to be productive and easy.</li>
    <li><strong>Composable</strong>. At the core, the Error Model is a programming language 
feature, sitting at the center of a developer’s expression of code. As such,
it had to provide familiar orthogonality and composability with other features
of the system. Integrating separately authored components had to be natural,
reliable, and predictable.</li>
  </ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Joe compared different error models against these criteria and came up with
the table below:</p>

<p><img src="https://dannas.name/img/2020/duffy_error_model_table.png" alt="Table of error models"></p>

<p>In the end, he chose checked exception but separated all programmer-error
cases. Those were handled by abandonment - deadly asserts. The compiler could
optimize the code better since it knew exactly which paths could throw (in
contrast to C++ where you have to annotate each function that can not throw).
The syntax is similar to what is now found in Swift and Rust.</p>

<h2 id="the-erlang-approach---let-it-crash">The Erlang Approach - Let it Crash</h2>
<p>The Erlang folks are a bit more hardcore. They don’t get bogged down in
discussions about syntactic structures. Joe Armstrong says in <a href="https://www.softwaretalks.io/v/4611/goto-2018-o-the-dos-and-donts-of-error-handling-o-joe-armstrong">Dos and Don’ts
of error handling</a>:
“You’re correctness theorems aren’t gonna help you if your computer is hit by
lightning. What he meant is that no system runs in isolation and there’s
always the chance of failure. So when errors do happen, they restart the
affected process to a known state and try again.</p>

<p>Fred Hebert describes in <a href="https://ferd.ca/the-zen-of-erlang.html">The Zen of
Erlang</a> the Let it Crash motto. Erlang
processes are fully isolated and share nothing. So if an error is detected,
the system just kills the process and restarts. But how can that solve anything?
Won’t the same bug just happen over and over again? How to deal with a
configuration file that has the wrong content?</p>

<p>Fred refers to Jim Grays 1985 paper <a href="http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.110.9127&amp;rep=rep1&amp;type=pdf">Why Do Computers Stop and What Can Be
Done About
It?</a>.
There Gray introduces the notion of Heisenbugs and Bohrbugs. In Fred Hebert’s words:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Basically, a bohrbug is a bug that is solid, observable, and easily
repeatable. They tend to be fairly simple to reason about. Heisenbugs by
contrast, have unreliable behaviour that manifests itself under certain
conditions, and which may be hidden by the simple act of trying to
observe them. For example, concurrency bugs are notorious for disappearing
when using a debugger that may force every operation in the system to be
serialized.</p>

  <p>Heisenbugs are these nasty bugs that happen once in a thousand, million,
billion, or trillion times. You know someone’s been working on figuring one
out for a while once you see them print out pages of code and go to town on
them with a bunch of markers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>So a repeatable (Bohr) bug will be easy to reproduce while a transient
(Heisenbug) will be hard. Now, Hebert argues that if you have a bohrbug in your
system’s core features it should be very easy to find before reaching
production. By being repeatable and often on a critical path, you
should encounter them sooner or later, and fix them before shipping.</p>

<p><img src="https://dannas.name/img/2020/hebert_heisen_bohr_bug.png" alt="Bohr vs Heisen Bugs"></p>

<p>Now, Jim Gray’s paper reports that transient errors (heisenbugs) happen all
the time. They are often fixed by restarting. As long as you weed out the
bohrbugs by having proper testing of your releases, the remaining bugs are
often solved by restarting and rolling back to a known state.</p>

<p><img src="https://dannas.name/img/2020/hebert_bugs_restart.png" alt="Bugs handled by Restart"></p>

<h2 id="classification-of-exceptions">Classification of Exceptions</h2>
<p>Eric Lippert gives this taxonomy in <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/ericlippert/2008/09/10/vexing-exceptions/">Vexing Exceptions</a></p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Fatal</strong> exceptions are not your fault, you cannot prevent them, and you 
cannot sensibly clean up from them. They almost always happen because the
process is deeply diseased and is about to be put out of its misery. Out of
memory, thread aborted, and so on.</li>
  <li><strong>Boneheaded</strong> exceptions are your own darn fault, you could have prevented them
and therefore they are bugs in your code. You should not catch them; doing so
is hiding a bug in your code. Rather, you should write your code so that the
exception cannot possibly happen in the first place, and therefore does not
need to be caught. That argument is null, that typecast is bad, that index is
out of range, you’re trying to divide by zero</li>
  <li><strong>Vexing</strong> exceptions are the result of unfortunate design decisions. Vexing
exceptions are thrown in a completely non-exceptional circumstance, and
therefore must be caught and handled all the time. The classic example of a
vexing exception is Int32.Parse, which throws if you give it a string that
cannot be parsed as an integer. Eric recommends calling the Try versions of these
functions instead.</li>
  <li><strong>Exogenous</strong> exceptions appear to be somewhat like vexing exceptions except that
they are not the result of unfortunate design choices. Rather, they are the
result of untidy external realities impinging upon your beautiful, crisp
program logic.</li>
</ul>

<p>Eric gives this pseduo-C# example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>try {
	using ( File f = OpenFile(filename, ForReading) ) {
	use(f);
	}
} catch (FileNotFoundException) {
	// Handle filename not found
}
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Can you eliminate the try-catch with this code?</p>
<div><div><pre><code>if (!FileExists(filaname))
    // Handle filename not found
else
    using (File f = ...
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>No, you can’t! The new code has a race condition. Eric suggests that you just
bite the bullet and always handle exceptions that indicate unexpected
exogenous conditions.</p>

<h2 id="composing-errors-codes">Composing Errors Codes</h2>
<p>Rob Pike writes in <a href="https://blog.golang.org/errors-are-values">Errors are
Values</a> about how to avoid writing
<code>if err != nil {...}</code> all the time in Go code. Instead of sprinkling if
statements, the error handling can be integrated into the type. He gives the
bufio packages’s <code>Scanner</code> as an example:</p>

<div><div><pre><code>scanner := bufio.NewScanner(input)
for scanner.Scan() {
    token := scanner.Text()
    // process token
}
if err := scanner.Err(); err != nil {
    // process the error
}
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>The check for errors is only done once. Rob also mentions that the
<code>archive/zip</code> and <code>net/http</code> packages use the same pattern. The <code>bufio</code>
package’s Writer does as well.</p>

<div><div><pre><code>b := bufio.NewWriter(fd)
b.Write(x)
b.Write(y)
b.Write(z)
// and so on
if b.Flush() != nil {
    return b.Flush()
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Fabien Giesen describes a similar pattern for error handling in <a href="https://fgiesen.wordpress.com/2011/11/21/buffer-centric-io/">Buffer
Centric I/O</a>. And
the pattern is used extensively throughout the Qt framework’s core classes.
Another name for it is sticky errors or error accumulator.</p>

<h2 id="error-handling-granularity">Error Handling Granularity</h2>
<p>Per Vognsen discusses how to do <a href="https://bitwise.handmade.network/episode/bitwise/bitwise006/#5537">course-grained error handling in C using
setjmp/longjmp</a>.
The use case there were for arena allocations and deeply nested recursive
parsers. It’s very similar to how C++ does exception handling, but without the
downsides of the costly C++ memory deallocation on stack unwinding. He goes on to say
that certain classes of push-oriented API’s, that has clear command-query separation,
don’t need to do fine-grained error handling. It’s the same idea as in the
previous section.</p>

<p>Fabien Giesen describes in <a href="https://gist.github.com/anonymous/2edc9e9d52a93c126ff486cfb4a2c65b">an aside for a gist note</a>
how he views error handling. He points out that it may be beneficial to only
provide a small set of error codes and that the selection of those should be
dictated by the question “what should I do next?”. E.g. there are many ways a
network connection can fail but providing a giant taxonomy of error codes
won’t help the calling code to decide what to do. Logging should be as
specific as possible but the users of an API just need to decide what to do
next.</p>

<p>Fabien wrote <a href="https://cbloomrants.blogspot.se/2010/06/06-07-10-exceptions.html?showComment=1275971007229#c4849051810850075252">in a blog
comment</a>
 that having stack unwinding do the cleanup on errors is a bad design that
costs lots of resources and is hard to control.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Cleanup stack”-based unwinding incurs a cost on every single function, which
means it’s equivalent to checking for error conditions in every single
function. That is a very bad way of implementing error handling; a method that
works much better is to just remember that an error occurred, but substitute
valid data as soon as possible.</p>

  <p>That is, separate “tactical” error handling (which just needs to make sure
your program ends up in a safe and consistent state) from “strategical” error
handling (which is usually at a pretty high level in an app and might involve
user interaction), and try to keep most intermediate layers unaware of both.</p>

  <p>I consider this good practice in general, not least because immediately
escalating error conditions not only makes for hard to understand control
flow, but also a bad user experience. Take broken P4 connections, copies of
large …</p></blockquote></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://dannas.name/error-handling">https://dannas.name/error-handling</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://dannas.name/error-handling</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23884505</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 20:19:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[PIFuHD: High-Resolution 3D Human Digitization]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 76 | Comments 16 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23884480">thread link</a>) | @jonbaer
<br/>
July 18, 2020 | https://shunsukesaito.github.io/PIFuHD/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://shunsukesaito.github.io/PIFuHD/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://shunsukesaito.github.io/PIFuHD/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23884480</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 20:15:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Booting to 'Hello Rust' on x86_64]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 237 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23881584">thread link</a>) | @micouay
<br/>
July 18, 2020 | https://micouy.github.io/posts/low-level-pt-1/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://micouy.github.io/posts/low-level-pt-1/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="content">
<article>
    
<p>This post is about how I booted to bare metal Rust on x86_64.
My goal is to describe my learning path and hopefully get
you interested in things I talk about. I’ll be very happy if you
find this content useful. Note that I’m a begginer and I may be wrong
about many things. If you want to learn more, I’ll put links to many resources.
You can find all the code in my <a href="https://github.com/micouy/gniazdo-os">repo</a>.</p>

<p>The inspiration for this project came from many sources. I think I first
discovered <a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/os-tutorial">cfenollosa/os-tutorial</a>.
I also read a few chapters from <a href="https://www.cs.bham.ac.uk/~exr/lectures/opsys/10_11/lectures/os-dev.pdf">Writing a Simple Operating System - from Scratch</a>.
It’s a good introduction to OS dev and related topics. First part
of the tutorial is about bootloaders. To get a grasp of what it’s
all about, I just read every part of the tutorial and tried to write the Assembly
code by myself.</p>
<p>Here’s a brief explanation of the boot process and what you have to do
at each stage. First the CPU thinks it’s an Intel 8086 model form 1970s IIRC. This stage is
called Real Mode. You have ~1MiB of memory and 16-bit <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Processor_register">registers</a>
at your disposition. In RM you are very limited. However, at this stage
you can use BIOS routines (or interrupts). They’re like an external library you can use to
print a character on the screen, read from and write to hard disk etc.
You can obviously do these things in other modes but you have to implement it yourself
or do some hacking to use the interrupts.</p>
<p>When you’re done with RM, you can switch to Protected Mode. In PM the address space
is extended (you can access more memory), 32-bit registers are enabled
and addressing works a bit different. To switch to PM,
you have to set up a <a href="http://www.osdever.net/tutorials/view/the-world-of-protected-mode">Descriptor Table</a>
which is a piece of data that tells the CPU
how to interpret addresses, and describes the characteristics of particular
parts of the memory.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: At first I thought that in PM address like <code>ds:ebx</code>
works just like in RM - <code>ds</code> is the segment (in ‘data’ memory if you want
to read/write to it or in ‘code’ memory if you jump to it) and <code>ebx</code>
is the offset in this segment. In reality <code>ds</code> acts like an index
into the descriptor table. Then, the selected descriptor is used
to translate the offset from the segment base (stored in <code>ebx</code>) to a physical address.
You can read more about addressing in PM <a href="http://ece-research.unm.edu/jimp/310/slides/micro_arch2.html">here</a>.
Also check out other stuff on <a href="http://ece-research.unm.edu/jimp/">their website</a>.</p>
<hr>

<p>The bootloader is a very short piece of code - it’s just 512 bytes long.
I once even ran out of space and had to remove some strings and unnecessary
code. The actual purpose of the bootloader is to load and run some other code.
The book suggested booting to PM and jumping to a 32-bit kernel written in C.
I didn’t really like programming in C and at this point I lost my motivation.</p>
<p>Another time I learned about Philipp Oppermann’s <a href="https://os.phil-opp.com/">blog</a>
on OS dev in Rust. I highly recommend it. I got really excited but,
unfortunately for me, Oppermann uses <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/grub/">GRUB</a>
(a kind of bootloader) so I decided to come back to the tutorial after
finishing my own bootloader. At that time booting to a program written in language
other than Assembly and compiled to a separate file was way beyond my capabilities
so I left the project for a while.</p>
<p>A couple weeks ago I got motivated enough to try to boot to a Rust program.
My plan was to switch to Long Mode. Then I could either run a 64-bit kernel
or load a second stage bootloader. Second stage bootloader is not limited
to one sector (can be more than 512 bytes long) and can be 32-bit
or even 64-bit so it has access to a larger address space and can load
arbitrarily large files from disk to memory (as long as you implement it).
Its purpose is to load larger kernels.</p>
<p>The first step was loading my program from hard disk to memory.
I took a naive approach. I compiled the bootloader and my program.
I concatenated both binaries together, one right after the other, to form one file, like this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">cat bootloader.bin hello_rust.bin &gt; img
</code></pre></div><p>I didn’t care if I could actually execute Rust code, I just wanted
to test if I can load it. I added necessary code to my bootloader
and ran the emulator. Unfortunately QEMU just kept restarting.
I’m not sure what went wrong but it didn’t matter since it
was a stupid way to do it. I could just test loading data from the disk on
a much simpler bootloader. I first tried to write it myself but after a while
I just grabbed some code from Stack Overflow and added a simple error message in case
the BIOS routine failed. After a couple of tries I finally managed to create
a two-stage bootloader in a single Assembly program. It worked something like this:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="nasm"><span>org</span> <span>0x7c00</span>
first_stage:
    <span>; load second stage.</span>

    <span>; `dl` register specifies which disk to load</span>
    <span>; data from. it is set by the CPU to the same device</span>
    <span>; the bootloader was loaded from.</span>

    <span>; set `es` to 0x7e0 and `bx` to 0x0.</span>
    
    <span>; the routine will load data to `(es &lt;&lt; 4) | bx`</span>
    <span>; or 0x7e00.</span>
    <span>mov</span> ax, <span>0x7e0</span>
    <span>mov</span> es, ax
    <span>mov</span> bx, <span>0x0</span>

    <span>mov</span> al, <span>0x1</span> <span>; # of sectors to read.</span>
    
    <span>push</span> ax <span>; store `al` for later.</span>

    <span>; specify where the data is stored on the disk.</span>
    <span>mov</span> ch, <span>0x0</span> <span>; cylinder.</span>
    <span>mov</span> dh, <span>0x0</span> <span>; head.</span>
    <span>mov</span> cl, <span>0x2</span> <span>; sector right after bootloader.</span>

    <span>; `int 0x13` with `ah` set to 0x2</span>
    <span>; loads data from disk to memory.</span>
    <span>mov</span> ah, <span>0x2</span>
    <span>int</span> <span>0x13</span>

    <span>pop</span> bx <span>; restore `al` to `bl`.</span>

    <span>; check whether the number of sectors read is correct.</span>
    <span>cmp</span> al, bl
    <span>jne</span> error
       
    <span>jmp</span> <span>0x7e00</span> <span>; jump to second stage.</span>

error:
    <span>; print error message, then halt.</span>
    <span>jmp</span> <span>$</span>

<span>; fill the rest of the first sector with zeros.</span>
<span>; it's 510 and not 512 because the last two bytes</span>
<span>; are 0xaa and 0x55 - the 'magic' number.</span>
<span>times</span> <span>510</span><span>-</span>(<span>$</span><span>-</span><span>$$</span>) db <span>0</span>
<span>dw</span> <span>0xaa55</span>

second_stage:
    <span>; do something, then halt.</span>
    <span>jmp</span> <span>$</span>

<span>; padding to fill the rest of the second sector with zeros.</span>
<span>times</span> <span>1024</span><span>-</span>(<span>$</span><span>-</span><span>$$</span>) db <span>0</span>
</code></pre></div><p>This way I didn’t have to link multiple files and NASM managed the padding of sectors
for me. The code correctly compiled to a single file which was exactly 1024 bytes long -
two entire sectors.</p>
<p>You can also use <code>align 512</code> instead of <code>times 1024-($-$$)</code> to allow
your code to be arbitrarily large. This could be useful if you wanted to program
the second stage of your bootloader in Assembly.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: Don’t assume that the registers are initialized with any particular
value. It took me half an hour or so to realize that I didn’t set some register
correctly in such a simple piece of code. IIRC there are only two things you can
be sure of - that the bootloader will be loaded to 0x7c00 and that the <code>dl</code> register
points to the same device the bootloader has been loaded from.</p>
<hr>

<p>After I managed to load the second sector I wanted to replace the Assembly code
with Rust code. To check whether I could execute it I needed to switch to Long Mode.
That’s because I had some problems with compiling Rust code to 32-bit
and I ended up using the <code>x86_64-unknown-none</code> target triple, just like
in Oppermann’s tutorial.</p>
<p>Long Mode adds a new memory model (paging), and enables the use
of 64-bit instructions and registers. Switching to LM requires setting up paging.
I identity-mapped the first 2 MiB of memory which is enough for now. I think it
can be modified later by my Rust program. I read the following guides on paging:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://wiki.osdev.org/Setting_Up_Long_Mode#Setting_up_the_Paging">https://wiki.osdev.org/Setting_Up_Long_Mode#Setting_up_the_Paging</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wiki.osdev.org/Paging#Enabling">https://wiki.osdev.org/Paging#Enabling</a></li>
<li><a href="https://intermezzos.github.io/book/first-edition/transitioning-to-long-mode.html">https://intermezzos.github.io/book/first-edition/transitioning-to-long-mode.html</a></li>
<li><a href="http://ece-research.unm.edu/jimp/310/slides/micro_arch3.html">http://ece-research.unm.edu/jimp/310/slides/micro_arch3.html</a></li>
<li><a href="https://os.phil-opp.com/entering-longmode/">https://os.phil-opp.com/entering-longmode/</a></li>
</ul>
<p>There are also other things you have to do before switching to LM
like checking <code>cpuid</code> instruction support and the highest instruction
op code available.</p>

<p>I figured that to execute Rust code I needed to glue it with
the bootloader to create a single binary. In this step I encountered
a few difficult problems:</p>
<ul>
<li>To work correctly, the bootloader has to be stored in the first 512 bytes of the file.
The last two bytes of this sector have to be 0xaa55.</li>
<li>My Rust code should also be aligned with the sectors and fill up the last sector
entirely. Of course I would fill it with some garbage values but they had to
be there.</li>
<li>The bootloader has to know how long the Rust code is.</li>
<li>Both programs will be loaded at specific locations in the memory
so I have to manage the offsets in addresses.</li>
</ul>
<p>Linker seemed like a tool made for this. I’ve never used a linker before so I just read
<a href="https://ftp.gnu.org/old-gnu/Manuals/ld-2.9.1/html_node/ld_toc.html"><code>ld</code>'s documentation</a>.
Unfortunately, I got a bit confused. I didn’t understand how the <code>.</code> operator
worked in linker scripts. I also got something wrong about the <code>AT()</code> instruction.
You can see the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/osdev/comments/hhd7uj/linking_bootloader_with_second_stage/">thread</a>
I started on Reddit.</p>
<p>Eventually I came up with such script:</p>
<pre><code>SECTIONS {
    .boot 0x7c00 : {
        *(.boot.*);
    }

    .hello_rust 0x7e00 : {
        *(.rust.*);
        . = ALIGN(512);
    } = 0xdeadc0de

    SECOND_STAGE_LENGTH = ((. - ADDR(.hello_rust)) &gt;&gt; 9);
}
</code></pre><p>Notice that I put all sections beginning with <code>.boot</code> in the first 512 bytes
and all sections beginning with <code>.rust</code> after 0x7e00. In order to make
it work I have to rename all sections in the ELF file emitted by <code>rustc</code>
so that they all start with a prefix. I do it using <code>objcopy</code>
(in some linkers this option is called <code>--prefix-sections</code>):</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">objcopy hello_rust.o hello_rust_prefixed.o --prefix-alloc-sections<span>=</span><span>'.rust'</span>
</code></pre></div><p>The there are two tricks in this script. The first one is that I align
the end of the <code>.rust</code> section to the nearest sector boundary with <code>. = ALIGN(512)</code>.
Then I fill the rest with some garbage using <code>= 0xdeadc0de</code>.
The second trick is in the last line. The <code>SECOND_STAGE_LENGTH</code>
variable tells the bootloader how many sectors the second stage occupies.
The size of this section is divided by 512 = 2^9. Since I know
that the end of this section is aligned with the boundaries
of the sectors I can just shift it 9 bits to the right.</p>
<p>These solutions seem a bit hacky. In my understanding the location
of a piece of code in an ELF file (most common target) doesn’t matter. This is not the
case with the bootloader since the code
must be aligned to 512 bytes and there must be a magic number
at the end of the first …</p></article></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://micouy.github.io/posts/low-level-pt-1/">https://micouy.github.io/posts/low-level-pt-1/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://micouy.github.io/posts/low-level-pt-1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23881584</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 14:27:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Kubectl – Configuration Guide]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 66 | Comments 25 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23881485">thread link</a>) | @lukasbar
<br/>
July 18, 2020 | https://knowledgepill.it/posts/kubernetes-kubectl-client-config/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://knowledgepill.it/posts/kubernetes-kubectl-client-config/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
  <p>Kubectl client gives us possibility to configure and switch easily between multiple K8s clusters.</p>
<h2 id="config-files-location-for-kubectl">Config files location for kubectl</h2>
<p>Main location for <code>kubectl</code> config files is <code>$HOME/.kube</code>, by default we have single config file named config:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ cd $HOME/.kube
<span>[</span>node1 .kube<span>]</span>$ ls -lah
total 4.0K
drwxr-xr-x <span>1</span> root root   <span>37</span> Mar <span>12</span> 20:48 .
dr-xr-x--- <span>1</span> root root   <span>19</span> Nov <span>29</span> 11:46 ..
drwxr-x--- <span>3</span> root root   <span>23</span> Mar <span>12</span> 20:48 cache
lrwxrwxrwx <span>1</span> root root   <span>26</span> Nov <span>29</span> 11:46 config -&gt; /etc/kubernetes/admin.conf
drwxr-x--- <span>3</span> root root 4.0K Mar <span>12</span> 20:48 http-cache
</code></pre></div><h2 id="multiple-config-files-and-kubeconfig-variable">Multiple config files and KUBECONFIG variable</h2>
<p>We can have multiple config files by setting proper <code>KUBECONFIG</code> shell variable.<br>
For example:</p>
<p><code>export KUBECONFIG=$KUBECONFIG:/root/.kube/additional_config</code></p>
<h2 id="check-config-from-kubectl">Check config from kubectl</h2>
<p>We can check current config(it will be empty because I don’t have anything in additional_config file - we’ll add something later - and this is only file in my <code>KUBECONFIG</code> variable):</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="yaml">[node1 ~]$ kubectl config view
<span>apiVersion</span>: v1
<span>clusters</span>: []
<span>contexts</span>: []
<span>current-context</span>: <span>""</span>
<span>kind</span>: Config
<span>preferences</span>: {}
<span>users</span>: []
</code></pre></div><p>Or from specific file - let’s see default file:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="yaml">[node1 ~]$ kubectl config --kubeconfig=.kube/config view
<span>apiVersion</span>: v1
<span>clusters</span>:
- <span>cluster</span>:
    <span>certificate-authority-data</span>: DATA+OMITTED
    <span>server</span>: https://<span>192.168</span><span>.0</span><span>.38</span>:<span>6443</span>
  <span>name</span>: kubernetes
<span>contexts</span>:
- <span>context</span>:
    <span>cluster</span>: kubernetes
    <span>user</span>: kubernetes-admin
  <span>name</span>: kubernetes-admin@kubernetes
<span>current-context</span>: kubernetes-admin@kubernetes
<span>kind</span>: Config
<span>preferences</span>: {}
<span>users</span>:
- <span>name</span>: kubernetes-admin
  <span>user</span>:
    <span>client-certificate-data</span>: REDACTED
    <span>client-key-data</span>: REDACTED
</code></pre></div><p>If you don’t set <code>KUBECONFIG</code> variable all configuration will be taken from <code>$HOME/.kube/config</code></p>
<h2 id="objects-in-kubectl-config">Objects in kubectl config</h2>
<p><code>kubectl</code> has in its config files following object types:</p>
<ul>
<li>clusters - info about K8s cluster - contain cluster name and connection parameters</li>
<li>users - info about users by which you want connect to K8s clusters</li>
<li>contexts - triple of cluster/user/namespace</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="modifying-config-from-kubectl">Modifying config from kubectl</h2>
<h3 id="add-cluster">Add cluster</h3>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config set-cluster dev --server<span>=</span>https://192.168.1.100 --certificate-authority<span>=</span>fake-ca
Cluster <span>"dev"</span> set.
<span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config set-cluster prod --server<span>=</span>https://10.1.1.100 --certificate-authority<span>=</span>fake-ca
Cluster <span>"prod"</span> set.
</code></pre></div><h3 id="add-users">Add users</h3>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config set-credentials developer --client-certificate<span>=</span>fake-cert-file --client-key<span>=</span>fake-key-seefile
User <span>"developer"</span> set.
<span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config set-credentials prod_admin --client-certificate<span>=</span>fake-cert-file --client-key<span>=</span>fake-key-seefile
User <span>"prod_admin"</span> set.
</code></pre></div><h3 id="add-contexts">Add contexts</h3>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config set-context simple_app_development --cluster<span>=</span>dev --namespace<span>=</span>simple_app_dev --user<span>=</span>developer
Context <span>"simple_app_development"</span> created.
<span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config set-context simple_app_production --cluster<span>=</span>prod --namespace<span>=</span>simple_app_prod --user<span>=</span>prod_admin
Context <span>"simple_app_production"</span> created.
</code></pre></div><h3 id="delete-clusterusercontext-from-config">Delete cluster/user/context from config</h3>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash">kubectl --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config config unset users.&lt;name&gt;
kubectl --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config config unset clusters.&lt;name&gt;
kubectl --kubeconfig<span>=</span>.kube/additional_config config unset contexts.&lt;name&gt;
</code></pre></div><h3 id="sample-config">Sample config</h3>
<div><pre><code data-lang="yaml">[node1 ~]$ kubectl config --kubeconfig=.kube/additional_config view
<span>apiVersion</span>: v1
<span>clusters</span>:
- <span>cluster</span>:
    <span>certificate-authority</span>: /root/fake-ca
    <span>server</span>: https://<span>192.168</span><span>.1</span><span>.100</span>
  <span>name</span>: dev
- <span>cluster</span>:
    <span>certificate-authority</span>: /root/fake-ca
    <span>server</span>: https://<span>10.1</span><span>.1</span><span>.100</span>
  <span>name</span>: prod
<span>contexts</span>:
- <span>context</span>:
    <span>cluster</span>: dev
    <span>namespace</span>: simple_app_dev
    <span>user</span>: developer
  <span>name</span>: simple_app_development
- <span>context</span>:
    <span>cluster</span>: prod
    <span>namespace</span>: simple_app_prod
    <span>user</span>: prod_admin
  <span>name</span>: simple_app_production
<span>current-context</span>: <span>""</span>
<span>kind</span>: Config
<span>preferences</span>: {}
<span>users</span>:
- <span>name</span>: developer
  <span>user</span>:
    <span>client-certificate</span>: /root/fake-cert-file
    <span>client-key</span>: /root/fake-key-seefile
- <span>name</span>: prod_admin
  <span>user</span>:
    <span>client-certificate</span>: /root/fake-cert-file
    <span>client-key</span>: /root/fake-key-seefile
</code></pre></div><h3 id="changing-context-to-work-with">Changing context to work with</h3>
<p>To get list of contexts(no need for <code>--kubeconfig</code> because we have our <code>additional_config</code> added to <code>KUBECONFIG</code> variable):</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config get-contexts
CURRENT   NAME                     CLUSTER   AUTHINFO     NAMESPACE
          simple_app_development   dev       developer    simple_app_dev
          simple_app_production    prod      prod_admin   simple_app_prod
</code></pre></div><p>To set context:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config use-context simple_app_development
Switched to context <span>"simple_app_development"</span>.
</code></pre></div><p>To get current context:</p>
<div><pre><code data-lang="bash"><span>[</span>node1 ~<span>]</span>$ kubectl config current-context
simple_app_development
</code></pre></div><hr>
<h3 id="for-those-who-want-to-know-even-more-worth-to-read">For those who want to know even more… Worth to read!</h3>
<p><a href="https://gardener.cloud/documentation/guides/client_tools/bash_kubeconfig/">Kubeconfig context as bash prompt - Georgi from Gardener</a> - shell tricks and Windows CLI aproach</p>
<hr>

</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://knowledgepill.it/posts/kubernetes-kubectl-client-config/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23881485</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 14:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[On Trouser Pockets]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 665 | Comments 338 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23881220">thread link</a>) | @diiq
<br/>
July 18, 2020 | https://sambleckley.com/writing/pockets.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sambleckley.com/writing/pockets.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><h3 id="tldr">TL;DR</h3> <p>The clothing industry rarely creates dramatically new patterns. It is more lucrative to make small, easy-to-manufacture changes that always use the same basic pattern.</p> <p>There is therefore lots of room to innovate clothing that is more appropriate for contemporary problems, because basic clothing patterns haven’t changed in decades.</p> <p>I made some trousers with unusual pockets, and I think they’re good.</p> <h3 id="pockets-are-either-ugly-or-useless">Pockets are either ugly or useless</h3> <p>Pockets in tight jeans look bad. Putting a modern slab phone, a wallet, and keys into a pair of skinny jeans will leave even the most fashionable figure looking looking like they’re wearing batman’s utility belt as underwear. Even empty, in tight pants a large pocket bag can show through.</p> <p>The alternative, as many women know from first-hand experience, is a pocket too small to put anything in.</p> <p>A wallet in the back pocket can cause back pain and bad posture.</p> <p>Many of us spend most of our time sitting, but all four traditional pockets are totally inaccessible in that position. So we take out our phone, just in case, before we sit down at the restaurant — guaranteeing a distraction.</p> <p>Aesthetics, storage, and access: these are user needs that are currently poorly fulfilled — and that means things are ripe for innovation.</p> <h3 id="a-brief-history">A brief history</h3> <p>If the space is so ripe, why has there been no pocket innovation recently?</p> <p>Women used to have pockets. That “used to” has to count back 150 or even 200 years, and those pockets were often a separate garment, either worn underneath and accessed through a slit in the dress, or worn around the hips overtop, rather than built into the dress directly — but regardless, “it has pockets!” as a joyous surprise is a modern invention. (Men’s pockets were also separate pouches if you go back far enough; but going back the same 150-200 years, they lived in the waistcoat and the mandatory jacket; if breeches had pockets they were behind the falls and so, I suspect, not used as much in public.)</p> <p>The 1880’s brought the 1940s brought the slow arrival of mass production to clothing — not of the textiles, which started much earlier, but of actual clothes. Before this era, clothes were made either at home, or they were made one at a time. (In a quiet resonance with today, this was done in part by women who worked almost entirely from home, only travelling to the workplace to pick up new work and drop off what had been completed).</p> <p>In retrospect, fashions changed mostly decade by decade rather than year by year, but they changed dramatically. The fashionable silhouette of the 1860s looks nothing like the 1880s, or the 1910’s — so different, in fact, that for women the foundation garments were completely unrelated entities: the crinoline of the 1860s is nothing like the bustle of the 1880s. A person who can cut and sew can sew an incredibly wide range of different things; why not play around?</p> <p>But with the advent of mass production in clothes factories, the whole layout of the factory floor was based on specific pattern piecing. Each station makes only a few operations on each garment, and garments flow from one station to the next. To completely change the <em>construction</em> of a garment means a radical overhaul of the whole assembly line.</p> <p>But to simply change the garment’s <em>proportions</em> is <em>easy</em>.</p> <p>And so we live in a world where every spring the morning talk shows invite someone on to say “this year, [culottes, boot-cuts, skinny jeans, flares, cuffs, boyfriend jeans, high waists, low-rise, acid-wash, raw denim] are coming back into fashion, so keep your eye out!” — but the trousers are made from the same basic pieces, constructed in the same ways, with only the measurements changing. They get longer or shorter, looser or tighter, and change color, but they’re not fundamentally <em>different</em>.</p> <p>It’s like a lack-luster procedural generation system. Sure, there are technically millions of possibilities, but somehow you still end up bored after seeing the first 5 or 6.</p> <p>Probably not coincidentally, the advent of mass production is also when women’s silhouettes turned slim, and when all those foundation garments mostly disappeared. Designs that banish structure from the garment and rely entirely on the body beneath are much easier and cheaper to manufacture.</p> <p>And when silhouettes turned slim, women lost pockets. The more body-hugging the clothing, the less room for pockets — or, rather, the more the pocket contents will show unflatteringly. (And as we know, it would be anathema for a women to show unflattering lump for something as silly as practicality, function, or utility.)</p> <p>And even as womenswear adopted men’s workwear styles, women got jeans but not the pockets to go with them. Spandex made it even easier to make mass-produced clothes “fit”, and fit tighter. The unsightly-lump factor wasn’t going away.</p> <p>Even more recently, menswear has returned to an incredibly slim silhouette. Guys in skinny jeans should, by this logic, not have pockets either. But they do.</p> <p>Women get no practicality and men get no grace.</p> <h3 id="what-if-we-redesigned-the-pocket-from-scratch">What if we redesigned the pocket from scratch?</h3> <p>Let’s design a trouser pocket! This process is going to land somewhere between UX and industrial design. I am, sadly, not in charge of a clothes factory, so I am not concerned with the problems of mass-production, but material properties and the construction process do still matter; but I am maybe more willing to make manufacturing sacrifices for usefulness than most industrial designers are able to be.</p> <h3 id="what-do-people-use-pockets-for">What do people use pockets for?</h3> <ul> <li>Storing things; most often phone, then keys, wallet or money-clip, and other small items. At the moment, a mask.</li> <li><em>Verifying</em> stored objects — the hip-slapping dance of making sure you have everything before walking out the door.</li> <li>They must be secure while standing, sitting, running for the bus, etc</li> <li>Things, especially phone, need to go in and out of storage frequently, almost unconsciously.</li> <li>Access to phone while seated in a restaurant; to keys and license while in car</li> <li>Aesthetically, we want a clean, graceful line from hip to ankle even while holding things.</li> </ul> <p>An initial solution can be based on just three questions:</p> <ul> <li>Where can your hands reach?</li> <li>Where is there extra space to put things?</li> <li>Where is there enough support to prevent items swinging around uncomfortably?</li> </ul> <p>These questions form a physical venn diagram, pointing at a pretty small area for investigation:</p> <p><img src="https://sambleckley.com/assets/images/pocket_venn.png" alt="The human body with overlapping regions of reach, space, and support."></p> <p>You can see that current pockets are located completely outside the area where there is potentially space; the hips and butt of modern pants, for both women and men, are closely fitted. If there’s any ease, it starts just above the knees.</p> <p>Conveniently, the point where the vastus lateralis starts to curve back in towards the knee, creating space, is also right around the lowest point your arms can reach without bending over, giving us a well-defined target.</p> <p>So I made a pair of trousers with no pockets at the waist, and a pair of welt pockets at the side seams, right at that point.</p> <p><img src="https://sambleckley.com/assets/images/pants1.jpg" alt="First pair of pants."></p> <h3 id="notes-from-user-testing">Notes from user testing:</h3> <ul> <li>A pocket needs to be big enough for a whole hand, not just phone, to allow for fishing out small items from the very bottom of the pocket-bag.</li> <li>The pocket bag slips down and back if it’s full and the wearer sits down. This is uncomfortable and</li> <li>The pocket mustn’t allow a slick round phone to fall out when sitting, especially when, e.g. jiggling a leg.</li> </ul> <h3 id="revisions">Revisions</h3> <p>Luckily, each of these notes point at simple revision, rather than the need to start again.</p> <ul> <li>Make the pockets wider.</li> <li>Anchor the bottom of the pocket bag to the side seam.</li> <li>Angle the opening so it’s higher in the back — this both makes it easier to slip a phone into the pocket, and makes the pocket “deeper” on the bottom side when sitting or crouching.</li> </ul> <p><img src="https://sambleckley.com/assets/images/pants2.jpg" alt="Second pair of pants."></p> <h3 id="outcome">Outcome</h3> <p>These are great. I completely forget my phone and wallet are there — they don’t restrict my movement, they’re completely invisible, and yet they’re easy to access while standing or sitting. There’s no temptation to slouch around with my hands stuffed in my pockets. They’re so straightforwardly better for my needs that I’m now frustrated when my new-pocket pants are dirty and I have to wear trousers with pockets that are just SO twentieth-century. I immediately made a pair of jeans in this pattern, too.</p> <p>Further revision is possible, of course; but while it will be easy to refine this design to suit my personal body and needs more precisely, there’s only so much refinement possible while remaining suitable for a wide range of body types. If you wanted to mass-produce a pocket like this, you’d want to use something like Dreyfuss’ Humanscale data to make sure the placement and size is appropriate for the widest range of people. Luckily, you’d have <em>some</em> additional information in the sizing of the <em>rest</em> of the pants.</p> <h3 id="appendix-sam-have-you-simply-invented-cargo-pants">Appendix: Sam, have you simply invented cargo pants?</h3> <p>No. Cargo pants solve different problems for different people.</p> <p>If cargo pants are appropriate for your daily life, you definitely don’t want or need my side-seam welt pockets; and vice-versa. Cargo pants aren’t office-wear; these dress pants aren’t combat-wear.</p> </div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sambleckley.com/writing/pockets.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23881220</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 13:16:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Typed Lisp, a Primer (2019)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 97 | Comments 21 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23878612">thread link</a>) | @jedimind
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://alhassy.github.io/TypedLisp.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://alhassy.github.io/TypedLisp.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id="text-typing-via-macros">
<p>
Checking the type of inputs is tedious and so I <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/cct5hp/functional_type_declarations_in_elisp/">guessed</a> it could be done using
macros and advice. Looking at <a href="https://docs.racket-lang.org/ts-guide/types.html">Typed Racket</a> for inspiration, the following
fictitious syntax would add advice to <code>f</code> that checks the optional arguments <code>xᵢ</code>
have type <code>σᵢ</code> and the mandatory positional arguments have type <code>τᵢ</code> according
to position, and the result of the computation is of type <code>τ</code>.
To the best of my knowledge, no one had done this for Emacs Lisp —I don't know why.
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type 'f ((<span>:x₁</span> σ₁) … (<span>:xₘ</span> σₘ)) (τ₁ … τₙ τ))
</pre>
</div>

<p>
To modify a variable, or function, we may simply redefine it; but a much more elegant and powerful
approach is to <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/elisp/Advising-Functions.html">“advise”</a> the current entity with some new behaviour. In our case of interest, we will
<i>advise functions to check their arguments before executing their bodies</i>.
</p>

<p>
Below is my attempt: <a id="org84d2c90"><code>declare-type</code></a>. Before you get scared or think it's horrendous, be charitable and
note that about a third of the following is documentation and a third is local declarations.
</p>
<div>
<pre>(<span>cl-defmacro</span> <span>declare-type</span> (f key-types <span>&amp;rest</span> types)
  <span>"Attach the given list of types to the function ‘f’</span>
<span>   by advising the function to check its arguments’ types</span>
<span>   are equal to the list of given types.</span>

<span>   We name the advice ‘⟪f⟫-typing-advice’ so that further</span>
<span>   invocations to this macro overwrite the same advice function</span>
<span>   rather than introducing additional, unintended, constraints.</span>

<span>   Using type specifiers we accommodate for unions of types</span>
<span>   and subtypes, etc ♥‿♥.</span>

<span>   ‘</span><span>key-types</span><span>’ should be of the shape (:x₀ t₀ ⋯ :xₙ tₙ);</span>
<span>    when there are no optional types, use symbol “:”.</span>

<span>    E.g., (declare-type my-func (:z string :w integer) integer symbol string)</span>
<span>  "</span>

  <span>;; </span><span>Basic coherency checks. When there aren't optional types, key-types is the “:” symbol.</span>
  (should (<span>and</span> (<span>listp</span> types) (<span>or</span> (<span>listp</span> key-types) (<span>symbolp</span> key-types))))

  (<span>letf*</span> ((pairify (<span>lambda</span> (xs) (<span>loop</span> for i in xs by #'<span>cddr</span>         <span>;; </span><span>Turn a list of flattenned pairs</span>
                                      for j in (<span>cdr</span> xs) by #'<span>cddr</span>   <span>;; </span><span>into a list of explicit pairs.</span>
                                      collect (<span>cons</span> i j))))         <span>;; </span><span>MA: No Lisp method for this!?</span>
         (result-type  (<span>car</span> (<span>-take-last</span> 1 types)))
         (types        (<span>-drop-last</span> 1 types))
         (num-of-types (<span>length</span> types))
         (key-types-og (<span>unless</span> (<span>symbolp</span> key-types) key-types))
         (key-types    (<span>funcall</span> pairify key-types-og))
         (advice-name  (<span>intern</span> (<span>format</span> <span>"%s-typing-advice"</span> f)))
         (notify-user  (<span>format</span> <span>"%s now typed %s → %s → %s."</span>
                               `,f key-types-og types result-type)))

      `(<span>progn</span>
         (<span>defun</span> ,advice-name (orig-fun <span>&amp;rest</span> args)

           <span>;; </span><span>Split into positional and key args; optionals not yet considered.</span>
           (<span>letf*</span> ((all-args
                     (<span>-split-at</span>
                       (<span>or</span> (<span>--find-index</span> (<span>not</span> (<span>s-blank?</span> (<span>s-shared-start</span> <span>":"</span> (<span>format</span> <span>"%s"</span> it)))) args) ,num-of-types)
                        args)) <span>;; </span><span>The “or” is for when there are no keywords provided.</span>
                  (pos-args  (<span>car</span> all-args))
                  (key-args  (<span>funcall</span> ,pairify (<span>cadr</span> all-args)))
                  (fun-result nil)
                  ((<span>symbol-function</span> 'shucks)
                     (<span>lambda</span> (eτ e g)
                       (<span>unless</span> (<span>typep</span> g eτ)
                         (<span>error</span> <span>"%s: Type mismatch! Expected %s %s ≠ Given %s %s."</span>
                                (<span>function</span> ,f) eτ e (<span>type-of</span> g) (<span>prin1-to-string</span> g))))))

         <span>;; </span><span>Check the types of positional arguments.</span>
         (<span>unless</span> (<span>equal</span> ,num-of-types (<span>length</span> pos-args))
           (<span>error</span> <span>"%s: Insufficient number of arguments; given %s, %s, but %s are needed."</span>
                  (<span>function</span> ,f) (<span>length</span> pos-args) pos-args ,num-of-types))
         (<span>loop</span> for (ar ty pos) in (<span>-zip</span> pos-args (<span>quote</span> ,types) (<span>number-sequence</span> 0 ,num-of-types))
               <span>do</span> (shucks ty (<span>format</span> <span>"for argument %s"</span> pos) ar))

         <span>;; </span><span>Check the types of *present* keys.</span>
         (<span>loop</span> for (k . v) in key-args
               <span>do</span> (shucks (<span>cdr</span> (<span>assoc</span> k (<span>quote</span> ,key-types))) k v))

         <span>;; </span><span>Actually execute the orginal function on the provided arguments.</span>
         (<span>setq</span> fun-result (<span>apply</span> orig-fun args))
         (shucks (<span>quote</span> ,result-type) <span>"for the result type (!)"</span> fun-result)

         <span>;; </span><span>Return-value should be given to caller.</span>
         fun-result))

      <span>;; </span><span>Register the typing advice and notify user of what was added.</span>
      (<span>advice-add</span> (<span>function</span> ,f) <span>:around</span> (<span>function</span> ,advice-name))
      ,notify-user )))
</pre>
</div>

<pre>declare-type
</pre>


<p>
There are some notable shortcomings: Lack of support for type variables and, for now, no support for
optional arguments. Nonetheless, I like it —of course.
( Using <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/elisp/Watching-Variables.html#Watching-Variables">variable watchers</a> we could likely add support for type variables as well as
function-types. )
</p>

<p>
<b>We accidentally forgot to consider an argument.</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₁ (<span>:z</span> <span>string</span> <span>:w</span> <span>list</span>) integer symbol <span>string</span>)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₁ now typed (:z string :w integer) → (integer symbol) → string.</span>

(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₁</span> (x y <span>&amp;key</span> z w) (<span>format</span> <span>"%s"</span> x))
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₁ now defined</span>

(f₁ 'x) <span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₁: Insufficient number of arguments; given 2, (x), but 3 are needed.</span>
</pre>
</div>
<p>
The type declaration said we needed 3 arguments, but we did not consider one of them.
</p>

<p>
<b>We accidentally returned the wrong value.</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₂ (<span>:z</span> <span>string</span> <span>:w</span> <span>list</span>) integer symbol <span>string</span>)
(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₂</span> (x y <span>&amp;key</span> z w) x)

(f₂ 144 'two)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₂: Type mismatch! Expected string for the result type (!) ≠ Given integer 144.</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
<b>We accidentally forgot to supply an argument.</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₃ (<span>:z</span> <span>string</span> <span>:w</span> <span>list</span>) integer symbol <span>string</span>)
(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₃</span> (x y <span>&amp;key</span> z w) (<span>format</span> <span>"%s"</span> x))

(f₃ 144)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₃: Insufficient number of arguments; given 1, (144), but 2 are needed.</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
<b>A positional argument is supplied of the wrong type.</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(f₃ 'one <span>"two"</span>)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒  f₃: Type mismatch! Expected integer for argument 0 ≠ Given symbol one.</span>

(f₃ 144 <span>"two"</span>)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₃: Type mismatch! Expected symbol for argument 1 ≠ Given string "two".</span>
</pre>
</div>
<p>
Notice: When multiple positional arguments have type-errors, the errors are reported one at a time.
</p>

<p>
<b>A keyword argument is supplied of the wrong type.</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(f₃ 1 'two <span>:z</span> 'no₀ <span>:w</span> 'no₁)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₃: Type mismatch! Expected string :z ≠ Given symbol no₀.</span>

(f₃ 1 'two <span>:z</span> <span>"ok"</span> <span>:w</span> 'no₁)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₃: Type mismatch! Expected string :w ≠ Given symbol no₁.</span>

(f₃ 1 'two <span>:z</span> <span>"ok"</span> <span>:w</span> 23)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₃: Type mismatch! Expected string :w ≠ Given integer 23.</span>

(f₃ 1 'two <span>:z</span> <span>"ok"</span> <span>:w</span> '(a b 1 2)) <span>;; </span><span>⇒ okay; no type-error.</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
<b>We have no optional arguments.</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₄ : integer symbol <span>string</span>)
(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₄</span> (x y <span>&amp;key</span> z w) (<span>format</span> <span>"%s"</span> x))

(f₄ 144 'two <span>:z</span> <span>"bye"</span>)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒  f₄: Type mismatch! Expected nil :z ≠ Given string "bye".</span>
<span>;; </span><span>( We shouldn't have any keyword :z according to the type declaration! )</span>

(f₄ 144 'two) <span>;; </span><span>⇒ "144"</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
<b>We can incorporate type specfiers such as unions!</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₅ : (<span>or</span> integer <span>string</span>) <span>string</span>)
(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₅</span> (x) (<span>format</span> <span>"%s"</span> x))

(f₅ 144)     <span>;; </span><span>⇒ "144"</span>
(f₅ <span>"neato"</span>) <span>;; </span><span>⇒ "neato"</span>

(f₅ 'shaka-when-the-walls-fell)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₅: Type mismatch! Expected (or integer string) for argument 0</span>
<span>;;       </span><span>≠ Given symbol shaka-when-the-walls-fell.</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
<b>No positional arguments but a complex optional argument!</b>
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₆ (<span>:z</span> (satisfies (<span>lambda</span> (it) (<span>and</span> (<span>integerp</span> it) (<span>=</span> 0 (<span>mod</span> it 5))))))
                 character)
(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₆</span> (<span>&amp;key</span> z) ?A)

(f₆ 'hi)     <span>;; </span><span>⇒  Keyword argument 144 not one of (:z)</span>
(f₆)         <span>;; </span><span>⇒ 65; i.e., the character ‘A’</span>
(f₆ <span>:z</span> 6)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒  f₆: Type mismatch!</span>
<span>;;    </span><span>Expected (satisfies (lambda (it) (and (integerp it) (= 0 (mod it 5))))) :z</span>
<span>;;    </span><span>≠ Given integer 6.</span>

(f₆ <span>:z</span> 10) <span>;; </span><span>⇒ 65; i.e., the expected output since 10 mod 5 ≈ 0 &amp; so 10 is valid input.</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
<b>Preconditions!</b> The previous example had a complex type on a keyword, but that was
essentially a pre-condition; we can do the same on positional arguments.
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₇ : (satisfies (<span>lambda</span> (it) (<span>=</span> it 5)))
                   integer)
(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₇</span> (n) n)
<span>;; </span><span>The identity on 5 function; and undefined otherwise.</span>

(f₇ 4)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒ f₇: Type mismatch! Expected (satisfies (lambda (it) (= it 5))) for argument 0</span>
<span>;;       </span><span>≠ Given integer 4.</span>

(f₇ 5) <span>;; </span><span>⇒ 5</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
<b>Postconditions!</b>
Given an integer greater than 5, we present an integer greater than 2; i.e.,
this is a constructive proof that \(∀ n • n &gt; 5 ⇒ n &gt; 2\).
</p>
<div>
<pre>(declare-type f₈ : (satisfies (<span>lambda</span> (in)  (<span>&gt;</span> in 5)))
                   (satisfies (<span>lambda</span> (out) (<span>&gt;</span> out 2))))
(<span>cl-defun</span> <span>f₈</span> (n) n)
<span>;; </span><span>The identity on 5 function; and undefined otherwise.</span>

(f₈ 4)
<span>;; </span><span>⇒  f₈: Type mismatch! Expected (satisfies (lambda (in) (&gt; in 5))) for argument 0</span>
<span>;;        </span><span>≠ Given integer 4.</span>

(f₈ 72) <span>;; </span><span>⇒ 72; since indeed 72 &gt; 5 for the input, and clearly 72 &gt; 2 for the output.</span>
</pre>
</div>

<p>
As it currently stands we cannot make any explicit references between the inputs
and the output, but that's an easy fix: Simply add a local function <code>old</code> to the
<a href="#org84d2c90"><code>declare-type</code></a> macro which is intentionally exposed so that it can be used in the
type declarations to refer to the ‘old’, or initial, values provided to the function.
Additionally, one could also add keyword arguments <code>:requires</code> and <code>:ensures</code>
for a more sophisticated pre- and post-condition framework.
<a href="https://github.com/sellout/quid-pro-quo">Something</a> along these lines is implemented for Common Lisp.
</p>

<p>
Here's a fun exercise: Recast the <a href="https://liquid.kosmikus.org/01-intro.html#/what-is-liquid-haskell">Liquid Haskell</a> examples in Lisp using this
<a href="#org84d2c90"><code>declare-type</code></a> form.
</p>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://alhassy.github.io/TypedLisp.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23878612</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 03:19:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Levandowski files suit against Uber [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 112 | Comments 91 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23877872">thread link</a>) | @MrSandman
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://ipfs.eternum.io/ipfs/Qmd9PTEtuSrKKtJQw36aNzpjJwZAdCdwCmUn4w21mmq74z/Levandowski-Uber-Complaint-1.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://ipfs.eternum.io/ipfs/Qmd9PTEtuSrKKtJQw36aNzpjJwZAdCdwCmUn4w21mmq74z/Levandowski-Uber-Complaint-1.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://ipfs.eternum.io/ipfs/Qmd9PTEtuSrKKtJQw36aNzpjJwZAdCdwCmUn4w21mmq74z/Levandowski-Uber-Complaint-1.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23877872</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:48:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The evidence which suggests that Covid-19 is not a naturally evolved virus [pdf]]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 475 | Comments 443 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23875758">thread link</a>) | @2a0c40
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://www.minervanett.no/files/2020/07/13/TheEvidenceNoNaturalEvol.pdf | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.minervanett.no/files/2020/07/13/TheEvidenceNoNaturalEvol.pdf">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.minervanett.no/files/2020/07/13/TheEvidenceNoNaturalEvol.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23875758</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 21:23:10 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Why are CEOs failing software engineers?]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 237 | Comments 157 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23872625">thread link</a>) | @kag0
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://iism.org/article/why-are-ceos-failing-software-engineers-56 | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://iism.org/article/why-are-ceos-failing-software-engineers-56">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://iism.org/article/why-are-ceos-failing-software-engineers-56</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23872625</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 16:55:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[We Don't Hate PHP]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 55 | Comments 76 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23871934">thread link</a>) | @Dwolb
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://www.hologram.io/blog/why-we-dont-hate-php | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.hologram.io/blog/why-we-dont-hate-php">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><div><p>Here at Hologram, we use two main programming languages for our backend stack: PHP and Python. Our PHP component is the one that is the most visible to users since that is our entire REST API.</p><p>We do get some questions on why we use PHP in such a major role because the conventional wisdom is that PHP is outdated or clunky. My contention is that PHP suffers from this view because of two reasons:</p><ol role="list"><li>People learned it back in 2005 when it was a younger language and was lacking a lot of really useful or common features like classes</li><li>In order to maintain compatibility, many popular applications *cough* Wordpress *cough* didn’t take advantage of a lot of the newer stuff and people had to keep hacking on old-fashioned PHP well past the time a lot of great new features were introduced.</li></ol><p>Because of this, I want to defend PHP as a really useful language and a great fit for our needs.</p><p>I think a lot of people already know that PHP has some good built-in web server features, like a global array for getting HTTP headers or built-in session cookie support, but they may not know about a lot of other features that make it a solid language overall.</p><p>Here are some of the great pieces of PHP:</p><h2>Classes!</h2><p>Yes, back in the day PHP didn’t have classes and things could get messy very quickly. I recall long lists of include calls to pull in all the functions you’d need and having to keep passing tons of arguments around to functions with really long names.<br></p><p>Well, have no fear; PHP has great object support these days. Classes, constructors, destructors, namespaces, inheritance, and all that good stuff.<br></p><p>But it goes beyond that into what is a great feature that is more unique to PHP:<br></p><h2>The Autoloader</h2><p>PHP has a useful feature where it can automatically load the file for a class if the class hasn’t been loaded already. This means no more blocks of include/require statements at the top of all your files. If you use a class then it gets loaded.<br></p><p>On its own, this is already really nice, but what makes this a game changer is that the specific autoloading logic can be totally customized in your application and multiple autoloaders can be chained together. This means that all of your third party libraries get autoloaded as well.</p><p>In your code, you just create your classes or call their methods and everything gets pulled in for you. No need to include anything manually or fight with include paths like in other languages. In the entire Hologram codebase outside of test code, we call <em>include()</em> or <em>require()</em> maybe twice.<br></p><p>But speaking of those third party libraries…<br></p><h2>Package Management</h2><p>PHP has package management systems to rival those of other languages. The one we use at Hologram is called Composer, which is the most popular one. It’s incredibly simple to use and stores all settings in JSON files. You can give it version ranges to use for each package and it’ll generate a lockfile that could be checked into the repo if you want to be extra careful about making sure everyone is using the exact same package revision.</p><p>To add a new package into the JSON file and install it, it’s as simple as</p><p><code>
    composer install somepackage
</code></p><h2>Frameworks</h2><p>PHP has a great developer community around it these days and so not only are there a ton of individual libraries to use, but full frameworks that can help make building an app much easier. At Hologram, we use the Slim Framework which has a very simple router for defining our API calls as well as other useful features, like an easy method for adding middleware which comes in handy for authentication and rate limiting code.<br></p><p>Other popular frameworks include Laravel and Symfony.</p><h2>PDO</h2><p>PHP has the best database integration of any language I’ve used and PDO is the cornerstone of that. PDO stands for PHP Database Objects and it is the preferred way to execute your SQL queries.<br></p><p>It includes all the usual functions for running queries and paging through the results. Rows can be returned as PHP associative arrays which means that all columns are properly labelled in the array itself.<br></p><p>The best part is that it supports parameterized queries and automatically sanitizes the inputs for you. This means that you can do something like this:</p><p><code>
    // define $database as a PDO object
    $stmt = $database-&gt;prepare("SELECT * FROM users WHERE id = ?;");
    $result = $stmt-&gt;execute([$idnumber]);
    $rows = $result-&gt;fetchAll();
</code></p><p>PDO will automatically replace that “?” with the value in <em>$idnumber</em> and it will properly escape things to prevent SQL injection attacks for you.</p><p>You can also do cool things like named parameters:</p><p><code>
    // define $database as a PDO object
    $values = ['id' =&gt; 10, 'email' =&gt; 'someemail@hologram.io'];
    $stmt = $database-&gt;prepare('SELECT * FROM users WHERE id = :id AND email = :email;');
    $result = $stmt-&gt;execute($values);
    $rows = $result-&gt;fetchAll();
</code></p><p>In this case, PDO will replace the parameters properly from that array while still sanitizing them.<br></p><p>PDO also exposes all the same interfaces regardless of the underlying database engine. There are of course the occasional SQL differences between engines, but most of the time you simply specify the type of database when you initially connect and then make all the same function calls you would for anything else.<br></p><h2>Phinx</h2><p>Speaking of databases, I want to mention a fantastic third party library we use called Phinx to do all of our database migrations. Anytime we need to make a schema change, we define it entirely using PHP code that Phinx then runs on the database. Migrations look like this:<br></p><p><code>
    $orders = $this-&gt;table('orders');
    $orders-&gt;addColumn('invoice_text', 'string', ['length'=&gt;256, 'default'=&gt;''])
           -&gt;update();
</code></p><p>Check them out at <a href="https://phinx.org/" target="_blank">phinx.org</a></p><h2>Lots of useful built-in functions</h2><p>One final aspect that makes things easier and faster in PHP is all of the great built-in utility functions.<br></p><p>Let’s say you have a result set from a database which would be an array of row arrays. You want to pull the name column from each one. You could of course do this with a map function, which PHP supports as well, but why not do this the easy way:</p><p><code>
$names = array_column($rows, 'name');
</code></p><p>‍<em>‍</em>That’s it. And it’s very fast, as that would all be running in PHP’s C internals.<br></p><p>There are dozens more like that, for everything from doing more array operations to parsing XML to manipulating uploaded files and PHP has great documentation on all of them.<br></p><p>A few useful ones that we like:</p><p><a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.array-chunk" target="_blank"><strong>array_chunk</strong></a><strong> </strong>- Break an array into smaller chunks of any size</p><p><a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.array-unique.php" target="_blank"><strong>array_unique</strong></a><strong> </strong>- Remove all duplicate values from an array</p><p><a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/class.datetime" target="_blank"><strong>DateTime</strong></a> - A whole class for handling dates that can also parse plain English date descriptions like “midnight first day of next month”</p><p><a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.fpassthru" target="_blank"><strong>fpassthru</strong></a> - Reads a file and sends it right back out to the user</p><p><a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.str-getcsv" target="_blank"><strong>str_getcsv</strong></a> - Part of built-in CSV parsing, this reads a CSV row from a string</p><p><a href="https://www.php.net/manual/en/function.urlencode" target="_blank"><strong>urlencode</strong></a> - URL encode a string</p><p>And don’t forget useful operators like <em>??</em> which allows you to check for index existence in an array while specifying a default value. </p><p><code>
$a = $some_array[$x] ?? 500;
</code></p><h2>Conclusion</h2><div><p>Consider PHP for your projects! It’s better than you think.</p></div><h3>Further Reading</h3><p>Modern PHP by Josh Lockhart (The author of the Slim Framework)</p><p><a href="https://phptherightway.com/">phptherightway.com</a> (Also by Josh Lockhart and Phil Sturgeon)</p></div></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.hologram.io/blog/why-we-dont-hate-php</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23871934</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 16:01:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Straightened Trees]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 184 | Comments 35 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23871907">thread link</a>) | @samizdis
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | http://danieltemkin.com/StraightenedTrees | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/http://danieltemkin.com/StraightenedTrees">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
    
    <h2>(2016 - now)</h2>
    <p>
        Using custom code, the natural curvature of each tree is "corrected." Manufactured objects, i.e. buildings and power lines, twist and contort around the artificially plumbed tree. Each photo is shot on large format film, the only medium that captures enough detail to straighten the tree without pixelly artifacts. Presented as silver gelatin prints.
    </p>
    <p>Gallery contact:</p>
    <p>
        <a href="https://higherpictures.com/artists/daniel-temkin/">Higher Pictures</a><br>
        980 Madison Avenue<br>
        New York, NY 10075<br>
        212 249 6100<br>
        <a href="mailto:office@higherpictures.com">office@higherpictures.com</a>
    </p>
    <h2>Press</h2>
    <ul>
        <li>Aperture, <a href="https://aperture.org/blog/back-future/"><i>Back to the Future</i></a></li>
        <li>Huffington Post, <a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/58bcdd62e4b02eac8876d08b"><i>Jon Feinstein's Future Isms</i></a></li>
        <li>Form Magazine, Issue 263, <a href="http://www.form.de/en/magazine/form263"><i>Design and Energy</i></a> (a feature on the work, offline only)</li>
    </ul>

    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/SummerIsland_border.jpg"></p><p>
            Summer Island<br>
            2016<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            37⅝ × 41¾ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/Harvard_border.jpg"></p><p>
            Harvard<br>
            2017<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            46⅓ × 38¼ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/WPico_border.jpg"></p><p>
            W. Pico<br>
            2016<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            38⅝ × 32⅛ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/WHastings_border.jpg"></p><p>
            W. Hastings, Vancouver<br>
            2017<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            48 × 60 inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/Saratoga_border.jpg"></p><p>
            Saratoga, NY<br>
            2016<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            47 × 60 inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/Central_Phoenix_border.jpg"></p><p>
            Central City Phoenix<br>
            2019<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            60 × 48½ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/guilfoyle_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Guilfoyle<br>
            2019<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            51 × 42¾ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/route17_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Route 17<br>
            2019<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            40 × 48 inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/silverlake_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Silver Lake<br>
            2019<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            31⅘ × 26⅔ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/vancouver_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Vancouver<br>
            2019<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            34⅓ × 44⅓ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/Calvary_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Calvary Cemetary<br>
            2019<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            38⅗ × 31⅛ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/s_dixie_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            South Dixie Hwy<br>
            2020<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            43.7 × 60 inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/santa_lucia_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Santa Lucia Dr<br>
            2020<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            36 × 29⅓ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/SouthOceanBlvd_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            South Ocean Blvd<br>
            2020<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            40 × 33½ inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/summa_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Summa Street<br>
            2020<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            43¼ × 40 inches
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <p><img src="http://danieltemkin.com/Content/StraightenedTrees/silverlake_shadows_1500.jpg"></p><p>
            Silver Lake (Shadows)<br>
            2018<br>
            silver gelatin print<br>
            37⅓ × 47½ inches
        </p>
    </div>
</div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>http://danieltemkin.com/StraightenedTrees</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23871907</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:58:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Ways to make a web component]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 344 | Comments 190 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23871367">thread link</a>) | @kjhughes
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://webcomponents.dev/blog/all-the-ways-to-make-a-web-component/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://webcomponents.dev/blog/all-the-ways-to-make-a-web-component/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><p>Compare coding style, bundle size and performance of 33 different ways to make a Web Component.</p><p>The same <code>&lt;my-counter/&gt;</code> Web Component has been written in 33 variants.</p><div id="vtabs-sources" selectedindex="1"><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/html5.svg"><p>HTMLElement</p><blockquote></blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/custom-elements.html">https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/custom-elements.html</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/DVpCIwHwTgts9Mg1tBHl?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>class MyCounter extends HTMLElement {
  constructor() {
    super();
    this.count = 0;

    const style = `
      * {
        font-size: 200%;
      }

      span {
        width: 4rem;
        display: inline-block;
        text-align: center;
      }

      button {
        width: 64px;
        height: 64px;
        border: none;
        border-radius: 10px;
        background-color: seagreen;
        color: white;
      }
    `;

    const html = `
      &lt;button id="dec"&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;${this.count}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;button id="inc"&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;
    `;

    this.attachShadow({ mode: 'open' });
    this.shadowRoot.innerHTML = `
    &lt;style&gt;
      ${style}
    &lt;/style&gt;
    ${html}
    `;

    this.buttonInc = this.shadowRoot.getElementById('inc');
    this.buttonDec = this.shadowRoot.getElementById('dec');
    this.spanValue = this.shadowRoot.querySelector('span');

    this.inc = this.inc.bind(this);
    this.dec = this.dec.bind(this);
  }

  inc() {
    this.count++;
    this.update();
  }

  dec() {
    this.count--;
    this.update();
  }

  update() {
    this.spanValue.innerText = this.count;
  }

  connectedCallback() {
    this.buttonInc.addEventListener('click', this.inc);
    this.buttonDec.addEventListener('click', this.dec);
  }

  disconnectedCallback() {
    this.buttonInc.removeEventListener('click', this.inc);
    this.buttonDec.removeEventListener('click', this.dec);
  }
}

customElements.define('my-counter', MyCounter);
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/lighterhtml.svg"><p>HTMLElement (w/ Lighterhtml)</p><blockquote>The hyperHTML strength &amp; experience without its complexity</blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="https://medium.com/@WebReflection/lit-html-vs-hyperhtml-vs-lighterhtml-c084abfe1285">https://medium.com/@WebReflection/lit-html-vs-hyperhtml-vs-lighterhtml-c084abfe1285</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/WebReflection/lighterhtml">https://github.com/WebReflection/lighterhtml</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/KWyZrrVnMQiyBbtxCNbY?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import { html, render } from 'lighterhtml';

class MyCounter extends HTMLElement {
  constructor() {
    super();
    this.count = 0;

    this.attachShadow({ mode: 'open' });

    this.update();
  }

  inc = () =&gt; {
    this.count++;
    this.update();
  };

  dec = () =&gt; {
    this.count--;
    this.update();
  };

  style() {
    return `
      * {
        font-size: 200%;
      }

      span {
        width: 4rem;
        display: inline-block;
        text-align: center;
      }

      button {
        width: 64px;
        height: 64px;
        border: none;
        border-radius: 10px;
        background-color: seagreen;
        color: white;
      }
    `;
  }

  template() {
    return html`
      &lt;style&gt;
        ${this.style()}
      &lt;/style&gt;
      &lt;button onclick="${this.dec}"&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;${this.count}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;button onclick="${this.inc}"&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;
    `;
  }

  update() {
    render(this.shadowRoot, this.template());
  }
}

customElements.define('my-counter', MyCounter);
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/lit.svg"><p>HTMLElement (w/ Lit-html)</p><blockquote>Lit-Html - An efficient, expressive, extensible HTML templating library for JavaScript</blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="https://lit-html.polymer-project.org/">https://lit-html.polymer-project.org/</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/polymer/lit-html">https://github.com/polymer/lit-html</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/GaPzgIw1vilgYvMOtNEf?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import { html, render } from 'lit-html';

class MyCounter extends HTMLElement {
  constructor() {
    super();
    this.count = 0;

    this.attachShadow({ mode: 'open' });
    this.update();
  }

  inc() {
    this.count++;
    this.update();
  }

  dec() {
    this.count--;
    this.update();
  }

  style() {
    return `
      * {
        font-size: 200%;
      }

      span {
        width: 4rem;
        display: inline-block;
        text-align: center;
      }

      button {
        width: 64px;
        height: 64px;
        border: none;
        border-radius: 10px;
        background-color: seagreen;
        color: white;
      }
    `;
  }

  template() {
    return html`
      &lt;style&gt;
        ${this.style()}
      &lt;/style&gt;
      &lt;button @click="${this.dec}"&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;${this.count}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;button @click="${this.inc}"&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;
    `;
  }

  update() {
    render(this.template(), this.shadowRoot, { eventContext: this });
  }
}

customElements.define('my-counter', MyCounter);
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/micro-black.svg"><p>HTMLElement (w/ uhtml)</p><blockquote>micro html is a ~2.5K lighterhtml subset to build declarative and reactive UI via template literals tags.</blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="https://github.com/WebReflection/uhtml">https://github.com/WebReflection/uhtml</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/WebReflection/uhtml">https://github.com/WebReflection/uhtml</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/qTJwr8p3KKI7Os2kjfxR?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import { html, render } from "uhtml";

class MyCounter extends HTMLElement {
  constructor() {
    super();
    this.count = 0;

    this.attachShadow({ mode: "open" });

    this.update();
  }

  inc = () =&gt; {
    this.count++;
    this.update();
  };

  dec = () =&gt; {
    this.count--;
    this.update();
  };

  template() {
    return html`
      &lt;style&gt;
        * {
          font-size: 200%;
        }

        span {
          width: 4rem;
          display: inline-block;
          text-align: center;
        }

        button {
          width: 64px;
          height: 64px;
          border: none;
          border-radius: 10px;
          background-color: seagreen;
          color: white;
        }
      &lt;/style&gt;
      &lt;button onclick="${this.dec}"&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;${this.count}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;button onclick="${this.inc}"&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;
    `;
  }

  update() {
    render(this.shadowRoot, this.template());
  }
}

customElements.define("my-counter", MyCounter);
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/canjs.svg"><p>CanJS</p><blockquote>Build CRUD apps in fewer lines of code.</blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="https://canjs.com/">https://canjs.com/</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/canjs/canjs">https://github.com/canjs/canjs</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/MBTglStR8yb68qzNSctg?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import { StacheElement } from "can";
// Extend Component to define a custom element
class MyCounter extends StacheElement {
  constructor() {
    super();
    this.viewRoot = this.attachShadow({ mode: "open" });
  }

  static view = `&lt;style&gt;
* {
  font-size: 200%;
}

span {
  width: 4rem;
  display: inline-block;
  text-align: center;
}

button {
  width: 64px;
  height: 64px;
  border: none;
  border-radius: 10px;
  background-color: seagreen;
  color: white;
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;button on:click="this.decrement()"&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;span&gt;{{ this.count }}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;button on:click="this.increment()"&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;`;
  static props = {
    count: 0
  };
  increment() {
    this.count++;
  }
  decrement() {
    this.count--;
  }
}
customElements.define("my-counter", MyCounter);
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/hyperhtml.svg"><p>HyperHTML Element</p><blockquote>Framework agnostic, hyperHTML can be used to render any view, including Custom Elements and Web Components.</blockquote><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/WebReflection/hyperHTML-Element">https://github.com/WebReflection/hyperHTML-Element</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/XR3LcEpSkTYsEimV9iYI?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import HyperHTMLElement from "hyperhtml-element";

class MyCounter extends HyperHTMLElement {
  constructor() {
    super();
    this.attachShadow({ mode: "open" });
  }

  created() {
    this.count = 0;
    this.render();
  }

  inc = () =&gt; {
    this.count++;
    this.render();
  };

  dec = () =&gt; {
    this.count--;
    this.render();
  };

  render() {
    return this.html`
    &lt;style&gt;
      * {
      font-size: 200%;
    }

    span {
      width: 4rem;
      display: inline-block;
      text-align: center;
    }

    button {
      width: 64px;
      height: 64px;
      border: none;
      border-radius: 10px;
      background-color: seagreen;
      color: white;
    }
    &lt;/style&gt;
    &lt;button onclick=${this.dec}&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;${this.count}&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;button onclick=${this.inc}&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;
    `;
  }
}

MyCounter.define("my-counter");
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/lit.svg"><p>LitElement</p><blockquote></blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="https://lit-element.polymer-project.org/">https://lit-element.polymer-project.org/</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/polymer/lit-element">https://github.com/polymer/lit-element</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/N2jGJFmFQfHkJDCXckE5?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import { LitElement, html, css } from 'lit-element';

export class MyCounter extends LitElement {
  static properties = {
    count: { type: Number }
  };

  static styles = css`
    * {
      font-size: 200%;
    }

    span {
      width: 4rem;
      display: inline-block;
      text-align: center;
    }

    button {
      width: 64px;
      height: 64px;
      border: none;
      border-radius: 10px;
      background-color: seagreen;
      color: white;
    }
  `;

  constructor() {
    super();
    this.count = 0;
  }

  inc() {
    this.count++;
  }

  dec() {
    this.count--;
  }

  render() {
    return html`
      &lt;button @click="${this.dec}"&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
      &lt;span&gt;${this.count}&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;button @click="${this.inc}"&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;
    `;
  }
}

customElements.define('my-counter', MyCounter);
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/neow.png"><p>Neow (Alpha)</p><blockquote>Modern, fast, and light it's the front-end framework to fall inlove with. (ALPHA)</blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="https://neow.dev/">https://neow.dev</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://webcomponents.dev/blog/all-the-ways-to-make-a-web-component/(alpha)">(alpha)</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/eYLyh4FLXdre3ica9B2R?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import { ComponentMixin } from "@neow/core";

class MyComponent extends ComponentMixin(HTMLElement) {
  static template = `
  &lt;style&gt;
    * {
      font-size: 200%;
    }

    span {
      width: 4rem;
      display: inline-block;
      text-align: center;
    }

    button {
      width: 64px;
      height: 64px;
      border: none;
      border-radius: 10px;
      background-color: seagreen;
      color: white;
    }
  &lt;/style&gt;
  &lt;button onclick="{{this.dec()}}"&gt;-&lt;/button&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;{{this.counter}}&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;button onclick="{{this.inc()}}"&gt;+&lt;/button&gt;
`;

  counter = 0;

  inc() {
    this.counter++;
  }

  dec() {
    this.counter--;
  }
}

customElements.define("my-counter", MyComponent);
</code></pre></section><section slot="panel"><img src="https://webcomponents.dev/assets/lib/omi.png"><p>Omi w/Class</p><blockquote>Front End Cross-Frameworks Framework - Merge Web Components, JSX, Virtual DOM, Functional style, observe or Proxy into one framework with tiny size and high performance. Write components once, using in everywhere, such as Omi, React, Preact, Vue or Angular.</blockquote><p>Homepage: <a href="http://omijs.org/">http://omijs.org</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Tencent/omi">https://github.com/Tencent/omi</a></p><a href="https://webcomponents.dev/edit/wh5JCTAGQKiOeZHMXL91?pm=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Try in WebComponents.dev</a><pre><code>import { define, WeElement, html } from "omi";

class MyCounter extends WeElement {
  static get propTypes() {
    return {
      count: Number
    };
  }

  static get defaultProps() {
    return { count: 0 };
  }

  install() {
    this.data = { count: this.props.count };
  }

  static get css() {
    return `
      * {
        font-size: 200%;
      }

      span {
        …</code></pre></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://webcomponents.dev/blog/all-the-ways-to-make-a-web-component/">https://webcomponents.dev/blog/all-the-ways-to-make-a-web-component/</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://webcomponents.dev/blog/all-the-ways-to-make-a-web-component/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23871367</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:11:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Arctic Code Vault Contributor]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 81 | Comments 68 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23871126">thread link</a>) | @dgellow
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://sam.elborai.me/blog/arctic-code-vault-contributor | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://sam.elborai.me/blog/arctic-code-vault-contributor">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://sam.elborai.me/blog/arctic-code-vault-contributor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23871126</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 14:51:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Adventures in Beam Optimization for MQTT]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 64 | Comments 1 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23870769">thread link</a>) | @pimterry
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://www.ably.io/blog/beam-optimization-mqtt/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://www.ably.io/blog/beam-optimization-mqtt/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://www.ably.io/blog/beam-optimization-mqtt/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23870769</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 14:25:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Come for the network, pay for the tool]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 63 | Comments 10 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23870661">thread link</a>) | @cookingoils
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://subpixel.space/entries/come-for-the-network-pay-for-the-tool/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://subpixel.space/entries/come-for-the-network-pay-for-the-tool/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to retrieve article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://subpixel.space/entries/come-for-the-network-pay-for-the-tool/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23870661</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 14:14:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Creating a Wireshark dissector in Lua (2017)]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 73 | Comments 5 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23870507">thread link</a>) | @xanthine
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://mika-s.github.io/wireshark/lua/dissector/2017/11/04/creating-a-wireshark-dissector-in-lua-1.html | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://mika-s.github.io/wireshark/lua/dissector/2017/11/04/creating-a-wireshark-dissector-in-lua-1.html">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div aria-label="Content">
      <div>
        <article itemscope="" itemtype="http://schema.org/BlogPosting">

  

  <div itemprop="articleBody">
    <p>This post will explain how you can easily create <a href="https://wiki.wireshark.org/Lua/Dissectors">protocol dissectors</a>
in Wireshark, using the Lua programming language. This is can be useful when you’re working with
a custom protocol that Wireshark doesn’t already have a dissector for. If Wireshark looks like
this for example</p>

<p><img src="https://mika-s.github.io/assets/creating-wireshark-dissectors-1/before.png" alt="Wireshark without dissector"></p>

<p>it’s hard to tell what the various bytes in the data part represents.</p>

<p>Wireshark is written in C, and dissectors for Wireshark are generally also written in C. However,
Wireshark has a Lua implementation that makes it easy for people who are unfamiliar with C to write
dissectors. For those who are unfamiliar with Lua, it’s a very light-weight programming language
that is designed to be implemented as a scripting language in applications to extend their
functionality.</p>

<p>The downside of using Lua is that the dissector will be slower than a dissector written in C.</p>

<p>Before we start writing the dissector, let’s go through a crash course on Lua. It’s not important
to know the language in detail, but we must know the basics.</p>

<h3 id="lua-crash-course">Lua crash course</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Lua is multi-paradigm, and supports procedural style, functional programming to some degree, and
it also has some object-oriented programming features. It doesn’t have classes, prototypes or
inheritance out of the box, but they can be made by the programmer.</li>
  <li>It’s dynamically typed.</li>
  <li>Scope is either <code>local</code> or <code>global</code>. It’s global if you don’t declare it.</li>
  <li>Semicolons are not needed. Whitespace is not important like in Python.</li>
  <li>Lines that start with <code>--</code> are comments.</li>
  <li>Don’t use <code>++</code> or <code>+=</code>. Use <code>i = i + 1</code> instead.</li>
  <li>Not equal in conditionals is <code>~=</code> rather than <code>!=</code>.</li>
  <li>Its types are: string, number, boolean, nil, function, userdata, thread and table. Number
represents all numbers, both floating points and integers. Booleans are either true or false.
Strings are either single-quote or double-quote. You can forget about thread and userdata.</li>
  <li>nil is a non-value. A variable will have the value nil before it’s assigned a proper value.</li>
  <li>In conditionals: nil and false are falsy, the rest are thruthy.</li>
  <li>Lua has a type called <code>table</code>, which is also the only data structure it has. Tables implements
associative arrays. Associative arrays can be indexed by both numbers and other types, such as
strings. They have no fixed size and elements can be added dynamically. Tables are often called
objects. They are created like this:</li>
</ul>



<p>Values are assigned like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>new_table</span><span>[</span><span>20</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>10</span>
<span>new_table</span><span>[</span><span>"x"</span><span>]</span> <span>=</span> <span>"test"</span>
<span>a</span><span>.</span><span>x</span> <span>=</span> <span>10</span>                    <span>-- same as a["x"] = 10</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>They can have functions and are generally very similar to objects in JavaScript.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Conditional branching looks like this:</li>
</ul>

<div><div><pre><code><span>if</span> <span>i</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> <span>then</span> <span>variable</span> <span>=</span> <span>200</span>
<span>elseif</span> <span>i</span> <span>==</span> <span>1</span> <span>then</span> <span>variable</span> <span>=</span> <span>300</span>
<span>else</span> <span>variable</span> <span>=</span> <span>400</span> <span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<ul>
  <li>Loops look like this:</li>
</ul>

<div><div><pre><code><span>while</span> <span>i</span> <span>&lt;</span> <span>10</span> <span>do</span>
  <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>i</span> <span>+</span> <span>1</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<div><div><pre><code><span>for</span> <span>i</span> <span>=</span> <span>0</span><span>,</span> <span>10</span><span>,</span> <span>1</span> <span>do</span>
  <span>print</span><span>(</span><span>i</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>That is <em>i = first</em>, <em>last</em>, <em>delta</em>. <code>break</code> can be used, but continue cannot.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Functions are declared like this:</li>
</ul>

<div><div><pre><code><span>function</span> <span>add</span><span>(</span><span>arg1</span><span>,</span> <span>arg2</span><span>)</span>
    <span>return</span> <span>arg1</span> <span>+</span> <span>arg2</span>
<span>end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and are called like this:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>local</span> <span>added_number</span> <span>=</span> <span>add</span><span>(</span><span>2</span><span>,</span> <span>3</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you see functions called like this:</p>



<p>then the functions <code>func1</code> and <code>func2</code> belongs to the table (object) <code>a</code>. Using colon is syntactic
sugar for passing the object itself as an argument to the function. That means <code>a:func1()</code> is
similar to <code>a.func1(a)</code>.</p>

<p>That’s the important stuff. You can read the <a href="https://www.lua.org/manual/5.3/">Lua 5.3 Reference Manual</a>
if you care about the details.</p>

<h3 id="setup">Setup</h3>

<p>If you go to Help –&gt; About Wireshark –&gt; Folders, you’ll find all the folders Wireshark reads Lua
scripts from. Choose either the Personal Lua Plugins, Global Lua Plugins or Personal configuration
folder. E.g. <em>C:\Program Files\Wireshark\plugins\2.4.2</em> on Windows. The script will be active when
Wireshark is started. You have to restart Wireshark after you do changes to the script, or reload
all the Lua scripts with <strong>Ctrl+Shift+L</strong>.</p>

<p>I’m using the latest version at the current date. What I’m doing here might not work on earlier
versions.</p>

<h3 id="the-protocol">The protocol</h3>

<p>The most interesting protocol to investigate in this post would probably be a custom one that
Wireshark doesn’t know of already, but all the custom protocols I’ve worked with have been work
related and I can’t post information about them here. So instead we’ll look at the
<a href="https://docs.mongodb.com/manual/reference/mongodb-wire-protocol/">MongoDB wire protocol</a>.</p>

<p><em>(There is already a <a href="https://wiki.wireshark.org/Mongo">Mongo dissector</a> in Wireshark, but I will not use that one.)</em></p>

<p>According to the specification linked to above, the MongoDB wire protocol is a TCP/IP protocol
using port number 27017. The byte ordering is little endian, meaning the least significant byte
comes first. Most protocols are big endian. The only difference is the ordering of the bytes. If
we had an int32 for example, with these bytes: <code>00 4F 23 11</code> in big endian, then the little endian
version would be <code>11 23 4F 00</code>. This is something must to take into account when writing the
dissector.</p>

<p>In this post, I’ll only take a look at the header of the protocol. It looks like this</p>

<p><img src="https://mika-s.github.io/assets/creating-wireshark-dissectors-1/mongodb-wire-protocol-header.png" alt="MongoDB protocol header"></p>

<p>We can see that it has four int32s, each containing 4 bytes, because 4*8 = 32.</p>

<h3 id="setting-up-the-boilerplate-code">Setting up the boilerplate code</h3>

<p>Let’s start by setting up some of the boilerplate code that’s needed in all dissectors:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>mongodb_protocol</span> <span>=</span> <span>Proto</span><span>(</span><span>"MongoDB"</span><span>,</span>  <span>"MongoDB Protocol"</span><span>)</span>

<span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>fields</span> <span>=</span> <span>{}</span>

<span>function</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>dissector</span><span>(</span><span>buffer</span><span>,</span> <span>pinfo</span><span>,</span> <span>tree</span><span>)</span>
  <span>length</span> <span>=</span> <span>buffer</span><span>:</span><span>len</span><span>()</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>length</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> <span>then</span> <span>return</span> <span>end</span>

  <span>pinfo</span><span>.</span><span>cols</span><span>.</span><span>protocol</span> <span>=</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>name</span>

  <span>local</span> <span>subtree</span> <span>=</span> <span>tree</span><span>:</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>,</span> <span>buffer</span><span>(),</span> <span>"MongoDB Protocol Data"</span><span>)</span>
<span>end</span>

<span>local</span> <span>tcp_port</span> <span>=</span> <span>DissectorTable</span><span>.</span><span>get</span><span>(</span><span>"tcp.port"</span><span>)</span>
<span>tcp_port</span><span>:</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>59274</span><span>,</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We start my creating a <a href="https://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsdg_html_chunked/lua_module_Proto.html#lua_class_Proto">Proto</a> (protocol) object and call it <code>mongodb_protocol</code>. The
table constructor takes two arguments: <code>name</code> and <code>description</code>. The protocol requires a <code>fields</code>
table and a dissector function. We haven’t added any fields yet, so the <code>fields</code> table is empty. The
dissector function is called once for every packet of our type.</p>

<p>The dissector function has three parameters: <code>buffer</code>, <code>pinfo</code> and <code>tree</code>. <code>buffer</code> contains the
packet’s buffer and is a <a href="https://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsdg_html_chunked/lua_module_Tvb.html#lua_class_Tvb">Tvb object</a>. It contains the data we want to dissect. <code>pinfo</code>
contains the columns of the packet list and is a <a href="https://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsdg_html_chunked/lua_module_Pinfo.html#lua_class_Pinfo">Pinfo object</a>. Finally, <code>tree</code> is
the tree root and is a <a href="https://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsdg_html_chunked/lua_module_Tree.html#lua_class_TreeItem">TreeItem object</a>.</p>

<p><img src="https://mika-s.github.io/assets/creating-wireshark-dissectors-1/columns.png" alt="Columns in packet list "></p>

<p><img src="https://mika-s.github.io/assets/creating-wireshark-dissectors-1/tree.png" alt="Tree in packet details pane"></p>

<p>Inside the dissector function, we start by checking the length of the buffer and then returning if
it’s empty.</p>

<p>As mentioned before, the <code>pinfo</code> object contains the columns in the packet list. We can use it to
set the protocol name when we receive a packet of MongoDB type. On the script’s first line we set
the name of the protocol to be “MongoDB” (by passing the name to the constructor). We set the
protocol column name here</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>pinfo</span><span>.</span><span>cols</span><span>.</span><span>protocol</span> <span>=</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>name</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and the protocol column name changes from TCP to MONGODB:</p>

<p><img src="https://mika-s.github.io/assets/creating-wireshark-dissectors-1/protocol-column.png" alt="Packet list protocol column"></p>

<p>We must then create a sub tree in the tree structure found in the Packet Details pane. It done by
adding an additional tree item to the tree object that was passed as an argument to the dissector
function.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>local</span> <span>subtree</span> <span>=</span> <span>tree</span><span>:</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>,</span> <span>buffer</span><span>(),</span> <span>"MongoDB Protocol Data"</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The string is the name of the sub tree. Without having added any fields it will look like this:</p>

<p><img src="https://mika-s.github.io/assets/creating-wireshark-dissectors-1/packet-pane-1.png" alt="Packet pane with MongoDB but without fields"></p>

<p>Finally, we must assign the protocol to a port. In my case, I’ll use port 59274, because that’s the
port I use to connect to the Mongo database.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>local</span> <span>tcp_port</span> <span>=</span> <span>DissectorTable</span><span>.</span><span>get</span><span>(</span><span>"tcp.port"</span><span>)</span>
<span>tcp_port</span><span>:</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>59274</span><span>,</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p><code>"udp.port"</code> can also be used, if the protocol uses UDP rather than TCP.</p>

<h3 id="adding-fields">Adding fields</h3>

<p>The script already runs at this stage, but it isn’t doing anything useful. For the script to do
something useful we have to add the fields that we want to parse. Fields are made by creating
<a href="https://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsdg_html_chunked/lua_module_Proto.html#lua_class_ProtoField">ProtoField</a> objects. We can start off simple by adding only the first field.
The first field in the MongoDB wire protocol specification is the message length, which is an int32.</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>mongodb_protocol</span> <span>=</span> <span>Proto</span><span>(</span><span>"MongoDB"</span><span>,</span>  <span>"MongoDB Protocol"</span><span>)</span>

<span>message_length</span> <span>=</span> <span>ProtoField</span><span>.</span><span>int32</span><span>(</span><span>"mongodb.message_length"</span><span>,</span> <span>"messageLength"</span><span>,</span> <span>base</span><span>.</span><span>DEC</span><span>)</span>

<span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>fields</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span> <span>message_length</span> <span>}</span>

<span>function</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>dissector</span><span>(</span><span>buffer</span><span>,</span> <span>pinfo</span><span>,</span> <span>tree</span><span>)</span>
  <span>length</span> <span>=</span> <span>buffer</span><span>:</span><span>len</span><span>()</span>
  <span>if</span> <span>length</span> <span>==</span> <span>0</span> <span>then</span> <span>return</span> <span>end</span>

  <span>pinfo</span><span>.</span><span>cols</span><span>.</span><span>protocol</span> <span>=</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>name</span>

  <span>local</span> <span>subtree</span> <span>=</span> <span>tree</span><span>:</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>,</span> <span>buffer</span><span>(),</span> <span>"MongoDB Protocol Data"</span><span>)</span>

  <span>subtree</span><span>:</span><span>add_le</span><span>(</span><span>message_length</span><span>,</span> <span>buffer</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>4</span><span>))</span>
<span>end</span>

<span>local</span> <span>tcp_port</span> <span>=</span> <span>DissectorTable</span><span>.</span><span>get</span><span>(</span><span>"tcp.port"</span><span>)</span>
<span>tcp_port</span><span>:</span><span>add</span><span>(</span><span>59274</span><span>,</span> <span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>We add the following above the dissector function:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>message_length</span> <span>=</span> <span>ProtoField</span><span>.</span><span>int32</span><span>(</span><span>"mongodb.message_length"</span><span>,</span> <span>"messageLength"</span><span>,</span> <span>base</span><span>.</span><span>DEC</span><span>)</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The first argument is used as a label in the filter settings, second is used as a label in the sub
tree and the last is used to decide how the variable’s value should be displayed. In this case I
want to show the value in decimal, but I could also use <code>base.HEX</code> to show it in hexadecimal format.
Hexadecimal format doesn’t work for int32 though.</p>

<p><code>ProtoField</code> has several types of functions we can use: <code>uint8()</code>, <code>uint16()</code>, <code>string()</code> and so on.
We have to use the one that matches the specification. A list of all the functions can be found
<a href="https://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsdg_html_chunked/lua_module_Proto.html#lua_fn_ProtoField_char_abbr___name____base____valuestring____mask____desc__">here</a>.</p>

<p>We then add the field to the <code>fields</code> table of the protocol:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>mongodb_protocol</span><span>.</span><span>fields</span> <span>=</span> <span>{</span> <span>message_length</span> <span>}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>and finally add the field to the sub tree:</p>

<div><div><pre><code><span>subtree</span><span>:</span><span>add_le</span><span>(</span><span>message_length</span><span>,</span> <span>buffer</span><span>(</span><span>0</span><span>,</span><span>4</span><span>))</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I use <code>add_le</code> rather than <code>add</code>, because we are working with a little-endian protocol. If the
protocol was big endian we would have to use <code>add</code>. The function takes two arguments: the field we
made further up, and a <a href="https://www.wireshark.org/docs/wsdg_html_chunked/lua_module_Tvb.html#lua_class_TvbRange">buffer range</a>. We can get a range of the buffer by using
the range function that is a part of the buffer object. <code>buffer(offset,length)</code> is the short form
for the range function. <code>buffer(0,4)</code> means we want to start at the first byte, and then take 4
bytes. The reason we want to start at 0 is because we’re dealing with the first field in the header.
We take 4 bytes because that is the size of an int32.</p>

<p>After reloading the Lua script with <strong>Ctrl+Shift+L</strong> Wireshark should look like this:</p>

<p><img src="https://mika-s.github.io/assets/creating-wireshark-dissectors-1/messageLength-added.png" alt="Message length added to sub tree"></p>

<p>We can see that it parses the messageLength correctly. We can also see that we don’t …</p></div></article></div></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://mika-s.github.io/wireshark/lua/dissector/2017/11/04/creating-a-wireshark-dissector-in-lua-1.html">https://mika-s.github.io/wireshark/lua/dissector/2017/11/04/creating-a-wireshark-dissector-in-lua-1.html</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://mika-s.github.io/wireshark/lua/dissector/2017/11/04/creating-a-wireshark-dissector-in-lua-1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23870507</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 13:58:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Improving Performance of PHP for Arm64 and Impact on Amazon EC2 M6g Instances]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 105 | Comments 39 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23870240">thread link</a>) | @zdw
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://idk.dev/improving-performance-of-php-for-arm64-and-impact-on-amazon-ec2-m6g-instances/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://idk.dev/improving-performance-of-php-for-arm64-and-impact-on-amazon-ec2-m6g-instances/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div id=""><p><em>This post is contributed by Sebastian Pop, Senior Software Engineer, Amazon Web Services.</em></p><p>AWS recently launched the Amazon EC2 M6g instances powered by Graviton2. Compared to similar-sized M5 instances, Graviton2 instances provide up to 40% better cost-performance on several open-source application stacks.</p><p>This blog discusses how AWS worked together with the PHP community to drive major improvements to the performance of the PHP software stack on the Graviton2-based instances. By using M6g instances, the latest release of PHP-7.4 currently experiences up to 37% faster execution time compared to the previous release PHP-7.3. This significantly lowers the cost of running PHP software such as WordPress on Amazon EC2 M6g instances.</p><h3>A better Zend optimizer for Arm64</h3><p>Zend optimizer is a component of the PHP runtime system that improves performance by up to 30% on a range of Zend micro-benchmarks. Before PHP 7.4 the Zend optimizer was not enabled for Arm. AWS added Arm64-specific implementations to several functions of the PHP interpreter.<br>AWS evaluated the performance impact of the software changes to the PHP interpreter by running the standard micro-benchmarks distributed with the Zend optimizer: bench.php and micro_bench.php. To look at the performance of PHP interpreter as used in a fully loaded server, the benchmarks are set to run as many copies in parallel as vCPUs in the system, that is, each vCPU runs one copy of the benchmark such that the utilization of the system is above 95%. The experiment was run on a 16 vCPUs Graviton2 M6g.4xl and a 16 vCPUs Intel M5.4xl instances. Between PHP versions 7.3 and 7.4 the execution time of M6g instances improved by up to 37%. The following images demonstrate the benchmark results: the first image shows improved execution time of Zend/bench.php with newer versions of PHP, and the second image illustrates a faster execution time with newer versions of PHP on Zend/micro_bench.php.</p><p><img src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png" alt="PHP performance with Graviton2" width="1027" height="300" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png"></p><h3>Performance evaluation of WordPress on Ubuntu 19.04</h3><p>While the synthetic benchmarks proved M6g’s superior performance, I also looked at WordPress, a PHP-based real-world application. The following image shows the setup of the experiment:</p><p><img src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1594781652_527_Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png" alt="PHP WordPress" width="497" height="145" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1594781652_527_Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png"></p><p>The machine represented in the middle of the image is the system under test (SUT) that is an M6g.4xl and an M5.4xl. To measure the performance of PHP independently of other components in the system, the MySQL database is set to run on a separate C5.4xl instance, in blue on the figure. The program WRK generates the HTTP requests for the main page of WordPress. WRK runs on a separate C5.4xl instance represented in orange on the figure. To minimize network noise, the three machines are allocated in the same cluster placement group. The SUT runs the NGINX web-server and the PHP interpreter. The NGINX web-server is configured with the fast CGI interface PHP-FPM. All the machines run Ubuntu 19.04.</p><p>With the software changes in PHP-7.4 and PHP-8, WordPress can serve up to 17% more pages per second on M6g.4xl vs. M5.4xl. Combined with the 20% lower cost of M6g instances, running PHP-7.4 and WordPress provides up to 34% better price/performance on M6g instances vs. M5 instances. The following image illustrates the performance of PHP versions 7.3, 7.4, and 8 when running on M6g.4xl and M5.4xl instances:</p><p><img src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1594781652_522_Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png" alt="Wordpress NGINX performance" width="483" height="253" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1594781652_522_Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png"></p><p>Looking at the scalability of WordPress-NGINX benchmark on the M6g instances, and a better performing PHP-7.4 release, adding more vCPUs scales almost linearly in the number of served pages until eight vCPUs. However, on the beta version of PHP-8 from August 20, 2019 that contains even more optimizations, the scalability trend continues up to 32 vCPUs (after which CPU utilization drops below 90%.)<br>On the low-cost end of the spectrum, AWS offers an M6g.medium instance with 1vCPU that can sustain up to 77 pages per second which may be interesting for small (cost-conscious) users of WordPress.</p><p><img src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1594781652_655_Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png" alt="Scalability of WordPress NGINX" width="497" height="453" data-old-src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7" data-src="https://idk.dev/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1594781652_655_Improving-performance-of-PHP-for-Arm64-and-impact-on-Amazon.png"></p><h3>How to install PHP-7.4</h3><p>Installation instructions: https://www.php.net/install<br>Installation instructions for Ubuntu: https://computingforgeeks.com/how-to-install-php-on-ubuntu/</p><h3>AWS contributions to PHP-7.4</h3><h3>Patches impacting performance of WordPress benchmark</h3><p>The 20% performance difference from PHP-7.4 and PHP-8 master is due to https://github.com/php/php-src/commit/682b54f68748715f85e9ac4a267477d9ac61918a that removes support for PHP-4 constructors deprecated in PHP-7.0 https://wiki.php.net/rfc/remove_php4_constructors.<br>As this has been committed early after the PHP-7.4 branch has been cut, the patch may be easily applied to the PHP-7.4 branch to get the performance benefits that we see in PHP-8 master.<br>There are two other patches that impact the performance of the WordPress-NGINX benchmark, and both have been applied to master and PHP-7.4 branch:</p><h3>Future developments</h3><p>PHP-8 plans to release in 2021 with more improvements for Arm64: an improved toupper/tolower function brings performance up by 16.5x. https://github.com/php/php-src/pull/4439</p><p>AWS has contributed changes to PCRE2 release 10.34. PCRE2 version 10.34 is used in PHP-8 to match regular expressions. PCRE2 accounted for about 8% of execution time in WordPress benchmark. The change contributed by AWS to PCRE2 vectorizes first character match and matching pairs of characters with NEON instructions: performance improves by up to 8x on M6g. https://lists.exim.org/lurker/message/20191106.052444.1ea1a176.en.html</p><p>PHP-8 plans to feature a new JIT compiler that optimizes the PHP byte-code in the Opcache. The JIT is currently developed on x86 and is based on Lua’s JIT. As Lua’s JIT supports ARM64, we work with PHP developers to enable and to tune the Opcache JIT in PHP-8 to get the best performance on AWS Graviton processors.</p><p>The interaction with PHP community was through early discussion with the maintainers of the PHP Zend optimizer on our plans to improve performance on ARM, patch reviews that improved the quality of our submissions, and follow-up patches from the community to address problems uncovered during review of our patches. AWS continues to contribute ARM performance improvements to PHP-8. We followed the same pattern of involvement with the PCRE community, and continue to work with other open-source communities to bring our expertise and knowledge in improving the performance and tuning of ARM-based AWS Graviton systems.</p><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>PHP release 7.4 is key to obtain maximum performance from the Graviton2-based M6g instances. PHP 7.4 makes the M6g instances even more appealing by delivering both higher performance and lower cost compared to M5 instances.</p><p>To get started, check out the New – EC2 M6g Instances, powered by AWS Graviton2, and please leave comments!</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://idk.dev/improving-performance-of-php-for-arm64-and-impact-on-amazon-ec2-m6g-instances/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23870240</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 13:30:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Turning the IDE Inside Out with Datalog]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 189 | Comments 26 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23869592">thread link</a>) | @arjunnarayan
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://petevilter.me/post/datalog-typechecking/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://petevilter.me/post/datalog-typechecking/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://petevilter.me/post/datalog-typechecking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23869592</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 12:01:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[How do I design a game from scratch? A primer on core loops]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 234 | Comments 42 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23869155">thread link</a>) | @NuclearTide
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://teamavocado.co/core-loop/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://teamavocado.co/core-loop/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>Start with the core loop (part 2 of the "make a sports game" tutorial)</p><div><p>Published </p><!-- --><p>July 17th, 2020</p></div><blockquote><p><em>This is part 2 of a tutorial series on making a sports game.</em></p><em>If you haven't, you can <a href="https://teamavocado.co/sports-game" target="_blank">click to read part 1 in a new tab</a>.</em></blockquote><p>After you've made your first Pong / Breakout / Snake clone, what do you make next?</p><p>You see these incredibly intricate games on the PICO-8 BBS:</p><p><span>
      <a href="https://teamavocado.co/static/e2d7eaea3b7e6d3de43cbd2b0e909661/0a47e/carts.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="awesome PICO-8 carts" title="awesome PICO-8 carts" src="https://teamavocado.co/static/e2d7eaea3b7e6d3de43cbd2b0e909661/0a47e/carts.png" srcset="https://teamavocado.co/static/e2d7eaea3b7e6d3de43cbd2b0e909661/5a46d/carts.png 300w,https://teamavocado.co/static/e2d7eaea3b7e6d3de43cbd2b0e909661/0a47e/carts.png 600w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p><p>And wonder, <em>"How do I get there? How do I understand complex game design ideas like the pros do?"</em></p><p><em>"How do I break down my awesome game idea into concrete tasks, so that I can actually make it?"</em></p><p>Once you've gotten a grasp on coding basics, complement your budding development skills with design skills.</p><p>Master the concept of the <strong>core loop</strong> to take your game dev to the next level.</p><p>Eager to learn more? Let's apply the core loop concept to a sports game.</p><h2 id="identify-the-core-loop">1. Identify the core loop</h2><p>Take a look at Pico Tennis, by <a href="https://twitter.com/gamecactus">Paranoid Cactus</a>:</p><undefined><span>
      <a href="https://teamavocado.co/static/fe46bd14f32816c8b5c262b5a937bff5/6bfd0/pico_tennis.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="Pico Tennis" title="Pico Tennis" src="https://teamavocado.co/static/fe46bd14f32816c8b5c262b5a937bff5/6bfd0/pico_tennis.png" srcset="https://teamavocado.co/static/fe46bd14f32816c8b5c262b5a937bff5/5a46d/pico_tennis.png 300w,https://teamavocado.co/static/fe46bd14f32816c8b5c262b5a937bff5/0a47e/pico_tennis.png 600w,https://teamavocado.co/static/fe46bd14f32816c8b5c262b5a937bff5/6bfd0/pico_tennis.png 1011w" sizes="(max-width: 1011px) 100vw, 1011px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span><br></undefined><p>It's a PICO-8 implementation of tennis, and it's really good!</p><p>You can play it on mobile through the BBS. I'll give you a few minutes to check it out:</p><blockquote><a href="https://www.lexaloffle.com/bbs/?tid=31450" target="_blank"><em>Play Pico Tennis here</em></a></blockquote><hr><p>Back? Great! Back to core loops.</p><p>Maybe it's obvious, but you might have noticed a looping structure to your interactions with the game:</p><p><span>
      <a href="https://teamavocado.co/static/bafdd938d707012b3b021fd2b74999c9/302a4/pico_tennis_loop.png" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
    <span></span>
  <img alt="pico tennis loop" title="pico tennis loop" src="https://teamavocado.co/static/bafdd938d707012b3b021fd2b74999c9/302a4/pico_tennis_loop.png" srcset="https://teamavocado.co/static/bafdd938d707012b3b021fd2b74999c9/5a46d/pico_tennis_loop.png 300w,https://teamavocado.co/static/bafdd938d707012b3b021fd2b74999c9/0a47e/pico_tennis_loop.png 600w,https://teamavocado.co/static/bafdd938d707012b3b021fd2b74999c9/302a4/pico_tennis_loop.png 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px" loading="lazy">
  </a>
    </span></p><p>The player serves. Then,</p><p>The opponent returns. The player returns.</p><p>The opponent returns. The player returns.</p><p><em>Ad infinitum.</em> Until either the player or opponent breaks the loop, because they failed to return the ball.</p><p>Tennis folks call this a rally, but for us, this repeating structure is the game's core loop. It's exactly what we were looking for.</p><p>A core loop is the game's <em>essential activity</em>. Every sport has one, and every game has one:</p><ul><li>Baseball: a pitcher pitches a ball; a batter hits the ball, or misses.</li><li>Football: a quarterback receives the ball, and makes a play.</li></ul><p>Games have larger loops of course! In baseball, runners run to bases around a diamond. There are innings. There are game series.</p><p>But we seek the smallest, tightest loop of the game. Such that if you take this loop away, the game won't work.</p><p>Can you find a game that <em>doesn't</em> have a core loop? Heck, one can argue that visual novels –&nbsp;which are heavily story-based –&nbsp;have a core loop of dialogue navigation.</p><p>Since <a href="https://teamavocado.co/sports-game">we're making a boxing game</a>, let's identify the core loop:</p><ol><li>A boxer throws a punch.</li><li>An opponent evades or blocks the punch, or throws a punch back.</li></ol><p>From that core idea, we can scope our project.</p><h2 id="define-project-milestones">2. Define project milestones</h2><p>When game developers say to build on a strong core, they refer to core loops.</p><p>Wanna know why?</p><p>Once you've identified your game's core loop, the path forward is clear:</p><ol><li>🧭 <s><strong>The Goal.</strong> Do you want to tell a story? Express a feeling? Fulfill a game jam prompt? Make a game for a certain demographic?</s></li><li>🍏 <s><strong>The Core Loop.</strong> What's the essential activity that defines your game?</s></li><li>👩 <strong>The First Playable.</strong> Get stuff moving on screen ASAP. Code up your core loop so that your mom can play it.</li><li>🥞 <strong>The Horizontal Slice.</strong> Full gameplay. All game mechanics finalized, including progression and leveling mechanics.</li><li>🍰 <strong>The Vertical Slice.</strong> Full user experience with all game states. Includes menus, and win-lose conditions.</li><li>💅 <strong>Polish.</strong> Juice up your feedback. Add more content.</li><li>🎂 <strong>The Full Cake.</strong> The final game.</li></ol><p>Oh, and if you're using PICO-8, you might need to optimize tokens in between steps. 😛</p><p>These milestones will guide us through the rest of the tutorial series, so keep it in mind!</p><h2 id="design-your-game-loops-length">3. Design your game loop's length</h2><p>I think a <strong>good</strong> game is one where the total player time far exceeds the development time.</p><p>Why? Because players can replay your game over and over if it's genuinely fun. On the other hand, you only had to make the game once.</p><p>You get a lot more bang for your buck.</p><p>Part of that comes from the length of the higher-level game loop.</p><p>If you recall Pico Tennis, the <em>essential activity</em> is hitting the ball back and forth. But the higher-level <em>game</em> loop is the <em>rally</em>.</p><p>And in Pico Tennis, a rally lasts maybe a minute. This is important!</p><p>If you're designing for busy people who play games in pockets of time, maybe you want minute-long game loops. So players can play several rounds within the span of a coffee break.</p><p>(An interesting take: Jan Willem Nijman's <em>Minit</em> has game length in its name. Its game loop lasts exactly 60 seconds.)</p><blockquote><p><em>"Man, that's deep. Can I get some dog treats now?"</em></p><p><em>– Paraphrasing my dog, as she stares intently into my soul.</em></p></blockquote><p>Once you understand the idea of a core loop, you start to see them everywhere.</p><p>Take the game of life.</p><p>Not Conway's Game of Life! But actual day-to-day life.</p><p>The core loop of life is a <em>day</em>. And within those iterations lies a life <em>story</em>.</p><p>(From now on, maybe you'll think twice before creating a recurring event in Google Calendar.)</p><p>That's what we're aiming for. With a game's core loop, we tell a story.</p><p>What story do you want to tell?</p><p>In the next blog post, we'll discuss how to go from core loop to <a href="#define-project-milestones">First Playable</a>.</p><hr><h2>🏃‍♀️ Exercise</h2><p>Try it!</p><p>Head over to the PICO-8 BBS. (The link below opens a new tab, which you can play on mobile.)</p><blockquote><em><a href="https://www.lexaloffle.com/bbs/?sub=2&amp;cat=7#sub=2&amp;orderby=featured" target="_blank">Open PICO-8 BBS in new tab</a></em></blockquote><p>Choose a PICO-8 cart that you like, and give it a play.</p><p>What's that PICO-8 cart's core loop? In the comments below, feel free to tell me the game you played, and what you think of the game's core loop.</p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://teamavocado.co/core-loop/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23869155</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 10:40:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Things I wish I’d known about CSS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 844 | Comments 320 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23868355">thread link</a>) | @harshamv22
<br/>
July 17, 2020 | https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div>
                
                    <section>
                <p>I learned how to build websites the old fashioned way: looking at website source code and trying to replicate the things I saw. I threw in the odd book for the stuff I couldn’t <em>see</em> (like PHP/MySQL), and I was on my way.</p>

<p>This was back in 1999, when we’d write things like <code>&lt;font size="4" color="#000000"&gt;</code> and DHTML was a <em>thing</em>.</p>

<p>When CSS came along my approach to learning didn’t differ. But I <em>really</em> wish I’d taken the time to learn CSS properly: there was so much fundamental stuff I missed.</p>

<p>Here are some things I didn’t know that I wish I’d learned earlier.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="block-inline-and-inline-block">Block, inline and inline-block</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>Even though I <em>knew</em> about these properties, I didn’t fully understand them for a long time.</p>

<p>Here’s a breakdown:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>block</code> elements expand horizontally to take up a whole line (like a heading). We can apply vertical margin to these.</li>
<li><code>inline</code> elements expand horizontally just enough to contain their content (like <code>strong</code> or <code>em</code> elements). We <strong>cannot apply vertical margins to these</strong> and they should usually be placed inside a <code>block</code> element.</li>
<li><code>inline-block</code> elements are like <code>inline</code> elements, <strong>but you can apply vertical margins to these</strong> (making them useful for things like buttons).</li>
</ul>

<p>In the example below, <code>block</code> elements have a blue border, <code>inline</code> elements have an orange background, and our <code>inline-block</code> element has a red border.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                <p data-height="400" data-theme-id="37523" data-default-tab="css,result" data-user="websmyth" data-slug-hash="9cc40d6abf5c7f24360ec58c75c91fd3" data-editable="true" data-pen-title="Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1">
                        <span>See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth/pen/9cc40d6abf5c7f24360ec58c75c91fd3">
                        Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1</a> by Dave Smyth (<a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth">@websmyth</a>)
                        on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</span>
                        </p>
                
            </section>
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="images-are-inline">Images are inline</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>Images <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/img#Styling_with_CSS">being inline by default</a> isn’t a problem, but it can cause confusion when trying to position them or add vertical margins.</p>

<p>If your CSS reset doesn’t include this already, I’d suggest adding the following rule:</p>

<pre><code>img {
    display: block;
}
</code></pre>

<p>That will make their behaviour much more predictable. You might also want to add <code>max-width: 100%;</code> to stop them breaking out of their container, too.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="how-height-and-width-are-calculated">How height and width are calculated</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>By default, the width/height of a box is calculated by adding together the dimensions of the:</p>

<ul>
<li>Content area</li>
<li>Padding area</li>
<li>Border area</li>
</ul>

<p>This isn’t usually a problem for an element’s height: we’re usually not too bothered about how content reflows vertically. The problems usually occur when trying to calculate an element’s width, especially if there’s more than one element in a row.</p>

<p>If we had the following CSS:</p>

<pre><code>.some-class {
    width: 50%;
    padding: 2em;
    border: 0.1rem;
}
</code></pre>

<p>The total calculated <code>width</code> for <code>.some-class</code> would be:</p>

<p><code>50% + 4em + 0.2rem</code></p>

<p>That’s because of a property called <code>box-sizing</code> which has a default value of <code>content-box</code>. This value means the <code>width</code> property <strong>applies to the content area</strong>: everything else is added on top of this.</p>

<p>We can change this for all elements with the following rule:</p>

<pre><code>* {
    box-sizing: border-box;
}
</code></pre>

<p>Returning to our example, the element’s width would now apply to the <code>border</code>, so our element’s total <code>width</code> would be <code>50%</code>.</p>

<p>What happens to the <code>border</code> and <code>padding</code>? Those properties/values still apply, but they don’t affect the total <code>width</code> of the element: they sit within the defined area.</p>

<p>Check out this Codepen to see this in action:</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                <p data-height="400" data-theme-id="37523" data-default-tab="css,result" data-user="websmyth" data-slug-hash="a4b49c52737aacbfc70342ff2753b5b0" data-editable="true" data-pen-title="Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1">
                        <span>See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth/pen/a4b49c52737aacbfc70342ff2753b5b0">
                        Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1</a> by Dave Smyth (<a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth">@websmyth</a>)
                        on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</span>
                        </p>
                
            </section>
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                                    <header>
                        <h3>Margin</h3>
                    </header>
                                <article>
                    <p>We haven’t discussed <code>margin</code> here because <strong>margin is the space between elements</strong>. For that reason, it is never part of this calculation.</p>

                                    </article>
            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="padding-margin-arent-the-same">Padding &amp; margin aren’t the same</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>If an element has no <code>background</code> or <code>border</code>, it can appear that <code>padding</code> and <code>margin</code> are the same. They are not!</p>

<ul>
<li><code>margin</code> is the space <strong>between</strong> elements</li>
<li><code>padding</code> is space <strong>inside</strong> an element</li>
</ul>

<p>That makes <code>padding</code> useful for elements that have a <code>background</code>. We often don’t want the content to be close to the edge of the element’s box and <code>padding</code> helps us achieve that.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="margins-collapse">Margins collapse</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>This has been the source of frustration for CSS newcomers for a long time. Rachel Andrew <a href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2019/07/margins-in-css/#margin-collapsing">describes the behaviour</a> as:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When margins collapse, they will combine so that the space between the two elements becomes the larger of the two margins. The smaller margin essentially ending up inside the larger one.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>If we have two block elements with <code>margin-bottom: 1em</code> on one element and <code>margin-top: 1.5em</code> on the element directly below it, the total space between the two elements would be <code>1.5em</code>.</p>

<p>We can see that here:</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
                    <section>
                <p data-height="400" data-theme-id="37523" data-default-tab="css,result" data-user="websmyth" data-slug-hash="43f1491b85413fd9af705ccad492aa7f" data-editable="true" data-pen-title="Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1">
                        <span>See the Pen <a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth/pen/43f1491b85413fd9af705ccad492aa7f">
                        Boxes –&nbsp;Example #1</a> by Dave Smyth (<a href="https://codepen.io/websmyth">@websmyth</a>)
                        on <a href="https://codepen.io/">CodePen</a>.</span>
                        </p>
                
            </section>
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>When two margins meet, the larger margin absorbs the smaller margin. If the margins are the same value, they absorb each other.</p>

<p>As soon as we know this, <code>margin</code> calculations become easier. It might also change our approach to managing them, and that’s where something like <a href="https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/managing-vertical-margins-in-css">the Lobotomised Owl selector can be useful</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> Margins don’t collapse when the parent element is set to <code>display: grid</code> or <code>display: flex</code>.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="browsers-have-a-default-stylesheet">Browsers have a default stylesheet</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>CSS stands for <strong>Cascading Style Sheets</strong>. It’s no surprise therefore that the <strong>cascade</strong> is one of the fundamental concepts of CSS.</p>

<p>Though we might be aware of how our own stylesheets interact with each other, we have to remember that there’s <strong>always a default browser stylesheet</strong>. This is loaded <em>before</em> any custom stylesheets, making it easy to redeclare existing values.</p>

<p>The declared styles vary by browser, but they’re the reason that, by default:</p>

<ul>
<li>Headings have different sizes</li>
<li>Text is black</li>
<li>Lists have bullet points</li>
<li>Elements have any <code>display</code> property (such as <code>block</code> or <code>inline</code>)</li>
</ul>

<p>And many other things.</p>

<p>Even if a website only has a single stylesheet, that stylesheet will always be merged with the browser’s default styles.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="use-relative-units-everywhere">Use relative units everywhere</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>Using pixels (<code>px</code>) is tempting because they’re simple to understand: declare <code>font-size: 24px</code> and the text will be <code>24px</code>. But that won’t provide a great user experience, particularly for users who resize content at <a href="https://adrianroselli.com/2019/12/responsive-type-and-zoom.html#Update02">the browser level</a> or zoom into content.</p>

<p>I started using <code>em</code> (and later <code>rem</code>) for font sizing early. It took much longer to feel comfortable using <code>em</code> and <code>rem</code> for other things such as <code>padding</code>, <code>margin</code>, <code>letter-spacing</code> and <code>border</code>.</p>

<p>Understanding the difference between <code>em</code> and <code>rem</code> is critical to making relative units manageable. For instance, we might use <code>em</code> for <code>@media</code> queries and vertical margins, but <code>rem</code> for consistent <code>border-width</code>.</p>

<p>The benefits of going all-in on relative sizing are well-worth the small adjustment in thinking that requires.</p>

            </section>
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
        
        
                        
<h2 id="before-and-after-need-content">::before and ::after need content</h2> 
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
        
            
                    <section>
                <p>When using either …</p></section></div></div>
<br/><p><em>Article truncated for RSS feed. Read the full article at <a href="https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css">https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css</a></em></p>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://cssfordesigners.com/articles/things-i-wish-id-known-about-css</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23868355</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 08:17:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[Show HN: A completely different way to write responsive, vanilla, CSS]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 244 | Comments 43 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23865900">thread link</a>) | @James0x57
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/ | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/><div id="readability-page-1" class="page"><div><p>
        css-media-vars adds several --custom-css-variables, all namespaced with "--media-" and based on media queries, onto the HTML tag. These vars act as universal mixins for your CSS values. If the media query is true, your value will be used. If it's false, the var(..., fallback) will be used.</p><p>
        
        For example, there are several named breakpoints that respond to the width of the screen, such as <code>--media-lte-sm</code>.</p><p>
        
        In your CSS, if you want a value to only apply when the screen is less than or equal to the "small" breakpoint range, you mix it into your value:<br>
        <code>--my-small-value: var(--media-lte-sm) 2px;</code><br>
        From this point, you can use your variable anywhere and it will only be "2px" if the media query is true. Else, it uses the fallback you provide, like so:<br>
        <code>border: var(--my-small-value, 15px) solid green;</code><br>
        <img src="https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/suchborder.gif" alt="Border changing size at 900px breakpoint"><br>
        Here's a link to the jsbin pictured in the gif: <a href="https://jsbin.com/giqedowale/edit?css,output">https://jsbin.com/giqedowale/edit?css,output</a></p><p>
        
        If you need multiple break points, all you have to do is mix a different breakpoint into another variable and use it in the first fallback:<br>
        <code>
          --my-small-value: var(--media-lte-sm) 2px;<br>
          --my-medium-value: var(--media-md) 15px;<br>
          border: var(--my-small-value, var(--my-medium-value, 30px)) solid green;<br>
        </code><br>
        In this case, because the small values are listed first, this approach is <b>mobile-first</b>! CSS Variables don't compile the fallback unless it's used (similar to the expected short-circuting of conditionals in JavaScript).</p><p>
        
        This is all vanilla CSS. No JS or build step is necessary.<br>
        The library is small and built on a CSS trick called "Space Toggle" discovered in the development of <a href="http://augmented-ui.com/">augmented-ui</a>. You can read more about Space Toggle in these tweets which contain links to JSBins you can explore further with:<br>
        <a href="https://twitter.com/James0x57/status/1283596399196680192">Second Tweet, a simple demo</a><br>
        <a href="https://twitter.com/James0x57/status/1282303255826046977">First Tweet, an advanced demo</a></p><p>
        
        Browser support for CSS Variables is currently 94% globally according to <a href="https://caniuse.com/#feat=css-variables">caniuse</a>.<br>
        Each of the --media-* vars are using the actual media query in CSS to switch them to the "true" state. Browser support depends on the feature but will always behave as if it's "false" if the media query isn't supported in the user's browser, such as <code>--media-prefers-light</code> which only recently gained traction.
      </p></div></div>]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://propjockey.github.io/css-media-vars/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23865900</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 01:14:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[The Next Steps for Single Ownership and RAII]]>
            </title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[
Score 102 | Comments 37 (<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23865674">thread link</a>) | @verdagon
<br/>
July 16, 2020 | https://vale.dev/blog/next-steps-raii | <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/*/https://vale.dev/blog/next-steps-raii">archive.org</a>
<br/><!-- hnss:readable-content --><hr/>Unable to extract article]]>
            </description>
            <link>https://vale.dev/blog/next-steps-raii</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">hacker-news-small-sites-23865674</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:41:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
